<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 04:14:03 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/four-shot-dead-on-us-chicago-train-police-6477118]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Four Shot Dead On US' Chicago Train: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/four-shot-dead-on-us-chicago-train-police-6477118]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 02:47:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least four people were shot dead on a train in the US city of Chicago on Monday, police said, with a suspect apprehended soon after the mass shooting occurred.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least four people were shot dead on a train in the US city of Chicago on Monday, police said, with a suspect apprehended soon after the mass shooting occurred.</p>

<p>Police said they responded to a 911 emergency hotline call early on Monday morning, arriving at the Forest Park train station where they found the four victims.</p>

<p>"Three were pronounced dead on scene, the fourth was transported to Loyola University Medical Center in Maywood, where they were later pronounced," a police statement said.</p>

<p>Gun violence is common in the United States, a country where there are more firearms than people. Attempts to clamp down on gun rights are always met with stiff political resistance.</p>

<p>Chicago police put out a description of the suspected offender based on surveillence footage, and a suspect was later taken into custody with a firearm also recovered, the statement said.</p>

<p>"This appears to be an isolated incident with no immediate threat to the community," the statement said.</p>

<p>Chicago operates one of the largest public transportation networks in the United States, with more than 317,000 people using its train system on an average weekday, according to the Chicago Transit Authority.</p>

<p>"It's a horrible situation. It's definitely something that you don't want to wake up to. It's a Monday morning on a holiday," police official Christopher Chin told reporters, referring to the Labor Day holiday being observed in the United States.</p>

<p>This year, there have been at least 378 mass shootings -- defined as a shooting involving at least four victims -- across the United States, according to the Gun Violence Archive.</p>

<p>At least 11,463 people have been killed in firearms violence, according to the GVA.</p>

<p>In June, the US surgeon general issued a landmark advisory declaring gun violence a "public health crisis" and calling for wide-ranging firearm controls that have historically been quashed by political opposition.</p>

<p>Firearms in recent years have become the leading cause of deaths for Americans aged between one and 19, above motor vehicles, the report said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 11,463 people have been killed in firearms violence, according to the GVA. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hostages-will-return-inside-coffins-if-israel-hamas-6476824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hostages Will Return "Inside Coffins" If Israel...: Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hostages-will-return-inside-coffins-if-israel-hamas-6476824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 01:11:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas's armed wing said on Monday that hostages would return to Israel "inside coffins" if military pressure continued, warning that "new instructions" had been given to the militants guarding the captives if Israeli troops approached.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas's armed wing said on Monday that hostages would return to Israel "inside coffins" if military pressure continued, warning that "new instructions" had been given to the militants guarding the captives if Israeli troops approached.</p>

<p>"(Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin) Netanyahu's insistence on liberating the prisoners through military pressure instead of concluding a deal will mean that they will return to their families inside coffins," Abu Obeida, spokesman for the Ezzedine Al-Qassam Brigades, said in a statement.</p>

<p>"New instructions were issued to the mujahideen assigned to guard the prisoners regarding dealing with them if the occupation army approached their place of detention," he said, after Netanyahu earlier said the six hostages whose bodies were recovered at the weekend had been "executed".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dmff0tg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-kamala-harris-to-make-first-joint-campaign-appearance-6476727]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Kamala Harris To Make First Joint Campaign Appearance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-kamala-harris-to-make-first-joint-campaign-appearance-6476727]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:45:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden and Kamala Harris hit the campaign trail together for the first time Monday, in a public display of unity after she replaced him as candidate and revived Democratic election hopes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden and Kamala Harris hit the campaign trail together for the first time Monday, in a public display of unity after she replaced him as candidate and revived Democratic election hopes.</p>

<p>To mark the Labor Day holiday, the pair were set to attend an event with union members in the key battleground state of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, bowed out of the presidential race in late July under mounting pressure after his disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>His rapid endorsement of Vice President Harris, 59, saw her shore up party support and she became the formal Democratic nominee just weeks later.</p>

<p>Riding a wave of fresh enthusiasm, she has held packed rallies in key swing states across the country and raked in cash donations for the final two-month stretch of the campaign.</p>

<p>Polls show her entry improving the party's chances at defeating Republican Trump, but with the race still neck and neck.</p>

<p>Before her event with Biden in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Harris spoke to another union crowd in Detroit, Michigan, seeking to boost support from working-class voters that Trump claims as his base.</p>

<p>Flanked by leaders of the national teachers and autoworkers unions, Harris told the Detroit crowd that Trump "intends to pull us back, including back to a time before workers had the freedom to organize."</p>

<p>"We're not going back!" the crowd chanted, using one of her campaign slogans.</p>

<p>Trump took the weekend off from campaigning, and did not have public events scheduled Monday.</p>

<p>"For a candidate that claims to be rallying the support of workers, why is Donald Trump M.I.A. on Labor Day?" the Harris campaign needled in a statement.</p>

<p>The Republican, in a post on his Truth Social platform, touted his first term economic record and accused Harris and Biden of having "undone all of that."</p>

<p><strong>- Swing states -</strong></p>

<p>Harris last appeared with Biden after his speech two weeks ago at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</p>

<p>As she works to define her platform, the vice president has sought to promise change, while avoiding criticism of Biden's tenure.</p>

<p>On the issue of organized labor, she has tied herself closely to Biden.</p>

<p>"The most pro-labor administration in history, under President Biden and Vice President Harris' leadership, support for union membership has grown to its highest level in half a century," her campaign said in a statement.</p>

<p>Harris has faced scrutiny for pivoting from liberal positions she ran on when competing against Biden for the Democratic nomination in 2020.</p>

<p>Harris had previously pledged to ban fracking -- a major source of income in Pennsylvania -- but now has ruled that out.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania is one of a handful of states that will decide the election, and is viewed as possibly the one on which the outcome will hinge.</p>

<p>In Pittsburgh on Monday, Harris and Biden will speak at a union hall where they will meet local members.</p>

<p>Harris is expected to say that Pittsburgh-headquartered US Steel -- which Japan's Nippon Steel is seeking to buy -- should remain domestically owned, a campaign official said.</p>

<p>Monday's joint appearance with Biden is also seen as launching the two-month sprint to the November vote, with Labor Day marking the traditional end to the US summer.</p>

<p>Earlier Monday, Harris joined Biden at the White House for a briefing on hostages and ceasefire negotiations in the Israel-Hamas war.</p>

<p>Six hostages were killed in Gaza over the weekend, including a US citizen.</p>

<p>Harris's running mate, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, separately campaigned in Milwaukee, Wisconsin on Monday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k9qbmqk_kamala-harris_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[To mark the Labor Day holiday, the pair were set to attend an event with union members in Pennsylvania.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-seizes-venezuelan-president-nicolas-maduros-plane-over-violation-of-american-sanctions-6476598]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Seizes Venezuelan President's Plane Over Violation Of American Sanctions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-seizes-venezuelan-president-nicolas-maduros-plane-over-violation-of-american-sanctions-6476598]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:17:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Monday seized Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro's plane in the Dominican Republic and flew it to Florida, saying it acted over violation of US sanctions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Monday seized Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro's plane in the Dominican Republic and flew it to Florida, saying it acted over violation of US sanctions.</p>

<p>United States officials moved to take the aircraft, a Dassault Falcon 900EX private jet used by Maduro and members of his government, with the Justice Department saying the jet was "illegally purchased."</p>

<p>"The Justice Department seized an aircraft we allege was illegally purchased for $13 million through a shell company and smuggled out of the United States for use by Nicolas Maduro and his cronies," Attorney General Merrick Garland said in a statement.</p>

<p>Aircraft tracking site Flight Radar 24 showed that the jet flew from Santo Domingo to Fort Lauderdale on Monday morning.</p>

<p>The US says that in late 2022 and early 2023, individuals affiliated with Maduro allegedly used a Caribbean-based shell company to conceal their involvement in the illegal purchase of the jet.</p>

<p><strong>- 'False' victory claim -</strong></p>

<p>The aircraft was then illegally exported from the United States to Venezuela through the Caribbean in April 2023.</p>

<p>Since May 2023, the plane has flown almost exclusively to and from a military base in Venezuela.</p>

<p>The South American country was rocked by protests when Maduro was declared the winner of a disputed July 28 election, with dozens killed and more than 2,400 people arrested.</p>

<p>The opposition claims it won by a landslide and that it has the voting records to prove it.</p>

<p>The leftist Maduro government, brushing off accusations of authoritarianism, has resisted international pressure to release vote tally numbers to back up its claim of victory.</p>

<p>"Maduro and his representatives' have tampered with the results of the July 28 presidential election, falsely claimed victory, and carried out wide-spread repression to maintain power by force," a US National Security Council spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The seizure of the plane "is an important step to ensure that Maduro continues to feel the consequences from his misgovernance of Venezuela," they added.</p>

<p>The United States, the European Union and several Latin American countries have refused to recognize Maduro as having won without seeing detailed voting results.</p>

<p>Violence that accompanied the protests left 27 people dead and at least 192 wounded.</p>

<p>Since 2005, Washington has imposed sanctions on Venezuela that target individuals and entities "that have engaged in criminal, antidemocratic, or corrupt actions," according to a Congressional briefing document.</p>

<p>"In response to increasing human rights abuses and corruption by the government of Nicolas Maduro, in power since 2013, the Trump Administration expanded US sanctions to include financial sanctions, sectoral sanctions, and sanctions on the government."</p>

<p>Caracas was yet to comment on the seizure.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-02/7gtijdag_nicolas-maduro-reuters_625x300_09_February_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Aircraft tracking site Flight Radar 24 showed that the jet flew from Santo Domingo to Fort Lauderdale.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-historic-visit-to-brunei-to-bolster-cooperation-in-space-defence-6476547]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi's Historic Visit To Brunei To Bolster Cooperation In Space, Defence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-historic-visit-to-brunei-to-bolster-cooperation-in-space-defence-6476547]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:04:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi will become the first-ever Indian PM to visit Brunei when he travels to the country on September 3 and 4 for a bilateral visit. This is being seen as a significant step in bolstering ties between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will become the first-ever Indian PM to visit Brunei when he travels to the country on September 3 and 4 for a bilateral visit. This is being seen as a significant step in bolstering ties between the two nations.</p>

<p>"PM Modi at the invitation of His Majesty Sultan Hassanal Bolkiah is scheduled to visit Brunei during September 3-4. This will be the first ever bilateral visit by an Indian PM to Brunei," the Ministry of External Affairs said at the special briefing about the Prime Minister's visit.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi's visit coincides with 40th anniversary of establishment of diplomatic ties between India and Brunei.</p>

<p>PM Modi was earlier scheduled to attend the sixth summit of the Bay of Bengal Initiative for Multi-Sectoral Technical and Economic Cooperation (BIMSTEC) - scheduled to take place in Bangkok on September 3, 4 - which was postponed last week due to the formation of the new government in the country.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit to Brunei comes almost ten years after his first meeting with the Sultan of Hassanal Bolkiah in November 2014 on the sidelines of 25th ASEAN Summit in Myanmar. They met again during the 2017 East Asia Summit held in the Philippines.</p>

<p>In July, Foreign Minister S Jaishankar met his Brunei counterpart in Laos on the sidelines of ASEAN meetings. To celebrate the 40 years of diplomatic relations, the two also launched a logo together.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit will focus on enhancing trade ties, and bolster cooperation in the space and defence sectors. India already has multiple agreements with Brunei in the space sector and also has a telemetry station in the country. The PM's visit will help strengthen cooperation in this regard, the MEA said.</p>

<p>India and Brunei also look to enhance ties in energy security in terms of crude oil and hydrocarbons.</p>

<p>Currently India imports $270 million worth of crude oil from Brunei. Brunei has also played a key role in bringing India closer to ASEAN being the Country Coordinator for India from 2012 till 2015. Brunei has been supportive of India's 'Act East Policy'.</p>

<p>On defence, the MEA said, "We are still in discussions with Brunei to set up a joint working group on defence."</p>

<p>Indian naval and coast guard ships have regularly visited Brunei and two Indian defence companies - Bharat Electronics Ltd and MKU Limited - participated in the Defence Industry Exposition organised by Brunei Armed Forces in June 2024 for the first time. Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah and Crown Prince Al-Muhtadee Billah visited the Indian stalls during the expo and appreciated the Indian companies' participation.</p>

<p>As per the MEA, there are currently around 14,500 Indians living in Brunei Darussalam out of the total population of about 450,500 with more than half of the Indian expatriates being semi and unskilled workers, who work in oil and gas industries construction, retail businesses.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fkr4o48c_narendra-modi-hassanal-bolkiah-sultan-of-brunei-ians_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi meets Sultan of Brunei Darussalam Hassanal Bolkiah. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-top-court-confirms-x-suspension-over-alleged-judicial-transgressions-6476489]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Top Court Confirms X Suspension Over Alleged Judicial Transgressions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-top-court-confirms-x-suspension-over-alleged-judicial-transgressions-6476489]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 23:50:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazil's Supreme Court on Monday ratified the decision by one of its judges to suspend Elon Musk's X social network for alleged judicial transgressions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil's Supreme Court on Monday ratified the decision by one of its judges to suspend Elon Musk's X social network for alleged judicial transgressions.</p>

<p>Access to the network in the country has been blocked since Saturday morning, hours after judge Alexandre de Moraes ordered the suspension of the platform.</p>

<p>Moraes's ruling came after Musk failed to comply with an order to name a new legal representative for the company in Brazil -- a requirement X has rejected as "illegal."</p>

<p>Moraes and Musk have been locked in a high-profile feud for months as the judge has vowed to fight disinformation and Musk claims the supremacy of free speech.</p>

<p>On Monday, five Supreme Court judges, including Moraes himself, voted in a virtual session to uphold his ruling.</p>

<p>"Elon Musk demonstrated his total disrespect for Brazilian sovereignty and, in particular, the judiciary, positioning himself as a true supranational entity, immune to the laws of countries," Moraes said in the new ruling.</p>

<p>His colleague Flavio Dino added that "freedom of expression does not excuse repeated violations of the legal system."</p>

<p>Musk, who also owns Tesla and SpaceX, reacted with fury to last Friday's order, branding Moraes as an "evil dictator cosplaying as a judge" and accusing him of "trying to destroy democracy in Brazil."</p>

<p>The standoff began when Moraes ordered the suspension of several X accounts belonging to supporters of Brazil's former far-right president Jair Bolsonaro.</p>

<p>Bolsonaro had tried to discredit the voting systems used during the country's 2022 elections, which he lost.</p>

<p>Brazilian authorities are investigating whether Bolsonaro plotted a coup attempt to prevent his successor, Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva, from assuming office in January 2023.</p>

<p>Online users blocked by Moraes include far-right ex-congressman Daniel Silveira, who was sentenced to nine years in prison in 2022 on charges of leading a movement to overthrow the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In April, Moraes ordered an investigation of Musk, accusing him of reactivating some of the banned accounts.</p>

<p>Musk is also the subject of a separate investigation into the alleged use of public money to orchestrate disinformation campaigns in favour of Bolsonaro and those close to him.</p>

<p>The suspension of X came just over a month before municipal elections are to be held in Brazil.</p>

<p>In August, X announced it was shuttering its offices in Brazil due to the Moraes's actions, but assured clients they would still have access to its services.</p>

<p>Until Friday, X counted about 22 million users in Brazil, according to the site DataReportal.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/tl29m2d_x-generic_625x300_09_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The suspension of X came just over a month before municipal elections in Brazil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-viral-pak-army-mock-interview-bizarre-katrina-kaif-question-6476316]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Viral Pak Army Mock Interview, Bizarre 'Katrina Kaif' Question]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-viral-pak-army-mock-interview-bizarre-katrina-kaif-question-6476316]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 23:22:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A mock interview for the selection of officers in the Pakistani Army went viral on social media after the interviewer asked a candidate a bizarre question which featured Bollywood actor Katrina Kaif.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mock interview of Pakistan's military exam for the selection of officers went viral on social media after the interviewer asked a candidate a question which featured Bollywood actor Katrina Kaif.</p>

<p>Sarmad Muhammad Khan, a former Pakistan Army officer who runs the 'World Times Forces Academy', asked the candidate, Ali Abbas, "Who is your favourite actress?" The candidate said Dur-e-Fishan Saleem, a Pakistani actress, followed by further questions on why he likes her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A few minutes later, Mr Khan asked Mr Abbas, "Who is your favourite actress in Bollywood?" The candidate said, "Sir, Katrina Kaif."</p>

<p>Mr Khan gave the candidate a situation where "India is planning an attack on Pakistan, and Katrina Kaif has the information on how we (Pakistan) can stop them. She asked you to make some sort of relationship with her to get the information...Will you do it?" The candidate said, "Sir, obviously for the country's protection, I have to do it."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Pakistan civil service mock interview ? <a href="https://t.co/HxWdYp032W">pic.twitter.com/HxWdYp032W</a></p>
— Johns (@JohnyBravo183) <a href="https://twitter.com/JohnyBravo183/status/1829779639302308012?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 31, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>To his counter, the interviewer told the candidate "The situation is similar, but you are in Afghanistan and a person named Gul Khan asked you to do the same to get the information, will you do you now?" The candidate asked, "What kind of relationship?" Mr Khan admonished the candidate and said, "Is this your character?" Mr Khan then gave feedback the Mr Abbas, explaining the flaws in his responses.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZesbFrTAmio" rel="no follow, no index">The interviewer asked the follow-up question at the end of the interview</a>. The two clips have been combined in the now-viral video.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Several users of X and Instagram have reacted to the video, mocking Mr Khan's line of questioning. Some users from Pakistan recalled their experience of giving the ISSB interview and shared how it "feels relatable to them".</p>

<p>The Inter-Services Selection Board (ISSB) is a personality assessment exam for the selection of commissioned officers into the Pakistan Army, Navy and Air Force, similar to the procedure in India, where candidates who want to join the forces as officers undergo the Services Selection Board (SSB) interview before joining the military training academy.</p>

<p>The video has over 89,000 views on YouTube, and the channel 'World Times CSS Videos' has over 3.3 lakh subscribers. The candidate, Ali Abbas, was giving a mock interview for the Pakistan Military Academy's 119 Long Course.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r1j7um3g_pak-mock-interview_625x300_02_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several users of X and Instagram have reacted to the video.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-envoy-bangladesh-home-adviser-meet-discuss-security-cooperation-safety-of-indians-6475816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Envoy, Bangladesh Home Adviser Meet, Discuss Security Cooperation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-envoy-bangladesh-home-adviser-meet-discuss-security-cooperation-safety-of-indians-6475816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:27:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma today met interim government's Home and Agriculture Adviser Lt Gen (Retd.) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury and discussed areas of engagement to advance security cooperation and safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma today met interim government's Home and Agriculture Adviser Lt Gen (Retd.) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury and discussed areas of engagement to advance security cooperation, exchanged views on border management, capacity building, and safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>During his meeting with Mr Chowdhury, Mr Verma also announced that Indian visa centres are now issuing a limited number of visas for Bangladeshi nationals, primarily for emergency medical needs and students pursuing studies abroad.</p>

<p>"HC Pranay Verma called on Bangladesh Home &amp; Agriculture Adviser Lt Gen (Retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today. Discussed areas of engagement to advance India-Bangladesh security cooperation, exchanged views on border management, capacity building, and safety &amp; security of India nationals &amp; students in Bangladesh," the High Commission of India in Bangladesh said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">HC Pranay Verma called on ??Home &amp; Agriculture Adviser H.E. Lt Gen (Retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today. Discussed areas of engagement to advance????security cooperation, exchanged views on border management, capacity building, and safety &amp; security of ??nationals &amp; students in?? <a href="https://t.co/oXLpi7F5MC">pic.twitter.com/oXLpi7F5MC</a></p>
— India in Bangladesh (@ihcdhaka) <a href="https://twitter.com/ihcdhaka/status/1830561362394919098?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>They also discussed areas of mutual interest in the agriculture sector, including possible collaboration between agricultural research institutions and exchanges in mechanized farming, post-harvest management etc, the mission said in another post.</p>

<p>According to the Daily Star newspaper, the meeting addressed a range of bilateral issues, including police reforms, border security, and the safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Our two countries should work together on flood warning and forecasting," the adviser was quoted as saying by the paper.</p>

<p>Mr Verma assured him of India's assistance with necessary data and information for flood warning and forecasting, the paper added.</p>

<p>The adviser assured the high commissioner that the Indian nationals residing in Bangladesh would be provided full security. He added that Indian students are welcome to continue their studies in Bangladesh, the paper said.</p>

<p>The interim government headed by 84-year-old Nobel laureate Yunus was installed days after prime minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled to India on August 5 following unprecedented anti-government student-led protests over a controversial quota system in government jobs.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g38ke30g_indian-envoy-pranay-verma-meets-bangladesh-home-adviser-jahangir-alam-chowdhury_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma met Bangladesh Home Adviser Lt Gen (Retd.) JA Chowdhury]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volkswagen-weighs-first-ever-germany-plant-closures-to-cut-costs-6475662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Volkswagen Weighs First-Ever Germany Plant Closures To Cut Costs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volkswagen-weighs-first-ever-germany-plant-closures-to-cut-costs-6475662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:43:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Volkswagen AG is considering unprecedented factory closures in Germany in a bid for deeper cutbacks, delivering another blow to Chancellor Olaf Scholz's government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Volkswagen AG is considering unprecedented factory closures in Germany in a bid for deeper cutbacks, delivering another blow to Chancellor Olaf Scholz's government.</p>

<p>The potential measures, targeting its main passenger car brand as well as other group operations, also include trying to end the company's pact with unions to keep jobs secure until 2029, the company said Monday. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Any shutdowns would mark the first closures in Germany during the company's 87-year history, setting VW up for a clash with powerful unions.</p>

<p>"The economic environment has become even tougher and new players are pushing into Europe," VW Chief Executive Officer Oliver Blume said in a statement. "Germany as a business location is falling further behind in terms of competitiveness."</p>

<p>A full-blown labor dispute would be a major test for the CEO - who also heads up the Porsche sports car brand - after union clashes felled a number of his VW predecessors. The company has struggled to cut costs at its namesake passenger brand where profit margins have long lagged, with efforts becoming harder amid a sputtering transition to EVs and a consumer spending slowdown.</p>

<p>Works council head Daniela Cavallo said VW's management had failed after meetings detailed that the company's core brand, making the Golf and Tiguan models, threatened to become loss-making, according to a separate statement. The company is plotting to close at least one larger carmaking factory and one component site in Germany, it said, alongside abolishing wage agreements.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4i8bid1o_volkswagen-germany-struggles-with-cost-cuts-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>VW employs about 650,000 workers globally, almost 300,000 of which are in Germany. Half the seats on the company's supervisory board are held by labor representatives, and the German state of Lower Saxony - which owns a 20% stake - often sides with trade union bodies.</p>

<p>Previous clashes ended or shortened the tenures of top executives including former CEO Bernd Pischetsrieder, ex-VW brand chief Wolfgang Bernhard and more Herbert Diess, Blume's predecessor as CEO. All three tried to push through efficiencies particularly at VW's domestic German operations.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/42bj4p6o_volkswagen-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volkswagen's headquarters in Wolfsburg, Germany. (Photo: Krisztian Bocsi / Bloomberg)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-immediately-suspends-30-of-its-350-arms-export-licenses-to-israel-6475594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Immediately Suspends 30 Of Its 350 Arms Export Licenses To Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-immediately-suspends-30-of-its-350-arms-export-licenses-to-israel-6475594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:33:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain will immediately suspend 30 of its 350 arms export licenses with Israel because there is a risk such equipment might be used to commit serious violations of international humanitarian law, foreign minister David Lammy said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain will immediately suspend 30 of its 350 arms export licenses with Israel because there is a risk such equipment might be used to commit serious violations of international humanitarian law, foreign minister David Lammy said on Monday.</p>

<p>Soon after the Labour Party won an election in July, Mr Lammy said he would update a review on arms sales to British ally Israel to ensure these complied with international law.</p>

<p>"It is with regret that I inform the House (of Commons, lower house of parliament) today that the assessment I have received leaves me unable to conclude anything other than that for certain UK arms exports to Israel, there does exist a clear risk that they might be used to commit or facilitate a serious violation of international humanitarian law," Lammy said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/repgssu8_keir-starmer-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The decision was made after a risk assessment of such equipment by the UK.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-pak-ex-pm-imran-khan-says-will-hold-talks-only-with-powerful-establishment-6475550]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Imran Khan Says Will Hold Talks Only With Pakistan Powerful Establishment]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-pak-ex-pm-imran-khan-says-will-hold-talks-only-with-powerful-establishment-6475550]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:29:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jailed former prime minister Imran Khan Monday dismissed rumours about negotiations with the Pakistan government, saying he will hold talks only with the powerful establishment to end the political impasse in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jailed former prime minister Imran Khan Monday dismissed rumours about negotiations with the Pakistan government, saying he will hold talks only with the powerful establishment to end the political impasse in the country.</p>

<p>"Whenever the topic of negotiations arises, they start making noise about May 9 (violence). We are always ready for talks. We will speak with those who make the decisions," Mr Khan told reporters inside the Adiala Jail Rawalpindi after hearing of the Toshakhana case against him.</p>

<p>His 'no' to any idea of sitting with the government comes as local media reported over the weekend about the potential talks between the government and the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf party.</p>

<p>However, Mr Khan's statement showed that he was standing by his position that any parleys to steer the country out of prevailing political instability and end his miseries would be held with the powerful army.</p>

<p>The former premier also fired a broadside at the government, saying that whenever the idea of talks is floated, the ruling party brings in May 9 as a diversion and demands an apology. He said the May 9 violence was the "insurance policy" of the government and if the issue was put aside, the government would collapse.</p>

<p>He also suggested forming a judicial commission to investigate the events of May 9 and fix the responsibility.</p>

<p>On May 9 last year, violent protests erupted after the arrest of 71-year-old Mr Khan by paramilitary Rangers from the premises of the Islamabad High Court in connection with an alleged corruption case.</p>

<p>His party workers allegedly vandalised a dozen military installations, including the Jinnah House (Lahore Corps Commander House), the Mianwali airbase and the ISI building in Faisalabad. A mob also attacked the Army headquarters in Rawalpindi.</p>

<p>Mr Khan also talked about his decision to take part in the election of the Chancellor of Oxford University and said his win would be a matter of pride for Pakistan.</p>

<p>Highlighting his achievements in cricket and philanthropy, Mr Khan claimed that he was Pakistan's biggest philanthropist, having established two hospitals and two universities, with a third university currently under construction.</p>

<p>He accused former premier Nawaz Sharif of benefiting from additional votes to win elections. On a lighter note, he talked about two upcoming entries in the Guinness Book of World Records.</p>

<p>First would be Sharif's "U-turn" on his slogan "give honour to the vote" and substituting it with "give respect to the Boot." Second would be also by Sharif that in Mr Khan's words, he allegedly aligned with all four umpires (four military dictators) and still lost the match.</p>

<p>Sharif, who was ousted from power in 2017 after his conviction by the Supreme Court, had chanted the slogan 'give respect to vote'.</p>

<p>Mr Khan alleges that Sharif made a deal with the establishment to come back from exile in London to gain power for his brother Shehbaz Sharif.</p>

<p>Mr Khan was arrested on August 5 last year after his conviction in the first Toshakhana corruption case filed by the Election Commission of Pakistan. Since then, he has been in jail in different cases.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jbg3lne_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He accused former premier Nawaz Sharif of benefiting from additional votes to win elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-13-wounded-in-suicide-bombing-in-afghanistans-kabul-cops-6475387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Killed, 13 Wounded In Suicide Bombing In Afghanistan's Kabul]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-13-wounded-in-suicide-bombing-in-afghanistans-kabul-cops-6475387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:04:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A suicide bomber detonated explosives in the Afghan capital on Monday, police said, killing six people and wounding 13 more.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A suicide bomber triggered explosives in the Afghan capital on Monday, police said, killing six people and wounding 13 more.</p>

<p>Violence has waned in Afghanistan since the 2021 Taliban takeover, however, several militant groups remain active including the regional chapter of Islamic State.</p>

<p>There was no immediate claim of responsibility for Monday afternoon's attack, which took place in the Qala-e-Bakhtiar area of Kabul's southern outskirts.</p>

<p>Kabul police spokesman Khalid Zadran said "a person wearing explosives on his body detonated", and one woman was among the fatalities.</p>

<p>"The injured were transferred to hospitals on time and investigations are ongoing," he posted on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Afghanistan's Taliban authorities have declared security their highest priority since surging back to power following the chaotic withdrawal of foreign forces three years ago.</p>

<p>While their sweeping security operations have led to a decline in militants challenging their rule, according to analysts, they also downplay or delay confirmation of attacks.</p>

<p>The last suicide attack in Afghanistan claimed by the regional chapter of Islamic State was in the southern city of Kandahar -- the Taliban's historic stronghold -- in March.</p>

<p>Taliban authorities said only three people were killed while a hospital source put the toll far higher at 20.</p>

<p>Taliban government spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid told AFP last month that Islamic State "existed here before but we suppressed them very hard".</p>

<p>"No such groups exist here that can pose a threat to anyone," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kfim27vg_kabul-blast-generic_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It took place in the southern Kabul area of Qala-e-Bakhtiar. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-researchers-find-probable-launch-site-of-russias-nuclear-powered-missile-9m370-burevestnik-6475004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia's "Invincible" Nuclear-Powered Nuke Launch Site Detected: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-researchers-find-probable-launch-site-of-russias-nuclear-powered-missile-9m370-burevestnik-6475004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 20:12:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two U.S. researchers say they have identified the probable deployment site in Russia of the 9M370 Burevestnik, a new nuclear-powered, nuclear-armed cruise missile touted by President Vladimir Putin as "invincible."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two U.S. researchers say they have identified the probable deployment site in Russia of the 9M370 Burevestnik, a new nuclear-powered, nuclear-armed cruise missile touted by President Vladimir Putin as "invincible."</p>

<p>Putin has said the weapon - dubbed the SSC-X-9 Skyfall by NATO - has an almost unlimited range and can evade U.S. missile defences. But some Western experts dispute his claims and the Burevestnik's strategic value, saying it will not add capabilities that Moscow does not already have and risks a radiation-spewing mishap.</p>

<p>Using images taken on July 26 by Planet Labs, a commercial satellite firm, the two researchers identified a construction project abutting a nuclear warhead storage facility known by two names - Vologda-20 and Chebsara - as the new missile's potential deployment site. The facility is 295 miles (475 km) north of Moscow.</p>

<p>Reuters is the first to report this development.</p>

<p>Decker Eveleth, an analyst with the CNA research and analysis organization, found the satellite imagery and identified what he assessed are nine horizontal launch pads under construction. They are located in three groups inside high berms to shield them from attack or to prevent an accidental blast in one from detonating missiles in the others, he said.</p>

<p>The berms are linked by roads to what Eveleth concluded are likely buildings where the missiles and their components would be serviced, and to the existing complex of five nuclear warhead storage bunkers.</p>

<p>The site is "for a large, fixed missile system and the only large, fixed missile system that they're (Russia) currently developing is the Skyfall," said Eveleth.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry and Washington embassy did not respond to a request to comment on his assessment, Burevestnik's strategic value, its test record and the risks it poses.</p>

<p>A Kremlin spokesman said these were questions for the defence ministry and declined further comment.</p>

<p>The U.S. State Department, the CIA, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence and the U.S. Air Force National Air and Space Intelligence Center declined to comment.</p>

<p>The identification of the missile's probable launch site suggests that Russia is proceeding with its deployment after a series of tests in recent years marred by problems, said Eveleth and the second researcher, Jeffery Lewis, of the Middlebury Institute of International Studies at Monterey.</p>

<p>Lewis agreed with Eveleth's assessment after reviewing the imagery at his request. The imagery "suggests something very unique, very different. And obviously, we know that Russia is developing this nuclear-powered missile," he said.</p>

<p>Hans Kristensen of the Federation of American Scientists, who also studied the Vologda imagery at Eveleth's request, said that it appears to show launch pads and other features "possibly" related to Burevestnik. But he said he could not make a definitive assessment because Moscow does not typically place missile launchers next to nuclear warhead storage.</p>

<p>Eveleth, Lewis, Kristensen and three other experts said Moscow's normal practice has been stockpiling nuclear payloads for land-based missiles far from launch sites - except for those on its deployed Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) force.</p>

<p>But deploying the Burevestnik at Vologda would allow the Russian military to stockpile the nuclear-armed missiles in its bunkers, making them available to launch quickly, said Lewis and Eveleth.</p>

<p>Deputy Foreign Minister Sergei Ryabkov said Russia will make changes to its guidelines on the use of nuclear weapons in response to what it regards as Western escalation in the war in Ukraine, state news agency TASS reported on Sunday.</p>

<p><strong>POOR TEST RECORD</strong></p>

<p>A 2020 report by the United States Air Force's National Air and Space Intelligence Center said that if Russia successfully brought the Burevestnik into service, it would give Moscow a "unique weapon with intercontinental-range capability".</p>

<p>But the weapon's checkered past and design limitations raised doubts among eight experts interviewed by Reuters about whether its deployment would change the nuclear stakes for the West and other Russian foes.</p>

<p>The Burevestnik has a poor test record of at least 13 known tests, with only two partial successes, since 2016, according to the Nuclear Threat Initiative (NTI), an advocacy group focused on reducing nuclear, biological and emergent technology risks.</p>

<p>The setbacks include a 2019 blast during the botched recovery of an unshielded nuclear reactor allowed to "smoulder" on the White Sea floor for a year following a prototype crash, according to State Department reports.</p>

<p>Russia's state nuclear agency Rosatom said five staff members died during the testing of a rocket on August 8. Putin presented their widows with top state awards, saying the weapon they were developing was without equal in the world, without naming the Burevestnik.</p>

<p>Pavel Podvig, a Geneva-based expert on Russia's nuclear forces, Lewis, Eveleth, and other experts said it will not add capabilities that Moscow's nuclear forces already do not have, including the ability to overwhelm U.S. missile defences.</p>

<p>Moreover, its nuclear-powered engine threatens to disgorge radiation along its flight path and its deployment risks an accident that could contaminate the surrounding region, said Cheryl Rofer, a former U.S. nuclear weapons scientist and other experts.</p>

<p>"The Skyfall is a uniquely stupid weapon system, a flying Chernobyl that poses more threat to Russia than it does to other countries," agreed Thomas Countryman, a former top State Department official with the Arms Control Association, referring to the 1986 nuclear plant disaster.</p>

<p>NATO did not respond to questions about how the alliance would respond to the weapon's deployment.</p>

<p>Little publicly is known about the Burevestnik's technical details.</p>

<p>Experts assess that it would be sent aloft by a small solid-fuel rocket to drive air into an engine containing a miniature nuclear reactor. Superheated and possibly radioactive air would be blasted out, providing forward thrust.</p>

<p>Putin unveiled it in March 2018, saying the missile would be "low flying," with nearly unlimited range, an unpredictable flight path and "invincible" to current and future defences.</p>

<p>Many experts are sceptical of Putin's claims.</p>

<p>The Burevestnik, they say, could have a range of some 15,000 miles (23,000 km) - compared to more than 11,000 miles (17,700 km) for the Sarmat, Russia's newest ICBM - while its subsonic speed would make it detectable.</p>

<p>"It's going to be as vulnerable as any cruise missile," said Kristensen. "The longer it flies, the more vulnerable it becomes because there is more time to track it. I don't understand Putin's motive here."</p>

<p>The Burevestnik's deployment is not banned by New START, the last U.S.-Russian accord limiting strategic nuclear weapon deployments, which expires in February 2026.</p>

<p>A provision allows Washington to request negotiations with Moscow on bringing the Burevestnik under the caps but a State Department spokesperson said no such talks had been sought.</p>

<p>Citing the war in Ukraine, Russia has spurned U.S. calls for unconditional talks on replacing New START, stoking fears of an all-out nuclear arms race when it expires.</p>

<p>Podvig said Moscow might use the missile as a bargaining chip if talks ever resume.</p>

<p>He called the Burevestnik a "political weapon" that Putin used to bolster his strongman image before his 2018 re-election and to telegraph to Washington that it cannot dismiss his concerns over U.S. missile defences and other issues.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cadomeog_9m370-burevestnik-launch-site_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reuters is the first to report this development.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-navys-p8i-poseidon-aircraft-reaches-france-1st-ever-deployment-in-europe-6472691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Navy's P8i Poseidon Aircraft Reaches France, 1st-Ever Deployment In Europe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-navys-p8i-poseidon-aircraft-reaches-france-1st-ever-deployment-in-europe-6472691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 19:55:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a first-ever such deployment by India in Europe, an Indian Navy P8i aircraft has landed in France at the Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a first-ever such deployment by India in Europe, an Indian Navy P8i Poseidon aircraft has landed in France at the Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube. The purpose of the deployment is to participate in the joint naval exercise 'Varuna' in which France is also participating.</p>

<p>"A P8i aircraft of the Indian Navy has reached France to participate in a joint naval exercise with the French Navy," a senior navy official said.</p>

<p>The 2024 edition of Indo-French bilateral naval 'Exercise Varuna', is scheduled from September 2 to September 4 in the Mediterranean Sea.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="2024 edition of Indo-French naval Exercise Varuna is scheduled from Sept 2-4 in the Mediterranean Sea" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lg7ok3to_indian-navy-maritime-exercise-ians_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="2024 edition of Indo-French naval Exercise Varuna is scheduled from Sept 2-4 in the Mediterranean Sea" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">2024 edition of Indo-French naval 'Exercise Varuna' is scheduled from Sept 2-4 in the Mediterranean Sea</p>
</div>

<p>"The drill will include advanced tactical exercises underscoring the deepening synergy and interoperability between the two navies," a spokesperson of the Indian Navy said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This deployment comes 63 years after the Indian Navy's Alize aircraft, operating from the erstwhile INS Vikrant, last flew at Hyeres Airbase," the spokesperson said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Indian Navy personnel of the P-8I aircraft upon touch down at Frances Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k82h0878_indian-navy-p8i-poseidon-aircraft-with-2-sukhoi-su30-mki_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="Indian Navy personnel of the P-8I aircraft upon touch down at Frances Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">An Indian Navy P8i Poseidon aircraft has landed in France at the Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube</p>
</div>

<p>INS Tabar, which had earlier arrived in Toulon will also be participating in the exercise.</p>

<p><strong>THE INDIAN NAVY P8i AIRCRAFT</strong></p>

<p>The P-8 Poseidon is a maritime patrol and reconnaissance aircraft developed and produced by United States' Boeing Defense. It is derived from the civilian Boeing 737-800 airliner. The P8i is a variant of the P-8 Poseidon specially designed for the Indian Navy.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Indian Navys fleet of P8i has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7ttse4b4_indian-navy-p8i-fleet_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="Indian Navys fleet of P8i has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Indian Navy's fleet of P8i Poseidon has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013.</p>
</div>

<p>The Indian Navy's P8i fleet aims to replace the aging Tupolev Tu-142M maritime surveillance turboprops.</p>

<p>Indian Navy's fleet of P8i Poseidon has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013. The Indian Navy has twelve P8i aircraft in total. The P8i is not just responsible for coastal patrolling but is also used for other critical missions like maritime surveillance, anti-submarine and anti-surface warfare, search-and-rescue, anti-piracy, and supporting operations of other arms of the military.</p>

<p><strong>THE VARUNA NAVAL EXERCISE</strong></p>

<p>The Varuna Naval Exercise is a bilateral maritime drill between the Indian and French navies. The drill usually sees participation of guided missile frigates, tanker, Maritime Patrol Aircraft and integral helicopters from the two sides.</p>

<p>Indian &amp; French Navy bilateral naval exercise was initiated in 1993. The exercise was later christened as 'Varuna' in 2001 and has since become a hallmark of robust India-France strategic bilateral relationship. Having grown in scope and complexity over the years, this exercise provides an opportunity to learn from each other's best practices and procedures.</p>

<p>According to the Ministry of Defence, the exercise also facilitates operational level interaction between the two navies to foster mutual cooperation for good order at sea, underscoring the shared commitment to ensuring security, safety and freedom of the global maritime commons.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t637rkmc_indian-navy-p8i-poseidon-1st-deployment-in-europe-pti_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian Navy personnel of the P-8I aircraft upon touch down at France's Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/at-global-meet-s-jaishankar-shares-indian-perspective-of-global-situation-at-ambassadors-conference-of-austrian-foreign-ministry-6474707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Global Meet, S Jaishankar Shares "Indian Perspective Of Global Situation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/at-global-meet-s-jaishankar-shares-indian-perspective-of-global-situation-at-ambassadors-conference-of-austrian-foreign-ministry-6474707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 19:34:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Monday virtually addressed the Ambassadors Conference of Austrian Foreign Ministry at the invitation of Austrian Foreign Minister Alexander Schallenberg.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Monday virtually addressed the Ambassadors Conference of Austrian Foreign Ministry at the invitation of Austrian Foreign Minister Alexander Schallenberg.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar shared Indian perspective on global situation and the prospects of bilateral relationship and European Union.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Mr Jaishankar said, "Pleased to address the Ambassadors Conference of Austrian Foreign Ministry today. Thank FM Alexander Schallenberg for the invitation. Shared with them Indian perspective of the global situation, as well as the prospects for our own bilateral relationship and that with the European Union."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Pleased to address the Ambassadors Conference of <a href="https://twitter.com/MFA_Austria?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MFA_Austria</a> today. Thank FM <a href="https://twitter.com/a_schallenberg?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@a_schallenberg</a> for the invitation.<br />
<br />
Shared with them Indian perspective of the global situation, as well as the prospects for our own bilateral relationship and that with the European Union.<br />
<br />
?? ?? <a href="https://t.co/qcS3VU019i">pic.twitter.com/qcS3VU019i</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1830546101725736999?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, Schallenberg lauded Mr Jaishankar and emphasised that during such challenging times, effective foreign policy relies on continuous engagement with key partners outside of Europe more than ever.</p>

<p>"On the occasion of our annual ambassadors conference, great to hear from my good friend @DrSJaishankar. In these challenging times, effective foreign policy relies on continuous engagement with key partners outside of Europe more than ever," posted the Austrian Foreign Minister on X.</p>

<p>Notably, Prime Minister Narendra Modi paid an official visit to Austria on July 9-10, 2024, this was the first visit by an Indian Prime Minister to Austria in 41 years, marking the 75th year of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p>

<p>The visit aimed to elevate bilateral relations to new heights through enhanced cooperation in various sectors, including technology, economy, and global security.</p>

<p>PM Modi and Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer emphasised that the shared values of democracy, freedom, international peace and security, a rules-based international order with the UN Charter at its core, the shared historical linkages, and the long-standing ties between the two countries are at the centre of the growing enhanced partnership.</p>

<p>They reiterated their commitment to continue their efforts towards deepening and widening bilateral, regional and international cooperation for a more stable, prosperous and sustainable world.</p>

<p>Both nations reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific region, ensuring maritime security and adhering to international laws such as United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS).</p>

<p>Discussions included assessments of developments in Europe and West Asia, with a shared focus on restoring peace and adherence to international law, notably concerning the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>The leaders welcomed the launch of the India-Middle East-Europe Corridor (IMEC) and Austria's interest to engage with this initiative.</p>

<p>The leaders agreed on a future-oriented economic partnership focusing on green and digital technologies, infrastructure, renewable energy, and smart cities.The first high-level bilateral Business Forum was convened, promoting partnerships across sectors and encouraging CEO-level interactions to explore new opportunities.</p>

<p>Recognizing their commitments under the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), both countries pledged to collaborate on renewable energy, with a specific focus on Austria's Hydrogen Strategy and India's Green Hydrogen Mission. As parties to the UNFCCC and committed to limiting the global temperature increase to below 2°C, leaders acknowledged the importance of reducing climate change risks.</p>

<p>They noted the EU's target for climate neutrality by 2050, Austria's goal for 2040, and India's aim for net zero emissions by 2070.</p>

<p>Initiatives such as the Start-Up Bridge and exchanges under Austria's Global Incubator Network and India's Start-Up India were highlighted as crucial for fostering innovation and entrepreneurship.</p>

<p>They also acknowledged the increasing importance of digital technologies in industrial processes (Industry 4.0), including in the sustainable economy.</p>

<p>Both leaders reiterated their commitment to multilateralism and supported comprehensive reforms of the United Nations. India reiterated its support for Austria's UNSC candidature for the term 2027-28, while Austria expressed its support for India's candidature for the period 2028-29.</p>

<p>India invited Austria to join the International Solar Alliance (ISA), highlighting collaboration in renewable energy and sustainable development.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iltj1phg_s-jaishankar-_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar shared the prospects of bilateral relationship and European Union.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-urges-countries-to-accelerate-measures-to-reduce-road-traffic-deaths-6473910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Urges Countries To Accelerate Measures To Reduce Road Traffic Deaths]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-urges-countries-to-accelerate-measures-to-reduce-road-traffic-deaths-6473910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 17:58:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization on Monday called on countries in the WHO South-East Asia Region to accelerate measures to reduce road traffic deaths, a leading cause of mortality among young people aged 15-29.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization on Monday called on countries in the WHO South-East Asia Region to accelerate measures to reduce road traffic deaths, a leading cause of mortality among young people aged 15-29.</p>

<p>"Vulnerable road users, including pedestrians, bicyclists and two or three-wheelers constitute 66 per cent of all reported road traffic deaths in our region," said Saima Wazed, Regional Director, WHO South-East Asia, in her address at the 15th World Conference on Injury Prevention and Safety Promotion (Safety 2024) which began here today.</p>

<p>She emphasised that the roads and their networks need to be designed prioritising those most at risk -- children and adolescents, people with disabilities, pedestrians and other vulnerable groups.</p>

<p>The WHO South-East Asia Region accounted for 330,223 of the 1.19 million estimated global road traffic deaths in 2021, representing 28 pc of the global burden, the WHO said in a statement.</p>

<p>With 70 per cent of the global population projected to live in urban areas by 2030, demand for public transport will surge. The WHO South-East Asia Region, amid rapid urbanisation, faces shared challenges -- a high prevalence of motorised two and three-wheelers, inadequate traffic injury data, poor pedestrian and cyclist infrastructure, and limited emergency services, it said.</p>

<p>Unlike high-income countries, where road safety measures often focus on car occupants, low and middle-income countries need to prioritise the safety of vulnerable road users, such as pedestrians, cyclists and riders of two and three-wheelers who are disproportionately at higher risk.</p>

<p>Strengthening trauma and emergency care systems, enhancing road safety data, strong leadership and promoting collaboration among all stakeholders are essential for improving road safety, the statement said.</p>

<p>"I am a great believer in collaborations and partnerships -- and expanding these to non-traditional stakeholders," said the regional director.</p>

<p>"This can be our moment to rethink and redo mobility for healthy cities. A holistic approach requires a cross-cutting, multi-sectoral approach, requiring collaboration with local governments, urban planners, traffic policing, law enforcement and others," she added.</p>

<p>Road safety, a public health and development priority, is crucial to achieving the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). In September 2020, the UN General Assembly launched the Decade of Action for Road Safety 2021-2030 which aims to reduce road traffic deaths and injuries by at least 50 per cent by 2030, Wazed said.</p>

<p>While the WHO South-East Asia Region saw a 2 per cent decrease in road fatalities in 2021, contributing to a global 5 per cent reduction, further efforts are needed to meet global targets.</p>

<p>At the World Conference, the regional director launched the 'WHO South-East Asia Regional Status Report on Road Safety: Towards Safer and Sustainable Mobility.' "This report outlines road traffic injury patterns in our countries and highlights best practices and country-specific interventions. It is both timely and essential for assessing our current position, and for guiding necessary actions to achieve global targets," she stated.</p>

<p>Addressing these challenges and implementing recommended strategies will be key to advancing road safety and reaching the 2030 targets, Wazed stated.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j2om9ag8_saima-wajid_625x300_02_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vulnerable road users constitute 66% of all reported road traffic deaths in our region, said Saima Wajid]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-bids-to-join-brics-in-push-to-build-alliances-beyond-west-6473870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkey Bids To Join BRICS In Push To Build Alliances Beyond West]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-bids-to-join-brics-in-push-to-build-alliances-beyond-west-6473870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 17:53:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Turkey has formally asked to join the BRICS group of emerging-market nations as it seeks to bolster its global influence and forge new ties beyond its traditional Western allies, according to people familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Turkey has formally asked to join the BRICS group of emerging-market nations as it seeks to bolster its global influence and forge new ties beyond its traditional Western allies, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The view of President Recep Tayyip Erdogan's administration is that the geopolitical center of gravity is shifting away from developed economies, according to the people, who spoke on condition of anonymity because they aren't authorized to comment.</p>

<p>The country's new diplomatic push reflects its aspirations to cultivate ties with all sides in a multipolar world, while still fulfilling its obligations as a key member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, they said.</p>

<p>Straddling Europe and Asia, Turkey submitted an application to join BRICS some months ago amid frustration over a lack of progress in its decades-old bid to join the European Union, the people added. The bid is also partly a result of rifts with fellow NATO members after Turkey maintained close links with Russia following its invasion of Ukraine in 2022, the people added. Turkey's foreign ministry and presidency declined to comment.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Bosphorus strait in Istanbul. (Photo Credit: Moe Zoyari / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qinv9hto_bosphorus-strait-istanbul-turkey-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="The Bosphorus strait in Istanbul. (Photo Credit: Moe Zoyari / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The Bosphorus strait in Istanbul. (Photo Credit: Moe Zoyari / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p>"Turkey can become a strong, prosperous, prestigious and effective country if it improves its relations with the East and the West simultaneously," Erdogan said in Istanbul over the weekend. "Any method other than this will not benefit Turkey, but will harm it."</p>

<p>The BRICS grouping, named after Brazil, Russia, India and China and South Africa, includes some of the biggest emerging economies. It got four new members at the start of this year when Iran, the United Arab Emirates, Ethiopia and Egypt joined its ranks. Saudi Arabia was invited to join, though the kingdom is yet to do that.</p>

<p>The group's further enlargement could be discussed during a summit in Kazan, Russia, from Oct. 22-24, said the people. Malaysia, Thailand and Turkey's close ally Azerbaijan are among other countries looking to join.</p>

<p>The BRICS touts itself as an alternative to what its members see as Western-dominated institutions such as the World Bank and International Monetary Fund. New members can potentially get access to financing through its development bank as well as broaden their political and trading relationships.</p>

<p>Erdogan's ruling Justice and Development Party has long accused Western nations of thwarting Turkish aspirations for a self-sufficient defense industry and strong economy. The president has repeatedly called for an overhaul of the United Nations Security Council to broaden its five permanent members, and expressed interest in joining the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, set up by Russia and China as a rival to NATO.</p>

<p>"We do not have to choose between the European Union and the Shanghai Cooperation Organization as some people claim," Erdogan said. "On the contrary, we have to develop our relations with both these and other organizations on a win-win basis."</p>

<p>BRICS expansion has largely been driven by China, which is trying to boost its global clout by courting nations traditionally allied with the US.</p>

<p>Turkey has been in talks to join the EU since 2005, but has encountered a series of obstacles, including what that bloc describes as the country's democratic shortcomings.</p>

<p>Turkey believes joining the BRICS could help the country improve economic cooperation with Russia and China, and become a trade conduit between the EU and Asia. It wants to be a hub for gas exports out of Russia and Central Asia, the people said.</p>

<p>Erdogan's administration has been trying to lure investment from Chinese electric carmakers, which could potentially take advantage of Turkey's customs union with the EU to boost their market access.</p>

<p>"BRICS is an organization that increases the diversity of approaches, identities and politics in the global economic system," Turkey's Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan said after attending a BRICS foreign ministers meeting in June.</p>

<p>Still, Turkey is making parallel efforts to rejuvenate membership talks with the EU. That remains "a strategic target," Fidan said last week after attending informal talks with EU counterparts for the first time in five years.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t6dduh54_recep-tayyip-erdogan-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Straddling Europe and Asia, Turkey submitted an application to join BRICS some months ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/firing-outside-ap-dhillons-canada-house-gangster-claims-responsibility-6473453]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Firing Outside AP Dhillon's Canada House, Gangster Claims Responsibility]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/firing-outside-ap-dhillons-canada-house-gangster-claims-responsibility-6473453]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 17:05:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shots were reportedly fired outside Punjabi singer AP Dhillon's house on Victoria Island in Canada's Vancouver.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shots were reportedly fired outside Punjabi singer AP Dhillon's house on Victoria Island in Canada's Vancouver. The incident took place yesterday and a man named Rohit Godara, a member of the Lawrence Bishnoi gang, has reportedly taken responsibility for the incident.</p>

<p>A video, which can not be independently verified, shows a man standing outside a house firing multiple shots at night. The video is being circulated on the internet but the location remains unverified.</p>

<p>AP Dhillon lives on Victoria Island in British Columbia.</p>

<p>A purported post is being circulated where the gangster, Rohit Godara, is claiming that the firing took place at two locations in Canada - Victoria Island and Woodbridge Toronto. According to the post, he fired outside the singer's house after he featured Salman Khan in a music video. He also gave death threats to the singer in the purported post. The gangster claims he is associated with Lawrence Bishnoi.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Shots being fired outside a house in Canada" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s7r8t488_firing-canada_625x300_02_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Shots being fired outside a house in Canada" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Shots being fired outside a house in Canada</p>
</div>

<p>Security agencies are verifying the claims made in the post and analysing the video. The singer is yet to respond to the incident. The police in Canada have not responded to the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>AP Dhillon is known for blending the 80s-style synth-pop with Punjabi music. His rise on the global canvas has been meteoric owing to songs like 'Brown Munde', 'Excuses', 'Summer High', 'With You', 'Dil Nu', and 'Insane', among others.</p>

<p>In November last year, gangster Lawrence Bishnoi claimed responsibility for a purported shooting at singer Gippy Grewal's house in Canada. The alleged incident took place in the White Rock neighbourhood in Vancouver.</p>

<p>In April, two motorcycle-borne persons opened fire outside Khan's residence at the Galaxy Apartment in Mumbai's Bandra area and fled the spot. The Mumbai police declared jailed gangster Lawrence Bishnoi and his younger brother Anmol Bishnoi as "wanted accused" in connection with the incident.</p>

<p>Last year, the National Investigation Agency (NIA) said that Mr Khan topped the list of 10 main targets that jailed gangster Lawrence Bishnoi planned to eliminate, citing the actor's infamous 1998 black buck hunting incident, which according to the gangster, offended the Bishnoi community.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3ek8af9_-old-money_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-tv-or-screen-for-toddlers-at-all-sweden-recommends-parents-6473141]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No TV Or Screen For Toddlers At All, Sweden Recommends Parents]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-tv-or-screen-for-toddlers-at-all-sweden-recommends-parents-6473141]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 16:27:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Children under the age of two should be kept away from digital media and television completely, Sweden's Public Health Agency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Toddlers should not be allowed to watch screens at all, Sweden told parents on Monday.</p>

<p>Children under the age of two should be kept away from digital media and television completely, the country's Public Health Agency said.</p>

<p>Kids between the ages of two and five should be limited to a maximum of one hour of screen time a day, it said in new recommendations, while those aged six to 12 should spend no more than an hour or two a day in front of a screen.</p>

<p>Teenagers aged 13 to 18 should be limited to two to three hours per day, the agency said.</p>

<p>"For too long, smartphones and other screens have been allowed to enter every aspect of our children's lives," Public Health Minister Jakob Forssmed told reporters.</p>

<p>The minister said that Swedish teens aged 13 to 16 spend six and a half hours a day on average in front of their screens, outside of school hours.</p>

<p>Forssmed said that didn't leave "a lot of time for communal activities, physical activity or adequate sleep", and lamented a Swedish "sleep crisis" noting that more than half of 15-year-olds did not get enough sleep.</p>

<p>The health agency also recommended that kids not use screens before going to bed and that phones and tablets be kept out of bedroom at night.</p>

<p>It cited research showing that excessive screen use can lead to poor sleep, depression and body dissatisfaction.</p>

<p>Sweden's government has previously said it is looking at a ban on smartphones in primary schools.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/1rfldvag_tv-generic_625x300_28_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The health agency also recommended that kids not use screens before going to bed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-hates-donald-trump-wants-kamala-harris-to-win-ex-aides-stunning-claim-6472810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Melania Trump Hates Donald Trump, Wants Kamala Harris To Win": Ex-Aide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-hates-donald-trump-wants-kamala-harris-to-win-ex-aides-stunning-claim-6472810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 15:40:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The former White House Communications Director Anthony Scaramucci has made a stunning claim - that Donald Trump's wife Melania is secretly rooting for Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The former White House Communications Director Anthony Scaramucci has made a stunning claim - that Donald Trump's wife Melania is secretly rooting for Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris. He went on to claim that Melania Trump is supporting Kamala Harris because "she hates Donald Trump".</p>

<p>Mr Scaramucci, in his recent interview on the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iOCyN9nXXIE" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">MediasTouch podcast</a>, claimed Melania Trump is even more enthusiastic about a Kamala Harris victory than he is.</p>

<p>Interestingly, Mr Scaramucci's remarks come at a time when the former First Lady has been absent at husband Donald Trump's political campaign rallies. She was seen only at a few fundraising events and the rally in which there was an assassination attempt on Trump.</p>

<p>Speaking with host Ben Meiselas, Mr Scaramucci claimed Melania Trump is far more keener than him to see Kamala Harris take over the White House. In a response to a question, he said "Maybe Melania Trump. That could be the only person I think of. Because she hates (Trump)," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Scaramucci went on to say that his wife hates Donald Trump too. "My wife hates Trump as much as Melania does," adding jokingly that even the host of the interview is "nicer to Trump than Melania is".</p>

<p><strong>WHO IS ANTHONY SCARAMUCCI?</strong></p>

<p>Anthony Scaramucci was responsible for all communications at the White House for a mere eleven days in 2017 - from July 21 to July 31, following which he was fired by Donald Trump. According to UK news website <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-4718658/Sean-Spicer-resigns-White-House-Press-Secretary.html" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Daily Mail</a>, Mr Scaramucci's appointment led to White House Press Secretary Sean Spicer's resignation the very next day. Mr Spicer had voiced his displeasure about Mr Scaramucci being hired.</p>

<p>Within a few days of his appointment Mr Scaramucci found himself in a major PR mess, soon after which then President Donald Trump fired him. John Kelly, the Chief of Staff at the time also questioned his credibility.</p>

<p><strong>DONALD TRUMP TRASHES CLAIMS</strong></p>

<p>Donald Trump has rubbished Mr Scaramucci's comments about him and his wife Melania. Mr Trump dismisses his allegations saying his former aide is a bitter man who holds a grudge.</p>

<p><strong>MELANIA TRUMP'S LOW ATTENDANCE AT TRUMP RALLIES</strong></p>

<p>Melania Trump has been keeping a low profile and has hardly attended husband Donald Trump's rallies. She is reportedly occupied with her son Barron Trump's college education and spends most of her time in New York, where her son is planning to attend college. She has also expressed her fondness for New York.</p>

<p>Melania Trump is reportedly focusing more on family and personal milestones, than on Donald Trump's 2024 Presidential campaign. On October 1 this year, she will release her memoir, Melania. Her office describes the book as "a powerful and inspiring story of a woman who has forged her own path, overcome challenges, and defined personal excellence."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/ccijet1o_donald-trump-melania-trump_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A former Trump aide has claimed that Melania Trump is rooting for Kamala Harris over Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>