<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 12:05:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-farhad-shakeri-afghan-man-behind-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-trump-6978018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Farhad Shakeri, Afghan Man Behind Alleged Iran Plot To Kill Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-farhad-shakeri-afghan-man-behind-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-trump-6978018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:31:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Farhad Shakeri, an Afghan national who was deported from the United States in 2008, has been accused of plotting to assassinate Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Farhad Shakeri, an Afghan national who was deported from the United States in 2008, has been accused of plotting to assassinate Donald Trump. The 51-year-old allegedly masterminded a murder-for-hire operation in coordination with the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps (IRGC).</p>

<p>On November 8, Shakeri and two others were charged in a criminal complaint for their alleged involvement in the plot to assassinate a US citizen of Iranian descent in New York. While the other two suspects were arrested, Shakeri remains at large and is believed to be in Iran.</p>

<p>According to a criminal complaint, in September 2024, Shakeri was instructed by an official from the IRGC to focus on “assassinating, former President of the United States, Donald J. Trump.” This directive came after Shakeri had already been involved in multiple operations on behalf of the IRGC, utilising his criminal network to support the group's agenda.</p>

<p>The criminal complaint added that according to Shakeri, during his meeting with an IRGC official on or about October 7, 2024, he was instructed to provide a plan within seven days to kill Trump. If Shakeri failed to do so within that timeframe, the IRGC official said the plan would be delayed until after the US Presidential elections. It was believed that Trump would lose, and it would then be easier to carry out the assassination. Shakeri told the FBI that he did not intend to propose a plan within the set deadline.</p>

<p>The US Department of Justice stated, “Shakeri has informed law enforcement that he was tasked on October 7, 2024, with providing a plan to kill President-elect Donald J. Trump. During the interview, Shakeri claimed he did not intend to propose a plan to kill Trump within the timeframe set by the IRGC.”</p>

<p>Shakeri was also assigned to keep an eye on two Jewish American citizens in New York and was offered $500,000 by an IRGC official for the murder of either target. Additionally, he was instructed to target Israeli tourists in Sri Lanka.</p>

<h2><strong>Background of Farhad Shakeri</strong></h2>

<p>Shakeri, an asset of the IRGC based in Tehran, immigrated to the US as a child. He was deported in 2008 after serving 14 years for a robbery conviction. In recent months, Shakeri has been involved in leveraging a network of criminal associates he met in US prisons to assist the IRGC. He has reportedly been supplying the IRGC with operatives for conducting surveillance and assassinations targeting individuals of interest, according to the US Department of Justice.</p>

<p>Though he was deported in 2008, his parole monitoring continued until 2015. In 2019, he was detained in Sri Lanka in connection with the seizure of a large quantity of heroin, highlighting an ongoing series of alleged criminal activities linked to his network.</p>

<p>Shakeri faces multiple charges, including conspiring to provide material support to a foreign terrorist organisation, which could result in up to 20 years in prison. He is also charged with providing material support to the same organisation, as well as conspiring to violate sanctions against the Iranian government under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, each of which carries a potential 20-year prison sentence.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s3p31418_trump-afp_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Farhad Shakeri was instructed by an IRGC official to focus on assassinating Trump (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-killed-30-injured-in-railway-station-blast-in-pakistan-report-6978296]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[21 Killed, 46 Injured In Railway Station Blast In Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-killed-30-injured-in-railway-station-blast-in-pakistan-report-6978296]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:15:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 21 people were killed and 46 others injured on Saturday in a powerful bomb explosion at a crowded railway station in Pakistan's restive Balochistan province.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 21 people were killed and 46 others injured on Saturday in a powerful bomb explosion at a crowded railway station in Pakistan's restive Balochistan province, officials said.</p>

<p>The explosion ripped through the provincial capital Quetta's railway station as passengers gathered on the platform before the scheduled departure of the Jaffar Express to Peshawar.</p>

<p>Quetta Senior Superintendent Police (SSP) Operations Muhammad Baloch said initial findings point to a possible suicide bombing.</p>

<p>He also confirmed that 21 people were killed in the explosion, adding that the number of victims could rise.</p>

<p>Baloch Liberation Army (BLA) has claimed responsibility for the attack.</p>

<p>Preliminary reports indicate that the explosion took place at the railway station's booking office.</p>

<p>Rescue and law enforcement teams responded immediately, securing the area and transporting the injured and dead to Civil Hospital Quetta, according to the provincial government spokesperson Shahid Rind.</p>

<p>An emergency was declared at the hospital where additional medical staff was summoned to deal with the injured, where officials said that 46 injured have been shifted so far.</p>

<p>The blast, which also damaged the platform's roof, was heard far and wide in various areas of the city.</p>

<p>Balochistan Chief Minister Sarfraz Bugti condemned the attack, terming it as "a horrific act targeting innocent civilians", and ordered an immediate investigation.</p>

<p>He said that terrorists are increasingly aiming civilians, labourers, women, and children, and vowed that those responsible would be pursued relentlessly.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/hnf0rnu_pakistan-police-generic_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Officials said the train had not arrived at the platform at the time of the blast. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-2-0-doubling-down-or-back-to-zero-6978279]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Trump 2.0: Doubling Down Or Back To Zero?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-2-0-doubling-down-or-back-to-zero-6978279]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:11:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Trump prepares to saunter to the White House yet again, it is worthwhile to quote John Wayne, the famous Hollywood Wild West icon: "A man deserves a second chance, but keep an eye on him."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ucnv8l_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The results of the US elections held last week have produced both relief and shock in equal measure.</p>

<p>The world at large and the Americans in particular are relieved that even if the outcome was largely unexpected, it was unambiguous, decisive and uncontested. This belied many foreboding predictions. There was a clear swing towards the hard right, with the Republican Party making major gains. Donald Trump, its candidate, defied all odds to win the Presidency. The Republicans expanded their control of the Senate and are poised for a majority in the House of Representatives as well. Factoring in the right-leaning Supreme Court and Federal Reserve under pressure to ease its ‘tight money' policy—the GOP has never had it this good for a long time.</p>

<h2><strong>A Rude Shock For All</strong></h2>

<p>On the other hand, the “winner taking it all” outcome was a rude surprise not only for the defeated Democrats but also for the psephologists and the mainstream media, who predicted a victory for Kamala Harris and a greater countervailing balance in Congress. Few expected a massive popular endorsement of Mr Trump, a populist with controversial views often bordering on unsubstantiated extremism. To many, the outcome raised questions about the maturity of the electorate and fidelity to the electoral process itself. Despite a booming economy, low inflation and low unemployment, the American voter succumbed to clever manipulation of popular perceptions with pet popular peeves about immigration, globalisation and personal economics being weaponised. For many, this was not an outcome the US deserved.</p>

<p>But now that this is a<em> fait accompli</em>, the larger question that needs to be answered is: How will this binary split play out during the incoming Trump Presidency? A lot would depend on whether Trump 2.0 would hark back to Trump 1.0 or whether the experiences of being the 45th President have been internalised for the 47th Presidency. This requires a granular analysis to discern the likely course of Trump 2.0.</p>

<h2><strong>An Unapologetic Trump&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>To begin with, some basic observations are in order. Firstly, when the 78-year-old person concerned is not only unapologetic but triumphant about his past term, it raises some pertinent issues about his plans for the future in a vastly different context. Most of the catchy electoral promises made by candidate Trump were bare-bone intentions without precise targets. Similarly, many of the policy priorities articulated during the campaign intersect domestic and foreign affairs. Some of the planned and pre-announced quick fixes for the beginning of Trump 2.0 may open new Pandora's boxes. Further, given the unpredictability and transactional inconsistencies seen in Trump 1.0—from building an anti-immigrant wall on the southern border to the Summits with Kim Jong Un—were infructuous and were quietly abandoned. It cast doubts about keeping the new promises. Lastly, the bitter polarisation and name-calling of Trump 1.0 is a legacy that may haunt Trump 2.0. All these tactical complexities and shifts presage a pattern making Trump 2.0 invariably joined at the hip with Trump 1.0.</p>

<h2><strong>Pardons To MAGA To Immigration, A Domestic Roller-Coaster</strong></h2>

<p>Opening overtures of Trump 2.0 are likely to be dominated by domestic agenda. It's partly because his support base expects it and also because he has greater authority to do so. Firing inconvenient officials and presidential pardons, etc, are likely to be in the first flush. It may follow some measures at score-settling with “the enemies within” even as the bite may be less than the bark. He would find ways to flesh out his catchphrases such as “America First” and “Make America Great Again". Stopping illegal immigration and deporting those who have already done so would be a priority, even as some of these measures may be legally questionable.</p>

<p>On the economic side, Trump 2.0 may prune welfare spending and have a smaller government to balance with the promised lowering of taxes. Other intended moves such as high tariffs on imports and “Drill, Baby, Drill” may have collateral consequences in terms of trade wars, higher inflation, further demonise the “big oil”, environmental damage and lower export revenues. Rewarding Elon Musk and other corporate friends may lead to allegations of crony capitalism. The US political system does grant the President a high degree of impunity and the political context at the Congress and Supreme Court may be salubrious. Nevertheless, Mr Trump comes with the baggage of having been impeached twice and has the dubious distinction of being the first US President found guilty of 34 felony counts. His penchant for leaving a positive legacy is likely to restrain him.</p>

<h2><strong>The World Has Changed</strong>—<strong>For Trump, Too</strong></h2>

<p>In the foreign policy domain, President Trump would discover that the international context has turned far more complicated and nuanced. Despite bragging about his foreign policy accomplishments, Trump 1.0 was scarred by failed tactical initiatives, such as a deal with the Taliban, mollycoddling autocrats, reneging on the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) with Iran, antagonising longstanding partners, undermining multilateral architecture, etc. No wonder most partners reacted cautiously to the Trump victory. Even the ruling British Labour Party, for instance, had to painfully ruminate over the serious pejoratives it used to describe Trump 1.0. The rightist fringes in Europe and Israel have warmly welcomed his re-ascendence. The countries demonised during Trump 1.0, such as China, and Iran, reacted with predictable defiance.</p>

<p>The reactions to his elections were a foretaste of the kind of difficulties Trump 2.0 is likely to face as his ambitious agenda. While the US remains the world's primordial superpower, her hard and soft powers are significantly lower now, making unilateral pursuit of a wish list more difficult, particularly as he promises to avoid military engagements abroad. Trump 1.0 diplomacy was more about treating the symptoms than the disease. Living in denial was an often-exercised option on softer global issues such as climate change and disarmament. These tactical approaches merely kicked the can down the road, making the hotspots more numerous, more entrenched and intractable as evinced in the South China Sea, the Urals and the Middle East. Further, the cynical transactional approaches of Trump 1.0 lacked moral underpinnings, often reducing them to exercises in cynical manipulations and/or arm-twisting. More dangerously, it often allowed Trump's interlocutors to pander to flattery or deception to get their goals.</p>

<h2><strong>'A Man Deserves A Second Chance, But...'</strong></h2>

<p>The US under Trump 2.0 has two divergent options: isolationism and living in denial and inverted snobbery, or getting down from the moral horse and engaging either singly or through the same multilateral institutions that were often disfranchised during Trump 1.0. If Trump 2.0 intends to go beyond the palliatives deals and resolve the stubborn global crises, it would need to reinvent and realign itself with the new realities of the China-Russia nexus, more assertive middle-rung countries, including India, Brazil, Mexico, Iran, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela, France, Germany, etc. Even traditional partners such as the UK, Japan, Australia, and Israel need to be courted afresh.</p>

<p>With his disregard for conventions, clipped deliveries, one-liners and over-the-top High Noons too often, Trump 1.0 styled itself more as an urbane cowboy than the conventional politician. We do not know if the invocation to resonate with the WASP psyche was accidental or deliberate. As he prepares to saunter to the White House yet again, it is worthwhile to quote John Wayne, the famous Hollywood Wild West icon: "A man deserves a second chance, but keep an eye on him."</p>

<p><em>(Mahesh Sachdev is a former Indian Ambassador. He currently heads Eco-Diplomacy and Strategies, a Delhi-based consultancy)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hkkhbshg_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-australia-today-row-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-threatened-us-australian-outlet-facing-canada-ban-6974746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Khalistani Terrorist Threatened Us': Australian Outlet Facing Canada Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-australia-today-row-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-threatened-us-australian-outlet-facing-canada-ban-6974746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:05:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Australia Today founder and editor-in-chief Jitarth Jai Bhardwaj has questioned the Justin Trudeau government as to why the rights of the Hindu community in Canada are not being upheld.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calling the blocking of the prominent diaspora outlet 'Australia Today' by Canada, the "murder of free press", its founder and editor-in-chief Jitarth Jai Bhardwaj questioned the Justin Trudeau government as to why the rights of the Hindu community in the country are not being upheld, as they face "repeated attacks on their places of worship."</p>

<p>This comes after Canada blocked the outlet's social media handles and pages shortly after it aired a press conference of External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar with his Australian counterpart Penny Wong in Canberra. During the presser, the EAM slammed Canada for making allegations against India without any specific evidence and termed the "surveillance of Indian diplomats" unacceptable and also highlighted that the "political space has been given in Canada to anti-India elements."</p>

<p>On Thursday, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) also lambasted Canada for its "hypocrisy towards freedom of speech" following the blocking of 'The Australia Today' in the country.</p>

<p>Following the blocking by the Trudeau government, Mr Bhardwaj raised concerns over the move and said the publication would continue to advocate for open media.</p>

<p>In an interview with ANI, Mr Bhardwaj opened up about how their supporters notified them about not being able to access the outlet's content in Canada. After that, they found out that the press conference and interview of EAM Jaishankar went off the social media platform.</p>

<p>"We were notified by a lot of readers, followers of our page that they are not able to watch or view our content on Facebook and Instagram which they were able to watch like 10-15 minutes back and now they were not. They were trying to share it with their friends and colleagues and all of a sudden the press conference and the interview went off from the Facebook page and there was a notification written there that this content was not available for viewing in Canada by the order of Canadian government legislation," he said.</p>

<p>Condemning the Trudeau government's "dictatorial" move as a "murder of press freedom", the editor of the outlet said there should be a space for diverse views in a democracy.</p>

<p>"This is a murder of press freedom. This is not free speech, this is not how democracies act, and this is the way for dictators to act and clamp down on the press. In every democracy, there is space for diverse views and for the press to debate, interpret, analyse all those diverse views," Mr Bhardwaj said.</p>

<p>He added, "It seems that Canada is not kind of happy with how we were asking questions to Indian and Australian foreign ministers and they were not happy to see that a lot of Canadians were responding to it and they were trying to educate themselves than what Canadian government has been propagating for long now."</p>

<p>The Australia Today founder further elaborated on the news coverage of his outlet, and said they aim to provide coverage to the 'vibrant' Indian democracy, which he said, is being "left out".</p>

<p>"Australia Today is a news outlet that works for multicultural communities in the West. We do stories from UK, Canada, US, Australia, New Zealand, Fiji, Singapore, everywhere the Indian diaspora is hardworking and vibrant. Their stories are important, however, they are being left out by the so-called mainstream media, and this platform Australia Today highlights the issues which are very important to the Indian Australian community and Indian diaspora as a whole," he said.</p>

<p>While stating that the coverage of 'The Australia Today' is being appreciated everywhere for highlighting the condition of the Indian community, Mr Bhardwaj also shed light on the 'threats' received by the outlet. He alleged that the news platform and its journalists have been threatened by India-designated terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun and other Khalistani extremists.</p>

<p>"Our coverage about what is happening by Khalistani groups in Canada or in the US was getting a lot of traction there. Our reporting was being appreciated in all the places. Gurpatwant Singh Pannun threatened us after issuing a video. He put pictures of me and my team online, telling his supporters to harm us in different ways. This has been going on and we have been reporting continuously without fear," he said.</p>

<p>Referring to the situation in Canada, 'The Australia Today' editor-in-chief said that the Hindu community is being "attacked, persecuted and suppressed" not just by the extremist elements, but also by the police and the authorities.</p>

<p>He also said that his outlet is willing to interview Prime Minister Justin Trudeau and ministers and ask why the rights of the Hindu community are not being realised in his country as they continue to face one untoward incident after the other.</p>

<p>"I'm just a reporter. I can report on what is going on. So I can say that the Hindu community is being attacked in Canada right now. The Hindu community is being persecuted in Canada right now by police, RCMP, and authorities. Everyone is working as if to suppress the rights of Canadian Hindu citizens," Mr Bhardwaj said.</p>

<p>"That's what I see right now and that's what we are reporting. If Trudeau or his ministers are happy to talk to us, we are happy to interview them and ask simple questions that any and every journalist should be asking them right now. Why Hindu community in Canada is being treated the way they are being treated? Why their rights are not upheld? Why are their temples being attacked? These are the questions Trudeau should be answering right now," he added.</p>

<p>Being asked about whether 'The Australia Today' will try to challenge the Canadian government's order, the editor said they would focus on reporting the issues of Canadian citizens without any fear.</p>

<p>"I don't think Canadian government is listening right now. But we will not stop doing what we do, that is reporting. Reporting the issues of Canadian citizens, Canadian Indians, and multilingual communities. That we will keep on doing," Mr Bhardwaj stressed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/l8063v1o_gurpatwant-singh-pannun-twitter_625x300_12_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-official-meets-taliban-minister-ex-afghan-president-hamid-karzai-6978130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Official Meets Taliban Minister, Ex Afghan President Hamid Karzai]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-official-meets-taliban-minister-ex-afghan-president-hamid-karzai-6978130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:49:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a significant move, an Indian delegation met Afghanistan's acting Defence Minister Mullah Mohammad Yaqoob and offered the use of Chabahar Port in Iran to businesses in his country, and also discussed extending humanitarian assistance to Kabul.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant move, an Indian delegation met Afghanistan's acting Defence Minister Mullah Mohammad Yaqoob and offered the use of Chabahar Port in Iran to businesses in his country, and also discussed extending humanitarian assistance to Kabul.</p>

<p>The delegation was led by J P Singh, the Joint Secretary of the Pakistan-Afghanistan-Iran division in the External Affairs Ministry.</p>

<p>During a weekly media briefing here, External Affairs Ministry spokesman Randhir Jaiswal said that apart from Mohammad Yaqoob, the delegation also met with former President Hamid Karzai and other senior ministers, along with the heads of UN agencies.</p>

<p>"They had discussions on India's humanitarian assistance, also how the Chabahar Port can be utilised by the business community in Afghanistan for transactions and for export and import and any other thing that they would like to do," Jaiswal said in response to a question.</p>

<p>India does not recognise the Taliban regime that has been ruling Afghanistan since 2021.</p>

<p>India has been providing humanitarian aid, including wheat, medicines and medical supplies, to the Afghan people from time to time.</p>

<p>"I also want to recall here that providing humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan is an important part of our assistance programme and so far in the last few months, and a few years, we have dispatched several shipments of humanitarian assistance. We have longstanding ties with the people of Afghanistan, and these ties will continue to guide our approach towards the country," Jaiswal said.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, India signed a 10-year contract with Iran to develop and operate the Chabahar Port which was built with its assistance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1eemmk2_indian-delegate-meets-taliban-leader-_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India does not recognise the Taliban regime that has been ruling Afghanistan since 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oxford University Student Committed Suicide Due To 'Cancel Culture', Probe Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:45:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A consultant who investigated the case stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The suicide of a student at Oxford University has led to calls to review the 'cancel culture' prevalent in the elite institutions of the UK. Alexander Rogers (20), a third-year studying materials science at Corpus Christi College, took his own life in January earlier this year, after being 'ostracised' by his peers, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2024/11/07/oxford-student-kills-himself-cancel-culture-inquest-suicide/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Telegraph</em></a>. Following two-day inquest proceedings at Oxford Coroner's Court, coroner Nicholas Graham concluded that the ostracisation "led him to form an intention to take his own life". The final report added that Rogers was "distraught" that his friends shunned him following an unreported allegation.</p>

<p>A former partner had alleged "discomfort over a sexual encounter" involving Rogers on January 11. Four days later, on January 15, a missing person's report was filed as Rogers wrote to friends, expressing "remorse for his actions and a belief that they were unintentional but unforgivable". His body was later pulled from the River Thames.</p>

<p>"While what we are dealing with here is in the interest of the public the family additionally has to carry the unique burden of grief, which is a heavy one. From what we have heard Alexander was an extremely able and popular young man and his passing is sad indeed," Graham added.</p>

<p>Dr Dominique Thompson, an independent consultant who investigated the case, stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture". She added that the allegation levelled caused a "pile-on" effect of students siding against Rogers because of an "unwritten" moral code to "do the right thing".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/anurag-kashyap-on-defending-sandeep-reddy-vanga-s-animal-5666884" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Asked To Explain His Sandeep Reddy Vanga Post, Anurag Kashyap Says: "Don't Like This Cancel Culture"</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>University taking action</strong></h3>

<p>Notably, the university was not aware of the cancel culture before the report and has since accepted its recommendations which "are being addressed with some diligence".</p>

<p>"Oxford University and Corpus Christi College extend our deepest sympathies to Alexander's family and everyone in our community who has been saddened by his tragic death," read a statement by the university.</p>

<p>"The College commissioned an independent review to identify all learning in this case with the aim of minimising the chance of such a tragic loss happening again," it added.</p>

<p>A prevention of future death report has also been sent to the Department of Education to consider the prevalence of "cancel culture" across higher education.</p>

<p>Roger's family said their priority was ensuring that the culture of social ostracisation is recognised so that similar tragedies can be prevented from reoccurring.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k1099l_alexander-rogers-suicide_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alexander Rogers took his life in January earlier this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oxford University Student Died By Suicide Due To 'Cancel Culture', Probe Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:45:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A consultant who investigated the case stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The suicide of a student at Oxford University has led to calls to review the 'cancel culture' prevalent in the elite institutions of the UK. Alexander Rogers (20), a third-year studying materials science at Corpus Christi College, took his own life in January earlier this year, after being 'ostracised' by his peers, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2024/11/07/oxford-student-kills-himself-cancel-culture-inquest-suicide/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Telegraph</em></a>. Following two-day inquest proceedings at Oxford Coroner's Court, coroner Nicholas Graham concluded that the ostracisation "led him to form an intention to take his own life". The final report added that Rogers was "distraught" that his friends shunned him following an unreported allegation.</p>

<p>A former partner had alleged "discomfort over a sexual encounter" involving Rogers on January 11. Four days later, on January 15, a missing person's report was filed as Rogers wrote to friends, expressing "remorse for his actions and a belief that they were unintentional but unforgivable". His body was later pulled from the River Thames.</p>

<p>"While what we are dealing with here is in the interest of the public the family additionally has to carry the unique burden of grief, which is a heavy one. From what we have heard Alexander was an extremely able and popular young man and his passing is sad indeed," Graham added.</p>

<p>Dr Dominique Thompson, an independent consultant who investigated the case, stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture". She added that the allegation levelled caused a "pile-on" effect of students siding against Rogers because of an "unwritten" moral code to "do the right thing".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/anurag-kashyap-on-defending-sandeep-reddy-vanga-s-animal-5666884" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Asked To Explain His Sandeep Reddy Vanga Post, Anurag Kashyap Says: "Don't Like This Cancel Culture"</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>University taking action</strong></h3>

<p>Notably, the university was not aware of the cancel culture before the report and has since accepted its recommendations which "are being addressed with some diligence".</p>

<p>"Oxford University and Corpus Christi College extend our deepest sympathies to Alexander's family and everyone in our community who has been saddened by his tragic death," read a statement by the university.</p>

<p>"The College commissioned an independent review to identify all learning in this case with the aim of minimising the chance of such a tragic loss happening again," it added.</p>

<p>A prevention of future death report has also been sent to the Department of Education to consider the prevalence of "cancel culture" across higher education.</p>

<p>Roger's family said their priority was ensuring that the culture of social ostracisation is recognised so that similar tragedies can be prevented from reoccurring.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k1099l_alexander-rogers-suicide_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alexander Rogers took his life in January earlier this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-net-worth-surpasses-300-billion-after-donald-trumps-us-election-win-6978055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk's Net Worth Surpasses $300 Billion After Trump's US Election Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-net-worth-surpasses-300-billion-after-donald-trumps-us-election-win-6978055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:31:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk has added more to his personal fortune since Donald Trump's US election win than anyone else tracked by the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's net worth has surpassed $300 billion for the first time in almost three years, as shares of Tesla Inc. soar on bets that his close ties with President-elect Donald Trump will bolster the company.</p>

<p>Musk has added more to his personal fortune since Trump's win than anyone else tracked by the Bloomberg Billionaires Index. Tesla's stock has jumped 28% since Tuesday's close, increasing his wealth by $50 billion to $313.7 billion.</p>

<p>Trump has openly suggested moves that would benefit Musk's businesses. He said he'd reconsider his plans to slow the move to electric vehicles because of the Tesla co-founder's backing. Trump also voiced support for SpaceX, which makes up $82 billion of Musk's net worth, and its push to reach Mars. And the president-elect has floated the idea of Musk serving in a newly created role in his administration as efficiency czar.</p>

<p>"One of the best strategic bets he ever made was ultimately this bet on Trump," Wedbush Securities analyst Dan Ives said Thursday on Bloomberg TV. "Musk is the big winner in this Trump sweepstakes."</p>

<p>Musk inserted himself late into the presidential race, campaigning alongside Trump in the weeks leading up to the election and bankrolling stunts such as a $1 million daily sweepstakes for voters in battleground states. He became a part of Trump's inner circle, spending election night at Mar-a-Lago in Palm Beach.</p>

<p>Musk, 53, is the only person to ever have a fortune in excess of $300 billion, a mark he last reached in January 2022, according to Bloomberg's wealth index. It's still short of his all-time high of $340.4 billion in 2021.</p>

<p>Even before the election, Musk's net worth had been on the rise, with strong Tesla earnings in mid-October adding $34 billion to his fortune in a day.</p>

<p>Most of Musk's fortune is tied up in Tesla, the world's largest electric-vehicle manufacturer, whose prospects depend heavily on the federal government. Musk said during a Tesla earnings call last month that he'd push for a federal approval process for autonomous vehicles - a centerpiece of the company's future strategy - if selected for a role in the Trump administration.</p>

<p>Trump initially said he'd roll back EV initiatives in his acceptance speech at the Republican National Convention in July, but changed his position a month later.</p>

<p>"I'm for electric cars," Trump said at a rally in Atlanta. "I have to be, because Elon endorsed me very strongly."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lpgnudlg_elon-musk-donald-trump-bloomberg_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has close ties with US President-elect Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pakistan-pm-shehbaz-sharifs-message-to-donald-trump-an-x-faux-pas-6978004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak PM Shehbaz Sharif Congratulates Donald Trump On X, Gets Community Noted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pakistan-pm-shehbaz-sharifs-message-to-donald-trump-an-x-faux-pas-6978004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:21:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif extended his congratulations to Donald Trump for his "historic victory" in securing a second term as US President.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif extended his congratulations to Donald Trump for his "historic victory" in securing a second term as US President. However, the message, posted on X (formerly Twitter), came with a faux pas - given that Sharif's government has imposed a nationwide ban on the platform.</p>

<p>Sharif's post, which wished Trump well and expressed an eagerness to "strengthen and broaden the Pakistan - US partnership," was immediately flagged with a Community Note. The note pointed out that the Pakistani Prime Minister was in fact accessing the platform via a VPN, which, according to Pakistan's legal framework, is in violation of national regulations.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif has banned X (formerly Twitter) in Pakistan. He is using a VPN to access X, which is unlawful according to Pakistani law," the X Community Note read.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ev9d7an_shehbaz-sharif-twitter-community-note_625x300_09_November_24.jpg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Screengrab of Shehbaz Sharif's post that received a Community Note on X.</p>
</div>

<p>Pakistan's interior ministry announced in April that access to X had been blocked due to national security concerns, with users reporting difficulties accessing the platform since mid-February. Despite the government's official stance, Sharif and other officials appear to have found ways to bypass the block using VPNs. In fact, many Pakistani leaders, including those from Sharif's own party, have continued to use the platform freely, ignoring their own legal restrictions.</p>

<p>The ban itself has stirred controversy. Initially, the government cited concerns over the platform's refusal to comply with local laws, including the controversial 2021 law called Removal and Blocking of Unlawful Online Content Rules. The government also raised alarms over "hostile elements" using social media to destabilise Pakistan, but critics argue that the restriction is politically motivated, particularly in the wake of allegations of election rigging.</p>

<p>Sharif's own political rival, Imran Khan, has been one of the most vocal users of social media in Pakistan, particularly X, &nbsp;where his party, the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI), has garnered millions of followers. Khan, in jail now, claimed that his ousting in 2022 was orchestrated by the military and that the elections earlier this year were manipulated to keep his party out of power. The government's restriction of X, some suggest, is an attempt to silence such opinions, particularly as the platform has been a critical outlet for dissent.</p>

<p>Critics argue that the Ministry of Interior overstepped its bounds in imposing the restriction, bypassing the Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA), which is the only body authorised to regulate online content under the Prevention of Electronic Crimes Act, 2016. The real motivation behind the ban is to force X to comply with local censorship demands, as has been the case with other platforms like YouTube and TikTok.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/au3tdfno_shehbaz-sharif-reuters_625x300_04_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pakistan's interior ministry announced in April that access to X was blocked over national security.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistans-punjab-shuts-amusement-parks-museums-for-10-days-due-to-severe-smog-6977921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Shuts Parks, Museums As Air Quality Worsens, Multans AQI Crosses 2,100]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistans-punjab-shuts-amusement-parks-museums-for-10-days-due-to-severe-smog-6977921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:06:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Punjab government in a bid to combat the hazardous smog conditions in the province, shut down amusement parks and museums for 10 days, from November 8 to 17, ARY News reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Punjab government in a bid to combat the hazardous smog conditions in the province, shut down amusement parks and museums for 10 days, from November 8 to 17, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>As per the ban imposed on Friday, the districts affected by this ban include Lahore, Gujranwala, Faisalabad, Multan, Sheikhupura, Kasur, Nankana Sahib, Gujarat, Hafizabad, Mandi Bahauddin, Sialkot, Narowal, Chiniot, Jhang, and Toba Tek Singh, ARY News reported. Lodhran, Vehari, and Khanewal districts are also under smog-related restrictions.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Pakistan's air pollution reached an alarming level, with seven cities topping the list of the world's most polluted cities, as per ARY News. Pakistan's meteorologists predicted worsening smog conditions due to low wind speeds of 11km/h around Lahore and 7km/h near Multan.</p>

<p>Multan's air quality had an AQI score of 2,135, and that of Lahore was 676. Peshawar, Islamabad, Hariput, Rawalpindi and Karachi fell under the 'hazardous air quality' category, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>Earlier on Thursday, Lahore ranked number one on the most polluted city rankings, released by IQAir at a staggering 784.</p>

<p>Lahore's atmosphere has remained dangerous for its residents for weeks following its position as one of the cities with the world's highest AQI. The pollution levels have time and again touched 1,000 for the city.</p>

<p>As per Geo News, the prolonged exposure has increased hospital admissions for respiratory issues, with Lahore and other cities like Multan, Kasur, Sheikhupura, and Gujranwala severely affected.</p>

<p>The persistent dangerous atmosphere has made it difficult for citizens to breathe, leaving them vulnerable to respiratory diseases, as they struggle to continue with their daily activities.</p>

<p>Doctors have advised the residents of Lahore to wear masks when stepping outside their homes.</p>

<p>Geo News reported that private and government educational institutions, teaching up to the higher secondary level, in the city as well as other districts of Pakistan's Punjab have also been closed by the government till November 17, as per notification.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Punjab education department has ordered to keep tuition centres and academies closed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pkq2c0g8_lahore_625x300_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Doctors have advised the residents of Lahore to wear masks when stepping outside their homes. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/relief-workers-directed-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-during-hurricane-milton-report-6977914]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Relief Workers Told To Avoid Homes With Trump Signs During Hurricane Milton]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/relief-workers-directed-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-during-hurricane-milton-report-6977914]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:03:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Florida Governor Ron DeSantis took to X (formerly Twitter) and announced an investigation into the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The disaster relief workers in the US state of Florida were directed to "avoid homes" with signs supporting President-elect Donald Trump when Hurricane Milton ravaged the area, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/08/us-news/fema-workers-told-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-in-hurricane-ravaged-florida-community/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>NY Post</em></a>, citing the Daily Wire. Marn'i Washington, a Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) supervisor passed the order to her workers both verbally and in a Microsoft Teams chat used by the group, which was working to secure homes and rescue people around Lake Placid - one of the worst-affected areas.</p>

<p>"Avoid homes advertising Trump," Washington wrote in a "best practices" memo sent to employees. As many as 20 homes displaying signs for the Republican leader - a common sight during the election season, were ignored between the end of October and into November, as part of the directive by Washington.</p>

<p>"I thought we could go help and make a difference. When we got there we were told to discriminate against people. It's almost unbelievable to think that somebody in the federal government would think that's okay," one of the workers was quoted as saying by the outlet.</p>

<p>Florida Governor Ron DeSantis took to X (formerly Twitter) and announced an investigation into the matter, calling it a "blatant weaponization of government by partisan activists".</p>

<p>"At my direction, the Division of Emergency Management is launching an investigation into the federal government's targeted discrimination of Floridians who support Donald Trump," wrote DeSantis.</p>

<p>"New leadership is on the way in DC, and I'm optimistic that these partisan bureaucrats will be fired," he added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The blatant weaponization of government by partisan activists in the federal bureaucracy is yet another reason why the Biden-Harris administration is in its final days.<br />
<br />
At my direction, the Division of Emergency Management is launching an investigation into the federal… <a href="https://t.co/3uFpE62vxb">https://t.co/3uFpE62vxb</a></p>
— Ron DeSantis (@GovRonDeSantis) <a href="https://twitter.com/GovRonDeSantis/status/1855030970140770445?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>A FEMA official conceded that they were aware of the incident and "taking action at this moment regarding the situation". Meanwhile, Washington had not been punished for the guidance but shifted to a different Florida county, according to the last update.</p>

<p>Notably, Trump and Vice President-elect JD Vance had criticised the current Biden-Harris administration for their slow response to the disaster as the region was pummeled by several two hurricanes in a relatively short period.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/milton-explained-how-milton-became-a-powerful-hurricane-and-why-its-a-concern-6750186" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Explained: How Milton Became A Powerful Hurricane And Why It's A Concern</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Hurricane Milton's impact</strong></h3>

<p>At least 16 people lost their lives when Hurricane Milton dumped around 229 mm of rainfall in just three hours in Florida, causing flash flooding. Powerful tornadoes that preceded the hurricane's landfall further added to the destruction. At one point, over three million people were without electricity as the hurricane tore through the region.</p>

<p>A study last year stated that storms originating in the Atlantic Ocean were now more than twice as likely to strengthen from Category 1 to Category 3 in just 36 hours, based on data from 2001-2020 compared with 1971-1990.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qv1t50f_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump election signs seen in the yards]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-a-hard-fought-loss-will-kamala-harris-chart-a-new-course-6973556]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After US Election Loss, What's Next For Kamala Harris?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-a-hard-fought-loss-will-kamala-harris-chart-a-new-course-6973556]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:40:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will demit office in 72 days and has no immediate plans as far as her political career is concerned.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris addressed a sombre crowd at her alma mater Howard University after she lost to Republican rival Donald Trump. She vowed to continue the fight that fuelled her campaign for the US election.</p>

<p>The 60-year-old will demit office in 72 days and has announced no immediate plans as far as her political career is concerned.</p>

<p>So what is next for Kamala Harris?</p>

<p><b>Prepare For 2028?</b></p>

<p>The most obvious choice before the former Democratic nominee is to take time and prepare for another bid in 2028. There are a few examples from the past. John Kerry, the 2004 nominee, lost to George Bush but didn't entirely disappear from the political scene after that. He served as the Secretary of State in Barack Obama's second term.</p>

<p><b>Back To The Senate?</b></p>

<p>Like John Kerry, returning to state politics and building the momentum again is an option. However, the road for Ms Harris doesn't appear to be an easy one. Longtime Democrat donor Mark Buell expressed the disappointment shared by many in her home state. “Everybody is devastated,” he was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/07/us/politics/kamala-harris-2028-run-for-president.html"><em>New York Times</em></a>.</p>

<p>Richie Greenberg, a Republican commentator based in San Francisco, said that Ms Harris might struggle to secure the fundraising support she once enjoyed.</p>

<p><strong>Role In The Democratic Party</strong></p>

<p>One potential path for Ms Harris could be that of a spokesperson within the Democratic Party, given her broad name recognition and connections. However, Greenberg thinks she will face challenges reigniting financial support from her base in San Francisco.</p>

<p><strong>A Tell-All Book</strong></p>

<p>Like at least two of the former Democratic nominees -- Hillary Clinton and Al Gore -- who lost the Presidential bids and decided to immerse themselves in writing and other pursuits, Ms Harris could also think in the same direction. While Hillary wrote a book titled '<em>What Happened</em>' after losing to Trump in 2016, Gore produced a documentary film '<em>An Inconvenient Truth'</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Enjoy Time Away From Politics</strong></p>

<p>In a couple of months, Ms Harris will be out of the Vice-President's office and can do what she promised to herself on October 27. “I plan on putting on some pounds after this is over,” she said at a Pennsylvania bookstore. “They're working me to the bone.”</p>

<p>Other than that, Harris could also follow in the footsteps of Ms Clinton, who hasn't been that active in politics and is more focused on her personal life. However, she continues to maintain a good rapport with donors.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/morejb4o_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris conceded defeat after she bagged 226 electoral votes against Donald Trump's 301.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-amid-india-canada-diplomatic-standoff-a-bombshell-from-justin-trudeau-6977740]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid India-Canada Diplomatic Rift, Justin Trudeau's "Khalistani" Admission]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-amid-india-canada-diplomatic-standoff-a-bombshell-from-justin-trudeau-6977740]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:23:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the diplomatic standoff between India and Canada continues, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has admitted for the first time the presence of Khalistanis in his country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the diplomatic standoff between <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/india-canada" target="_blank">India and Canada</a> continues, Canadian Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/justin-trudeau" target="_blank">Justin Trudeau</a> has admitted for the first time the presence of Khalistanis in his country. In an unexpected statement, Trudeau acknowledged the presence of a Khalistan support base within Canada but quickly added that they do not represent the Sikh community as a whole. His remark came during a Diwali celebrations event at Ottawa's Parliament Hill.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Relations between India and Canada have deteriorated since the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar, a Khalistani terrorist, outside a gurdwara in Surrey, British Columbia, in June 2023. Trudeau's allegation that India may have been involved in the murder set off a diplomatic firestorm that continues to rage. During his Diwali address, Trudeau stated that while there are supporters of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's government in Canada, they do not represent all Hindu Canadians either.</p>

<p>"There are many supporters of Khalistan in Canada, but they do not represent the Sikh Community as a whole. There are supporters of the Modi government in Canada, but they do not represent all Hindu Canadians as a whole," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Growing Tensions</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier this week, protesters, some waving Khalistani flags, clashed with devotees at a temple in Canada's Brampton, throwing punches, swinging poles, and disrupting a consular event that had drawn Indian nationals and Canadian citizens alike. Videos that quickly went viral on social media appeared to show protesters physically confronting worshippers outside the temple grounds. The footage depicted chaotic scenes of fistfights, with people hitting each other with poles as the tension escalated.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau condemned the violence, stressing that every Canadian has the right to practice their faith in peace. "The acts of violence at the Hindu Sabha Mandir in Brampton today are unacceptable. Every Canadian has the right to practice their faith freely and safely," Trudeau wrote on X (formerly Twitter). "Thank you to the Peel Regional Police for swiftly responding to protect the community and investigate this incident."</p>

<p>The Centre expressed deep concern over the safety of Indian nationals in Canada, while unequivocally condemning the attack on the Hindu Sabha temple.</p>

<p>"We have seen violent disruption today (November 3), orchestrated by anti-India elements outside the consular camp co-organised with the Hindu Sabha Mandir in Brampton, near Toronto," said MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal in a statement. "We also remain very concerned for the safety of applicants, including Indian nationals, on whose demand such events are organised in the first place. Despite these efforts by anti-India elements, our Consulate was able to issue more than 1,000 life certificates to the Indian and Canadian applicants."</p>

<h3><strong>No Evidence, Only Intelligence</strong></h3>

<p>India has consistently rejected any link to the murder of Nijjar, a designated terrorist by the National Investigation Agency (NIA), and accused Trudeau's administration of pandering to Khalistani sympathisers for political gain. The Trudeau government has accused India of being complicit in Nijjar's killing, a claim India has vehemently denied.</p>

<p>India has termed the allegations as politically motivated, pointing to Canada's failure to address the rising tide of pro-Khalistan sentiment in the country. In the aftermath of Nijjar's death, Canadian police suggested that six Indian diplomats were involved in the plot, a claim that India quickly dismissed as "preposterous." Despite multiple exchanges, including meetings at international forums like the G20 Summit, Canada has failed to provide any conclusive evidence linking India to the murder.</p>

<p>Last month, the Centre issued a blistering response to Canada's charges, rejecting claims that India's High Commissioner to Canada, Sanjay Kumar Verma, was a "person of interest" in Nijjar's murder. India not only dismissed the claims about Verma but also pointed out that despite repeated requests for evidence, Canada had failed to share any substantive proof to substantiate its allegations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a startling admission during a public inquiry in October, Trudeau admitted that Canada had no "hard evidentiary proof" in 2023 to support allegations linking Indian government agents to the killing of Nijjar. &nbsp;Speaking during a public inquiry into alleged foreign interference in Canada's federal electoral processes and democratic institutions, Trudeau revealed that his claims about India's involvement were based on intelligence rather than conclusive evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was briefed on the fact that there was intelligence from Canada, and possibly from Five Eyes allies that made it fairly clear, incredibly clear, that India was involved in this... Agents of the government of India were involved in the killing of a Canadian on Canadian soil," he said.</p>

<p>Trudeau explained that Canada had the option to go public with the allegations during the G20 summit held in New Delhi in September 2023 but chose not to.</p>

<p>"Our response was, well, it's within your security agencies," Mr Trudeau said, recounting Canada's exchanges with India. "At that point, it was primarily intelligence, not hard evidentiary proof. So we said, let's work together and look into your security services."</p>

<p>The Indian government has argued that Canada provides a safe haven for pro-Khalistani extremists and separatists who pose a threat to India's security. New Delhi also said that it had requested action against these elements, which Canada had failed to take seriously.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/33o00gkg_justin-trudeau-afp-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Relations between India and Canada have deteriorated since the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dark-moments-in-history-joe-biden-on-attacks-on-israeli-fans-in-amsterdam-6977701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Dark Moments In History...": Biden On Attacks On Israeli Fans In Amsterdam]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dark-moments-in-history-joe-biden-on-attacks-on-israeli-fans-in-amsterdam-6977701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:14:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Friday (local time) condemned the recent attacks on Israeli soccer fans in Amsterdam Friday, calling the incident "despicable and echo dark moments in history when Jews were persecuted."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Friday (local time) condemned the recent attacks on Israeli soccer fans in Amsterdam Friday, calling the incident "despicable and echo dark moments in history when Jews were persecuted."</p>

<p>Biden said he has been in touch with Israeli and Dutch officials and that he appreciates "Dutch authorities' commitment to holding the perpetrators accountable."</p>

<p>In a post on X, Biden said, "The Antisemitic attacks on Israeli soccer fans in Amsterdam are despicable and echo dark moments in history when Jews were persecuted. We've been in touch with Israeli and Dutch officials and appreciate Dutch authorities' commitment to holding the perpetrators accountable. We must relentlessly fight Antisemitism, wherever it emerges."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Antisemitic attacks on Israeli soccer fans in Amsterdam are despicable and echo dark moments in history when Jews were persecuted.<br />
<br />
We've been in touch with Israeli and Dutch officials and appreciate Dutch authorities' commitment to holding the perpetrators accountable.<br />
<br />
We…</p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1854953886328799588?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>His statement comes a day after Israeli soccer fans were assaulted by young people in hit-and-run scooter attacks. Dutch authorities said the incident was likely a result of calls on social media to attack Jewish people.</p>

<p>The state of Israel in a post on X condemned the attacks and recalled the attack on Jews during the Nazi rule in Germany.</p>

<p>"Hundreds of fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv Football Club were ambushed and brutally attacked in Amsterdam last night after the match against AFC Ajax. Mobs chanted anti-Israel slogans and proudly shared videos of their violent acts on social media--kicking, beating, even running over Israeli citizens. On the eve of Kristallnacht--when Jews in Nazi Germany faced brutal attacks--it is horrifying to witness antisemitic violence on the streets of Europe once again. Israeli PM Netanyahu and Foreign Minister Gideon Sa'ar announced Israel is sending an aid mission, including two rescue planes."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Antisemitic attacks on Israeli soccer fans in Amsterdam are despicable and echo dark moments in history when Jews were persecuted.<br />
<br />
We've been in touch with Israeli and Dutch officials and appreciate Dutch authorities' commitment to holding the perpetrators accountable.<br />
<br />
We…</p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1854953886328799588?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>As per The Times of Israel, the fans of Israeli football club Maccabi Tel Aviv were attacked in the streets of Amsterdam after they lost to Amsterdam's team Ajax. The attackers were allegedly shouting slogans of "free Palestine" and were carrying Palestinian flags.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="iw">בהערכת מצב במשרד החוץ: לא נקבל פגיעה ביהודים - לא באמסטרדם, לא באירופה, לא בשום מקום אחר. <a href="https://t.co/taYRSvf4bG">pic.twitter.com/taYRSvf4bG</a></p>
— Benjamin Netanyahu - בנימין נתניהו (@netanyahu) <a href="https://twitter.com/netanyahu/status/1854886036846874824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Times of Israel, quoting certain Hebrew media outlets, said that some of the Israelis' passports were stolen and several of them were injured.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said in a statement during his visit to the Israeli Foreign Ministry that the 86th anniversary of Kristallnacht was "marked on the streets of Amsterdam".</p>

<p>"Tomorrow, 86 years ago, was Kristallnacht, when Jews on European soil were attacked for being Jews. This has now recurred," Netanyahu said referring to the events of November 9, 1938, a Nazi pogrom that acted as a catalyst in the persecution of Jews that eventually led to the killing of 6 million European Jews by the Nazis and their supporters during the Holocaust, as per The Times of Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o30es1hg_joe-biden-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's statement comes a day after Israeli soccer fans were assaulted by young people. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-tracker-president-elect-donald-trump-live-updates-trump-live-news-today-6977652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada On "High Alert", Braces For Migrants Fleeing US After Trump Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-tracker-president-elect-donald-trump-live-updates-trump-live-news-today-6977652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:07:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump will return to the White House after winning a defining mandate in the November 5 elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump will return to the White House after winning a defining mandate in the November 5 elections. Trump, who has already appointed his chief of staff for the White House, won 295 electoral college votes as against his Democratic rival Kamala Harris' 226 votes besides. He also won the popular vote - while Trump got 74 million popular votes, Harris got 70 million. He is now expected to make changes to key policies that will impact the lives of millions of immigrants in the US.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump Tracker: News about Trump ahead of his grand return</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/e59m21a8_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/geomagnetic-shield-weakening-over-north-america-claim-chinese-researchers-6977665]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Geomagnetic Shield Weakening Over North America, Claim Chinese Researchers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/geomagnetic-shield-weakening-over-north-america-claim-chinese-researchers-6977665]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:04:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over the last 30 years, the magnetic field strength in the region has dropped to a level that is barely above the global average.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese scientists have claimed that the magnetic shield over North America is weakening rapidly while strengthening in the eastern hemisphere. Led by Professor Fang Hanxian of the National University of Defence Technology, the study, published in&nbsp;<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.sjdz.org.cn/en/article/doi/10.19975/j.dqyxx.2024-012" rel="nofollow, noindex">Review of Geophysics and Planetary Physics</a></em>, claims the shift of the geomagnetic poles from the western to the eastern hemisphere might be the possible reason for the "exceptionally fast" loss of the field strength. Fang's team used the latest models and data to reconstruct the global magnetic field strength change since 1900.</p>

<p>The findings showed that between 1930 to 1990, the field strength in North America increased and was higher than in many other regions of the world. However, over the last three decades, especially by 2020, the magnetic field strength in the region had dropped to a level that is barely above the global average.</p>

<p>"After 2000, the speed exceeded 50km per year, far surpassing the movement speed of the magnetic pole in the southern hemisphere," Fang was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3285683/magnetic-shield-over-north-america-losing-strength-exceptionally-fast-pla-scientists" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>SCMP</em></a>.</p>

<p>"Apart from the weakening magnetic field in North America, the strength in other major regions is showing an increasing trend," Fang said, adding that Australia, the North Atlantic Ocean and Africa were experiencing the fastest growth.</p>

<p>Over the past century, the magnetic pole in the northern hemisphere had drifted eastward at a speed of about 10 km per year, the study highlighted.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/heres-how-a-phd-student-discovered-long-lost-maya-city-while-browsing-google-6906358" rel="Nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Here's How A PhD Student Discovered Long-Lost Maya City While Browsing Google</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>The geomagnetic shield</strong></h3>

<p>Earth's geomagnetic field, also called the magnetosphere, is a kind of natural barrier that protects the planet from harmful cosmic radiation which can cause erosion of our atmosphere by solar wing. Unlike planets in our immediate vicinity such as Mercury, Venus and Mars, Earth is surrounded by powerful, dynamic forces that play the role of gatekeeper, repelling unwanted energy and trapping most of it at a safe distance from the planet in a twin doughnut-shaped zones called the Van Allen Belts.</p>

<p>In 2018, a study by the National Autonomous University of Mexico found that low geomagnetic fields prevailed in the Maya area, just before the Mayan civilisation collapsed. Some other studies have also attributed the downfall of ancient civilisations in Iran and Syria to the sudden changes in the magnetic field.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6f6f9hu8_north-america_625x300_09_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North America is witnessing loss of geomagnetic field]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heat-air-pollution-disease-how-climate-change-affects-health-6977578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Heat, Air Pollution, Disease: How Climate Change Affects Health]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heat-air-pollution-disease-how-climate-change-affects-health-6977578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 08:42:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Record-breaking heat, extreme weather events, air pollution and the spread of infectious disease: climate change poses an already vast yet rising threat to the health of humans around the world, experts warn.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Record-breaking heat, extreme weather events, air pollution and the spread of infectious disease: climate change poses an already vast yet rising threat to the health of humans around the world, experts warn.</p>

<p>The latest round of UN climate talks begin next week during what is expected to be the hottest year in recorded history -- and in the shadow of climate sceptic Donald Trump's re-election as US president.</p>

<p>The COP29 negotiations will be held in Azerbaijan as the world continues to emit increasing levels of planet-heating fossil fuels, even as many nations have been lashed by devastating floods, droughts, heatwaves and storms.</p>

<p>"Climate change is making us sick, and urgent action is a matter of life and death," the World Health Organization warned this week.</p>

<p>Here are some of the ways that global warming affects health.</p>

<p><strong>Extreme Heat</strong></p>

<p>The EU's climate monitor said this week that 2024 is "virtually certain" to surpass last year to become the hottest year in recorded history. It is also expected to be the first year that is more than 1.5 degrees Celsius warmer than the 1850-1900 pre-industrial average.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Out of 15 ways that climate change impacts health being tracked by experts as part of The Lancet Countdown, 10 have now "reached concerning new records", according to the group's latest report.</p>

<p>The number of over-65s who died from heat has risen by 167 percent since the 1990s, just one of the recent all-time highs, the report said.</p>

<p>Extreme heat leads to numerous health risks such as kidney disorders, strokes, adverse pregnancy outcomes, cardiovascular and respiratory diseases, organ failure and ultimately death.</p>

<p>Jeni Miller, executive director of the Global Climate and Health Alliance, said "this year has underlined the growing impacts of a warming climate on people's health and wellbeing".</p>

<p>She pointed to extreme heat leading to 700 deaths and more than 40,000 cases of heat stroke in India, "climate-exacerbated" rains causing a dam to collapse in Nigeria killing 320, and 48 out of 50 US states "experiencing moderate or worse drought".</p>

<p>Spain is meanwhile still recovering from its deadliest floods in a generation, while parts of the United States and Cuba are picking up the pieces after recent hurricanes.</p>

<p>Droughts, floods and other extreme weather events are also expected to hit global crops, leading to rising hunger in many regions.</p>

<p><strong>Air Pollution</strong></p>

<p>Almost all -- 99 percent -- of the world's population breathes air that exceeds the World Health Organization's guidelines for air pollution.</p>

<p>This pollution has been found to increase the risk of respiratory diseases, strokes, heart disease, lung cancer, diabetes and other health problems, posing a threat that has been compared to tobacco.</p>

<p>Almost seven million premature deaths a year are linked to air pollution, according to the WHO.</p>

<p>Just last week, Pakistan's second-biggest city Lahore recorded air pollution at 40 times the level deemed acceptable by the WHO.</p>

<p>In better news, the Lancet Countdown report found that deaths from fossil fuel-related air pollution fell by nearly seven percent from 2016 to 2021, mainly due to efforts to reduce pollution from burning coal.</p>

<p><strong>Infectious Diseases</strong></p>

<p>The changing climate means that mosquitoes, birds and mammals will roam beyond their previous habitats, raising the threat that they could spread infectious diseases with them.</p>

<p>Dengue, chikungunya, Zika, West Nile virus and malaria are all mosquito-borne diseases that could spread wider in a warming world.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The transmission risk of one dengue-spreading mosquito has risen by 43 percent over the last 60 years, according to the Lancet Countdown. A new global record of over five million dengue cases was recorded last year.</p>

<p>Storms and floods create stagnant water that are breeding grounds for mosquitoes, and also increase the risk of water-borne diseases such as cholera, typhoid and diarrhoea.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2q5md86g_cop29_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[COP29 negotiations will be held in Azerbaijan as the world continues to emit fossil fuels.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/myanmars-war-torn-rakhine-faces-famine-with-2-million-people-at-risk-un-says-6977542]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Myanmar's War-Torn Rakhine Faces Famine With 2 Million People At Risk: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/myanmars-war-torn-rakhine-faces-famine-with-2-million-people-at-risk-un-says-6977542]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 08:34:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Myanmar's war-ravaged Rakhine state could face imminent famine according to a United Nations report, which estimates that more than two million people could be at the risk of starvation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar's war-ravaged Rakhine state could face imminent famine according to a United Nations report, which estimates that more than two million people could be at the risk of starvation.</p>

<p>Rice production in Rakhine, a western state that borders Bangladesh, has declined due to shortages of seeds and fertilizers, severe weather and the displacement of people who can no longer farm, according to the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP).</p>

<p>Aid agencies, including the Red Cross, have faced severe difficulties in assessing humanitarian needs and delivering aid due to restrictions from Myanmar's military government.</p>

<p>"Rakhine stands on the precipice of an unprecedented disaster," the UNDP said in a report late on Thursday.</p>

<p>"Combined with the near-total halt of trade, over two million people are at risk of starvation."</p>

<p>The number of internally displaced people in Rakhine has risen by more than 60% from October 2023 to August this year, with more than 500,000 now relying entirely on aid, the UNDP said.</p>

<p>Myanmar has been in turmoil since the military ousted the elected government of Nobel laureate Aung San Suu Kyi in 2021, sparking mass protests that escalated into an armed rebellion on multiple fronts.</p>

<p>With more than three million people displaced and much of the country in chaos, humanitarian aid has become critical in Myanmar.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the junta did not answer calls seeking comment on the report.</p>

<p>Violence has been on the increase since conflict reignited in Rakhine last November following the collapse of a ceasefire between the Arakan Army (AA) and the military. Rebel forces have since made substantial gains.</p>

<p>Though the military has for years been accused of persecuting the Muslim minority Rohingya community in Rakhine, the Arakan Army has also been accused of targeting them, which it has denied. An AA spokesperson did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The fighting has triggered a new wave of Rohingya refugees fleeing into Bangladesh, where more than a million Rohingya live in huge refugee camps.</p>

<p>"Without urgent action, 95% of the population will regress into survival mode," the UNDP report said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0ljbd8tg_united-nations_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[With over 3 million people displaced, humanitarian aid has become critical in Myanmar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/authorities-probing-bigoted-text-messages-that-spread-alarm-across-us-6977503]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Authorities Probing Bigoted Text Messages That Spread Alarm Across US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/authorities-probing-bigoted-text-messages-that-spread-alarm-across-us-6977503]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 08:22:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Federal and state authorities are investigating a wave of bigoted text messages sent anonymously that have spread alarm among Black Americans across the country this week, officials and recipients told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Federal and state authorities are investigating a wave of bigoted text messages sent anonymously that have spread alarm among Black Americans across the country this week, officials and recipients told Reuters.</p>

<p>The messages urged recipients in multiple states, including Alabama, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Virginia, to report to a plantation to pick cotton, an offensive reference to past enslavement of Black people in the United States.</p>

<p>It is unclear who is behind the reported texts, how many people had received them, or how the recipients were targeted.</p>

<p>The Federal Communications Commission said on Friday its enforcement bureau was among those probing the incidents.</p>

<p>Lousiana Attorney General Liz Murrill, a Republican, told Reuters on Friday that her office is among those investigating the text messages, adding that some targets - herself included - also received emails.</p>

<p>Murrill, who is white, said one of the messages hit her personal email box at 8:17 a.m. Friday, according to a screenshot of the message she shared with Reuters.</p>

<p>The message greeted her with an ethnic slur and said "Now that trump is president, you have been selected to pick cotton at the nearest plantation" and that "Our guys will come get you in a van."</p>

<p>She said the FBI was also looking into the messages.</p>

<p>The FBI on Thursday said in a statement it was "aware of the offensive and racist text messages sent to individuals around the country," and that it was in contact with the Justice Department and other federal authorities on the matter.</p>

<p>"It could be coming from a basement in Baton Rouge, or it could be a basement in Bangladesh," said Murrill. "It's obviously intended to play on people's emotion in the wake of the election. I'm urging people to rise above it, don't give these malcontents the benefit of capturing any of emotional bandwidth."</p>

<p>Monèt Miller, an Atlanta-based publicist, said that when she shared on social media that she had received a text message telling her to report to her "nearest plantation," she was shocked at how many other Black Americans chimed in to say they had gotten similar messages.</p>

<p>"To find out that all these African American people are getting it, that was the scariest part about it," she said. "Who is doing that?"</p>

<p>People in at least 21 states received the texts, including high school and college students, CNN and the Associated Press reported.</p>

<p>"These actions are not normal. And we refuse to let them be normalized," NAACP President Derrick Johnson said in a statement from the civil rights organization, which advocates for racial justice and rights for Black Americans.</p>

<p>"These messages represent an alarming increase in vile and abhorrent rhetoric from racist groups across the country."</p>

<p>Some Black Americans have said they fear a rollback of civil rights after Republican Donald Trump, who won Tuesday's presidential election over Democrat Kamala Harris, takes office on Jan. 20. Trump, who made racist and sexist attacks against his Black opponent, has pledged to end federal diversity and inclusion programs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"President Trump's campaign has absolutely nothing to do with these text messages," his spokeswoman Karoline Leavitt said in a statement on Friday.</p>

<p>At least some of the messages were distributed via the TextNow messaging service, which enables people to send texts via app, TextNow said. It said once they were made aware of the situation the account or accounts responsible were shut down within an hour, adding that the texts were sent across multiple carriers nationwide in what it called "an attack."</p>

<p>Some school districts issued warnings and urged students and parents to report any such texts to school staff or local authorities.</p>

<p>The run-up to Tuesday's election included the biggest rise in U.S. political violence since the 1970s, including some racist attacks on Harris supporters, according to cases identified by Reuters.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-12/5ku2mg0g_racismgeneric_625x300_22_December_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The FBI said in a statement it was "aware of the offensive and racist text messages".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/musks-spacex-working-on-starlink-equivalent-marslink-for-the-red-planet-6977373]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk's SpaceX Working On Starlink Equivalent 'Marslink' For Red Planet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/musks-spacex-working-on-starlink-equivalent-marslink-for-the-red-planet-6977373]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 07:42:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Musk took to X to confirm the development, adding that the ultimate goal was to increase the speed of data transfer across such vast distances.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk-owned SpaceX is working on a Starlink equivalent for Mars that will allow relatively quick communication to and fro from the Red Planet to Earth. The project was mentioned during Thursday's (Nov 7) meeting for the Mars Exploration Program Analysis Group (MEPAG), dedicated to supporting NASA missions to the Martian surface, according to the minutes of the meeting. Under the proposed pitch to NASA, SpaceX will place multiple satellites in Mars orbit to provide "full visibility and interoperability for the ground and orbital assets".</p>

<p>Starlink will leverage its advanced laser communication tech to maintain a constant data flow between planets. The high-speed data relay system will be capable of transmitting 4 MBPS or more, across 1.5 astronomical units which is the distance between Earth and Mars. This network could serve Mars missions, allowing real-time images and data streams from Mars to Earth, as well as supporting future ground operations and Mars orbit assets.</p>

<p>Musk took to X (formerly Twitter) to confirm the development, adding that the ultimate goal was to increase the speed of data transfer across such vast distances.</p>

<p>"This is just a very basic first step. Earth and Mars will ultimately need &gt;petabit/sec connectivity," Musk said on X (formerly Twitter).</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is just a very basic first step.<br />
<br />
Earth and Mars will ultimately need &gt;petabit/sec connectivity. <a href="https://t.co/FBXeDQeczZ">https://t.co/FBXeDQeczZ</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1854915519100707092?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-elon-musk-starlink-what-trumps-praise-for-musks-starlink-could-mean-for-internet-in-india-6962613" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Trump's Praise For Musk's Starlink: A Signal For India Telecom Giants</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>'Sci-fi concept'</strong></h3>

<p>Netizens, in awe of the sci-fi concept, applauded the move, while some cast doubts over the speed of the transfer which might be plagued by latency issues.</p>

<p>"Preparing internet access on Mars now before most people can even grasp the concept of traveling there is amazing. This is confidence in the future. I love this determination," said one user, while another added: "I have to admit this is pretty remarkable stuff."</p>

<p>A third added: "The latency of a ping though...that would still lead to one heck of a lag. Even if you put the game servers in the middle, on the best day, you're not going to do Diablo players from Mars and Earth in the same game."</p>

<p>Starlink has been a revolutionary piece of tech which allows users to access high-speed internet from any corner of the planet. Using thousands of satellites in the Low Earth Orbit (LEO), the internet data is beamed through radio signals.</p>

<p>This type of internet service does not require overhead or underground wires, making it accessible for users in precarious conditions. During Hurricane Helene that hit the US earlier this year, Starlink proved to be a lifesaver as those stranded in difficult situations managed to communicate via it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/ftj6snog_ukraine-starlink-reuters_625x300_09_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starlink allows users to access internet without using overhead or underground wires]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>