<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 10:27:57 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/documented-dreamers-children-of-indian-american-immigrants-face-deportation-as-time-runs-out-6189959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Children Of Indian-American Immigrants Face Deportation As Time Runs Out]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/documented-dreamers-children-of-indian-american-immigrants-face-deportation-as-time-runs-out-6189959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 10:09:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There does not seem to any light at the end of the tunnel for children of legal immigrants, a significantly large number of whom are Indian-Americans who came to the US as a young kid with their parents and now risk being deported back.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There does not seem to any light at the end of the tunnel for children of legal immigrants, a significantly large number of whom are Indian-Americans who came to the US as a young kid with their parents and now risk being deported back to the country where they don't know anyone because of them being aging out when they turn 21.</p>

<p>There are around 250,000 of such children of legal immigrants, a significantly large number of whom are Indians. The White House on Thursday blamed the Republicans for this legislative impasse.</p>

<p>"I talked about the bipartisan agreement that came together from the Senate where we negotiated a process to help the so-called documented Dreamers. And sadly, Republicans, and I've said this many times already at this podium today, which is that they voted it down twice. They voted it down twice,' White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre told reporters at her daily news conference.</p>

<p>Last month led by Senator Alex Padilla, Chair of the Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, and Border Safety, and Representative Deborah Ross, a bipartisan group of 43 lawmakers called on Biden Administration to take urgent action to protect the more than 250,000 Documented Dreamers - children of long-term visa holders - who are at risk of aging out of their dependent status and are forced to self-deport if they are ineligible for another status.</p>

<p>"These young people grow up in the United States, complete their education in the American school system, and graduate with degrees from American institutions," wrote the lawmakers. "However, due to the long green-card backlog, families with approved immigrant petitions are often stuck waiting decades for permanent resident status," they said in a letter to the Biden Administration on June 13.</p>

<p>Last month, Improve The Dream, an organization representing these children of legal immigrants, met with over 100 congressional offices and senior administration officials.</p>

<p>"It is disappointing to see the lack of action and associated proposed regulations deprioritized and delayed. It is time for action and I hope President Biden and the administration see the support from this bipartisan letter and show they care about one of the most bipartisan issues in Congress and rectify the mistakes of the past,' said Dip Patel, founder of Improve The Dream comments.</p>

<p>At the same time, he expressed gratitude for the bipartisan members of Congress leading in a letter asking for urgent administrative policy improvements and who continue to champion a permanent solution through Congress.</p>

<p>"I was forced to start visa-hopping to be able to stay in this country when I was 20 years old, right before I aged out, as a junior at the University of Minnesota - Duluth. I am about to turn 27 this August. Soon, if my time visa-hopping was personified, they would be older than I was when I first came to the United States," Jefrina, currently a graduate student pursuing my MBA at the Saint Mary's University of Minnesota told PTI.</p>

<p>She came to the US from India in 2005 at the age of 7. "I arrived under a dependent H-4 visa. My family applied for permanent residency in 2010 when I was 12 years old, and I unwittingly fell in love with this country. In the last 19 years, Minnesota has undoubtedly become my home," she said.</p>

<p>"My young adult life has been a series of temporary fixes to avoid self-deportation. I graduate from my Masters program in December, and I'm yet again at the crossroads of leaving my family, pets, friends, and a myriad of unquantifiable reasons I call Minnesota my home," Jefrina said.</p>

<p>Praneetha, a Cloud Engineer based in Texas, who came to the US with her family when she was 8 years old as a dependent on her parents' work visa, and after living in the US for more than 15 years, is left with no clear path toward permanent residency and has to hop from visa to visa in order to continue living and working in the country.</p>

<p>Roshan was forced to leave the US last month. He was working with- an American semiconductor manufacturing company. He came to the US with his Mom and brother at the age of 10 on an H4 visa- he grew up in Boston and graduated from Boston College in 2021 with a degree in Economics.</p>

<p>Roshan grew up in the US for almost 16 years but aged out in 2019. He had to leave the US in June without a clear path for returning, living, and working in the only country that he has truly called home.</p>

<p>Patel said every day without action results in young adults, who have been lawfully raised in the United States by skilled workers and small business owners, to be forced to leave the country, separating them from their families and stopping their ability to contribute to the country.</p>

<p>The administration has heard countless stories and examples of American-raised and educated STEM and health care talent (which comprises 87% of all impacted by aging-out, according to Improve The Dream's survey) contributing in other countries now due to barriers in our legal immigration system.</p>

<p>"Our country is not only losing young talent who were raised and educated here, but we're also losing many of their parents, who have years of practical experience as small business owners or in fields like medicine, engineering, and artificial intelligence. The economic case is clear and the moral case is clear. It is common sense," he said in response to a question.</p>

<p>"All major administrative actions have excluded this population from receiving benefit, despite the tools for such relief being available and being used for others. Until Congress can pass the bipartisan America's Children Act, we need urgent action by the administration to prioritize this issue, which has bipartisan support from Congress and the general public, and clear economic benefit," Patel told Press Trust of India.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-04/us-visa-us-immigration-istock_650x400_41524626692.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[No light at the end of the tunnel for children of legal immigrants in the United States.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wealth-of-worlds-top-1-grew-by-42-trillion-over-the-past-decade-oxfam-6198897]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Wealth Of World's Top 1% Grew By $42 Trillion Over The Past Decade: Oxfam]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wealth-of-worlds-top-1-grew-by-42-trillion-over-the-past-decade-oxfam-6198897]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 09:37:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world's richest one per cent increased their fortune by $42 trillion over the past decade, which is nearly 34 times more than the entire bottom 50 per cent of the world's population, according to a new analysis by Oxfam.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world's richest one per cent increased their fortune by $42 trillion over the past decade, which is nearly 34 times more than the entire bottom 50 per cent of the world's population, according to a new analysis by Oxfam. The organisation released the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.oxfam.org/en/press-releases/top-1-percent-bags-over-40-trillion-new-wealth-during-past-decade-taxes-rich-reach">new report </a>ahead of the third meeting of G20 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors in Brazil. It said that the average net worth of the elite jumped by nearly $400,000 per person, after adjusting for inflation, compared to $335 for the bottom half of residents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Inequality has reached obscene levels, and until now governments have failed to protect people and planet from its catastrophic effects," said Oxfam International's Head of Inequality Policy, Max Lawson. "The richest one percent of humanity continues to fill their pockets while the rest are left to scrap for crumbs," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Oxfam's research also found that the share of income of the top 1 per cent of earners in G20 countries has risen by 45 per cent over four decades while top tax rates on their incomes were cut by roughly a third.</p>

<p>"Globally, billionaires have been paying a tax rate equivalent to less than 0.5 percent of their wealth. Their fortunes has risen by an annual average of 7.1 percent over the last four decades, and an annual net wealth tax of at least 8 percent would be needed to reduce billionaires' extreme wealth. G20 countries are home to nearly four out of five of the world's billionaires," the report read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The latest analysis comes as the advocacy group, along with several partners, is calling on G20 leaders to hike taxes on the ultra-rich.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-disowned-by-transgender-daughter-hes-desperate-for-attention-6193039">Elon Musk Disowned By Transgender Daughter: "He's Desperate For Attention"</a></strong></p>

<p>As part of its G20 presidency, the Brazilian government recently also commissioned a study on raising taxes on the wealthy. It found that a 2 per cent minimum tax on global billionaires' wealth would yield between $200 billion and $250 billion from about 3,000 taxpayers annually.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Momentum to increase taxes on the super-rich is undeniable, and this week is the first real litmus test for G20 governments. Do they have the political will to strike a global standard that puts the needs of the many before the greed of an elite few?" Mr Lawson said.</p>

<p>Notably, Oxfam regularly issues reports highlighting global inequality and pushes for changes to start evening the playing field.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/djqnh78g_dollar-generic-unsplash_625x300_22_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Average net worth of the elite jumped by nearly $400,000 per person, per the report.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-vs-kamala-harris-jd-vance-defends-childless-cat-ladies-remark-amid-huge-backlash-6198858]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Running Mate On Why He Called Kamala Harris "Childless Cat Lady"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-vs-kamala-harris-jd-vance-defends-childless-cat-ladies-remark-amid-huge-backlash-6198858]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 09:27:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[JD Vance, former US President Donald Trump's running mate, has defended his 2021 remarks where he referred to Democratic politicians as a "bunch of childless cat ladies with miserable lives".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>JD Vance, former US President Donald Trump's running mate, has defended his 2021 remarks where he referred to Democratic politicians as a "bunch of childless cat ladies with miserable lives".</p>

<p>JD Vance, who appeared on The Megyn Kelly Show on Friday, said "Obviously, it was a sarcastic comment. I've got nothing against cats. People are focusing so much on the sarcasm and not on the substance of what I actually said."</p>

<p>"The simple point that I made is that having children, becoming a father, becoming a mother, I really do think it changes your perspective in a pretty profound way," he told The Megyn Kelly Show.</p>

<p>"This is not about criticizing people who for various reasons don't have kids. This is about criticizing the Democratic party for becoming anti-family and anti-child," he said.</p>

<p>JD Vance had singled out Kamala Harris, now the Democratic Presidential nominee, among others during a 2021 interview and said those without offspring, especially "childless cat ladies", had no "direct stake" in the country.</p>

<p>Speaking to Tucker Carlson on Fox News, he had said the US was being run by "a bunch of childless cat ladies who are miserable at their own lives and the choices that they've made and so they want to make the rest of the country miserable, too."</p>

<p>Vance's comments have drawn sexism charges ahead of the US Presidential elections that the Republicans were touted to win until President Joe Biden bowed out from the race.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris's lack of biological children has been regarded as an issue by the Republicans, but she has received support from politicians, celebrities, and from her own family. Her supporters also pointed out that no US president has ever physically given birth, since all have been men.</p>

<p>Kerstin Emhoff, the mother of Harris' stepchildren, has slammed the attacks on the Vice President as "baseless" in a statement to CNN.</p>

<p>"For over 10 years, since Cole and Ella were teenagers, Kamala has been a co-parent with Doug and I. I love our blended family and am grateful to have her in it," she said.</p>

<p>Vance, 39, was tapped by Trump days after a failed assassination attempt on the former president upended what had already been a chaotic presidential contest.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/env6pf5g_jd-vance_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance's comments have drawn sexism charges]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/180-000-gazans-displaced-in-4-days-as-israeli-aggression-continues-6198554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[180,000 Gazans Displaced In 4 Days As Israeli Aggression Continues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/180-000-gazans-displaced-in-4-days-as-israeli-aggression-continues-6198554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 07:56:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 180,000 Palestinians have fled fierce fighting around the southern Gaza city of Khan Yunis in four days, the United Nations said Friday, after an Israeli operation to extract captives' bodies from the area.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 180,000 Palestinians have fled fierce fighting around the southern Gaza city of Khan Yunis in four days, the United Nations said Friday, after an Israeli operation to extract captives' bodies from the area.</p>

<p>Recent "intensified hostilities" in the Khan Yunis area, more than nine months into the Israel-Hamas war, have fuelled "new waves of internal displacement across Gaza", said the UN humanitarian agency, OCHA.</p>

<p>It said "about 182,000 people" have been displaced from central and eastern Khan Yunis between Monday and Thursday, and hundreds are "stranded in eastern Khan Yunis".</p>

<p>The Israeli military on Monday ordered the evacuation of parts of the southern city, announcing its forces would "forcefully operate" there, including in an area previously declared a safe humanitarian zone.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Israel said five bodies of captives seized during Hamas's October 7 attack that triggered the war had been recovered from the area.</p>

<p>Israel's military said on Friday that its forces had "eliminated approximately 100 terrorists" in the city this week.</p>

<p>Israel's military chief, Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi said the captives' bodies were pulled from underground tunnels and walls in "a hidden place".</p>

<p>Troops "were near those fallen bodies in the past, we did not know how to reach them" until this week, Halevi said in a statement.</p>

<p>Witnesses and rescuers said heavy battles continued around eastern Khan Yunis on Friday. The Nasser Hospital said 26 bodies were brought to the medical site.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack on southern Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Out of 251 people taken hostage that day, 111 are still held in the Gaza Strip, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive against Hamas has killed at least 39,175 Palestinians in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>According to UN figures, the vast majority of Gaza's 2.4 million people have been displaced at least once by the fighting.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mcg97b3_khan-yunis_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military on Monday ordered the evacuation of parts of the southern city.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-confirms-donald-trump-was-hit-by-bullet-in-assassination-attempt-6198413]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Confirms Donald Trump Was Hit By Bullet In Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-confirms-donald-trump-was-hit-by-bullet-in-assassination-attempt-6198413]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 07:08:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump was indeed hit by an assassin's bullet or a fragment of one, the Federal Bureau of Investigation said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump was indeed hit by an assassin's bullet or a fragment of one, the Federal Bureau of Investigation said Friday, putting to rest questions over the nature of the Republican candidate's wounding at a campaign rally this month.</p>

<p>"What struck former President Trump in the ear was a bullet, whether whole or fragmented into smaller pieces, fired from the deceased subject's rifle," the FBI said in a statement.</p>

<p>Trump's right ear was covered in blood on July 13 after he was injured during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The FBI deemed the assault -- in which a gunman fired eight bullets from outside the event's security perimeter -- an assassination attempt.</p>

<p>But FBI chief Christopher Wray told US lawmakers on Wednesday that there was some doubt as to "whether or not it's a bullet or shrapnel that, you know, that hit his ear."</p>

<p>Following the new statement from the FBI -- which Trump has long alleged is part of a "deep state" conspiring against him -- the Republican posted on his Truth Social platform: "I assume that's the best apology that we'll get from Director Wray, but it is fully accepted!"</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, he posted a letter from his former White House doctor saying the wound was almost certainly due to a bullet.</p>

<p>"There is absolutely no evidence that it was anything other than a bullet," wrote Ronny Jackson, now a Republican congressman from Texas, on Truth Social.</p>

<p>Two rally attendees were seriously wounded in the attack, and a 50-year-old Pennsylvania firefighter was shot dead, according to officials. The gunman was killed by a US Secret Service sniper.</p>

<p>Since the shooting, Trump has made the attack a key part of his campaign pitch, telling a crowd in Michigan that he "took a bullet for democracy."</p>

<p>At the Republican National Convention where he was anointed the party's nominee for president, Trump said he had "God on my side" as he described the attack.</p>

<p>And at Trump rallies, many of the former president's supporters have taken to wearing bandages on their right ears, a reference to the attack.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Trump had also denied Wray's comments and accused him of political partisanship.</p>

<p>"It was, unfortunately, a bullet that hit my ear, and hit it hard. There was no glass, there was no shrapnel," he said.</p>

<p>A New York Times investigation published Friday said "a detailed analysis of bullet trajectories, footage, photos and audio... strongly suggests Mr Trump was grazed by the first of eight bullets fired by the gunman."</p>

<p>Trump's campaign has not released any medical reports or statements from his current physician, instead quoting Jackson -- a former White House physician who is a staunch political ally of the ex-president.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump's right ear was covered in blood on July 13.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/karachi-this-pakistani-city-is-ranked-second-riskiest-for-tourists-report-6197683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Pakistani City Is Ranked Second-Riskiest For Tourists]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/karachi-this-pakistani-city-is-ranked-second-riskiest-for-tourists-report-6197683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 02:46:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Karachi has been ranked as the second-riskiest city for tourists, with a rating of 93.12 out of 100, according to a July 11 Forbes Adviser list, reported Dawn.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Karachi has been ranked as the second-riskiest city for tourists, with a rating of 93.12 out of 100, according to a July 11 Forbes Adviser list, reported Dawn.</p>

<p>The July 11 Forbes Adviser list of three of the riskiest cities highlighted that Karachi was second just behind Venezuela's Caracas, which had a score of 100, while Myanmar's Yangon ranked third with a score of 91.67 out of 100.</p>

<p>According to the ranking, the city had the highest personal security risk, reflecting risk from crime, violence, terrorist threats, natural disasters, and economic vulnerabilities.</p>

<p>It added that Karachi had the second-worst (level 3, reconsider travel) travel safety rating from the US State Department, as reported by Dawn.</p>

<p>Moreover, Karachi has the fourth-highest infrastructure security risk, reflecting the availability and quality of city infrastructure, according to the report.</p>

<p>To uncover the most and least risky cities for tourists, Forbes Adviser said that it compared 60 international cities across seven key metrics.</p>

<p>Notably, Karachi has repeatedly appeared on lists of "unlivable" cities.</p>

<p>Earlier in 2017, the city was named among the least safe cities in the world by the Economist Intelligence Unit, according to Dawn.</p>

<p>The research and analysis division of the Economist Group ranked Karachi among the top five "least livable" urban centres in the world.</p>

<p>Earlier on Thursday, five people died after two groups exchanged fire at each other in Karachi's defence area in Pakistan, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>DIG South Asad Raza confirmed that a total of five individuals lost their lives while two others got injured after an exchange of fire between two groups in Karachi's Defence Nishat Commercial area.</p>

<p>Moreover, eyewitnesses to the incident reported that several people were injured during the violent altercation, and vehicles belonging to both groups involved in the incident were also seen at the scene.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/fva5rje_karachi-generic-getty_625x300_27_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Karachi also has the fourth-highest infrastructure security risk (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-takes-action-against-france-5-nations-over-budget-rule-violation-6196912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EU Takes Action Against France, 5 Nations Over Budget Rule Violation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-takes-action-against-france-5-nations-over-budget-rule-violation-6196912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 23:10:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France, Italy and five other EU countries were placed in a formal procedure on Friday for violating the bloc's budget rules, a step that could lead to unprecedented penalties unless they take corrective measures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>France, Italy and five other EU countries were placed in a formal procedure on Friday for violating the bloc's budget rules, a step that could lead to unprecedented penalties unless they take corrective measures.</p>

<p>"Today the Council adopted decisions establishing the existence of excessive deficits for Belgium, France, Italy, Hungary, Malta, Poland and Slovakia," the body representing the 27 member states said.</p>

<p>Known as an "excessive deficit procedure", it kickstarts a process forcing a country to negotiate a plan with Brussels to get their debt or deficit levels back on track.</p>

<p>The seven countries had deficits -- the gap between government revenue and spending -- above three percent of gross domestic product, in violation of the bloc's fiscal rules.</p>

<p>France's deficit reached 5.5 percent in 2023, but it appears that bringing it down would be difficult because of political uncertainty following the results of a snap election that was won by a leftwing coalition demanding much higher public spending.</p>

<p>The EU countries with the highest deficit-to-GDP ratios last year were Italy (7.4 percent), Hungary (6.7 percent), Romania (6.6 percent) and Poland (5.1 percent).</p>

<p>The council also said Romania had "not taken effective action" against its excessive deficit, despite having a procedure opened against it in 2020 and would therefore be kept under watch.</p>

<p>As a next step, the countries will have to send medium-term plans by September about how they will rectify the breach.</p>

<p>Then the European Commission in November will deliver assessments of the plans with details on the route they must take to return to fiscal health.</p>

<p>This is the first time Brussels is rebuking EU states since the bloc suspended the rules after the 2020 coronavirus pandemic and the energy crisis triggered by Russia's war on Ukraine, as states propped up businesses and households with public money.</p>

<p>The EU spent two years during the suspension to reform the budget rules to give greater leeway for investment in critical areas like defence.</p>

<p>But two sacred objectives remain: a state's debt must not go higher than 60 percent of national output, with a public deficit of no more than three percent.</p>

<p>Countries failing to remedy the situation can in theory be hit with fines of 0.1 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) per year, until action is taken to address the violation.</p>

<p>In practice, though, the commission has never gone as far as levying fines, fearing it could trigger unintended political consequences and hurt a state's economy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/6op53pqo_european-union-generic_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The EU spent two years during the suspension to reform the budget rules. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-working-hard-to-reverse-terribly-low-birth-rate-says-kremlin-6196861]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Working Hard To Reverse "Terribly Low" Birth Rate, Says Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-working-hard-to-reverse-terribly-low-birth-rate-says-kremlin-6196861]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 23:04:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin said Friday that it was "working hard" to reverse declining birth rates in Russia, warning that "disastrous" demographic trends were putting the country's future at risk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin said Friday that it was "working hard" to reverse declining birth rates in Russia, warning that "disastrous" demographic trends were putting the country's future at risk.</p>

<p>Russia has faced a myriad of demographic challenges since the collapse of the USSR, including an ageing population, an outflow of men due to the conflict in Ukraine and the lowest fertility rate in 17 years.</p>

<p>"It is now at a terribly low level -- 1.4 (births per woman). This is comparable to European countries, Japan and so on. But this is disastrous for the future of the nation," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told a media festival.</p>

<p>"Anyone with many children is a hero. We live in the largest country in the world. And there are fewer of us every year. And the only way to cope with this is to increase the average birth rate," Peskov said.</p>

<p>Russia had a population of about 148 million people at the breakup of the Soviet Union in 1991, a figure that now stands at around 144 million after a protracted period of high deaths and low births in the 1990s.</p>

<p>The country's birth rate has not recovered since Soviet times despite President Vladimir Putin's government offering generous payouts and mortgage subsidies to large families.</p>

<p>Recent problems include large numbers of Covid deaths, hundreds of thousands of men fleeing the country to avoid being mobilised to fight in Ukraine, and migration into Russia hitting a ten-year low in 2023.</p>

<p>Russia's population could drop to 130 million by the 2040s, demographers have forecasted.</p>

<p>When asked whether young families could still have faith in the future, the Kremlin pointed to similar demographics in other countries.</p>

<p>"This is unfortunately a trend," Peskov said.</p>

<p>"The situation will remain difficult for some period of time, but the government is working hard on this issue, and it is one of the top priorities of the President of Russia," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/8206hht8_dmitry-peskov-reuters_625x300_03_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Anyone with many children is a hero," said Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-preparing-for-decisive-offensive-against-hezbollah-6196815]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Preparing For "Decisive Offensive" Against Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-preparing-for-decisive-offensive-against-hezbollah-6196815]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:56:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli military commander said Friday that troops in the country's north were preparing for "a decisive offensive" against Lebanon's Hezbollah after months of deadly cross-border exchanges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli military commander said Friday that troops in the country's north were preparing for "a decisive offensive" against Lebanon's Hezbollah after months of deadly cross-border exchanges.</p>

<p>Israeli forces have traded near-daily fire with Hamas ally Hezbollah since the Palestinian group's October 7 attack on southern Israel started the ongoing war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Major General Ori Gordin, Israel's commanding officer in the north, told troops that "we have already eliminated more than 500 terrorists in Lebanon, the great majority of them from Hezbollah", an army statement said.</p>

<p>According to an AFP tally, more than nine months of violence have killed at least 523 people in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Most of them, 342 people, have been confirmed to be Hezbollah operatives but the tally also includes 104 civilians. Gordin did not mention civilian casualties.</p>

<p>In northern Israel, at least 18 Israeli soldiers and 13 civilians have been killed, according to the military.</p>

<p>The exchanges of fire have been largely restricted to the border areas and displaced tens of thousands of Lebanese as well as Israeli residents.</p>

<p>The Israeli military has "destroyed thousands" of targets across the border, Gordin said.</p>

<p>The statement said troops were now preparing "for the transition to offence".</p>

<p>"When the moment comes and we go on the offensive, it will be a decisive offensive," Gordin added.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah says it is acting in support of Hamas with its attacks on Israel since October 8.</p>

<p>The escalating violence and unsuccessful mediation efforts have raised fears of all-out conflict between Israel and Hezbollah, which last went to war in 2006.</p>

<p>Israel has demanded that parts of southern Lebanon be cleared of Hezbollah operatives in line with a UN Security Council resolution that ended the 2006 war.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2225v5kg_israel-army_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah says it is acting in support of Hamas with its attacks on Israel since October 8. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-national-duped-on-promise-of-job-returns-from-saudi-says-embassy-6196705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Duped On Promise Of Job Returns From Saudi, Says Embassy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-national-duped-on-promise-of-job-returns-from-saudi-says-embassy-6196705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:35:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian Embassy in Saudi Arabia on Friday confirmed the return of an Indian national who was stranded in the Gulf nation after being duped by an agent who had promised getting him a job in Qatar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Embassy in Saudi Arabia on Friday confirmed the return of an Indian national who was stranded in the Gulf nation after being duped by an agent who had promised getting him a job in Qatar.</p>

<p>Mr Kumar, a resident of Andhra Pradesh, was allegedly cheated by a job agent who had promised him a job in Qatar but sent him to Saudi Arabia, Khaleej Times reported.</p>

<p>The Indian Embassy also thanked the community volunteers who worked with the Embassy to ensure Mr Kumar's safe return to India.</p>

<p>"Few days back, plight of an Indian National, Mr Veerendra Kumar was brought to the attention of the Embassy. We are happy to announce that he has safely returned to now. We wish to thank all the community volunteers who worked with the Embassy to ensure his safe return to India," the Indian Embassy stated on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Few days back, plight of an Indian National, Mr Veerendra Kumar was brought to the attention of the Embassy. We are happy to announce that he has safely returned to ?? now. We wish to thank all the community volunteers who worked with the Embassy to ensure his safe return to ??. <a href="https://t.co/pMEJTTXZPq">pic.twitter.com/pMEJTTXZPq</a></p>
— India in Saudi Arabia (@IndianEmbRiyadh) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndianEmbRiyadh/status/1816776727533670566?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Earlier, after the video of Veerandra Kumar pleading for help surfaced, Telugu Desam Party leader Nara Lokesh assured that he would work for his return to India.</p>

<p>"Veerendra, we will bring you back home safely! Don't worry!" he said in a post on X on July 19.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Veerendra, we will bring you back home safely! Don't worry! <a href="https://t.co/GKk9j4n64R">https://t.co/GKk9j4n64R</a></p>
— Lokesh Nara (@naralokesh) <a href="https://twitter.com/naralokesh/status/1814359817592680966?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Veerendra Kumar said he was cheated by a job agent who had promised him a job in Qatar but sent him to Saudi Arabia where he was asked to work as a herder in the desert.</p>

<p>He reached the international airport in Hyderabad on Friday where his family was waiting for him, Khaleej Times reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jj8trt5_indian-national-duped-saudi_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Veerendra Kumar said he was cheated by a job agent who had promised him a job in Qatar]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexican-drug-lord-ismael-el-mayo-zambada-pleads-not-guilty-to-us-charges-6196641]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexican Drug Lord Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada Pleads Not Guilty To US Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexican-drug-lord-ismael-el-mayo-zambada-pleads-not-guilty-to-us-charges-6196641]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:25:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alleged Mexican kingpin Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada has pleaded not guilty to U.S. drug trafficking charges, court records showed on Friday, after he and a son of another drug lord were arrested on Thursday in El Paso, Texas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alleged Mexican kingpin Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada has pleaded not guilty to U.S. drug trafficking charges, court records showed on Friday, after he and a son of another drug lord were arrested on Thursday in El Paso, Texas.</p>

<p>Court records showed that Zambada on Friday waived his right to appear personally in court and directed that a not guilty plea be entered on his behalf.</p>

<p>He was ordered detained without bond and is scheduled to be arraigned before U.S. Magistrate Judge Anne Berton next Wednesday, the records showed. His lawyer did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Both Zambada and Joaquin Guzman Lopez, a son of Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman, face multiple charges in the U.S. for funneling huge quantities of fentanyl and other drugs to U.S. streets.</p>

<p>Their detentions were a dramatic achievement for U.S. law enforcement that could also shake up the Mexican drug landscape.</p>

<p>Mexico's government was informed of the detentions by the U.S. government, but Mexican authorities did not participate in the operation, Mexican Security Minister Rosa Rodriguez said on Friday.</p>

<p>Rodriguez added that it was unclear if Zambada and Guzman Lopez handed themselves over to U.S. authorities voluntarily.</p>

<p>"The Mexican government did not participate in this detention or surrender," Rodriguez said at a press conference.</p>

<p>Zambada, who is believed to be in his 70s, and Guzman Lopez, who is in his 30s, were detained after landing in a private plane in the El Paso area.</p>

<p>Zambada co-founded the Sinaloa Cartel with El Chapo, who was extradited to the U.S. in 2017 and is serving a life sentence in a maximum-security prison.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/uc77cd78_ismael-el-mayo-zambada_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zambada co-founded the Sinaloa Cartel with El Chapo. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-netanyahu-meets-donald-trump-for-talks-seeking-to-ease-tensions-6196582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli PM Netanyahu Meets Donald Trump For Talks Seeking To Ease Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-netanyahu-meets-donald-trump-for-talks-seeking-to-ease-tensions-6196582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:16:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu visited former U.S. President Donald Trump at Trump's Florida resort on Friday for a meeting that could ease tensions between two leaders who forged a close alliance during Trump's years in the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu visited former U.S. President Donald Trump at Trump's Florida resort on Friday for a meeting that could ease tensions between two leaders who forged a close alliance during Trump's years in the White House.</p>

<p>Netanyahu met Trump, the Republican nominee in the 2024 U.S. presidential race, a day after Netanyahu met Democratic President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris, who is running against Trump in the Nov. 5 U.S. election.</p>

<p>The longtime Israeli leader rearranged his US travel schedule to meet Trump. He landed in Palm Beach early on Friday.</p>

<p>Opinion polls put Harris and Trump in a close race for the White House, prompting world leaders like Netanyahu, traditionally more aligned with Trump's Republicans than Biden's Democrats, to strike a balance in dealings with the U.S.</p>

<p>Nine months into an Israeli offensive in Gaza, Harris pressed Netanyahu on the suffering of Palestinians in the enclave in talks that were watched for signs of how she might shift American policy if she becomes president.</p>

<p>"I made clear my serious concern about the dire humanitarian situation there," Harris said on Thursday after the meeting. "I will not be silent."</p>

<p>"Israel has a right to defend itself. And how it does so matters," she said.</p>

<p>Israeli officials criticized Harris for saying it was time for the war to end.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News on Thursday, Trump called for a quick end to the war and a return of the hostages Hamas holds in Gaza, adding that Israel has to better manage its "public relations."</p>

<p>"I want him (Netanyahu) to finish up and get it done quickly," Trump said. "They are getting decimated with this publicity."</p>

<p>Trump also criticized those who protested a speech Netanyahu gave to the U.S. Congress on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Dozens of Democrats boycotted the speech, voicing dismay over the thousands of civilian deaths in Gaza and the displacement of most of its 2.3 million people.</p>

<p><strong>NETANYAHU, TRUMP LOOK TO EASE TENSIONS</strong></p>

<p>The meeting between Trump and Netanyahu signaled that both were looking to ease tensions.</p>

<p>The Israeli leader angered Trump when he congratulated Biden on his victory over Trump in the 2020 election. Trump has falsely claimed the election was stolen from him by voter fraud.</p>

<p>Trump more recently criticized Netanyahu for Israeli security failures around the Oct. 7 Hamas attack on Israel that triggered the Israeli offensive in Gaza.</p>

<p>Hamas and its allies killed 1,200 people and took 250 hostage, according to Israeli tallies. Some 120 hostages are still being held though Israel believes one in three are dead.</p>

<p>In defiant remarks to Congress on Wednesday, Netanyahu defended Israel's military and dismissed criticism of a campaign which has devastated Gaza and killed more than 39,000 people, according to health officials in the Hamas-ruled enclave.</p>

<p>Israeli officials estimate that some 14,000 fighters from&nbsp; groups including Hamas and Islamic Jihad have been killed or taken prisoner out of a force they estimated to number more than 25,000 at the start of the war.</p>

<p>In Wednesday's speech, Netanyahu praised Biden's support for Israel.</p>

<p>But to cheers from Republicans, he touched on Trump's pro-Israel record as president. He praised Trump's decision to move the U.S. embassy from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem, a long-held goal of conservatives that infuriated Palestinians.</p>

<p>He also cited the Abraham Accords, landmark U.S.-brokered agreements signed during Trump's White House years that normalized bilateral relations between Israel and both Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p>Palm Beach County Sheriff Ric Bradshaw encouraged peaceful protests but said he did not expect demonstrations on the scale of what happened during Netanyahu's speech in Washington when thousands of activists marched - vandalizing some landmarks and confronting police - to protest the war in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/has938mg_donald-trump-netanyahu_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump recently criticized Netanyahu for Israeli security failures around the Oct. 7 Hamas attack.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/court-convicts-man-after-woman-dies-at-slapping-therapy-workshop-in-uk-6196448]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Court Convicts Man After Woman Dies At "Slapping Therapy" Workshop In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/court-convicts-man-after-woman-dies-at-slapping-therapy-workshop-in-uk-6196448]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 21:53:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An alternative healer was on Friday found guilty of the manslaughter by gross negligence of a diabetic woman who died from medical complications at a "slapping therapy" workshop in the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An alternative healer was on Friday found guilty of the manslaughter by gross negligence of a diabetic woman who died from medical complications at a "slapping therapy" workshop in the UK.</p>

<p>Hongchi Xiao, 60, from Cloudbreak, California, was convicted following a trial at a court in Winchester, southern England.</p>

<p>He was charged in November following the death of Danielle Carr-Gomm, 71, who was taking part in a session at a hotel to help her diabetes in October 2016.</p>

<p>The pensioner died at a "paida lajin" workshop, which involves patients being slapped or slapping themselves repeatedly.</p>

<p>Prosecutors told the court the alternative healer breached his duty of care towards Carr-Gomm by failing to take reasonable steps to ensure medical assistance when she was suffering from a "medical crisis", namely ketoacidosis.</p>

<p>Diabetic ketoacidosis is a serious condition that can happen in people with diabetes due to a lack of insulin and requires urgent medical treatment.</p>

<p>Xiao, who was born in China, was extradited to the UK from Australia.</p>

<p>Carr-Gomm, who was described by her family as an avid follower of holistic medicine and alternative therapies, was born in France and moved to the UK at the age of 21.</p>

<p>She was diagnosed with diabetes in 1999 but struggled to inject insulin because of a fear of needles.</p>

<p>The head of the Crown Prosecution's special crime division, Rosemary Ainslie, said: "Hongchi Xiao knew the consequences of Danielle Carr-Gomm's decision to stop taking insulin could be fatal, he had seen it before.</p>

<p>"Hongchi Xiao was the man in charge, yet he failed to respond to Mrs Carr-Gomm's worsening condition with tragic consequences.</p>

<p>"His failure to take reasonable steps to help Mrs Carr-Gomm substantially contributed to her death and amounted to gross negligence."</p>

<p>Xiao will be sentenced on October 1.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/gs634ql8_hongchi-xiao_625x300_03_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Xiao, who was born in China, was extradited to the UK from Australia. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-charged-after-he-deliberately-forces-train-to-crash-for-a-youtube-video-6195841]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Teen Charged After He Deliberately Forces Train To Crash For A Video]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-charged-after-he-deliberately-forces-train-to-crash-for-a-youtube-video-6195841]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to court documents, the Nebraska teen allegedly caused the train to go off the tracks, recorded the incident, and shared the footage on YouTube.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 17-year-old teenager in the US has been accused of deliberately causing a train derailment to record it and post it on YouTube. According to court documents, the Nebraska teen allegedly caused the train to go off the tracks, recorded the incident, and shared the footage on YouTube, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/07/25/teen-train-crash-derailment-record-youtube-video-nebraska-21299670/">Metro</a></em> reported.</p>

<p>The incident happened in April this year when the teen allegedly tampered with a rail switch, causing two locomotives and five fully loaded coal trains to veer off the tracks and crash into an empty coal car. He then alerted authorities to the derailment and asked the investigator who arrived what caused the crash. He told the investigator he was a train enthusiast and showed him the video he had shot of the derailment.</p>

<p>When authorities said they did not know the cause of the derailment, the boy said, ''Obviously a switch was flipped the wrong way.''</p>

<p>An investigator with BNSF Railway found that a padlock supposed to be attached to the switch was missing, indicating tampering. Three days later,&nbsp;a BNSF investigator obtained CCTV footage showing a 1996 Buick Park Avenue in the vicinity, with the same teenager walking towards the switch at the south end of the tracks. According to the affidavit, the teen was later recorded returning to his vehicle.</p>

<p>A <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q97XRpF6SZA">video of the derailment was posted on a YouTube account</a> believed to be linked to the teen, an investigator said. Authorities also discovered that a tripod had been set up near the accident site just four minutes before the train derailed. The derailment caused $350,000 in damages to BNSF Railway and the Omaha Public Power District, as per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/teen-accused-derailing-train-recording-crash-posting-online-rcna163686">NBC News.&nbsp;</a></em></p>

<p>The 17-year-old was charged in Lancaster County Juvenile Court on Wednesday, but prosecutors have requested that the case be moved to adult court. He faces two felony charges of criminal mischief in connection with a train derailment.</p>

<p>''My office will file a motion to transfer the case to adult court and it will be up to the juvenile court Judge to transfer the case or have it remain in juvenile court,'' Lancaster County Attorney Patrick Condon told <em>McClatchy News.</em></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8tlh7drg_train_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The derailment caused $350,000 in damages to BNSF Railway and the Omaha Public Power District]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-railway-attacks-force-new-uk-pm-to-change-olympics-travel-plan-6195791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Railway Attacks Force New UK PM To Change Olympics Travel Plan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-railway-attacks-force-new-uk-pm-to-change-olympics-travel-plan-6195791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:17:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Keir Starmer changed his travel plans to get to the Olympics on Friday after Eurostar trains were disrupted due to sabotage attacks against French rail networks, Downing Street said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer changed his travel plans to get to the Olympics on Friday after Eurostar trains were disrupted due to sabotage attacks against French rail networks, Downing Street said.</p>

<p>Starmer was meant to be travelling on the cross-Channel rail service from London to Paris for the Olympics opening ceremony, in his first visit to France since being elected earlier this month.</p>

<p>But a spokeswoman said he flew instead due to the delays and cancellations.</p>

<p>France is welcoming dozens of heads of state and government and royalty for the Olympics that begin with a dazzling ceremony on the river Seine on Friday.</p>

<p>Just hours before the ceremony, arson attacks threw France's high-speed rail network into chaos affecting tens of thousands of passengers, in what officials called premeditated acts of "sabotage".</p>

<p>One in four Eurostar trains were cancelled, the company said, with the disruption set to continue over the weekend.</p>

<p>Beyond the cancellations, Eurostar trains departing and arriving in Paris will run on regular lines rather than high-speed routes.</p>

<p>That would add an extra 90 minutes onto a Paris-London trip that usually takes around two hours and 20 minutes, Eurostar said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g6af87ko_keir-starmer-afp-_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[France is welcoming dozens of heads of state and government and royalty for the Olympics. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boop-the-ick-chefs-kiss-new-additions-to-cambridge-dictionary-6195543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Boop', 'The Ick', 'Chef's Kiss' New Additions To Cambridge Dictionary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boop-the-ick-chefs-kiss-new-additions-to-cambridge-dictionary-6195543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:46:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A few other quirky additions include IYKYK, which is the written abbreviation for "if you know you know".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Informal words used as slang, such as 'boop' and 'the ick', are among more than 3,200 new words and phrases added to the Cambridge Dictionary in its latest update this week.</p>

<p>'Boop', which is defined as "a gentle hit or touch on a person's or animal's nose or head, showing that you like them or as a "joke", and 'the ick', which refers to "a sudden feeling that you dislike someone or something or are no longer attracted to someone because of something they do", are among the slangs to make it to the online edition for 2024 so far.</p>

<p>'Chef's kiss', or a movement in which you put your fingers and thumb together, kiss them, then pull your hand away from your lips as a way of showing that you think that something or someone is perfect or excellent, is another such informal phrase that has been recognised formally.</p>

<p>"Language is always changing, and this means that the 'Cambridge Dictionary' team stays busy researching new words and meanings that enter the English language," the dictionary said in a statement on Thursday.</p>

<p>"Many new additions come from the fields of science and technology, including 'scicomm' - the activity of explaining scientific work and information to people who are not scientists, or articles, talks, etc. that do this, and deep-sky - existing in or relating to the part of space outside the solar system," it said.</p>

<p>A few other quirky additions include IYKYK, which is the written abbreviation for "if you know you know". It is used mostly on social media and in text messages to imply a shared joke or shared knowledge with the reader that other people might not understand.</p>

<p>The noun "face journey" has been added to refer to "a series of expressions that appear on someone's face showing different emotions that they are experiencing as a reaction to something".</p>

<p>Cambridge Dictionary said its team records how English is actually used by real people and uses the Cambridge English Corpus, a huge collection of written and spoken English, to gather evidence for how a new word is used by different people and in a variety of situations.</p>

<p>"We also collect evidence of new words that have only appeared in English very recently. We feature three of these on our weekly About Words blog, where readers can vote on which words they think should be added to the dictionary," it explained, with reference the process behind adding on new terms.</p>

<p>Online gaming also inspired several new entries, such as 'backread' - to read through a series of messages or internet posts that you did not see when they were first created, often starting with the most recent, in order to learn what happened or was discussed earlier; 'speedrun' - to complete a computer game, or part of a computer game, as quickly as possible, especially by taking advantage of any glitches; and 'side quest' - a part of a computer game that has its own aim and story but is not part of the main game.</p>

<p>New additions from the world of music include 'soca' or a type of music that is a mixture of soul and calypso, originally from the Caribbean, and 'jug band' which refers to a small group of performers who play jazz, blues, or folk music on very simple musical instruments, especially using objects such as empty jugs as instruments.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-12/dictionary-generic_650x400_61449816760.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Online gaming also inspired several new entries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-should-we-go-gazans-forced-to-shelter-in-former-prison-amid-war-6195540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Where Should We Go": Gazans Forced To Shelter In Former Prison Amid War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-should-we-go-gazans-forced-to-shelter-in-former-prison-amid-war-6195540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:45:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After weeks of Israeli bombardment left them with nowhere else to go, hundreds of Palestinians have ended up in a former Gaza prison built to hold murderers and thieves.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After weeks of Israeli bombardment left them with nowhere else to go, hundreds of Palestinians have ended up in a former Gaza prison built to hold murderers and thieves.</p>

<p>Yasmeen al-Dardasi said she and her family passed wounded people they were unable to help as they evacuated from a district in the southern city of Khan Younis towards its Central Correction and Rehabilitation Facility.</p>

<p>They spent a day under a tree before moving on to the former prison, where they now live in a prayer room. It offers protection from the blistering sun, but not much else.</p>

<p>Dardasi's husband has a damaged kidney and just one lung, but no mattress or blanket.</p>

<p>"We are not settled here either," said Dardasi, who like many Palestinians fears she will be uprooted once again.</p>

<p>Israel has said it goes out of its way to protect civilians in its war with the Palestinian group Hamas, which runs Gaza and led the attack on Israel on Oct. 7 that sparked the latest conflict.</p>

<p>Palestinians, many of whom have been displaced several times, say nowhere is free of Israeli bombardment, which has reduced much of Gaza to rubble.</p>

<p>An Israeli air strike killed at least 90 Palestinians in a designated humanitarian zone in the Al-Mawasi area on July 13, the territory's health ministry said, in an attack that Israel said targeted Hamas' elusive military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Gaza's health ministry said Israeli military strikes on areas in eastern Khan Younis had killed 14 people.</p>

<p>Entire neighbourhoods have been flattened in one of the most densely populated places in the world, where poverty and unemployment have long been widespread.</p>

<p>According to the United Nations, nine in ten people across Gaza are now internally displaced.</p>

<p>Israeli soldiers told Saria Abu Mustafa and her family that they should flee for safety as tanks were on their way, she said. The family had no time to change so they left in their prayer clothes.</p>

<p>After sleeping outside on sandy ground, they too found refuge in the prison, among piles of rubble and gaping holes in buildings from the battles which were fought there. Inmates had been released long before Israel attacked.</p>

<p>"We didn't take anything with us. We came here on foot, with children walking with us," she said, adding that many of the women had five or six children with them and that water was hard to find.</p>

<p>She held her niece, who was born during the conflict, which has killed her father and brothers.</p>

<p>When Hamas-led gunmen burst into southern Israel from Gaza on Oct. 7 they killed 1,200 people and took more than 250 people hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>More than 39,000 Palestinians have been killed in the air and ground offensive Israel launched in response, Palestinian health officials say.</p>

<p>Hana Al-Sayed Abu Mustafa arrived at the prison after being displaced six times.</p>

<p>If Egyptian, U.S. and Qatari mediators fail to secure a ceasefire they have long said is close, she and other Palestinians may be on the move once again. "Where should we go? All the places that we go to are dangerous," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c57jnb5o_gazans-shelter-_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Palestinians say nowhere is free of Israeli bombardment. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ancient-palestine-site-receives-unesco-tag-amid-raging-conflict-in-gaza-6195467]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ancient Palestine Site Receives UNESCO Tag Amid Raging Conflict In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ancient-palestine-site-receives-unesco-tag-amid-raging-conflict-in-gaza-6195467]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:36:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid the ongoing conflict in Gaza, the ancient heritage site of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer in Palestine on Friday received the UNESCO tag and was simultaneously put on the List of World Heritage in Danger after an "emergency nomination".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid the ongoing conflict in Gaza, the ancient heritage site of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer in Palestine on Friday received the UNESCO tag and was simultaneously put on the List of World Heritage in Danger after an "emergency nomination".</p>

<p>The announcement was made during the ongoing 46th session of the World Heritage Committee (WHC) in Delhi. India is hosting the key UNESCO event for the first time.</p>

<p>Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer in Palestine has been inscribed on the World Heritage List and List of World Heritage in Danger, it was announced in the plenary meeting of the session.</p>

<p>Israel has been carrying out a massive military offensive in Gaza following the unprecedented and multi-pronged attacks on Israeli cities by Hamas militants on October 7.</p>

<p>India in November had urged both the sides to eschew violence, de-escalate the situation and create conditions for an early resumption of direct peace negotiations towards a two-state solution to the Palestine issue.</p>

<p>Friday's inscription has raised hopes about protection of such heritage sites.</p>

<p>The UNESCO in a statement later said that "this decision recognises both the site's value and the need to protect it from danger".</p>

<p>"In view of the threats to this heritage site posed by the ongoing conflict in the Gaza Strip, the World Heritage Committee used the emergency inscription procedure provided for in the World Heritage Convention," it said.</p>

<p>In accordance with the terms of the Convention, "its 195 States Parties are committed to avoid taking any deliberate measures likely to cause direct or indirect damage to this site, which is now inscribed on the World Heritage List, and to assist in its protection", the world body said.</p>

<p>The UNESCO said inclusion on the List of World Heritage in Danger automatically opens the door to "enhanced international technical and financial assistance mechanisms to guarantee the protection of the property and, if necessary, to help facilitate its rehabilitation".</p>

<p>The monastery of Saint Hilarion/Tell Umm Amer, one of the oldest sites in the Middle East, was founded by Saint Hilarion and was home to the first monastic community in the Holy Land.</p>

<p>Situated at the crossroads of the main routes of trade and exchange between Asia and Africa, it was a centre for religious, cultural and economic exchanges, illustrating the prosperity of desert monastic sites in the Byzantine period, the statement said.</p>

<p>In December 2023, at its 18th session, the UNESCO's Intergovernmental Committee for the Protection of Cultural Property in the Event of Armed Conflict had already decided to grant "provisional enhanced protection" to the monastery under the 1954 Hague Convention and its Second Protocol.</p>

<p>The Palestinian delegation which included Mounir Anastas, Ambassador and Permanent Delegate of Palestine to UNESCO, thanked UNESCO for this dual inscription which seeks to bring a protective cover and world's attention to the heritage site located in areas facing conflicts.</p>

<p>"I am honoured to have this inscription taking place in the greatest democracy in the world. Thank you, India. I would like to express my deepest gratitude to all Committee members for their valuable support for this inscription," Anastas said in his statement made in the session right after the inscription.</p>

<p>He also thanked ICOMOS, an advisory body of the UNESCO, and the Secretariat of the UNESCO.</p>

<p>Various state parties from Lebanon, Turkiye and Kazakhstan welcomed the UNESCO inscription of the heritage site in Palestine, with some of them underlining the need for cultural heritage preservation in times of armed conflicts.</p>

<p>The nomination for the site of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer was an "emergency nomination".</p>

<p>Paris-based International Council on Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS) also made a presentation on this site.</p>

<p>The nomination dossier was submitted in June 2024 followed by a "desk review".</p>

<p>"Situated on the coastal dunes in Nuseirat Municipality, the ruins of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer represent one of the earliest monastic sites in the Middle East, dating back to the 4th century," according to the UNESCO website.</p>

<p>"Founded by Saint Hilarion, the monastery began with solitary hermits and evolved into a coenobitic community. It was the first monastic community in the Holy Land, laying the groundwork for the spread of monastic practices in the region. The monastery occupied a strategic position at the crossroads of major trade and communication routes between Asia and Africa," it said.</p>

<p>This prime location facilitated its role as a hub of religious, cultural, and economic interchange, exemplifying the flourishing of monastic desert centres during the Byzantine period, the world body said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/589mo1v8_saint-hilarion-monastery_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has been carrying out a massive military offensive in Gaza. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-bangladesh-student-protest-leaders-taken-by-police-from-hospital-report-6194846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Bangladesh Student Protest Leaders Taken By Police From Hospital: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-bangladesh-student-protest-leaders-taken-by-police-from-hospital-report-6194846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 18:22:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladeshi police detectives on Friday forced the discharge from hospital of three student protest leaders blamed for deadly unrest, taking them to an unknown location, staff told news agency AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladeshi police detectives on Friday forced the discharge from hospital of three student protest leaders blamed for deadly unrest, taking them to an unknown location, staff told AFP.</p>

<p>Asif Mahmud, Nahid Islam and Abu Baker Majumder are all members of Students Against Discrimination, the group responsible for organising recent street rallies against civil service hiring rules.</p>

<p>At least 193 people were killed in the ensuing police crackdown and clashes, according to an AFP count of victims reported by police and hospitals, in some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's tenure.</p>

<p>The trio were being treated for injuries that they said were caused by torture in earlier police custody at a hospital in the capital Dhaka.</p>

<p>"They took them from us," Gonoshasthaya hospital supervisor Anwara Begum Lucky told AFP. "The men were from the Detective Branch."</p>

<p>She added that she had not wanted to discharge the student leaders but police had pressured the hospital chief to do so.</p>

<p>Islam's elder sister Fatema Tasnim told AFP from the hospital that six plainclothes detectives had taken all three men.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/61s1g2k_bangladesh-students-protest-reuters_625x300_06_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["They took them from us," Gonoshasthaya hospital supervisor Anwara Begum Lucky said (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-slams-un-expert-for-anti-semitism-over-hitler-netanyahu-comparison-6194793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Slams UN Expert For "Anti-Semitism" Over Hitler-Netanyahu Comparison]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-slams-un-expert-for-anti-semitism-over-hitler-netanyahu-comparison-6194793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 18:16:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel on Friday slammed a UN rights expert for "anti-Semitism" after she endorsed a social media post comparing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to Adolf Hitler.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel on Friday slammed a UN rights expert for "anti-Semitism" after she endorsed a social media post comparing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to Adolf Hitler.</p>

<p>Francesca Albanese, the United Nations special rapporteur on the rights situation in the Palestinian territories, has faced harsh criticism from Israel previously, especially after she in March accused the country of committing genocide in the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>On Thursday, she responded to a post on X, formerly Twitter, displaying a picture of Hitler being celebrated by a crowd with Nazi salutes and cheers above a shot of Netanyahu appearing to be greeted by US congressmen this week.</p>

<p>"History is always watching," Craig Mokhiber, a former UN human rights official who resigned late last October accusing the world body of failing to prevent the "genocide" of Palestinian civilians in Gaza, wrote in the post.</p>

<p>"This is precisely what I was thinking today," Albanese, an independent expert appointed by the UN Human Rights Council in 2022 but who does not speak on behalf of the United Nations, said in her response on Thursday.</p>

<p>Israel's foreign ministry was quick to respond, slamming her on X as being "beyond redemption".</p>

<p>"It is inconceivable that (Albanese) is still allowed to use the UN as a shield to spread anti-Semitism," it said.</p>

<p>Israel's mission to the UN in Geneva also chimed in.</p>

<p>"When a current UN 'expert' endorses Holocaust distortion spread by the former (UN rights office) director in New York... the system is rotten to its core," it said.</p>

<p>"It's high time to #UNseatAlbanese!"</p>

<p>Israel's new ambassador in Geneva, Daniel Meron, used the same hashtag, decrying that "Francesca Albanese abuses her (UN) title to spread hatred and inflammatory rhetoric".</p>

<p>Israel's top ally the United States also weighed in.</p>

<p>"UN Special Rapporteur's comparison of Benjamin Netanyahu to Adolf Hitler is reprehensible and antisemitic," US ambassador to the UN Human Rights Council in Geneva Michele Taylor said on X.</p>

<p>"There should be no place for such dehumanising rhetoric. Special rapporteurs should be striving to improve human rights challenges, not inflame them."</p>

<p>Albanese on Friday hit back at the criticism, insisting that "the memory of the Holocaust remains intact".</p>

<p>"Institutional rants and outburst of selective moral outrage will not stop the course of justice, which is finally in motion."</p>

<p>The Hamas attack that started the war on October 7 resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people in Israel, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Out of 251 people taken hostage that day, 111 are still held in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive against Hamas has killed at least 39,175 Palestinians in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory offensive against Hamas has killed 39,175 Palestinians in Gaza: Hamas (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>