<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:28:36 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-says-1-301-deaths-during-hajj-most-pilgrims-unregistered-report-5954459]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Says 1,301 Deaths During Hajj, Most Pilgrims Unregistered: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-says-1-301-deaths-during-hajj-most-pilgrims-unregistered-report-5954459]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:08:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia said Sunday that more than 1,300 pilgrims died during the hajj pilgrimage which unfolded during intense heat, and that most of the deceased did not have official permits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia said Sunday that more than 1,300 pilgrims died during the hajj pilgrimage which unfolded during intense heat, and that most of those who have died did not have official permits.</p>

<p>"Regrettably, the number of mortalities reached 1,301, with 83 percent being unauthorised to perform hajj and having walked long distances under direct sunlight, without adequate shelter or comfort," the official Saudi Press Agency reported.</p>

<p>An AFP tally last week, based on official statements and reports from diplomats involved in their countries' responses, put the count at more than 1,100.</p>

<p>Arab diplomats told AFP that Egyptians accounted for 658 deaths -- 630 of them unregistered pilgrims.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Riyadh had not publicly commented on the deaths or provided its own&nbsp;count until Sunday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Friday, however, a senior Saudi official gave AFP a partial&nbsp;count of 577 deaths for the two busiest days of hajj: June 15, when pilgrims gathered for hours of prayers in the blazing sun on Mount Arafat, and June 16, when they participated in the "stoning of the devil" ritual in Mina.</p>

<h3><strong>'Misjudgement'</strong></h3>

<p>The official also defended Riyadh's response, saying: "The state did not fail, but there was a misjudgement on the part of people who did not appreciate the risks."</p>

<p>The Saudi health minister, Fahd Al-Jalajel, on Sunday described management of the hajj this year as "successful", SPA reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He said the health system "provided more than 465,000 specialised treatment services, including 141,000 services to those who didn't obtain official authorisation to perform hajj," according to SPA, which summarised an interview he gave to the state-affiliated Al-Ekhbariya channel.</p>

<p>The hajj is one of the five pillars of Islam that all Muslims with the means must complete at least once in their lives.</p>

<p>Saudi officials have said 1.8 million pilgrims took part this year, a similar number to last year, and that 1.6 million came from abroad.</p>

<p>For the past several years the mainly outdoor rituals have fallen during the sweltering Saudi summer.</p>

<p>Temperatures in Mecca this year climbed as high as 51.8 degrees Celsius (125 degrees Fahrenheit).</p>

<p>On Saturday, Egyptian Prime Minister Mostafa Madbouly ordered 16 tourism companies stripped of their licences and referred their managers to the public prosecutor over illegal pilgrimages to Mecca, Egypt's cabinet said.</p>

<p>It said the rise in the number of deaths of unregistered Egyptian pilgrims stemmed from some companies which "organised the hajj programmes using a personal visit visa, which prevents its holders from entering Mecca" via official channels.</p>

<p>Hajj permits are allocated to countries on a quota system and distributed to individuals by lottery.</p>

<p>Even for those who can obtain them, the steep costs spur many to attempt the hajj without a permit, though they risk arrest and deportation if caught.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/g68pm4v8_hajj-reuters-1200_625x300_21_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Temperatures in Mecca this year climbed as high as 51.8 degrees Celsius (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-war-blocks-exams-and-shatters-palestinian-students-dreams-5954384]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza War Blocks Exams And Shatters Palestinian Students' Dreams]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-war-blocks-exams-and-shatters-palestinian-students-dreams-5954384]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 23:48:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Teenagers across the Gaza Strip should have been taking their final exams this month, a last hurdle before university and lifelong dreams, but the war in the Palestinian territory has crushed those hopes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Teenagers across the Gaza Strip should have been taking their final exams this month, a last hurdle before university and lifelong dreams, but the war in the Palestinian territory has crushed those hopes.</p>

<p>According to the education ministry in the Hamas-run Gaza Strip, 85 percent of educational facilities in the territory are out of service because of the war.</p>

<p>"I was eagerly awaiting the exams, but the war prevented that and destroyed that joy", said Baraa al-Farra, an 18-year-old student displaced from Khan Yunis in southern Gaza.</p>

<p>"At first we were waiting in the hope that the war would end and we would catch up," he said.</p>

<p>But "we don't know how long it will last or how many years it will deprive us of our educational lives."</p>

<p>Almost nine months of war in Gaza began with an unprecedented October 7 attack on southern Israel by the Islamist militant group Hamas. The attack resulted in the deaths of 1,194 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,598 people, also mostly civilians, according to the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza.</p>

<p>The Education Cluster, a UN-backed organisation, estimated in a report this month that more than 75 percent of Gaza's schools would need full reconstruction or major rehabilitation to reopen.</p>

<p>Many have been turned into shelters for Gaza's displaced and others have been damaged in bombardment.</p>

<p><strong>'Books not bombs'</strong></p>

<p>Liliane Nihad, an 18-year-old displaced to Khan Yunis from Gaza City, in the territory's north, said she and her fellow students had "been waiting 12 years to take these exams and pass and feel happy and enter university... but we have been deprived of all that by this damned war".</p>

<p>Nihad said she had been hoping to study English and to get a doctorate, "but all of that has evaporated".</p>

<p>Displaying their anger at the situation, dozens of students and teachers held a protest in Gaza City's Al-Rimal neighbourhood on Saturday.</p>

<p>"We demand our right to take high school exams" and "We want books, not bombs" they chanted, while empty chairs were laid out to symbolise those students killed in the war.</p>

<p>Mediation has failed to bring an end to the fighting, leaving Gaza's young people with deep uncertainty about their futures.</p>

<p>Farra said he wanted to get out of the territory to achieve his dreams.</p>

<p>"I hope that the crossing will be opened so that I can travel in order to complete my education and not waste my years because I am young and want to achieve my ambitions."</p>

<p>For now, he faces the harsh realities of life under siege.</p>

<p>"I wish I could experience the fatigue of staying up late studying now and not the fatigue of queueing for sweet and salty water" in the territory where clean water is scarce, like many other essentials.</p>

<p><strong>'Psychologically exhausted'</strong></p>

<p>Pupils in the Israeli-occupied West Bank will take the exams, as will those Gazans who managed to escape to neighbouring Egypt.</p>

<p>Even for these pupils, however, the war has been hugely disruptive.</p>

<p>"We are psychologically exhausted and not well prepared" said Muhammad Osama, a student from Gaza's southernmost city of Rafah, after completing his religious studies exam in Cairo.</p>

<p>In the West Bank, violence has further escalated since the start of the Gaza war. According to the Palestinian official news agency Wafa, 20 high school students are among the hundreds of Palestinians killed there.</p>

<p>Wafa reported that 89,000 students from Gaza and the West Bank had been expected to take high school exams this year.</p>

<p>Back in Gaza, however, there will be no exams at all.</p>

<p>The UN, citing the Palestinian ministry of education, said about 39,000 high school students in Gaza are unable to take their tests.</p>

<p>Sulaf Mousa, an 18-year-old from Al-Shati Camp west of Gaza City, hit by a deadly air strike on Saturday, said he had hoped to study medicine and become a doctor.</p>

<p>"Now, we hope we will survive the war and not lose more than we have already lost," Mousa said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/a82aksnc_gaza-strip-1200_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunmen-kill-6-cops-a-priest-in-russias-dagestan-says-counter-terror-agency-5954338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunmen Kill 6 Cops, A Priest In Russia's Dagestan, Says Counter Terror Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunmen-kill-6-cops-a-priest-in-russias-dagestan-says-counter-terror-agency-5954338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 23:37:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gunmen on Sunday attacked a synagogue and churches, killing a priest and six police officers in Russia's Caucasus region of Dagestan, the national counter-terrorism agency and police said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gunmen on Sunday attacked a synagogue and churches, killing a priest and six police officers in Russia's Caucasus region of Dagestan, the national counter-terrorism agency and police said.</p>

<p>The attacks took place in Dagestan's largest city of Makhachkala and in the coastal city of Derbent.</p>

<p>Russia's Investigative Committee said it had opened criminal probes over "acts of terror".</p>

<p>Dagestan is a largely Muslim region of Russia bordering Georgia and Azerbaijan.</p>

<p>"This evening in the cities of Derbent and Makhachkala armed attacks were carried out on two Orthodox churches, a synagogue and a police check-point," said the National Antiterrorism Committee in a statement to RIA Novosti news agency.</p>

<p>"As a result of the terrorist attacks, according to preliminary information, a priest from the Russian Orthodox Church and police officers were killed."</p>

<p>In all, six police officers had been killed and another 12 wounded in the attacks, the spokeswoman for Dagestan's interior ministry, Gayana Gariyeva, told RIA Novosti.</p>

<p>A 66-year-old priest was killed in Derbent, the press secretary of Dagestan's interior ministry, Gariyeva told the agency.</p>

<p>"The synagogue in Derbent is on fire," the chairman of the public council of Russia's Federation of Jewish Communities, Boruch Gorin wrote on Telegram.</p>

<p>"It has not been possible to extinguish the fire. Two are killed: a policeman and a security guard".</p>

<p>He added: "The synagogue in Makhachkala has also been set on fire and burnt down. During the attack on the Orthodox church in Derbent, the priest's throat was cut."</p>

<p>The leader of Dagestan, Sergei Melikov, wrote on Telegram: "This evening in Derbent and Makhachkala unknown (attackers) made attempts to destabilise the situation in society.</p>

<p>"They were confronted by Dagestani police officers."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/2irvkl08_dagestan-1200_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-feminists-march-against-far-right-with-days-before-vote-5953907]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Feminists March Against Far Right With Days Before Vote]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-feminists-march-against-far-right-with-days-before-vote-5953907]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 22:19:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of people turned out in France on Sunday for feminist demonstrations against the far right, which is expected to come out on top in June 30 snap elections, as parties sought to shore up support with days to go.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of people turned out in France on Sunday for feminist demonstrations against the far right, which is expected to come out on top in June 30 snap elections, as parties sought to shore up support with days to go.</p>

<p>With the far-right National Rally (RN) polling at around 35 percent, "we have to remind people that they're the ones who talked about 'comfort abortions', who are always attacking family planning services," said Morgane Legras, a nuclear engineer and feminist activist taking part in the thousands-strong march in Paris.</p>

<p>Protesters wearing violet marched from the Place de la Republique square in central Paris to Place de la Nation in the east, bearing signs with messages such as "Push back the far right, not our rights".</p>

<p>Other rallies took place in around 50 other cities such as Toulouse.</p>

<p>France's two-round election system makes it difficult to predict which party could ultimately claim a majority in the lower house of parliament, handing them the prime minister's post which is second in power to President Emmanuel Macron.</p>

<p>Since Macron dissolved parliament after a European Parliament election battering, his centrists are badly lagging the RN as well as a reforged left-wing alliance called the New Popular Front (NFP) in surveys of voting intentions.</p>

<p>The RN has garnered unprecedented levels of support after a decades-long "de-demonisation" push to distance its image from its roots, including a co-founder who was a member of the Nazi Waffen-SS paramilitary.</p>

<p>But the core of its message remains hostility to immigration, Islam and the European Union.</p>

<p>Senior RN lawmaker Sebastien Chenu gestured towards Muslim and Jewish voters Sunday by vowing not to ban the ritual slaughter of livestock to produce halal or kosher meat.</p>

<p>"Everyone will be able to keep eating kosher meat if they want," Chenu told Jewish broadcaster Radio J.</p>

<p>He added that a historic far-right policy of barring the kippa in public spaces -- in the footsteps of an existing law forbidding the full-body burka worn by some Muslim women -- was not top of the RN's agenda, saying its priority was to fight "the Islamist threat".</p>

<p><strong>'Do better'</strong></p>

<p>In Macron's camp, Prime Minister Gabriel Attal acknowledged that the European Parliament result -- where they scored just 14 percent -- was "a message to us that we have to do better with our methods, with our governance" of the country.</p>

<p>If his party defies the odds to come top in the legislative polls, he vowed "change", including a turn to "seeking out coalitions with the French public, with civil society" in an interview with broadcaster RTL.</p>

<p>Macron's alliance would open up to "all who want to come, from the conservative right to the social-democratic left", Macron's former prime minister Edouard Philippe told broadcaster France 3.</p>

<p>Attal also hammered the centrists' mantra about the threats from "extremes" on the left and right, saying both promised a "tax bludgeoning... a shredder for the middle classes".</p>

<p>The RN especially is "not ready to govern... it's a party of opposition, not a party of government", Attal said.</p>

<p>In a sign of the disquiet abroad over Macron's snap poll gamble, German Chancellor Olaf Scholz told public broadcaster ARD on Sunday that he was "concerned about the elections in France", though "it's up to the French people to decide".</p>

<p><strong>'Shut up'</strong></p>

<p>The left-wing NFP alliance continued to show strains Sunday, after parties hastily re-knitted ties sundered over differing responses to Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel and the ongoing retaliation by Israeli forces in Gaza.</p>

<p>Divisions are particularly stark over whether their candidate for prime minister should be Jean-Luc Melenchon, head of France Unbowed (LFI) -- the largest party in the grouping, some of whose members have been accused of anti-Semitism.</p>

<p>Melenchon should "shut up", former Socialist president Francois Hollande said Sunday, as "people reject him more strongly" than the RN's leaders Marine Le Pen and Jordan Bardella.</p>

<p>"Do we want the left to win, or do we want to be stoking conflict?" he said.</p>

<p>Melenchon said on Saturday that he aimed "to govern the country".</p>

<p>"I will never give up the honour of being a target" for attacks, Melenchon told a rally in the southern city of Montpellier on Sunday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/10n80g6_france-protest-1200_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-wolves-brutally-attack-37-year-old-woman-in-zoo-outside-paris-report-5953458]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Wolves Brutally Attack 37-Year-Old Woman In Zoo Outside Paris: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-wolves-brutally-attack-37-year-old-woman-in-zoo-outside-paris-report-5953458]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 20:48:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three wolves in a zoo outside Paris attacked a 37-year-old woman leaving her fighting for her life, a source familiar with the case and local prosecutors said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three wolves in a zoo outside Paris attacked a 37-year-old woman leaving her fighting for her life, a source familiar with the case and local prosecutors said.</p>

<p>The woman was bitten "on the neck, the calf and the back" at the Thoiry zoo around 40 kilometres (25 miles) west of the French capital, the source familiar with the case told AFP.</p>

<p>Maryvonne Caillibotte, chief prosecutor in Versailles, said the woman's life was in danger.</p>

<p>The woman is believed to have gone out alone for a jog after spending the night with her family in a safari-style lodge at the zoo, which it advertised on its website at between 220 and 760 euros ($235-810) per night.</p>

<p>Lodges in the wolf zone promise "silence, rest and disconnection", according to the zoo's adverts. They offer "a one-of-a-kind, very intimate experience with the arctic wolves you'll be able to see from the living room".</p>

<p>The woman "ended up in the safari zone, which is supposed to be restricted to cars. That's where she was attacked by three wolves," Caillibotte said.</p>

<p>She added that it was not clear "whether she made a mistake or the trail wasn't clearly marked".</p>

<p>First responders got to the scene "very quickly", the wolves were "moved away, then returned to their area," Caillibotte siad.</p>

<p>The source familiar with the case earlier said the woman must have got through "security systems, a trench and an electric fence supposed to keep the animals in".</p>

<p>Police are investigating the incident.</p>

<p>Thoiry zoo was founded in 1968 by Paul de la Panouse, owner of a local chateau that has been in his family since the 16th Century.</p>

<p>He recalled to regional newspaper L'Independant in April how he initially stocked the zoo with a ship loaded with 120 animals brought from Kenya.</p>

<p>De la Panouse sold the zoo to a group of investors in 2018.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/0s1thgs_wolves-generic-pixabay_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police are investigating the incident. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-forces-tie-wounded-palestinian-to-jeep-in-west-bank-raid-5953391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Forces Tie Wounded Palestinian To Jeep In West Bank Raid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-forces-tie-wounded-palestinian-to-jeep-in-west-bank-raid-5953391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 20:34:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli troops tied a wounded Palestinian to a military vehicle during a raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin, the army said Sunday, admitting that soldiers had violated operational procedures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli troops tied a wounded Palestinian to a military vehicle during a raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin, the army said Sunday, admitting that soldiers had violated operational procedures.</p>

<p>Footage of the incident, which occurred on Saturday, has gone viral and shows a man strapped horizontally to the bonnet of a military jeep as it passes through a narrow alley.</p>

<p>Medics identified the Palestinian as Mujahid Raed Abbadi, 24, who told AFP he lives in the Jenin refugee camp.</p>

<p>The military said a Palestinian man was wounded during a "counterterrorism operation" to arrest wanted suspects in the area of Wadi Burqin, between the town of Burqin and Jenin.</p>

<p>During an exchange of fire between troops and militants in Burqin's Jabriyat neighbourhood, a Palestinian was wounded and apprehended, the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>The statement referred to him as a "suspect", but did not specify any accusations against Abbadi, who medics told AFP was being treated at Jenin's Ibn Sina hospital, and not in Israeli custody.</p>

<p>The military said: "In violation of orders and standard operating procedures, the suspect was taken by the forces while tied on top of a vehicle."</p>

<p>He was later transferred to the Palestinian Red Crescent for treatment, it said.</p>

<p>"The conduct of the forces in the video of the incident does not conform to the values of the IDF (military)," the statement said.</p>

<p>"The incident will be investigated and dealt with accordingly."</p>

<p>Francesca Albanese, the United Nations special rapporteur on the rights situation in the Palestinian territories, suggested the troops were using Abbadi to shield themselves from gunfire.</p>

<p>"#HumanShielding in action", Albanese wrote on social media platform X, sharing footage of the incident.</p>

<p>At the hospital, Abbadi said he was hit and wounded as he stepped out of his uncle's house in Jabriyat.</p>

<p>"I tried to withdraw and get inside the house, but they started shooting", hitting him in the hand, Abbadi told AFP in his hospital bed.</p>

<p><strong>'Stomped my head'</strong></p>

<p>He said he fell to the ground in an area behind the military jeep and was hit once more, with a bullet penetrating his leg.</p>

<p>According to Abbadi, rescuers or medics were unable to reach him for more than two hours as he lay on the ground.</p>

<p>"I started crawling" trying to escape as fighting continued around him, he said, before the Israeli troops noticed him.</p>

<p>"When they (the soldiers) arrived they stomped on my head and hit my face, my injured leg and hand," Abbadi recalled.</p>

<p>"They were laughing and playing while they hit me."</p>

<p>The soldiers lifted him and threw him on the ground before tying him to the bonnet of the jeep, he said.</p>

<p>Bahaa Abu Hammad, the doctor treating Abbadi at Ibn Sina hospital, told AFP that "he has burns on his back from neck to lower back" from being tied to the military jeep in the scorching summer heat.</p>

<p>Jenin has long been a stronghold for Palestinian militant groups, and the Israeli army routinely carries out raids in the city and an adjacent refugee camp.</p>

<p>Violence in the West Bank, which had already surged before the Israel-Hamas war broke out on October 7, has only escalated since.</p>

<p>At least 553 Palestinians have been killed in the West Bank by Israeli troops or settlers since the Gaza war broke out, according to Palestinian officials.</p>

<p>Attacks by Palestinians have killed at least 14 Israelis in the West Bank over the same period, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The Gaza Strip has been gripped by more than eight months of war since Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,194 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Militants took 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza, including 41 the army says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's military offensive on Gaza has since killed at least 37,598 people, also mostly civilians, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/cnu4mqec_israeli-forces-1200_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindujas-not-imprisoned-human-trafficking-charges-dismissed-spokesperson-5953187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hindujas Not Imprisoned, Human Trafficking Charges Dismissed: Spokesperson]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindujas-not-imprisoned-human-trafficking-charges-dismissed-spokesperson-5953187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:58:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four members of Britain's richest family, the Hindujas, on Sunday said they have not been subjected to any imprisonment, conviction, sentence or detention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four members of Britain's richest family, the Hindujas, on Sunday said they have not been subjected to any imprisonment, conviction, sentence or detention. Prakash Hinduja, 78, and his wife Kamal Hinduja, 75, son Ajay, 56, and his wife Namrata, 50, were accused of "usury" for allegedly having taken advantage of their vulnerable immigrant staff to pay them a pittance.</p>

<p>In the statement, a spokesperson of the Hindujas said the family members have not been imprisoned and human trafficking charges against them has been dismissed.</p>

<p>"The four Swiss-national members of the Hinduja Family, Kamal and Prakash Hinduja, Namrata and Ajay Hinduja, have not been subjected to any imprisonment, conviction, sentence or detention," the spokesperson said in the statement.</p>

<p>"Per Swiss law procedures, the lower court's judgment is rendered ineffective and inoperative as the presumption of innocence is paramount until and unless a final judgment by the highest adjudicating authority is enforced.</p>

<p>"The most serious of the charges, human trafficking, against them were completely dismissed by the court yesterday.</p>

<p>"It may be noted that the case has no complainants left anymore and they had declared in the court that they were led into signing statements that they didn't even understand. They had neither intended to nor initiated such proceedings. All of them further testified that the four Hinduja family members treated them with 'respect, dignity and like family.'</p>

<p>"The four family members have full faith in the Swiss judicial process and remain confident that the truth will prevail."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tg30klj_hindujas-afp_625x300_22_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A spokesperson of the Hindujas said the family members have not been imprisoned]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-defence-minister-heads-to-us-for-critical-talks-on-gaza-war-5952965]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Heads To US For "Critical" Talks On Gaza War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-defence-minister-heads-to-us-for-critical-talks-on-gaza-war-5952965]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:12:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant was headed to Washington on Sunday for "critical" talks on the Gaza war raging since October 7 and surging cross-border tensions with Lebanon's Hezbollah movement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant was headed to Washington on Sunday for "critical" talks on the Gaza war raging since October 7 and surging cross-border tensions with Lebanon's Hezbollah movement.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu voiced hope for speedy progress on unfreezing US arms and ammunition deliveries from Israel's top ally which he said had dropped off sharply in recent months.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden has been at odds with Israel's veteran right-wing leader over Gaza's surging civilian death toll, but US officials have said they were not aware of what Netanyahu was referring to on the arms issue.</p>

<p>The Israeli premier on Sunday told his cabinet that "about four months ago, there was a dramatic drop in the supply of armaments arriving from the US to Israel. We got all sorts of explanations, but... the basic situation didn't change."</p>

<p>However, he voiced hope the issue would now be cleared up: "In light of what I have heard in the last day, I hope and believe that this issue will be resolved in the near future."</p>

<p>Israeli forces again bombed Gaza on Sunday, a day after tens of thousands staged a protest rally in Tel Aviv against the government and to demand the return of hostages being held by Hamas.</p>

<p>Tensions have also flared on Israel's northern border with Lebanon whose Iran-backed Hezbollah movement has traded daily cross-border fire with the army, heightening fears of all-out war.</p>

<p>Gallant said he would "discuss developments in Gaza and Lebanon", vowing that "we are prepared for any action that may be required in Gaza, Lebanon and in additional areas".</p>

<p>He stressed that "our ties with the United States are more important than ever. Our meetings with US officials are critical to this war."</p>

<p>- 'War of annihilation' -</p>

<p>In Gaza, Israeli forces kept striking targets and battling Hamas, the Islamist militant group Israel has vowed to destroy over its October 7 attack, in a war that has devastated much of the coastal territory.</p>

<p>Warplanes had struck "dozens of terror targets throughout the Gaza Strip, including military structures, terrorists and terrorist infrastructure" over the past 24 hours, a military statement said.</p>

<p>As the Gaza war has raged on for over eight months, Israeli protesters have taken to the streets week after week demanding greater efforts to bring home the remaining hostages.</p>

<p>A rally in Tel Aviv on Saturday evening drew more than 150,000 people, according to the organisation Israel Democracy HQ ~CHECK~ Hofshi B'Artzenu, which called it the biggest rally since the Gaza war began.</p>

<p>Many demonstrators voiced anger and frustration with Netanyahu and his far-right allies, accusing them of prolonging the war and putting the country's security and hostages at risk.</p>

<p>Many held signs reading "Crime Minister" and "Stop the War" while some lay on the ground covered in red paint to protest what they labelled the death of Israel's democracy.</p>

<p>In an address to the crowd, Yuval Diskin, a former head of Israel's domestic security agency Shin Bet, condemned Netanyahu as Israel's "worst prime minister".</p>

<p>- Lebanon tensions -</p>

<p>The Gaza war broke out with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,194 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 41 are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,598 people, also mostly civilians, Gaza's health ministry said.</p>

<p>An Israeli siege has deprived Gaza's 2.4 million people of most drinking water, food, fuel and other essentials.</p>

<p>"This war must stop," said Umm Siraj al-Balawi, surviving in a makeshift shelter amid a field of rubble, with strung-up sheets protecting her young children from the blazing sun.</p>

<p>"People are getting displaced from house to house, tent to tent, school to school," she said. "This is a war of displacement. It's a war of annihilation."</p>

<p>Lebanon's Hezbollah meanwhile said it had targeted a military position in northern Israel "with an attack drone" in response to the killing of a commander of the Jamaa Islamiya group in a strike on eastern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel said no one was injured in the attack Sunday.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had hours earlier published a video excerpt purporting to show locations in Israel along with their coordinates, amid heightening fears of an all-out conflict.</p>

<p>Israel's military said last Tuesday that a plan for a Lebanon offensive had been "approved and validated".</p>

<p>Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah responded with threats that no part of Israel would be spared in the event of a full-scale war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/7kvtbavs_yoav-gallant-1200_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heavy-rain-triggers-floods-and-landslides-in-switzerland-5952872]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Heavy Rain Triggers Floods And Landslides In Switzerland]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heavy-rain-triggers-floods-and-landslides-in-switzerland-5952872]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 18:57:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Emergency services with helicopters, drones and rescue dogs searched on Saturday for three people who were missing after violent downpours caused floods and landslides in southwestern Switzerland.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Emergency services with helicopters, drones and rescue dogs searched on Saturday for three people who were missing after violent downpours caused floods and landslides in southwestern Switzerland.</p>

<p>MeteoSchweiz, the government's office for weather and climate, said 124 mm (4.88 inches) of rain fell in Mesolcina valley in the canton of Grisons on Friday, with 63 mm (2.48 inches) falling in a one-hour period.</p>

<p>"It was not the level of rain, but the concentration of rain in such a short period of time which caused the problems," a spokesman for MeteoSchweiz said.</p>

<p>"This concentration of rain happens only once every 30 years."</p>

<p>Several rivers burst their banks in Mesolcina valley, also known as Misox, covering roads, fields and villages with rubble, earth and wood.</p>

<p>Three houses and three cars were swept away by water in the village of Sorte, Grisons police said. Two police officers were able to escape from their vehicle which was submerged up to its roof.</p>

<p>Four people were initially reported missing, although a woman was later found under rubble and taken to hospital in nearby Lugano. A search was still underway for three other people who police said could have been in their homes when the flooding took place.</p>

<p>Police urged people not to travel to the region as many roads were closed. Five villages were without electricity.</p>

<p>In the western canton of Valais, 230 people were evacuated since Friday after heavy rainfall caused flooding and mudslides.</p>

<p>The road and railway line to the town of Zermatt, next to the Matterhorn mountain, was also closed, although police said they hoped to reopen the routes on Saturday evening.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/9mkdlhl4_switzerland-rain-1200-_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flights-cancelled-at-uks-3rd-busiest-manchester-airport-after-power-cut-5952843]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Flights Cancelled At UK's 3rd-Busiest Airport After Power Cut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flights-cancelled-at-uks-3rd-busiest-manchester-airport-after-power-cut-5952843]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 18:51:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Flights at the UK's third-busiest airport were being delayed or cancelled Sunday after a major power cut, the airport operator said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Flights at the UK's third-busiest airport were being delayed or cancelled Sunday after a major power cut, the airport operator said.</p>

<p>The Manchester Airports Group, which also operates London Stansted and the East Midlands airports, said Manchester Airport had been "affected by a major power cut in the area earlier this morning."</p>

<p>Power has now been restored at the international airport in the north of England, but passengers due to travel from Terminals One and Two were told to "not come to the airport" as all flights were cancelled "until further notice".</p>

<p>Passengers for Terminal Three were told to come to the airport as normal, but were warned they "could be affected by delays".</p>

<p>The airport operator said that while passengers already checked in were scheduled to depart as planned, the disruption meant "some baggage may not be on those flights".</p>

<p>"We will work with airlines and handling partners to reunite affected passengers with their luggage as soon as possible", the group added.</p>

<p>The airline Jet2 -- which operates from both terminals -- said that as well as cancelling dozens of flights, it was unable to load bags onto planes as the airport's baggage system remained "inoperable".</p>

<p>Airline easyJet, which operates flights from Terminal One, warned of "very long queues" for security, and said passengers could only board flights with cabin bags.</p>

<p>In addition, some arriving flights were being diverted to other airports according to the airport statement, including London Heathrow and Birmingham.</p>

<p>Some flyers took to X, formerly known as Twitter, to describe the "chaos", with one passenger saying they had been waiting for their bags after landing after midnight and another saying they were "stuck on the plane".</p>

<p>The UK's travel industry has been hit by a series of disruptions in the last few years, including technical problems and industrial action affecting rail and air passengers.</p>

<p>Last month, a nationwide outage of immigration e-gates caused long delays for thousands of passengers.</p>

<p>In August last year, the country faced its worst air traffic control disruption in almost ten years due to a technical fault.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tm86m25o_manchester-airport-1200_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/german-town-votes-to-wipe-out-its-pigeon-population-heres-why-5951378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Uproar After German Town Votes To Wipe Out Its Pigeon Population]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/german-town-votes-to-wipe-out-its-pigeon-population-heres-why-5951378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 15:11:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A German town, Limburg an der Lahn, has voted to exterminate its entire population of pigeons, sparking a fight between the residents and animal rights activists.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A German town, Limburg an der Lahn, has voted to exterminate its entire population of pigeons, sparking a fight between the residents and animal rights activists. The residents voted in favour of culling the birds earlier this month, in a referendum, according to local media.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The report revealed that the legal fight against the pigeons was prompted by innumerable complaints over the birds' faeces. These complaints were registered by residents, restaurateurs and market vendors around Limburg's Neumarkt central square.</p>

<p dir="ltr">On June 20, Limburg officials said they were still considering whether to proceed with the referendum results.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The report quoted town spokesman Johannes Laubach, as saying, “There is no timetable for implementation. The resolution stipulates that there will be another comprehensive case-by-case review before implementation.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">The residents and business owners claimed that they have been frustrated by the town's pigeons for years now.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The report added that last year in November, the town's council decided that a falconer should be commissioned to kill Limburg's pigeon population.</p>

<p dir="ltr">It stated, “The falconer will lure the birds into a trap, hit them over the head with a wooden stick to stun them, and then break their necks.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">This decision led to fierce protests from animal rights activists and a petition for signatures, after which a referendum was initiated.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In a post on X (formerly Twitter), DW added, “Animal rights activists are horrified that the cull is going ahead, while critics say that pigeon culls aren't really effective since any remaining birds will reproduce, replenishing the population. Other German cities, like Frankfurt, rely on a form of birth control and replace real eggs with plaster ones to keep its pigeons in check, while the city of Hagen is trialling a drug that makes the birds temporarily infertile.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Flying rats, vermin, rats with wings — urban pigeons have a bad reputation that's hard to shake off.<br />
<br />
In one German town, however, pigeon-human relations have taken a macabre turn.<br />
<br />
Limburg an der Lahn, in the western German state of Hesse, voted last week to exterminate its… <a href="https://t.co/CZ2IZoxzeo">pic.twitter.com/CZ2IZoxzeo</a></p>
— DW News (@dwnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/dwnews/status/1803547496138023054?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">After the referendum, Limburg's mayor Marius Hahn said the citizens had decided “that the pigeon population should be reduced over the next two years by a falconer who stuns and kills animals.” On Thursday, the mayor informed a final review of the implementation of the referendum was still pending.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/su7fabg_pigeon-generic_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Officials said they were still considering whether to proceed with the results. (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-soldiers-tie-injured-palestinian-to-jeep-in-west-bank-video-viral-5951073]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Soldiers Tie Injured Palestinian To Jeep In West Bank, Video Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-soldiers-tie-injured-palestinian-to-jeep-in-west-bank-video-viral-5951073]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 13:21:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli troops tied a wounded Palestinian man to a military vehicle during a raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin, the army said Sunday, admitting that soldiers had violated operational procedures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli troops tied a wounded Palestinian man to a military vehicle during a raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin, the army said Sunday, admitting that soldiers had violated operational procedures.</p>

<p>Footage of the incident, which occurred on Saturday, has gone viral and shows a Jenin resident strapped horizontally to the bonnet of a military jeep as it passes through a narrow alley.</p>

<p>The military said the Palestinian was wounded during a "counterterrorism operation" launched to apprehend wanted suspects.</p>

<p>During an exchange of fire between troops and militants, one of the suspects was wounded and apprehended, the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>"In violation of orders and standard operating procedures, the suspect was taken by the forces while tied on top of a vehicle," the statement said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The conduct of the forces in the video of the incident does not conform to the values of the IDF (military)," it added.</p>

<p>"The incident will be investigated and dealt with accordingly," the military said, adding that the wounded man was transferred to the Palestinian Red Crescent for treatment.</p>

<p>Jenin has long been a stronghold for Palestinian groups, and the Israeli army routinely carries out raids in the city and adjacent refugee camp.</p>

<p>Violence in the West Bank, which had already surged before the Israel-Hamas war broke out on October 7, has only escalated since.</p>

<p>At least 549 Palestinians have been killed in the West Bank by Israeli troops or settlers since the Gaza war broke out, according to Palestinian officials.</p>

<p>Attacks by Palestinians have killed at least 14 Israelis in the West Bank over the same period, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The Gaza Strip has been gripped by more than eight months of war since Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,194 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Militants took 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza, including 41 the army says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's military offensive on Gaza has since killed at least 37,551 people, also mostly civilians, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/14eup9ns_palestinian-man-jeep_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-man-tortured-burnt-alive-over-quran-desecration-27-arrested-5950985]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Man Tortured, Burnt Alive Over Quran Desecration, 27 Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-man-tortured-burnt-alive-over-quran-desecration-27-arrested-5950985]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 13:05:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a shocking incident that took place in Pakistan's Swat, a mob allegedly tortured a man to death by burning him alive over alleged desecration of the Holy Quran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident that took place in Pakistan's Swat, a mob allegedly tortured a man to death by burning him alive over alleged desecration of the Holy Quran.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, police have arrested 27 suspects including two brothers, ARY News reported on Sunday.</p>

<p>The incident occurred on June 20 in Madyan, a town in the Swat district, a popular tourist spot located 340 km from the capital city of Islamabad.</p>

<p>According to Swat District Police Officer (DPO) Zahidullah Khan, the police had moved the suspect of the alleged desecration incident to the police station but a charged mob "attacked the police station and took the suspect away".</p>

<p>"People set fire to the police station and a mobile vehicle," the DPO said, adding that the suspect was "torched".</p>

<p>Videos making the rounds on social media show a mob circling a body on fire in the middle of the road, along with a large number of people outside a police station. Dawn.com's correspondent has reached out to the police for confirmation of the footage, Dawn reported.</p>

<p>DPO Khan said a heavy police force was deployed in Madyan and was trying to control the tense situation.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the police teams are conducting raids for more arrests in the Madyan incident.</p>

<p>Earlier, Federal Minister Ahsan Iqbal condemned the lynching incident in Swat and called to stop this 'street justice'.</p>

<p>Ahsan Iqbal during the budget debate in the National Assembly, called the incident horrific.</p>

<p>Ahsan said that parliament had to take stern notice of "mob justice", as it had brought Pakistan "to the brink of destruction".</p>

<p>"We must take notice of this incident. We have now reached to a point where religion being used to justify mob violence and street justice, flagrantly violating the Constitution, the law and the state," he lamented.</p>

<p>At least 2,120 people are reported to have been accused of committing blasphemy between 1987 and 2022, as per Dawn.</p>

<p>Last month, police saved a Christian man from enraged people in Sargodha on allegations of desecration of the Holy Quran, He died nine days later due to his injuries.</p>

<p>In 2022, a middle-aged man was stoned to death by a mob over alleged desecration in a remote village of Khanewal district.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ppu3a0no_pak-man-burnt-alive_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-implores-christians-to-boost-turnout-courts-black-voters-5950360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In 4 Years, Don't Vote, I Don't Care": Trump's Election Appeal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-implores-christians-to-boost-turnout-courts-black-voters-5950360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 10:41:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former President Donald Trump told evangelical voters they needed to boost their turnout at the polls as he sought in a pair of Saturday campaign events to shore up - and expand - his base.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former President Donald Trump told evangelical voters they needed to boost their turnout at the polls as he sought in a pair of Saturday campaign events to shore up - and expand - his base.</p>

<p>Trump spoke Saturday afternoon to the Faith and Freedom Coalition conference in Washington, a gathering of evangelical conservatives who have provided a bedrock of support for his three presidential bids. Later, the presumptive Republican presidential held a rally in North Philadelphia as part of his effort to make inroads with Black voters in the pivotal swing state of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Trump told his supporters that to defeat President Joe Biden, he needed them "to turn out in the largest numbers ever."</p>

<p>"The evangelicals and Christians, they don't vote as much as they should, I don't know if you know that," Trump said. "They go to church every Sunday, but they don't vote."</p>

<p>Trump went on to complain that gun-rights activists also didn't vote in high enough numbers, and said ballot drop-off boxes should be placed inside of churches.</p>

<p>"You got to get out, just this time," Trump continued. "I don't care in four years - you don't have to vote, OK? In four years, don't vote, I don't care."</p>

<p>Trump received a hero's welcome from the organization, founded by conservative activist Ralph Reed, despite a presidency during which he took little action on many of the group's key priorities, from combating same-sex marriage to ending the legalization of medical marijuana.</p>

<p>Still, Trump's push to appoint Supreme Court justices who overturned Roe v. Wade - along with his embrace of culture-war clashes - have cemented his appeal with evangelicals and his standing as the leader of the Republican Party.</p>

<p>Trump's occasionally chiding effort to convert the enthusiasm at the Washington event into votes at the ballot box underscored the extent his hopes for a second term rely on motivating dedicated supporters. Polls show wide swaths of moderate swing voters disappointed with both candidates and considering third-party options or disinclined to vote.</p>

<p>"I think it's sort of a protest. You're so angry about what's happening," Trump said. "Do you know the power you'd have if you would vote?"</p>

<p>Even as Trump's political operation focuses on turning out dedicated conservatives, he's also seeking to appeal to Black and Latino voters - who have traditionally supported Democratic presidential candidates - but have felt the brunt of post-pandemic inflation. Trump's rally at Temple University in Philadelphia came just days after a visit to a Black church in Detroit.</p>

<p>"We will also work to lift up Black, Hispanic and other communities in Philadelphia and all across the United States," Trump said.</p>

<p>Polls show Biden's standing among minority voters has softened, possibly providing an opening to Trump and Republicans who hope to draw just enough support to win close battleground states.</p>

<p>Trump's efforts have been complicated by his frequent descriptions of cities with large Black populations as crime-ridden and failing, as he did last week while discussing Milwaukee, which will host the Republican National Convention, with GOP lawmakers.</p>

<p>In Philadelphia, Trump lamented that "convenience stores are closing down left and right" and described statistics showing the city's murder rate falling substantially as "fake news." As of April, homicides in Philadelphia were down by more than a third compared to the prior year.</p>

<p>Trump also flashed his propensity for controversy at both stops, telling attendees that he had pitched Dana White, the head of Ultimate Fighting Championship, on an event that would pit the champion of his league against a competing "migrant league of fighters."</p>

<p>Trump has regularly highlighted instances of undocumented migrants committing violent crime and warned immigrants were "poisoning the blood of our country," while critics - including Biden - have argued the rhetoric is racially coded.</p>

<p>"I think the migrant guy might win," Trump said. "That's how tough they are. He didn't like that idea too much, but actually not the worst idea I've ever had."</p>

<p>Biden won Pennsylvania in 2020, and his hopes of carrying the state in November's rematch with Trump will hinge in part on his ability to turn out Black voters and hold on to working-class voters in the state. A Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll in May found Trump leads Biden 48% to 46% in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The state has become a focal point for his reelection bid. According to an internal memo from the Trump allied super-PAC, Make America Great Again Inc., the group has and will continue to center its efforts and funding across Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>More broadly, Biden has also struggled to sell blue-collar workers, important in states including Michigan, on his economic agenda.</p>

<p>Trump has been ramping up his campaigning after becoming the first former president convicted of a felony, in his New York hush-money trial. He has also managed to use the conviction to boost his war chest, with the campaign raising $141 million in May, surpassing the $85 million Biden raised that month.</p>

<p>Trump's visit to Washington on Saturday is his second this month. Last week, he returned to Capitol Hill for the first time since the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the US Capitol by supporters looking to block certification of the 2020 election, meeting with House and Senate Republicans.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/p3aqmncg_donald-trump_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has regularly highlighted instances of undocumented migrants committing violent crime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beyond-nvidia-the-search-for-ais-next-breakthrough-5950184]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Beyond Nvidia: The Search For AI's Next Breakthrough]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beyond-nvidia-the-search-for-ais-next-breakthrough-5950184]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 10:04:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For a few days, AI chip juggernaut Nvidia sat on the throne as the world's biggest company, but behind its staggering success are questions on whether new entrants can stake a claim to the artificial intelligence bonanza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For a few days, AI chip juggernaut Nvidia sat on the throne as the world's biggest company, but behind its staggering success are questions on whether new entrants can stake a claim to the artificial intelligence bonanza.</p>

<p>Nvidia, which makes the processors that are the only option to train generative AI's large language models, is now Big Tech's newest member and its stock market takeoff has lifted the whole sector.</p>

<p>Even tech's second rung on Wall Street has ridden on Nvidia's coattails with Oracle, Broadcom, HP and a spate of others seeing their stock valuations surge, despite sometimes shaky earnings.</p>

<p>Amid the champagne popping, startups seeking the attention of Silicon Valley venture capitalists are being asked to innovate -- but without a clear indication of where the next chapter of AI will be written.</p>

<p>When it comes to generative AI, doubts persist on what exactly will be left for companies that are not existing model makers, a field dominated by Microsoft-backed OpenAI, Google and Anthropic.</p>

<p>Most agree that competing with them head-on could be a fool's errand.</p>

<p>"I don't think that there's a great opportunity to start a foundational AI company at this point in time," said Mike Myer, founder and CEO of tech firm Quiq, at the Collision technology conference in Toronto.</p>

<p>Some have tried to build applications that use or mimic the powers of the existing big models, but this is being slapped down by Silicon Valley's biggest players.</p>

<p>"What I find disturbing is that people are not differentiating between those applications which are roadkill for the models as they progress in their capabilities, and those that are really adding value and will be here 10 years from now," said venture capital veteran Vinod Khosla.</p>

<p>- 'Won't keep up' -</p>

<p>The tough-talking Khosla is one of OpenAI's earliest investors.</p>

<p>"Grammarly won't keep up," Khosla predicted of the spelling and grammar checking app, and others similar to it.</p>

<p>He said these companies, which put only a "thin wrapper" around what the AI models can offer, are doomed.</p>

<p>One of the fields ripe for the taking is chip design, Khosla said, with AI demanding ever more specialized processors that provide highly specific powers.</p>

<p>"If you look across the chip history, we really have for the most part focused on more general chips," Rebecca Parsons, CTO at tech consultancy Thoughtworks, told AFP.</p>

<p>Providing more specialized processing for the many demands of AI is an opportunity seized by Groq, a hot startup that has built chips for the deployment of AI as opposed to its training, or inference -- the specialty of Nvidia's world-dominating GPUs.</p>

<p>Groq CEO Jonathan Ross told AFP that Nvidia won't be the best at everything, even if they are uncontested for generative AI training.</p>

<p>"Nvidia and (its CEO) Jensen Huang are like Michael Jordan... the greatest of all time in basketball. But inference is baseball, and we try and forget the time where Michael Jordan tried to play baseball and wasn't very good at it," he said.</p>

<p>Another opportunity will come from highly specialized AI that will provide expertise and know-how based on proprietary data which won't be co-opted by voracious big tech.</p>

<p>"Open AI and Google aren't going to build a structural engineer. They're not going to build products like a primary care doctor or a mental health therapist," said Khosla.</p>

<p>Profiting from highly specialized data is the basis of Cohere, another of Silicon Valley's hottest startups that pitches specifically-made models to businesses that are skittish about AI veering out of their control.</p>

<p>"Enterprises are skeptical of technology, and they're risk-averse, and so we need to win their trust and to prove to them that there's a way to adopt this technology that's reliable, trustworthy and secure," Cohere CEO Aidan Gomez told AFP.</p>

<p>When he was just 20 and working at Google, Gomez co-authored the seminal paper "Attention Is All You Need," which introduced Transformer, the architecture behind popular large language models like OpenAI's GPT-4.</p>

<p>The company has received funding from Nvidia and Salesforce Ventures and is valued in the billions of dollars.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/c47af5b_nvidia-_625x300_23_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nvidia is now Big Tech's newest member]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-had-another-secret-child-with-neuralink-employee-report-5950152]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Had Another Secret Child With Neuralink Employee: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-had-another-secret-child-with-neuralink-employee-report-5950152]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 09:59:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla and Neuralink CEO Elon Musk had another child with one of his employees earlier this year, reports suggest. Mr Musk and Shivon Zilis, head of Neuralink's special projects, had a third child together earlier this year, Bloomberg reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla and Neuralink CEO Elon Musk had another child with one of his employees earlier this year, reports suggest. Mr Musk and Shivon Zilis, head of Neuralink's special projects, had a third child together earlier this year, Bloomberg reported. The two already share a pair of twins who were born in 2021.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The tech billionaire has also filed a petition to change the children's names to "have their father's last name and contain their mother's last name as part of their middle name."</p>

<p>Mr Musk has 11 living children who are publicly known: five with his first wife author Justine Musk, three with the musician Grimes, and three with Ms Zilis. He has said that the world faces an underpopulation crisis and people with high IQs should procreate."</p>

<p>"If people don't have more children, civilization is going to crumble. Mark my words,” he had said in 2021, the same year he had twins with Ms Zilis with one of his employees.</p>

<p>Mr Zilis has said Mr Musk encouraged her to have children and later offered to be the sperm donor. “I can't possibly think of genes I would prefer for my children,” Zilis is quoted as saying in “Elon Musk,” a biography by author Walter Isaacson.</p>

<p>On Thursday, he reposted a chart that claims Europe is suffering from a “fertility crisis,” saying “civilization may end with a bang or with a whimper (in adult diapers)".&nbsp;</p>

<p>A recent Wall Street Journal report claimed that a woman, who resigned from SpaceX in 2013, alleged that Mr Musk had asked her to have his babies, on multiple occasions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The report also stated that the SpaceX CEO, who is accused of having sexual relationships with two of his employees, including an intern, had also exposed himself to a flight attendant in 2016 and offered to buy her a horse in exchange for sex acts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8trrs42_elon-musk_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A recent report claimed that a SpaceX employee alleged that Mr Musk had asked her to have his babies]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elephant-in-zambia-pulls-us-tourist-out-of-safari-vehicle-tramples-her-to-death-5949792]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elephant In Zambia Pulls Woman Out Of Safari Vehicle, Tramples Her To Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elephant-in-zambia-pulls-us-tourist-out-of-safari-vehicle-tramples-her-to-death-5949792]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 08:19:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to a police statement, her injuries included deep wounds on the right shoulder blade and forehead, a fractured left ankle, and a slightly depressed chest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a terrifying incident, a US tourist from New Mexico was killed by an elephant in Zambia after it attacked her vehicle during a safari drive on Wednesday. Officials reported that the elephant pulled Juliana Gle Tourneau, 64, out of&nbsp;the vehicle and trampled her, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/06/21/elephant-toss-us-tourist-trample-dead-zambia-21083502/">Metro</a></em> reported. The incident occurred near the Maramba Cultural Bridge in Livingstone when the group had stopped due to traffic caused by an elephant herd.</p>

<p>She was taken to a clinic in Mosi-oa-Tunya National Park, where she was declared dead on arrival. According to a police statement, her injuries included deep wounds on the right shoulder blade and forehead, a fractured left ankle, and a slightly depressed chest.</p>

<p>Ms Tourneau died around 5.50 pm ''after being knocked from a parked vehicle which had stopped due to traffic caused by elephants around the Maramba Cultural Bridge'', Southern Province Police Commissioner Auxensio Daka told Zambian station&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=1123915438722352">ZNBC</a></em>&nbsp;on Friday.</p>

<p>Officials did not say whether anyone else was injured or what led to the elephant's aggression.</p>

<p>This tragic event marks the second fatal elephant attack on a US tourist in Zambia this year. In March, Gail Mattson, a 79-year-old woman from Minnesota, was killed in a similar incident during a game drive in Zambia's Kafue National Park. An elephant charged and overturned the truck, resulting in her death and injuries to five others.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In response to these incidents, Zambian authorities have urged tourists to exercise extreme caution while observing wildlife. Similar concerns have been raised in neighbouring countries like Zimbabwe and Botswana, which have also reported increasing elephant populations and deadly attacks in recent years.</p>

<p>According to experts, human deaths are rare in encounters with elephants. ''This is a freak accident. It's probably just some sort of coming together of unfortunate circumstances that led to this,'' Nikhil Advani, a senior director at the World Wildlife Fund, a nonprofit that works on environmental protection and conservation efforts told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/22/world/africa/us-tourist-killed-elephant-zambia.html">New York Times.&nbsp;</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/56qa5vdg_elephant-_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Officials did not say whether anyone else was injured or what led to the elephants aggression.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-destroys-3-houthi-vessels-in-red-sea-rebels-strike-back-5949744]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Military Destroys 3 Houthi Vessels In Red Sea, Rebels Strike Back]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-destroys-3-houthi-vessels-in-red-sea-rebels-strike-back-5949744]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 08:00:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. forces destroyed three Iranian-backed Houthi uncrewed surface vessels in the Red Sea in the past 24 hours, the U.S. Central Command (CENTCOM) said on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. forces destroyed three Iranian-backed Houthi uncrewed surface vessels in the Red Sea in the past 24 hours, the U.S. Central Command (CENTCOM) said on Saturday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, the Houthis launched three anti-ship ballistic missiles into the Gulf of Aden but there were no injuries or significant damage reported by U.S., coalition, or merchant vessels, CENTCOM added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The U.S. military's Central Command also dismissed as "categorically false" recent claims about a successful attack by Houthi forces on the aircraft carrier Dwight D. Eisenhower.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/pr4n5o3c_houthi-rebels_625x300_26_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-u-turn-gives-green-card-hopes-to-indian-students-5949725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Green Card After Graduation? Donald Trump's U-Turn Gives Hopes To Indians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-u-turn-gives-green-card-hopes-to-indian-students-5949725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 07:56:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump, vying to return to the top post in elections due this year, has softened his stand on immigration with a new proposal that will benefit Indian and other foreign students.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump, vying to return to the top post in elections due this year, has softened his stand on immigration with a new proposal that will benefit Indian and other foreign students.</p>

<p>The Republican leader known for his staunch remarks against immigrants has promised that if he's elected, foreign students who graduate from US colleges will automatically get Green Card, which allows permanent residency in the US.</p>

<p>Trump said these students become multibillionaires after they return to their home countries like India and China after graduating from US colleges. He sought to replicate the same in the US.</p>

<p>The US presidential elections due in November is expected to see a second edition of President Joe Biden versus Donald Trump, in which immigration and deportation of illegal immigrants are among the key issues for voters.</p>

<p>Trump had earlier this year branded illegal immigrants "animals, not human" at an election campaign. He, however, said in a recent podcast that he always supported a merit-based legal immigration system.</p>

<p>He said in the "All-In" podcast that he plans to offer Green Cards automatically as part of a diploma to students who graduate from a US college, which will help them continue their stay in the country.</p>

<p>The podcast was hosted by Chamath Palihapitiya, Jason Calacanis, David Sacks, and David Friedberg - all venture capitalists, three of whom are immigrants.</p>

<p>Speaking in the podcast, Trump recalled "stories where people graduated from a top college or from a college, and they desperately wanted to stay here, they had a plan for a company, a concept, and they can't - they go back to India, they go back to China, they do the same basic company in those places...and they become multi-billionaires employing thousands and thousands of people, and it could have been done here."</p>

<p>A Green Card is an identity document for permanent residency in the United States.</p>

<p>The former president further lamented that "we lose people from Harvard, MIT, from the greatest schools".</p>

<p>He also reiterated his first-term policy of foreign students getting a Green Card after receiving a higher education degree in the STEM (science, technology, engineering, and math) field.</p>

<p>"Anybody graduates from a college, you go in there for two years or four years, if you graduate or you get a doctorate degree from a college, you should be able to stay in this country," Trump said.</p>

<p>"We force the brilliant people, the people that graduate from college, the people that are number one in their class from the best colleges, you have to be able to recruit these people and keep the people," the former president asserted.</p>

<p>He said some graduates at the top of the class can't even make a deal with the company because they don't think they will be able to stay in the country, but that is "going to end one day".</p>

<p>Trump's recent remarks were in contrast to the immigration policies of his administration when he was in power, which included restrictions on green cards and visas.</p>

<p>The US has over a million foreign students studying in colleges there, as of the 2022-23 academic year, and this figure can only be expected to rise.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3irh8p6g_trump_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump had earlier this year branded illegal immigrants "animals, not human".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fireworks-from-yacht-spark-forest-fire-on-greek-island-13-arrested-5949668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fireworks From Yacht Spark Forest Fire On Greek Island, 13 Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fireworks-from-yacht-spark-forest-fire-on-greek-island-13-arrested-5949668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 07:38:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident has caused widespread outrage in Greece, which is already grappling with multiple wildfires amidst its first heatwave of the year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thirteen people have been arrested following a forest fire on the Greek island of Hydra, which authorities believe was started by fireworks launched from a yacht. The fire, which started on Friday, devastated the island's sole pine forest. Although now under control, the fire presented significant challenges for firefighters who had to access the area by sea and use helicopters to drop water due to the lack of roads leading to the beach.</p>

<p>Hydra, southwest of Athens in the Saronic Gulf, is popular among foreign visitors and those travelling on yachts.</p>

<p>The latest blaze was ''caused by fireworks launched from a boat and burned the only pine forest on the island in a place that is difficult to access and has no road'', Hydra's firefighting team said on Facebook.</p>

<p>In a statement on Saturday, Greek authorities confirmed the arrest of 13 Greek citizens who are scheduled to appear before prosecutors on Sunday. An&nbsp;official said the people were arrested at an Athens area marina.</p>

<p>The incident has caused widespread outrage in Greece, which is already grappling with multiple wildfires amidst its first heatwave of the year. The country has been on high alert for wildfires due to dry conditions, strong winds, and high temperatures, which are expected to persist throughout the summer. Officials say 64 forest and brush fires have broken out in Greece over the past 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hydra's mayor, Giorgos Koukoudakis, expressed anger over the reckless actions that led to the fire.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are indignant that some people so irresponsibly throw fireworks into a pine forest," Hydra's mayor, Giorgos Koukoudakis, told Greek broadcaster ERT.</p>

<p>In a related incident, a 55-year-old volunteer firefighter succumbed to injuries sustained while combating a fire in the Ilia region of the Peloponnese peninsula.</p>

<p>Scientists have warned that fossil fuel emissions caused by humans are worsening the length and intensity of heat waves around the world.</p>

<p>Additionally, arson remains a significant problem, with 79 people arrested for arson last August. To combat this, Greece increased penalties for both deliberate and negligent arson last year, introducing fines of up to 200,000 Euro and jail sentences of up to 20 years​</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/uv3rfu5g_forest-fire_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hydra is popular among foreign visitors and those travelling on yachts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>