<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:37:20 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-2011-hit-and-run-is-fake-news-spread-by-russia-microsoft-6592237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' '2011 Hit-And-Run' Is Fake News Spread By Russia: Microsoft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-2011-hit-and-run-is-fake-news-spread-by-russia-microsoft-6592237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:35:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A false claim circulating on social media that Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralysed after an alleged hit-and-run in San Francisco in 2011 is the work of a covert Russian disinformation operation, according to new research by Microsoft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A false claim circulating on social media that Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralysed after an alleged hit-and-run in San Francisco in 2011 is the work of a covert Russian disinformation operation, according to new research by Microsoft.</p>

<p>Researchers found that the operation created a video, paid an actor to appear as the alleged victim, and spread the claim through a fake website for a non-existent San Francisco news outlet named "KBSF-TV". The Russian group responsible, which Microsoft dubs Storm-1516, is described as a Kremlin-aligned troll farm.</p>

<p>The discovery is a sign of Russia ramping up its foreign influence efforts ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election, Microsoft said.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the Russian embassy in Washington did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>"Russian influence operations initially struggled to pivot operations aimed at the Democratic campaign following President Biden's departure from the U.S. 2024 presidential race," a blog published on Tuesday by Microsoft said.</p>

<p>"In late August, however, elements of prolific Russian actor Storm-1516 began producing content implicating Vice President Harris and Governor Walz in outlandish fake conspiracy theories," Microsoft said, referring to Harris' running mate, Tim Walz.</p>

<p>Storm-1516 is known for producing misleading videos featuring on-screen or voice actors who impersonate whistleblowers or journalists that share false, scandalous information, experts say.</p>

<p>A website for KBSF-TV was created shortly before publishing its first related article about the alleged driving incident, according to online registration records. The claim was circulated on social media platforms, including X.com, using the hashtag #HitAndRunKamala.</p>

<p>The video was also shared on Sept. 3 on X.com by Aussie Cossack, who describes himself as a "Registered foreign agent for Sputnik News," with the message "make this go viral MAGA folks." In total, it is estimated the video has been viewed more than 2.7 million times.</p>

<p>"Many entities within the pro-Russian ecosystem advanced the video and its claims," said Microsoft's Threat Analysis Center. "Storm-1516 relies on some of these personalities, such as Aussie Cossack, to drive amplification of its videos."</p>

<p>Cossack did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Earlier this month the U.S. Justice Department filed money-laundering charges against two employees of Russian state media network RT for what officials said was a scheme to hire an American company to produce online content to influence the election.</p>

<p>US officials say Russia's goal is to exacerbate US political divisions and weaken public support for American military aid to Ukraine. Harris says if elected she will continue supporting Ukraine in its defence against Russia's invasion.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Social media claims about Kamala Harris' "hit-and-run" is fake news, a Microsoft research shows.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-3-600-food-packaging-chemicals-found-in-human-bodies-in-new-study-6592181]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 3,600 Food Packaging Chemicals Found In Human Bodies In New Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-3-600-food-packaging-chemicals-found-in-human-bodies-in-new-study-6592181]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:30:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Around 100 of these chemicals are considered to be of "high concern" to human health, said lead study author Birgit Geueke.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 3,600 chemicals used in food packaging or preparation have been detected in human bodies, some of which are hazardous to health, while little is known about others, a study published on Tuesday said. Around 100 of these chemicals are considered to be of "high concern" to human health, said lead study author Birgit Geueke from the Food Packaging Forum Foundation, a Zurich-based NGO.</p>

<p>Some of these chemicals are relatively well-studied and have already been found in human bodies, such as PFAS and bisphenol A -- both of which are the target of bans.</p>

<p>But little is known about the health effects of others, Geueke told AFP, calling for more research into how chemicals used in packaging end up being swallowed along with food.</p>

<p>The researchers had previously catalogued around 14,000 food contact chemicals (FCCs), which are capable of "migrating" into food from packaging made of plastic, paper, glass, metal or other materials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They can also come from other parts of the food-making process, such as from conveyer belts or kitchen utensils.</p>

<p>The researchers then searched for these chemicals in existing biomonitoring databases, which track chemicals in human samples.</p>

<p>The team was expecting to find a few hundred FCCs, Geueke said. Instead, they were surprised to find 3,601 -- a quarter of all the known FCCs.</p>

<p>Geueke emphasised that this study could not show that all these chemicals necessarily ended up in bodies from food packaging, as "other exposure sources are possible".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the "high concern" chemicals were numerous PFAS, also known as forever chemicals, which have been detected in many parts of the human body in recent years and linked to a range of health problems.</p>

<p>Also detected was bisphenol A, a hormone-disrupting chemical used to make plastics that has already been banned from baby bottles in many countries.</p>

<p>Another hormone-disrupting chemical was phthalates, which has been linked to infertility.</p>

<p>Less is known about oligomers, which are also byproducts of plastic production.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There is almost no evidence on the health effects of these chemicals," Geueke said.</p>

<p>When it comes to toxicology, an old saying is that "the dose makes the poison".</p>

<p>A limitation of the study was that it could not say whether there were particularly high concentrations of any of the chemicals, Geueke acknowledged.</p>

<p>But she warned that these chemicals can interact with each other, pointing to a single sample that had up to 30 different PFAS.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Geueke recommended that people reduce their contact time with packaging -- and to avoid heating up food in the packaging it came in.</p>

<p>Duane Mellor, an expert in evidence-based medicine at the UK's Aston University and not involved in the research, praised the "very thorough piece of work".</p>

<p>"However, it does not cover how much of these chemicals we are exposed to and hints at other sources of these chemicals in our environment," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Rather than being "unduly alarmed", Mellor suggested that people "demand better data and minimise unnecessary exposure to chemicals which may ultimately impact our health".</p>

<p>Some of the chemicals are also already facing bans.</p>

<p>The European Union is in the final stages of banning the use of PFAS in food packaging. The EU has also proposed a similar ban for bisphenol A from the end of this year.</p>

<p>The study was published in the Journal of Exposure Science and Environmental Epidemiology.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/55a8ckv_food-packaging-chemicals-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Pagers Turned Bombs And Why Israel Is Being Blamed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:19:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of pagers exploded within seconds across the Lebanon yesterday in a synchronized attack targeting the US-designated terror group Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of pagers exploded within seconds across the Lebanon yesterday in a synchronized attack targeting the US-designated terror group Hezbollah. The explosions killed at least nine and injured 2,800 individuals in the country that has been caught up in the Israel-Palestine tensions in its backyard.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, the political force running Lebanon, has blamed Israel for the attack. Throughout Gaza war, it supported Hamas and exchanged fire across its southern border with Israel in support for its Palestinian group.</p>

<p>No country or group has claimed responsibility for the attack yet. But fingers pointing at Israel raise a big question over the capabilities of Mossad, the Israeli spy agency known for carrying out targeted attacks on foreign soils.</p>

<h2><strong>Pager bombs - a reality?</strong></h2>

<p>Pagers are wireless low-tech means of communication that lost popularity in the nineties with the emergence of mobile phones. They can display text messages but not relay voice calls. Hezbollah uses pagers to avoid location-tracking by Israel.</p>

<p>The ones used that exploded yesterday came fitted with explosives from Taiwan, reported the New York Times. Gold Apollo, a Taiwanese firm, had placed the order and the pagers were tampered by Israeli agents before they arrived in Lebanon, the US-based newspaper said citing unnamed officials.</p>

<p>Some 3,000 pagers were part of a recent order for Gold Apollo that included mostly its AR-924 model, reported the NYT.</p>

<p>Israeli intelligence infiltrated the production process of the pagers and fitted the explosives that could be triggered remotely without any suspicion, said news agency AFP citing a Brussel-based security analyst.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884">Inside Lebanon Politics: Hezbollah, Iran And A Larger Battle For Hegemony</a></p>

<p>Mossad had been planning the attack for months, according to Reuters. They fitted the Taiwan-made devices with up to 3 grams of explosives that went unnoticed by Hezbollah, it reported cited Lebanese sources.</p>

<p>The trigger was activated and about 3,000 pagers exploded when a codeword was sent to them, the news agency reported.</p>

<p>Gold Apollo founder Hsu Ching-Kuang has denied making the pagers. He said a European firm that had the right to use his company's brand name had made the pagers. This claim could not be independently verified.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Israel Is Being Blamed</strong></h2>

<p>Early Tuesday morning, Israeli PMO released a statement that the safe return of residents evacuated from northern Israel - which borders southern Lebanon - was among its war goals.</p>

<p>Hours later, blasts rocked Lebanon.</p>

<p>Mossad, which has a long history of carrying out sophisticated remote attacks on foreign soil, came under question though Israel never claims responsibility for such covert operations.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229">3 Grams Of Explosives Per Pager: Israel's Complex Op To Hurt Hezbollah</a></p>

<p>The latest such incident that was linked to Israel was the killing of a top Hamas commander in Iran. Ismail Haniyeh's assassination in a blast at a high-security VIP compound in a posh Tehran locality was carried out by Mossad, The Telegraph (UK) reported. The bomb was smuggled in months ago, the NYT had said, and was triggered remotely after Haniyeh entered that particular room.</p>

<p>Mossad also played a big role in the 'Operation Wrath of God' covert operation, codenamed Bayonet, which was activated to avenge the murders of 11 Israeli athletes by Palestinian operatives at the 1972 Olympics in Munich.</p>

<p>During the operation, they used telephones not only to track their enemies but to kill them. A top leader of the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) was killed in Paris in a blast that occurred after he answered a telephone call. This marked the emergence of what came to be known as telephone bombs.</p>

<p>Mobile phones were the next target as technology evolved. A bomb-making expert of the Hamas was killed in 1996 after his mobile phone blasted when he answered a call.</p>

<p>Linked or not, attacks on Palestinians and their allies using telephone, mobile phone, and now pagers complete a cycle of using communication means as weapons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iuermu3_pagers-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pagers are wireless low-tech means of communication that lost popularity in the nineties. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-loses-canadas-closely-watched-montreal-by-election-6592098]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau's Party Loses Closely-Watched Montreal By-Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-loses-canadas-closely-watched-montreal-by-election-6592098]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:18:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canada's ruling Liberal Party lost a long-held parliamentary seat in Montreal on Tuesday, a sign of mounting trouble for Prime Minister Justin Trudeau.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada's ruling Liberal Party lost a long-held parliamentary seat in Montreal on Tuesday, a sign of mounting trouble for Prime Minister Justin Trudeau.</p>

<p>The loss marks the second high-profile defeat for Trudeau, who has held the top elected office in Canada since 2015, after a Conservative party candidate won a June by-election in the Toronto area.</p>

<p>Monday's election in the LaSalle-Emard-Verdun district of Montreal was won by Bloc Quebecois candidate Louis-Philippe Sauve, who received 28% of the votes compared to 27.2% cast for Liberal Party candidate Laura Palestini, according to Elections Canada.</p>

<p>"Obviously, it would have been nicer to be able to win and hold Verdun, but there's more work to do and we're going to stay focused on doing it," Trudeau said to reporters Tuesday in response to the election results.</p>

<p>The election was notable for having 91 candidates on the ballot, although most were not running serious campaigns; rather, they signed up for the race as a show of protest for the Longest Ballot Committee, an activist group which seeks electoral reforms in Canada.</p>

<p>Trudeau and the Liberal Party face all-time low popularity after nine years in power, with Conservative party leader Pierre Poilievre leading Trudeau in polls.</p>

<p>According to a Leger poll conducted last week, Conservatives lead Liberals in voting intention 45% to 25%.</p>

<p>Elections must be called by October of next year.</p>

<p>Trudeau's government suffered a major setback this month when a minority leftwing party ended its coalition agreement with the Liberal Party, putting the latter at risk of losing confidence votes.</p>

<p>Despite the upheaval, experts believe elections will not be called in Canada until next spring instead of the upcoming fall or winter.</p>

<p>Trudeau said on Tuesday he plans to remain in office, saying there's "work we're going to continue to do."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5segqcpc_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau's ruling Liberal Party has lost a long-held parliamentary seat in Montreal, Canada.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-roberson-author-john-grisham-joins-bid-to-save-man-on-death-row-for-daughters-death-6591920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Author John Grisham Joins Bid To Save Man On Death Row For Daughter's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-roberson-author-john-grisham-joins-bid-to-save-man-on-death-row-for-daughters-death-6591920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:51:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lawmakers in Texas, medical experts and the best-selling novelist John Grisham are pushing to save an autistic death row inmate whose daughter died in 2002 in a tragedy blamed on shaken baby syndrome.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lawmakers in Texas, medical experts and the best-selling novelist John Grisham are pushing to save an autistic death row inmate whose daughter died in 2002 in a tragedy blamed on shaken baby syndrome. Robert Roberson, 57, is scheduled to be executed on October 17 for the death of his two-year-old daughter Nikki in 2002.</p>

<p>Roberson took the girl to a hospital with severe head trauma and the child died the next day.</p>

<p>Lawyers for Roberson filed papers Tuesday with Texas Governor Greg Abbott and the Texas Board of Pardons and Paroles seeking clemency, or failing that, a 180-day stay of execution.</p>

<p>They argued that the diagnosis of shaken baby syndrome, made at the hospital where the child died, was erroneous.</p>

<p>In a letter to Texas officials, 34 doctors argued that the cause of death was in fact severe pneumonia, aggravated by the little girl's being prescribed the wrong medication.</p>

<p>The appeal also argues that Roberson's autism, which was not officially diagnosed until 2018, was misconstrued at the time as showing indifference to the death of the toddler and that this perception weighed heavily in his conviction.</p>

<p>"What's amazing about Robert's case is that there was no crime," Grisham, author of best-selling thrillers such as "The Firm" and "A Time to Kill," told a news conference. Grisham is a former lawyer who has been active in fighting cases of wrongful conviction.</p>

<p>"When you get into wrongful convictions you realize how many innocent people are in prison and how we could stop it, if we had the political gumption to do so. These cases really keep me awake at night," he said.</p>

<p>Roberson's attorney, Gretchen Sween, said "the state of Texas is preparing, in essence, to execute Forrest Gump." She was alluding to the gentle, mildly disabled character played by Tom Hanks in the 1994 film of the same name.</p>

<p>Sween argued that during the medical crisis involving his daughter, Roberson "shut down, and his external lack of affect was judged as a lack of caring."</p>

<p>Former police officer Brian Wharton, who led the investigation at the time, said the diagnosis of shaken baby syndrome "led the investigation from that point forward to the exclusion of all other possibilities."</p>

<p>"Knowing everything that I know now, I am firmly convinced that Robert is an innocent man," said Wharton, who is now a Methodist minister.</p>

<p>Wharton said that for the rest of his life he will regret his role in Roberson's arrest and prosecution.</p>

<p>Eighty-four Texas lawmakers signed a letter in support of the request for clemency for Roberson, more than a third of them Republicans.</p>

<p>These legislators said they are acting out of "grave concern that Texas may put him to death for a crime that did not occur, as new evidence suggests."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t9q9t8og_robert-roberson_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Robert Roberson's daughter died in 2002 in a tragedy blamed on shaken baby syndrome]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joachim-de-bellay-tomb-an-excavation-may-solve-centuries-old-mystery-at-notre-dame-in-paris-6591872]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[An Excavation May Solve Centuries-Old Mystery At Notre Dame In Paris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joachim-de-bellay-tomb-an-excavation-may-solve-centuries-old-mystery-at-notre-dame-in-paris-6591872]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:46:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A centuries-old mystery surrounding a poet buried in Notre Dame in Paris could be close to being solved thanks to archaeological digs at the world-famous cathedral, researchers said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A centuries-old mystery surrounding a poet buried in Notre Dame in Paris could be close to being solved thanks to archaeological digs at the world-famous cathedral, researchers said on Tuesday. The exact whereabouts of the tomb of Joachim de Bellay, a French Renaissance poet, has puzzled researchers for many years.</p>

<p>De Bellay, a member of a literary group known as La Pleiade, died aged 37 in 1560. His family asked for him to be buried in Notre Dame's Saint-Crepin chapel. But when the site was renovated in 1758, no trace of his remains could be found.</p>

<p>His remains' precise location was shrouded in mystery until 2022 when archaeologists, sifting through the site in the aftermath of the 2019 fire that destroyed much of Notre Dame, found two tombs at the cathedral's crossing.</p>

<p>The scientists, working for the national institute for preventative archaeology, rapidly identified one of them as that of Antoine de La Porte, a cleric who died in the early 1700s.</p>

<p>But they could not immediately figure out who was buried in the other one.</p>

<p>Using modern methods of analysis, the researchers began to find clues as to his possibly identity. All pointed to de Bellay.</p>

<p>A deformation of his iliac bone told them that he did a lot of horse-riding.</p>

<p>De Bellay "was a skilled rider, he went from Paris to Rome on horseback", Eric Cubrezy, a doctor and archaeologist, told reporters.</p>

<p>In addition, an incision made by a saw in the corpse's skull, as well as a broken sternum, suggested the body had undergone an autopsy before being embalmed -- just like de Bellay.</p>

<p>The final, and most telling, clue was traces of a rare illness, a bone tuberculosis leading to chronic meningitis, consistent with the poet's medical history.</p>

<p>French daily Le Monde, describing the mystery around the missing corpse as "a cold case", said the latest find was the "most spectacular result" of the Notre Dame digs launched after the 2019 catastrophic fire.</p>

<p>The archaeologists themselves preferred to remain cautious.</p>

<p>"There are still some doubts," said Christophe Besnier, one of the scientists in charge of the excavation site.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mrknfbd_notre-dames-dead-poet-mystery-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joachim de Bellay's remains' precise location was shrouded in mystery until 2022]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-of-craters-suggests-earth-once-had-saturn-like-rings-6591771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Of Craters Suggests Earth Once Had Saturn-Like Rings]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-of-craters-suggests-earth-once-had-saturn-like-rings-6591771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:30:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The study said that the asteroid belt was formed due to the break-up of an asteroid passing within Earth's Roche limit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earth has had a long history, but millions of years ago, the planet even had Saturn-like ring of debris around it. Surprised? A new study by Andy Tomkins and his colleagues at Monash University in Melbourne has suggested that the rings lasted for tens of millions of years, and may have affected the planet's climate. The study is based on the assessment of 21 asteroid craters from the 'Ordovician impact spike' period 466 million years ago. The researchers said these crater sites were caused by larger objects in a previously unidentified ring being pulled out of orbit and crashing into Earth.</p>

<p>The study has been published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0012821X24004230?via%3Dihub"><em>Earth and Planetary Science Letters</em></a>. The team noticed the asteroids that the craters were located in a narrow band of land close to the equator.</p>

<p>Asteroids normally strike at random locations, but looking at this pattern, researchers feel that it happened after Earth's close encounter with a large asteroid millions of years ago.</p>

<p>They have theorised in the study that the asteroid broke apart due to tidal forces and formed a debris ring around our planet, similar to the rings seen around Saturn.</p>

<p>"Over millions of years, material from this ring gradually fell to Earth, creating the spike in meteorite impacts observed in the geological record," Mr Tomkins was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/space/earth-asteroid-saturn-ring-hidden-craters-b2614683.html"><em>The Independent</em></a>.</p>

<p>"We also see that layers in sedimentary rocks from this period contain extraordinary amounts of meteorite debris," he explained.</p>

<p>But how did the craters emerge so close to the equator? Mr Tomkins and his team point to the movement of continents due to plate tectonics. They say at that time, all the sites would have been located close to the equator.</p>

<p>The team also relied on previous research having identified a consistent meteorite signature in a number of limestone deposits, also from that time and also once close to the equator.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1aie6a3_earth-saturn-like-rings_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The asteroid belt existed around Earth more than 450 million years ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kristina-khorram-once-diddys-right-hand-now-his-manipulator-in-chief-in-sex-trafficking-case-6591462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Rappers' Trusted Aide Linked To Sex Trafficking In Ongoing Investigation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kristina-khorram-once-diddys-right-hand-now-his-manipulator-in-chief-in-sex-trafficking-case-6591462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:02:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hip-hop mogul Sean Diddy' Combs' chief of staff, Kristina Khorram, who was once described as his "right hand", is now considered a "manipulator in chief", sources close to the federal sex trafficking investigation have said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hip-hop mogul Sean ‘Diddy' Combs' chief of staff, Kristina Khorram, who was once described as his “right hand”, is now considered a “manipulator in chief”, sources close to the federal sex trafficking investigation have said.</p>

<p>Combs, 54, was indicted on Tuesday on three federal counts: sex trafficking, racketeering, and transportation to engage in prostitution. Despite pleading not guilty, Combs remains in custody after a judge rejected his $50 million bail request, reported the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/17/entertainment/sean-diddy-combs-manipulator-in-chief-kristina-khorram/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">NY Post</a>.</p>

<p>The federal indictment accuses Combs of orchestrating a sex trafficking operation with the help of “certain employees”, including high-ranking supervisors. These employees allegedly facilitated sexual performances, referred to as “Freak Offs,” that involved sex workers and were organised to include “controlled substances, baby oil lubricant, extra linens, and lighting.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the indictment does not name specific individuals, sources suggest Kristina Khorram, who has not been charged with any crime, may hold vital information about the operation. "If anybody is the gatekeeper, Kristina would know everything," a source told the NY Post.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier this year, federal raids at Combs' mansions uncovered narcotics and over 1,000 bottles of baby oil and lubricant. Investigators have reportedly obtained key evidence, including text messages and recordings, some allegedly implicating Khorram.</p>

<p>In 2021, Diddy publicly praised Khorram, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10159056349829697&amp;id=23291809696&amp;set=a.408569254696&amp;locale=sl_SI ">posting on Facebook</a> that the 37-year-old has been his “right hand for the last 8 years” and has “consistently proven to execute and get s**t done”. “Don't know how I'd function without her,” he wrote.</p>

<p>However, allegations against Kristina Khorram have surfaced in a separate lawsuit filed by rapper Lil Rod (real name Rodney Jones) in February 2024. In his suit, Khorram is compared to Ghislaine Maxwell, the notorious aide of sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, and is accused of “ordering sex workers and prostitutes” for Combs.</p>

<p>The lawsuit also claims Khorram required Combs' household staff to carry a “fanny pack” filled with various drugs, including cocaine, GHB and ecstasy, to satisfy the hip-hop star's drug habits.</p>

<p>Lil Rod's lawsuit also states that Khorram “knowingly and intentionally participated in, perpetrated, assisted and facilitated a sex-trafficking venture,” and alleges she was instrumental in organising Combs' alleged “Freak Off” events. According to the suit, another employee, Stevie J, was recruited to help find sex workers for these parties.</p>

<p>Diddy's legal team has denied all allegations, dismissing Lil Rod's claims as fabrications. A source suggested that Khorram might choose to cooperate with federal authorities. “At least if she's smart, she will be,” the source added.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mo9uurjg_kristina-khorram-facebook_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kristina Khorram has not been charged with any crime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-long-road-to-1600-pennsylvania-avenue-joe-bidens-five-decade-political-career-6591534]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Long Road To White House: Joe Biden's Five-Decade Political Career]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-long-road-to-1600-pennsylvania-avenue-joe-bidens-five-decade-political-career-6591534]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 11:56:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the 46th President of the United States, Joe Biden's leadership has been marked by several challenges. But his steady hand and experience have allowed Mr Biden to push forward.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joseph Robinette Biden Jr, the 46th and current President of the United States, has had a storied and resilient political career spanning over five decades. His journey from a young senator to reaching the pinnacle of power in the US (as President in the White House located on 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, DC) has been marked by personal tragedy, political triumphs and a life-long commitment to public service.</p>

<h3><strong>Early Life and Background</strong></h3>

<p>Joe Biden was born on November 20, 1942, in Scranton, Pennsylvania into a working-class family. Mr Biden's early years were shaped by the economic challenges faced by his parents during and after World War II. His father, Joseph Biden Sr, struggled with financial difficulties, working as a car salesman after losing his earlier business. His mother, Catherine Eugenia Finnegan Biden, was a homemaker who played a significant role in shaping his strong moral values and sense of responsibility.</p>

<p>Mr Biden's family later moved to Claymont, Delaware, where he would spend the majority of his childhood and eventually attend Archmere Academy, a private Catholic school. He was an active student, participating in sports and developing leadership skills that would serve him in his political future. Mr Biden graduated from the University of Delaware in 1965 with a degree in history and political science, followed by a law degree from Syracuse University in 1968.</p>

<h3><strong>Family Life: Tragedy And Resilience</strong></h3>

<p>Joe Biden's personal life has been marred by deep loss and tragedy, which has significantly shaped his character and approach to public service. In 1966, Biden married Neilia Hunter, and the couple had three children: Beau, Hunter and Naomi. However, in 1972, just weeks after Mr Biden was elected as a senator from Delaware, Neilia and one-year-old Naomi were tragically killed in a car accident. His sons, Beau and Hunter, were severely injured but survived.</p>

<p>Mr Biden seriously considered stepping down from his newly won Senate seat to care for his sons but was persuaded to continue by colleagues. This moment solidified Biden's reputation as a family-oriented politician who always placed his loved ones first.</p>

<p>In 1977, Mr Biden married Jill Jacobs, an educator with a doctorate in education, who has stood by his side through the highs and lows of his career. Together, they have a daughter, Ashley Biden, who is a social worker and activist.</p>

<p>Tragedy struck Mr Biden again when his eldest son, Beau Biden, who had served as Delaware's attorney general and was considered a rising star in Democratic politics, died from brain cancer in 2015. Beau's death was a crushing blow for Mr Biden, and he often speaks of his son's legacy as a major influence in his decision to run for President.</p>

<h3><strong>Political Career: From Senator To Vice President</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Biden's political career began at the age of 30 when he became the sixth-youngest Senator in US history. Representing Delaware, he held his Senate seat for 36 years, focusing on issues such as foreign policy, criminal justice, and civil rights. Mr Biden was known for his bipartisan approach to governance, working across the aisle with Republicans on key legislation.</p>

<p>During his time in the Senate, Mr Biden chaired both the Senate Committee on Judiciary and the Senate Foreign Relations Committee. He played a pivotal role in shaping US foreign policy, particularly in the Balkans during the 1990s and in the lead-up to the Iraq War in 2003. His support for the 1994 Crime Bill, which increased penalties for certain crimes and expanded the prison system, has been both lauded and criticised in later years, especially as the conversation around criminal justice reform has evolved.</p>

<p>In 2008, Biden was selected as Barack Obama's running mate. As Vice President, Biden helped steer the country through the 2008 financial crisis and played a key role in passing the Affordable Care Act. He also led initiatives related to foreign policy, particularly with respect to Iraq and Ukraine, and domestic efforts on cancer research, mental health, and violence against women.</p>

<h3><strong>2020 Presidential Campaign And Victory</strong></h3>

<p>Joe Biden's path to the presidency was far from smooth. After two unsuccessful runs in 1988 and 2008, Mr Biden entered the 2020 Democratic primary initially as a moderate candidate in a crowded field. His experience, moderate positions and perceived electability against then-President Donald Trump helped him secure the Democratic nomination.</p>

<p>The 2020 election was one of the most contentious in US history, held amid a global pandemic, widespread economic uncertainty and social unrest following the murder of George Floyd. Mr Biden ran on a platform focused on unifying the country, combating the COVID-19 pandemic and addressing systemic racism. His choice of Senator Kamala Harris as his running mate also made history, as she became the first woman, the first Black woman, and the first South Asian American to serve as Vice President. She is now running for President.</p>

<p>On November 7, 2020, Mr Biden was declared the winner of the presidential election, securing 306 electoral votes to Trump's 232. Despite challenges to the results and the Capitol insurrection on January 6, 2021, he was inaugurated on January 20, 2021, as the 46th President of the United States.</p>

<h3><strong>Age And Experience: A Historic Presidency</strong></h3>

<p>At 78 years old, Joe Biden became the oldest president in US history at the time of his inauguration. His age became a topic of both concern and admiration with critics questioning his cognitive abilities, which ultimately led him to drop off the race and support Ms Harris.</p>

<p>The concerns around Mr Biden's age became more profound since his disastrous performance in a television debate against Donald Trump in June this year. Mr Biden's confused answers and body language led to calls that the 81-year-old was too old for the job. He ultimately dropped out of the race on July 21.</p>

<h3><strong>Policies And Achievements As President</strong></h3>

<p>Since taking office, Joe Biden's presidency has been defined by his handling of the COVID-19 pandemic, economic recovery, and his push for large-scale infrastructure investment. His administration passed the $1.9 trillion American Rescue Plan, which provided financial relief to millions of Americans affected by the pandemic, expanded unemployment benefits and accelerated vaccine distribution.</p>

<p>In November 2021, Mr Biden signed the $1.2 trillion Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, which aimed to modernise America's roads, bridges and public transit systems, and expand broadband internet access. The legislation was seen as a major bipartisan victory for Mr Biden, who had campaigned on his ability to work across party lines.</p>

<p>The Democrat leader has also focused on issues like climate change, proposing ambitious goals to reduce carbon emissions and promote clean energy. His administration rejoined the Paris Agreement and committed to making the US a leader in the global fight against climate change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ofrrpqv8_joe-biden-afp_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden dropped out of US presidential race in July this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-polls-frontrunners-whats-at-stake-implications-for-india-6591362]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Polls: Frontrunners, What's At Stake, Implications For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-polls-frontrunners-whats-at-stake-implications-for-india-6591362]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 11:28:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The political landscape in Sri Lanka is set to change as its citizens elect a new President on Saturday. Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The political landscape in Sri Lanka is set to change as its citizens elect a new President on Saturday. Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates in the country's first election after the people's uprising of 2022, which led to then President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's ouster.</p>

<p>This year's election is dominated by two major alliances, the SJB (Samagi Jana Balawegaya) and the NPP (National People's Power), apart from various smaller parties and independent candidates.</p>

<p>President Ranil Wickremesinghe of the UNP (United National Party) is contesting as an independent. Wickremesinghe, popularly known as RW, is being supported by many rebel legislators of the SLPP (Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna) headed by former president Mahinda Rajapaksa. Also in the contest are opposition leader Sajith Premadasa from the SJB alliance; leftist leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake of the JVP (Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna) - the presidential candidate of NPP - and Mahinda's son, Namal Rajapaksa, as the SLPP candidate.</p>

<p>Poll surveys and experts suggest that Lankan voters are prioritising issues such as economy, education, health, law, and security. Matters of corruption and wrongdoing among politicians, which dominated the electoral narrative, have receded into the background after the 2022 unrest. Since most governments in the past didn't solve the corruption issue, people feel it's better to talk about development. They hope to elect a leader who can pull them out of dire poverty.</p>

<h2><strong>Gloomy past</strong></h2>

<p>In the last election, held after the Easter bombings on April 21, 2019, Gotabaya Rajapaksa of SLPP (Namal's uncle) won a decisive victory and Sajith Premadasa came second. However, three years later, the world saw Sri Lankans oust President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, having endured a steady economic slide. The flawed economic and monetary policies of Gotabaya, along with the COVID-19 pandemic that dented tourism - a chunk of the economy - resulted in an unsustainable debt level. In April 2022, Sri Lanka defaulted on its debt and asked the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for assistance. The Russia-Ukraine war further aggravated the crisis with rising food, medicine and fuel prices resulting in mass protests never seen before in the country's history.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Sri Lankas Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/oaet1ah_sajith-premadasa-afp_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Sri Lankas Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Sri Lanka's Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters.</p>
</div>

<p>The uprising was given the name of '<em>Janatha Aragalaya</em>' (a Sinhala term). Then Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa resigned and subsequently, his brother Gotabaya Rajapaksa quit as President and fled. Ranil Wickremesinghe, a former minister, became Prime Minister. In July 2022, Ranil took over as president through a parliamentary vote with the support of the Rajapaksas' party SLPP, which still has the majority in the legislature. Ranil Wickremesinghe adopted severe austerity measures, with support from the IMF.</p>

<h2><strong>New leaders</strong></h2>

<p>Gotabaya Rajapaksa's inept governance and his decision to leave the country tarred the image of the Rajapaksa clan and the SLPP the most. Most SLPP MPs are supporting either Ranil or Sajith in this election. Namal Rajapaksa, they say, is just a symbolic candidate to keep the SLPP alive.</p>

<p>Sajith's SJB has the support of the Tamil and Muslim minorities, who form 11% and 9% of the population.</p>

<p>Though Tamil parties have fielded a common candidate, the largest party ITAK (Ilankai Tamil Arasu Kachchi) has extended its support to Sajith Premadasa. In 2019 also, Tamils had voted for Sajith but there was an unprecedented consolidation of Sinhala votes behind Gotabhaya Rajapaksa after the Easter bombings, which helped him win the election.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="National Peoples Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jcgsatu_anura-kumara-dissanayaka-afp_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="National Peoples Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">National People's Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally.</p>
</div>

<p>The political space created by Rajapaksas' dismissal was filled by Anura Kumara Dissanayake and the JVP, who urged Sri Lankans to go for a broader change. Once in the margins, the party has emerged as a credible, major political force.</p>

<p>As far as Ranil Wickremesinghe is concerned, most members of his party UNP are now with Sajith, though he has support from some legislators of the SLPP like state Defence Minister Premitha Bandara Tennakoon. Ranil is banking on his handling of the economic crisis to fetch him votes.</p>

<p>"People want change this time. They don't want to vote for the same party and old candidates. The new voters, especially on social media, are rooting for Anura Dissanayake. However, on the ground Sajith has a lot of support base, especially in the rural areas," says Thushara Gooneratne, editor-in-chief, Mawrata News.</p>

<p>"Most people think of Sajith as pro-poor just like his father, former President R Premadasa."</p>

<h2><strong>India's Stake</strong></h2>

<p>In recent times, anti-India sentiment has surged in the neighbourhood, because of various reasons. Be it Nepal, Maldives, Sri Lanka or Bangladesh, politicians have been successful in diverting the people's ire towards India.</p>

<p>For India, the sorry plight of the Tamil population in the north and east of Sri Lanka has been a concern for a long time. Successive Lankan governments have failed to implement the 13th Amendment signed as part of India-Sri Lanka agreement in 1987, which provided for devolution of powers to local governments in the north and the east. India, in fact, raised the Sri Lankan Tamil issue at the 51st session of the United Nations Human Rights Council in Geneva in 2022. With the new government, India would like to push for the restoration of provincial councils, which would give a measure of autonomy to Lankan Tamils.</p>

<p>India has stakes in a stable and peaceful Sri Lanka. It wants to restrict China's growing interference in the country because of its geo-strategic location in the Indo-Pacific. The 99-year lease of Hambantota port to China in 2017, feeding the debt-trap narrative, has exacerbated India's concerns.</p>

<p>Anura Dissanayake's party has often been seen as close to China, India's principal geopolitical rival. But for some time now, Dissanayake has enjoyed a different kind of authority within Sri Lankan politics, which has in turn earned him recognition as a rising political force even from India's point of view. As a reflection of this, New Delhi invited Dissanayake in February to engage with him.</p>

<p>"Whoever wins this time will engage with India. Sajith is pro-India. But even Dissanayake, who was known to be anti-India before. India is important for Sri Lanka's growth and stability," says Thushara.</p>

<p>India needs all the goodwill it can command in order to navigate the increasing complexities in the neighbourhood, The escalating regional conflicts and a continuous shift in the global economic order. A friendly, stable neighbourhood is a good start.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8ougknao_sri-lanka-polls_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-instagrams-teen-accounts-will-protect-underage-users-6591169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Instagram's "Teen Accounts" Will Protect Underage Users]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-instagrams-teen-accounts-will-protect-underage-users-6591169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:58:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Instagram has introduced new safety measures to better protect underage users from online harm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Instagram has introduced new safety measures to better protect underage users from online harm. The key change is the creation of "Teen Accounts," designed to shield users aged 13 to 17 from the mental health challenges often linked to social media use.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why the update?</strong></h2>

<p>Experts and authorities have long criticised Instagram for its role in worsening mental health problems such as anxiety, addiction, cyberbullying, eating disorders and low self-esteem, among teens. Governments and advocacy groups around the world have called for stronger safeguards. Some, like in the US and Australia, are setting age restrictions for social media use.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meta, Instagram's parent company, response is this significant update that defaults teens' accounts to private, limits who can contact them, and controls what content they are exposed to.</p>

<h2><strong>Features of "Teen Accounts"</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Private accounts - Teens aged 13 to 17 will have their accounts set to private by default, making it harder for strangers to view or interact with their profiles.</li>
	<li>Messaging restrictions - Direct messaging (DM) will have tighter controls, allowing teens to receive messages only from people they follow. This reduces the chances of contact with unwanted or harmful individuals.</li>
	<li>Sensitive content restrictions - Teens will have limited exposure to potentially harmful or inappropriate content.</li>
	<li>Limited interactions - Interaction with adult accounts that do not follow them back will be limited, reducing risks like unsolicited DMs or predatory behaviour.</li>
	<li>Time limit reminders - Teens will receive notifications encouraging them to set time limits on how long they use the app. This will promote healthier usage habits.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Parental supervision</strong></h2>

<p>Meta is also introducing a 'Parents' Supervision Feature', providing parents with more control over their teen's Instagram activity:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Parents can set maximum daily screen time for their children.</li>
	<li>They can see what topics their teen is viewing and monitor who they are chatting with.</li>
	<li>Parents can block access to the app during certain hours to help regulate screen time.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Age Verification: How it works</strong></h2>

<p>Instagram will use new technology to verify user ages:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Partnering with Yoti, Instagram will allow teens to verify their age through a video selfie.</li>
	<li>Teens can also ask their mutual friends to verify their age if required.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/qqv8pi2_instagram-generic-unsplash_625x300_23_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new Instagram update defaults teenagers' accounts to private.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tupperware-files-for-bankruptcy-after-years-long-sales-struggle-6591096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tupperware Files For Bankruptcy After Years-Long Sales Struggle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tupperware-files-for-bankruptcy-after-years-long-sales-struggle-6591096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:41:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tupperware Brands Corp. filed for bankruptcy following a years-long struggle with sales declines and growing competition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tupperware Brands Corp. filed for bankruptcy following a years-long struggle with sales declines and growing competition.</p>

<p>Publicly-traded Tupperware filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection, listing assets of between $500 million to $1 billion and liabilities of $1 billion to $10 billion, according to its court filing. The company will seek court approval to facilitate a sale process of the business and to continue operating during bankruptcy proceedings, it said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>The kitchenware company, which for decades dominated the world of food storage, since 2020 had warned of doubt in its ability to stay in business. As of June of this year, it planned to close its only US factory and lay off almost 150 employees.</p>

<p>The bankruptcy filing in Delaware follows months-long negotiations between Tupperware and its lenders over how to manage more than $700 million in loans. The creditors had agreed to give it some breathing room on that debt, but the business continued to deteriorate.</p>

<p>Tupperware founder Earl Tupper in 1946 introduced its plastic products to the public, and subsequently patented their flexible airtight seal. The brand's goods later flooded into American homes, largely by way of independent sales parties hosted in suburban homes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6as4m1f8_tupperware-bloodmberg_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Publicly-traded Tupperware filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-pager-attacks-what-is-a-pager-and-why-hezbollah-still-relies-on-this-outdated-device-6590890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is A Pager And Why Hezbollah Still Relies On This Outdated Device]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-pager-attacks-what-is-a-pager-and-why-hezbollah-still-relies-on-this-outdated-device-6590890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:09:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A pager or ‘beeper’ is a small, portable communication device that receives short messages, typically numeric or alphanumeric, over a radio frequency signal. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least nine people were killed and nearly 3,000 wounded in Lebanon after thousands of wireless devices used by Hezbollah members exploded on Tuesday. A senior Lebanese security source claimed that Israel's Mossad spy agency planted explosives inside 5,000 Taiwan-made pagers or "beepers" ordered by the Iran-backed group months before the blasts.</p>

<h3><strong>What are pagers?</strong></h3>

<p>A <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pager-bombs-target-hezbollah-in-lebanon-what-we-know-so-far-5-points-6588316">pager</a> or 'beeper' is a small, portable communication device that receives short messages, typically numeric or alphanumeric, over a radio frequency signal. Pagers were widely used before cell phones became popular. It was a crucial communication tool, especially for professionals like doctors, journalists, technicians, and managers. It allowed them to receive important messages and sound alerts, even in remote areas.</p>

<h3><strong>How do pagers work?</strong></h3>

<p>The operation of a pager was straightforward yet efficient. When a message was sent via radio waves, the device would alert the user with a distinct beep. This prompt would then require the user to locate a nearby public or landline phone to respond to the message.</p>

<p>The first pager was patented in the US in 1949 by inventor Alfred Gross. The term "pager" was officially registered in 1959 by Motorola.</p>

<p>Motorola's first pager, the Pageboy 1 created in 1964, allowed an audible alert to be sent by telephone before the technology was perfected and allowed, from the 80s, to send written messages</p>

<p>As technology progressed, pagers underwent significant improvements. The newer models were equipped with a small screen, enabling them to display short messages directly on the device.</p>

<p>61 million pagers were in circulation worldwide in 1994, says an AFP report quoting US-based pager manufacturer Spok.</p>

<p>However, by the 1990s, mobile phones started to replace these little devices. The convenience of mobile phones quickly diminished the demand for pagers, and by the late 1990s, beepers had mostly vanished from public use.</p>

<p>Pagers continue to be used in some sectors, like hospitals, especially in the US.</p>

<h3><strong>Why Hezbollah members still use pagers</strong></h3>

<p>The recent cyberattack targeting Iran-backed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229">Hezbollah</a> revealed that pagers, which many assumed had become obsolete, were still in use by the group.</p>

<p>The pagers were used by Hezbollah fighters as a low-tech means of communication to evade Israeli location-tracking. Pagers use their own frequency and are therefore considered more reliable as they bypass mobile telephone networks that can be impacted by frequent interruptions, connection issues or can be intercepted.</p>

<p>According to reports, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229">Israel's Mossad spy agency</a> planted explosives inside 5,000 pagers imported by Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations.</p>

<p>The Lebanese security source told Reuters said the pagers were from Taiwan-based Gold Apollo, but the company said in a statement it did not manufacture the devices. It said they were made by a company called BAC which has a licence to use its brand, but gave no more details.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source said the group had ordered 5,000 beepers from Gold Apollo, which several sources say were brought into the country earlier this year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j8sqsfc_pagers_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trump-said-on-getting-a-call-from-kamala-harris-after-2nd-assassination-bid-6590390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Shares What Kamala Harris Told Him On Call After Assassination Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trump-said-on-getting-a-call-from-kamala-harris-after-2nd-assassination-bid-6590390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:00:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump says that he got "a very nice call" from his Democratic adversary Kamala Harris on Tuesday following the second assassination attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump says that he got "a very nice call" from his Democratic adversary Kamala Harris on Tuesday following the second assassination attempt.</p>

<p>"Today, a little while ago, I got a very nice call from Kamala," he said on Tuesday, mispronouncing her name as "Kamaala".</p>

<p>"It was very nice... was very, very nice. and we appreciate that," he said at a townhall meeting in Flint, Michigan, without elaborating on their conversation.</p>

<p>While a section of the crowd appeared to boo, he added, "But we have to take back our country. We have to win. We're going to win."</p>

<p>Giving her version of the call, Vice-President Harris said, "I checked on him to see if he was OK."</p>

<p>"And I told him what I have said publicly, there's no place for political violence in our country," she said at a meeting of Black journalists in Philadelphia.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden had also talked to him by phone on Monday and Trump mentioned that at the meeting.</p>

<p>About his brushes with assassination attempts, Trump boasted, "Only consequential Presidents get shot at."</p>

<p>Trump's Secret Service detail thwarted an attack on him on Sunday when an agent spotted a man with a semi-automatic rifle hidden in bushes at the periphery of a golf course in Florida where he was playing.</p>

<p>The agent fired at the gunman, who fled and was later captured.</p>

<p>The man identified as Ryan Routh had donated to a committee supporting Democratic candidates and had voted in the party's primary election.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News Digital on Monday, Trump blamed Biden and Kamala Harris for the attempted attack.</p>

<p>Routh "believed the rhetoric of Biden and Harris, and he acted on it," he said.</p>

<p>"Their rhetoric is causing me to be shot at, when I am the one who is going to save the country," Trump asserted.</p>

<p>Trump was injured in his ear when a sniper shot at him at a Pennsylvania rally in July.</p>

<p>Trump and Harris first met face-to-face at their debate last Tuesday in Philadelphia where she walked up to him and shook his hand.</p>

<p>The next day at the commemoration of the 9/11 terrorist attack in New York they spoke to each other and shook hands.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t62tibb8_donald-trump-kamala-harris-_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said he got "a very nice call" from his Democratic adversary Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/new-chinese-heliport-puts-pressure-on-remote-frontier-in-eastern-arunachal-6590683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Chinese Heliport Puts Pressure On Remote Frontier In Eastern Arunachal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/new-chinese-heliport-puts-pressure-on-remote-frontier-in-eastern-arunachal-6590683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 09:28:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new Chinese heliport being constructed 20 km east of the Line of Actual Control may give Chinese armed forces the ability to speedily move in military resources into an under-developed, remote area along the Indo-Chinese frontier.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new Chinese heliport being constructed 20 kilometres east of the Line of Actual Control near the sensitive 'Fishtails' region of Arunachal Pradesh, may give Chinese armed forces the ability to speedily move in military resources into an under-developed, remote area along the Indo-Chinese frontier.</p>

<p>The heliport, images of which appear in this report, lies along the banks of the Gongrigabu Qu river in the Nyingchi Prefecture of the Tibet Autonomous Region. This is within Chinese territory that India does not dispute.</p>

<p>Open-source satellite imagery available on EOS Data Analytics shows that till December 1, 2023, there was no construction at the site where the heliport is being constructed. A subsequent satellite image dated December 31, shows land being cleared for construction. The latest Maxar-sourced high-resolution images, shot on September 16, indicate that the facility is in an advanced state of construction.</p>

<p>Geospatial intelligence experts such as Damien Symon who first highlighted the existence of the heliport point out that "this new heliport will allow the People's Liberation Army (PLA) to intensify intelligence-gathering, surveillance, and reconnaissance activities." This closes logistical challenges in the densely forested region which features rugged mountains that make military movement cumbersome. The construction of the heliport "enables rapid troop deployment to distant areas, strengthening patrol efficiency and augmenting China's overall military footprint in these strategically important, remote locations."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Click here for high-res" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f3hq7r1o_helicopter-arunachal_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Click here for high-res" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The heliport also features at least three hangars, a sizeable apron area for helicopters to be positioned, an air traffic control facility and associated buildings and structures. Click <a href="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j9gihj6g_helicopter-arunachal_625x300_17_September_24.jpg">here</a> for high-res</p>
</div>

<p>Military sources who are monitoring the construction of the heliport add that while "this is definitely military infrastructure being constructed," the new facility may also have a dual-use function to enable the movement of civilians into the remote area. The heliport, they add, enhances Chinese "defensive and offensive operations [and] their reaction capabilities increase." This enables a speedy build-up of troops during a contingency.</p>

<p>The Fishtails area of Arunachal Pradesh, named after the distinctive shape of the boundary-line in this area, is comprised of Fishtail 1 and Fishtail 2. While Fishtail 1 lies in the Dibang Valley, Fishtail 2 is partly in the Anjaw district of the state. Both areas are considered 'sensitive', in other words, zones where China and India have differing perceptions of the Line of Actual Control.</p>

<p>"This heliport will be a threat to key areas which are considered 'sensitive' here," says Lt General Pravin Bakshi (retired), who headed the Eastern Command of the Indian Army. "I would take serious note and look to orchestrate a suitable response, if ever required, in concern with the Indian Air Force so as to prevent any 'grey-zone' warfare being efficiently prosecuted by the Chinese here." Grey-Zone warfare refers to a form of conflict which falls below the threshold of conventional war while still threatening boundary lines through coercive means that threaten stability.</p>

<p>The heliport under construction features a 600-metre runway which can be used for rolling take-offs of helicopters, a technique used in high-altitude areas where there is less power available for helicopters to use. Despite this runway, the new heliport is situated in an area where the altitude is substantially lower than large tracts of the Tibetan plateau. This benefits helicopter operations. "While the rest of the plateau has a disadvantage because of altitude, the general altitude in this area is in the 1500 metre (approximately 5000 feet) range which allows greater payload to be carried by choppers and aircraft."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Click here for high-res" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rrkft89o_helicopter-arunachal_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Click here for high-res" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The heliport under construction features a 600-metre runway which can be used for rolling take-offs of helicopters. Click <a href="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rki18uqg_helicopter-arunachal_625x300_17_September_24.jpg">here</a> for high-res</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The heliport also features at least three hangars, a sizeable apron area for helicopters to be positioned, an air traffic control facility and associated buildings and structures.</p>

<p>China's construction of the new heliport comes at a time when Beijing is in the process of constructing hundreds of 'Xiaokang' or dual-use villages along the frontier with India. These villages are a tool for China to assert its claims in disputed areas along the Line of Actual Control. By constructing these villages and changing facts of the ground, China has been involved in what India's late Chief of Defence Staff General Bipin Rawat referred to as "salami slicing" of territory. This has been particularly evident in the Kingdom of Bhutan, where undefended parts of its border regions, including <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/chinas-biggest-land-grab-carves-into-ancestral-areas-of-bhutans-royal-family-4811168">ancestral lands of its royal family</a>, have been physically taken over by the Chinese, who have built townships connected by an extensive road-network.</p>

<p>"This illustrates how China is quietly creating new facts on the ground," says Brahma Chellaney, a leading strategic affairs expert who focusses closely on China. "The current efforts to defuse the military standoff raise the question as to what a possible deal can accomplish, given the new military realities China has created along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) since 2020."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/39oejstc_china-map_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>India, which has engaged China in protracted talks after the violent skirmishes of 2020 in Ladakh, has begun countering China's border strategy by launching the 'Vibrant Villages' development project that covers 3,000 villages in four Northeastern border states, including Arunachal Pradesh. Rs 4,800 crore has been allotted for the first phase of the project. Separately, a 2,400-kilometre trans-Arunachal highway is being completed that drastically reduces travel time, particularly in Eastern Arunachal Pradesh. The highway, along with separate road projects in the state, enable connectivity to frontline Army posts as well.</p>

<p>Shifting pressure to the east of Arunachal Pradesh through the construction of the new heliport, however, "opens up a new vista," says Lt General Bakshi. Despite the rapid build-up of infrastructure along the frontier, "This area remains the least developed in our area of responsibility."</p>

<p><strong>With inputs from Divyam Sharma</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/je7td2g8_new-chinese-heliport-map_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Heliport along the banks of Gongrigabu Qu river. High res <a href=" https://rb.gy/56r4jk ">here</a>]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-xec-covid-variant-spreads-to-27-countries-heres-what-we-know-so-far-6590482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New XEC Covid Variant Spreads To 27 Countries, Here's What We Know So Far]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-xec-covid-variant-spreads-to-27-countries-heres-what-we-know-so-far-6590482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 08:39:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have warned that a "more contagious" variant of Covid-19, dubbed XEC, is spreading more rapidly across Europe and could soon become the dominant strain.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have warned that a "more contagious" variant of Covid-19, dubbed XEC, is spreading more rapidly across Europe and could soon become the dominant strain. According to<em> the BBC</em>, the new variant was first identified in Germany in June, and since then, the XEC variant has emerged in the UK, US, Denmark and several other countries. Experts have said that the new variant, a sublineage of the omicron variant, has some new mutations that might help it spread this autumn, although vaccines should still help prevent severe cases.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The XEC variant is a hybrid of the earlier omicron subvariants KS.1.1 and KP.3.3, which is currently dominant in Europe. So far, 500 samples from 27 countries, including Poland, Norway, Luxembourg, Ukraine, Portugal and China, have been found to contain XEC, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/new-xec-covid-variant-symptoms-signs-b2613998.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Independent</em></a> reported. Experts point to strong growth of the variant in Denmark, Germany, the UK, and the Netherlands.</p>

<p>Professor Francois Balloux, Director of the Genetics Institute at University College London, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1jddenj5p5o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC&nbsp;</em></a>that although XEC has a "slight transmission advantage" over other recent Covid variants, vaccines should still offer good protection. But he also added that XEC may become the dominant subvariant over the winter.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wear-proper-undergarments-delta-airlines-new-memo-for-flight-attendants-6587880">"Wear Proper Undergarments": Delta Airlines' New Memo For Flight Attendants</a></strong></p>

<p>Director of the Scripps Research Translational Institute, in California, Eric Topol said XEC is "just getting started". "And that's going to take many weeks, a couple months, before it really takes hold and starts to cause a wave," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"XEC is definitely taking charge. That does appear to be the next variant. But it's months off from getting into high levels," said Mr Topol.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Symptoms of XEC Covid</strong></h2>

<p>The symptoms of the XEC variant are similar to those of previous Covid variants, including fever, sore throat, cough, loss of sense of smell, loss of appetite, and body aches.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But since it is still only a sub-family of the same omicron lineage, experts say keeping up to date with vaccines and booster shots would offer sufficient protection against severe illness and hospitalisation.</p>

<p>Separately, the US Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has also advised people to practise good hygiene and take steps for cleaner air.</p>

<p>Moreover, researchers have called for monitoring the XEC more closely to better understand its symptoms.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/d31ktkno_covid-19-_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[So far, 500 samples from 27 countries have been found to contain XEC.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-after-second-assassination-bid-only-consequential-presidents-get-shot-at-6590479]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Only Consequential Presidents Get Shot At": Trump After Assassination Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-after-second-assassination-bid-only-consequential-presidents-get-shot-at-6590479]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 08:39:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's election rival Kamala Harris said Tuesday she had reached out to the former president after the thwarted attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump resumed campaigning Tuesday for the first time since a second apparent attempt on his life, boasting "only consequential presidents get shot at" while praising Kamala Harris for making a phone call to check on him. Trump spoke at a town hall meeting before fervent supporters in Flint, a beleaguered industrial city that was once a jewel of the US automotive industry in swing state Michigan, before factories closed due to foreign competition.</p>

<p>Trump drew a link between what the FBI called a foiled assassination bid against him Sunday at his golf course in Florida and his pledge to slap heavy tariffs on imports of cars from Mexico and China.</p>

<p>"And then you wonder why I get shot at, right? You know, only consequential presidents get shot at," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump's election rival Harris, campaigning in another swing state, Pennsylvania, said Tuesday she had reached out to the former president after the thwarted attack.</p>

<p>"I checked on him to see if he was OK. And I told him what I have said publicly -- there's no place for political violence in our country," Harris said in an interview with the National Association of Black Journalists (NABJ).</p>

<p>The White House described it as a "cordial and brief conversation." Trump said Harris "could not have been nicer."</p>

<p>Trump has said the would-be shooter was a follower of what he called President Joe Biden's and Harris's rhetoric insisting that he is a threat to US democracy.</p>

<p>At the town hall meeting, Trump supporters said the foiled attack made them support him even more.</p>

<p>"I believe that they want to kill Trump so that Trump cannot try to make his second term in office," said retired autoworker Donald Owen, 71.</p>

<h3><strong>'Zero jobs'</strong></h3>

<p>Trump depicted himself at the event as the savior of the US auto industry as it competes with foreign companies.</p>

<p>He insisted: "If a tragedy happens, and we don't win, there will be zero car jobs, manufacturing jobs, it will all be out of here."</p>

<p>Trump also defended his convoluted, rambling way of speaking, and then in a tangent on fossil fuel drilling he said, "We have Bagram in Alaska. They say it might be as big, might be bigger than all of Saudi Arabia."</p>

<p>But Bagram is an air base in Afghanistan. Trump may have confused it with a place in Alaska called the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, or ANWR.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Harris used her interview in Pennsylvania to give her first reaction to a row over false stories spread by Trump that Haitian immigrants were eating residents' cats and dogs in a town in Ohio.</p>

<p>Dozens of bomb threats were made against the community in the town of Springfield after Trump and his running mate JD Vance publicly boosted the fake story, forcing the closure of some schools.</p>

<p>"It's a crying shame, literally, what's happening to those families, those children in that community," Harris said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Hateful'</strong></h3>

<p>"It's got to stop. We've got to say that you cannot be entrusted with standing behind the seal of the president of the United States engaging in that hateful rhetoric," she added.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Trump was whisked away by the US Secret Service after gunman Ryan Routh was discovered in a hedgerow at his Florida golf course.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was the second such close call for the Republican nominee in as many months, after a bullet grazed his ear in a shooting at a rally in Pennsylvania that left one man dead in June.</p>

<p>The dueling visits of Trump in Michigan and Harris in Pennsylvania come as both focus on the half-dozen swing states critical to winning in the election.</p>

<p>A new poll from Suffolk University and USA Today shows Harris with a slight 49-46 percent edge over Trump in Pennsylvania, thanks in large part to major support from women voters.</p>

<p>It confirms a large gender gap in the race, at least in Pennsylvania, with Harris leading with women by 56 percent to 39 percent, and Trump earning male votes by a slimmer 53-41 percent.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3gpq8if_donald-trump_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-on-alert-as-hezbollah-vows-retaliation-over-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6590328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Israel Will Certainly Receive Its Punishment": Hezbollah After Pager Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-on-alert-as-hezbollah-vows-retaliation-over-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6590328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:57:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran-backed Hezbollah vowed to retaliate against Israel after accusing it of detonating pagers across Lebanon, that killed nine people and injured about 2,800 others on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Hezbollah warned Israel it would be punished after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-pagers-explode-in-lebanon-several-members-injured-in-biggest-security-breach-says-hezbollah-6587184#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">hundreds of pagers used by its members exploded</a> in its strongholds in southern Lebanon.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The Iran-backed group said at least two of its fighters and a young girl were among the dead.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Lebanese Health Minister Firass Abiad said some "2,800 people were injured, about 200 of them critically" with injuries mostly reported to the face, hands and stomach.</li>
	<li>According to media reports, Iran's ambassador in Beirut was also wounded in a pager explosion but his injuries were not serious.</li>
	<li>The New York Times reported that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229" target="_blank">Israel hid explosive material in the Taiwan-made Gold Apollo pagers</a> before they were imported to Lebanon. The material was implanted next to the battery with a switch that could be triggered remotely to detonate. Gold Apollo, however, said it did not make the pagers used in the explosion and said they were made by a company in Europe that had the right to use the Taiwanese firm's brand.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah said it holds the Israeli enemy "fully responsible for this criminal aggression". Israel "will certainly receive its just punishment for this sinful aggression," it said in a statement.</li>
	<li>The US, which is <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-aware-not-involved-us-on-lebanon-pager-blasts-6589968" target="_blank">Israel's top arms provider</a> and close ally, said it was "not involved" and "not aware of this incident in advance".</li>
	<li>Hamas, which is waging war with Israel in Gaza, said the pager blasts were an "escalation" that would only lead Israel to "failure and defeat".</li>
	<li>The pager attacks came hours after Israel announced it was broadening the aims of the Gaza war to include its fight against Hezbollah along its border with Lebanon.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah and the Israeli military have been exchanging fire since the October 7 attacks by Hamas on Israel that triggered the Gaza war.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3egae548_lebanon-hospital_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah Pager Attack: About 2,800 people were injured after pagers used by Hezbollah exploded]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-brazil-mayoral-candidate-attacks-opponent-with-chair-on-live-tv-6590259]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Brazil Mayoral Candidate Attacks Opponent With Chair On Live TV]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-brazil-mayoral-candidate-attacks-opponent-with-chair-on-live-tv-6590259]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:37:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A mayoral debate in Brazil turned ugly when one of the candidates attacked a rival with a metal chair on live TV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mayoral debate in Brazil turned ugly when one of the candidates attacked a rival with a metal chair on live TV. According to <em>CNN</em>, the incident took place on Sunday, September 15. Pablo Marcal was delivering his speech when Jose Luiz Datena suddenly appeared from the shadows and attacked Mr Marcal with the chair. A video from the debate, broadcast live by <em>TV Cultura</em>, showed the tense exchange between the two before Mr Datena launched the heavy chair from close range at his counterpart's head.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The footage showed Mr Datena walking up to his victim and swinging the metal chair at his counterpart, although the latter managed to raise an arm at the last minute and deflect the blow slightly. Following the incident, Mr Marcal was hospitalised with suspected fractured ribs and breathing difficulties. The hospital said he had suffered trauma to his chest and wrist, but without any major complications, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/16/americas/sao-paulo-mayoral-debate-chair-attack-intl-latam/index.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?????? ??? ??? ???? ???????<br />
??During the debate for the São Paulo mayoral race in Brazil, socialist candidate José Luiz Datena threw a chair at libertarian candidate Pablo Marçal. I'd pay more attention to the debates in my country if they were like this. <a href="https://t.co/zvKKXardrD">pic.twitter.com/zvKKXardrD</a></p>
— Ara American Uncensored (@realaraamerican) <a href="https://twitter.com/realaraamerican/status/1836025771858522457?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Datena later told TV Cultura that he had attacked Mr Marcal because he had brought up old sexual harassment allegations against Mr Datena that were dismissed several years ago. "He came with a case that was archived, that was not even investigated by the police because there was no evidence. Something from 11 years ago that caused a very serious situation within my family," Mr Datena said, per the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the incident, Mr Datena was expelled from the debate. However, on Monday he insisted that while he had made a mistake he did not regret his actions.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wear-proper-undergarments-delta-airlines-new-memo-for-flight-attendants-6587880">"Wear Proper Undergarments": Delta Airlines' New Memo For Flight Attendants</a></strong></p>

<p>Mr Marcal, on the other hand, compared the attack to the July assassination attempt against former US President Donald Trump and the stabbing of former Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro during the 2018 election. His team has vowed to take legal action.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Pablo Marcal was cowardly attacked by Jose Luiz Datena, who hit him in the ribs with an iron chair," Mr Marcal's team said, adding that it was unfortunate the debate had continued without him.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the remaining candidates Guilherme Boulos, Marina Helena, Ricardo Nunes and Tabata Amaral continued the debate following the attack. <em>TV Cultura</em> said it regretted the incident and had pressed ahead with the discussion in accordance with the rules after the other candidates agreed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o6o0qve_brazil-mayor-debate_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Sunday, September 15.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Grams Of Explosives Per Pager: Israel's Complex Op To Hurt Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:29:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Mossad spy agency planted a small amount of explosives inside 5,000 Taiwan-made pagers ordered by Lebanese group Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Mossad spy agency planted a small amount of explosives inside 5,000 Taiwan-made pagers ordered by Lebanese group Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told Reuters.</p>

<p>The operation was an unprecedented Hezbollah security breach that saw thousands of pagers detonate across Lebanon, killing nine people and wounding nearly 3,000 others, including the group's fighters and Iran's envoy to Beirut.</p>

<p>Iran-backed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-on-alert-as-hezbollah-vows-retaliation-over-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6590328">Hezbollah</a> has vowed to retaliate against Israel, whose military declined to comment on the blasts.</p>

<p>The plot appears to have been many months in the making, several sources told Reuters.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source said the group had ordered 5,000 beepers made by Taiwan-based Gold Apollo, which several sources say were brought into the country earlier this year.</p>

<p>Gold Apollo founder Hsu Ching-Kuang said the pagers used in the explosion were made by a company in Europe that had the right to use the Taipei-based firm's brand, the name of which he could not immediately confirm.</p>

<p>"The product was not ours. It was only that it had our brand on it," he told reporters on Wednesday, without naming the company which did make the devices.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source identified a photograph of the model of the pager, an AP924, which like other pagers wirelessly receive and display text messages but cannot make telephone calls.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-page-attacks-what-is-a-pager-and-why-hezbollah-still-relies-on-this-outdated-device-6590890#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories">Hezbollah fighters have been using pagers</a> as a low-tech means of communication in an attempt to evade Israeli location-tracking, two sources familiar with the group's operations told Reuters this year.</p>

<p>But the senior Lebanese source said the devices had been modified by Israel's spy service "at the production level."</p>

<p>"The Mossad injected a board inside of the device that has explosive material that receives a code. It's very hard to detect it through any means. Even with any device or scanner," the source said.</p>

<p>The source said 3,000 of the pagers exploded when a coded message was sent to them, simultaneously activating the explosives.</p>

<p>Another security source told Reuters that up to three grams of explosives were hidden in the new pagers and had gone "undetected" by Hezbollah for months.</p>

<p>Neither Israel nor Gold Apollo immediately responded to Reuters requests for comment.</p>

<p>Images of destroyed pagers analyzed by Reuters showed a format and stickers on the back that were consistent with pagers made by Gold Apollo, based in Taipei.</p>

<p>Hezbollah was reeling from the attack, which left fighters and others bloodied, hospitalised or dead. One Hezbollah official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the detonation was the group's "biggest security breach" since the Gaza conflict between Israel and Hezbollah ally Hamas erupted on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>"This would easily be the biggest counterintelligence failure that Hezbollah has had in decades," said Jonathan Panikoff, the U.S. government's former deputy national intelligence officer on the Middle East.</p>

<p><strong>Break Your Phones, Group Ordered</strong></p>

<p>In February, Hezbollah drew up a war plan that aimed to address gaps in the group's intelligence infrastructure. Around 170 fighters had already been killed in targeted Israeli strikes on Lebanon, including one senior commander and a top Hamas official in Beirut.</p>

<p>In a televised speech on Feb. 13, the group's Secretary General Hassan Nasrallah sternly warned supporters that their phones were more dangerous than Israeli spies, saying they should break, bury or lock them in an iron box.</p>

<p>Instead, the group opted to distribute pagers to Hezbollah members across the group's various branches - from fighters to medics working in its relief services.</p>

<p>The explosions maimed many Hezbollah members, according to footage from hospitals reviewed by Reuters. Wounded men had injuries of varying degrees to the face, missing fingers and gaping wounds at the hip where the pagers were likely worn.</p>

<p>"We really got hit hard," said the senior Lebanese security source, who has direct knowledge of the group's probe into the explosions.</p>

<p>The pager blasts came at a time of mounting concern about tensions between Israel and Hezbollah, which have been engaged in cross-border warfare since the Gaza conflict erupted last October.</p>

<p>While the war in Gaza has been Israel's main focus since the Oct. 7 attack by Hamas-led gunmen, the precarious situation along Israel's northern border with Lebanon has fueled fears of a regional conflict that could drag in the United States and Iran.</p>

<p>A missile barrage by Hezbollah the day after Oct. 7 opened the latest phase of conflict and since then there have been daily exchanges of rockets, artillery fire and missiles, with Israeli jets striking deep into Lebanese territory.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said it does not seek a wider war but would fight if Israel launched one.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant told US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin on Monday that the window was closing for a diplomatic solution to the standoff with the Iranian-backed Hezbollah movement in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Still, experts said they did not see the pager blasts as a sign that an Israeli ground offensive was imminent.</p>

<p>Instead, it was a sign of Israeli intelligence's apparently deep penetration of Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"It demonstrates Israel's ability to infiltrate its adversaries in a remarkably dramatic way," said Paul Pillar, a 28-year veteran of the U.S. intelligence community, mainly at the CIA.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rqune5nk_israel-hezbollah-attack_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pagers Explode In Lebanon: The operation was an unprecedented Hezbollah security breach]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>