<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:34:24 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-soccer-fans-attacked-in-amsterdam-pm-netanyahu-sends-rescue-planes-6972838]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Soccer Fans Attacked In Amsterdam, Netanyahu Sends Rescue Planes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-soccer-fans-attacked-in-amsterdam-pm-netanyahu-sends-rescue-planes-6972838]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:25:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel PM Benjamin Netanyahu has ordered the dispatch of two planes to Amsterdam to evacuate Israeli soccer fans who were attacked by an alleged Pro-Palestinian mob on Thursday night.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel PM Benjamin Netanyahu has ordered the dispatch of two planes to Amsterdam to evacuate Israeli soccer fans who were attacked by an alleged Pro-Palestinian mob on Thursday night.</p>

<p>The fans had travelled to the Netherlands to watch the Europa League match between Maccabi Tel Aviv vs Ajax Amsterdam.</p>

<p>The assault began after Maccabi Tel Aviv's loss to Ajax, with attackers targeting Israelis at various locations across the city, chanting "Free Palestine" and throwing insults in Arabic.</p>

<p>At least 10 Israelis were injured in the violence, with some reports suggesting that two individuals are still unaccounted for. Additionally, attackers stole passports from some of the targeted individuals.</p>

<p>Israel Foreign Ministry has advised its citizens in the Netherlands to remain indoors and avoid going out, while Foreign Minister Gideon Sa'ar has asked Dutch authorities to help Israelis safely reach the airport.</p>

<p>Israeli Security Minister Itamar Ben-Gvir condemned the attacks, describing them as an act of anti-Semitism with Israelis being beaten, kicked, run-over, and even being thrown into the river.</p>

<p>Former Israeli special envoy Noa Tishby claimed one fan was forced to say "Free Palestine" before being released.</p>

<p>In response to the violence, Israel PM Netanyahu called for Dutch authorities to act swiftly to ensure the safety of Israelis, calling the incident "serious."</p>

<p>Former Israel PM Naftali Bennett also called for immediate action, urging authorities to act immediately to prevent further harm.</p>

<p>The Israeli Embassy in the United States stated that Maccabi Tel Aviv fans were attacked as they left the stadium.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mnumrpkg_amsterdam-clashes_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli Embassy in the US stated Maccabi Tel Aviv fans were attacked as they left the stadium.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-says-india-deserves-to-be-in-list-of-global-superpowers-6971363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Deserves To Be In List Of Global Superpowers: Vladimir Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-says-india-deserves-to-be-in-list-of-global-superpowers-6971363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:42:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India deserves to be included in the list of global superpowers as its economy is currently growing faster than in any other country, Russian President Vladimir Putin has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India deserves to be included in the list of global superpowers as its economy is currently growing faster than in any other country, Russian President Vladimir Putin has said.</p>

<p>Addressing the&nbsp;plenary session of the Valdai Discussion Club in Sochi on Thursday, Putin also said Russia is developing relations with India in all directions and there is a great degree of trust in bilateral ties.</p>

<p>"India should undoubtedly added to the list of superpowers, with its billion-and-a-half population, the fastest growth among all economies in the world, ancient culture and very good prospects for further growth," he said.</p>

<p>Calling India a great country, Putin said: "We are developing relations with India in all directions. India is a great country, now the largest in terms of population: 1.5 billion people, plus 10 million every year. " He said India is leading the world in economic growth.</p>

<p>"Our vision of where and at what pace our relations will develop is based on today's realities. The volume of our cooperation is increasing many times over, every year," Putin was quoted by Russian news agency Tass as saying.</p>

<p>Putin added that the contacts between India and Russia in the security and defence sphere are developing.</p>

<p>"Look at how many types of Russian military equipment are in service with the Indian armed forces. There is a great degree of trust in this relationship. We don't just sell our weapons to India; we design them jointly," he said.</p>

<p>Putin named the BrahMos cruise missile project as an example.</p>

<p>"In fact, we made it [the missile] fit for use in three environments - in air, in sea and on land. These projects, conducted for the benefit of India's security, are ongoing," he said.</p>

<p>"This is widely known and no one has issues with that, but these projects demonstrate a high level of mutual trust and cooperation. So this what we will keep doing in the near term, and, I hope, will continue to do in the more distant future," he said.</p>

<p>Putin acknowledged certain difficulties on the border between India and China, the agency reported.</p>

<p>However, he said wise and competent people who keep the future of their nations in mind, are searching for compromises and will eventually find them.</p>

<p>"If this approach continues to gain momentum, compromises can be found, and they will be found," Putin said.</p>

<p>The ties between India and China nosedived following a fierce clash in the Galwan Valley in June 2020 that marked the most serious military conflict between the two sides in decades.</p>

<p>On October 21, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said in New Delhi that an agreement had been finalised between India and China following negotiations over the past several weeks and that it would lead to a resolution of the issues that arose in 2020.</p>

<p>The agreement was firmed up on patrolling and disengagement of troops along the Line of Actual Control in eastern Ladakh, a breakthrough to end the over four-year standoff.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/scbinsc8_pm-modi-vladimir-putin_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin said India should undoubtedly added to the list of superpowers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-prepares-for-trumps-return-focuses-on-ties-and-stability-6971980]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Prepares For Trump's Return, Focuses On Ties And Stability]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-prepares-for-trumps-return-focuses-on-ties-and-stability-6971980]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:32:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After Donald Trump first entered the White House eight years ago, rattled Chinese leaders responded to his tariffs and fiery rhetoric with force, resulting in a trade war that plunged ties between the globe's largest economies to multiyear lows.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After Donald Trump first entered the White House eight years ago, rattled Chinese leaders responded to his tariffs and fiery rhetoric with force, resulting in a trade war that plunged ties between the globe's largest economies to multiyear lows.</p>

<p>This time around, Beijing has been preparing for Trump's return by deepening ties with allies, boosting self-reliance in tech, and setting aside money to prop up the economy that is now more vulnerable to fresh tariffs already threatened by Trump.</p>

<p>While some retaliation to those moves might be unavoidable, China will focus on exploiting rifts between the US and its allies, experts say, and aim to lower the temperature to help strike an early deal to cushion the blow from trade friction.</p>

<p>Zhao Minghao, international relations expert at Shanghai's Fudan University said China probably wouldn't replay the playbook from the first Trump presidency when Beijing had a very strong reaction to Trump's moves on tariffs.</p>

<p>He pointed out Chinese President Xi Jinping's message to Trump from Thursday, in which Xi called for "cooperation" and not "confrontation," emphasising "stable, sound and sustainable" relations between the two superpowers.</p>

<p>"Trump is not a stranger to Beijing at this time," Zhao told Reuters. "Beijing would respond in a measured way and make efforts to communicate with the Trump team."</p>

<p>While Chinese tech giants are now far less reliant on US imports, the economy - hit by a massive property crisis and saddled with unsustainable debt - is in a weaker position than in 2016, struggling to eke out 5% growth compared to 6.7% then.</p>

<p>To make things worse, Trump has pledged to end China's most-favored-nation trading status and slap tariffs on Chinese imports in excess of 60% - much higher than those imposed during his first term.</p>

<p>Fudan's Zhao said Beijing has this scenario gamed out but expects tariffs to come in below the level pledged on the campaign trail because "that would significantly push up the inflation in the US".</p>

<p>Still, that threat alone has unnerved producers in the world's largest exporter because China sells goods worth more than $400 billion a year to the US and hundreds of billions more in parts for products Americans buy elsewhere.</p>

<p>Li Mingjiang, a scholar at the Rajaratnam School of International Studies in Singapore, said that as a result, the Chinese economy might require even more stimulus than the $1.4 trillion expected on Friday.</p>

<p>"It'll be a very serious blow to China's international trade that will affect jobs and government revenues," said Li. "China will probably have to come up with a much bigger stimulus package domestically."</p>

<p><strong>CHARM OFFENSIVE</strong></p>

<p>To boost global trade, China has been on a diplomatic blitz, shoring up alliances, mending fences with foes, and continuing difficult talks with the European Union, even after the bloc imposed stiff tariffs on Chinese electric vehicles.</p>

<p>Last month China ended a four-year military stand-off with India on their disputed border; in August, it resolved a two-year spat with Japan over the discharge of radioactive water from the Fukushima nuclear plant; and Premier Li Qiang in June visited Australia - the first such trip in seven years.</p>

<p>Also last month, both Xi and Li attended separate summits of BRICS - which now accounts for 35% of the global economy - and the 10-state Shanghai Cooperation Organisation, as China deepens ties with the Global South.</p>

<p>"The first Trump administration did not show a lot of interest in robust engagement in Africa, Latin America, and Southeast Asia, which provided the Chinese a lot of latitude to operate in these markets largely uncontested," said Eric Olander, editor-in-chief of the China-Global South Project.</p>

<p>In Europe, trade tensions with China could be counterbalanced by worries over Trump's potentially reduced role in the Ukraine war and his economic policies, creating an opening for Beijing, say some experts.</p>

<p>"China will carry on reaching out to Europeans, the British, the Australians and even the Japanese, not only to try to drive a wedge between the US and the countries of the north," said Jean-Pierre Cabestan, an expert at Hong Kong's Baptist University.</p>

<p>"But also as part of its mission to rebalance its foreign trade in favour of the Global South," he said.</p>

<p><strong>TECH PUNCHLINE</strong></p>

<p>During the first trade war, Trump banned high-tech exports to China and sanctioned companies including China's largest chipmaker SMIC, prompting its tech sector to become domestic-focused and self-sufficient.</p>

<p>Winston Ma, a former managing director for the China Investment Corporation (CIC), China's sovereign wealth fund, said a major trigger for this shift was Trump's ban on the sale of components to Chinese telecommunications firm ZTE in 2018.</p>

<p>That was "really scary from a China perspective, so they began to prepare. It was the start of that sort of defensive thinking," added Ma.</p>

<p>Soon after, Xi urged the nation to boost self-reliance in science and tech, pushing China to build-up crucial industries including AI and space.</p>

<p>The result: Eight years ago, China had only four government procurement projects worth over $1.4 million, replacing foreign hardware and software with domestic alternatives. That number has exploded to 169 such projects this year, data show.</p>

<p>Despite these strides, chipmakers "definitely feel the tightening - these Chinese companies couldn't supply to global clients and can't have access to the latest chips," said Ma.</p>

<p>Nazak Nikakhtar, a Commerce Department official under Trump who knows his advisers, said she expected Trump to be "much more aggressive about export control policies towards China."</p>

<p>She anticipated "a significant expansion of the entity list," that restricts exports to those on it to capture affiliates and business partners of listed companies.</p>

<p>Ma, the ex-CIC executive, said the restrictions will have an impact for some time as the US expands the sanctions regime to overseas suppliers.</p>

<p>"I think the punchline is that the coming years are the most critical for this US-China tech rivalry."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6s65qfo8_us-china_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China will focus on exploiting rifts between the US and its allies, experts say. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-1800s-to-cop29-highlights-of-un-climate-talks-over-the-years-6971863]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From 1800s To COP29: Highlights Of UN Climate Talks Over The Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-1800s-to-cop29-highlights-of-un-climate-talks-over-the-years-6971863]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:17:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This year's UN climate conference in Baku, Azerbaijan, marks the world's 29th leadership gathering to confront global warming since the first "Conference of the Parties" in 1995.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year's UN climate conference in Baku, Azerbaijan, marks the world's 29th leadership gathering to confront global warming since the first "Conference of the Parties" in 1995.</p>

<p>Here are some of the most significant moments in the history of climate talks:</p>

<p><strong>1800s -</strong> For about 6,000 years before the industrial era, global levels of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) remained around 280 parts per million ("ppm"). Several European scientists begin studying how different gases trap heat, and in the 1890s Svante Arrhenius of Sweden calculates the temperature effect from doubling atmospheric CO2 levels, demonstrating how burning fossil fuels will warm the planet.</p>

<p><strong>1938 -</strong> British engineer Guy Callendar determines that global temperatures are rising in line with increasing CO2 levels, and hypothesises that the two are linked.</p>

<p><strong>1958 - </strong>American scientist Charles David Keeling starts measuring CO2 levels over Hawaii's Mauna Loa Observatory, resulting in the "Keeling Curve" graph that shows CO2 concentrations rising.</p>

<p><strong>1990 -</strong> At the UN's Second World Climate Conference, scientists highlight the risks of global warming to nature and society. British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher calls for binding emissions targets.</p>

<p><strong>1992 - </strong>Countries at the Rio Earth Summit sign the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). The treaty establishes the idea of "common but differentiated responsibilities," meaning developed countries must do more to tackle climate-warming emissions because they emitted the most historically.</p>

<p><strong>1995 -</strong> UNFCCC signatories hold the first "conference of parties," or COP, in Berlin, with the final document calling for legally binding emissions targets.</p>

<p><strong>1997 -</strong> At COP3 in Kyoto, Japan, parties agree to varied emissions cuts for each of the developed countries. In the United States, Senate Republicans denounce the Kyoto Protocol as "dead on arrival".</p>

<p><strong>2000 -</strong> After losing the US presidential election, Al Gore begins giving talks worldwide on climate science and policy that eventually are made into the 2006 documentary An Inconvenient Truth. The film wins an Academy Award, while Gore and the UN climate science authority - the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change - receive the Nobel Peace Prize.</p>

<p><strong>2001 - </strong>US President George W. Bush calls the Kyoto Protocol "fatally flawed," signaling the country's effective exit.</p>

<p><strong>2005 - </strong>The Kyoto Protocol goes into effect after Russia ratifies it, meeting a requirement for ratification by at least 55 countries accounting for at least 55% of emissions.</p>

<p><strong>2009 - </strong>COP15 talks in Copenhagen nearly collapse after wrangling over a post-Kyoto framework, with countries voting to instead "take note" of a non-binding political statement.</p>

<p><strong>2010 - </strong>COP16 in Cancun fails to set new binding emissions targets, but the Cancun Agreements establishes a Green Climate Fund to help developing countries cut emissions and adapt to the conditions of a warmer world.</p>

<p><strong>2011 - </strong>COP17 talks in Durban, South Africa, falter after China, the United States and India refuse binding emissions cuts before 2015. Delegates instead extend the Kyoto Protocol through 2017.</p>

<p><strong>2012 - </strong>As Russia, Japan and New Zealand resist new emissions targets that do not extend to developing nations, countries at COP18 in Doha extend the Kyoto Protocol through 2020.</p>

<p><strong>2013 -</strong> Atmospheric CO2 levels cross 400 ppm for the first time in recorded history.</p>

<p><strong>2015 - </strong>The global average temperature rises beyond 1 degree Celsius over the preindustrial average. The COP21 talks result in The Paris Agreement, the first pact to call for increasingly ambitious emissions pledges from both developed and developing countries. Delegates also pledge to try to keep warming to within 1.5 C (2.7 Fahrenheit).</p>

<p><strong>2017 -</strong> US President Donald Trump pledges to remove the United States from the Paris treaty, which happens in 2020.</p>

<p><strong>2018 - </strong>Teen activist Greta Thunberg captures global attention while protesting outside Swedish parliament, and over time, rallies youths to join weekly climate protests worldwide.</p>

<p><strong>2020 - </strong>The annual COP is postponed amid the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>

<p><strong>2021 - </strong>Newly elected US President Joe Biden rejoins the Paris Agreement. Later at COP26, the Glasgow Pact sets a goal of using less coal and resolves some rules for trading carbon credits to offset emissions.</p>

<p><strong>2022 - </strong>The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change warns that the world is at risk of catastrophic and irreversible climate change. Later that year, COP27 in Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt, agrees to form a Loss and Damage Fund for costly climate disasters, but does little to address the emissions fuelling such disasters.</p>

<p><strong>2023 -</strong> At COP28 in the oil-producing United Arab Emirates, countries agree to transition away from fossil fuel use.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2q5md86g_cop29_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[29th UN Climate Change conference is set to be held in Baku, Azerbaijan from November 11-22. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-puri-on-buying-russian-oil-explains-why-india-did-entire-world-a-favour-6971824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Did Entire World A Favour": Minister On Why India Buys Russian Oil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-puri-on-buying-russian-oil-explains-why-india-did-entire-world-a-favour-6971824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:11:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Union Petroleum and Natural Gas minister Hardeep Singh Puri said oil will remain a key part of the world's energy supply for years to come.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's decision to buy oil from Russia amid global uncertainties helped prevent a potential spike in global oil prices, Union Petroleum and Natural Gas minister Hardeep Singh Puri said in a recent interview with CNN.</p>

<p>Speaking to CNN's Becky Anderson on the sidelines of the annual energy industry event ADIPEC in Abu Dhabi on Thursday, Union minister Puri explained that if the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/business-news/indias-russian-oil-imports-rise-11-7-in-sept-from-aug-data-shows-6801145">Indian government hadn't bought Russian oil</a>, global oil prices would have gone up to 200 dollars for everyone.</p>

<p>Oil will remain a key part of the world's energy supply for years to come, he said.</p>

<p>Mr Puri told CNN, "Earlier I said I hope there will be a reduction in oil price. Today I'm more confident that there will be.".</p>

<p>"By 2026, when more energy is available in the market, As a student of the situation, I think that the likelihood of prices remaining stable and coming down are higher," Mr&nbsp;Puri said.</p>

<p>On being asked <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-urges-india-to-maintain-implementation-of-russian-oil-price-cap-5370773">why India reduced oil imports from Russia</a> in October by around 10 per cent, Mr Puri explained that happened because of competitive oil rates in the market. "There are other people willing to supply at the same competitive rate because the OPEC position is they don't deal with price. There's healthy competition going on. If you don't get it from one, you get it from someone else", he said.</p>

<p>On being questioned whether the reduction in Russian oil imports was a strategic decision, Mr&nbsp;Puri said, "These are oil decisions taken in the marketplace. When we faced February 22 there were 13 million barrels of Russian oil on the market suddenly if that oil had gone off the market and India had decided to shift its 5 million barrels to say suppliers in the Gulf, the price of oil would have gone up to 200 a barrel. So I think we did everybody a favour".</p>

<p>He said technological changes such as green hydrogen and the transition to cleaner energy will change the global oil demand landscape in five years.</p>

<p>Mr&nbsp;Puri also took to his X account to share details and said, "India did the entire world a favour by buying Russian oil because if we had not done so, the global oil prices would have skyrocketed to USD 200/barrel. Russian oil was never under any sanctions and there was only a price cap, which Indian entities also followed."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">India did the entire world a favour by buying Russian oil because if we had not done so, the global oil prices would have skyrocketed to $200/barrel. Russian oil was never under any sanctions and there was only a price cap, which Indian entities also followed.<br />
<br />
Let us not forget… <a href="https://t.co/JZsvoFX74T">pic.twitter.com/JZsvoFX74T</a></p>
— Hardeep Singh Puri (@HardeepSPuri) <a href="https://twitter.com/HardeepSPuri/status/1854589611437154670?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He also pointed out that some "ill-informed commentators" wanting to put restrictions on India when European and Asian countries had also engaged in significant energy purchases from Russia.</p>

<p>"Let us not forget that while some ill-informed commentators talked about putting restrictions on India, many other European and Asian nations bought much more crude oil, diesel, LNG, rare earth minerals worth billions of dollars from Russia. We will continue to buy energy from whoever offers the best rates to our oil companies" Mr Puri wrote.</p>

<p>The union minister also noted in his X post, "We need to ensure steady availability, affordability and sustainability of energy for our 7 crore citizens who visit a petrol pump every day. That's our top priority. India is the only major consumer where fuel prices have come down significantly in the last three years despite unprecedented global price increases in other nations".</p>

<p>India is the third largest oil consumer in the world, as estimated by the International Energy Agency.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2e6ar8m_hardeep-singh-puri_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Oil will remain a key part of the world's energy supply for years to come, Mr Puri said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkish-boss-denies-indian-man-wedding-leave-he-marries-over-video-call-6971673]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkish Boss Denies Indian Man Wedding Leave, He Marries Over Video Call]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkish-boss-denies-indian-man-wedding-leave-he-marries-over-video-call-6971673]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:48:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The marriage ceremony of Adnan Muhammad, a resident of Bilaspur, had to be performed virtually as the company for which he works in Turkiye refused to grant him leave, his family members said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A virtual 'nikah' was solemnised in Himachal Pradesh with the groom in Turkiye and the bride in Mandi. The marriage ceremony of Adnan Muhammad, a resident of Bilaspur, had to be performed virtually as the company for which he works in Turkiye refused to grant him leave, his family members said.</p>

<p>Also, the ailing grandfather of the bride insisted that she get married at the earliest, they added.</p>

<p>The family members of the groom and the bride agreed to a virtual 'nikah' and the barat from Bilaspur reached Mandi on Sunday. The marriage was held on Monday.</p>

<p>The couple connected through video calling and a qazi performed the rituals with the duo saying "qubool hai" thrice.</p>

<p>Akram Mohammad, the uncle of the girl said the wedding was made possible only due to the advanced technology.</p>

<p>Last year in July, Ashish Singha from Kotgarh in Shimla and Shivani Thakur from Bhuntar in Kullu tied the knot through video-conferencing as the barat could not reach its destination due to landslides and flash floods.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-01/clrnskf8_pakistan-wedding-generic_625x300_16_January_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ailing grandfather of the bride insisted that she get married at the earliest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mark-zuckerberg-avoids-personal-liability-in-meta-addiction-cases-6971394]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg Avoids Personal Liability In Meta Addiction Cases]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mark-zuckerberg-avoids-personal-liability-in-meta-addiction-cases-6971394]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:09:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A federal judge again rejected a bid to hold Mark Zuckerberg individually liable in two dozen lawsuits accusing Meta Platforms Inc. and other social media companies of addicting children to their products.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A federal judge again rejected a bid to hold Mark Zuckerberg individually liable in two dozen lawsuits accusing Meta Platforms Inc. and other social media companies of addicting children to their products.</p>

<p>US District Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers, who is overseeing the cases, sided with the Meta chief executive officer on Thursday, finding that a revised complaint still wasn't legally sufficient to proceed. The decision dismisses <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/internet/news/meta-bans-accounts-tracking-private-jets-mark-zuckerberg-elon-musk-6856057">Zuckerberg</a> as an individual defendant without affecting claims against Meta as a company.</p>

<p>Lawsuits filed on behalf of young people have alleged that Zuckerberg was repeatedly warned by Meta employees that Instagram and Facebook weren't safe for children but ignored the findings and chose not to share them publicly.</p>

<p>Holding CEOs of large companies personally responsible for wrongdoing is generally difficult because of a corporate law tradition of shielding executives from liability.</p>

<p>"While possible that discovery may reveal a more active participation and direction by Zuckerberg in Meta's alleged fraudulent concealment, the allegations before the court are insufficient to meet the standard for corporate-officer liability," Rogers said in her order.</p>

<p>The cases naming <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/cryptocurrency/news/mark-zuckerberg-metaverse-usd-201-billion-fortune-6684341">Zuckerberg</a> are a small subset of a collection of more than 1,000 suits in state and federal courts in California by families and public school districts against Meta along with Alphabet Inc.'s Google, ByteDance Ltd.'s TikTok, and Snap Inc., owner of the Snapchat platform. Rogers and a state judge in Los Angeles have allowed some claims to proceed against the companies while dismissing others.</p>

<p>The case is In Re Social Media Adolescent Addiction/Personal Injury Products Liability Litigation, 22-md-03047, US District Court, Northern District of California (Oakland).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lvjgmba8_mark-zuckerberg_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/archaeologists-uncover-17th-century-anti-vampire-grave-with-woman-buried-with-sickle-around-neck-6970904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In 17th-Century "Anti-Vampire" Grave, Woman Buried With Sickle Around Neck]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/archaeologists-uncover-17th-century-anti-vampire-grave-with-woman-buried-with-sickle-around-neck-6970904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:54:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Archaeologists investigating a 400-year-old grave in northern Poland have found the remains of a young woman buried with a sickle across her neck and a padlock on her left big toe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Archaeologists investigating a 400-year-old grave in northern Poland have found the remains of a young woman buried with a sickle across her neck and a padlock on her left big toe. Legends and burial customs of the time reveal that people believed such measures would protect them against any potential supernatural acts.</p>

<p>Named "Zosia" by locals, the woman's remains were first unearthed in 2022. Since then, scientists have been analysing her skeleton to understand her background and why she was buried in a way that suggests fears of vampirism or demonic reanimation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Recently, Swedish forensic artist Oscar Nilsson recreated her facial features using a 3D-printed model of her skull. “He added so much feeling, so much emotion,” Dariusz Polinski, professor at Nicolaus Copernicus University in Poland told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/07/science/vampire-woman-facial-reconstruction-poland/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>, calling the reconstruction “mind-blowing.”</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ueek4a3_anti-vampire-grave-poland_625x300_08_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Further studies on Zosia's skeletal remains have offered clues to her life and possible hardships. Analysis revealed she was likely between 18 and 20 years old and may have suffered from health issues such as severe headaches, fainting spells, and a chest tumour. These conditions were not the cause of her death, which remains unknown. More tests are underway.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fine silver and gold threads found in her grave suggest Zosia may have belonged to a high-status family, perhaps from southern Scandinavia. Mr Polinski said that during this era, Poland and Sweden were engaged in conflict.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j1a1uqu8_anti-vampire-grave-poland_625x300_08_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The burial methods – initially a padlock on her toe, later the addition of the sickle – were typical “anti-vampire” practices of the time. Mr Polinski explained, “Initially she was buried in a coffin in a natural position, with the head towards the west and on a pillow and the padlock on her toe.” But superstitious locals might have reopened her grave, disturbed her remains, and placed the sickle across her neck, likely after a local misfortune was attributed to her spirit.</p>

<p>The burial site, which archaeologists began exploring in 2005, is believed to have served as a cemetery for around four generations in the 17th century, although no written records exist. The team continues to explore the site, where other unsettling graves, including that of a child buried face down and a pregnant woman, suggest a broader ritualistic pattern.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jtf0v4a_antivampire-grave-poland_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Named "Zosia" by locals, the woman's remains were first unearthed in 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-media-shares-surge-by-nearly-8-after-his-election-win-6971196]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Media Shares Surge By Nearly 8% After His US Presidential Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-media-shares-surge-by-nearly-8-after-his-election-win-6971196]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:38:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After Donald Trump's landslide win in Tuesday's US elections, shares in Trump Media & Technology Group surged, adding nearly $300 million to the President-elect's fortune.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After Donald Trump's landslide win in Tuesday's US elections, shares in Trump Media &amp; Technology Group surged, adding nearly $300 million to the President-elect's fortune. Trump Media shares rose almost 8 percent by midday, reaching just under $37, following a premarket surge that briefly sent shares above $40, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tylerroush/2024/11/06/donald-trumps-net-worth-adds-nearly-300-million-after-election-win-as-trump-media-shares-surge/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">Forbes</a> reported.</p>

<p>This bump has pushed the value of Trump's approximately 57 percent stake – around 114.75 million shares – in the media company up by $290 million, now totalling $4.1 billion. The uptick in trading comes on the heels of a volatile Tuesday session when shares initially soared by over 18 percent to $40.74 before slipping back and eventually closing down by 1 percent.</p>

<p>Despite this market boost, Trump Media reported a $19.2 million loss for its third quarter, with revenues falling 5.6 percent year-over-year. Nonetheless, October was a banner month for the company, with shares jumping 119 percent, peaking at $54.68 – the highest since June.</p>

<p>Donald Trump's net worth is estimated at $6.3 billion, according to recent evaluations by Forbes. His fortune, tied heavily to Trump Media's fluctuating stock value, briefly surpassed $8 billion earlier this year amid high trading volatility. The company, which went public through a reverse merger, has seen its stock rise and fall in response to Trump's campaign activities, including significant shifts after debates with US President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Since going public, Trump Media has been closely aligned with Trump's political trajectory. Valued at nearly $10 billion in May, the stock saw a dramatic dip below $11, risking restrictions on Trump's ability to liquidate shares. In recent weeks, however, the stock, pushed by election-betting markets favouring Trump's campaign, rebounded significantly.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j546pg1o_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump Media shares rose almost 8 per cent by midday, reaching just under $37.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chinas-17-year-old-maths-prodigy-was-assisted-by-teacher-to-ace-the-global-contest-probe-finds-6971183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Maths "Prodigy" Cheated To Ace The Global Contest, Probe Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chinas-17-year-old-maths-prodigy-was-assisted-by-teacher-to-ace-the-global-contest-probe-finds-6971183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:36:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 17-year-old student in China hailed as a "genius" for her score in a maths competition cheated, competition organisers said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 17-year-old student in China hailed as a "genius" for her score in a maths competition cheated, competition organisers said. According to the <em>South China Morning Post</em>, Jiang Ping, a fashion design student from a rural town in Jiangsu province, came into the limelight in June after securing 12th rank in the Alibaba Global Mathematics Competition's preliminaries. She was the first finalist since the contest began in 2018 to have come from a lowly vocational school. The majority of the 800 finalists came from elite universities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The competition results turned Ms Ping into an overnight sensation, with many calling her a "prodigy" on social media, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3285002/teen-chinese-maths-genius-was-helped-teacher-ace-global-contest-probe-finds" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>SCMP</em></a>. However, the attention also prompted scrutiny as other contestants questioned her scores and maths competence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a joint letter sent to the organising committee in June, other finalists alleged that the 17-year-old had made "several apparent writing mistakes" in an online video and that she "seemed unfamiliar with these mathematical expressions and symbols". They demanded an investigation into Ms Ping. They also called for her answers to the preliminary test questions to be made public.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the event's organising committee said an investigation found that Ms Ping achieved the results with her teacher's help. It said that the teenager had violated competition rules in the preliminary round, by receiving help from her teacher, who was also a contestant himself. "This has exposed problems like inadequacies in the competition format and the lack of rigour in supervision. We sincerely apologise," organisers said in a statement, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c87xj8d0131o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Ping's school, Lianshui Secondary Vocational School, also confirmed that Wang Ruihui, the teacher of Jiang Ping, had helped the 17-year-old and that Wang had been given a warning and disqualified from teachers' awards for the year. The statement also called for leniency and protection for the teenager.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/pak-woman-gets-rejected-from-job-interview-after-unreliable-ai-detector-flags-her-original-work-6970219">Pak Woman Gets Rejected From Job Interview After "Unreliable AI Detector" Flags Her Original Work</a></strong></p>

<p>The competition committee apologised, acknowledging shortcomings in the management of the event and pledging improvement, the outlet reported. The committee also announced its winners on Sunday, recognising 86 participants for their achievements.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on social media, Sunday's revelation sparked a wave of criticism of Ms Ping and her teacher. "Mathematics is objective and cold. You can cheat for once and fool all the people who know little of mathematics, but you cannot fool all of the mathematicians in the game," one user said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, some users spoke up for the teenager, arguing that the bigger responsibility lay with her school and teacher. "Jiang Ping is not innocent, that's without question. But who are the worst parties in this? The adults brought this child along to do a bad deed, and let her suffer all the consequences," said one user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Even if the whole thing was faked, Jiang Ping was not the mastermind behind it. She should not be burned at the stake," commented another.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8ial3ofo_maths-generic_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Ping ranked 12th in the preliminaries of the mathematics competition. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-outlet-that-interviewed-s-jaishankar-responds-to-canadas-ban-6971182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian Outlet That Interviewed S Jaishankar Responds To Canada's Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-outlet-that-interviewed-s-jaishankar-responds-to-canadas-ban-6971182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:35:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian news outlet has raised concerns over press freedom after it was blocked by Canada for airing an interview with Foreign Minister S Jaishankar and the press conference of Australian Senator Penny Wong.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian news outlet has raised concerns over press freedom after it was blocked by Canada for airing an interview with Foreign Minister S Jaishankar and the press conference of Australian Senator Penny Wong. Responding to the ban, The Australia Today's managing editor Jitarth Jai Bharadwaj said the move has made it difficult for the team, but they are undeterred by such obstacles.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar's Australia visit ended Thursday, during which he met Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and co-chaired the 15th Foreign Ministers' Framework Dialogue with Ms Wong. Canada blocked the outlet's social media pages soon after it held a press conference with Mr Jaishankar and Ms Wong. The move coming amid diplomatic tensions between New Delhi and Ottawa, sparked a strong response from India, who called out their "hypocrisy" towards freedom of speech.</p>

<p>The Australia Today responded to the ban this morning, stating that they will be undeterred by such obstacles.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Statement from The Australia Today:<br />
We at <a href="https://twitter.com/TheAusToday?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@TheAusToday</a> would like to extend our heartfelt gratitude to every <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/news?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#news</a> outlet, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/journalist?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#journalist</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/supporter?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#supporter</a> who stood by us during a challenging time. The recent restriction and ban on our interview with Indian External Affairs Minister… <a href="https://t.co/53UTd5Le19">pic.twitter.com/53UTd5Le19</a></p>
— The Australia Today (@TheAusToday) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheAusToday/status/1854666666174824494?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"The recent restriction and ban on our interview with Indian External Affairs Minister @DrSJaishankar and the press conference with Australian Foreign Minister @SenatorWong on #socialmedia, under orders from the Canadian government, have been difficult for our team and those who value free and open #journalism," said Mr Bharadwaj's statement.</p>

<p>The Australia Today vowed to continue advocating for an open and inclusive media landscape as it thanked the fraternity for being a beacon of strength amid the restrictions. "We remain steadfast in our mission to bring important stories and voices to the public, undeterred by these obstacles," said managing editor Mr Bharadwaj in the statement.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-australia-today-india-calls-out-canadas-move-against-australian-outlet-that-interviewed-s-jaishankar-6965431">India Calls Out Canada's Move Against Australian Outlet That Interviewed S Jaishankar</a></p>

<p>Besides concerns over press freedom, the ban also turned out to be the latest point of friction between India and Canada that threatens to worsen their diplomatic tensions. On being asked about the matter yesterday, Ministry of External Affairs Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said the social media handles and pages of the "diaspora outlet" have been blocked and are not available for viewers in Canada.</p>

<p>"We were surprised. It looks strange to us. But, nonetheless, these are actions that yet again highlight the hypocrisy of Canada towards freedom of speech. In his media interactions, the External Affairs Minister spoke about three things: a pattern of Canada making allegations without evidence, the surveillance of Indian diplomats - which he termed unacceptable - and the political space being given in Canada to anti-India elements. So you can draw your conclusions from that on why the Australia Today channel was blocked," said the top diplomat.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-replies-to-we-need-your-help-removing-trudeau-post-6970273">Elon Musk Replies To 'We Need Your Help Removing Trudeau' Post</a></p>

<p>India-Canada's ties strained after Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau blamed Indian agents for the murder of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar. The charge was trashed by India as baseless. Last month, the relationship hit a new low with Canada terming the Indian High Commissioner as a "person of interest" in the killing. The move saw India withdrawing some top diplomats from the country while dismissing the charge as "ludicrous".</p>

<p>Last week, India flagged a violation of diplomatic conventions by the Canadian government for putting some of its consular officials under audio and video surveillance. Canada could not hide behind the technicalities to justify its harassment, the government had said while lodging a protest with the Canadian government.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d83eucg_s-jaishankar_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-elizabeths-1947-wedding-cake-slice-auctioned-for-rs-2-40-lakh-6971123]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Queen Elizabeth's 1947 Wedding Cake Slice Auctioned For Rs 2.40 Lakh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-elizabeths-1947-wedding-cake-slice-auctioned-for-rs-2-40-lakh-6971123]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:35:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 77-year-old slice of wedding cake from the 1947 royal wedding of Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip has just been sold for &#163;2,200 (around Rs 2.40 lakh) at an auction.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 77-year-old slice of wedding cake from the 1947 royal wedding of Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip has just been sold for £2,200 (around Rs 2.40 lakh) at an auction. Described as a “very rare slice,” the cake has remained preserved since the couple's marriage on November 20, 1947. But it no longer appears suitable for consumption.</p>

<p>The slice, kept in its original packaging, features a small box with a silver emblem of the then-Princess Elizabeth. Inside, the box holds an intricate doily, which has helped preserve the cake for over 70 years. The original recipient of this specific slice was Marion Polson, a housekeeper at HolyroodHouse in Edinburgh, Scotland, who received it as a gift from Buckingham Palace.</p>

<p>According to auction house <a href="https://www.reemandansie.com/news-item/slice-of-queens-wedding-cake-sells-for-2k/" rel="nofollow,noindex">Reeman Dansie</a>, Marion Polson was the housekeeper at the Palace of Holyroodhouse from 1931 to 1969.</p>

<p>Alongside the cake, Polson received a personal letter from Elizabeth, thanking her for the wedding gift. “We are both enchanted with the dessert service; the different flowers and the beautiful colouring will, I know, be greatly admired by all who see it. This is a present which we shall use constantly, and whenever we do we shall think of the kindness and good wishes for our happiness which it represents,” reads the typewritten note, signed by the future queen.</p>

<p>“The Wedding of H.R.H. Princess Elizabeth to Lieutenant Prince Philip of Greece R.N. on 20th November 1947, (later H.M. Queen Elizabeth II and H.R.H. The Duke of Edinburgh), a rare piece of wedding cake in original box with presentation card and original packaging addressed to 'Miss Polson, Palace of Holyroodhouse, Edinburgh, Scotland' Postmarked 21 April 1948. Sold with a printed letter from H.R.H. Princess Elizabeth thanking the Royal Household Staff for their Wedding Present,” the auction house wrote on its website.</p>

<p>According to <a href="http://https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/07/style/cake-elizabeth-philip-wedding-sale-intl-scli/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>, the original wedding cake was an elaborate creation, standing nine feet tall and weighing 500 pounds (around 227 kg). Decorated with coats of arms from both families, it also featured sugar sculptures representing the couple's favourite activities. The massive cake provided 2,000 slices for wedding guests, with additional portions distributed to charities and organisations. One tier was saved for the christening of their first child, Prince Charles.</p>

<p>While a few pieces of the cake have been preserved and auctioned over the years, they remain highly sought after by royal memorabilia collectors. In 2013, another slice from the 1947 cake was auctioned by Christie's, fetching £1,750 (around Rs 1.91 lakh).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j4iv8s78_queen-elizabeth-wedding-cake-slice_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Described as a "very rare slice," the cake has remained preserved since the couple's marriage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/americans-see-immigration-as-donald-trumps-top-priority-fear-mass-deportation-6971178]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Americans See Immigration As Trump's Top Priority, Fear Mass Deportation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/americans-see-immigration-as-donald-trumps-top-priority-fear-mass-deportation-6971178]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:34:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Americans see immigration as the most pressing issue for President-elect Donald Trump to address, and a large majority believe he will order mass deportations of people living in the US illegally, a Reuters/Ipsos poll that closed Thursday found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Americans see immigration as the most pressing issue for President-elect Donald Trump to address, and a large majority believe he will order mass deportations of people living in the US illegally, a Reuters/Ipsos poll that closed Thursday found.</p>

<p>But respondents to the two-day poll, conducted in the hours after the Republican clinched his election victory, were divided about his plans to expel large numbers of people.</p>

<p>Asked what Trump's top priority should be in the first 100 days following his Jan. 20 inauguration, 25% of respondents said he should prioritize immigration, a much larger share than any other issue. Some 14% of respondents said Trump should focus on income inequality, 12% said taxes and smaller shares picked healthcare, crime, jobs or the environment.</p>

<p>Some 82% of respondents in the poll considered it likely that Trump would order mass deportations, including similar shares of Democrats and Republicans. Many said they are concerned about the expected policy, including 82% of Democrats and 40% of independents. About nine in 10 Republicans said they were not concerned Trump could order mass deportations.</p>

<p>Trump campaigned to return to the White House vowing a vast immigration crackdown, including a promise to deport record numbers of immigrants in an operation Trump's running mate JD Vance estimated could remove 1 million people per year.</p>

<p>During his campaign, Trump frequently called attention to crimes reportedly committed by immigrants lacking legal status, though numerous studies have shown immigrants do not commit crimes at higher rates than native-born Americans.</p>

<p>Trump backers - including some who could enter his second administration - anticipate the Republican will call on everyone from the US military to diplomats overseas to turn the promise of mass deportations into reality. The effort would include cooperation with Republican-led states and using federal funding as leverage against resistant jurisdictions.</p>

<p>Immigrant advocates warn that Trump's deportation effort would be costly, divisive and inhumane.</p>

<p>Trump told NBC News in an interview on Thursday that he would carry out his promise of mass deportations regardless of cost, saying, "It's not a question of a price tag. It's not - really, we have no choice."</p>

<p>Americans are divided over the possible mechanics of mass deportations, such as whether they might involve detention camps.</p>

<p>Some 58% of Republicans in the poll - but only 15% of Democrats - agreed with a statement the immigrants without authorization to be in the country should be "arrested and put in detention camps while awaiting deportation hearings." About 75% of Democrats opposed rounding up immigrants in that manner, as did 31% of Republicans.</p>

<p>Trump plans to use a 1798 wartime statute known as the Alien Enemies Act to rapidly deport alleged gang members, an action that would almost certainly be challenged in court.</p>

<p>The law has been used three times, according to the Brennan Center for Justice: the War of 1812, World War One and World War Two, when it was employed to justify internment camps for people of Japanese, German and Italian descent.</p>

<p>The Reuters/Ipsos poll, which was conducted online, surveyed 1,471 adults nationwide and the results had a margin of error of 3 percentage points for all respondents and 5 points for Republicans and Democrats.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/noj1nsk8_us-migrants_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Advocates warn that deportation effort would be costly, divisive and inhumane. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-flee-out-of-control-california-wildfire-as-homes-burn-6971085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Flee Out-Of-Control California Wildfire As Homes Burn]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-flee-out-of-control-california-wildfire-as-homes-burn-6971085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:21:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of people were urged to flee an out-of-control wildfire burning around communities near Los Angeles on Thursday, with scores of homes already lost to the fast-moving flames.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of people were urged to flee an out-of-control wildfire burning around communities near Los Angeles on Thursday, with scores of homes already lost to the fast-moving flames.</p>

<p>Fierce seasonal winds had cast embers up to three miles (five kilometers) from the seat of the fire around Camarillo, with new spots burning on hillsides, farmland and in residential areas.</p>

<p>The Mountain Fire grew rapidly from a standing start early Wednesday, and by the following day had consumed 20,485 acres (8,290 hectares), with towering flames leaping unpredictably and sending residents scrambling.</p>

<p>The fire was only five percent contained as of Thursday evening, authorities said, although wind patterns were expected to favor firefighters through the night.</p>

<p>"We've been up all night watching this. I haven't slept," Erica Preciado told one local broadcaster as she drove her family out of the danger zone.</p>

<p>"We're just trying to get a safe place. I didn't even know what to take. I just have everything in my car," she said, gesturing tearfully to her packed vehicle.</p>

<p>Authorities said that based on initial inspections, at least 132 homes had been completely destroyed, with 88 more damaged by the fires.</p>

<p>One man told broadcaster KTLA he and his family had fled their home of 27 years, finding out later that it had been destroyed.</p>

<p>"It's all gone," he said, his voice catching. "It's all gone."</p>

<p>Dawn Deleon described how she had only moments to flee with her six dogs.</p>

<p>"We watched the neighbors' houses burning and figured it was time to get out of there," she said.</p>

<p>"We left and were just gone for five minutes and went back to get my phone, and the house was already on fire and gone."</p>

<p><strong>Winds to abate</strong></p>

<p>Ventura County Fire Department officials said they were throwing resources at the blaze in an area that is home to 30,000 people, but that changing wind patterns meant there was hope the fire could die down in the coming days.</p>

<p>"Winds are subsiding over the lower elevations while remaining still gusty over the higher elevations," said Ariel Cohen of the National Weather Service.</p>

<p>"By the time we get to 11:00 am (on Friday) the winds will further subside across the region, and we are not expecting any red flag warnings to be in effect for the area."</p>

<p>On Thursday, California Governor Gavin Newsom visited communities impacted by the fire and declared a state of emergency in the worst-affected area of Ventura County.</p>

<p>There, crews on the ground had defended homes with hose lines working alongside bulldozers that were trying to remove fuels.</p>

<p>Helicopter pilots worked throughout the night on Wednesday dropping water, said Ventura County fire captain Trevor Johnson. That was expected to continue on Thursday night.</p>

<p>Hoses ran dry for crews battling the flames at one point late Wednesday, Ventura County Fire Chief Dustin Gardner said.</p>

<p>He said hundreds of fire trucks had been pumping water all night, putting a strain on resources.</p>

<p>"We have been fighting fire actively now for 26 hours, and we found all of those fire trucks hooked up to all of those hydrants, and we drained water systems down," he told reporters.</p>

<p>That affected supplies higher up hillsides, and forced crews to shuttle water up to the blazes.</p>

<p>He said while it was not a common problem, it is known to happen in major incidents.</p>

<p>"It's normal enough that we plan for it, so it's impactful, but it will be mitigated," he said.</p>

<p><strong>'Very dangerous'</strong></p>

<p>At least 400 homes had been evacuated, Ventura County Sheriff Jim Fryhoff said, adding that 250 residents had chosen to stay behind.</p>

<p>"I urge everyone to stay out of the areas that are impacted. The fire is still very dangerous," he said.</p>

<p>The cause of the fire was not immediately known, but meteorologists had raised a Red Flag Warning and a rare Particularly Dangerous Situation (PDS) warning in the area, indicating dangerous fire conditions.</p>

<p>They said two years of above-average rainfall had sparked abundant growth of vegetation, which was now all bone-dry after a long, hot summer.</p>

<p>Electricity companies had cut power to tens of thousands of customers in the area -- a common strategy in California during high winds in a bid to reduce the risk of new fires from toppled power lines.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l7ah3qdo_los-angeles-fire_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mountain fire grew rapidly from a standing start and had consumed 20,485 acres by following day. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-trumps-win-many-despondent-americans-research-moving-abroad-6971024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Trump's Win, Americans Research "Move To" Canada, New Zealand, Australia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-trumps-win-many-despondent-americans-research-moving-abroad-6971024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:14:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Many Americans are worried that Trump's presidency could drive a bigger wedge between Democrats and Republicans on issues such as race, gender, what and how children are taught, and reproductive rights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As U.S. election exit polls began to point to a second presidency for Donald Trump, many Americans were already looking for another kind of exit: moving abroad.</p>

<p>Google searches for "move to Canada" surged 1,270% in the 24 hours after U.S. East Coast polls closed on Tuesday, company data shows. Similar searches about moving to New Zealand climbed nearly 2,000% while those for Australia jumped 820%.</p>

<p>Late Wednesday evening on the US East Coast, Google searches about emigrating were hitting all-time highs for all three countries, according to a Google official.</p>

<p>The search giant does not provide absolute figures but data from the Immigration New Zealand website showed the site logged some 25,000 new U.S. users on Nov. 7, compared to 1,500 for the same day last year.</p>

<p>Some immigration lawyers are also being inundated with queries.</p>

<p>"Every half hour there is a new email enquiry," said Evan Green, managing partner at Canada's oldest immigration law firm, Green and Spiegel.</p>

<p>The sudden enthusiasm for emigration echoes the interest in moving abroad seen after Trump's 2016 victory. This time, however, the Republican's re-election has followed a particularly divisive campaign in which nearly three-quarters of U.S. voters said they felt American democracy was under threat, according to Edison Research exit polls.</p>

<p>Many Americans are also worried that his presidency could drive a bigger wedge between Democrats and Republicans on issues such as race, gender, what and how children are taught, and reproductive rights.</p>

<p>"Trump is obviously the impetus, but it's also societal. The majority of Americans voted for him and some people don't necessarily feel comfortable living in that kind of society anymore. People are afraid they are going to lose freedoms," said Green.</p>

<p>In a Reddit group dedicated to those leaving the U.S., called "r/AmerExit," hundreds shared suggestions about ideal destinations and tips for getting visas and jobs. Some users said they feared for their country, their safety, or both after Trump's election.</p>

<p>Even before the election, those fears were increasingly cited by Americans looking to emigrate to Canada, according to Heather Bell, an immigration consultant at Vancouver law firm Bell Alliance.</p>

<p>Few, however, manage to follow through, said Bell.</p>

<p>"Immigrating to Canada is not easy, especially now with the government reducing the numbers of temporary and permanent migrants coming to Canada," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jt70oiio_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some immigration lawyers are also being inundated with queries. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lngs-climate-impact-a-cleaner-alternative-or-hidden-emitter-6970985]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[LNG's Climate Impact: A Cleaner Alternative Or Hidden Emitter?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lngs-climate-impact-a-cleaner-alternative-or-hidden-emitter-6970985]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:09:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Liquefied natural gas (LNG) has positioned itself as a "transition" fuel to replace highly polluting coal. While LNG burns cleaner than coal, its climate impact is darkened by energy-intensive production and frequent leaks from gas fields.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Liquefied natural gas (LNG) has positioned itself as a "transition" fuel to replace highly polluting coal. While LNG burns cleaner than coal, its climate impact is darkened by energy-intensive production and frequent leaks from gas fields.</p>

<p><strong>Why is LNG so popular?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Global demand for natural gas is expected to rise by 2.5 percent in 2024 to a record level, mostly driven by LNG.</p>

<p>European nations have been big importers to replace Russian gas while Asian nations need it to fuel their growing economies.</p>

<p>Natural gas needs expensive pipelines to be developed from production sites to distribution networks.</p>

<p>Once it is chilled to -163 degrees Celsius however, it liquifies and its volume shrinks by 600 times.</p>

<p>This makes it feasible to transport by special ships and it can then be turned back into gas and injected into existing distribution networks.</p>

<p><strong>Leaks</strong></p>

<p>The oil and gas industry often points out that gas-fired power stations emit 2.5 times fewer emissions than their coal counterparts.</p>

<p>Scientists and climate activists say that not only smokestack emissions need to be taken into account, but the entire production and distribution chain.</p>

<p>And that involves a lot of energy for LNG.</p>

<p>"You have to expend so much energy to extract the gas from the ground, to liquefy the gas, to transport it," Rystad Energy analyst Patrick King.</p>

<p>Another problem is the industry is notorious for leaks: from the fields, pipelines and processing facilities. And natural gas is mostly methane, which is much more powerful greenhouse gas than CO2: 86 times as powerful during the first 20 years it is in the atmosphere and 28 times more powerful a century.</p>

<p>"Why lock yourself into another emitter fuel?" said Ana Maria Jaller-Makarewicz, an analyst at the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis (IEEFA).</p>

<p>"Do the transition directly," she said.</p>

<p><strong>Variable carbon footprints</strong></p>

<p>King said LNG produces more emissions than natural gas transported through pipelines.</p>

<p>Some studies indicate that its climate impact could be worse than coal.</p>

<p>A Cornell University study published last month calculated that LNG produced in the United States had a carbon footprint a third higher than coal when production and transport were included, over a 20-year horizon.</p>

<p>Even over a longer period -- 100 years -- its carbon footprint remained the same or higher than that of coal.</p>

<p>But a study by Rystad Energy published earlier this year concluded the opposite. It found that on average, electricity produced with LNG had a lower carbon footprint than carbon when the entire production chain was taken into account.</p>

<p>It also said that even LNG produced in America and shipped across the Pacific to generate electricity could have a carbon footprint just half of the cleanest coal-fired plant.</p>

<p>However, the report did also note considerable differences between different gas fields in reducing methane leaks, which affects their climate impact.</p>

<p>Jonathan Stern, a researcher at the Oxford Institute for Energy Study, said it was extremely complicated to determine whether LNG or coal was worse for the climate.</p>

<p>"It's a subject where you need to be confident that you've got data which is independent and verified," he said.</p>

<p>"And mostly we don't have that data."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/78teoong_lng-import_625x300_26_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some studies indicate that LNG's climate impact could be worse than coal. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andre-beadle-1stockf30-influencer-and-youtuber-famous-for-drag-racing-videos-dies-in-high-speed-bmw-car-crash-6970721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[YouTuber Famous For Drag Racing Videos Dies In High-Speed BMW Car Crash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andre-beadle-1stockf30-influencer-and-youtuber-famous-for-drag-racing-videos-dies-in-high-speed-bmw-car-crash-6970721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:03:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 25-year-old influencer and YouTuber, famous for his drag-racing videos, died in a car crash early Wednesday morning on the Nassau Expressway in Queens, New York.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 25-year-old influencer and YouTuber, famous for his drag-racing videos, died in a car crash early Wednesday morning on the Nassau Expressway in Queens, New York. Andre Beadle, known online as 1Stockf30, was reportedly driving eastbound “at a high rate of speed” in a 2023 BMW when he lost control of the vehicle, New York police confirmed.<br />
<br />
Police shared he “veered to the right,” going off the right side of the road and into the shoulder, where his vehicle collided with a metal pole, authorities told <a href="https://people.com/youtube-star-andre-beadle-dies-25-crashing-bmw-8741322 ">People magazine</a>. Emergency responders arrived at the scene around 1:12 am, and Beadle was transported to Jamaica Hospital Medical Centre, where he was pronounced dead. The Highway District's Collision Investigation Squad is continuing to investigate the incident.<br />
<br />
Mr Beadle, who had 59,500 YouTube subscribers and nearly 250,000 followers on Instagram, frequently shared content on street racing and his experiences with high-performance cars. In a video titled “I'm bringing the M240 back to the streets + Trackhawk vs 1Stock Corvette $10,000 race,” he took his BMW to get it serviced in preparation for an upcoming race.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eHYU-mJALiA?si=-vU4KWTf2SUd3iDD" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Some of Mr Beadle's videos, filmed alongside other popular street racers, included disclaimers urging viewers to “follow the road code and drive with care.”<br />
<br />
In June, Mr Beadle revealed in a video that he previously crashed his BMW at “170 mph.”<br />
<br />
Fans and supporters have been invited to gather at Haffen Park on Friday, November 8, at 4:30 pm for a balloon release in his honour.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by 1Stock ???? (@1stockf30)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>“Bring some balloons and come celebrate life with the young legend and trendsetter,” read a post shared to Mr Beadle's Instagram on Wednesday. The tribute described him as “driven by passion” and “fueled by the thrill,” adding, “May you find the ultimate track among the stars.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bunqqt5o_andre-beadle-instagram_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andre Beadle frequently shared content on street racing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rahul-gandhi-writes-to-kamala-harris-after-donald-trump-wins-2024-us-elections-6970900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Your Unifying Message Of Hope...": Rahul Gandhi Writes To Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rahul-gandhi-writes-to-kamala-harris-after-donald-trump-wins-2024-us-elections-6970900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:54:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi's message to Kamala Harris came after she lost to Donald Trump in the hotly-contested US presidential polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi has written to outgoing US Vice President Kamala Harris congratulating her on her spirited presidential campaign and said her unifying message of hope will continue to inspire many.</p>

<p>Ms Harris lost to Donald Trump in the hotly-contested US presidential polls.</p>

<p>"I would like to congratulate you on your spirited Presidential campaign. Your unifying message of hope will continue to inspire many," Mr Gandhi said in his letter to Harris.</p>

<p>Under the Biden administration, India and the United States have deepened cooperation on issues of global importance, the former Congress chief said.</p>

<p>"Our shared commitment to democratic values will continue to guide our friendship. As the Vice-President, your determination to bring people together and find common ground will be remembered," Mr Gandhi said in his letter dated November 7.</p>

<p>"I wish you the very best in your future endeavours," he added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gc81into_kamala-harris-rahul-gandhi_625x300_08_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heres-who-could-join-trumps-new-administration-team-6970848]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Here's Who Could Join Donald Trump's New Administration Team]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heres-who-could-join-trumps-new-administration-team-6970848]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:49:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump is expected to draw top advisers and cabinet secretaries from a pool of Wall Street and business executives including officials from his first term - at least the ones who stuck by him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's team is forming a new administration and the president-elect is expected to draw top advisers and cabinet secretaries from a pool of Wall Street and business executives including officials from his first term - at least the ones who stuck by him.</p>

<p>Republicans are on track to win total control of government, gaining not just the White House but also the Senate. And as of Thursday, they are leading to control the US House. That means Trump's nominees for 4,000 government posts, including more than two dozen cabinet officials, could sail through the confirmation process in the Senate.</p>

<p>Trump's transition work was formally launched in August, with Howard Lutnick, chief executive officer of Cantor Fitzgerald LP, and Linda McMahon, co-founder of World Wrestling Entertainment, serving as co-chairs. Both have been spending time at Mar-a-Lago with Trump, where interviews for cabinet jobs are expected to take place.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Trump named campaign manager <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/susie-wiles-donald-trumps-aid-and-1st-woman-white-house-chief-of-staff-6969540" target="_blank">Susie Wiles as his White House chief of staff</a>. She will be the first woman to hold one of the most powerful jobs in Washington. She will likely have direct control over the president's schedule, and is in a position to drive high-priority policy coordination within the administration and Congress.</p>

<p>She was widely credited with bringing order and discipline to the chaotic world that Trump often cultivates, and helped him navigate both the general election and the Republican primaries.</p>

<p>Trump has also suggested he might tap Elon Musk or Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to drive some of his agenda.</p>

<p>Trump's transition team is far more organized than in 2016 as the team aims to avoid repeating the early, chaotic days of the 2017 White House. Before the end of November, he could name the leaders of the Treasury and State departments. Trump himself had not weighed in on personnel matters before Election Day. What follows is a list based on who has advised and promoted him during the campaign, helped raise money, and who people familiar with the matter say have been floated over the past few months.</p>

<p><strong>Treasury Secretary</strong></p>

<p>This job comes with enormous responsibility over the global economy. Treasury chiefs serve as the key spokesperson for the world's reserve currency, economic cheerleader, financial market regulator, signatory of the almighty buck. They wade through political thickets, spearhead international economic diplomacy, and bring Wall Street know-how to crisis situations that require them to get into the financial system's plumbing. At the same time, they must exude predictability and stability - sometimes through their own personal gravitas - that keeps investors at peace.</p>

<p><strong>Scott Bessent:</strong> He runs macro hedge fund Key Square Capital Management and caught the attention of Trump's inner circle early this year. He's helped craft key economic policy speeches, raised money for the campaign and gone on TV to promote Trump's second-term agenda. Over the past few months, Bessent has accused Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen of political interference in debt issuance, slammed the Federal Reserve over September's half-point rate cut, and floated ideas to rev up US currency policy to fit a protectionist agenda.</p>

<p><strong>Jay Clayton:</strong> As SEC chair, Clayton had a partisan mandate to help public companies by relaxing rules and enforcement. Still, as SEC chair - an independent regulator - he often moved cautiously on rules changes and frequently sided with Democrats. He has made television appearances to promote the impact of his time at the top Wall Street regulator, while questioning the effectiveness of current SEC Chair Gary Gensler's aggressive stance against industry.</p>

<p><strong>Senator Bill Hagerty:</strong> A Tennessee native, Hagerty is on the Senate Banking Committee that oversees regulatory matters and monetary policy, among other issues. He was an economic adviser to President George H.W. Bush and then went into private equity. He was elected to the Senate in 2020. Republicans have a majority in the Senate, but it's questionable whether with that narrow a margin Trump would remove a Republican from the chamber.</p>

<p><strong>Robert Lighthizer:</strong> He is among few Cabinet-level advisers from Trump's first term who has not only remained loyal through Trump's post-presidency controversies, but has also been a close adviser this year. He was the US Trade Representative in the first term, serving as an architect of the adversarial US posture with China. Investors are wary of Lighthizer for Treasury because of what it might mean for markets if the proud China hawk steers Trump toward hefty tariffs. He may also be considered to run the Commerce Department, or as a trade advisor in the White House.</p>

<p><strong>Howard Lutnick:</strong> The CEO of Cantor Fitzgerald has quickly become Trump's transition co-chair and top cheerleader on Wall Street. From the Hamptons to the heartland, he's cultivated donors - raising $15 million in one event alone. While Cabinet officials and other high-ranking political appointees are required to publicly disclose their assets and divest any that could cause a conflict of interest, Lutnick could serve as a special government employee. Those positions, which can be unpaid, allow an individual to work up to 130 days for a federal agency or the White House, and do not require divestment or public disclosure.</p>

<p><strong>John Paulson:</strong> Trump has referred to Paulson as a "money machine" for famously making $15 billion betting against subprime mortgages. Both he and Trump were born in Queens, are familiar with messy divorces and legal fights, and are philosophically aligned. Paulson was a member of Trump's economic advisory council during his first presidential bid, has personally donated and helped raise more than $50 million at a gathering in his Palm Beach home - all proof of the loyalty that Trump likes. Paulson would come with complications. He has a large, undisclosed stake in the preferred shares of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac. Taking the top Treasury job would require divestment since the secretary oversees the government-controlled mortgage giant, meaning a potential loss for Paulson.</p>

<p><strong>Glenn Youngkin:</strong> The current governor of Virginia and a former executive of Carlyle Group Inc., Youngkin kept Trump at arm's length in his 2021 campaign. Democratic nominee Kamala Harris carried Virginia in Tuesday's election in the purple state, but he has been more supportive of Trump in recent years. His term is up in 2025.</p>

<p><strong>National Economic Council Director</strong></p>

<p>A president's economic team includes a director for the White House's National Economic Council. This job requires someone with political acumen and the ability to promote the president's agenda in Congress and with the public. Anyone under consideration for the Treasury post could end up as NEC director. Kevin Hassett, an economist who served as head of Trump's Council of Economic Advisers in the first term, and Kevin Warsh, a former Federal Reserve official, are contenders for that job.</p>

<p><strong>Secretary of State</strong></p>

<p>The secretary of state is the top US diplomat, with the job of selling US policy to the rest of the world and persuading foreign allies and adversaries to stick to US national security objectives. But the secretary also oversees State's own intelligence service, negotiates global treaties and civilian airline routes to foreign countries, and helps evacuate Americans from war zones.</p>

<p><strong>Ric Grenell:</strong> Grenell previously served as Trump's ambassador to Germany and then acting national intelligence chief. He is seen as fiercely loyal to Trump, and led efforts to protest the 2020 vote that Trump falsely claimed was stolen from him in Nevada.</p>

<p><strong>Hagerty:</strong> While he's also among those touted for Treasury chief, his experience as US Ambassador to Japan during Trump's first term and time on the Senate Foreign Relations Committee since then mean he could step into the State Department.</p>

<p><strong>Steven Mnuchin:</strong> The former Treasury chief is one of the few officials from Trump's first term that lasted all four years, and remained loyal even after January 6. He landed a job in the first administration after serving as the 2016 campaign's national finance chairman, raising millions of dollars, but has remained largely out of re-election efforts in 2024. During his time at Treasury the US continued its ramped-up use of economic sanctions on adversaries including Iran, Russia and Venezuela, drawing the agency deeper into the national security sphere. That sets him up as a potential secretary of State, although conflicts abound for him, too. Since leaving government, he started Liberty Strategic Capital, a private equity firm that has attracted billions of dollars from the Middle East.</p>

<p><strong>Robert O'Brien:</strong> O'Brien was Trump's national security adviser for a year and a half at the end of his first term. He focused on confronting China over actions that threatened Hong Kong, its aggressive action in the South China Sea, and criticized the nation's response to the outbreak of Covid-19. He also served when the US carried out the drone strike that killed Qassem Soleimani, the head of the Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps and chief of the Quds Force intelligence group. O'Brien is seen as more of a traditional foreign policy conservative than a disruptor.</p>

<p><strong>Marco Rubio:</strong> Trump called him "Little Marco" during the 2016 primary, but the senator from Florida played a key role in advising Trump on foreign policy in his first term, particularly regarding Latin America and Venezuela. Rubio is a member of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, vice chairman of the Senate Intelligence Committee and a member of the Gang of 8, senior legislators who are briefed on classified intelligence matters from the executive branch. He's strongly defended Trump's immigration policies and his goal of ending the Ukraine war, as well as being a top supporter of Israel's war against Iran-backed proxies. Trump considered him as a possible running mate this year.</p>

<p><strong>Commerce Secretary</strong></p>

<p>The Commerce Department was a relative policy backwater in the first Trump administration, with Secretary Wilbur Ross perhaps best known for falling asleep in meetings. But President Joe Biden's secretary, Gina Raimondo, injected a new energy and importance. That has grown with the $280 billion Chips and Science Act passed in 2022, with the department awarding companies with tens of billions of dollars to return semiconductor production to the US from Asia. Commerce plays a key role in trade promotion, as well as with export controls used to keep cutting-edge technology out of the hands of China, Russia and other geopolitical rivals. Two people so far are under consideration: Lighthizer and McMahon.</p>

<p><strong>US Trade Representative</strong></p>

<p>The US Trade Representative will also be key for Trump's populist agenda. Two former USTR officials from the Trump era are under consideration: Jamieson Greer, who served as chief of staff to Lighthizer when he had that role, and Stephen Vaughn, who served as USTR general counsel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vb8qv2dg_donald-trump_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has named campaign manager Susie Wiles as his White House chief of staff. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-re-election-spurs-record-64-billion-surge-for-worlds-wealthiest-6970767]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Re-Election Spurs Record $64 Billion Surge For World's Wealthiest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-re-election-spurs-record-64-billion-surge-for-worlds-wealthiest-6970767]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:34:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The re-election of Donald Trump spurred a surge in wealth for the worlds 10 richest billionaires, who collectively gained $64 billion in a single day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican Donald Trump's US presidential election victory over his Democrat rival Kamala Harris has triggered an unprecedented surge in the net worth of the world's 10 richest individuals, who collectively gained $64 billion.</p>

<p>This remarkable growth is the largest since <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-07/trump-s-election-win-supercharges-net-worth-of-world-s-richest-by-64-billion" rel="nofollow,noindex">Bloomberg</a>'s Billionaires Index inception in 2012.<br />
<br />
<strong>Here's how they fared:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Elon Musk: Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk's fortune soared by $26.5 billion to an incredible $290.3 billion.</li>
	<li>Jeff Bezos: Amazon founder Jeff Bezos saw his net worth jump by $7.1 billion -- roughly 3.2 per cent -- bringing him to $228.3 billion.</li>
	<li>Mark Zuckerberg: Meta's Mark Zuckerberg held steady with a net worth of $202.5 billion, unchanged despite significant market shifts.</li>
	<li>Larry Ellison: Oracle co-founder and Trump ally Larry Ellison enjoyed a $5.5 billion gain, pushing his net worth up 5.4 per cent to $193.5 billion.</li>
	<li>Bernard Arnault: LVMH Chairman Bernard Arnault, the only person in the top 10 list based out of the US, experienced a slight dip of 1.6 per cent, landing at $173.2 billion.</li>
	<li>Bill Gates: Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates saw a modest 1.2 per cent increase, with his wealth climbing to $159.5 billion.</li>
	<li>Larry Page and Sergey Brin: Google co-founders Larry Page and Sergey Brin both posted 3.6 per cent gains. While Page's wealth reached $158.3 billion, Brin's climbed to $149.1 billion.</li>
	<li>Warren Buffett: Berkshire Hathaway's Warren Buffett added $7.5 billion, growing his net worth by 5.4 per cent to $147.8 billion.</li>
	<li>Steve Ballmer: Former Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer saw his fortune rise by 2 per cent to $145.9 billion.</li>
	<li>Binance founder Changpeng Zhao's wealth increased by $12.1 billion to reach $52.7 billion, while Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong's fortune surged by 30 per cent, adding $11 billion to his portfolio.</li>
</ul>

<p>According to Bloomberg, much of this wealth boost is due to a post-election rally in US stocks, with the S&amp;P 500 hitting a record 2.5% gain — the strongest post-election surge in history. The US dollar also gained, said Bloomberg, impacting these billionaires' financial positions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hnr2dd48_elon-musk-jeff-bezos_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>