<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 14:16:53 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-22-found-beaten-to-death-days-after-judge-released-ex-boyfriend-from-jail-6089628]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman, 22, Found Dead Days After Judge Released Ex-Boyfriend From Jail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-22-found-beaten-to-death-days-after-judge-released-ex-boyfriend-from-jail-6089628]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 14:18:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 22-year-old university student in the United States was found beaten to death and wrapped in a sheet in the back seat of her car - days after her boyfriend was let out of jail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 22-year-old university student in the United States was found beaten to death and wrapped in a sheet in the back seat of her car - days after her boyfriend was let out of jail. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, Lauren Johansen's body was discovered wrapped in trash bags and a sheet on July 3 at a cemetery in Mississippi. Her father said he pleaded with a judge not to release her ex-boyfriend from jail, warning he would "kill her" if he did. However, the judge didn't heed his warnings and five days later, the body of the 22-year-old was found mutilated in her own car and police say her boyfriend was responsible.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/11/us-news/nursing-student-lauren-johansen-found-beaten-to-death-after-dads-chilling-warning-to-judge/"><em>Post</em></a>, Ms Johansen's former partner, 23-year-old Bricen Rivers, has been arrested and charged with her murder. He had been released on a bond just five days before the 22-year-old's death. He was previously held for aggravated kidnapping for brutally beating Ms Johansen and holding her hostage during a December trip to Nashville.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Johansen was on track to get her nursing degree. She was first reported missing on July 2 when her sister woke up alone in their shared apartment with the front door wide open and their security camera smashed. The same morning, her father said he woke up to a notification that her location-tracking app had been turned off. He then reported her missing, and the next day, officers informed him that they had located her car in a nearby cemetery.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Johansen was found dead in her car which was parked in the middle of a cemetery in Harrison County, Mississippi. Her mutilated body was wrapped up in trash bags over the back seats.</p>

<p>"She was basically beaten to death. Her face was smashed in, her head was smashed in, she was brutally beaten to the point she couldn't see out of either eye when she finally died and there was multiple holes in her head," Ms Johansen's father said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I helped the coroner lift her body out of the car. It was just mutilated," he continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/china-company-confines-employee-to-small-dark-room-for-4-days-heres-why-6089196">China Company Confines Employee To "Small Dark Room" For 4 Days. Here's Why</a></strong></p>

<p>The father also said that he had warned the judge that if her boyfriend was let out of jail, he would kill her. He alleged that Rivers had held his daughter hostage in December and beat her while the couple were on vacation in Nashville. He also added that in the moments leading to Rivers' December arrest, police officers found Lauren Johansen badly beaten and trying to escape a rental vehicle as Rivers reached for a firearm.</p>

<p>The heartbroken father slammed the criminal justice system in Tennessee for failing his family. "I think the criminal justice system in Nashville, Tennessee, failed my daughter and our family. The world shouldn't work this way," he said. "She was really beautiful, super, super smart. She had dreams and hopes that were larger than life. Everything she did, everything she touched," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now, Rivers, who was arrested following a six-hour manhunt, faces a murder charge and is being held on a $1 million bond.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/a2c6t9lo_lauren-johansen_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bricen Rivers was arrested on July 4 following a six-hour manhunt.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/a-street-in-uae-named-after-84-year-old-doctor-of-indian-origin-george-matthew-6089295]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Street In UAE Named After 84-Year-Old Doctor of Indian Origin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/a-street-in-uae-named-after-84-year-old-doctor-of-indian-origin-george-matthew-6089295]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 14:15:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A road in the UAE capital of Abu Dhabi has been named after an 84-year-old doctor with Indian roots as a tribute to his significant contributions to the country's health sector.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A road in the UAE capital of Abu Dhabi has been named after an 84-year-old doctor with Indian roots as a tribute to his significant contributions to the country's health sector.</p>

<p>The Department of Municipalities and Transport (DMT) has named a road in Abu Dhabi after Dr George Matthew to recognise his contributions as part of its “Honouring UAE's Visionaries: Commemorative Streets” project, which aims to honour individuals who have greatly contributed to the nation's development.</p>

<p>The road near Sheikh Shakbooth Medical City in Al Mafraq will now be known as George Matthew Street.</p>

<p>Reflecting on his journey, Dr Matthew said, “When I first arrived in the UAE, the infrastructure was still evolving. Inspired by the late HH Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, the Father of the Nation, I dedicated myself to helping the people. I am deeply grateful that my efforts have been recognised.” Dr Matthew arrived in the UAE in 1967 at the age of 26. Initially preparing to move to the US, he was persuaded by a missionary friend's description of Al Ain's beauty to stay.</p>

<p>His application for a position as Al Ain's first government doctor was successful, leading to the opening of the first clinic under Sheikh Zayed's blessing.</p>

<p>Starting his service as a General Practitioner, Dr Matthew, affectionately called Matyous (Emirati pronunciation of Mathew) by the locals, witnessed and contributed to the growth of modern medicine in the UAE.</p>

<p>He held several key positions, including Medical Director of Al Ain Region in 1972 and Health Authority Consultant in 2001. His contributions significantly advanced healthcare services in the emirate and promoted a modern medical culture in the country.</p>

<p>Dr Matthew went to England to learn management of tropical diseases, and later to Harvard for specialised studies in hospital management.</p>

<p>His commitment to education and professional development has been instrumental in shaping the healthcare landscape of the UAE. He played a vital role in educating and training healthcare workers, and his dedication earned him the trust and admiration of his colleagues and the community.</p>

<p>Known for his dedication and expertise, Dr Matthew has been a valuable source of medical knowledge for the Al Ain community.</p>

<p>In recognition of his service, the UAE granted Dr Matthew and his family citizenship 10 years ago.</p>

<p>Dr Matthew continues to work in the Private Health department alongside Dr Abdul Rahim Jaafar, another leading healthcare expert in the country.</p>

<p>Expressing his gratitude, Dr Matthew said, “I am ready to do whatever I can for the country and its citizens as long as I live. I pray that God will give me more time to serve.” Dr Matthew grew up in Thumpamon, Pathanamthitta, in Kerala, and graduated with an MBBS in 1965 from Trivandrum Medical College.</p>

<p>He moved to the UAE with his wife, Valsa, after their marriage. Their daughter also works in the government sector. PTI CORR GSP AKJ GSP</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5gfdqsto_george-matthew-uae_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The road near Sheikh Shakbooth Medical City in Al Mafraq will now be known as George Matthew Street.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-mistakenly-refers-to-ukraines-zelensky-as-vladimir-putin-how-he-reacted-6089337]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Biden Calls Him "President Putin". How Ukraine's Zelensky Reacted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-mistakenly-refers-to-ukraines-zelensky-as-vladimir-putin-how-he-reacted-6089337]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 13:37:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In yet another gaffe amid concerns over his re-election bid, US President Joe Biden today mistakenly introduced his Ukraine counterpart Volodymyr Zelensky as his Russian rival Vladimir Putin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In yet another gaffe amid concerns over his re-election bid, US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-denies-reports-of-8-pm-bedtime-but-says-he-needs-to-pace-himself-6088864" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> today mistakenly introduced Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelensky as his Russian rival Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>"And now I want to hand it over to the president of Ukraine, who has as much courage as he has determination, ladies and gentlemen, President Putin," he said, referring to Zelensky while speaking on the sidelines of the NATO Summit in Washington.</p>

<p>Zelensky looked nonplussed, then was seen shaking his head and smiling to himself.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-says-neurological-exams-find-him-in-good-shape-6088759" target="_blank">Biden</a>, 81, then quickly corrected himself and said, "President Putin, you're going to beat President Putin, President Zelensky. I am so focused on beating Putin."</p>

<p>Zelensky, who had by then recovered from his bafflement, responded by saying, "I am better (than Putin)."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Biden is Blunder King ?<br />
<br />
Watch Zelensky's reaction when Biden calls him Putin! <a href="https://t.co/SlGVFBB9ze">pic.twitter.com/SlGVFBB9ze</a></p>
— BALA (@erbmjha) <a href="https://twitter.com/erbmjha/status/1811607877993529601?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"You are a hell of a lot better," Biden replied before Zelensky began his address.</p>

<p>Shortly afterward, Biden made another blunder when he referred to his deputy, Kamala Harris, as "Vice President" Trump at a high-stakes news conference.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-job-joe-donald-trump-mocks-joe-biden-gaffes-in-middle-of-nato-press-meet-6087136" target="_blank">"Great Job Joe": Donald Trump Mocks Joe Biden Gaffes</a></strong></p>

<p>"Look, I wouldn't have picked Vice President Trump to be vice president if she was not qualified to be president. So start there," he said as he responded to a question from a journalist about his confidence in Indian-origin leader Kamala Harris.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Oh MY GOD.<br />
<br />
Now Biden has just referred to Vice president Kamala Harris as VICE PRESIDENT TRUMP.<br />
<br />
What the fuck is going on?!<br />
<br />
This is actually painful to watch.<a href="https://t.co/fHYKtk95BF">pic.twitter.com/fHYKtk95BF</a></p>
— Supertanskiii (@supertanskiii) <a href="https://twitter.com/supertanskiii/status/1811547581660688722?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The latest gaffes come amid growing calls for Biden, who is already the oldest person to ever serve as the US president, to step aside.</p>

<p>The calls have grown louder ever since his poor performance against Donald Trump, 78, in a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apart-from-biden-and-trump-these-are-5-other-key-candidates-in-us-elections-6087973" target="_blank">US presidential</a> debate two weeks ago.</p>

<p>Even members of his <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-joe-biden-is-ignoring-fellow-democrats-calls-to-leave-race-6087324">Democratic Party</a> are concerned about his ability to win the November 5 election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pjqn6kqg_joe-biden-zelensky_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's blunder came while he was speaking on the sidelines of the NATO Summit in Washington]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woolly-mammoth-dna-frozen-52-000-years-ago-may-be-used-to-revive-species-6089043]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woolly Mammoth DNA, Frozen 52,000 Years, Ago May Be Used To Revive Species]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woolly-mammoth-dna-frozen-52-000-years-ago-may-be-used-to-revive-species-6089043]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 12:54:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[About 52,000 years ago, the skinned hide of a Siberian woolly mammoth was exposed to conditions so frigid that it spontaneously freeze-dried, locking its DNA fragments into place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About 52,000 years ago, the skinned hide of a Siberian woolly mammoth was exposed to conditions so frigid that it spontaneously freeze-dried, locking its DNA fragments into place.</p>

<p>In a study published Thursday in the journal Cell, scientists reported using this remarkable sample to reconstruct the animal's genome in three dimensions -- a breakthrough that could yield important new insights about extinct species and even boost efforts to bring them back to life.</p>

<p>Until now, ancient DNA specimens have only been found in short, scrambled fragments, severely limiting the amount of information researchers could extract.</p>

<p>"Now we show that, at least under some circumstances, it's not just those snippets of that DNA that survive, but they survive in such a way that preserves the original arrangement," co-author Olga Dudchenko, a geneticist at Baylor College of Medicine, told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Understanding the 3D architecture of an organism's genome -- the complete set of its DNA -- is crucial for identifying which genes are active in specific tissues, revealing why brain cells think, heart cells beat, and immune cells fight disease.</p>

<p>It was long assumed that due to the rapid degradation of very small particles, such information would inevitably be lost to history.</p>

<p>But around a decade ago, an international team of scientists set out to find an ancient sample where the 3D organization of the DNA remained intact such that it could be fully reconstructed with a new analytical technique.</p>

<p>Their quest led them to an exceptionally well-preserved woolly mammoth sample, excavated in northeastern Siberia in 2018.</p>

<p>Whether the hirsute pachyderm -- a female with a distinctive mullet-style hairdo -- died naturally or was killed by humans is unknown. However, it does appear that early humans skinned her, leaving tissue around the head, neck, and left ear intact, according to Dudchenko.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Woolly mammoth jerky&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The team hypothesizes that the skin cooled and dehydrated, transitioning into a glasslike state that trapped its molecules in place and preserved the shape of its chromosomes, or the threadlike structures that hold DNA strands.</p>

<p>Essentially, they had discovered a piece of freeze-dried woolly mammoth jerky.</p>

<p>To test the resilience of jerky, they subjected lab-made and store-bought beef jerky pieces to a series of tests simulating the kind of damage ancient samples might encounter over millennia.</p>

<p>"We fired a shotgun at it. We ran over it with a car. We had a former starting pitcher for the Houston Astros throw a fastball at it," said Cynthia Perez Estrada, co-author of the study and a researcher at Baylor College of Medicine and Rice University.</p>

<p>The jerky would break into tiny bits, shattering as dramatically as window glass at times. "But at the nano-scale, the chromosomes were intact, unchanged," said Perez Estrada in a statement.</p>

<p>One significant discovery from their research established that mammoths had 28 pairs of chromosomes. The finding aligns with the 28 chromosomal pairs found in elephants, the closest living relatives of mammoths, "but before this study, it was anybody's guess," said Dudchenko.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Fossil chromosomes'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The team's analysis also identified several "candidate" genes which might be responsible for what made woolly mammoths woolly -- including a gene responsible for long, thick eyelashes, and another associated with sparse sweat glands.</p>

<p>Erez Lieberman Aiden of Baylor College of Medicine, who co-led the team, told AFP that while the researchers' goal was not to bring mammoths back, the information they gleaned could be used for such efforts.</p>

<p>A Japanese team is looking at cloning woolly mammoths, while a group in the United States is aiming to create genetically "mammothized" elephants.</p>

<p>Within the skin, "96 per cent of genes are basically in the same activity state as an elephant," said Aiden, meaning that scientists working on de-extinction could now focus on the remaining four per cent.</p>

<p>The team now hopes that the benefit of their study will extend far beyond their special sample and open a new chapter in paleogenetics if other such "fossil chromosomes" can be found.</p>

<p>The Arctic permafrost remains a promising place to look, and it is also possible that mummification from ancient civilizations in warmer climates could preserve genomic structures too, according to Dudchenko.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3uvglml8_woolly-mammoth-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The international team of scientists had discovered a piece of freeze-dried woolly mammoth sample.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/billionaire-income-tax-would-be-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-ex-pms-tell-g20-to-tax-super-rich-6088945]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Would Be A Shot In The Arm For...": Ex PMs Tell G20 To Tax Super-Rich]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/billionaire-income-tax-would-be-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-ex-pms-tell-g20-to-tax-super-rich-6088945]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 12:38:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former presidents and prime ministers have sent an open letter to current leaders of the world's 20 largest economies urging support for a global tax on billionaires, which they called a rare political opportunity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former presidents and prime ministers have sent an open letter to current leaders of the world's 20 largest economies urging support for a global tax on billionaires, which they called a rare political opportunity.</p>

<p>The move comes as Brazil's G20 presidency, which put the proposal on the table in February, seeks to build support for a declaration at the group's finance ministers and central bank governors meeting later this month in Rio de Janeiro.</p>

<p>Signed by 19 Club de Madrid members, a forum of former leaders with over 100 participants, the letter praised U.S. President Joe Biden's billionaire income tax proposal but called for joint cooperation to combat tax evasion by the wealthiest.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-super-rich-club-has-15-members-with-fortunes-over-100-billion-5682347">Global Super-Rich Club Has 15 Members With Fortunes Over $100 Billion</a></strong></p>

<p>"A global deal to tax the ultra-rich would be a shot in the arm for multilateralism: proving that governments can come together for the common good," said the letter.</p>

<p>Among signatories from across the political spectrum were Chile's Michelle Bachelet, Sweden's Stefan Lofven, Spain's Felipe Gonzalez and Jose Luis Rodriguez Zapatero, France's Dominique de Villepin, Canada's Kim Campbell, Australia's Julia Gillard and South Korea's Han Seung-soo.</p>

<p>Brazil's proposal, crafted by French economist Gabriel Zucman from the independent EU Tax Observatory, calls for an annual 2% levy on fortunes exceeding $1 billion, which could raise up to $250 billion annually from about 3,000 individuals.</p>

<p>While the communique from the latest G7 meeting in June said the group would continue collaborating with the Brazilian G20 presidency to enhance international cooperation and bolster efforts toward progressive and equitable taxation of individuals, some nations have already raised objections.</p>

<p>In May, German Finance Minister Christian Lindner said his country sees new components of a global tax agenda with great skepticism, while U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said the United States could not support negotiations involving redistributing proceeds among countries.</p>

<p>France, Spain, Colombia, Belgium, the African Union and South Africa, which will assume the G20 presidency next year, have already supported the initiative.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e1r5tv8_elon-musk-and-jeff-bezos_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-denies-reports-of-8-pm-bedtime-but-says-he-needs-to-pace-himself-6088864]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Denies Reports Of 8 pm Bedtime, But Says He Needs To Pace Himself]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-denies-reports-of-8-pm-bedtime-but-says-he-needs-to-pace-himself-6088864]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 12:21:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Thursday denied needing to be in bed by 8:00 pm as he faced a barrage of questions from reporters about a disastrous debate performance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Thursday denied needing to be in bed by 8:00 pm as he faced a barrage of questions from reporters about a disastrous debate performance that sparked calls for him to end his reelection bid.</p>

<p>Reports of his early bedtime were "not true," although he added: "Instead of my every day starting at 7:00 am and going to bed at midnight, it would be smarter for me to pace myself a little more."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jdufu96_biden3_625x300_06_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["It would be smarter for me to pace myself a little more," said US President Joe Biden.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-says-neurological-exams-find-him-in-good-shape-6088759]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden Says Neurological Exams Find Him In "Good Shape"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-says-neurological-exams-find-him-in-good-shape-6088759]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 12:04:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden, seeking to allay concerns about his mental fitness as he seeks reelection, said Thursday that neurological exams found he is in "good shape."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden, seeking to allay concerns about his mental fitness as he seeks reelection, said Thursday that neurological exams found he is in "good shape."</p>

<p>"I've taken three significant and intense neurological exams by a neurologist," Biden said, the most recent in February.</p>

<p>"And they say I'm in good shape."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c68fmg1o_joe-biden_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said he has been examined by neurologists and they say he is in "good shape."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-kamala-harris-is-qualified-to-be-president-6087491]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Says Kamala Harris Is "Qualified To Be President"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-kamala-harris-is-qualified-to-be-president-6087491]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 11:47:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Thursday said his deputy, Vice President Kamala Harris, is "qualified" to lead the county.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Thursday said his deputy, Vice President Kamala Harris, is "qualified" to lead the county.</p>

<p>At a press conference in Washington, Joe Biden said, "From the very beginning, I made no bones about that. She is qualified to be the president. That's why I picked her."</p>

<p>When asked about the reasons for this, he said "Firstly because of the way she's handled the issue of freedom of women's bodies, to have control of their bodies and secondly, her ability to handle almost any issue on the board."</p>

<p>"This was a hell of a prosecutor. She was a first rate person and in the Senate, she was really good. I wouldn't have picked her unless I thought she was qualified to be the president," Joe Biden said.</p>

<p>The president mistakenly referred to Kamala Harris as Donald Trump during the press conference. He said, "I wouldn't have picked Trump to be the vice president, did I think she was not qualified to be president."</p>

<p>"The fact is that the consideration is that I think I'm the most qualified person to run for president. I beat him once and I will beat him again," Joe Biden said.</p>

<p>"The idea that senators and congressmen are running for office worrying about the ticket is not unusual. And I might add, there were at least five presidents running or incumbent presidents who had lower numbers than I have now later in a campaign," he said.</p>

<p>So, there's a long way to go in this campaign and so I'm just going to keep moving, he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/plp3h208_biden-kamala-harris_625x300_17_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden said today that Kamala Harris is qualified to be the President of The United States.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-giorgia-meloni-rolls-eyes-as-biden-is-late-for-nato-summit-6088629]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Giorgia Meloni Rolls Eyes As Biden Is Late For NATO Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-giorgia-meloni-rolls-eyes-as-biden-is-late-for-nato-summit-6088629]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 11:43:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Another person standing with Ms Meloni and Finnish President Alexander Stubb pulled out his phone to check the time, and the Italian PM rolled her eyes again before noticing the cameras.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video showing an annoyed Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni waiting for US President Joe Biden is gaining traction on social media. The video was shot on Thursday morning when Ms Meloni and other world leaders were waiting for President Biden and the alliance's Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg to start the third day of the NATO summit in Washington, according to <em>New York Post</em>. While speaking to Finnish President Alexander Stubb, Ms Meloni rolled her eyes and checked a non-existent watch as the clock ticked past the scheduled time.</p>

<p>As per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/11/us-news/italian-pm-meloni-rolls-eyes-as-biden-is-late-to-nato-summit/"><em>Post</em> report</a>, the summit was scheduled to start at 10am.</p>

<p>Another person standing with Ms Meloni and Mr Stubb pulled out his phone to check the time, and the Italian PM rolled her eyes again before noticing the cameras.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Giorgia <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Meloni?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Meloni</a> in top eye-rolling form as leaders at the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NATO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NATO</a> summit wait for Stoltenberg and Biden to arrive for the first session today. <a href="https://t.co/KVSobO8QNU">pic.twitter.com/KVSobO8QNU</a></p>
— Life On Earth (@e_jagat_) <a href="https://twitter.com/e_jagat_/status/1811576162281218081?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The clip has been posted by several users on X, including a <em>Financial Times</em> reporter.</p>

<p>As per the <em>Post</em> report, Mr Biden and Mr Stoltenberg finally opened the day at 10.40am. His another engagement, a solo press conference, was also pushed back by the White House.</p>

<p>This is not the first time that an encounter between the two world leaders gained traction on social media. Last month, Mr Biden was seen awkwardly saluting Ms Meloni after he arrived in Italy for the G7 summit.</p>

<p>Later, the 81-year-old leader was seen smiling and slowly walking away from a group of world leaders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Italian PM had quickly come to Mr Biden's rescue, diverting his attention to the group of leaders as they posed for a photograph. Biden, then, shuffled back to the group.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s2l8178g_giorgia-meloni-with-biden-afp_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Italian PM Giorgia Meloni with US President Joe Biden at the NATO Summit on Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-population-to-peak-in-early-2060s-to-1-7-billion-then-decline-un-6088019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[By 2100, India's Population To Decline, But Still 2.5 Times That Of China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-population-to-peak-in-early-2060s-to-1-7-billion-then-decline-un-6088019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 11:27:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's population is projected to peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion and then decline by 12 per cent, but the country will remain the world's most populous throughout the century, the United Nations has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's population is projected to peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion and then decline by 12 per cent, but the country will remain the world's most populous throughout the century, the United Nations has said.</p>

<p>The World Population Prospects 2024 report, released here on Thursday, said that the world's population is expected to continue growing over the coming 50-60 years, reaching a peak of around 10.3 billion people in the mid-2080s, up from 8.2 billion in 2024. After peaking, the global population is projected to start declining gradually, falling to 10.2 billion people by the end of the century.</p>

<p>India, which surpassed China as the world's most populous nation last year, will continue to hold that position through 2100.</p>

<p>"The population of India, which is expected to remain the world's largest throughout the century, will likely decline by 12 per cent after reaching its peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion," the UN report published by the United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs (DESA), Population Division said.</p>

<p>According to the report, India's population in 2024 is projected at 1.45 billion and this will peak to 1.69 billion in 2054. After this, India's population is projected to decline to 1.5 billion by the end of the century in 2100, but the country will still remain the most populous nation on Earth.</p>

<p>Responding to a question by PTI on population projections for India, Senior Population Affairs Officer, Population Division, UN DESA Clare Menozzi said at a press conference that "India is currently the largest country in the world in terms of population, and it is projected to stay so throughout the century. The population is currently estimated at 1.45 billion, and it's supposed to increase further" to 1.69 billion.</p>

<p>"It's supposed to peak around the 2060s in size and then it starts to slightly decline. So by the end of the century, India is projected to be around 1.5 billion, but still the largest country in the world by a large margin." The report said that China's population, currently 1.41 billion in 2024, will fall to 1.21 billion in 2054 and further decline to 633 million by 2100.</p>

<p>"It is anticipated that China, the country currently with the world's second-largest population, will likely experience the largest absolute population loss between 2024 and 2054 (204 million)," followed by Japan (21 million) and Russia (10 million). "Longer-range population projections are more uncertain" for China, it said.</p>

<p>"However, due to its large size and sustained low level of fertility, China is also likely to record the largest population decline of any country through the end of the century (786 million people). By 2100, China is projected to have lost more than a half of its current population and to have returned to a population size comparable to that recorded in the late 1950s (50 per cent probability)."</p>

<p>Responding to a question on the significantly low population projection for China, Director of the Population Division at UN DESA John Wilmoth said that "it really relates to the level of fertility that's observed currently in China. The current number is right around one birth per woman on average over a lifetime."</p>

<p>"Given that you need 2.1 births to maintain the current population without migration, if fertility levels remain at such a low level, even if they come up slightly, any fertility level if it's below two, or especially below 1.8 or below 1.5, you're really getting into low levels of fertility and it produces a long run decline that's quite significant. And that's true for China. It's true for some other countries in this analysis," Wilmoth said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/jrmv5a_population-generic-india-ians_625x300_09_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India's population is projected to peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion and then decline by 12%]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-seeks-absolute-immunity-wants-hush-money-conviction-tossed-out-6088343]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Seeks "Absolute Immunity", Wants Hush Money Conviction Tossed Out]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-seeks-absolute-immunity-wants-hush-money-conviction-tossed-out-6088343]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 10:50:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lawyers for Donald Trump on Thursday asked the judge who presided over his hush money trial to throw out his conviction, citing the recent Supreme Court ruling that a former US president enjoys broad immunity from prosecution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lawyers for Donald Trump on Thursday asked the judge who presided over his hush money trial to throw out his conviction, citing the recent Supreme Court ruling that a former US president enjoys broad immunity from prosecution.</p>

<p>"The jury's verdicts must be vacated and the indictment dismissed," Trump's attorneys said in a court filing with New York Judge Juan Merchan.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was convicted in New York in May of 34 counts of falsifying business records to cover up hush money payments made to porn star Stormy Daniels, who alleged she had a sexual encounter with the real estate tycoon.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers, in asking Merchan for the conviction to be dismissed, cited the landmark Supreme Court ruling from earlier this month that a president enjoys "absolute immunity" for official acts.</p>

<p>Some of the evidence introduced by prosecutors during the hush money trial involved actions taken while Trump was in the White House and testimony from White House aides, they said.</p>

<p>Trump, who is expected to be formally named the Republican Party nominee for president next week, had been scheduled to be sentenced in the case on Thursday, but Merchan postponed sentencing following the Supreme Court ruling.</p>

<p>Merchan said he would rule on the Trump dismissal motion on September 6 and hold sentencing -- if still necessary -- on September 18.</p>

<p>Manhattan prosecutor Alvin Bragg said in an earlier court filing that he was not opposed to the sentencing delay, but that he believed the "defendant's (dismissal) arguments to be without merit."</p>

<p>Trump, the first former US president convicted of a crime, faces four criminal cases and has been doing everything in his power to delay the trials until after the November election.</p>

<p>He faces charges in Washington and Georgia related to efforts to overturn the results of the 2020 election he lost to Democrat Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Trump is also accused in an indictment filed in Florida of endangering national security by holding onto top secret documents after leaving the White House.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/trbnmngo_donald-trump_625x300_02_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump, the first former US president convicted of a crime, faces four criminal cases.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/openai-chatgpt-ai-problem-solving-openai-scale-ranks-progress-toward-human-level-problem-solving-6088297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Scale Ranks Progress Toward Human-Level Problem Solving]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/openai-chatgpt-ai-problem-solving-openai-scale-ranks-progress-toward-human-level-problem-solving-6088297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 10:44:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI has said for years that it's working to build what's often referred to as artificial general intelligence, or AGI - essentially, computers that can do a better job on most tasks than people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI has come up with a set of five levels to track its progress toward building artificial intelligence software capable of outperforming humans, the startup's latest effort to help people better understand its thinking about safety and the future of AI.</p>

<p>The ChatGPT maker, seen by many as a leader in the race to build more powerful AI systems, shared the new classification system with employees on Tuesday during an all-hands meeting, an OpenAI spokesperson said. The tiers, which OpenAI plans to share with investors and others outside the company, range from the kind of AI available today that can interact in conversational language with people (Level 1) to AI that can do the work of an organization (Level 5).</p>

<p>OpenAI executives told employees that the company believes it is currently on the first level, according to the spokesperson, but on the cusp of reaching the second, which it calls "Reasoners." This refers to systems that can do basic problem-solving tasks as well as a human with a doctorate-level education who doesn't have access to any tools.</p>

<p>At the same meeting, company leadership gave a demonstration of a research project involving its GPT-4 AI model that OpenAI thinks shows some new skills that rise to human-like reasoning, according to a person familiar with the discussion who asked not to be identified because they were not authorized to speak to press. Reached for comment about the demonstration, the spokesperson said OpenAI is always testing new capabilities internally, a common practice in the industry.</p>

<p>OpenAI has said for years that it's working to build what's often referred to as artificial general intelligence, or AGI - essentially, computers that can do a better job on most tasks than people. Such systems do not currently exist. OpenAI Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman has previously said he expects AGI could be reached this decade.</p>

<p>AI researchers have long debated how to determine the criteria for reaching AGI. In a November 2023 paper, several researchers at Google DeepMind proposed a framework of five ascending levels of AI, including tiers such as "expert" and "superhuman." The rankings resemble a system often referred to in the automotive industry in order to assess the degree of automation for self-driving cars.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eev1j57o_openai-imagines-future_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>According to the levels OpenAI has come up with, the third tier on the way to AGI would be called "Agents," referring to AI systems that can spend several days taking actions on a user's behalf. Level 4 describes AI that can come up with new innovations. And the most advanced level would be called "Organizations."</p>

<p>The levels were put together by executives and other senior leaders at OpenAI, and it is considered a work in progress. The company will gather feedback from people including employees, investors and its board, and may tweak the levels over time.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/hptnt2j_sam-altman_625x300_22_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[CEO Sam Altman previously said he expects artificial general intelligence could be reached this decade]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apart-from-biden-and-trump-these-are-5-other-key-candidates-in-us-elections-6087973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apart From Biden And Trump, These Are 5 Other Key Candidates In US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apart-from-biden-and-trump-these-are-5-other-key-candidates-in-us-elections-6087973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:46:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic President Joe Biden and Republican former President Donald Trump will face each other in the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, after a divisive, closely fought contest. Several third-party hopefuls are also running.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic President Joe Biden and Republican former President Donald Trump will face each other in the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, after a divisive, closely fought contest. Several third-party hopefuls are also running.</p>

<p>Here is a list of the candidates:</p>

<h3><strong>REPUBLICAN PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>DONALD TRUMP</strong></h4>

<p>Trump, 78, became the first former U.S. president to be convicted of a crime when a Manhattan jury in May found him guilty of falsifying documents to cover up a payment to a porn star to silence her ahead of the 2016 election. He says he is innocent and will appeal the conviction.</p>

<p>Trump's July 11 sentencing was postponed until Sept. 18 after he asked for a chance to argue he should have been immune from prosecution following a July Supreme Court ruling that presidents are entitled to immunity from criminal prosecution for official acts.</p>

<p>On Monday, the Republicans National Convention convenes to formally nominate the former president to face Biden in what would be the first presidential rematch in nearly 70 years. The party mirrored Trump's views in its new policy platform.</p>

<p>Trump, in office from 2017-2021, has leveraged his unprecedented legal challenges to solidify support among his base and has cast his third bid for the White House in part as "retribution" against perceived political enemies.</p>

<p>But after his felony conviction, 10% of Republican and 25% of independent registered voters said they were less likely to vote for him, Reuters/Ipsos polling found.</p>

<p>Trump faces 54 charges in three other criminal cases: a federal case involving efforts to subvert the 2020 election, a Georgia election interference case and a federal case in Florida over his handling of classified documents after leaving office. He denies any wrongdoing.</p>

<p>However, he is unlikely to face any other trials before the Nov. 5 election. July's Supreme Court ruling on presidential immunity makes it improbable that Trump will be tried on federal criminal charges regarding efforts to undo the 2020 election loss to Biden before voters cast their ballots.</p>

<p>Trump has refused to commit to accepting the 2024 election results or to rule out possible violence around the Nov. 5 contest or his sentencing and is already laying the groundwork to contest a potential election loss.</p>

<p>He calls his supporters jailed for the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the U.S. Capitol "hostages" and "warriors," and uses increasingly dystopian rhetoric, including calling his enemies "vermin."</p>

<p>If elected, Trump has vowed "revenge" on his political enemies and said he would not be a dictator except "on day one," later calling that "a joke."</p>

<p>He also wants the power to replace federal civil service workers with loyalists, while a consortium of Trump-friendly think tanks touts a sweeping policy agenda known as "Project 2025" that takes aim at diversity programs and the Justice Department's independence, among other reported plans. Trump has sought to distance himself from the plan.</p>

<p>On foreign policy, Trump sparked criticism from Western leaders for saying the U.S. would not defend NATO members that did not spend enough on defense and that he would encourage Russia to attack them. He has also questioned military aid for Ukraine.</p>

<p>Trump has made immigration a top domestic campaign issue, vowing to carry out mass deportations with the National Guard and possibly federal troops, end birthright citizenship, and expand a travel ban on people from certain countries.</p>

<p>He has referred to some migrants as "animals" who are "poisoning the blood of our country," among other inflammatory remarks, and has not ruled out building detention camps on U.S. soil. But foreigners who graduate from a U.S. college would get a green card allowing them to stay, he said, which his campaign later said would only apply to the "most skilled" graduates who had been vetted.</p>

<p>On abortion, Trump takes credit for the U.S. Supreme Court ruling overturning Roe v. Wade and has said abortion should remain a state issue.</p>

<p>While he has criticized some Republican-led state actions such as those in Florida and Arizona, he said he would allow Republican-led states to track women's pregnancies and prosecute those who violate their state bans. Trump has said he does not support a ban on access to birth control.</p>

<p>He promised to eliminate Obamacare health insurance before saying on April 11 that he would not "terminate" it. On education, he has pledged to halt federal funding to schools with vaccine mandates and to eliminate the U.S. Department of Education. He has also vowed to undo much of the Biden administration's work to fight climate change.</p>

<h3><strong>DEMOCRATIC PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>JOE BIDEN</strong></h4>

<p>Biden has cast himself as the country's best hope to defend American liberties and protect democracy, saying Trump is unhinged and threatens the future of the country.</p>

<p>While he faced no serious challenger in the Democratic primaries, his weak performance at the first presidential debate against Trump has prompted some Democrats to call for him to step aside as the party prepares to formally nominate him.</p>

<p>Already the oldest U.S. president ever at 81, Biden must now convince his own party as well as voters that he is more fit for office than Trump, who is just three years his junior.</p>

<p>One in three Democrats think Biden should end his reelection bid following the debate, but no prominent elected Democrat does any better than Biden in a hypothetical match-up against Trump, according to a Reuters/Ipsos poll released in July.</p>

<p>The July Reuters/Ipsos poll puts both Biden and Trump on 40% among registered voters, suggesting that Biden had not lost ground since the debate. Trump leads Biden in many battleground states, several other polls have shown.</p>

<p>The economy will also likely be a major factor in determining whether Biden returns to the White House amid low approval ratings.</p>

<p>While the U.S. escaped an anticipated recession and is growing faster than economists expected, voters have been disenchanted with rising food costs, higher fuel prices and elevated interest rates, even as more recent data shows consumer prices moderating and inflation cooling.</p>

<p>Biden pushed through massive economic stimulus and infrastructure spending packages to boost U.S. industrial output but has received next to no credit from voters so far.</p>

<p>His campaign has highlighted new semiconductor manufacturing plants, housing plans and other economic efforts. Two labor groups, the United Auto Workers Union and the North America's Building Trade Union, have endorsed him while the Teamsters have yet to announce which candidate they are backing. Three groups representing older Americans have also endorsed Biden.</p>

<p>Along with Vice President Kamala Harris, Biden has zeroed in on abortion as a top issue. They also created a new coalition to court Black voters, a critical voting bloc.</p>

<p>Biden's handling of immigration policy has been criticized by Republicans and some Democrats as he has struggled with millions of migrants crossing the U.S.-Mexico border.</p>

<p>In June, he signed an executive order to curb migration along the southern border. He also announced a new path for citizenship for certain immigrants in the country illegally who are married to U.S. citizens.</p>

<p>The president has led the response of Western governments to Russia's invasion of Ukraine, persuading allies to punish Russia and support Kyiv, including at NATO's summit in Washington. He also secured additional funding from Congress.</p>

<p>Biden has provided military aid to Israel after Hamas' Oct. 7 attack while urging more humanitarian assistance for Palestinians as a May Reuters/Ipsos poll found Democrats remain divided over the issue.</p>

<p>He has faced criticism from many Democrats and younger voters for continuing to give weapons to Israel while largely failing to curb Israel's deadly military offensive in Gaza. Biden has presented a new Israeli proposal for a fresh Gaza ceasefire in exchange for the release of hostages while talks to end the conflict continue.</p>

<h4><strong>MARIANNE WILLIAMSON</strong></h4>

<p>Best-selling author and self-help guru Marianne Williamson, 72, relaunched her long-shot 2024 presidential bid earlier this year focusing on "justice and love" less than one month after dropping out.</p>

<p>In a February statement, she said she was getting back in to fight Trump's "dark and authoritarian vision" after earlier suspending it because she was losing "the horse race."</p>

<p>Williamson previously ran as a Democrat in the 2020 presidential primary but dropped out before voting began.</p>

<h3><strong>INDEPENDENTS</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>ROBERT F. KENNEDY JR.</strong></h4>

<p>An anti-vaccine activist and environmental advocate, Kennedy, 70, is running as an independent after initially challenging Biden for the Democratic nomination but missed the deadline to qualify for the first presidential debate.</p>

<p>While he lags in overall polling, Kennedy could siphon votes from Trump and Biden, with a June Reuters/Ipsos poll showing he was backed by 10% of respondents.</p>

<p>The son of Democratic U.S. Senator Robert F. Kennedy, who was assassinated in 1968 during his own presidential bid, Kennedy has drawn rebukes from his famous family, which endorsed Biden.</p>

<p>Kennedy, who chose wealthy lawyer Nicole Shanahan as his running mate, supports Israel and questioned a six-week ceasefire backed by Biden.</p>

<p>He said he views the U.S. southern border situation as a humanitarian crisis and opposes Trump's border wall. He has also vowed to repeal parts of Biden's climate bill over tax breaks he says help the oil industry.</p>

<p>Kennedy has taken different positions on abortion rights, including restrictions on when a woman can access an abortion. He told Reuters he thought every abortion was a "tragedy" but that it should be a woman's right "throughout the pregnancy."</p>

<p>He has been criticized for making false medical claims over the years on vaccines but says he would still allow Americans to access them.</p>

<p>Asked about an alleged sexual assault, he said in July that he has "so many skeletons in my closet." His campaign has also said Kennedy had a brain worm more than a decade ago but he has fully recovered.</p>

<p>Kennedy's campaign has said he is officially on the ballot in a handful of states so far, including California, Michigan and Utah, although he faces a challenging, costly battle to be listed in all 50.</p>

<h4><strong>CORNEL WEST</strong></h4>

<p>The political activist, philosopher and academic is making a third-party bid for president that is most likely to appeal to progressive, Democratic-leaning voters.</p>

<p>West, 71, initially ran as a Green Party candidate but said in October that people "want good policies over partisan politics" and declared himself an independent. He has promised to end poverty and guarantee housing.</p>

<h3><strong>GREEN PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>JILL STEIN</strong></h4>

<p>Jill Stein, a physician who ran under the Green Party in 2016, is trying once again in 2024.</p>

<p>She launched her current campaign accusing Democrats of betraying their promises "for working people, youth and the climate again and again - while Republicans don't even make such promises in the first place."</p>

<p>Stein, 74, raised millions of dollars for recounts after Trump's surprise 2016 victory. Her allegations yielded only one electoral review in Wisconsin that showed Trump had won.</p>

<h3><strong>LIBERTARIAN PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>CHASE OLIVER</strong></h4>

<p>While the Libertarian Party invited both Trump and Kennedy to speak at their convention in late May, it ultimately selected Chase Oliver, 38. Oliver ran for a Georgia state Senate seat in 2022 and garnered 2% of the vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/svuvbrhc_trump-biden-split-reuters_625x300_06_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden is being called to step aside after his weak performance in the debate against Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/air-vistara-an-aviation-icon-fades-away-6086551]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Air Vistara: An Aviation Icon Fades Away, And The Chaos It Leaves Behind]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/air-vistara-an-aviation-icon-fades-away-6086551]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:30:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vistara, with its reputation for service excellence and 70 new planes, contrasts sharply with Air India's outdated fleet. It is baffling that the Civil Aviation Ministry allowed the merger of a modern, well-functioning airline like Vistara with an ou]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j7auhnbg_vistara_625x300_12_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On December 10, 2022, we were booked in Business Class to Dubai on Air India. Upon reaching the check-in counter, we were informed that five seats in business class were broken. Consequently, we were offered extra legroom seats in economy class while retaining our business class seats for the next flight.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The staff tried to reassure us that it would be fine for a short flight, but we had important meetings scheduled in Dubai the following morning, so we declined. After learning that the issue was with the TVs, we expressed that we didn't mind as we just wanted to sleep. Despite this, we were forced to write a letter stating we had no objection to flying with broken seats in business class to avoid future claims for compensation.</p>

<p>This was my first experience with Air India post the Tata takeover. As we boarded the flight, we saw empty business-class seats. Interestingly, just before take-off, five people in pilots' uniforms occupied the supposedly broken seats, leaving business class fully occupied. The TV in my seat, which was claimed to be non-functional, worked perfectly fine. It was clear this was done to accommodate their own team.</p>

<p>While it's easy to dwell on negative experiences, there was a positive aspect to this journey. On our return flight on December 13, which was a midnight flight, it was my daughter's birthday. The Air India crew overheard this and, instead of the usual welcome drink, they brought champagne for all of us to celebrate even before we took off. This thoughtful gesture was indeed touching. When I inquired whether this change was due to the Tata takeover, the crew responded that this was always how Air India operated, which was intriguing.</p>

<h2><strong>What Does Air India Stand For?</strong></h2>

<p>Although I am not an aviation expert, my background in hospitality and customer service makes me appreciate organisations focused on service excellence. Transforming Air India is indeed an uphill task, but with dedicated efforts, it holds the potential for significant improvement and success. My friends working in the transformation team are committed to changing the airline, but culture is not built in a day. It takes years and positive reinforcement of company values. What does Air India stand for? Even they are struggling with that.</p>

<p>It's important to understand where Air India was before the Tata Group buyout. Air India operates over 140 aircraft, most of which are over a decade old and have never been refurbished. Airline veterans say that every seven to eight years, there should be a full refurbishment to keep the cabin fresh and functional. With broken seats and worn-out interiors, there is a significant problem, as there are no spare parts available, taking up to 18 months to get replacements. For example, even when the new flight on the Zurich to Delhi sector launched on June 16, my daughter was informed that 12 seats in business class were broken. Competing with Swiss Air from Zurich, which has great aircraft and service, Air India's branding suffers as people are unlikely to return after a poor first experience.</p>

<h2><strong>The Vistara Shutdown</strong></h2>

<p>One of the biggest blunders by the Tata Group is shutting down Vistara. The merger with Air India is poorly executed and ill-timed. The government and the Tata Group were aware that Air India was a defunct asset with old, tired planes, yet they approved the merger plan for short-term financial gain. Why couldn't the merger have been postponed for two years? The financial burden of maintaining Vistara could have been justified by its operational excellence and newer planes.</p>

<p>Vistara, with its reputation for service excellence and 70 new planes, contrasts sharply with Air India's outdated fleet. It is baffling that the Civil Aviation Ministry allowed the merger of a modern, well-functioning airline like Vistara with an outdated one and has approved Tata's decision to rebrand it as Air India.</p>

<p>Poor product and poor communication are two significant issues. Air India should conduct a masterclass on how not to communicate while running a consumer company. I recently travelled from Delhi to Hyderabad on Air India. The aircraft was fine and the service was great. But there was a communication problem. The flight was supposed to take off at 9:40 am, but it took off 40 minutes later without any announcement. The crew later informed us that a connecting flight from Amsterdam had passengers boarding this flight. This could have been communicated to all passengers so everyone knows the reason for the delay.</p>

<h2><strong>Respecting Public Opinion</strong></h2>

<p>Air India needs a communication protocol. Weekly updates on the fleet, on-time performance, and consistency on social media channels can help shift consumer opinion. Public opinion overwhelmingly suggests that the merger was a mistake. The Tata Group, the Competition Commission of India, and the Civil Aviation Ministry could have conducted a small consumer survey. My tweet on this received overwhelming responses - over 95% felt that Vistara and Air India should not have merged. Recent mishandling cases in Air India, whether it is long waits or lack of communication, highlight this.</p>

<p>The transformation team at Air India is under immense pressure, trying their best. Building a culture of service excellence takes time. With the sudden merger of a well-functioning airline with an old one, the hope is that the amalgamation will create a better airline. However, why couldn't this merger wait for 24 months? In a resurgent India, this is a classic case of ignoring public opinion. Flying in India is becoming restricted to a duopoly, so the consumer's choice is limited.</p>

<p>In conclusion, India faces challenging times in aviation. As a consumer, you have everything to lose post-September, when Vistara fades away. All you can do is pray that your Air India flight takes off on time and that you have a new plane. And do remember, good times don't last forever, the new feeling of flying Vistara is gone and dead too soon. The only silver lining is that even bad times don't last forever, and maybe Indigo and Akasa will take service excellence to new heights, till a resurgent Air India becomes the airline that you really want to be proud of.</p>

<p><em>(Kapil Chopra is the Founder of EazyDiner, India's most loved restaurant reservation app and The Postcard Hotel.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/57vgdbuo_vistara_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-good-reason-to-talk-to-putin-says-us-president-biden-6087873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Good Reason" To Talk To Putin, Says US President Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-good-reason-to-talk-to-putin-says-us-president-biden-6087873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:26:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has said that he has "no good reason" to talk to Vladimir Putin at the moment unless the Russian leader changes his behaviour.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden has said that he has "no good reason" to talk to Vladimir Putin at the moment unless the Russian leader changes his behaviour.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old president made these remarks on Thursday at a highly-anticipated solo press conference at the end of the NATO Summit in Washington.</p>

<p>“I have no good reason to talk to Putin right now. There's not much that he is prepared to do in terms of accommodating any change in his behaviour, but there isn't any world leader I'm not prepared to deal with,” Biden told reporters when asked if he is ready to talk to Putin.</p>

<p>“But I understand your generic point is, is Putin ready to talk? I'm not ready to talk to Putin unless Putin's ready to change his behaviour and the idea -- look, Putin's got a problem," Biden said, dismissing concerns about his health despite a growing list of Democratic leaders urging him to step aside from the 2024 presidential election following last month's disastrous debate with his Republican rival, Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"First of all, in this war that he supposedly has won, and by the way, I think, don't hold me to the exact number, but I think that Russia had 17.3 per cent of Ukraine that they've conquered, now it's 17.4. I mean, in terms of percentage of territory,” he said.</p>

<p>“They've not been very successful. They've caused horrible damage, and loss of life, but they've also lost over 350,000 troops, military, killed or wounded. They have over a million people, particularly young people with technical capability leaving Russia because they see no future there. They've got a problem,” said the president.</p>

<p>“But what they do have control of is they are very good at controlling and running the public outcry that relates to how they use mechanisms to communicate with people. They lie like hell to the constituencies. They lie like hell about what's going on. So the idea that we're going to be able to fundamentally Change Russia in the near term is not likely,” he told reporters.</p>

<p>“But one thing for certain. If we allow Russia to succeed in Ukraine, they're not stopping in Ukraine...I'm prepared to talk to any leader who wants to talk, including if Putin calls me and wants to talk. The last time, I talked to Putin was trying to get him to work on an arms control agreement related to nuclear weapons and space. That didn't go very far,” he said.</p>

<p>“So, my point is I'm prepared to talk to anybody, but I don't see any inclination. There is an inclination on the part of the Chinese to keep in contact with me because they're not sure where this all goes. Look what's happened in Asia. We have strengthened the Asian-Pacific area more than anyone else has,” he said.</p>

<p>“I asked our NATO allies that we bring on the group from the South Pacific, Australia, New Zealand, Japan, Australia. I've met twice now, with the 14 leaders of the Pacific island nations, and we've slowed down what's going on there. We've slowed down China's reach. But there's a lot of work to do. This is a moving target, and I don't take it lightly,” Biden said.</p>

<p>He used the press conference to deliver a forceful defence of his foreign and domestic policies and batted away questions about his ability to serve another four years, declaring, "I'm not in this for my legacy. I'm in this to complete the job." There have been concerns about Biden's ability to serve another four-year term as president since his stumbling performance in a presidential debate opposite Donald Trump last month.</p>

<p>Age and mental fitness have recently become a major issue in the US presidential race.</p>

<p>While the issue has troubled President Biden, and his Republican rival Trump, 78, in the past, things reached a tipping point after Biden's disastrous debate performance last month.</p>

<p>While Biden is the oldest president in US history, Trump, if elected in November, would be the second oldest.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opt29ctk_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-set-to-deploy-starwars-laser-weapons-to-take-down-n-korean-drones-6087822]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Set To Deploy 'StarWars' Laser Weapons For Drone Defence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-set-to-deploy-starwars-laser-weapons-to-take-down-n-korean-drones-6087822]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:11:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea on Thursday announced that it is ready to start mass-producing laser weapons like those in the 'Star Wars' franchise to shoot down North Korean drones.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea on Thursday announced that it is ready to start mass-producing laser weapons like those in the<em> 'Star Wars' </em>franchise to shoot down North Korean drones. According to <em>Newsweek</em>, the drone-killing system, called the Block-I, will be deployed later this year. With this, South Korea will become the world's first country to deploy a technology that is being developed by several armed forces. Moreover, the country's Defense Acquisition Program Administration (DAPA) announced that an even more powerful version is also being planned, which could be a "game changer" in the future.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/south-korea-develops-laser-drone-defense-1923766"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, South Korea has named its laser program the "StarWars Project". The country's DAPA, which handles defence procurement, development and production, announced a 100 billion won contract to build the drone-killing weapon. It touted the weapon as effective and cheap and revealed that the laser is quiet and invisible, and one shot costs only 2,000 won.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our country is becoming the first country in the world to deploy and operate laser weapons, and our military's response capabilities on North Korea's drone provocation will be further strengthened," the agency said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thetimes.com/world/asia/article/south-koreas-star-wars-laser-to-bring-down-drones-at-110-a-shot-fscqswpks"><em>Times </em></a>reported that Block-I uses fibre optic cables to generate a laser beam intended to be fired at relatively close range against small drones. Each shot is silent and invisible to the naked eye. It lasts 10 to 20 seconds and creates a temperature of more than 700 Celsius, which is enough to damage and disable a drone's engine or battery. It can be fired wherever there is a sufficient supply of electricity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Cost per fire is extremely cheap compared with other guided weapons," Jo Yong-jin, a spokesman for the DAPA, told reporters in Seoul. "Responses to low-cost strike assets and weapons, such as small drones, will be able to take place very effectively and efficiently," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>South Korean aerospace company Hanwha Aerospace Co. is contracted to manufacture the weapons. <em>Newsweek </em>reported that DAPA is already planning to develop a more powerful, longer-ranged anti-aircraft laser weapon: the Block-II. This weapon will involve boosting the power of the laser beam to hundreds of kilowatts, with the aim of taking down larger targets like ballistic missiles and planes.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/switzerland-halts-rollout-of-sarco-suicide-pods-dubbed-tesla-of-euthanasia-6085239">Switzerland Halts Rollout Of 'Sarco' Suicide Pods, Dubbed "Tesla Of Euthanasia"</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, several countries, including the US, UK, Israel, Turkey, Germany and Japan have also developed laser weapons. Earlier this year, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-shows-uks-first-laser-weapon-that-can-hit-a-coin-from-a-kilometre-away-5223169">UK's Ministry of Defence</a> tested a laser weapon, DragonFire, which reportedly destroyed incoming drones from several miles away during a trial. With this, the ministry hopes that it will pave the way for a low-cost alternative to missiles to shoot down targets like drones. It further said that the weapon is precise enough to hit a coin from a kilometre away.&nbsp;</p>

<p>DragonFire will be used both by the Army and the Royal Navy as part of their future air defence capabilities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8s9gfsv_laser-_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[South Korea has named its laser program the "StarWars Project". (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-man-25-arrested-for-groping-at-canada-water-park-6087794]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Man, 25, Arrested For Groping At Canada Water Park]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-man-25-arrested-for-groping-at-canada-water-park-6087794]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:10:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian origin man was arrested for groping women at a public water park in Canada on July 7, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian origin man was arrested for groping women at a public water park in Canada on July 7, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 25-year-old walking at a public water park on Mountain Road in Moncton, and groping people. According to the police, there were at least twelve victims, some of whom were under the age of 16.</p>

<p>Police located the man who was still on the premises, and arrested him. He was later released from custody, and is now scheduled to appear in Moncton Provincial Court on October 24.</p>

<p>"This is still an active investigation, and we are working diligently to understand if there were other victims," police said in an official press release.</p>

<p>Police also asked people to come forward in case they know anything related to the case.</p>

<p>"We are asking parents to speak to their children if they attended this location on July 7. We also want people to know that a sexual assault complaint can be made at any time. If you are a victim of sexual misconduct, please contact us. You will be listened to, and you will be believed", the press release said.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/gg48gv18_canada-police_625x300_09_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police located the man who was still on the premises, and arrested him.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/they-spared-nothing-israel-bombs-gaza-killing-25-in-fiercest-week-of-war-6087783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Spared Nothing": Israel Bombs Gaza Killing 25 In "Fiercest" Week Of War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/they-spared-nothing-israel-bombs-gaza-killing-25-in-fiercest-week-of-war-6087783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:04:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel rained bombs on Gaza City during a week that residents described as comparable to the fiercest battle of the war, while a Palestinian Islamic Jihad official on Thursday said a new round of peace talks ended with no agreements yet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel rained bombs on Gaza City during a week that residents described as comparable to the fiercest battle of the war, while a Palestinian Islamic Jihad official on Thursday said a new round of peace talks ended with no agreements yet.</p>

<p>Israel has been bombarding the Gaza Strip for 10 months in a war that has laid waste to the territory and killed more than 38,000 Palestinians, according to medical authorities in Gaza.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Israeli airstrikes killed at least six people in Gaza City and 19 in the rest of the Gaza Strip, according to Palestinian authorities. The civil emergency service said the bodies of at least 30 Palestinians killed in the previous three days also laid scattered on unreachable roads in Gaza City.</p>

<p>The latest round of peace talks ended with no agreements, while Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accused Palestinian operative group Hamas of making demands that contradicted a framework deal brokered by Washington. Netanyahu did not say what those demands were.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Palestinian Islamist operative&nbsp;group said mediators had yet to provide it with updates on the state of the talks since it made concessions last week in response to a U.S.-backed Israeli peace offer.</p>

<p>Washington is pushing for a peace deal at talks in Egypt and Qatar to end the Gaza war, now in its 10th month. The head of Israel's Shin Bet intelligence agency was headed to Cairo to pursue the negotiations, Netanyahu's office said.</p>

<p>In Washington, White House National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan said many details still need to be hammered out to secure a deal.</p>

<p>In its statement on Thursday, Hamas accused Israel of "stalling to buy time to foil this round of negotiations, as it has done in previous rounds", all of which have ended in failure since a week-long truce in November.</p>

<p>As peace talks dragged on, Gaza City residents endured a fierce night of bombing.</p>

<p>Home to more than a quarter of Gaza's residents before the war, Gaza City was largely razed to the ground in late 2023, but hundreds of thousands of Palestinians have returned to homes in the ruins. Israel has once again ordered them out, though it is unclear where residents can go safely. Israel controls most of Gaza's borders.</p>

<p>Many say they will not leave.</p>

<p>"We will die but not leave to the south. We have tolerated starvation and bombs for nine months and we are ready to die as martyrs here," said Mohammad Ali, 30, reached by text message.</p>

<p>Ali, whose family has relocated several times within the city, said they had been running short of food, water and medicine.</p>

<p>"The occupation (Israel) bombs Gaza City as if the war was restarting. We hope there will be a ceasefire soon, but if not then is God's will."</p>

<p>The Israeli army told Gaza City residents on Wednesday to use two "safe routes" to head south. Some posted a hashtag on social media: "We are not leaving".</p>

<p>Asked by Reuters to comment on its operations in Gaza City, the Israeli military said in a statement its forces were working to dismantle Hamas capabilities, and that it "follows international law and takes feasible precautions to mitigate civilian harm." It said the same was not true of Hamas.</p>

<p>Critics have accused Israel of committing genocide against Palestinians, which Israel denies. It characterizes its actions as self-defense, though the International Court of Justice ordered Israel in January to take action to prevent acts of genocide.</p>

<p>Israel launched its assault on the Gaza Strip last year after Hamas-led&nbsp;operatives&nbsp;entered southern Israel, killing 1,200 people and capturing more than 250 hostages according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>An Israeli military report on Thursday acknowledged that it had failed to protect the citizens of one of the worst-hit communities, Kibbutz Be'eri, where more than 100 people were killed.</p>

<h3><strong>PALESTINIAN CIVILIANS CALL FOR WAR TO END</strong></h3>

<p>The negotiations in Qatar and Egypt follow important concessions last week from Hamas, which accepted that a truce could begin and some hostages be released without Israel first agreeing to end the war.</p>

<p>Just east of Gaza City in the Shejaia suburb, residents were returning on foot to a desolate moonscape of destroyed buildings after Israeli forces withdrew following a two-week offensive.</p>

<p>The territory's main cemetery had been bulldozed by the army. People wheeled supplies on the back of bicycles across rubble-strewn tracks, passing the remains of burnt-out and blasted Israeli armoured vehicles.</p>

<p>"We have returned to Shejaia after 15 days. You can see the destruction. They spared nothing, even trees, there was a lot of greenery in this area. What is the guilt of stones and trees? And what is my guilt as a civilian?" resident Hatem Tayeh told Reuters in the ruins.</p>

<p>"There are bodies of civilian people. What is the guilt of the civilian? Who are you fighting?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ojngdn18_israel-hamas-war-gaza-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As peace talks dragged on, Gaza City residents endured a fierce night of bombing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madan-ashrit-highway-landslide-sweeps-two-passenger-bus-in-central-nepal-highway-five-dozen-people-suspected-missing-6087525]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Landslide Sweeps Two Passenger Bus In Central Nepal Highway, 60 Missing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madan-ashrit-highway-landslide-sweeps-two-passenger-bus-in-central-nepal-highway-five-dozen-people-suspected-missing-6087525]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 08:31:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least five dozen people are suspected to be missing after a landslide along the Madan-Ashrit Highway in Central Nepal swept two passenger buses in early Friday morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least five dozen people are suspected to be missing after a landslide along the Madan-Ashrit Highway in Central Nepal swept two passenger buses in early Friday morning.</p>

<p>As per the officials on the site of the incident, the bus is assumed to have been swept down to the Trishuli River which has swollen hampering the search and rescue operation.</p>

<p>"As per the preliminary information both the buses were carrying a total of 63 people, including the bus drivers. The landslide swept the buses at around 3:30 AM. We are at the incident site and a search operation is underway. Incessant rain is hampering our efforts to search for the missing buses," Indradev Yadav, Chief District Officer, Chitwan confirmed ANI over the phone.</p>

<p>As per the official, the landslide swept the Kathmandu-bound Angel bus and Ganpati Deluxe, which was heading from Kathmandu to Rautahat's Gaur. As per the preliminary reports of the officials, there were 24 people onboard the bus that was heading to Kathmandu and 41 people were travelling in another bus.</p>

<p>Taking to X, Nepal PM Pushpa Kamal Dahal stated, "I am deeply saddened by the reports of about five dozen passengers that are missing when bus was washed away by a landslide on the Narayangadh- Muglin road section and the loss of properties due to floods and landslides in different parts of the country. I direct all agencies of the government, including the home administration, to search and effectively rescue the passengers."</p>

<p>All the flights from Kathmandu to Chitwan's Bharatpur has been cancelled for the day as the weather remains grim.</p>

<p>Three of the passengers on the Ganpati Deluxe managed to escape after jumping out of the vehicle. Nepal Police and Armed Police Force personnel are heading towards the incident sites for rescue operations, Superintendent of Police Bhawesh Rimal informed. Debris from landslides at various places has obstructed traffic on the Narayanghat-Mugling road section.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j8qj6h7_madanashrit-highway-nepal-landslide-ani-twitter_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As per the official, the landslide swept the Kathmandu-bound Angel bus and Ganpati Deluxe.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alec-baldwin-charged-with-involuntary-manslaughter-had-live-rounds-on-set-6087627]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alec Baldwin, Charged With Involuntary Manslaughter, Had Live Rounds On Set]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alec-baldwin-charged-with-involuntary-manslaughter-had-live-rounds-on-set-6087627]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 08:28:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Live rounds were found in the cartridge belts of Alec Baldwin and another actor on the set of a Western movie that was the scene of a fatal shooting, a police technician testified Thursday at the trial of the Hollywood star.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Live rounds were found in the cartridge belts of Alec Baldwin and another actor on the set of a Western movie that was the scene of a fatal shooting, a police technician testified Thursday at the trial of the Hollywood star.</p>

<p>Baldwin, 66, is charged with involuntary manslaughter in connection with the October 2021 death of cinematographer Halyna Hutchins during filming of the movie "Rust."</p>

<p>The actor -- known for the television comedy "30 Rock" -- was holding a prop revolver during a rehearsal in a church when it fired a live round, killing Hutchins and wounding the movie's director.</p>

<p>Marissa Poppell, a crime scene technician, testified that a number of live rounds were mixed in with dummy rounds on the set of the movie being filmed in New Mexico, where the trial is taking place.</p>

<p>Poppell, under questioning from Baldwin's attorney, Alex Spiro, on the second day of the trial said a live round was found in Baldwin's bandolier.</p>

<p>"You had no reason to think that Mr Baldwin had any idea that was there?" Spiro asked.</p>

<p>"Correct," Poppell replied.</p>

<p>She said another actor on the set, Jensen Ackles, also had a live bullet in his bandolier and also had no reason to believe that he knew it was there either.</p>

<p>The jury was also shown photographs of ammunition boxes on a prop cart with live rounds mixed in with dummy bullets. The bullets are largely indistinguishable.</p>

<p>During opening arguments on Wednesday, prosecutor Erlinda Ocampo Johnson accused Baldwin of violating basic gun safety rules and playing "make-believe" with a deadly weapon.</p>

<p>Baldwin had behaved in "a reckless manner" and "without due regard for the safety of others" on set, Johnson said, allegedly failing to take weapons training seriously and regularly pointing firearms at people on set.</p>

<p>Baldwin faces up to 18 months in prison if found guilty.</p>

<p>Spiro, whose other clients include Elon Musk and Jay-Z, said Baldwin had no reason to believe the gun might be loaded and was not responsible as an actor for checking the weapon's contents.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Armorer convicted&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Hutchins, the victim, was originally from Ukraine, and her career as a Hollywood cinematographer was thriving when she was killed at the age of 42.</p>

<p>The tragedy occurred during a rehearsal in a small chapel on the Bonanza Creek Ranch, a historic location for Western movies, midway through the filming of "Rust."</p>

<p>Baldwin was practising a scene in which his outlaw character, trapped by two marshals, brandishes his Colt six-shooter.</p>

<p>In his opening arguments, Spiro focused blame on the movie's safety officials, including armourer Hannah Gutierrez, for allowing live rounds to be brought on set.</p>

<p>Gutierrez was convicted by the same court this year and is serving an 18-month sentence.</p>

<p>It is not known if Baldwin will take the stand in his defense. Legal experts say it would be a risky move, exposing the allegedly temperamental actor to hostile cross-examination.</p>

<p>The trial is scheduled to conclude on Friday of next week, with jury deliberations to follow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/vdq3r1f8_alec-baldwin_625x300_24_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alec Baldwin faces up to 18 months in prison if found guilty.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>