<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 11:24:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-says-share-owners-dont-count-as-working-people-6869339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Share Owners Don't Count As "Working People": UK PM Keir Starmer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-says-share-owners-dont-count-as-working-people-6869339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 11:24:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Keir Starmer says Britons who get additional income from stock holdings don't count as 'working people,' suggesting he's willing to raise taxes on investors.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer says Britons who get additional income from stock holdings don't count as 'working people,' suggesting he's willing to raise taxes on investors.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When asked by Sky News if someone who works but also gets income from shares or property is a working person, Starmer said "they wouldn't come within my definition." His government has repeatedly promised not to raise taxes on who he considers to be working people, including ruling out raising income tax, national insurance on employees and value added tax.</p>

<p>"People will know whether they're in that group or not, those people who work hard and are anxious about whether they can make ends meet and know that should something happen to them and their family, they can't write a cheque to get out of the problem," Starmer said, when asked for his definition.</p>

<p>His spokesman Dave Pares later clarified that a person who holds a small amount of savings in stocks and shares still counts as a working person, despite Starmer's earlier comments. He said that Starmer was referring to someone who primarily gets their income from assets.</p>

<p>Starmer's new government has sought to demonstrate its commitment to wealth creation in the run-up to this budget, including hosting a summit earlier this month for businesses and investors designed to raise billions of private money for the UK. Earlier this week, he said there's "no reason" for entrepreneurs to leave Britain, despite the prospect of tax rises.</p>

<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer Rachel Reeves has conceded that she's looking at other taxes to ensure "the sums add up," leading to widespread expectation that employers will pay more national insurance and that capital gains and inheritance taxes will go up. An increase in capital gains tax is likely to impact people selling property as well as shares.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reeves is under pressure to increase public spending despite the limited fiscal room she inherited from her Conservative predecessors preventing her from offering large giveaways. She confirmed on Thursday that she will change the fiscal rules underpinning the UK's spending plans in order to boost government investment, a move that could allow Britain to borrow as much as &amp;#163;70 billion ($91 billion) more over the next five years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8i2brjgg_keir-starmer-bloomberg_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer suggested he's willing to raise taxes on investors.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-dendy-cinemas-partner-for-australias-1st-national-indian-film-festival-6869315]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NDTV, Dendy Cinemas Partner For Australia's 1st National Indian Film Festival]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-dendy-cinemas-partner-for-australias-1st-national-indian-film-festival-6869315]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 11:20:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The National Indian Film Festival of Australia (NIFFA) will be held across seven cities in Australia from February 13-16 2025.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Centre for Indian Cinema has announced an initiative to create the biggest celebration of Indian cinema in Australasia with Australia's first and only National Indian Film Festival of Australia (NIFFA). The festival will be held across seven cities in Australia from February 13-16 2025, with Australia cinema chain Dendy Cinemas, major Indian news media company NDTV and cinema advertising company Val Morgan, coming on board as stakeholders.</p>

<p>The festival is the brainchild of filmmaker and Australia's leading expert on Indian cinema, Anupam Sharma, who will head the festival with industry veteran Peter Castaldi serving as festival director.</p>

<p>"Australia was craving for a professional national celebration of Indian cinema, and it is an absolute honour to receive the support of mainstream Australia with Dendy as our major partner and NDTV as media partner. This will be one of the rare film festivals which will be produced by filmmakers," Mr Sharma said.</p>

<p>"One of the most important and exciting aspects of the festival will be the programming coverage on NDTV about Australia-India cultural and artistic ties, which will reach a potential audience of over 350 million across NDTV platforms. Money cannot buy such exposure for Australian cultural links with India," he added.</p>

<p>Sanjay Pugalia, NDTV's Director and Editor-in-Chief, said, "As NDTV expands globally and the Indian diaspora flourishes across Australasia, partnering with this premier celebration of Indian cinema felt like a perfect fit. We at NDTV are happy to amplify the festival's spirit worldwide, bringing it to Indian communities across the globe and celebrating the ever-growing impact of Indian filmmaking on the international stage."</p>

<p>Sharon Strickland, the CEO of Dendy Cinema, said, "Dendy Cinema is honoured to partner with the National Indian Film Festival of Australia, bringing the best of Indian cinema to audiences across Australia. With a resurgence of Indian films making a strong impact at the global box office, this collaboration highlights our commitment to showcasing diverse and culturally significant stories. We are excited to support this festival, celebrating the vibrant creativity and growing influence of Indian filmmaking on the world stage."</p>

<p>Festival Director, Peter Castaldi, said, "I am delighted to have been invited to take such an important role in this vital Indo-Australian cultural and business initiative. On the back of the co-production treaty, sparking a resurgence of film links and high box office revenue in Australasia for pan-Indian films, it makes sense to offer a national audience the opportunity to enjoy a professionally curated taster of the vitality of the amazingly rich and diverse Indian production sector. I look forward to working with the NIFFA to deliver exciting, informative and entertaining experiences for all Australians."</p>

<p>The NIFFA will see a weekend of celebrations and screenings around Australia in Sydney, Melbourne, Perth, Adelaide, the Gold Coast, Darwin and Hobart.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/eiomppgg_sydney_625x300_25_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsofts-satya-nadella-received-79-1-million-pay-in-2024-a-63-hike-6869286]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft's Satya Nadella Received $79.1 Million Pay In 2024, A 63% Hike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsofts-satya-nadella-received-79-1-million-pay-in-2024-a-63-hike-6869286]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 11:18:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp. Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella received a pay package worth $79.1 million for fiscal 2024, a 63% increase from the prior year as the software maker worked to extend its strong position in artificial intelligence tools.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Corp. Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella received a pay package worth $79.1 million for fiscal 2024, a 63% increase from the prior year as the software maker worked to extend its strong position in artificial intelligence tools.</p>

<p>About 90% of Nadella's compensation for the year ended in June was in Microsoft shares, the company said in a regulatory filing on Thursday. It's the largest award he has received in any year since he was paid $84 million in 2014, the year he became Microsoft's third chief executive.</p>

<p>Nadella's pay would have been about $5 million higher had he not requested a pay cut "to reflect his personal accountability" for changes the company is making to reflect cybersecurity risks, Microsoft's board compensation committee wrote in the filing on Thursday. The company has faced mounting scrutiny in recent years, including from the US Cyber Safety Review Board, for a series of embarrassing hacks of its software.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The board reviewed the company's performance and strongly believes that Mr. Nadella provided exceptional leadership and was both critical in achieving both the extremely strong performance of the company and personally responsible for the ongoing repositioning of its investments and priorities," Microsoft's board compensation committee wrote.</p>

<p>Chief Financial Officer Amy Hood's pay package for the year rose to $25.8 million, an increase of 30% from a year earlier, according to the filing. President Brad Smith got a 29% bump to $23.4 million.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/41lijjq8_satya-nadella-bloomberg_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Satya Nadella's pay would have been about $5 million higher had he not requested a pay cut]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-fallout-from-kfc-to-burger-king-chains-remove-onions-on-e-coli-risk-6869271]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From KFC To Burger King, Chains Remove Onions On E. Coli Risk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-fallout-from-kfc-to-burger-king-chains-remove-onions-on-e-coli-risk-6869271]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 11:15:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yum! Brands Inc. and Burger King removed onions from some of their locations as the restaurant industry investigates an E. Coli outbreak first traced to McDonald's Corp.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yum! Brands Inc. and Burger King removed onions from some of their locations as the restaurant industry investigates an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/e-coli-outbreak-whats-is-mcdonalds-e-coli-outbreak-causes-and-symptoms-6852562">E. Coli outbreak</a> first traced to McDonald's Corp.</p>

<p>Yum withdrew fresh onions from some Taco Bell, Pizza Hut and KFC locations "out of an abundance of caution," the company said Thursday in a statement to Bloomberg News, without disclosing which stores and regions were affected or naming suppliers.</p>

<p>"We will continue following supplier and regulatory guidance to ensure the ongoing safety and quality of our food," the company said.</p>

<p>Burger King said Thursday that it gets some of its onions from a Colorado facility run by Taylor Farms, which supplied the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/slivered-onions-likely-culprit-says-mcdonalds-as-it-tackles-e-coli-crisis-6861191">McDonald's restaurants</a> that have been impacted by the outbreak.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Taylor Farms issued a recall of some its yellow onion batches despite finding no traces of E. coli as of Wednesday. Restaurant distributors US Foods Holding Corp. and Sysco Corp. have also notified customers of the recall.</p>

<p>"Despite no contact from health authorities and no indications of illness, we proactively asked our 5% of restaurants who received whole onions distributed by this facility to dispose of them immediately two days ago and we are in the process of restocking them from other facilities," Burger King said.</p>

<p>Fat Brands Inc., owner of restaurants including Johnny Rockets, said it pulled all of Taylor Farms' fresh onion products.</p>

<p>"We have identified an extremely limited number of Buffalo's Cafe locations and Ponderosa and Bonanza Steakhouses that are currently utilizing Taylor Farms as a supplier for onions," the company said in a statement Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The restaurant industry is on alert after the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said Tuesday that an E. coli outbreak likely tied to pre-slivered onions served on McDonald's Quarter Pounders sickened dozens of people in the US and killed one. Burger King said it buys whole onions that are cut, peeled and sliced in its restaurants.&nbsp;</p>

<p>McDonald's pulled the popular product from about 20% of its more than 13,000 US restaurants, and it's working with health authorities to confirm the source of the contamination.</p>

<p>Chipotle Mexican Grill Inc. said in a statement Thursday that it doesn't source onions from Taylor Farms or any ingredients from the Colorado facility.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Inspire Brands Inc., which owns Arby's, Buffalo Wild Wings, Sonic, Jimmy John's, Baskin-Robbins and Dunkin', said its onions don't come from the facility. It hadn't pulled onions or any other ingredients from restaurants as of Thursday evening in New York.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0h0asmp_mcdonalds-bloomberg_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[McDonald's pulled the popular product from about 20% of its more than 13,000 US restaurants.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mother-of-delphi-victim-breaks-down-as-final-moments-of-daughters-life-shown-in-court-6869043]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mother Breaks Down As Delphi Murder Victim's Last Moments Shown In Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mother-of-delphi-victim-breaks-down-as-final-moments-of-daughters-life-shown-in-court-6869043]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 11:08:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The mother of Liberty "Libby" German broke down when a video showing the final moments of her daughter's life was played in the courtroom during the Delphi murder trial.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mother of Liberty “Libby” German broke down when a video showing the final moments of her daughter's life was played in the courtroom during the Delphi murder trial. The bodies of Libby, 14, and Abby, 13, were found on February 14, 2017, after they went missing during a hike.</p>

<p>During the <a href="http://https://www.wrtv.com/news/delphi/delphi-murders-trial-examination-of-physical-evidence-recovered-at-crime-scene-a-focus-of-day-4 " rel="nofollow,noindex">court proceedings on Tuesday</a>, the 43-second video was shown to the jury. In the clip, recorded on February 13, 2017, Libby and her friend Abigail “Abby” Williams were seen walking on the Monon High Bridge in Delphi, Indiana, before a man, later identified as the "Bridge Guy," appeared to follow them. This chilling video became one of the key pieces of evidence in the years-long investigation.</p>

<p>This was also the first time the complete footage was displayed publicly outside of law enforcement.</p>

<p>Libby's mother got emotional as the girl in the video said, "There's no path. The trail ends here so we have to go down here?" Moments later, a man's voice chillingly instructed, "Guys, down the hill." These were the final known moments of the girls before their bodies were discovered the next day.</p>

<p>The case went cold for years before a breakthrough came in October 2022 with the arrest of Richard Allen, a 52-year-old local man. Allen was charged with murder and kidnapping. During the trial, prosecutors argued that Allen forced the girls off the trail before slitting their throats. The video of Allen allegedly approaching the girls, recorded by Libby on her phone, was retrieved and has since become a central piece of evidence.</p>

<p>On the day of the murders, several eyewitnesses claimed to have seen a man fitting the description of "Bridge Guy" on the same trail. Railly Voorhies, one of the witnesses who testified in court, recalled passing a man who seemed “unhappy” on the trail. She later identified him as the man shown in the footage.</p>

<p>The trial now focuses on whether Allen was responsible for the killings.</p>

<p>Prosecutors have presented forensic evidence, including a shoe, fibres and a cartridge found near the crime scene. The trial is ongoing, with more witnesses expected to testify. If convicted, Allen could face life in prison.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o5rv7eg8_liberty-german-abigail-williams-facebook_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This was also the first time the complete footage was displayed publicly outside of law enforcement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-plan-to-recreate-extinct-creatures-like-dinosaurs-as-robots-6869113]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Plan To Recreate Extinct Creatures Like Dinosaurs As Robots]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-plan-to-recreate-extinct-creatures-like-dinosaurs-as-robots-6869113]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 10:50:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers hope these robotic recreations will enhance our understanding of the natural world and evolutionary history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists are looking into the idea of utilising robotics to recreate long-extinct animals like dinosaurs and marine reptiles, according to a report in <em>Science Robotics. </em>By imitating the motions and anatomical features of extinct animals like the Tyrannosaurus Rex, these devices may offer important new insights into evolution. The goal of these artificial recreations, according to researchers, is to improve our knowledge of evolution and the natural environment.</p>

<p>"We have these animals that evolution has created over millions and millions of years, but with a couple lines of code or a new 3D-printed leg we can simulate those millions of years of evolution in a single day of engineering effort," Dr Michael Ishida, of the University of Cambridge and a co-author of the review article, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/oct/23/long-extinct-animals-resurrected-robots-evolution"><em>The Guardian.</em></a></p>

<p>"Building a robot [based on these living species of fish] will hopefully give us a little bit of insight into what kind of evolutionary pressures, or what kind of mechanics, started to force fish to develop these different anatomies that would be useful on land," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/oct/23/long-extinct-animals-resurrected-robots-evolution">he said</a>, adding that such learning would help the team develop paleo-inspired robots of extinct fish.</p>

<p>In the review article, scientists propose "paleoinspired robotics," an emerging research paradigm that combines the traditional bioinspired robotics framework with the study of evolutionary trajectories. Paleoinspired robotics markedly expands upon the conventional objectives and methodologies associated with bioinspired robotics.</p>

<p>As per the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scirobotics.adn1125"><em> research article</em></a>, traditionally, bioinspired robotics research focuses on replicating and understanding certain features of a single extant animal. Conversely, paleoinspired robotics seeks to investigate the consequences of anatomical changes on the kinematics, biomechanics, and energetics of multiple species in different time periods, especially as applied to overarching evolutionary trajectories. Augmenting the field of palaeontology with paleoinspired robotics enables the investigation of evolutionary feasibility of features, and the comparison between paleoinspired robotics and bioinspired robotics facilitates the study of artificial evolution.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9l2fo68o_tyrannosaurus-rex_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Scientists are investigating the potential of recreating extinct animals likeTyrannosaurus rex.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-pride-lone-child-brings-hope-to-japans-puppet-village-6869047]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Our Pride": Lone Child Brings Hope To Japan's Puppet Village]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-pride-lone-child-brings-hope-to-japans-puppet-village-6869047]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 10:38:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Riding his tricycle with cheerful abandon, Kuranosuke Kato is the only child in his tiny, depopulated Japanese village overrun by life-sized puppets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Riding his tricycle with cheerful abandon, Kuranosuke Kato is the only child in his tiny, depopulated Japanese village overrun by life-sized puppets.</p>

<p>The two-year-old was the first baby in two decades for Ichinono, one of more than 20,000 communities in Japan where the majority of residents are aged 65 and above, according to the internal affairs ministry data.</p>

<p>Revitalising rural areas is one of Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba's key campaign pledges as he fights to retain a majority in a general election on Sunday.</p>

<p>Ishiba has called Japan's low birth rate a "quiet emergency", one that is starkly evident in places like Ichinono, a bucolic hamlet home to fewer than 60 people.</p>

<p>"If the village is left as it is now, the only thing that awaits us is extinction," said 74-year-old Ichiro Sawayama, head of its governing body.</p>

<p>Many developed nations are facing the same demographic timebomb, but Japan, which allows relatively low levels of immigration, already has the world's second-oldest population after Monaco.</p>

<p>Silence pervades the air in Ichinono, where residents have handcrafted stuffed mannequins to create a semblance of a bustling society.</p>

<p>Some puppets ride swings while others push a cart of firewood, smiling eerily at visitors.</p>

<p>"We're probably outnumbered by puppets," Hisayo Yamazaki, an 88-year-old widow, told AFP.</p>

<p>Rice harvesting and sake brewing used to keep Ichinono afloat. Most families in the village used to have children, Yamazaki recalled.</p>

<p>But "we were afraid they would become unmarriageable if they remained stuck in a remote place like this", so they were encouraged to attend city colleges.</p>

<p>"Out they went, and they never came back, getting jobs elsewhere. We're now paying the price," she said.</p>

<p><strong>Pastoral living</strong></p>

<p>One family in Ichinono is a bit different: 33-year-old Rie Kato and 31-year-old Toshiki Kato moved from big city Osaka to Ichinono in 2021, then they had Kuranosuke.</p>

<p>The couple decided to ditch urban life for the countryside as the pandemic allowed for more flexible working.</p>

<p>As the youngest resident by far, their son is adored by the other villagers, who bring him home-cooked meals and collectively look after him.</p>

<p>The toddler is "our pride", village head Sawayama beams, while widow Yamazaki says he is "practically my great-grandchild -- such a sweet thing".</p>

<p>The Katos say it is a good thing that he is growing up with the community of Ichinono instead of the anonymity of an Osaka apartment.</p>

<p>"Just by being born here, our son benefits from the love, support and hope of so many people -- even though he has achieved absolutely nothing in life yet," laughed his father Toshiki.</p>

<p>His mother Rie said neighbours in the tight-knit village sometimes ask her a favour or invite her to play the croquet-like sport gateball. The family also helps harvest edamame beans with their neighbours.</p>

<p>"I feel like my self-worth, as an individual, is recognised here," she said. "I'm sure that's how Kuranosuke will feel about himself growing up."</p>

<p><strong>'Recreate' Japan?</strong></p>

<p>But Ichinono's insularity can be a turn-off for outsiders.</p>

<p>Outdated rules still exist on paper requiring aspiring newcomers to be vouched for by at least three long-term residents, and proffer sacks of rice or cash.</p>

<p>Those edicts -- meant to "keep the village cohesive" -- are no longer applied to avoid scaring people away, Sawayama said.</p>

<p>While rural decline is a global phenomenon, Japan's topography may worsen the problem, said Taro Taguchi, a community development professor at Tokushima University.</p>

<p>"Probably nowhere do people live on hillsides as much as in Japan," due to a large population and the scarcity of flat farmland, he told AFP.</p>

<p>But the "higher risk of natural disasters and greater proximity to vermin" on mountains make them less attractive when people can choose where they live.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Ishiba has vowed to "recreate Japan" with policies including doubling subsidies for struggling regions.</p>

<p>But Taguchi cautioned that similar subsidies were often approved by the central government in the past to fund "flashy" revitalisation projects like fancy cafes.</p>

<p>"These initiatives did little to support locals' livelihoods," he said.</p>

<p>While working remotely in the IT sector, Toshiki Kato has launched a side project refurbishing century-old houses.</p>

<p>"My humble hope is to help add some new value to these homes, and keep Ichinono's death at bay even just a year longer," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/th72tqr8_japan-puppet-village_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-baseball-coach-charged-with-sexually-abusing-7-kids-in-us-6868752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Baseball Coach Charged With Sexually Abusing 7 Kids In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-baseball-coach-charged-with-sexually-abusing-7-kids-in-us-6868752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 09:45:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former baseball coach Nicolas Morton faces charges ranging from sex abuse to sexual misconduct with a child under 13 years old and forcibly touching kids' intimate parts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former baseball coach at a private school in Brooklyn has been accused of sexually abusing seven boys, including kids as young as 12. Coach Nicolas Morton allegedly even threatened to evict boys from the baseball team if they did anything about his advances. According to information made public along with a 20-count sex crime indictment against him in Brooklyn Supreme Court, the 31-year-old, who worked at Packer Collegiate Institute, grabbed the genitalia of at least three of those boys.</p>

<p>Morton faces charges ranging from sex abuse to sexual misconduct with a child under 13 years old and forcibly touching kids' intimate parts.</p>

<p>The boys, aged 12 to 14, exposed their coach after getting fed up with Morton's alleged sadistic behaviour, according to Gwen Barnes of the Brooklyn District Attorney's Special Victims Bureau, reported the <a href="http://https://nypost.com/2024/10/24/us-news/ex-baseball-coach-at-a-ritzy-nyc-private-school-is-accused-of-sexually-abusing-seven-children/" rel="nofollow,noindex">New York Post</a>.</p>

<p>Morton appeared handcuffed, with a bath towel draped over his wrists, in a Brooklyn courtroom for the hearing. At least 15 of his friends and family members were in the audience.</p>

<p>Barnes highlighted the bravery of the children and told a judge during Morton's arraignment on October 24 that the boys came “forward and stood up for themselves and each other.” All the boys played on Morton's private travel team, NYC Freedom Baseball.</p>

<p>As Barnes revealed a list of accusations against Morton, the coach stood silent, head down. Barnes said that Morton jokingly started making perverted requests of his players at the Brooklyn Heights K-12 school, Packer Collegiate, along with hard workouts that he used as leverage to fulfil his leering desires. “He groomed them by speaking about sex and masturbation and other graphic topics,” Barnes said, adding, “It got to the point he would threaten that they wouldn't make the team when they didn't show him their pubic hair, and sometimes he would insist on seeing their penises.”</p>

<p>Morton was also accused of groping players, some of whom he had been coaching since they were as young as 11. These incidents reportedly involved touching both above and underneath their clothing, and over their underwear, according to Barnes.</p>

<p>Morton's defence attorney, Robert Geor, unsuccessfully attempted to secure his client's release without bail. He argued that Morton “comes from a law enforcement family,” highlighting connections to the Nassau Police Department and the NYPD's 111 precinct in Bayside. The judge established bail at $75,000, with Georges stating that his client's father intended to cover the amount.</p>

<p>The next hearing date has been set for December 13.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/oshohg3c_arrest-generic_625x300_17_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-gives-at-least-132-million-to-elect-donald-trump-6868743]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Spent At Least $132 Million To Elect Donald Trump, Allies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-gives-at-least-132-million-to-elect-donald-trump-6868743]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 09:41:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk gave another $56 million to elect Donald Trump and other Republicans in the final weeks of the 2024 election, bringing to at least $132 million the amount spent by the world's richest person to elevate his allies to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk gave another $56 million to elect Donald Trump and other Republicans in the final weeks of the 2024 election, bringing to at least $132 million the amount spent by the world's richest person to elevate his allies to the White House and Congress, federal filings show.</p>

<p>The donations - revealed in disclosures with the Federal Election Commission Thursday - show that the Tesla Inc. and SpaceX chief executive officer has poured money into the Washington trifecta: funding Trump's White House bid, along with supporting House and Senate Republicans.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-elon-musk-says-he-is-all-in-for-donald-trump-as-the-next-us-president-6740162">Musk, who had only given</a> modest political donations until the 2024 election cycle, funneled $43.6 million in the first half of October into America PAC, the group he founded, bringing his total for the year to $118.6 million. He also spent millions more spreading money around the political system which helps him build a network of allies.</p>

<p>The filings show donations through Oct. 16 and are the final detailed look at federal campaigns' and super political action committees' finances before Election Day on Nov. 5.</p>

<p>Musk's super PAC is paying for operations to boost voter turnout for Trump in battleground states and Republicans in swing districts that could help the GOP win a House majority. America PAC is also spending on digital ad campaigns, some of which target young men, trying to get them to the polls to offset Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris' advantage among women voters.</p>

<p>Musk's giving to other groups included $10 million to the Senate Leadership Fund, a super PAC that aims to elect Senate Republicans, and $2.3 million to the Sentinel Action Fund, a super PAC doing get-out-the-vote work for Republican Senate campaigns in Montana, Nevada, Ohio and Pennsylvania.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The donations are the latest demonstration of how Musk, whose companies boast billions of dollars worth of federal contracts and who has personally bristled at government regulations, is expanding his political influence network to include a potential future president and members of Congress.</p>

<p>His political activities have received some scrutiny from federal officials. The US Justice Department sent a letter to his super PAC this week warning that a program to give $1 million a day to registered voters in swing states who sign an online petition may violate federal laws. It's illegal to pay individuals to vote or to register to vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In addition to Musk, eight other individuals also donated to America PAC, including investor Nelson Peltz and members of the DeVos family, who are longtime Republican donors. Betsy DeVos was Trump's education secretary.</p>

<p>America PAC spent $47 million and had $3.3 million cash on hand heading into the last 19 days before Election Day. Since its launch earlier this year through Oct. 16, America PAC has spent $105 million backing Trump.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-elon-musk-donates-nearly-75-million-for-donald-trumps-presidential-cause-6807420">Musk is playing</a> an unprecedented role in the 2024 campaign for a political donor. In addition to his donations, he's appeared on stage with Trump and held his own campaign rallies without the former president. At an event earlier this month in Pennsylvania, Musk used ominous rhetoric, telling the crowd that "this election is going to decide the fate of America. And along with the fate of America, the fate of western civilization."</p>

<p>The former president has said he would ask Musk to join his administration should he win a second term, heading up an effort to cut government waste nicknamed the Department of Government Efficiency, or DOGE, a reference to a cryptocurrency Musk has embraced.</p>

<p>Deep-pocketed donors are playing a critical role in supporting Trump, who lags far behind Harris in fundraising. She's been outspending his campaign in all seven of the battleground states that will decide the election in the final stretch since Labor Day, according to data from AdImpact. Her media buys total $352 million compared to $214 million for Trump.</p>

<p>Harris' financial advantage has also allowed her to open more then 330 field offices staffed with more than 2,000 paid employees to help conduct its voter-mobilization operations. But the candidates are statistically tied among likely voters in each of the seven swing states in the Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll, with the razor-thin margins in these battlegrounds underscoring how the final blitz of advertising, rallies and door-knocking campaigns could decide who claims the White House.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pm2k6j18_elon-musk-donald-trump-_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk is playing an unprecedented role in the 2024 campaign for a political donor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-journalists-killed-in-israeli-strike-says-lebanese-state-media-6868976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Journalists Killed In Israeli Strike, Says Lebanese State Media]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-journalists-killed-in-israeli-strike-says-lebanese-state-media-6868976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 09:29:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanese state media said Friday that separate Israeli air strikes killed three journalists in eastern Lebanon and flattened buildings in southern suburbs of Beirut.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese state media said Friday that separate Israeli air strikes killed three journalists in eastern Lebanon and flattened buildings in southern suburbs of Beirut.</p>

<p>"Our correspondent in Zahle reported the death of three journalists in an Israeli raid on Hasbaya," Lebanon's official National News Agency (NNA) said, adding that Israeli military planes struck at 3:30 am (0030 GMT) near the Syrian border.</p>

<p>Local media reported that the air raid hit a hotel in Hasbaya, around 50 kilometres south of the Lebanese capital.</p>

<p>Separately, in Beirut's southern Choueifat Al-Amrousieh area, Israeli warplanes "destroyed two buildings and ignited a large fire, and black smoke covered the area," according to NNA.</p>

<p>"The raid that targeted the Saint Therese area also caused the collapse of two buildings near the Constitutional Council."</p>

<p>The NNA report of the strikes on Beirut's south on Thursday came about half an hour after Israel issued evacuation warnings for the Hezbollah bastion following intense assaults the night before.</p>

<p>"You are located near facilities and sites belonging to Hezbollah, which the Israeli Defense Forces will be targeting in the near future," said the Israeli army's Arabic-language spokesman Avichay Adraee in a post on X that included maps of the locations.</p>

<p>AFPTV footage showed plumes of smoke rising from Beirut's south following the strikes and AFP correspondents in the capital heard loud bangs.</p>

<p>"Israeli warplanes launched a new strike a short while ago on the Choueifat" area of south Beirut, NNA said, adding later that Haret Hreik and Hadath were also targeted.</p>

<p>On Wednesday evening, Israeli strikes levelled six buildings in south Beirut, state media and AFP footage showed, with Israel's army saying it had hit Hezbollah weapons production facilities "under and inside civilian buildings".</p>

<p>On September 23, Israel launched an intense air campaign in Lebanon and later announced ground incursions, following a year of limited cross-border clashes with Iran-backed Hezbollah over the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Since then, Israeli strikes in Lebanon have killed at least 1,580 people, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures, though the real number is likely to be higher due to gaps in the data.</p>

<p>The Committee to Protect Journalists has documented at least 128 journalists and media workers killed in Gaza, the West Bank, Israel and Lebanon since the Israel-Hamas war began in October 2023.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i51mhs6o_israeli-air-strike_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Local media reported that the air raid hit a hotel in Hasbaya, around 50 kms south of Beirut.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ey-fires-staff-in-us-for-taking-multiple-online-training-courses-at-once-6868561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EY Fires Staff In US For Taking Multiple Online Training Courses At Once]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ey-fires-staff-in-us-for-taking-multiple-online-training-courses-at-once-6868561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 09:02:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ernst & Young (EY) recently fired dozens of employees in the US for attending multiple online training courses simultaneously during the firm's learning week organised earlier this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ernst &amp; Young (EY) recently fired dozens of employees in the US for attending multiple online training courses simultaneously during the firm's learning week organised earlier this year. According to the <em>Financial Times</em>, the company said that the act amounted to an ethical breach. "Our core values of integrity and ethics are at the forefront of everything we do. Appropriate disciplinary action was recently taken in a small number of cases where individuals were found to be in violation of our global code of conduct and US learning policy," EY said. However, the dismissals, which took place last week, have sparked an internal debate about business ethics and the limits of multitasking.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Following the termination, several employees who were sacked for the reason spoke with the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ft.com/content/dff2246e-e949-4cfb-833d-a8e38ba1e7da" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Financial Times</em></a>, countering that there was no prior warning from the company against attending multiple courses at the same time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Their emails marketing EY Ignite actually encouraged us to join as many sessions as our schedule allowed," one person told the <em>FT</em>, adding, "We all work with three monitors. I was hoping to hear new ideas that I could bring to the table to separate myself from others."</p>

<p>Another person who lost their job said that the firm "breeds a culture of multitasking". "If you are forced to bill 45 hours a week and do many more hours of internal work, how can it not?" the former employee said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A third person said, "I know a partner who will do two (client) calls and switch their camera on and off depending on who he is talking to. If this is unethical, then that is unethical, too."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/man-gets-rejection-mail-from-company-in-the-middle-of-interview-hilariously-unfortunate-6868319">Man Gets Rejection Mail From Company In The Middle Of Interview: "Hilariously Unfortunate"</a></strong></p>

<p>EY termed the sackings as "appropriate disciplinary action", saying attending more than one course at the same time was a breach of the company's ethics. But some staff reacted to the latest dismissals by calling them a disproportionately severe response.&nbsp;</p>

<p>EY's response was "just bizarre", said one employee, adding, "Perhaps reduce their rating, deduct bonus, or even delay promo, but simply terminating them effective immediately is just cruel... If this was so important, then implement better systems."</p>

<p>The firm has since updated its guidance for training events, explicitly requiring staff to "be present for all content and class interactions." The dismissed employees were reportedly not provided severance packages.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/jafprsms_ey-generic_625x300_26_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The firm has since updated its guidance for training events.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-bank-rolls-out-new-strategy-to-boost-economic-opportunities-for-women-6868433]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Bank's New Gender Strategy To Increase Women's Economic Participation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-bank-rolls-out-new-strategy-to-boost-economic-opportunities-for-women-6868433]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 08:36:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Bank announced a new gender strategy aimed at boosting economic opportunities for women and enabling their participation in the global economy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Bank announced on Thursday a new gender strategy aimed at boosting economic opportunities for women and enabling their participation in the global economy through social protection and access to broadband and capital.</p>

<p>The Gender Strategy 2024-2030, unveiled during the International Monetary Fund and World Bank annual meetings in Washington, has set goals by 2030 that aim to enable 300 million more women to use broadband internet, unlocking essential services, financial services, education and job opportunities.</p>

<p>It also aims to support 250 million women with social protection programs focusing on the poorest and most vulnerable, and to provide 80 million more women and women-led businesses with capital, addressing constraints to entrepreneurship growth.</p>

<p>"When we increase women's economic participation, it not only boosts the global economy, but also strengthens families and communities," World Bank President Ajay Banga said in a statement. "Through economic empowerment, we are building a ladder out of poverty and extending hope and dignity as far as possible."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/working-women_650x400_41520575665.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/us-election-we-still-dont-know-what-kamala-harris-really-is-about-6864983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: We Still Don't Know What Kamala Harris Really Is About]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/us-election-we-still-dont-know-what-kamala-harris-really-is-about-6864983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 08:00:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Republicans stole the constituency in broad daylight, while the Democrats were busy playing woke and pandering to the extreme fringe of the party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3op979r_kamala-harris_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>With less than two weeks to voting day, the US presidential race remains maddeningly deadlocked and statistically tied. A gain of a percentage point here, a fraction there could mean victory or defeat. &nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
That said, Donald Trump appears to have some last-minute momentum while Kamala Harris seems to be struggling to win new converts while losing a percentage of traditional voters. Although the average of various national polls still shows Harris ahead with 48.1% and Trump at 46.4%, her four-point lead in August has narrowed and changed the ‘vibe' somewhat. But national polls don't tell the real story, it's state polls where the action is because of the complicated Electoral College system in the presidential election.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Of the seven so-called battleground states – Pennsylvania, Wisconsin, Michigan, Georgia, Arizona, Nevada and North Carolina –Trump is ahead in five and Harris in two in a sign of the wheels turning in his favour. But it's all within the margin of error.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Beyond The "Vibes" Campaign</strong></h2>

<p>Last week, Nate Silver, a reputed pollster, listed 24 reasons why Trump could win, ranging from the Electoral College bias favouring Republicans, voters' negative perceptions about the economy, illegal immigration ballooning under the current administration where Harris is Vice-President to the shift in Black and Latino male vote towards Trump, and, most importantly, Harris's failure to define herself on issues in a manner that resonates.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Being a “joyful warrior” and running a “vibes” campaign is proving inadequate—voters are worried about inflation, not what influencers say. Harris has been in office for nearly four years but can't seem to disassociate herself from the administration's failed policies in a way that works for her.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
No surprise then the Democrats are anxious while the Republicans are swaggering a bit at the moment. But the tables could turn yet again because polls can be and have been wrong in the past two elections. Things could swing either way in the final phase, depending on voter turnout and the ground game where Democrats have a definite edge. The Dems also have more money—the Harris campaign has collected $1 billion in small and large donations.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Harris's Warnings Are Not Working</strong></h2>

<p>But what about the closing arguments to sway those who are still undecided? Trump and Harris are making a similar case—‘elect me because the other is a threat to democracy, your way of life and to America itself'. While Trump's arsenal always had shades of the apocalypse—Democrats as ‘closet communists', Harris as a ‘radical leftist', ‘illegals are invading', ‘world is in chaos'--Harris has also caught the fever in the final stretch.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Her attacks are increasingly pointed. She is busy painting Trump as toxic, dangerous, unchecked, unstable, even a potential dictator and a man who can't follow a thought for a minute. A second Trump administration would be a living manifestation of Project 2025, an extremist agenda prepared by ultra-conservatives. The plan includes mass firing of government workers and dismantling the entire department of education. &nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
The problem is, the warnings are not working, especially with blue-collar voters. Her campaign might be making a mistake by hammering the wrong nail. Voters have already factored in Trump's dangerous flaws and taken a measure. They have filtered out what they don't like. His inflammatory rhetoric and threats to unleash the military on fellow Americans (Democrats) are seen as bombastic talk and not a plan of action. After two assassination attempts, he is also a beneficiary of some sympathy, especially with those who feel the Democrats overreached by drowning him in legal cases.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>An Undefined Candidate</strong></h2>

<p>By contrast, Harris remains largely undefined for many Americans. Is she a populist who will take on big business, or will she swim within her lane? Even when given a chance to clarify her positions on illegal immigration and what she would do differently to fix the economy, she played safe instead of striking a different note. It reinforced the idea she's an incumbent defending the current administration's record, not a candidate of change who will “turn the page” as she says.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Voters are hungering for “change” from this administration's policies, whether on the economy, broken borders, or two raging wars. Trump has hammered on all those issues from the start and set the narrative of Democrats' failure on all three.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
While Harris may be struggling with male voters, she does have an advantage with women on the issue of reproductive rights. No matter how Trump spins it, he can't get away from the fact that his Supreme Court appointees dismantled Roe v. Wade, taking away a woman's right to have an abortion. The court sent the matter to states resulting in a patchwork of restrictive laws, with some states banning abortions after six weeks of pregnancy. Harris is passionate when speaking on the issue, unlike any other. She needs to hammer on it until the end to rouse women to come out in ever greater numbers. At the same time, she could admit that illegal immigration should have been managed better.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Dems and liberals feel outraged that Trump, a convicted felon, might win the White House again, but voters have other things on their minds. It doesn't help Harris to parade Republicans who broke from Trump and consider him a closet fascist at her town hall meetings. It doesn't matter how many Republicans sign letters in her support. What matters are her plans, policies and predilections, which even at this late stage remain largely confined to her website. They haven't been translated into effective messaging to voters.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The McDonald's Masterstroke</strong></h2>

<p>Economic populism is working well for Trump. He appeared at a McDonald's in the battleground state of Pennsylvania last Sunday to cook fries and hand out orders at the drive-in window. It was a political masterstroke and reinforced the image that he connects with average folks. How a billionaire who has played the system forever can also play a messiah for the working class will remain a mystery, but that's where the messaging of one camp has succeeded over the other.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
The Democratic Party's disconnect from working-class voters—Blacks, Whites and Latinos—is shocking to some, but it's been in the process for some time. The Republicans stole the constituency in broad daylight, while the Democrats were busy playing ‘woke' and pandering to the extreme fringe of the party. In the process, the Dems lost touch with a majority of everyday Americans who don't live in California and New York.</p>

<p><em>(Seema Sirohi is a Washington, DC-based columnist and the author of 'Friends With Benefits: The India-US Story', a book about the past 30 years of the relationship)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/a0a3koa8_kamala-harris_625x300_24_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/menendez-brothers-jailed-for-life-for-killing-parents-could-be-freed-6868251]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Menendez Brothers, Jailed For Life For Killing Parents, Could Be Freed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/menendez-brothers-jailed-for-life-for-killing-parents-could-be-freed-6868251]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 07:30:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lyle and Erik Menendez, who in 1989 murdered their wealthy parents, could be released from prison after a US prosecutor said he would ask a judge to look again at their sentences.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lyle and Erik Menendez, the two brothers whose grisly 1989 murder of their wealthy parents was the subject of a recent Netflix series, could be released from prison after a US prosecutor said Thursday he would ask a judge to look again at their sentences.</p>

<p>The pair were sentenced to life without the possibility of parole for the shotgun slayings in the family's swanky Beverly Hills home, following a blockbuster trial that gripped the United States and grabbed headlines around the world.</p>

<p>Prosecutors at the time argued that the two had plotted to murder Jose and Mary Louise "Kitty" Menendez in a bid to hasten a $14 million inheritance.</p>

<p>But supporters said they were the victims of sustained sexual and physical abuse, and had snapped after years of suffering at the hands of a tyrannical father.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/menendez-brothers-killed-parents-to-avoid-abuse-relatives-urge-their-release-6808424">Menendez Brothers Killed Parents To Avoid Abuse, Relatives Urge Their Release</a></p>

<p>"After a very careful review of all the arguments... I believe that under the law, resentencing is appropriate, and I am going to recommend that to a court tomorrow," Los Angeles District Attorney George Gascon told reporters Thursday.</p>

<p>Gascon said his recommendation would be that the brothers be resentenced for murder, a charge that carries a sentence of 50 years to life.</p>

<p>"Since they were under 26 years of age at the time that these crimes occurred, they would be eligible for parole immediately."</p>

<p>Gascon, who is facing a tough re-election battle in November, said while he did not condone the violent murders the Menendez brothers -- aged 19 and 21 at the time -- carried out, he believed there were specific circumstances.</p>

<p>"If you get abused, the right path is to call the police, seek help. But I understand also how sometimes people get desperate."</p>

<p><strong>'Compassionate'</strong></p>

<p>Erik Menendez, now 53, and Lyle Menendez, now 56, have served nearly 35 years in prison since their convictions.</p>

<p>Their cousin Karen Vander Molen hailed Gascon's "compassionate" announcement.</p>

<p>"We know this wasn't an easy decision, but it is the right one," she said.</p>

<p>"This is about truth, justice and healing. It is time for Lyle and Erik to come home."</p>

<p>She said the decision "gives us all hope the truth will finally be heard and Erik and Lyle can begin to heal from the horrors of their past."</p>

<p>It will be up to a judge to make the final determination on Gascon's recommendation, which he acknowledged was not unanimous even within his own department.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear when a hearing on the matter might be held, although Gascon said his office would file the court papers on Friday.</p>

<p>Legal experts told local media the brothers would not be leaving prison anytime soon, with a long legal process still ahead.</p>

<p><strong>Global headlines</strong></p>

<p>Their initial trial, starting in 1993, was one of the first televised US murder cases and made daily headlines around the world. It ended in a mistrial due to a deadlocked jury, but they were found guilty in a second trial.</p>

<p>Last year, attorneys filed a court petition setting out new evidence which they said demonstrates Jose Menendez's history of sexual abuse.</p>

<p>Among the new evidence was a letter Erik wrote to a cousin months before the murders, saying "I've been trying to avoid dad. It's still happening... Every night I stay up thinking he might come in."</p>

<p>Roy Rossello, a former member of 1980s boy band Menudo, said in a documentary series released last year that he was drugged and raped by Jose Menendez in the 1980s.</p>

<p>Earlier this month Gascon told reporters he had "a moral and an ethical obligation to review what is being presented to us."</p>

<p>His comments came two weeks after the release of Netflix crime drama "Monsters: The Lyle and Erik Menendez Story." The streaming giant also put out a documentary film, "The Menendez Brothers," last week.</p>

<p>Gascon said the Netflix show resulted in a large number of calls to his office about the case.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/licm4blo_menendez-brothers_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Erik Menendez, now 53, and Lyle, now 56, have served nearly 35 years in prison since their convictions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/commonwealth-summit-in-samoa-presses-uk-to-compensate-for-brutal-past-6868183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles Faces Calls To Compensate For UK's Brutal Past At Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/commonwealth-summit-in-samoa-presses-uk-to-compensate-for-brutal-past-6868183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 07:24:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's King Charles faced calls to reckon with his country's colonial past Friday, as a summit of Commonwealth allies turned into a factious debate about the legacy of slavery and empire.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's King Charles faced calls to reckon with his country's colonial past Friday, as a summit of Commonwealth allies turned into a factious debate about the legacy of slavery and empire.</p>

<p>Leaders from the 56-nation Commonwealth -- made up mostly of British ex-colonies -- gathered for a summit in Samoa, hoping to prove the bloc is still relevant.</p>

<p>But instead of uniting to tackle pressing issues like climate change, Charles III's maiden summit as king has been overshadowed by history.</p>

<p>Many African, Caribbean and Pacific nations want to see Britain -- and other European powers -- pay financial compensation for slavery, or to at least make political amends.</p>

<p>They want this summit in particular to commit to a discussion on the topic of reparatory justice -- a debate Britain's cash-strapped government has tried to stymie.</p>

<p>The Bahamas' Prime Minister Philip Davis told AFP that a debate about the past was vital.</p>

<p>"The time has come to have a real dialogue about how we address these historical wrongs," he said.</p>

<p>"Reparatory justice is not an easy conversation, but it's an important one," Davis added.</p>

<p>"The horrors of slavery left a deep, generational wound in our communities, and the fight for justice and reparatory justice is far from over".</p>

<p>The British royal family, which benefited from the slave trade over centuries, has also faced calls to apologise.</p>

<p>But the monarch stopped well short of that on Friday, asking summit attendees to "reject the language of division".</p>

<p>"I understand, from listening to people across the Commonwealth, how the most painful aspects of our past continue to resonate," he said.</p>

<p>"None of us can change the past. But we can commit, with all our hearts to learning its lessons and to finding creative ways to right inequalities that endure."</p>

<p><strong>'Honesty and integrity'</strong></p>

<p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer has publicly rejected calls to pay reparations, and aides have ruled out an apology at the summit.</p>

<p>A draft summit communique calling for debate on colonialism is the subject of fierce negotiations.</p>

<p>One diplomatic source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told AFP that developed countries were trying to water down the language in the final communique.</p>

<p>"The call for reparations isn't simply about financial compensation; it's about recognising the enduring impact of centuries of exploitation and ensuring that the legacy of slavery is addressed with honesty and integrity," Davis insisted.</p>

<p>Joshua Setipa from Lesotho -- who is one of three candidates vying to be the next Commonwealth's secretary-general -- said reparations could include non-traditional forms of payment such as climate financing.</p>

<p>"We can find a solution that will begin to address some injustices of the past and put them in the context happening around us today," he told AFP ahead of the summit.</p>

<p>Kingsley Abbott, Director of the Institute of Commonwealth Studies at the University of London said the apparent inclusion of the text on reparatory justice was a "significant advancement" for the Commonwealth.</p>

<p>He told AFP it "reveals the door to meaningful dialogue is opening".</p>

<p>The British monarch is concluding an 11-day tour of Australia and Samoa, both independent Commonwealth states -- the first major foreign trip since his cancer diagnosis earlier this year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jmu03m2_king-charles-samoa-commonwealth-summit-_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Britain's King Charles III's maiden summit as king has been overshadowed by history.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shipping-firm-to-pay-100-million-in-us-baltimore-bridge-collapse-settlement-6868119]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Shipping Firm To Pay $100 Million In Baltimore Bridge Collapse Settlement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shipping-firm-to-pay-100-million-in-us-baltimore-bridge-collapse-settlement-6868119]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 07:04:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Justice Department said Thursday that it has reached a $100 million settlement with the Singaporean owner and operator of a cargo ship that destroyed a Baltimore bridge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Justice Department said Thursday that it has reached a $100 million settlement with the Singaporean owner and operator of a cargo ship that destroyed a Baltimore bridge.</p>

<p>The 1,000-foot (300-meter) M/V Dali collided with the Francis Scott Key Bridge in the early morning of March 26, killing six road workers and blocking the busy shipping channel.</p>

<p>Grace Ocean Private Ltd and Synergy Marine Private Ltd have agreed to pay $101.1 million to settle a civil suit aimed at recovering costs incurred in responding to the disaster and for removing tons of bridge debris from the channel leading to the port of Baltimore, the Justice Department said.</p>

<p>"Nearly seven months after one of the worst transportation disasters in recent memory, which claimed six lives and caused untold damage, we have reached an important milestone with today's settlement," Benjamin Mizer, a senior Justice Department official, said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This resolution ensures that the costs of the federal government's cleanup efforts in the Fort McHenry Channel are borne by Grace Ocean and Synergy and not the American taxpayer," Mizer said.</p>

<p>The Justice Department said the settlement does not include any damages for eventual rebuilding of the Francis Scott Key Bridge. That is the subject of a separate claim from the state of Maryland.</p>

<p>The families of the six road workers who lost their lives are also pursuing legal claims of their own.</p>

<p>The Fort McHenry channel leading to the port of Baltimore, a key hub for the auto industry, reopened to commercial navigation on June 10.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/7r3333hg_baltimore-bridge-afp_625x300_19_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 1,000-foot M/V Dali collided with the Francis Scott Key Bridge in the early morning of March 26.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-running-to-be-an-american-tyrant-singer-bruce-springsteen-6868052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Donald Trump Running To Be An American Tyrant": Singer Bruce Springsteen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-running-to-be-an-american-tyrant-singer-bruce-springsteen-6868052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 06:49:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bruce Springsteen took the stage Thursday at Kamala Harris's star-studded campaign rally in swing state Georgia, with the rock legend warning that White House hopeful Donald Trump aims to be an "American tyrant."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bruce Springsteen took the stage Thursday at Kamala Harris's star-studded campaign rally in swing state Georgia, with the rock legend warning that White House hopeful Donald Trump aims to be an "American tyrant."</p>

<p>Harris is cranking up the celebrity wattage -- including with Beyonce in Texas on Friday, according to reports -- at a series of concerts in battleground states to boost support in the final days of a nail-biting election.</p>

<p>Thursday's rally in Atlanta is also Harris's first campaign stop with Barack Obama, the only Black president in American history and who remains widely popular with Democratic voters.</p>

<p>But it was Springsteen's gritty commentary at the start that echoed through the packed rally, where the iconic singer said he would "oppose" the Republican former president because "Donald Trump is running to be an American tyrant."</p>

<p>Large numbers of Americans, including about 2.2 million in Georgia, have already cast ballots in early voting, reflecting intense engagement ahead of Election Day on November 5.</p>

<p>Springsteen brought his brand of socially conscious, working-class anthems including "The Promised Land" to get out the vote and bolster Harris's blue-collar credentials.</p>

<p>The vice president herself had raised the stakes further in a CNN appearance late Wednesday when she said she considers 78-year-old Trump to be a "fascist" -- as charged in a bombshell interview by the Republican's former chief of staff John Kelly.</p>

<p>Trump, the oldest major presidential nominee in US history and the first to be running with a criminal record, is also casting the election as an existential battle for the United States.</p>

<p>But it will have profound personal implications too, given he is the subject of serious criminal probes into his attempt to overturn his 2020 election loss and his post-presidential hoarding of top-secret documents.</p>

<p>The Republican was campaigning Thursday in the western battleground of Arizona where he conjured dark imagery of migrant violence and warned that America had become "a dumping ground" for dangerous and undocumented immigrants.</p>

<p>"We're like a garbage can for the world," Trump said.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Revenge' -</strong></p>

<p>In a radio interview on his way to the rally in Arizona and then another in Nevada -- both swing states -- Trump announced that if elected he'd fire the special prosecutor overseeing his remaining cases in "seconds."</p>

<p>Harris, 60, for her part assailed Trump for "plotting revenge and retribution" against his political enemies, and took a swipe at his energy levels.</p>

<p>"The sad part about that is he's trying to be president of the United States -- probably the toughest job in the world -- and he's exhausted," Harris told reporters.</p>

<p>The election remains a toss-up, with the two candidates jostling within the margin of error in polls from all the swing states set to tip the overall national result.</p>

<p>US media reported Thursday that Beyonce -- whose hit "Freedom" is already the Harris campaign's signature song -- will join the Democrat when she visits Houston on Friday to highlight abortion rights.</p>

<p>Obama, 63, has been making his own headlining appearances in support of Harris in a slew of swing states, including Pennsylvania, Wisconsin and Michigan.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign hopes the former president will reverse fears of eroding support among Black voters.</p>

<p>Harris, 60, is of mixed Black and South Asian heritage, and is vying to become the country's first female president.</p>

<p><strong>- American Dream 'unreachable ' -</strong></p>

<p>Trump was expected to attack Harris's economic policies at a rally in Tempe, Arizona.</p>

<p>His campaign said the current vice president had "made the American Dream of home ownership unreachable for young Americans and families."</p>

<p>But in his 55-minute address Trump made zero mention of soaring housing costs, opting instead to blame Harris for a "migrant invasion" that has overwhelmed American cities.</p>

<p>"No person who is responsible for so much bloodshed and death on our soil can ever be allowed to become the president of the United States," he said.</p>

<p>Trump then was set to attend a Las Vegas rally aimed at recruiting volunteers and celebrating the Asian American and Pacific Islander community.</p>

<p>Like Harris, Trump also heads Friday to Texas, where he is to deliver remarks on border security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8e50gqnc_bruce-springsteen_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US musician Bruce Springsteen performed on Thursday during a campaign rally to support Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-warned-about-terror-plot-against-israeli-tourists-3-arrested-6865412]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Warned About Terror Plot Against Israeli Tourists, 3 Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-warned-about-terror-plot-against-israeli-tourists-3-arrested-6865412]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 06:28:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lankan police arrested three persons on suspicion of plotting an attack against Israeli tourists in the eastern coast surfing resort of Arugam Bay following a tip-off from Indian intelligence, authorities said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lankan police arrested three persons on suspicion of plotting an attack against Israeli tourists in the eastern coast surfing resort of Arugam Bay following a tip-off from Indian intelligence, authorities said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Public Security Minister Vijitha Herath said all three suspects arrested by the Terrorism Investigation Division of the police are Sri Lankan nationals.</p>

<p>They are being interrogated to ascertain if they had a plan to carry out the attack targeting Israelis, the minister said.</p>

<p>Earlier, police announced the arrest of two persons and said it came as a result of Indian intelligence information, which warned of an attack between October 19 and 23.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the US embassy and the British High Commission in Colombo issued statements warning their citizens that they had received credible information targeting Arugam Bay and urged tourists to avoid the area until further notice.</p>

<p>Responding to the opposition's criticism that the public was not informed about the threat until the US embassy issued its travel advisory, Herath said, "We did not inform the public until the information could be verified." "Some information has been revealed that there may be potential threats to the safety of the tourists who visited Sri Lanka," Herath was quoted as saying by local media.</p>

<p>"Intelligence agencies received information about it. Upon receiving that information, we immediately took action," he added.</p>

<p>He said the government had taken swift action to provide security at all coastal areas and tourism sites after receiving the information.</p>

<p>Herath said adequate measures have been put in place to ensure the safety of all tourists.</p>

<p>He said US Ambassador Julie Chung had informed the government of the travel advisory on the Arugam Bay security situation.</p>

<p>The US warned its citizens to avoid the popular tourists' resort on the eastern coast until further notice. Security has been beefed up in the region.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the police said that the security net has been extended to the southern coast and the southeastern resort areas.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka's Muslim minority groups have condemned the wars in Gaza and Lebanon by holding continuous anti-Israel protests.</p>

<p>Several posts have appeared on social media calling for a boycott of Israeli businesses on the east coast.</p>

<p>The police vowed to accord protection to all foreign nationals. A hotline has been set up for tourists to alert authorities of any suspicious activities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/54b2tq4g_sri-lanka-beach-generic-reuters_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Sri Lankan police vowed to accord protection to all foreign nationals.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brics-leaders-commit-to-building-democratic-multipolar-world-order-vladimir-putin-6867931]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BRICS Leaders Commit To Building Democratic, Multipolar World Order: Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brics-leaders-commit-to-building-democratic-multipolar-world-order-vladimir-putin-6867931]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 06:03:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[BRICS countries are committed to fostering a more democratic and multipolar world order, Russian President Vladimir Putin said, during his press conference on the last day of the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BRICS countries are committed to fostering a more democratic and multipolar world order, Russian President Vladimir Putin said, during his press conference on the last day of the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.</p>

<p>Putin noted on Thursday that the Kazan Declaration, endorsed at the summit, outlines a positive agenda for the future, the Kremlin reported.</p>

<p>"It is important that the declaration reaffirms the commitment of all our states to building a more democratic, inclusive, and multipolar world order based on international law and the UN Charter," he said.</p>

<p>Putin also said that the BRICS group is open to all who share its values, with members dedicated to finding joint solutions free from external pressure or narrow approaches, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>The bloc does not operate in a closed format, he stressed at the press conference.</p>

<p>The Russian President confirmed that BRICS leaders have agreed on the list of BRICS partner countries.</p>

<p>"Some countries that have participated in these events have submitted their proposals and requests for full-fledged participation in the work of the BRICS association," Putin added.</p>

<p>He said that BRICS nations haven't developed and are not developing any alternatives to SWIFT, adding however that the issue remains important, and member countries are moving towards the use of national currencies.</p>

<p>He said BRICS members are currently using the Financial Messaging System created by the Russian Central Bank.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/otk5js9_putin_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin confirmed that BRICS leaders have agreed on the list of BRICS partner countries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-hamas-commander-who-involved-in-october-7-attack-killed-6867905]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Commander Who Doubled As UN Aid Worker Killed In Gaza, Says Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-hamas-commander-who-involved-in-october-7-attack-killed-6867905]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 05:56:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's military said on Thursday it killed a Hamas commander who took part in the Oct. 7, 2023 assault on southern Israel and who also worked for the U.N. aid agency in the Gaza Strip.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Israel's military said on Thursday it killed a Hamas commander who took part in the Oct. 7, 2023 assault on southern Israel and who also worked for the U.N. aid agency in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The agency, UNRWA, has been accused by Israel for having many employees who double as members of Hamas and other armed group. The U.N. said in August that nine UNRWA staff were possibly involved in the Oct. 7 attacks and fired them.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from UNRWA regarding the latest Israeli allegation. Separately, the agency on Wednesday had said that one of its staff members was killed in an Israeli strike in central Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said that Mohammad Abu Itiwi was killed on Wednesday. It said he was a Hamas commander and had been involved in the murder and abduction of Israeli civilians. It also said he had been employed by UNRWA since July 2022 and that his name appeared on a list of the agency's employees.</p>

<p>UNRWA provides education, health and aid to millions of Palestinians in Gaza, the West Bank, Jordan, Lebanon and Syria. It has long had tense relations with Israel but relations have deteriorated sharply since the start of the war in Gaza and Israel has called repeatedly for UNRWA to be disbanded.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rngv1mh8_israel-hamas-war_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military said that Mohammad Abu Itiwi was killed on Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>