<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 01:04:11 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-barry-wilmore-boeing-starliner-why-nasa-picked-elon-musks-spacex-to-bring-back-astronauts-from-space-6410789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why NASA Picked Elon Musk's SpaceX To Bring Back Astronauts From Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-barry-wilmore-boeing-starliner-why-nasa-picked-elon-musks-spacex-to-bring-back-astronauts-from-space-6410789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 23:30:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA today picked Elon Musk's SpaceX to bring back Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore from space next year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA today picked Elon Musk's SpaceX to bring back Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore from space next year. Eighty days ago, the two astronauts arrived at the International Space Station aboard Boeing's Starliner for an 8-day mission. They were forced to extend their stay because of major technical issues with the Boeing capsule.</p>

<p>The astronauts are expected to return in February next year, after spending a total of eight months in orbit, on a SpaceX Crew Dragon spacecraft due to launch next month as part of a routine astronaut rotation mission.</p>

<p>NASA chief Bill Nelson said Starliner's propulsion system is too risky to carry its first crew home. Starliner will undock from the ISS without a crew and attempt to return to Earth as it would have with astronauts aboard.</p>

<p>The space agency's decision to pick Boeing's top space rival marked a fresh setback to the Starliner test mission. Boeing had hoped the mission would redeem the troubled program after years of development problems and over $1.6 billion in budget overruns since 2016.</p>

<p>Nelson said he discussed the agency's decision with Boeing's new CEO Kelly Ortberg.</p>

<p>The SpaceX Crew-9 mission will take off in late September, but carrying only two passengers instead of the originally planned four.</p>

<p>It will remain moored to the ISS until its scheduled return in February, bringing back its own crew members plus their two stranded colleagues.</p>

<p>The veteran <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronauts-sunita-williams-barry-butch-wilmore-in-space-for-80-days-will-return-february-next-year-says-nasa-6410618">NASA astronauts</a>, both former military test pilots, became the first crew to ride Starliner on June 5 when they were launched to the ISS.</p>

<p>Starliner's propulsion system suffered multiple glitches beginning in the first 24 hours of its flight to the ISS, triggering months of cascading delays. Five of its 28 thrusters failed and it sprang several leaks of helium, which is used to pressurise the thrusters.</p>

<p>Since Starliner docked to the ISS in June, Boeing has scrambled to investigate what caused its thruster mishaps and helium leaks. The company arranged tests and simulations on Earth to gather data that it has used to try and convince NASA officials that Starliner is safe to fly the crew back home.</p>

<p>But results from that testing raised more difficult engineering questions and ultimately failed to quell NASA officials' concerns about Starliner's ability to make its crewed return trip - the most daunting and complex part of the test mission.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/720ksnho_sunita-williams_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmor are expected to return in February next year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-president-touts-new-drone-missile-calls-putin-sick-old-man-6410785]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine President Calls Putin "Sick Old Man From Red Square" In New Video]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-president-touts-new-drone-missile-calls-putin-sick-old-man-6410785]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 23:25:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelensky touted a newly developed Ukrainian "drone missile" on Saturday that he said would take the war back to Russia and scornfully derided Russia's Vladimir Putin as a "sick old man from Red Square".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky touted a newly developed Ukrainian "drone missile" on Saturday that he said would take the war back to Russia and scornfully derided Russia's Vladimir Putin as a "sick old man from Red Square".</p>

<p>As Ukraine marked 33 years of post-Soviet independence, Mr Zelensky said the new weapon, Palianytsia, was faster and more powerful than the domestically made drones that Kyiv has so far used to fight back against Russia, striking its oil refineries and military airfields.</p>

<p>"Our enemy will ... know what the Ukrainian way for retaliation is. Worthy, symmetrical, long-ranged," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Zelensky said the new class of Ukrainian weapon had been used for a successful strike on a target in Russia, but did not say where.</p>

<p>He used derisive language to describe Russia's 71-year-old president and the nuclear rhetoric coming out of Moscow.</p>

<p>"A sick old man from Red Square who constantly threatens everyone with the red button will not dictate any of his red lines to us," he said in a video on the Telegram messaging app.</p>

<p>Russia, which has attacked Ukraine with many thousands of missiles and drones since it invaded in February 2022, has decried Ukraine's drone attacks as terrorism. Moscow's troops are advancing in Ukraine's east and occupy 18% of the country.</p>

<p>Mr Zelensky has been pressing Kyiv's allies to allow him to use Western weapons deeper in Russian territory such as to strike airbases used by Russian warplanes that pound Ukraine with missiles and glide bombs.</p>

<p>"I want to stress once more that our new weapon decisions, including Palianytsia, is our realistic way to act while some of our partners are unfortunately delaying decisions," Mr Zelensky told a news conference.</p>

<p>Ukrainians say the word "Palianytsia", a type of Ukrainian bread, is too difficult to pronounce for Russians and it has been used - sometimes humorously - during the war as a way to tell Ukrainians and Russians apart.</p>

<p>"It will be very difficult for Russia, difficult to even pronounce what exactly has hit it," Mr Zelensky said of the drone missile.</p>

<h3><strong>TOP COMMANDER PROMOTED</strong></h3>

<p>In a decree, Mr Zelensky promoted his top commander, Colonel General Oleksandr Syrskyi, to the rank of general, a tacit gesture of praise after Ukraine's lightning cross-border incursion into Russia's Kursk region launched on Aug. 6.</p>

<p>Cast by Russia as an escalation and major provocation, Ukraine's incursion has captured more than 90 settlements in the Kursk region according to Kyiv, the biggest invasion of Russia since World War Two.</p>

<p>Speaking at a joint news conference with Poland's and Lithuania's leaders, Mr Zelensky told reporters the operation had in part been a preventive move to stop Russian plans to capture the northern city of Sumy.</p>

<p>Apart from capturing prisoners of war and creating a "buffer zone", Mr Zelensky said the operation had other objectives that he could not disclose publicly.</p>

<p>Independence Day has surged in importance for Ukrainians during the invasion, which has spurred widespread patriotic sentiment.</p>

<p>This year the public holiday took place after the US and German embassies issued warnings of a heightened risk of Russian missile and drone attacks across the country.</p>

<p>There had been no major strikes as of 1800 local time, but the air raid siren sounded in Kyiv late afternoon.</p>

<p>To mark the date, Mr Zelensky ratified the Rome Statute, paving the way for Ukraine to join the International Criminal Court, one of many steps needed to join the European Union, accession to which Kyiv sees as a priority.</p>

<p>He also signed legislation banning the activities of religious groups linked to Russia, creating a legal instrument for the government to ban a branch of the Orthodox Church seen as linked to Russia.</p>

<p>Ukraine and Russia also said they had each secured the release of 115 prisoners of war in an exchange. The Russian Defence Ministry said its freed servicemen had been captured during Ukraine's attack in the Kursk region.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b97l8398_ukraine-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Today Ukraine marks 33 years of post-Soviet independence]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronauts-sunita-williams-barry-butch-wilmore-in-space-for-80-days-will-return-february-next-year-says-nasa-6410618]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From 8 Days To 8 Months: NASA Astronauts To Return From Space Next Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronauts-sunita-williams-barry-butch-wilmore-in-space-for-80-days-will-return-february-next-year-says-nasa-6410618]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 22:51:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two NASA astronauts who flew to the International Space Station in June aboard Boeing's faulty Starliner capsule will need to return to Earth on a SpaceX vehicle early next year, NASA said on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two NASA astronauts who flew to the International Space Station in June aboard Boeing's faulty Starliner capsule will need to return to Earth on a SpaceX vehicle early next year, NASA said on Saturday, deeming issues with Starliner's propulsion system too risky to carry its first crew home.</p>

<p>The agency's decision, tapping Boeing's top space rival to return the astronauts, is one of NASA's most consequential in years. Boeing had hoped the test mission would redeem the Starliner program after years of development problems and over $1.6 billion in budget overruns since 2016.</p>

<p>Boeing is also struggling with quality issues on production of commercial planes, its most important products.</p>

<p>Veteran NASA astronauts <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronaut-sunita-williams-may-have-to-wait-months-in-space-what-nasa-is-planning-now-5994474">Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams</a>, both former military test pilots, became the first crew to ride Starliner on June 5 when they were launched to the ISS for what was expected to be an eight-day test mission.</p>

<p>But<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-barry-wilmore-boeing-starliner-why-nasa-picked-elon-musks-spacex-to-bring-back-astronauts-from-space-6410789"> Starliner's propulsion system suffered a series of glitches</a> beginning in the first 24 hours of its flight to the ISS, triggering months of cascading delays. Five of its 28 thrusters failed and it sprang several leaks of helium, which is used to pressurize the thrusters.</p>

<p>In a rare reshuffling of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-80-days-in-space-why-she-has-not-returned-to-earth-6409042">NASA's astronaut operations</a>, the two astronauts are now expected to return in February 2025 on a SpaceX Crew Dragon spacecraft due to launch next month as part of a routine astronaut rotation mission. Two of the Crew Dragon's four astronaut seats will be kept empty for Wilmore and Williams.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Starliner will undock from the ISS without a crew and attempt to return to Earth as it would have with astronauts aboard.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Boeing struggled for years to develop Starliner, a gumdrop-shaped capsule designed to compete with Crew Dragon as a second U.S. option for sending astronaut crews to and from Earth's orbit.</p>

<p>Starliner failed a 2019 test to launch to the ISS uncrewed, but mostly succeeded in a 2022 do-over attempt where it also encountered thruster problems. Its June mission with its first crew was required before NASA can certify the capsule for routine flights, but now Starliner's crew certification path has been upended.</p>

<p>Since Starliner docked to the ISS in June, Boeing has scrambled to investigate what caused its thruster mishaps and helium leaks. The company arranged tests and simulations on Earth to gather data that it has used to try and convince NASA officials that Starliner is safe to fly the crew back home.</p>

<p>But results from that testing raised more difficult engineering questions and ultimately failed to quell NASA officials' concerns about Starliner's ability to make its crewed return trip - the most daunting and complex part of the test mission.</p>

<p>NASA's decision, and Starliner's now-uncertain path to certification, will add to the crises faced by new Boeing CEO Kelly Ortberg, who started this month with the goal to rebuild the planemaker's reputation after a door panel dramatically blew off a 737 MAX passenger jet in midair in January.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3gtjeop8_sunita-williams_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams are former military test pilots]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-access-to-food-water-migrants-from-india-nepal-stuck-at-brazilian-airport-since-weeks-6410244]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Access To Food: Indian Migrants Stuck For Weeks At Brazilian Airport]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-access-to-food-water-migrants-from-india-nepal-stuck-at-brazilian-airport-since-weeks-6410244]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 21:40:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of migrants from India, Nepal and Vietnam have been stuck in Sao Paulo's international airport for weeks in alarming conditions as they wait to enter Brazil, according to the Public Defender's Office and documents seen by Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of migrants from India, Nepal and Vietnam have been stuck in Sao Paulo's international airport for weeks in alarming conditions, sleeping on the floor as they wait to enter Brazil, according to the Public Defender's Office and documents seen by Reuters on Friday.</p>

<p>A spokesman for the office said a 39-year-old migrant from Ghana died two weeks ago of unknown causes. It was not clear whether he died while retained at the airport or on the way to hospital.</p>

<p>At least 666 migrants without visas were waiting to enter Brazil at Guarulhos airport, the official said, with the added uncertainty that the government plans to tighten entry rules on Monday to stem a flow of foreigners using Brazil as a stopover to get to the United States and Canada.</p>

<p>The migrants are held in a restricted area where there is no access to a shower and their movements are limited, making it hard for them to obtain food and water, while children and adolescents are enduring winter cold with no blankets, the official said.</p>

<p>The Public Defender's Office found that the migrants' human rights were being violated with their health deteriorating.</p>

<p>The agency said conditions for the migrants need to be urgently improved while their status is being resolved, and urged authorities in a statement to comply with Brazil's legislation based on the humanitarian principle of accepting refugees and not returning them to their country of origin.</p>

<p>Starting on Monday, foreign travellers without a Brazilian visa who are headed for another country must travel straight on to their destination or return to their home country, Brazil's public security ministry told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Brazil has seen a boom in foreign travellers, particularly from Asia, landing in the country for a supposed layover en route to North America, the ministry said in statement.</p>

<p>To enter Brazil, they ask for refugee status, alleging persecution and threats in their home countries, but a majority travel north when they can, according to two reports from authorities seen by Reuters and a senior police source.</p>

<p>Now, those passengers arriving in Sao Paulo without a visa will not be allowed to stay in Brazil, the ministry said.</p>

<p>It was not clear whether the new rules will apply to migrants already at the Sao Paulo airport or apply only to those arriving after the rules go into effect.</p>

<p>Immigration experts are concerned that the proposed rules counter the 1951 UN Refugee Convention, to which Brazil is a party and which calls on countries to take in those at risk in their home country, even if they are undocumented.</p>

<p>The head of Brazil's refugee committee, Jean Uema, told Reuters the rules would apply specifically to Sao Paulo airport and there would be no change to Brazil's policy on asylum seekers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qh16tfi_sao-paulo-airport-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brazil has introduced new rules for foreign travellers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singles-in-pakistan-defy-tradition-meet-potential-partners-at-matchmaking-event-6410087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistani Singles Defy Tradition, Meet Potential Partners At Dating Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singles-in-pakistan-defy-tradition-meet-potential-partners-at-matchmaking-event-6410087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 21:14:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of young singles gathered this week to meet potential marriage partners in Pakistan's eastern city of Lahore, the first attempt by a UK-based matrimonial app to help people find spouses in person in the conservative Islamic country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of young singles gathered this week to meet potential marriage partners in Pakistan's eastern city of Lahore, the first attempt by a UK-based matrimonial app to help people find spouses in person in the conservative Islamic country.</p>

<p>Typically, marriages in Pakistan are arranged by parents who look for suitable matches for their children from within their communities or the extended family. Dating apps are generally stigmatised and gender segregation socially and at work remains common in the country of 240 million people.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Lahore event was organised by Muzz, formerly Muzzmatch, which says its app is based on Islamic etiquette. The app is restricted to Muslim users, and, in a nod to traditional values, gives the option of blurring pictures except for specific matches and allows for chaperones to oversee meetings.</p>

<p>Other smaller events are also emerging in the country to challenge traditional matchmaking norms.</p>

<p>Despite criticism online in the past for the app, the Muzz event was attended by about 100 people.</p>

<p>Aimen, a 31-year-old woman who did not want to be further identified, said she used the app on the recommendation of her U.S.-based brother.</p>

<p>"I used the app for two weeks, but then I saw an ad for this event and thought, why not meet people in person?" she told Reuters.</p>

<p>She said that her mother would have accompanied her as a chaperone but couldn't attend because of ill-health.</p>

<p>Muzz, launched in 2015 in the Britain, which also has a sizeable Muslim population, has over 1.5 million users in Pakistan, its second-largest market after Morocco.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moaz, a 27-year-old man, said he has been using Muzz for a year and that he was hopeful of finding a wife through the app.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I do get matches, but they have different priorities," he said adding that girls on the app expect him to involve his parents from the beginning.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"That is not (immediately) possible," he said, stressing the need of getting to know someone before taking the next big step.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Annie's Matchmaking Party, another Lahore event last week, used an algorithm to match 20 young professionals after a selection process and invited them to the meet.</p>

<p>Noor ul Ain Choudhary, the 30-year-old organizer, faced criticism online that her event promoted a "hookup culture". She countered that it aimed to provide a safe space for singles to meet and connect.</p>

<p>"In Pakistan, we've had two options: biased arranged marriages or time-consuming dating apps with no guarantees. Safety during meetings is also a concern," she said.</p>

<p>Abdullah Ahmed, 22, was bullish about in person events and said he was convinced he may have found his perfect match at the Muzz gathering.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The highlight was meeting an amazing girl," he said, beaming with excitement, adding that they instantly clicked and swapped social media handles.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We're both Marvel fans! We're already planning to catch the new Deadpool &amp; Wolverine together," he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/r73i1088_pakistan-matchmaking-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Lahore event was organised by UK-based matrimonial app Muzz]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-africa-to-bomb-island-with-pesticides-to-kill-mice-that-eat-albatrosses-alive-6409987]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Africa To Bomb Island With Pesticides To Kill Albatross-Eating Mice]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-africa-to-bomb-island-with-pesticides-to-kill-mice-that-eat-albatrosses-alive-6409987]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 20:58:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Conservationists said Saturday that they plan to bomb a remote South African island with tonnes of pesticide-laced pellets to kill mice that are eating albatrosses and other seabirds alive.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Conservationists said Saturday that they plan to bomb a remote South African island with tonnes of pesticide-laced pellets to kill mice that are eating albatrosses and other seabirds alive.</p>

<p>Hordes of mice are devouring the eggs of some of the world's most important seabirds that nest on Marion Island, about 2,000 kilometres (1,240 miles) southeast of Cape Town, and have started eating live birds, leading conservationist Mark Anderson said.</p>

<p>This includes the iconic Wandering Albatross, with a quarter of the world's population nesting on the Indian Ocean island.</p>

<p>"The mice have now, for the first time last year, been found to be feeding on adult Wandering Albatrosses," Anderson told a meeting of BirdLife South Africa, the country's leading bird conservation organisation.</p>

<p>Gruesome images presented at the meeting showed bloodied birds, some with flesh chewed off their heads.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Of the 29 species of seabirds that breed on the island, 19 are threatened with local extinction, the Mouse-Free Marion Project said. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Mouse attacks have escalated in recent years but the birds do not know how to respond because they evolved without terrestrial predators, said Anderson, a leader of the project and CEO of BirdLife South Africa.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Mice just climb onto them and just slowly eat them until they succumb," he told AFP. It can take days for a bird to die. "We are losing hundreds of thousands of seabirds every year through the mice."&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Extreme conditions</strong></h3>

<p>Billed as one of the world's most important bird conservation efforts, the Mouse-Free Marion Project has raised about a quarter of the $29 million it needs to send a squad of helicopters to drop 600 tonnes of rodenticide-laced pellets onto the rugged island.</p>

<p>It wants to strike in 2027 in winter, when the mice are most hungry and the summer-breeding birds are largely absent.</p>

<p>The pilots will have to fly in extreme conditions and reach every part of the island, which is about 25 kilometres long and 17 kilometres wide.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We have to get rid of every last mouse," Anderson said. "If there was a male and female remaining, they could breed and eventually get back to where we are now."</p>

<p>The mice are proliferating because warmer temperatures due to climate change means they are breeding more frequently over a longer period, Anderson said. After eating through plants and invertebrates, the mice turned to the birds.</p>

<p>House mice were introduced to the island in the early 1800s. Five cats were brought in around 1948 to control their numbers. But the cat numbers grew to about 2,000 and they were killing about 450,000 birds a year. An eradication project removed the last cat in 1991.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/562kpbl8_albatross_625x300_24_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gruesome images presented at the meeting showed bloodied birds.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beekeepers-in-france-see-catastrophic-year-as-honey-production-falls-6409747]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Beekeepers In France See "Catastrophic" Year As Honey Production Falls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beekeepers-in-france-see-catastrophic-year-as-honey-production-falls-6409747]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 20:16:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Beekeepers across France say it has been a disastrous year for honey, with bees starving to death and production plummeting by up to 80 percent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Beekeepers across France say it has been a disastrous year for honey, with bees starving to death and production plummeting by up to 80 percent.</p>

<p>Mickael Isambert, a beekeeper in Saint-Ours-les-Roches in central France, lost 70 percent of his honey and had to feed his colonies sugar to help them survive after a cold, rainy spring.</p>

<p>"It has been a catastrophic year," said Isambert, 44, who looks after 450 hives.</p>

<p>A beehive typically produces 15 kilos (33 pounds) of honey a year, but this time, Isambert said his farm had only produced between five and seven kilos.</p>

<p>When it rains, bees "don't fly, they don't go out, so they eat their own honey reserves," said his co-manager and fellow beekeeper Marie Mior.</p>

<p>Low temperatures and heavy rainfall have prevented bees from gathering enough pollen, and flowers from producing nectar -- which the insects collect to make honey.</p>

<h3><strong>'Some died of hunger'</strong></h3>

<p>Bad weather has affected honey producers countrywide, with spring production dropping by 80 percent in some regions -- figures that summer harvests will struggle to offset, said the French national beekeeping union (Unaf).</p>

<p>Rainfall rose by 45 percent on the yearly average, Unaf said in a letter to its local branches.</p>

<p>"With weather conditions that have been catastrophic in many regions with abundant rain... and low temperatures until late, many beekeepers' viability is under threat," said Unaf.</p>

<p>Temperatures stagnated below 18 degrees Celsius (64 Fahrenheit), the minimum temperature needed for flowers to produce nectar, said Jean-Luc Hascoet, a beekeeper in Brittany in western France who lost about 15 colonies.</p>

<p>"For some of my colleagues it was worse," he said.</p>

<p>"In June, the bee population increases and the needs of the colonies grow but as nothing was coming in, some died of hunger," said Hascoet.</p>

<h3><strong>'Black year'</strong></h3>

<p>French beekeepers had already been reeling from dealing with several seasons of scorching heat and delayed frosts, according to Unaf president Christian Pons, making this "black year" even worse.</p>

<p>"Ten years ago, I made one and a half to two tons of honey per site, compared to 100 kilos today," said Pons, a beekeeper in the southern Herault region.</p>

<p>Honeymakers earlier this year protested against "unfair competition" by foreign producers, which led to the government releasing five million euros ($5.6 million) in aid.</p>

<p>French consumers eat on average 45,000 tons of honey per year, about 20,000 tons of which is produced in France, according to the left-wing Peasants Confederation union.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lb745i0o_bees-france-afp_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bad weather has affected honey producers across France]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-80-days-in-space-why-she-has-not-returned-to-earth-6409042]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[80 Days On, Why Sunita Williams Is Still In Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-80-days-in-space-why-she-has-not-returned-to-earth-6409042]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 18:18:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In June 2024, when the Boeing Starliner spacecraft carried NASA astronauts Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore to space, it was going to be a short eight-day mission. However, it's been 80 days since the launch and the two astronauts are yet to return.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In June 2024, when the Boeing Starliner spacecraft carried NASA astronauts Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore to space, it was going to be a short eight-day mission. However, it's been 80 days since the launch and the two astronauts are yet to return.<br />
<br />
Launched on June 5, the test flight landed on the International Space Station (ISS) on June 6. Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore are still stuck in space, while the date of their return journey remains undecided. Some technical problems with the Boeing Starliner have left NASA unable to move on with their plans.</p>

<p><strong>What is the mission?</strong></p>

<p>The purpose of the<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-will-sunita-williams-come-back-to-earth-nasa-shares-big-update-6399519"> Boeing Starliner mission was to demonstrate the spacecraft's capability to safely carry people to and from the ISS. </a>As part of NASA's Commercial Crew Program, Boeing, the aerospace company, views this trip as critical to its goal of joining Elon Musk's SpaceX in offering regular crew transportation services to the space agency.<br />
<br />
<strong>Why is the Boeing Starliner still stuck in space?</strong></p>

<p>Helium leaks: The spacecraft's service module reported several tiny helium leaks making it unsafe for travel. Helium is essential to preserving the spacecraft's structural integrity and manoeuvrability.</p>

<p>Thruster problems: The propulsion system of the spaceship experienced malfunctions with five of its thrusters. These components are essential for space travel and docking.<br />
<br />
Valve issues:&nbsp;Multiple issues with a valve responsible for regulating the flow of oxidizers were detected. The valve is essential for propulsion.<br />
<br />
<strong>What is NASA doing?&nbsp;</strong><br />
<br />
<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasas-latest-update-on-sunita-williams-barry-wilmore-return-from-space-when-and-where-to-watch-6407915">NASA</a> and Boeing engineers are attempting to resolve the issues with the spacecraft. They are examining data from the spacecraft's propulsion system and are testing the spacecraft thrusters. Several scenarios are being explored using simulators stationed on the ground to find and address the problems.<br />
<br />
NASA will hold a press conference later on Saturday to update the world on when the two astronauts may return to Earth.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/l3auvipg_sunita-williams_625x300_07_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Launched on June 5, the test flight landed on the International Space Station (ISS) on June 6.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-suspends-us-presidential-campaign-endorses-donald-trump-6408961]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Robert Kennedy Jr Suspends US Presidential Campaign, Endorses Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-suspends-us-presidential-campaign-endorses-donald-trump-6408961]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 18:03:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. said on Friday he would suspend his campaign, and endorsed Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. said on Friday he would suspend his campaign, and endorsed Republican Donald Trump, likely ending a presidential bid that he began as a Democrat trading on one of the most famous names in American politics.</p>

<p>His campaign indicated that he feared staying in the race would siphon support from former President Trump, who is locked in a tight contest with Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris ahead of the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>An environmental lawyer, anti-vaccine activist and son and nephew of two titans of Democratic politics who were assassinated during the turbulent 1960s, Kennedy entered the race in April 2023 as a challenger to President Joe Biden for the Democratic nomination.</p>

<p>With voters at the time turned off by both the aging Biden and the legally embattled Trump, interest in Kennedy soared. He shifted his plans and decided to run as an independent, and a November 2023 Reuters/Ipsos poll showed Kennedy drawing the support of 20% of Americans in a three-way race with Biden and Trump.</p>

<p>He ran a high-profile advertisement during the February 2024 Super Bowl that invoked his father, US Senator Robert F. Kennedy, and uncle, US President John F. Kennedy, and drew outrage from much of his high-profile family, who condemned his campaign.</p>

<p>For a time, both the Biden and Trump campaigns showed signs they were worried that Kennedy could draw enough support to change the election outcome. He faced an uphill battle in winning spots on the ballot as an independent but secured key positions including in Georgia, Michigan, Minnesota and North Carolina -- half of the competitive swing states expected to determine the election's outcome.</p>

<p>But as the race changed quickly in the last two months -- with Trump surviving an assassination attempt and the 81-year-old Biden bowing to pressure from his own party and passing the campaign torch to Harris -- voter interest in Kennedy, 70, waned.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An Ipsos poll early this month showed his national support had fallen to 4%, a tiny number, but one that could still be meaningful in a tight race such as the current Trump-Harris matchup.</p>

<p>His campaign had signaled over the past few days that a change was coming, as Kennedy set his Phoenix address. His running mate Nicole Shanahan said in an interview earlier that if the pair stayed in the race as independents, they could ultimate boost Harris' chances.</p>

<p>In exchange for endorsing Trump, Kennedy was hoping for a job in a potential Trump administration, a super PAC supporting Kennedy told Reuters on Wednesday. He also wanted Trump to allow his political movement to continue in some fashion, which could include staying on the ballot in some states.</p>

<p>Kennedy painted himself as a political outsider. He told Reuters in an interview in March that if elected president he would not restrict abortion, would repeal many provisions of Biden's signature Inflation Reduction Act and would seek to close down the southern border to immigrants entering the US illegally. He also offered staunch support for Israel.</p>

<p>Trump mega-donor Timothy Mellon, an 82-year-old banking heir, has given millions of dollars this election cycle in support of Kennedy, and given $75 million in support of Trump, according to Federal Election Commission filings through July 31.</p>

<p>Shanahan has donated over $15 million to the Kennedy campaign, FEC filings showed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a video of a phone call posted online last month, Trump suggested to Kennedy that the independent candidate could do something to support the Trump campaign. Soon after, both candidates spoke a day apart from each other at a bitcoin conference in Nashville, trying to court votes.</p>

<p><strong>BEAR, BRAIN WORMS &nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Kennedy said this month in a video posted online that he dumped a dead bear in New York City's Central Park a decade ago and staged it to look like a bike had hit it. He proclaimed he had "so many skeletons in my closet" after a former family babysitter accused him of sexual assault. He denied that a picture of him posing with the barbecued carcass of a large animal belonged to a canine.</p>

<p>And then there was the brain worm. Kennedy had a parasite in his brain more than a decade ago, but has since fully recovered, a fact unearthed by the New York Times and confirmed by the campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Those stories prompted ridicule from late-night talk show hosts.</p>

<p>The Democratic Party especially has been ruthless in their opposition to Kennedy's candidacy including waging legal challenges against his ballot access, as concern grew that Kennedy could hurt the party's chances in November.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e4jkrhng_rfk-jr-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Robert F Kennedy Jr entered the race in April 2023 as a challenger to President Joe Biden. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starbucks-in-us-new-mexico-nicknamed-charbucks-after-2-arson-attacks-6408851]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Starbucks In US' New Mexico Nicknamed "Charbucks" After 2 Arson Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starbucks-in-us-new-mexico-nicknamed-charbucks-after-2-arson-attacks-6408851]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:48:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After two arson attacks at a Starbucks construction site in Taos, New Mexico, a developer is trying again to build the chain's first drive-through cafe in the mountain town with a history of revolts and opposition by some to national chains.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After two arson attacks at a Starbucks construction site in Taos, New Mexico, a developer is trying again to build the chain's first drive-through cafe in the mountain town with a history of revolts and opposition by some to national chains. &nbsp;</p>

<p>It did not take long for locals in this community of 6,500 to come up with a nickname for the would-be coffee shop: "Charbucks." Meanwhile, the building contractor from Albuquerque, the state's largest city, has installed video cameras and a security guard sleeps at the site in a camouflage trailer.</p>

<p>Just over a mile north of the site of the store, which Starbucks hopes to open in the spring of 2025, patrons at one of Taos' oldest independent coffee shops are tight-lipped about the attacks.</p>

<p>"We don't know who did it, but we loved it," said Todd Lazar, a holistic healer, as he chatted with other regulars on a bench outside the World Cup, just off Taos' central plaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Their conversation echoes criticism Starbucks faced as it moved into Europe and Asia that the US coffee chain clashes with local culture and will shovel money out of communities. Starbucks operates or licenses around 39,500 cafes worldwide.</p>

<p>Stickers plastered on locally owned businesses show the Starbucks logo - which features a mermaid - on fire, with the mermaid's face replaced by La Calavera Catrina, a skull character associated with Mexico's Day of the Dead and that country's national identity.</p>

<p>After the first fire in August 2023, the word "NO" preceded by an expletive was spray-painted on the partially burned structure intended to be a Starbucks.</p>

<p>From the 1680 Indigenous Pueblo Revolt against Spanish settlement, to the 1847 Taos Revolt against US occupation and more recently an arson attack on a development tycoon and opposition to a billionaire's ski resort development, Taos locals have resisted outside forces.</p>

<p>"Taos is a dynamic and volatile contact zone between different groups, imperial powers, ecotones," said Sylvia Rodriguez, emerita professor of anthropology at the University of New Mexico who has conducted research on her home town of Taos for decades.</p>

<p>Located 7,000 feet (2,134 meters) above sea level in northern New Mexico's high mountain desert, Taos is known for its UNESCO World Heritage Site Native American settlement, art scene and steep ski runs.</p>

<p>The area also has deep social inequalities and disconnect between Indigenous, Hispano - descendants of colonial settlers - and other communities, with New Mexico's highest property crime rate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>People like Lazar complain that a wave of remote workers during and after the pandemic are driving demand for national chains and exacerbating housing shortages common in US West resort towns.</p>

<p>Taos' town council supported the store on grounds it would provide employment and tax revenue, according to Christopher Larsen, the town's economic development director</p>

<p><strong>"NOT COOL"</strong></p>

<p>World Cup owner Andrea Meyer said jobs were not the problem.</p>

<p>"People are showing up saying 'I'd love to work here, I can't afford to live here,'" said Meyer, who runs a cash-only cafe with no Wi-Fi so as to encourage patrons to talk to one other. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>Few working households can afford Taos' average home price of $460,000. Around a third of housing units sit vacant, some as second homes and vacation dwellings, others after traditional Hispano families left the area, or other factors, according to census data. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Two or three national chains pulled out of Taos projects after Starbucks burned a second time on Oct. 23, 2023, according to Larsen.</p>

<p>"The feeling is that Taos doesn't want corporate America," he said.</p>

<p>Starbucks spokesman Sam Jefferies said employee safety was its top priority and it would work closely with police once the store opened. No one has been injured in the fires.</p>

<p>The town has licensed Starbucks outlets in two supermarkets. Jefferies said the performance of cafes in nearby towns was a factor in opening a Taos store. &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Based on news reports over the last three decades, Taos appears to be the only place in the world where a future Starbucks cafe has been burned to the ground.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Neither contractor Hart Construction nor Arizona-based developer and building owner Clint Jameson responded to requests for comment. On his company website, Jameson, who plans to lease the property to Starbucks, describes himself as "relentless" and a "development maverick."</p>

<p>The town and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) have offered a $30,000 reward for information on the fires. Police believe they know the culprit, or culprits, but lack evidence to place them at the site during the blazes, Larsen said. Taos Police Chief John Wentz declined to comment. ATF spokesman Cody Monday said the agency continued following leads and searching for the suspect or suspects.</p>

<p>At the Coffee Apothecary a mile south of the town's central plaza, owner Pablo Flores vouched for demand for Starbucks-like drinks such as iced caramel frappes, which he tells disappointed customers he does not serve.</p>

<p>The specialty coffee roaster lamented the cookie-cutter sameness of national chains sprouting south of town but abhorred their destruction. He saw the fires as an example of how dialogue has broken down amid political polarization across the country.</p>

<p>"Taos is changing and if you don't like the way it's changing, do not support that business," said Flores, whose family has lived in Taos for generations. "Don't burn it down, that's not cool."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7uqe0ng_new-mexico-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The site of a future drive-through Starbucks store in Taos, New Mexico.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-swap-115-prisoners-of-war-in-uae-brokered-deal-6408760]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia, Ukraine Swap 115 Prisoners Of War Each In UAE-Brokered Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-swap-115-prisoners-of-war-in-uae-brokered-deal-6408760]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:34:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia and Ukraine announced Saturday they had exchanged 115 prisoners of war each, just over two weeks after Kyiv launched a surprise incursion into Russia's Kursk region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia and Ukraine announced Saturday they had exchanged 115 prisoners of war each, just over two weeks after Kyiv launched a surprise incursion into Russia's Kursk region.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The exchange came as Kyiv mounts its offensive in Kursk and as Russia eyes more east Ukrainian towns. It also came on Ukrainian Independence Day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Both countries thanked the United Arab Emirates, who said it mediated the swap deal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Another 115 of our defenders have returned home today. These are soldiers of the National Guard, the Armed Forces, the Navy, the State Border Guard Service," Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He published photographs of men wrapped in Ukrainian flags.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kyiv had said it had taken hundreds of Russian soldiers captive in its Kursk incursion launched on August 6.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moscow confirmed the exchange and said it had returned 115 soldiers taken captive in Kursk:&nbsp;</p>

<p>"As a result of a negotiation process, 115 Russian servicemen taken prisoner in the Kursk region have been returned from territories controlled by the Kyiv regime," the Russian defence ministry said. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The ministry said the troops were currently in neighbouring Belarus, where they are receiving "psychological-medical help" and will be brought to Russia soon.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It released images of the men near busses in a field.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The United Arab Emirates said it had "successfully mediated a new captives exchange between the Russian Federation and the republic of Ukraine."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kyiv and Moscow have held rounds of prisoner exchanges throughout the more than two-year war.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rlo0o4mo_ukraine-pow_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky posted photographs of men wrapped in Ukrainian flags]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-in-knife-attack-during-street-festival-in-germany-6408590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Killed In Knife Attack During Street Festival In Germany]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-in-knife-attack-during-street-festival-in-germany-6408590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:01:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German police on Saturday stepped up a major hunt for a man who stabbed three people to death and wounded eight others at a street festival in the city of Solingen, authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German police on Saturday stepped up a major hunt for a man who stabbed three people to death and wounded eight others at a street festival in the city of Solingen, authorities said.</p>

<p>Police closed off the centre of Solingen after the attack on Friday night at the city's "Festival of Diversity". A police statement said five of the wounded were in "serious" condition.</p>

<p>Special forces were helping security personnel in the city centre while a helicopter flew overhead, according to an AFP journalist.</p>

<p>"Our security authorities are doing everything they can to catch the perpetrator" of the "horrific act", Interior Minister Nancy Faeser said, with Chancellor Olaf Scholz saying he "must be caught quickly and punished".</p>

<p>Thousands of people had gathered in front of a stage on the first night of the "Festival of Diversity", part of a series of events to mark Solingen's 650th anniversary, when the killing started.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"An unidentified man attacked several people with a knife around 9.40 pm (1940 GMT)," said the statement released by police in the nearby city of Duesseldorf.</p>

<p>"Police are currently searching for the perpetrator with a large contingent," it added, encouraging witnesses to send them photos, videos and any other information about the attack.</p>

<p><strong>'A person fell'</strong></p>

<p>"Out of nowhere, a man armed with a knife stabbed people at random and killed them," regional interior minister Herbert Reul said in comments at the scene.</p>

<p>"Why? Nobody knows. We cannot say anything yet about the motive," he added.</p>

<p>Witness Lars Breitzke told the Solinger Tageblatt newspaper he was a few metres from the attack, not far from the festival stage, and "understood from the expression on the singer's face that something was wrong".</p>

<p>"And then, a metre away from me, a person fell," said Breitzke, who at first thought it was someone who had too much to drink.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When he turned around, he saw other people lying on the ground amid pools of blood.</p>

<p>In a statement, Solingen mayor Tim-Oliver Kurzbach said the whole city was in "shock, horror and great grief".</p>

<p>"We all wanted to celebrate our town's anniversary together and now we have to mourn the dead and injured," he said.</p>

<p><strong>'Brutal and senseless'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>"It tears my heart apart that there was an attack on our city. I have tears in my eyes when I think of those we have lost. I pray for all those who are still fighting for their lives," he said.</p>

<p>Hendrik Wuest, the premier of North Rhine-Westphalia state, also expressed his "shock and grief" in a post on social media platform X.</p>

<p>"An act of the most brutal and senseless violence has struck at the heart of our state," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The whole of North Rhine-Westphalia stands by the people of Solingen, especially the victims and their families."</p>

<p>Solingen is a city of some 150,000 people located between Duesseldorf and Cologne.</p>

<p>People had gathered in the town on Friday evening for the first day of the three-day "Festival of Diversity".</p>

<p>It was set to feature music, street theatre, variety shows and comedians in the city centre and several other areas, it said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Up to 75,000 visitors had been expected to attend.</p>

<p><strong>Festival cancelled&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The Solinger Tageblatt said one of the festival organisers went on stage to announce it was cancelled.</p>

<p>Thousands of people cleared the area, the paper reported, with a journalist at the scene describing the atmosphere as "ghostly".</p>

<p>"People left the scene in shock, but calmly," Philipp Mueller, one of the organisers, told the newspaper.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mueller said the rest of the festival would also be cancelled.</p>

<p>Germany has seen a series of knife attacks over the past 12 months, with the government promising to crack down on knife crime.</p>

<p>A police officer was killed and five people were wounded in a knife attack at a far-right rally in the city of Mannheim in May.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-10/23l1m92g_knife-attack-pixabay-650_625x300_15_October_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rest of the festival has been cancelled after the attack, the organiser said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-activists-block-parts-of-norway-gas-plant-6408466]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greta Thunberg, Activists Block Parts Of Norway Gas Plant In Protest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-activists-block-parts-of-norway-gas-plant-6408466]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 16:41:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protesters including Swedish activist Greta Thunberg and members of Extinction Rebellion on Saturday tried to blockade of a gas and oil processing plant in southwest Norway.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protesters including Swedish activist Greta Thunberg and members of Extinction Rebellion on Saturday tried to blockade of a gas and oil processing plant in southwest Norway.</p>

<p>In a post to social media, Extinction Rebellion Norway said eight kayaks and three motorboats had entered a security zone outside the Karsto processing plant to "prevent the normal operation of tankers."</p>

<p>Activists, including Thunberg, also gathered on land to block the facility's gates.</p>

<p>"We cannot stand idly by as the fossil fuel industry robs people of their lives and destabilises our life support systems," Thunberg was quoted saying in the post.</p>

<p>The Karsto plant is operated by Norway's Equinor and is the largest of its kind in Europe, according to the company.</p>

<p>According to Equinor, around 30 oil and gas fields are connected to the plant. A company spokeswoman confirm the protest had been started.</p>

<p>"A group of activists have gathered outside parts of the facility, but at this stage the plant is operating as normal," Ellen Maria Skjelbaek told AFP.</p>

<p>Skjelbaek said police were dealing with the protest.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/hf91jsp_greta-protest-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The gas company's spokesperson said the police were dealing with the protest]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasas-latest-update-on-sunita-williams-barry-wilmore-return-from-space-when-and-where-to-watch-6407915]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA's Latest Update On Sunita Williams' Return: When And Where To Watch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasas-latest-update-on-sunita-williams-barry-wilmore-return-from-space-when-and-where-to-watch-6407915]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 15:12:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Boeing's first crewed Starliner test flight, carrying NASA astronauts Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore, has been stuck in space for the past two months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Boeing's first crewed Starliner test flight, carrying NASA astronauts Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore, has been stuck in space for the past two months. The journey, originally an eight-day mission, has now completed 80 days in space.</p>

<p>NASA officials will provide an update on the mission on Saturday, August 24, detailing their strategy for bringing the astronauts back to Earth. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/leadership-to-discuss-nasas-boeing-crew-flight-test/">The press conference is set for Saturday at 1 p.m. EDT (1700 GMT)</a>. It will be headlined by NASA Administrator Bill Nelson along with other agency representatives. You can watch the live telecast on the NASA app and its YouTube channel at 10:30 pm IST.</p>

<p>Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore were sent on an eight-day mission to the International Space Station (ISS) on June 5. However, the pair's return was postponed indefinitely due to helium leaks and many thruster malfunctions on the spacecraft.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To comprehend the technical issues, NASA and Boeing have collected information about the spacecraft's helium and propulsion systems from both space and the ground.</p>

<p>According to the official statement, the review scheduled for later on Saturday will cover a mission status report, closeout actions, and a review of technical data. It will also certify flight rationale to proceed with undocking and return from the space station.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore have integrated with the rest of the crew currently aboard the International Space Station and are conducting routine tasks.</p>

<p>As part of its private Crew Program, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-will-sunita-williams-come-back-to-earth-nasa-shares-big-update-6399519">NASA selected two private spacecraft</a>, Boeing's Starliner and SpaceX's Crew Dragon capsule, to transport astronauts to and from the International Space Station. The present trip of Boeing's Starliner, the Crew Flight Test, is the company's first of at least six scheduled crewed missions for NASA under the multibillion-dollar contract. SpaceX has performed nine crewed flights for NASA since 2020 apart from numerous private missions of its own).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/m7e2cer_sunita-williams_625x300_29_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore were sent on an eight-day mission to ISS (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tributes-pour-in-for-hannah-lynch-business-tycoon-mike-lynchs-daughter-killed-in-yacht-tragedy-6407360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["She Loved Life": UK Billionaire's Daughter Dies In Sicily Yacht Wreck]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tributes-pour-in-for-hannah-lynch-business-tycoon-mike-lynchs-daughter-killed-in-yacht-tragedy-6407360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 15:04:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British business tycoon Mike Lynch and his 18-year-old daughter Hannah Lynch were killed after their luxury yacht Bayesian sank during a storm off the coast of Sicily on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British business tycoon Mike Lynch and his 18-year-old daughter Hannah Lynch were killed after their luxury yacht Bayesian sank during a storm off the coast of Sicily on Monday. On Friday, search divers recovered the seventh and final body from the sunken superyacht, reported <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/23/hannah-lynch-body-found-sicily-yacht/">The Washington Post</a>.</p>

<p>Cosimo Nicastro, a spokesman for the Italian Coast Guard, confirmed the identity of the victim as Hannah. I can confirm it to you, the last victim inside the hull has been found, he said. Mike's trial lawyer Christopher Morvillo, his trial witness Jonathan Bloomer, and three others were also killed in the tragedy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hannah Lynch's sister, Esme said that Hannah often burst into my bedroom and lay down with me, adding no matter what, she brought boundless love. "She was endlessly caring, passionately mad, unintentionally hilarious and the most amazing, supportive, and joyful sister and best friend to me," she said.</p>

<p>She had even more love to give endlessly to all her friends and passion to give to her incredible studies and goals, Esme told The Guardian. "She is my little angel, my star."</p>

<p>On behalf of the Lynch family, a spokesperson said they were devastated, in shock, and were being comforted and supported by family and friends. "Their thoughts are with everyone affected by the tragedy. They would like to sincerely thank the Italian coastguard, emergency services and all those who helped in the rescue. Their one request now is that their privacy be respected at this time of unspeakable grief," the statement added.</p>

<p>Jon Mitropoulos-Monk, Hannah Lynch's English professor at Latymer Upper School in West London was all praises for his student. He said he taught Hannah for four years and would remember her for what she taught him "kindness, compassion, and commitment".</p>

<p>She said she had never taught someone who "combined sky-high intellectual ability with warmth and enthusiasm" like Hannah did. She lit up the classroom with her energy, passion for learning, the teacher said about the 18-year-old.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Calling the 18-year-old one of the best English students in the country, she told the English&nbsp;daily, By age 16, she'd read Joyce, Faulkner and Nabokov  She loved literature, learning and life. She was so excited to start studying English at Oxford, a goal she had worked so hard towards."</p>

<p>When she got her place, she sought out every single member of the Latymer upper English department to thank them individually and give them a hug, the teacher added.</p>

<p>Hannah Lynch's friends had nothing but kind words for their friend. The love Hannah had for everything she held dear was passionate and pure, said Katya Lewis, adding her friend had a warm and beautiful soul.</p>

<p>"When I think of Hannah, I think of poetry, sunshine and her beautiful eyes," said Hannah's classmate, Gracie Lea.&nbsp;"She was easy to love: sincere, dedicated, fiercely intelligent and genuinely kind. I'll always remember her smiling."</p>

<p>Not long after the Bayesian sank, fifteen people, including Angela Bacares, Hannah Lynch's mother, were saved. During the preliminary search, Recaldo Thomas, the yacht pilot, was found dead.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0svm1r5g_hannah-lynch-_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hannah Lynch's friends had nothing but kind words for their friend.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mike-lynch-yacht-italy-opens-manslaughter-inquiry-in-uk-tycoon-mike-lynch-yacht-sinking-6407720]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Italy Opens Manslaughter Inquiry In UK Tycoon Mike Lynch Yacht Sinking]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mike-lynch-yacht-italy-opens-manslaughter-inquiry-in-uk-tycoon-mike-lynch-yacht-sinking-6407720]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 14:45:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Italian prosecutor has opened a manslaughter investigation into the deaths of British tech magnate Mike Lynch and six other people who were killed when a luxury yacht sank off Sicily this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Italian prosecutor has opened a manslaughter investigation into the deaths of British tech magnate Mike Lynch and six other people who were killed when a luxury yacht sank off Sicily this week.</p>

<p>The public prosecutor's office of Termini Imerese, headed by Ambrogio Cartosio, announced the investigation, saying the probe was not aimed at any individual person.</p>

<p>Lynch's 18-year-old daughter, Hannah, was also among those who died when the family's 56-metre-long (184-foot) boat, the Bayesian, capsized during a fierce, pre-dawn storm on Monday off Porticello, near Palermo.</p>

<p>Fifteen people survived, including Lynch's wife, whose company owned the Bayesian, and the yacht's captain.</p>

<p>The captain, James Cutfield, and the other survivors have been questioned by the coast guard on behalf of prosecutors. None of them have commented publicly on how the ship went down.</p>

<p>Hannah Lynch's body was discovered on Friday by divers who scoured the submerged vessel for the past five days. The five other dead passengers were recovered on Wednesday and Thursday, while the body of the only crew member who died, onboard chef Recaldo Thomas, was found on Monday.</p>

<p>The sinking has puzzled naval marine experts who say a boat like the Bayesian, built by Italian high-end yacht manufacturer Perini, should have withstood the storm and in any case should not have sunk as quickly as it did.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mh8ts768_mike-lynch_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fifteen people survived, including Mike Lynch's wife]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modi-arrives-in-delhi-after-concluding-his-visit-to-poland-ukraine-6407374]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Arrives In Delhi After Concluding His Visit To Poland, Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modi-arrives-in-delhi-after-concluding-his-visit-to-poland-ukraine-6407374]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 14:07:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi arrived at Palam airport in Delhi today after concluding his two-nation visit to Poland and Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi arrived at Palam airport in Delhi today after concluding his two-nation visit to Poland and Ukraine.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi's visit to Poland was the first by an Indian Prime Minister in 45 years. It was also the first Prime Ministerial visit from India to Ukraine.</p>

<p>During his visit to Ukraine, PM Modi and President Volodymyr Zelenskyy reiterated their readiness for further cooperation in upholding principles of international law, including the UN Charter.</p>

<p>They agreed on the desirability of closer bilateral dialogue in this regard.</p>

<p>The Indian side reiterated its principled position and focus on peaceful resolution through dialogue and diplomacy, as a part of which, India has attended the Summit on Peace in Ukraine, held in Burgenstock, Switzerland, in June 2024.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian side welcomed such participation by India and highlighted the importance of high-level Indian participation in the next Peace Summit.</p>

<p>India and Ukraine signed four agreements during the visit.</p>

<p>During his visit to Poland, PM Modi held bilateral discussions with his counterpart Donald Tusk. The two countries decided to elevate their ties to "Strategic Partnership".</p>

<p>The two leaders expressed their deepest concern over the war raging in Ukraine including its terrible and tragic humanitarian consequences.</p>

<p>They reiterated the need for a comprehensive, just, and lasting peace in line with international law, consistent with the purposes and principles of the UN Charter.</p>

<p>They also noted the negative impacts of the war in Ukraine with regard to global food and energy security, especially for the Global South.</p>

<p>In the context of this war, they shared the view that the use, or threat of use, of nuclear weapons is unacceptable.</p>

<p>Russia and Ukraine have been engaged in a conflict for nearly two-and-a-half years.</p>

<p>India and Poland also reiterated their unequivocal condemnation of terrorism in all its forms and manifestations and emphasised that no country should provide a safe haven to those who finance, plan, support or commit terrorist acts.</p>

<p>Both sides stressed the need for firm implementation of relevant resolutions of the UN Security Council, the UN General Assembly, as well as the implementation of the UN Global Counter-Terrorism Strategy. They also reaffirmed on the early adoption of the Comprehensive Convention on International Terrorism (CCIT).</p>

<p>The two sides reinforced their commitment to a free, open and rules-based Indo-Pacific in accordance with the international law of the sea as reflected in UNCLOS and with full respect for the sovereignty, territorial integrity and freedom of navigation to the benefit of the maritime security and international peace and stability.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0upebbhg_narendra-modi-plane-pti_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi arrived in Delhi today after concluding his two-nation visit to Poland and Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exclusive-bangladesh-social-welfare-adviser-sharmeen-murshid-on-growth-minorities-and-neighbourhood-6407480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Bangladesh Top Adviser On Growth, Minorities And Neighbourhood]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exclusive-bangladesh-social-welfare-adviser-sharmeen-murshid-on-growth-minorities-and-neighbourhood-6407480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 14:04:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh is carrying out "fundamental, philosophical" reforms to bring back the country on the path of growth after living through years of entrenched corruption under the now ousted Awami League government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh is carrying out "fundamental, philosophical" reforms to bring back the country on the path of growth after living through years of entrenched corruption under the now ousted Awami League government led by former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, the country's new adviser for social welfare told NDTV in an exclusive interview.</p>

<p>Sharmeen Murshid, who is one of the top advisers assisting Muhammad Yunus, the chief of the caretaker government, gave her insight into a wide range of critical issues that her country must tackle before it can finally leave the painful past firmly behind.</p>

<p>"The priority is to bring back law and order, and create conditions to hold proper, democratic elections, creating conditions of good governance and bringing normalcy," Ms Murshid told NDTV.</p>

<p>She said one of the indicators of Bangladesh returning to normal is the rise in remittance collections this month, which signals confidence among people in Bangladesh's ability to recover from political and economic turmoil.</p>

<p>"There is a reform agenda. In the past year, our understanding of our economy had been so hinged on misinformation. GDP (gross domestic product) rates were not truthful; we knew there was inflation, but never knew the rates. We had been seen dwindling foreign reserves... That was the situation we were living through. Very soon - it is not time yet to give you a large announcement - I can assure you that basic, fundamental changes are about to happen," Ms Murshid said.</p>

<p>"This month, we had the highest collection of remittances in the last three years. And I see that as a confidence that people show towards this government, and also an indicator that we are returning to stable ground," she added.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9tj5o3h8_bangladesh-_625x300_24_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>She credited the Nobel laureate Mr Yunus' track record and his acceptance in the international community as a strong point for Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"I would like to urge the credibility of our chief adviser is also a major factor. The acceptability both internationally among governments and institutions and our people who are now geared and so motivated in rebuilding the country and the economy, I think we are on the right track. Of course, no one said it is going to be easy. I think we are returning on strong ground," Ms Murshid told NDTV.</p>

<p><strong>On Attacks On Minorities</strong></p>

<p>Ms Murshid, while accepting there have been attacks on minorities in Bangladesh, denied large-scale targeting of minorities on religious grounds. Instead, she said, the violence reported from across Bangladesh was linked to political affiliation and not communal.</p>

<p>Lakhs of Hindus had taken to the streets in Bangladesh on August 11 to protest against attacks on the community after Ms Hasina resigned as Prime Minister and fled to India.</p>

<p>"The insecurity of vulnerable groups - call them minorities if you like - this government is making fundamental, philosophical changes. For example, we do not want to refer to anybody as minority. As professor Yunus said, we are one family. The violence that took place in specific categories have been because of the political turmoil. It was never because of communalism. This is where Indian media needs to come to Bangladesh," Ms Murshid told NDTV.</p>

<p>"There are certain categories of communities that belong to certain political parties. The regime that has just been dethroned, a large portion of the so-called minorities, actually had loyalty towards that political party. Mind you, in this change and shift, the violence that Awami League perpetrated on its own people have caused certain backlash against the Awami League as a party and its cadre who have systematically killed people. You must see it in that frame of reference, not in the frame of minorities as Hindus," the social welfare adviser said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/olckobog_bangladeshprotest_625x300_24_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>"We Are Not A Communal Nation"</strong></p>

<p>"Even yesterday, our young people, people from the masjids have been protecting temples and communities. That doesn't mean some lapses haven't happened. I won't say that. Some lapses have happened. But you must understand that we are not a communal nation. It is politics that use communalism to create communalism. We will rectify that, we will not allow that to happen," she said.</p>

<p>"I would like to request the Indian audience, please be sensitive about this. Remember, in this region of South Asia, we have had a long history of communal struggles. Anything that happens in India affects us. If there is violence on Christians, Muslims, Manipuris in your country, then that has direct impact on security in my country. I think when you ask me about future policies, I think they must be much more compassionate, much more understanding, much more sensitive. We need to work towards that together," Ms Murshid told NDTV.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, 76, resigned as Bangladesh's Prime Minister earlier this month following weeks of deadly protests that began as demonstrations by students against government job quotas, but surged into a movement demanding her resignation.</p>

<p>She had retained power for a fourth straight term in an election in January boycotted by the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), which had accused her Awami League of trying to legitimise sham elections.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's flagging economy, once among the world's fastest growing on the back of the country's booming garments sector, has stagnated. Inflation hovers around 10 per cent and dollar reserves are shrinking.</p>

<p>After Ms Hasina left the country, the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement proposed the name of Mr Yunus to head the country.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cli9gksg_sharmeen-murshid_625x300_24_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh social welfare adviser Sharmeen Murshid speaks to NDTV]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-fails-to-sway-pro-palestine-critics-may-impact-presidential-bid-6406934]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Fails To Sway Pro-Palestine Critics, May Impact Presidential Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-fails-to-sway-pro-palestine-critics-may-impact-presidential-bid-6406934]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 12:22:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disappointed Pro-Palestinian activists said Kamala Harris' speech to close the Democratic convention in Chicago failed to demonstrate any break from the status quo, after a week in which the most divisive issue facing the party was mostly ignored.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disappointed Pro-Palestinian activists said Kamala Harris' speech to close the Democratic convention in Chicago failed to demonstrate any break from the status quo, after a week in which the most divisive issue facing the party was mostly ignored.</p>

<p>Under pressure to respond to critics of US support for Israel's war in Gaza, the vice president used her Thursday night speech to repeat earlier calls for a ceasefire and a hostages deal. She said she supported Israel's right to defend itself while also favouring the Palestinian right to self-determination.</p>

<p>Abbas Alawieh, co-founder of the Uncommitted National Movement that mobilised more than 750,000 voters to protest US policy on Israel, said Harris missed an opportunity to win over those people, many of whom live in battleground states such as Michigan, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania and Arizona.</p>

<p>"What's needed in this moment is courageous leadership that breaks from the current approach," Alawieh told Reuters shortly after Harris formally accepted the party's nomination.</p>

<p>Uncommitted delegates and their allies had pushed unsuccessfully for a prime-time speaking slot at the Democratic National Convention (DNC) to address the latest bloodshed in the decades old Israeli-Palestinian conflict, which began on October 7 when Hamas attacked Israel, killing about 1,200, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's assault on Hamas-governed Gaza, with the aid of US support, has since killed 40,000 Palestinians, Gaza health officials say, along with displacing nearly its entire 2.3 million population, causing a hunger crisis and flattening almost the entire enclave.</p>

<p>Rima Mohammad, an Uncommitted delegate from Michigan, said the speech added to disappointment over the DNC's refusal to let a Palestinian speak, and offered nothing to assuage the concerns of her progressive, diverse community in Ann Arbor.</p>

<p>"I'm actually more concerned now," Mohammad said. "This is just a bad look. You're going to lose Michigan."</p>

<p>A campaign spokesperson declined to explain the decision not to schedule a speech by a Palestinian speaker at the DNC. The decision was made by DNC organisers in close consultation with the Harris campaign, sources familiar with the discussions said.</p>

<p>Party insiders fear the Gaza war could cost Harris needed votes in battleground states such as Michigan, which is home to large Muslim and Arab American populations and college campuses that have been the site of Gaza protests.</p>

<p>The convention was held in Chicago, home to the United States' largest Palestinian community, according to the Arab American Institute.</p>

<p>The DNC faced pro-Palestinian protests each day in Chicago, including thousands of demonstrators on Thursday night ahead of Harris' speech. Dozens of arrests were made during the week.</p>

<p>Protesters carried banners that read "No Embargo No Vote" and "No Ceasefire No Vote," while thousands chanted "Ceasefire now," and "Long live Palestine."</p>

<p>"Leading with Israel's right to defend itself in the wake of 40,000 massacred Palestinians is absolutely tone deaf," said Hatem Abudayyeh, spokesperson for the Coalition to March on the DNC and National Chair of the US Palestinian Community Network, who said Harris simply repeated President Joe Biden's positions.</p>

<p>"Harris said nothing new," he said. "We continue to demand that the US and Harris implement an arms embargo and stop sending weapons and all other aid to Israel."</p>

<p>Mohammad, Alawieh and other Uncommitted delegates spent the previous night on the sidewalk outside the convention to protest the DNC's rejection of their request for a Palestinian speaker.</p>

<p>They welcomed a call for a ceasefire and the return of hostages by the parents of one US hostage held in Gaza - Rachel Goldberg and Jon Polin - on Wednesday night, but said they should also have been given a chance to speak.</p>

<p>Pro-Palestinian protesters and delegates said they were heartened by messages of solidarity from the United Auto Workers union and the Movement for Black Lives, a network of over 150 leaders and organizations. Muslim Women for Harris-Walz said on X it would cease operations after the DNC decision.</p>

<p>Ruwa Romman, a Georgia state legislator and delegate who spent the night outside the DNC, said Uncommitted organizers had negotiated with the Harris campaign for weeks and provided a list of possible speakers, only to be rejected.</p>

<p>Prior to Harris' remarks, only a handful of speakers even addressed the war, including Biden, Senators Bernie Sanders and Raphael Warnock, and Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez.</p>

<p>One major Harris campaign donor, who requested anonymity to be candid about their private conversations with the campaign, said they worried that without a near-term ceasefire deal and clear statements from Harris about ending the war and protecting civilians, campus protests could flare again when universities resume classes in coming days.</p>

<p>"We need every vote," the donor said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ll6tujj8_gaza-protest-kamala-harris-_625x300_24_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US and Kamala Harris must stop sending weapons to Israel, say protestors (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-f-kennedy-jr-quits-white-house-race-a-look-at-his-bizarre-campaign-6406892]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Robert F Kennedy Jr Ends White House Bid, A Look At His Bizarre Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-f-kennedy-jr-quits-white-house-race-a-look-at-his-bizarre-campaign-6406892]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 12:19:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Robert F Kennedy Jr said he would suspend his campaign and endorsed Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Independent presidential candidate Robert F Kennedy Jr said on Friday he would suspend his campaign, and endorsed Republican Donald Trump. Robert, the nephew of former President John F Kennedy and the son of Senior Robert F Kennedy, projected himself as an alternative to Donald Trump for the Republican Party in the US. And despite his persistently poor polling numbers, Mr Kennedy was regularly featured in the news cycle, often for bizarre reasons.</p>

<p>Before suspending his White House bid and endorsing the former US President, Ms Kennedy ran a campaign filled with what many have described as outrageous moments.<br />
<br />
<strong>Brain worm</strong><br />
<br />
In May, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/08/us/rfk-jr-brain-health-memory-loss.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">The New York Times reported</a> that Mr Kennedy believed he had a brain tumor, which was actually the work of a hungry parasite. In a 2012 deposition during divorce proceedings from his second wife, he said that a physician thought an anomaly in his brain scans "was caused by a worm that got into my brain and ate a portion of it and then died." He indicated that he had been suffering from extreme mental haze and memory loss, which had reduced his earning potential.<br />
<br />
<strong>Kennedy's response to sexual assault allegations</strong><br />
<br />
In July,&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/story/robert-kennedy-jr-shocking-history" rel="nofollow,noindex">a Vanity Fair piece</a> claimed that Mr Kennedy sexually assaulted a former babysitter for the family. Mr Kennedy's response to the accusations can hardly be considered an apology. During his appearance on the podcast Breaking Point, he said, The [Vanity Fair] article is a lot of garbage. Listen, I have said this from the beginning. I am not a church boy. I am not running like that." Later, he claimed to have texted Cooney to express regret for his actions.<br />
<br />
<strong>Eating dogs</strong><br />
<br />
The same article featured a photo of Mr Kennedy grinning and pretending to bite on what looked like a grilled dog carcass.&nbsp;In an interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://youtu.be/kedriuDH5o0?si=QvHhtU5PbY8YysaK" rel="nofollow,noindex">News Nation</a>, he said that the image was actually of a goat they were going to eat. He said, "I'm a very adventurous eater, I'll eat virtually anything. There are two things I wouldn't eat  well, three. I wouldn't eat a human, I wouldn't eat a monkey, and I wouldn't eat a dog. I think I'd eat something else."<br />
<br />
<strong>Kennedy said he "won't take sides on 9/11"</strong><br />
<br />
Mr Kennedy declared that should he be elected president, he "wouldn't take sides on 9/11" and would be transparent on social media. He claimed his statement was inspired by a "60 Minutes" report on a theory that the Saudi government knew about the plot in advance. He continued, saying, "It's hard to tell what is a conspiracy theory and what isn't." He has previously floated other conspiracy theories about vaccinations, AIDS, and the murder of his uncle.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My take on 9/11: It's hard to tell what is a conspiracy theory and what isn't. But conspiracy theories flourish when the government routinely lies to the public. As President I won't take sides on 9/11 or any of the other debates. But I can promise is that I will open the files</p>
 Robert F. Kennedy Jr (@RobertKennedyJr) <a href="https://twitter.com/RobertKennedyJr/status/1809219969537962423?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><strong>The bear cub</strong><br />
<br />
In August, The New Yorker magazine got hold of a story about Mr Kennedy's adventures with a dead bear cub, 10 years ago. To get ahead of the New Yorker's scoop, Mr Kennedy shared the story on Twitter. The tale revealed that Kennedy had discovered a dead bear cub by the side of the road, he then loaded it into the back of his car, snapped a picture with the body, went to do some falconry and had dinner of steak. However, before leaving for the airport, he used the bear's body to stage a death resembling a bicycle hit-and-run incident in NYC's Central Park.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6nv463q_robert-f-kennedy-jr_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Robert F Kennedy Jr has endorsed Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>