<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:52:39 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lavish-blue-lobster-wine-feast-for-king-charles-cost-france-rs-4-crore-6228723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lavish Blue Lobster, Wine Feast For King Charles Cost France Rs 4 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lavish-blue-lobster-wine-feast-for-king-charles-cost-france-rs-4-crore-6228723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:52:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An extravagant feast for King Charles has cost the French government a whopping $500,000 million (Rs 4 crore), an audit report has found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An extravagant feast for King Charles has cost the French government a whopping $500,000 million (Rs 4 crore), an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ccomptes.fr/sites/default/files/2024-07/20240729-S2024-1053-Comptes-et-gestion-de-la-presidence-de-la-Republique_2023.pdf">audit report </a>has found.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President Emmanuel Macron's office planned a lavish spread during the monarch's visit in September last year. The grand state banquet held at the Palace of Versailles was attended by over 150 people as part of an attempt to boost a key alliance between the UK and France.</p>

<p>The event was a star-studded affair with actor Hugh Grant, football manager Arsene Wenger and Rolling Stone's Mick Jagger among those in attendance.</p>

<p>On the menu were blue lobster (a rare French delicacy), crab, poultry marinaded in champagne and a gratin of French mushrooms.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?? FRANCE: Images from the royal dinner at the Château de Versailles/ Images from the royal dinner at the Château de Versailles.<br />
<br />
50% of the population can't feed themselves and Macron spends the money with the pedophile King Charles ? <a href="https://t.co/5GYXMF6kDe">pic.twitter.com/5GYXMF6kDe</a></p>
— Angelus iustitiae (@AIustitiae) <a href="https://twitter.com/AIustitiae/status/1704948750827901233?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>An assortment of vintage wines, champagnes and a selection of international cheeses were on offer. For dessert, French macaroons with lychee, rose sorbet and raspberry compote were served.</p>

<p>In its annual report, the French auditing organisation Cour des Comptes warned that spending on state receptions had left the budget nearly $9 million in the red.</p>

<p>According to the new audit report, the whole dinner cost a total of $513,000 of which $179,000 was spent on food and $46,000 on drinks.</p>

<p>Speaking at the banquet, King Charles said President Macron's "generosity of spirit brings to mind how my family and I were so greatly moved by the tributes paid in France to my mother, the late queen”.</p>

<p>However, this was not the only lavish state dinner organised by the French government. In 2023, the president's office spent $446,000 on a dinner for Prime Minister Narendra Modi at the Louvre museum.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1r21ps28_king-charles-afp-_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The grand state banquet held at the Palace of Versailles was attended by over 150 people]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyehs-assassination-will-not-go-unanswered-hamas-6228484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Ismail Haniyeh's Assassination Will Not Go Unanswered": Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyehs-assassination-will-not-go-unanswered-hamas-6228484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:20:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Hamas official said Wednesday that the killing of the Palestinian movement's chief Ismail Haniyeh "will not go unanswered".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Hamas official said Wednesday that the killing of the Palestinian movement's chief Ismail Haniyeh "will not go unanswered".</p>

<p>"The assassination of leader Ismail Haniyeh is a cowardly act and will not go unanswered," Hamas policial bureau member Musa Abu Marzuk said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3mf50igo_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-ismail-haniyeh-rose-from-being-activist-to-chief-of-hamas-6228472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Ismail Haniyeh Rose From Being Activist To Chief Of Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-ismail-haniyeh-rose-from-being-activist-to-chief-of-hamas-6228472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:16:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ismail Haniyeh, the Hamas leader who was killed in Iran, was the tough-talking face of the Palestinian group's international diplomacy as war raged back in Gaza, where three of his sons were killed in an Israeli airstrike.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ismail Haniyeh, the Hamas leader who was killed in Iran, was the tough-talking face of the Palestinian group's international diplomacy as war raged back in Gaza, where three of his sons were killed in an Israeli airstrike.</p>

<p>But despite the rhetoric, he was seen by many diplomats as a moderate compared to the more hardline members of the Iran-backed group inside Gaza.</p>

<p>Appointed to the Hamas top job in 2017, Haniyeh moved between Turkey and Qatar's capital Doha, escaping the travel curbs of the blockaded Gaza Strip and enabling him to act as a negotiator in ceasefire talks or to talk to Hamas' ally Iran.</p>

<p>"All the agreements of normalisation that you (Arab states) signed with (Israel) will not end this conflict," Haniyeh declared on Qatar-based Al Jazeera television shortly after Hamas fighters launched the Oct. 7 raid.</p>

<p>Israel's response to the strike has been a military campaign that has killed more than 35,000 people inside Gaza so far, according to health authorities in the territory.</p>

<h3><strong>SONS KILLED IN AIRSTRIKE</strong></h3>

<p>Three of Haniyeh's sons - Hazem, Amir and Mohammad - were killed on April 10 when an Israeli air strike struck the car they were driving, Hamas said. Haniyeh also lost four of his grandchildren, three girls and a boy, in the attack, Hamas said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh had denied Israeli assertions that his sons were fighters for the group, and said "the interests of the Palestinian people are placed ahead of everything" when asked if their killing would impact truce talks.</p>

<p>For all the tough language in public, Arab diplomats and officials had viewed him as relatively pragmatic compared with more hardline voices inside Gaza, where the military wing of Hamas planned the Oct. 7 attack.</p>

<p>While telling Israel's military they would find themselves "drowning in the sands of Gaza", he and his predecessor as Hamas leader, Khaled Meshaal, had shuttled around the region for talks over a Qatari-brokered ceasefire deal with Israel that would include exchanging hostages for Palestinians in Israeli jails as well as more aid for Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel regards the entire Hamas leadership as terrorists, and has accused Haniyeh, Meshaal and others of continuing to "pull the strings of the Hamas terror organisation".</p>

<p>But how much Haniyeh knew about the Oct. 7 assault beforehand is not clear. The plan, drawn up by the Hamas military council in Gaza, was such a closely guarded secret that some Hamas officials seemed shocked by its timing and scale.</p>

<p>Yet Haniyeh, a Sunni Muslim, had a major hand building up Hamas' fighting capacity, partly by nurturing ties with Shi'ite Muslim Iran, which makes no secret of its support for the group.</p>

<p>During the decade in which Haniyeh was Hamas' top leader in Gaza, Israel accused his leadership team of helping to divert humanitarian aid to the group's military wing. Hamas denied it.</p>

<h3><strong>SHUTTLE DIPLOMACY</strong></h3>

<p>When he left Gaza in 2017, Haniyeh was succeeded by Yahya Sinwar, a hardliner who spent more than two decades in Israeli prisons and whom Haniyeh had welcomed back to Gaza in 2011 after a prisoner exchange.</p>

<p>"Haniyeh is leading the political battle for Hamas with Arab governments," Adeeb Ziadeh, a specialist in Palestinian affairs at Qatar University, said before his death, adding that he had close ties with more hardline figures in the group and the military wing.</p>

<p>"He is the political and diplomatic front of Hamas," Ziadeh said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh and Meshaal had met officials in Egypt, which has also had a mediation role in the ceasefire talks. Haniyeh travelled in early November to Tehran to meet Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Iranian state media reported.</p>

<p>Three senior officials told Reuters that Khamenei had told the Hamas leader in that meeting that Iran would not enter the war having not been told about it in advance. Hamas did not respond to requests for comment before Reuters published its report, and then issued a denial after its publication.</p>

<p>As a young man, Haniyeh was a student activist at the Islamic University in Gaza City. He joined Hamas when it was created in the First Palestinian intifada (uprising) in 1987. He was arrested and briefly deported.</p>

<p>Haniyeh became a protege of Hamas' founder Sheikh Ahmad Yassin, who like Haniyeh's family, was a refugee from the village of Al Jura near Ashkelon. In 1994, he told Reuters that Yassin was a model for young Palestinians, saying: "We learned from him love of Islam and sacrifice for this Islam and not to kneel down to these tyrants and despots."</p>

<p>By 2003 he was a trusted Yassin aide, photographed in Yassin's Gaza home holding a phone to the almost completely paralysed Hamas founder's ear so that he could take part in a conversation. Yassin was assassinated by Israel in 2004.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was an early advocate of Hamas entering politics. In 1994, he said that forming a political party "would enable Hamas to deal with emerging developments".</p>

<p>Initially overruled by the Hamas leadership, it was later approved and Haniyeh become Palestinian prime minister after the group won Palestinian parliamentary elections in 2006 a year after Israel's military withdrew from Gaza.</p>

<p>The group took control of Gaza in 2007.</p>

<p>In 2012, when asked by Reuters reporters if Hamas had abandoned the armed struggle, Haniyeh replied "of course not" and said resistance would continue "in all forms - popular resistance, political, diplomatic and military resistance".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dnhoh8vg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Haniyeh was appointed to the Hamas top job in 2017]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-just-saw-its-hottest-day-ever-heres-how-it-was-analysed-6228036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Just Saw Its Hottest Day Ever, Here's How It Was Analysed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-just-saw-its-hottest-day-ever-heres-how-it-was-analysed-6228036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This month's shocking heat findings, announced by the EU's Copernicus Climate Change Service, are based on "reanalysis,"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Sunday, July 21, the world had its hottest day on record. Just 24 hours later, that record broke again making last Monday very likely the hottest day in thousands of years.</p>

<p>It may seem improbable for scientists to gauge the world's hottest day given that they don't have temperature monitors in every corner of the world and less than a century of relatively widespread observations. But they've developed a technique that's increasingly useful as the planet heats up.</p>

<p>This month's shocking heat findings, announced by the EU's Copernicus Climate Change Service, are based on "reanalysis," a technique that mixes temperature data and models to provide a global view of the climate. The center creates a nearly real-time picture of the Earth's climate, including temperature, wind and precipitation, for (roughly) every 30-square-kilometer chunk of the planet's surface.</p>

<p>This reanalysis goes back to 1940, and it allows researchers to say with confidence when a record is broken, whether for a day, month or year. Beyond the new daily heat record, the data also shows that 2023 was the hottest year ever recorded and that every calendar month for the past 13 months has been the hottest on record.</p>

<p>Though there aren't thermometers in every corner of the world, Copernicus receives a large amount of weather data that it uses to underpin its reanalysis. "We have this constant flow of information coming into the center," says Carlo Buontempo, director of the Climate Change Service, which is part of the European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts (ECMWF).</p>

<p>Scientists at the center receive 100 million readings per day about weather conditions from around the world. Observations come from airplanes, satellites, ships, radar and surface-level weather stations - all feeding real-time information about temperature, wind, rain and snow information, as well as other factors like air pollution. This information is fed into a model, known as ERA5, which is already equipped with historic information about the global climate.</p>

<p>There are gaps in these observations because the data sources don't cover every part of the world. Weather conditions like cloudy skies may also reduce the amount of data coming from sources like satellites. To fill these gaps, the scientists take the predictions they have already made, based on the long-term ERA5 model, and test them against the observations. That means a forecast that predicts a particular temperature in a particular place will be tested against all the data researchers receive about the weather in that place and nearby, as well as broader forces like ocean currents and air circulation.</p>

<p>This is done repeatedly while assessing how compatible the prediction is with what's actually been recorded. The model also accounts for any errors in the recorded data, and relies on the laws of physics, including the weather patterns, currents and airflow that govern how the global climate works.</p>

<p>In this way, it's possible to create a complete picture that is as accurate as possible. That's what allows scientists to confidently declare records like when the world experiences the hottest day in human history.</p>

<p>Globally, five weather services - the US's National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and NASA, the ECMWF, the China Meteorological Administration, and the Japan Meteorological Agency - carry out continuous appraisals of global temperature using this technique. While their models differ slightly, the five groups have come to similar conclusions about record heat in recent months and years.</p>

<p>Historical data is trickier to come by. The longest-running temperature series, the Central England Temperature in the UK, started in the 17th century. Data from before humans were systematically monitoring temperatures comes from sources like bubbles of gas trapped in glacial ice, or tree rings. These sources aren't as specific as a thermometer reading, but it's possible to say with confidence that recent temperatures are likely the highest in around 100,000 years, Copernicus says.</p>

<p>Meteorologists also have a good idea when a particularly significant day, like the hottest day on record, is on its way. This is partly because global mean temperatures usually peak between early July and early August. Last year's hottest day - which was the previous record for the hottest ever - occurred in early July amid a historic oceanic heat wave. An intensifying El Nino - a natural global climate phenomenon that usually means hotter temperatures globally - provided yet another clue that record heat was brewing.</p>

<p>Until this July, it looked for a while like the world wouldn't set a new daily record, says Buontempo. "The global mean temperature for the oceans started rising again," he says. "Some of the people who systematically monitor our predictions started to sound alarm bells." By the start of last week, they were paying extra attention to the reanalysis and getting ready to make an announcement.</p>

<p>This technique isn't just useful for making "hottest day ever" announcements: It's being used to train AI forecasting models, especially for "ensemble" weather forecasts, which represent multiple possible future scenarios. It's also used by solar energy companies to help homeowners work out how much energy their panels might generate, and by wind energy companies to plan where to put wind farms.</p>

<p>Copernicus is currently working on a new model, known as ERA6, which will be more precise - dividing the world into 14 kilometer squares - and incorporate many more historic data sources, including early satellite readings from the 1970s.</p>

<p>For Buontempo, more important than any one day is the recent extraordinary streak of record-breaking months, given that's a better indicator of how rapidly the world is warming. But pinpointing a specific day does make a changing climate feel much more immediate.</p>

<p>"I think we have to make it more tangible, more direct, more visible," he says. "It is important that people are informed."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/059pkdkg_warmer-summer-heatwave-temperature-rise-global-warming-istock_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-killed-as-us-carries-out-defensive-air-strike-in-iraq-6228025]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Killed As US Carries Out 'Defensive' Air Strike In Iraq]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-killed-as-us-carries-out-defensive-air-strike-in-iraq-6228025]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:42:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American forces carried out a "defensive" air strike on combatants who were attempting to launch drones that were deemed a threat to US and allied troops, a US official said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American forces carried out a "defensive" air strike on combatants who were attempting to launch drones that were deemed a threat to US and allied troops, a US official said.</p>

<p>The strike -- which Iraqi sources said left at least four people dead -- was the first by American forces in Iraq since February when the US military said it killed a pro-Iran commander who was involved in attacks on the country's troops.</p>

<p>"Tonight, US forces in Iraq conducted a defensive air strike" in Babylon province "targeting combatants attempting to launch one-way attack uncrewed aerial systems", the US defence official said on condition of anonymity, adding that the Central Command assessed the drones "posed a threat to US and coalition forces."</p>

<p>"We maintain the inherent right to self-defence and will not hesitate to take appropriate action," the official added.</p>

<p>The Hashed al-Shaabi -- an alliance of pro-Iran former paramilitary groups that have been integrated into Iraq's security forces -- earlier said apparent missile strikes had left four people dead at a base in Babylon, but made no mention of an attempt to launch drones from the ground.</p>

<p>"Available information suggests that two patrols... were targeted with missiles fired from drones," the Hashed said in a statement.</p>

<p>An official from the alliance told AFP that "four people were killed and others were critically wounded in blasts that hit a base belonging to the Hashed al-Shaabi".</p>

<p>A security source confirmed that four people were killed, adding that the death count was expected to rise.</p>

<h3><strong>Repeated attacks&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>There have been two recent attacks targeting US and allied forces in Iraq.</p>

<p>Several rockets were launched toward the Ain al-Assad base last week, which hosts troops from the US-led coalition against the Islamic State jihadist group, officials said.</p>

<p>And on July 16, two drones were launched toward the same facility, one of which was "successfully destroyed" while another hit the base, causing "minimal damage," according to the Pentagon.</p>

<p>Prior to that, US troops in Iraq and Syria had not been targeted since April. But attacks against them were much more common in the first few months of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza when they were targeted more than 175 times.</p>

<p>The Islamic Resistance in Iraq, a loose alliance of Iran-backed groups, claimed the majority of the attacks, saying they were in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza.</p>

<p>In January, a drone strike blamed on those groups killed three US soldiers at a base in Jordan. In retaliation, US forces launched dozens of strikes against Tehran-backed fighters.</p>

<p>Since then, attacks against US troops have largely halted.</p>

<p>Baghdad has sought to defuse tensions, engaging in talks with Washington on the future of the US-led coalition's mission in Iraq.</p>

<p>The US military has around 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in Syria.</p>

<p>The coalition was deployed to Iraq at the government's request in 2014 to help combat the Islamic State group, which had taken over vast swathes of Iraq and neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>IS remnants still carry out attacks and ambushes in both countries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-03/us-air-strikes-in-syria-reuters-650_650x400_41425922819.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike was the first by US forces in Iraq since February (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Chief Ismail Haniyeh Killed In Iran's Capital, Group Confirms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:41:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh and one of his bodyguards were killed in Iran, the Palestinian group said in a statement today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh and one of his bodyguards were killed after their residence was targeted in Iran, the Palestinian group said in a statement today.</p>

<p>Hamas said Ismail Haniyeh was killed in "a treacherous Zionist raid on his residence in Tehran" Tuesday morning.&nbsp;The group said an investigation is on to find out more details about the attack.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was in the Iranian capital to attend the swearing-in of Iran's president Masoud Pezeshkian.<br />
<br />
"Brother, leader, mujahid Ismail Haniyeh, the head of the movement, died in a Zionist strike on his headquarters in Tehran after he participated in the inauguration of the new (Iranian) president," the statement read.</p>

<p>A senior Hamas official said Ismail Haniyeh's killing "will not go unanswered".&nbsp;"The assassination of leader Ismail Haniyeh is a cowardly act and will not go unanswered," Hamas policial bureau member Musa Abu Marzuk said.<br />
<br />
Iran's Revolutionary Guards also confirmed his death, saying Haniyeh's residence in Tehran was "hit" and he was killed along with a bodyguard.</p>

<p>The Israeli army did not immediately respond to Haniyeh's killing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel had vowed to kill Ismail Haniyeh and destroy the Hamas group after October 7 attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,400 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Haniyeh was elected head of the Hamas political bureau in 2017 to succeed Khaled Meshaal. Considered a pragmatist, Haniyeh lived in exile and split his time between Turkey and Qatar.</p>

<p>He had travelled on diplomatic missions to Iran and Turkey during the war, meeting both the Turkish and Iranian presidents.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was said to maintain good relations with the heads of the various Palestinian factions, including rivals to Hamas.</p>

<p>He joined Hamas in 1987 when the militant group was founded amid the outbreak of the first Palestinian intifada, or uprising, against Israeli occupation, which lasted until 1993.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/jq2p0l6g_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel had vowed to kill Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-reveals-how-wife-melania-reacted-to-rally-shooting-means-she-loves-me-6227888]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Reveals How Melania Reacted To Rally Shooting: "Means She Loves Me"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-reveals-how-wife-melania-reacted-to-rally-shooting-means-she-loves-me-6227888]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:10:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["She was watching live. It was all over the place, it was on television," Mr Trump said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former United States President Donald Trump recently revealed his wife Melania Trump's first reaction after he was shot at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. Mr Trump was hit in the ear in an assassination bid by a gunman at a campaign rally. Blood was visible on his cheeks and mouth. The shooter was identified as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks. He and a bystander were killed, while two spectators were critically injured.</p>

<p>"What was Melania's reaction, I hope you don't mind me asking, I know this is very personal, when she learned about what happened on that field in Butler?" <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/RpsAgainstTrump/status/1818144001184190673">Fox News host Laura Ingraham</a> asked the former president. "She was watching live. It was all over the place, it was on television," Mr Trump said.</p>

<p>"And I asked her that, I mean I wasn't there, I was on the ground-when the world started to, when you could talk to people and said, 'So what was your feeling,' and she was ah, she can't really even talk about it-"</p>

<p>The 45th US President continued, "Which is OK, because that means she likes me or she loves me. Let's say if she could talk about it freely, that would be, I'm not so sure which is better but ah, she either likes or loves me, that's nice."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the former first lady said that the gunman who opened fire at Mr Trump was a "monster". "A monster who recognized my husband as an inhuman political machine attempted to ring out Donald's passion -- his laughter, ingenuity, love of music, and inspiration," Melania Trump said in a statement shared on X.</p>

<p>"When I watched that violent bullet strike my husband, Donald, I realized my life, and Barron's life, were on the brink of devastating change," she said, referencing the couple's 18-year-old son.</p>

<p>"I am grateful to the brave secret service agents and law enforcement officials who risked their own lives to protect my husband," she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/l20e5rig_donald-trump-melania-trump-afp_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier, Melania Trump said that the gunman who opened fire at Mr Trump was a "monster".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-swimmer-ryan-murphy-learns-his-babys-sex-after-winning-olympic-bronze-medal-6227880]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Swimmer Ryan Murphy Learns His Baby's Sex After Winning Olympic Medal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-swimmer-ryan-murphy-learns-his-babys-sex-after-winning-olympic-bronze-medal-6227880]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:09:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Team USA and USA Swimming shared a photo of the moment on Instagram, showing Konttinen holding the sign with a beaming crowd around her.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ryan Murphy received a heartwarming surprise message from his wife, Bridget Konttinen while standing on the pool deck at the Paris Olympics on Monday night. As he looked up into the stands, he saw his wife holding a sign that revealed they were expecting a baby girl.</p>

<p>Mr Murphy had just won a bronze medal in the 100-meter backstroke. After the medal ceremony, he noticed Konttinen holding up a sign that read, "Ryan, it's a girl." This was the first time he learned the gender of their first child, due in January.</p>

<p>Team USA and USA Swimming shared a photo of the moment on Instagram, showing Konttinen holding the sign with a beaming crowd around her. The post was captioned, "Step 1: Win an Olympic medal. Step 2: Find out you're going to be a girl dad." Among the many congratulatory comments was one from Olympic legend Michael Phelps.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by USA Swimming (@usaswimming)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Rowdy Gaines, a retired Olympic swimmer and current NBC analyst, also commented on the reveal, saying, "This is so much bigger than ANY medal. Congrats Murph!!"</p>

<p>Murphy, who is 29, secured his third consecutive medal in the 100-meter backstroke at the Paris Games, adding to his gold from Rio and bronze from Tokyo. As captain of the 2024 USA team, he still holds the Olympic record in the event from his 2016 win.</p>

<p>Despite the joy of earning his third Olympic medal, Murphy said the news of his future child made the night even more special. "I think that just kind of like lit me up," he said. "And really brought this night to a whole other level."</p>

<p>Murphy will return to the pool on Wednesday to compete in the 200-meter backstroke.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/82qgt5qg_ryan-murphy-_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Murphy had just won a bronze medal in the 100-meter backstroke.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hermes-heir-who-promised-rs-10-000-crore-to-gardener-says-wealth-disappeared-6227871]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hermes Heir, Who Promised Rs 10,000 Crore To Gardener, Says He Lost Wealth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hermes-heir-who-promised-rs-10-000-crore-to-gardener-says-wealth-disappeared-6227871]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:04:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The heir to luxury fashion brand Hermes, who promised to leave half his wealth to his former gardener last year, is now claiming the money has vanished.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The heir to luxury fashion brand Hermes, who promised to leave half his wealth to his former gardener last year, is now claiming the money has vanished.</p>

<p>Nicolas Puech, the 81-year-old descendant of Hermes founder Thierry Hermes, told court that the 6 million shares of Hermès he owned which were worth about $13 billion (Rs 10,000 crore) have suddenly disappeared.</p>

<p>The billionaire has blamed his former wealth manager who worked for him for the last 20 years, claiming he played a part in the loss of the shares, according to a reports.</p>

<p>However, his claims were rejected by a Swiss court after it found that he was unable to provide any proof of wrongdoing. “The ‘gigantic fraud' to which he was victim was undetectable to common mortals,” the court said.</p>

<p>According to reports, it is unclear where the shares, which was deposited in a bank in Geneva in 2012, are now.</p>

<p>Mr Puech, a single man with no children, is one of the heirs to the luxury bag brand and had promised to leave half his fortune to his former gardener and handyman.</p>

<p>In 2023, he said he wants to leave a big portion of his wealth to his former gardener, who he's planning on adopting.</p>

<p>Reports say Mr Puech owns 5.7% of Hermes' shares, which might seem like a small portion but makes him the largest individual shareholder.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per Forbes, Mr Puech's current net worth is around $11.7 billion, making him the world's 161st-richest person.</p>

<p>Not much is known about the gardener-handyman other than that he has worked for Mr Puech for decades as a residence manager. He is currently 51 and originally from Morocco.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fh8se4po_nicolas-puech_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-challenges-donald-trump-for-debate-says-say-it-to-my-face-6227769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Say It To My Face": Kamala Harris Challenges Donald Trump For Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-challenges-donald-trump-for-debate-says-say-it-to-my-face-6227769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 07:55:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President and Democratic Party's presumptive presidential candidate Kamala Harris has challenged her Republican rival, former president Donald Trump, for a debate, provoking him to say whatever he has to say to her face.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President and Democratic Party's presumptive presidential candidate Kamala Harris has challenged her Republican rival, former president Donald Trump, for a debate, provoking him to say whatever he has to say to her face.</p>

<p>Addressing an election rally in the state of Georgia's Atlanta city on Tuesday, Harris, 59, said that the nature of presidential elections changed after she entered the race.</p>

<p>She officially declared her candidacy after incumbent President Joe Biden withdrew from the race for a second term on July 20.</p>

<p>“The momentum in this race is shifting. There are signs that Donald Trump is feeling it. You may have noticed. So last week, you may have seen, he pulled out of the debate in September he had previously agreed to,” Harris said.</p>

<p>“Well Donald, I do hope you'll reconsider meeting me on the debate stage because as the saying goes, if you got something to say, say it to my face,” she said to a cheering crowd.</p>

<p>“So, here's the funny thing about that. Here's the funny thing about that. He won't debate, but he and his running mate sure seem to have a lot to say about me," she said.</p>

<p>As per the campaign, approximately 10,000 people attended her rally in Atlanta, a key battleground state.</p>

<p>“The path to the White House runs right through this state, and you all helped us win in 2020, and we're going to do it again in 2024. Yes, we will,” she said.</p>

<p>Asserting that the campaign is not just about them versus Trump, Harris said, “Truly, this campaign is about two very different visions for our nation. One focused on the future. The other focused on the past.” “We are not going back because ours is a fight for the future. It is a fight for freedom," she said.</p>

<p>"Across our nation, we are witnessing a full-on assault on hard-fought, hard-won freedoms and rights. The freedom to vote. The freedom to be safe from gun violence. The freedom to live without fear of bigotry and hate. The freedom to love who you love openly and with pride. The freedom to learn and acknowledge our true and full history. And the freedom of a woman to make decisions about her own body and not let her government tell her what to do,” she said.</p>

<p>“Ours is a fight for the future and for freedom. I don't have to tell folks in Atlanta that generations of Americans before us led the fight for freedom. And now the baton is in our hands. Each and every one of us,” Harris said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris said that the nature of presidential elections changed after she entered the race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-say-it-to-my-face-dare-to-donald-trump-after-he-calls-her-crazy-6227772]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris' "Say It To My Face" Dare To Trump After He Calls Her "Crazy"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-say-it-to-my-face-dare-to-donald-trump-after-he-calls-her-crazy-6227772]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 07:34:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US presidential hopeful Kamala Harris launched a searing attack on Donald Trump Tuesday, telling her biggest campaign rally yet that the momentum was shifting in the White House race and daring the Republican to debate her face to face.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US presidential hopeful Kamala Harris launched a searing attack on Donald Trump Tuesday, telling her biggest campaign rally yet that the momentum was shifting in the White House race and daring the Republican to debate her face to face.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris's trip to Atlanta, Georgia, comes as reenergized Democrats regard the swing state as being in play again, after it looked beyond hope under President Joe Biden before his shock withdrawal from the 2024 election.</p>

<p>The presumptive Democratic nominee is aiming to expand the party's 2024 battleground map and appeal to young Black voters, delivering a firm, 20-minute speech to about 10,000 supporters in a packed arena and pledging Americans "are not going back" to the "failed policies" of Trump.</p>

<p>"Now, the baton is in our hands," Harris said to loud applause. "We have a fight in front of us... And we are the underdogs in this race."</p>

<p>Harris's nascent presidential bid took off following Biden's July 21 exit from the race, with much of the party coalescing behind her and her campaign raising a staggering $200 million.</p>

<p>"The momentum in this race is shifting, and there are signs that Donald Trump is feeling it," she said.</p>

<p>The Republican nominee recently said he would forego political tradition and not debate Harris and also unleashed a barrage of insults against his rival, calling her "crazy" and a "bum."</p>

<p>"Well Donald, I do hope you'll reconsider to meet me on the debate stage, because as the saying goes, if you've got something to say, say it to my face," Harris said, to roars of approval.</p>

<p>Harris also repeated her popular line about how, as a former prosecutor and California attorney general going up against predators and fraudsters, she knows "Donald Trump's type."</p>

<p>"In this campaign, I will proudly put my record against his any day of the week," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Extreme abortion bans'</strong></h3>

<p>With just 98 days before the election, Harris is under pressure to announce her vice presidential pick. Asked Tuesday whether she had chosen one, Harris told reporters: "Not yet."</p>

<p>The search must be nearing a conclusion, however, as her team announced Tuesday that Harris and her new running mate would campaign next week in battlegrounds Pennsylvania, Wisconsin, Michigan, North Carolina, Georgia, Arizona and Nevada.</p>

<p>With the White House race turned on its head, 59-year-old Harris on Tuesday unveiled her first television ad since replacing Biden, while the Trump camp released a dueling spot attacking her on the crucial election issue of immigration.</p>

<p>Harris swatted away the attack, saying in her speech that while the Biden administration worked with conservatives to craft critical border legislation, Trump "tanked" it for political gain.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump does not care about border security," she said. "He only cares about himself."</p>

<p>Harris said if elected she would focus on key economic goals such as expanding affordable health care and tackling rising consumer costs.</p>

<p>She also attacked Trump, 78, over his "extreme abortion bans," referring to restrictive new laws enacted in several states in the two years since the US Supreme Court -- featuring three justices nominated by Trump -- stripped constitutional protections for abortion.</p>

<h3><strong>Georgia in play</strong></h3>

<p>As for Georgia's potential competitiveness, Harris insisted "the path to the White House runs right through this state."</p>

<p>In a sign the southern state will be bitterly contested, Trump and his running mate J.D. Vance announced they would hold their own rally Saturday in Atlanta.</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris and her complicit cronies have made the great people of Georgia pay a hefty price for their woke policies," the Trump campaign said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Harris took over a bleak electoral map from the faltering Biden, with Democrats' hopes entirely based on the three Rust Belt post-industrial states of Michigan, Wisconsin and Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>But they are now looking again at other "sunbelt" states such as Georgia, Arizona and Nevada, all of which Democrats narrowly won in 2020.</p>

<p>Vance addressed a rally Tuesday in Henderson, Nevada, where he attacked Harris as "dangerously liberal," while Trump campaigns in Pennsylvania on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Adding some Atlanta glitz for younger voters w</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The White House race has turned on its head]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/allan-lichtman-what-expert-who-predicted-9-us-presidential-elections-correctly-said-on-donald-trump-vs-kamala-harris-6227708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Expert Who Predicted 9 US Polls Correctly Said On Trump vs Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/allan-lichtman-what-expert-who-predicted-9-us-presidential-elections-correctly-said-on-donald-trump-vs-kamala-harris-6227708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 07:16:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Allan Lichtman, often dubbed the "Nostradamus of US presidential elections", makes his predictions based on his "13 keys to the White House".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A historian who has correctly predicted the result of nine US elections has now weighed in on the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-gaining-ground-on-donald-trump-in-6-of-7-swing-states-report-6227053" target="_blank">Donald Trump vs Kamala Harris fight</a>.</p>

<p>Allan Lichtman, often dubbed the "Nostradamus of US presidential elections", makes his predictions based on his "13 keys to the White House".</p>

<p>The method consists of 13 true or false questions, and if six or more keys go against the incumbent party, the 77-year-old American University historian predicts their defeat. If fewer than six went against it, it would win.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The keys assess various factors, including economic performance, social stability, and incumbent charisma. Through careful analysis spanning historical data since former US president Abraham Lincoln's era, Lichtman has crafted a predictive model that transcends conventional methods used by traditional psephologists.</p>

<h3><strong>Allan Lichtman's "13 Keys To The White House"</strong></h3>

<p>From Ronald Reagan's re-election triumph amid economic recession to Bill Clinton's victory against George HW Bush, Allan Lichtman has correctly predicted crucial poll contests in the US.</p>

<p>The 13 keys to the White House as designed by him are as follows:&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Party Mandate: </strong>Post-midterm elections, the incumbent party secures more US House of Representatives seats than in the previous midterms.</p>

<p><strong>Nomination Contest:</strong> There's no significant challenge to the incumbent party's nomination.</p>

<p><strong>Incumbency:</strong> The sitting president represents the incumbent party.</p>

<p><strong>Third-party Factor:</strong> There's no noteworthy third-party or independent campaign.</p>

<p><strong>Short-term Economic Stability:</strong> The economy doesn't face recession during the election period.</p>

<p><strong>Long-term Economic Growth:</strong> Real per capita economic growth equals or surpasses the average growth of the preceding two terms.</p>

<p><strong>Policy Shift:</strong> The incumbent administration enacts major alterations in national policy.</p>

<p><strong>Social Stability:</strong> There's no prolonged social unrest throughout the term.</p>

<p><strong>Scandal-Free:</strong> The incumbent administration remains free from major scandals.</p>

<p><strong>Foreign/Military Mishaps:</strong> No significant failures occur in foreign or military affairs under the incumbent administration.</p>

<p><strong>Foreign/Military Triumphs:</strong> The incumbent administration achieves significant successes in foreign or military matters.</p>

<p><strong>Incumbent Charm:</strong> The incumbent party's candidate possesses charisma or enjoys national hero status.</p>

<p><strong>Challenger Appeal: </strong>The opposing party's candidate lacks charisma or national hero status.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump Or Kamala Harris, Who Will Win US Polls?</strong></h3>

<p>Allan Lichtman currently favours US Vice-President and Democrat <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fearless-kamala-harris-launches-50-million-ad-blitz-in-us-presidential-race-6224268" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> over her Republican rival <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-vances-childless-cat-ladies-comments-reflect-love-of-family-6219296" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a>. He told News Nation that he believes "a lot would have to go wrong for Harris to lose."</p>

<p>Democrats, with Harris being the likely nominee after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-calls-joe-bidens-shock-us-poll-exit-a-coup-by-democrats-6206072" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> quit the reelection race, currently hold six of the 13 keys, according to his prediction. These include a primary contest, short-term economy, long-term economy, policy change, no scandal, and no challenger charisma.</p>

<p>"Right now, Democrats have lost three keys" by switching to Harris, he told News Nation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He said Democrats lost the "party mandate" key due to big losses in the 2022 mid-term elections. He also said Harris has lost the "charisma" and "incumbency" keys.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I plan to make my official prediction in August after the Democratic convention.<br />
See my assessment below below on the 13 Keys Tracker on where The Keys stand NOW. Please listen to our LIVE show on 7–25–24, linked in the comments below, where we detail every Key. <a href="https://t.co/pJpkpa3SzW">pic.twitter.com/pJpkpa3SzW</a></p>
— Allan Lichtman (@AllanLichtman) <a href="https://twitter.com/AllanLichtman/status/1816847990566666389?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Under his prediction model, Democrats, however, would have to lose three more keys in order for him to predict a Harris loss. But he says that's not likely to happen.</p>

<p>He has said that he plans to make his official prediction for the 2024 White House race after the Democratic convention in August.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-drug-lords-son-pleads-not-guilty-to-drugs-charges-6227670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexico Drug Lord El Chapo's Son Pleads Not Guilty To Drugs Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-drug-lords-son-pleads-not-guilty-to-drugs-charges-6227670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 07:02:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The son of the former Sinaloa drug cartel leader Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman pleaded not guilty Tuesday to a raft of charges linked to one of the world's biggest illicit narcotics operations, prosecutors said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The son of the former Sinaloa drug cartel leader Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman pleaded not guilty Tuesday to a raft of charges linked to one of the world's biggest illicit narcotics operations, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Joaquin Guzman Lopez was arrested in a scheme allegedly orchestrated by Washington without the involvement of Mexico, in which he was detained in Texas last Thursday.</p>

<p>The judge in the case denied bail and remanded him in custody, ordering a case management hearing for September 30, the assistant US Attorney's office said in a statement to AFP.</p>

<p>Many of the details of the arrest operation, in which co-founder of the cartel Ismael Zambada Garcia, known as "El Mayo," was also taken into US custody, remain murky.</p>

<p>US media have quoted law enforcement sources as saying that Zambada was unwittingly lured across the Mexico border by Guzman Lopez, one of "El Chapo's" four sons.</p>

<p>According to a US Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) report released in May, the sons were engaged in an "internal battle" against Zambada, their father's former partner.</p>

<p>Guzman Lopez was indicted by a federal grand jury on charges of drug trafficking, money laundering and weapons charges, according to court documents previously released by prosecutors.</p>

<p>Broadcaster CNN reported that Guzman Lopez's lawyer, Jeffrey Lichtman, told reporters his client faces the death penalty in the case. Lichtman did not return an AFP request for comment.</p>

<p>There was "no agreement between Joaquin Guzman and the government. Period," Lichtman told reporters in Chicago.</p>

<p>Zambada's lawyer, Frank Perez, has maintained since Sunday that his client was "kidnapped" and taken to the United States against his will.</p>

<p>Zambada pleaded not guilty on Friday to drug trafficking and money laundering charges before a federal judge in Texas, and has another court appearance scheduled for Thursday in El Paso.</p>

<p>Guzman Lopez, aged in his 30s, is among the sons of "El Chapo" known collectively as "Los Chapitos," or "The Little Chapos."</p>

<p>"El Chapo" was convicted of drug charges in New York in 2019 and is serving a life sentence in a maximum security prison.</p>

<p>DEA chief Anne Milgram said Zambada's arrest "strikes at the heart of the cartel that is responsible for the majority of drugs, including fentanyl and methamphetamine, killing Americans from coast to coast."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7vj0hpbo_joaquin-guzman-lopez-_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Guzman Lopez, aged in his 30s, is among the sons of "El Chapo" known collectively as "The Little Chapos."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-israel-has-right-to-defend-itself-against-hezbollah-6227644]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Says Israel Has "Right To Defend Itself" Against Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-israel-has-right-to-defend-itself-against-hezbollah-6227644]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 06:58:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic election nominee, said Tuesday that Israel had a "right to defend itself" following a strike in Hezbollah's stronghol]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic election nominee, said Tuesday that Israel had a "right to defend itself" following a strike in Hezbollah's stronghold in southern Beirut.</p>

<p>Harris -- who last week struck a tough tone with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu over Israel's war on Gaza -- also called for a diplomatic solution to reduce the risk of all-out conflict on the Lebanon-Israel border.</p>

<p>"I want to address what's happened over the last few hours in terms of the Middle East, and be very clear Israel has a right to defend itself," Harris told reporters as she headed to an election rally in Atlanta, Georgia.</p>

<p>Israel said the attack on Tuesday had targeted a Hezbollah commander responsible for rocket fire that killed 12 children in the occupied Golan Heights at the weekend.</p>

<p>"What we know in particular is it (Israel) has the right to defend itself against a terrorist organization, which is exactly what Hezbollah is," added Harris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"But all of that being said, we still must work on a diplomatic solution to end these attacks, and we will continue to do that work."</p>

<p>Harris is effectively locked in as the Democratic presidential nominee for November's US election after President Joe Biden's shock decision to drop out of the White House race just over a week ago.</p>

<p>With speculation swirling about whether she would moderate Biden's stalwart support for Israel's Gaza war, Harris said last week after meeting Netanyahu in Washington that she "will not be silent" about Palestinian casualties there.</p>

<p>Harris said on Thursday she expressed "serious concern about the scale of human suffering" to Netanyahu, who held separate meetings with her and Biden.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/a6f6mv1_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_07_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris said that Israel had a "right to defend itself" following a strike against Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-says-his-party-ready-to-talk-with-military-6227604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jailed Ex-Pak PM Imran Khan Says His Party Ready To Talk With Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-says-his-party-ready-to-talk-with-military-6227604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 06:47:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Pakistan Prime Minister Imran Khan, said that his party is ready to hold talks with the military, a remark that drew a lot of flak from the Shehbaz Sharif-led government, Geo News repo]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Pakistan Prime Minister Imran Khan, said that his party is ready to hold talks with the military, a remark that drew a lot of flak from the Shehbaz Sharif-led government, Geo News reported.</p>

<p>The Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf founder, who appeared in a court established in Adiala jail for a hearing, said: "We are ready to hold talks with the military. The army should nominate their representative [for negotiations]."</p>

<p>Khan, who has been imprisoned for nearly a year, said that his party had never levelled allegations against the army, but had only criticised the armed forces.</p>

<p>He further said that if any PTI worker was found guilty in the May 9, 2023, riots then the authorities should penalise the individual.</p>

<p>The deposed premier further reiterated that the incumbent government wanted to destroy his party by creating a wedge between PTI and the armed forces.</p>

<p>Referring to the repeated arrests of PTI leadership across the province, the incarcerated PTI founder termed Punjab Chief Minister Maryam Nawaz "fascist."</p>

<p>Speaking about his arrest last year, Khan alleged that he was "abducted from the judicial complex" and "it was declared legal by the Islamabad High Court (IHC) Chief Justice Aamer Farooq."</p>

<p>The outreach by Imran drew sharp rebukes from the ruling Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz (PML-N) leaders, who slammed the jailed former premier for "dragging" the army into political matters, as reported by Geo News.</p>

<p>Addressing a press conference in Islamabad today, Federal Information Minister Attaullah Tarar said that the incarcerated ex-premier sought a dialogue with the army after the institution decided to remain apolitical, recalling that the same Khan had equated "neutral with animal" when the army announced staying away from political matters.</p>

<p>Calling the 71-year-old cricketer-turned-politician a "security risk" for the country's economy, Tarar said Khan has previously said "I will not spare," and now he has come down to making beseeching.</p>

<p>"You are a security risk for the country, as your people say that there is no Pakistan without the PTI founder," he said. He termed the PTI a "terrorist outfit," saying this terror organisation was not suitable for Pakistan, Geo News reported.</p>

<p>PML-N leader and Punjab minister Marriyum Aurangzeb also rebuked Imran Khan's call for talks, saying that the "self-proclaimed revolutionary figure" has descended from his previous stances of "I will not seek pardon" to seeking an apology.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/5gkcbqjg_imran-khan_625x300_23_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Imran Khan asked Pakistan army to nominate their representative for negotiations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violent-crowd-clashes-with-uk-police-after-young-girls-killed-6227514]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Violent Crowd Clashes With UK Police After Young Girls Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violent-crowd-clashes-with-uk-police-after-young-girls-killed-6227514]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 06:10:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A large crowd of anti-Muslim protesters clashed with police on Tuesday in a northern English town where three girls were stabbed to death and five other children critically wounded during an attack on a Taylor Swift-themed event on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A large crowd of anti-Muslim protesters clashed with police on Tuesday in a northern English town where three girls were stabbed to death and five other children critically wounded during an attack on a Taylor Swift-themed event on Monday.</p>

<p>The horrific stabbing incident in Southport, a quiet seaside town north of Liverpool, has shocked the nation. Police have said it was not linked to terrorism and that the suspect was born in the UK.</p>

<p>Yet far-right groups have stoked speculation that the teenage suspect was involved with Islam, and police said Tuesday's violence erupted when several hundred people began to throw items at a mosque. Police linked the crowd to the English Defence League, a group which has sometimes staged violent demonstrations against Islam.</p>

<p>Police vehicles were damaged and set alight, officers were pelted by bricks and large garbage containers. One video posted online showed the crowd chanting "we want our country back".</p>

<p>Away from the violence, hundreds had gathered for an emotional vigil to pay tribute to those killed in the attack, laying flowers and toys.</p>

<p>"The people of Southport are reeling after the horror inflicted on them yesterday. They deserve our support and our respect," Prime Minister Keir Starmer said.</p>

<p>"Those who have hijacked the vigil for the victims with violence and thuggery have insulted the community as it grieves. They will feel the full force of the law."</p>

<p>A 17-year-old male is currently in police custody on suspicion of murder and attempted murder after the bloody rampage at a "Taylor Swift yoga and dance workshop", a summer vacation event for children aged 6 to 11.</p>

<p>Witnesses described the attack as being like a scene from a horror film. In addition to the three deaths, eight children suffered stab wounds. Five of them and two adults who had tried to protect them remain in a critical condition.</p>

<p>The police have said the motive remained unclear and have not given any details about the suspect, beyond saying he was born in Wales and lived in a village nearby.</p>

<p>"There has been much speculation and hypothesis around the status of a 17-year-old male who is currently in police custody and some individuals are using this to bring violence and disorder to our streets," said Assistant Chief Constable Alex Goss.</p>

<p>"We have already said that the person arrested was born in the UK and speculation helps nobody at this time."</p>

<p>Goss and local politicians said those clashing with police involved many from outside the area, and the Liverpool Region Mosque Network said a minority of people were trying to use the incident to spread hatred.</p>

<p>"This evening we have seen distressing scenes outside Southport Mosque with angry protesters gathering outside," it said in a statement. "This is causing further fear and anxiety within our communities,"</p>

<p>Starmer had earlier paid a sombre visit to the town to lay flowers, and King Charles and his family have expressed their horror. U.S. singer Swift herself wrote on Instagram that she was "just completely in shock".</p>

<p><strong>JUST LITTLE KIDS</strong></p>

<p>"These were just little kids at a dance class. I am at a complete loss for how to ever convey my sympathies to these families," she said.</p>

<p>Her fans have raised more than 250,000 pounds ($320,850) online to help families of the victims and for the hospital where some of the children were being treated.</p>

<p>The three girls who died in the attack were named as Bebe King, aged 6, 7-year-old Elsie Dot Stancombe, and Alice Dasilva Aguiar, aged 9, whose parents are Portuguese.</p>

<p>"Keep smiling and dancing like you love to do our Princess, like we said before to you, you're always our princess and no one would change that. Love from Your Hero Daddy and Mummy," Aguiar's family said in a statement.</p>

<p>There has been increasing concern at rising levels of stabbings and knife crime in Britain, and the Southport attack follows other recent similar, indiscriminate rampages.</p>

<p>"I'm absolutely determined that my government will get to grips with it," Starmer said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7l5h3ce8_uk-protest_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police have said it was not linked to terrorism and that the suspect was born in the UK.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-carries-out-strike-in-iraq-amid-middle-east-tensions-6227455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Carries Out Strike In Iraq Amid Middle East Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-carries-out-strike-in-iraq-amid-middle-east-tensions-6227455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 05:50:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Tuesday carried out a strike in Iraq in self defence, a U.S. official told Reuters, as regional tensions rose after an Israeli airstrike in Beirut that Israel said killed Hezbollah's most senior commander.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Tuesday carried out a strike in Iraq in self defence, a U.S. official told Reuters, as regional tensions rose after an Israeli airstrike in Beirut that Israel said killed Hezbollah's most senior commander.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear if the U.S. strike was the same as the blasts reported earlier at a base south of Baghdad for Iraq's Popular Mobilization Forces, the official state security agency that includes several Iran-aligned armed groups.</p>

<p>Those blasts killed four people and injured three, according to police and medical sources.</p>

<p>In a statement after the blasts, the Popular Mobilization Forces made no accusation about who was responsible.</p>

<p>A U.S. official, speaking on the condition of anonymity, said the strike was carried out because of a threat to coalition forces based in Iraq. The official did not comment on any casualties.</p>

<p>Multiple rockets were launched toward Iraq's Ain al-Asad airbase housing U.S.-led forces last week, U.S. and Iraqi sources said, with no damage or casualties reported. U.S. officials said none of the rockets hit the base.</p>

<p>It was the first known U.S. strike in Iraq since February, when the U.S. military launched airstrikes in Iraq and Syria against more than 85 targets linked to Iran's Revolutionary Guard and the militias it backs.</p>

<p>Iraq, a rare ally of both Tehran and Washington which hosts 2,500 U.S. troops and has Iran-backed militias linked to its security forces, has witnessed escalating tit-for-tat attacks since the Israel-Hamas war erupted in October.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/uscrsqr8_us-troops-in-iraqafp650_625x300_11_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States on Tuesday carried out a strike in Iraq in self defence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-killed-top-hezbollah-commander-fuad-shukr-in-beirut-strike-6227253]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says It Killed Top Hezbollah Commander Fuad Shukr In Beirut Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-killed-top-hezbollah-commander-fuad-shukr-in-beirut-strike-6227253]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 04:45:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said its fighter jets "eliminated" Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in the area of Beirut on Tuesday, accusing him of being responsible for a rocket strike on the annexed Golan Heights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said its fighter jets "eliminated" Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in the area of Beirut on Tuesday, accusing him of being responsible for a rocket strike on the annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>"Israeli air force fighter jets eliminated the Hezbollah terrorist organisation's most senior military commander and the head of its strategic unit, Fuad Shukr, in the area of Beirut," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Fuad Shukr was the commander responsible for the Majdal Shams massacre, in which 12 children were murdered after Hezbollah fired an Iranian Falaq-1 rocket directly at a soccer field in northern Israel on Saturday evening," military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari said in a separate video statement.</p>

<p>"Fuad Shukr was the right-hand man to Hassan Nasrallah, Hezbollah's leader and his advisor in planning and directing attacks and operations."</p>

<p>Hagari said Shukr was a "senior terrorist who has the blood of Israelis and many others on his hands".</p>

<p>Since the start of the Gaza war, Shukr directed Hezbollah's attacks on Israel, the military said.</p>

<p>He was responsible for the majority of Hezbollah's most advanced weaponry, including precise-guided missiles, cruise missiles, anti-ship missiles, long-range rockets and UAVs, it added.</p>

<p>The military said that in the 1990s the Hezbollah commander was "directly involved" in the abduction of the bodies of three Israeli soldiers -- Benyamin Avraham, Adi Avitan and Omar Sawaid.</p>

<p>The three were killed by Hezbollah while patrolling the security fence adjacent to Har Dov, the military said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Since then, he has planned and directed numerous terror attacks against innocent civilians," it said.</p>

<p>While Israel wanted to end hostilities without any wider war with Hezbollah, its forces were ready for "any scenario," Hagari said.</p>

<p>"Hezbollah's ongoing aggression and brutal attacks are dragging the people of Lebanon and the entire Middle East into a wider escalation," he said.</p>

<p>"While we prefer to resolve hostilities without a wider war, the IDF (Israeli army) is fully prepared for any scenario."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3eouetvo_fuad-shukr-killed_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[uad Shukr was the right-hand man to Hassan Nasrallah, Israel said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-gaining-ground-on-donald-trump-in-6-of-7-swing-states-report-6227053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Gaining Ground On Trump In 6 Of 7 Swing States: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-gaining-ground-on-donald-trump-in-6-of-7-swing-states-report-6227053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 03:38:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris has gained ground against Republican Donald Trump in six of the seven swing states since President Joe Biden dropped out of the presidential race, according to a Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris has gained ground against Republican Donald Trump in six of the seven swing states since President Joe Biden dropped out of the presidential race, according to a Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll of registered voters published on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The poll - conducted online from July 24-28 - shows Harris leading Trump in Michigan by 11 percentage points, while in Arizona, Wisconsin and Nevada, she has a 2-point advantage. Trump is ahead of Harris in Pennsylvania by 4 points and in North Carolina by 2 points. They are on equal footing in Georgia.</p>

<p>Wisconsin is the only state of the seven where Trump has narrowed his deficit with Harris in comparison to Biden's performance in a previous poll.</p>

<p>Tuesday's poll has a margin of error of 3 percentage points in Arizona, Georgia and Pennsylvania, 4 percentage points in Michigan, North Carolina and Wisconsin, and 5 percentage points in Nevada.</p>

<p>In a Bloomberg/Morning Consult poll conducted July 1-5, Trump was ahead of Biden in Arizona by 3 percentage points; in Georgia by 1 point; in Nevada by 3 points; in North Carolina by 3 points; and in Pennsylvania by 7 points. Biden led in Michigan by 5 points and in Wisconsin by 3 points, the poll showed.</p>

<p>The margin of error in the July 1-5 poll was 3 percentage points in Georgia and Pennsylvania; 4 percentage points in Arizona, Michigan, North Carolina, and Wisconsin, and 5 percentage points in Nevada.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bqfnk8go_kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is gaining ground since Joe Biden dropped out of the US presidential race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-expected-to-announce-her-running-mate-as-early-as-monday-6226989]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Expected To Announce Her Running Mate As Early As Monday]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-expected-to-announce-her-running-mate-as-early-as-monday-6226989]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 03:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will announce her vice presidential pick as early as Monday before embarking on a multi-state battleground tour with her new running mate later in the week, two sources familiar with the planning said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris will announce her vice presidential pick as early as Monday before embarking on a multi-state battleground tour with her new running mate later in the week, two sources familiar with the planning said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The high-stakes decision on who will run with Harris has taken center stage since she became the Democratic frontrunner for the Nov. 5 election after U.S. President Joe Biden ended his White House bid just over a week ago.</p>

<p>Harris will announce her vice presidential pick before next week's tour of states that could swing to Republicans or Democrats in November, one of the sources said.</p>

<p>Harris' campaign did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>The short list of candidates under consideration include Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear, Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, U.S. Senator Mark Kelly of Arizona, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz and Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg.</p>

<p>On Monday, North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper and Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer both indicated they were out of the VP sweepstakes.</p>

<p>A handful of U.S. states, often called battlegrounds, have decided the presidential election in recent years, including Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>"There has been no date confirmed for VP Harris to announce her running mate," a campaign spokesperson told Reuters.</p>

<p>Typically, campaigns begin thinking about their vice-presidential pick after the primary race ends in the spring, giving them months to vet candidates and make a decision on who the candidate meshes with best personally and politically.</p>

<p>Harris is being forced to select her running mate on a highly compressed timeline. She faces an Aug. 7 deadline set by the Democratic National Committee, but the decision is likely to come sooner, according to the sources.</p>

<p>Eric Holder Jr., the former attorney general who led the vice-presidential vetting process for Barack Obama in 2008, is vetting Harris' picks through his law firm, Covington &amp; Burling.</p>

<p>The candidates are informally auditioning for the job, hitting the airwaves and campaign stops to showcase what they would bring to the Harris ticket.</p>

<p>Shapiro, for example, delivered a rousing testimonial about Harris in the Philadelphia suburbs on Monday.</p>

<p>"She's not only ready, she's damned ready," he said to a cheering crowd. "And you know who else knows she's ready? Donald Trump knows she's ready."</p>

<p>Walz, the governor of Minnesota, is credited with pushing the Democrats' new criticism of Trump and his running mate J.D. Vance - that they are "weird."</p>

<p>"The fascists depend on us going back, but we're not afraid of weird people," Walz said on Saturday of the Republican ticket. "We're a little bit creeped out, but we're not afraid."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/f31c6agc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will announce her new running mate later in the week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>