<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:33:16 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-confirms-military-plan-for-mass-deportation-of-undocumented-migrants-7050776]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Confirms Military Plan For Mass Deportation Of Undocumented Migrants]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-confirms-military-plan-for-mass-deportation-of-undocumented-migrants-7050776]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:32:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump confirmed Monday that he plans to declare a national emergency on border security and use the US military to carry out a mass deportation of undocumented migrants.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump confirmed Monday that he plans to declare a national emergency on border security and use the US military to carry out a mass deportation of undocumented migrants.</p>

<p>Immigration was a top issue in the election campaign, and Trump has promised to deport millions and stabilize the border with Mexico after record numbers of migrants crossed illegally during President Joe Biden's administration.</p>

<p>On his social media platform Truth Social, Trump amplified a recent post by a conservative activist that said the president-elect was "prepared to declare a national emergency and will use military assets to reverse the Biden invasion through a mass deportation program."</p>

<p>Alongside the repost, Trump commented, "True!"</p>

<p>Trump sealed a remarkable comeback to the presidency in his November 5 defeat of Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>He has been announcing a cabinet featuring immigration hardliners, naming former Immigration and Customs Enforcement acting chief Tom Homan as his "border czar."</p>

<p>Homan appeared at the Republican National Convention in July, telling supporters: "I got a message to the millions of illegal immigrants that Joe Biden's released in our country: You better start packing now."</p>

<p>Authorities estimate that some 11 million people are living in the United States illegally. Trump's deportation plan is expected directly to impact around 20 million families.</p>

<p>While the US government has struggled for years to manage its southern border with Mexico, Trump has super-charged concerns by claiming an "invasion" is underway by migrants he says will rape and murder Americans.</p>

<p>During his campaign, Trump repeatedly railed against undocumented immigrants, employing incendiary rhetoric about foreigners who "poison the blood" of the United States and misleading his audiences about immigration statistics and policy.</p>

<p>Trump has not elaborated on his immigration crackdown in any detail but during his election campaign repeatedly vowed to invoke the Alien Enemies Act of 1798 to speed up deportations.</p>

<p>Critics say the law is outdated and point to its most recent use during World War II to hold Japanese-Americans in internment camps without due process.</p>

<p>The number of US border patrol encounters with migrants crossing from Mexico illegally is now about the same as in 2020, the last year of Trump's first term, after peaking at a record 250,000 for the month of December 2023.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c31dbfe8_trump_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has not elaborated on his immigration crackdown in any detail. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-summit-global-south-impacted-by-food-fuel-fertiliser-crisis-amid-ongoing-conflicts-says-pm-modi-7049946]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Global South Impacted By Food, Fuel Crisis Amid Conflicts: PM Modi At G20]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-summit-global-south-impacted-by-food-fuel-fertiliser-crisis-amid-ongoing-conflicts-says-pm-modi-7049946]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:29:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The countries of the Global South are most adversely impacted by the food, fuel and fertilizer crisis caused by global conflicts, and G20 must focus on addressing the challenges, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The countries of the Global South are most adversely impacted by the food, fuel and fertilizer crisis caused by global conflicts, and G20 must focus on addressing the challenges, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Monday.</p>

<p>In an address on the first day of the G20 summit, PM Modi said India's G20 theme of "One Earth, One Family, One Future" is as relevant at the ongoing summit as it was last year.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, PM Modi, Chinese President Xi Jinping and British Prime Minister Keir Starmer are among the leaders attending the two-day summit at Rio de Janeiro's Modern Art Museum.</p>

<p>The people-centric decisions taken at the G20 Summit in New Delhi last year have been taken forward during Brazil's presidency of the bloc, PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"I would like to say that countries of the Global South are most adversely impacted by the food, fuel and fertilizer crisis caused by global conflicts," he said.</p>

<p>"So our discussions can only be successful when we keep in mind the challenges and priorities of the Global South," he added.</p>

<p>The prime minister made the remarks at the G20 session on 'Social Inclusion and the Fight Against Hunger and Poverty'.</p>

<p>The opening day's highlight was the launch of a global alliance to combat poverty and hunger that has been supported by at least 80 nations.</p>

<p>In his comments, PM Modi also called for reform of the institutions of global governance.</p>

<p>"And just as we amplified the voice of the Global South by granting permanent membership of G20 to the African Union during the New Delhi summit, we will reform institutions of global governance," he said.</p>

<p>The prime minister said India supports Brazil's initiative for a 'global alliance against hunger and poverty'.</p>

<p>"The people-centric decisions taken at the G20 Summit in New Delhi have been taken forward during Brazil's Presidency," he said.</p>

<p>"It is a matter of great satisfaction that we prioritised SDG (sustainable development goals). We focused on inclusive development, women-led development, and youth power," he said.</p>

<p>"And gave wings to the hopes and aspirations of the Global South. It is clear that One Earth One Family One Future is as relevant at this summit as it was last year," he added.</p>

<p>The theme of India's G20 presidency is drawn from the ancient Sanskrit text of Maha Upanishad.</p>

<p>"Over the last 10 years, we have lifted 250 million people out of poverty," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>In line with the theme of the session, PM Modi also gave an overview of India's success in addressing hunger and poverty.</p>

<p>"Over 800 million people are being given food grains free of cost. 550 million people are benefiting from the world's biggest health insurance scheme," he said.</p>

<p>"Now, 60 million senior citizens, over the age of 70, will also be able to benefit from free health insurance," he said.</p>

<p>"Maintaining our focus on women-led development and social inclusion, over 300 million women micro-entrepreneurs have been linked to banks and given access to credit," PM Modi added.</p>

<p>The prime minister also spoke about India's crop insurance scheme.</p>

<p>"Under the world's largest crop insurance scheme, over 40 million farmers have received benefits worth 20 billion US dollars," he said.</p>

<p>"Under the farmers' scheme, assistance worth over 40 billion dollars has been given to 110 million farmers. Institutional credit worth 300 billion US dollars is being given to farmers," he said.</p>

<p>PM Modi said India is not only ensuring food security but also focusing on nutrition. He said New Delhi is also contributing to global food security by sending food items to various countries.</p>

<p>"The main reason for our success is our approach: 'back to basics' and 'march to the future'," he said.</p>

<p>"We have focused not only on natural farming and organic farming but also on new technologies. We have focused on sustainable agriculture, protection of the environment, nutrition and food security by promoting Sri Ann or millets," he said.</p>

<p>The prime minister said India has developed over 2000 climate-resilient crop varieties and has started the 'Digital Agriculture Mission'.</p>

<p>"India's digital public Infrastructure enabled social and financial inclusion. With the aspirational districts and blocks project, we created a new model for inclusive development that strengthens the weakest link," he said.</p>

<p>PM Modi began his visit to Brazil after concluding a two-day trip to Nigeria.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/52294rv8_narendra-modi-g20-brazil-afp_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi made the remarks at the G20 summit in Brazil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-donald-trumps-cabinet-choices-are-giving-pakistan-sleepless-nights-7050704]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Donald Trump's Cabinet Choices Are Giving Pakistan Sleepless Nights]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-donald-trumps-cabinet-choices-are-giving-pakistan-sleepless-nights-7050704]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:16:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan is keeping a very close watch on how Donald Trump's cabinet is shaping up as Islamabad is getting increasingly jittery over the decisions being made so far.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan is keeping a very close watch on how Donald Trump's cabinet is shaping up as Islamabad is getting increasingly jittery over the decisions being made so far.</p>

<p>President-elect Trump has already picked a sizeable team for his second term in office as President, and policy makers, think tanks, and most of all, the Pakistani military establishment is reportedly having sleepless nights over key nominations.</p>

<p>Islamabad finds itself on a sticky-wicket as Trump's picks for Secretary of State, Secretary of Defence, National Security Adviser, and spy agency CIA chief all having very critical views of Pakistan while being much more considerate to New Delhi.</p>

<p>Not finding a place in Washington's foreign policy, top government and military officials in Pakistan are reportedly in a huddle to re-strategise its approach towards the United States.</p>

<h2><strong>SECRETARY OF STATE MARCO RUBIO</strong></h2>

<p>Senator Marko Rubio, who has been nominated as the next US Secretary of State, had introduced a bill fully endorsing India's views and concerns against Pakistan - a move that rang alarm bells in Pakistan Army headquarters in Rawalpindi.</p>

<p>Mr Rubio's proposed bill had mentioned Pakistan's direct involvement in sponsoring terrorism against India through various state-sponsored proxy groups, suggesting that Islamabad should not be given any US security assistance whatsoever.</p>

<p>Besides Pakistan, the bill, named 'US-India Defense Cooperation Act' and introduced in the Senate by Mr Rubio, also called for an extended defence cooperation with India to tackle China's increasing influence in the region.</p>

<p>According to the bill, Washington is advised to treat India at par with top US allies, including Japan, Israel, South Korea and NATO, on technology transfers. It also suggested that New Delhi should be provided with full security assistance through collaboration in defence, technology, economic investments and civil space.</p>

<h3><strong>NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISER MIKE WALTZ</strong></h3>

<p>Another key figure in Donald Trump's new administration is Mike Waltz - a staunch Pakistan critic, who has been nominated as the next US National Security Adviser.</p>

<p>Mr Waltz has been very critical of Pakistan in the past, telling Islamabad that "terrorism cannot be a tool of foreign policy. Be it the Lashkar-e-Taiba or other terrorist groups - it is simply unacceptable, and the Pakistani government, the Pakistani military and its intelligence service (ISI) have to move past that."</p>

<p>He has called for significantly higher pressure on Islamabad to be held accountable for terror financing and for the country to completely eliminate cross-border terrorism. Mr Waltz's views match that of New Delhi's.</p>

<h3><strong>US NATIONAL INTELLIGENCE DIRECTOR TULSI GABBARD</strong></h3>

<p>Tulsi Gabbard, who is set to be the US Director of Intelligence, a top post in the Trump administration has fully backed India's stand on cross-border terrorism from Pakistan. Ms Gabbard had extended her full support to New Delhi in its military escalation with Islamabad after the 2019 Pulwama terror attack.</p>

<p>She has also slammed Pakistan on multiple occasions for giving shelter to then Al Qaeda chief Osama Bin Laden, who was killed in a US Navy Seals operation in Abbottabad in Pakistan in 2011.</p>

<h3><strong>CIA CHIEF JOHN RATCLIFFE</strong></h3>

<p>The next CIA chief John Ratcliffe is also known for his hawkish view on China and Iran and someone who will keep a close watch on Islamabad's actions too - both overt and covert.</p>

<p>As Donald Trump's cabinet takes shape, analysts believe it is getting increasingly difficult for Islamabad to have the kind of relations it desires with Washington, and that Pak PM Shehbaz Sharif must walk the talk on action against terrorism and terror financing. It is also observed that Donald Trump's cabinet picks are a message that Islamabad is not on his priority list and certainly nowhere near the importance given to New Delhi.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/au3tdfno_shehbaz-sharif-reuters_625x300_04_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As Donald Trump picks his cabinet, Islamabad is getting increasingly jittery with his selections]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-israel-to-target-hezbollah-despite-potential-lebanon-ceasefire-benjamin-netanyahu-7050622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel To Target Hezbollah Despite Potential Lebanon Ceasefire: Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-israel-to-target-hezbollah-despite-potential-lebanon-ceasefire-benjamin-netanyahu-7050622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 23:55:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that Israel will continue to operate militarily against the Iran-backed Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah even if a ceasefire deal is reached in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that Israel will continue to operate militarily against the Iran-backed Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah even if a ceasefire deal is reached in Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The most important thing is not (the deal that) will be laid on paper... We will be forced to ensure our security in the north (of Israel) and to systematically carry out operations against Hezbollah's attacks... even after a ceasefire", to keep the group from rebuilding its forces, Netanyahu told the Israeli parliament.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h903pudo_netanyahu_625x300_10_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fined-25-4-million-by-india-antitrust-body-whatsapp-data-sharing-blocked-for-5-years-7050158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Fined $25.4 Million By India, WhatsApp Data Sharing Blocked For 5 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fined-25-4-million-by-india-antitrust-body-whatsapp-data-sharing-blocked-for-5-years-7050158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 22:37:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's competition watchdog directed WhatsApp to refrain from sharing user data for advertising purposes with other applications owned by Meta for a period of five years and fined the U.S. tech giant $25.4 million on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's competition watchdog directed WhatsApp to refrain from sharing user data for advertising purposes with other applications owned by Meta for a period of five years and fined the U.S. tech giant $25.4 million on Monday over antitrust violations related to the messaging application's 2021 privacy policy.</p>

<p>The Competition Commission of India (CCI) launched a probe in March 2021 into WhatsApp's privacy policy, which allowed data sharing with Facebook and its units, sparking global backlash.</p>

<p>"Sharing of user data collected on WhatsApp with other Meta companies... for purposes other than for providing WhatsApp service shall not be made a condition for users to access WhatsApp Service in India," the CCI said.</p>

<p>Meta did not immediately respond to Reuters' request for comment.</p>

<p>Tech giants, including Apple, Google and Meta face new regulatory challenges with India's proposed EU-like antitrust law.</p>

<p>The Indian government is currently examining a February report from a panel established by the corporate affairs ministry. The report proposed a new "Digital Competition Bill" to complement existing antitrust laws.</p>

<p>The U.S.-India Business Council, a key U.S. lobby group has already opposed the move, fearing its business impact.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dlcdtomo_meta-generic_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta faces new regulatory challenges with India's proposed EU-like antitrust law. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-peace-in-middle-east-might-be-beyond-donald-trumps-dealmaking-skills-7050063]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Peace In The Middle East Might Be Beyond Trump's Deal-Making Skills]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-peace-in-middle-east-might-be-beyond-donald-trumps-dealmaking-skills-7050063]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 22:27:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trumps re-election as the US president last week comes at a time of extreme volatility in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's re-election as the US president last week comes at a time of extreme volatility in the Middle East.</p>

<p>The president-elect has promised to end all wars. In his usual impulsive and unpredictable manner, he has pledged to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-russia-ukraine-war-un-election-a78ecb843af452b8dda1d52d137ca893">resolve</a> the Ukraine war within 24 hours of taking office and help Israel <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-mideast-netanyahu-israel-gaza-iran-wars-2e37305522d19bdc34e956586cce99bd">finish</a> its Gaza and Lebanon operations quickly.</p>

<p>Yet the Middle East is a complex place. Trump will have much difficulty balancing his ardent support of Israel and his other ambitions in the region, especially given the changing dynamics between Iran and its rival, Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>Here's what Trump can expect when he takes office in a few months.</p>

<h2>Collapse of talks between Israel and Hamas</h2>

<p>Overshadowed by the US election was Qatar's announcement that it has <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/09/politics/qatar-gaza-ceasefire-pause-mediator/index.html">paused</a> its role as a ceasefire mediator between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>The tiny, oil-rich emirate has worked hard over the past year to try to reach a deal to end the war. In the process, it made good use of its close relations with the United States, which has its largest Middle East military base in Qatar, and with Hamas, whose political leadership and office have been based in Doha. This, Qatar believed, would help it gain the confidence of the warring parties.</p>

<p>However, its efforts did not produce anything more than a <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2023/11/27/middleeast/israel-hamas-truce-extended-intl/index.html">brief ceasefire</a> last year, which resulted in the release of more than 100 Israeli hostages in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Lebanon Ceasefire: Israel and Lebanon are reportedly “in advanced stages” of reaching a ceasefire agreement. This deal appears to attempt to more successfully implement UNSCR 1701, which prohibits Lebanese Hezbollah military activity in southern Lebanon. <a href="https://t.co/lV2KCHvNcj">https://t.co/lV2KCHvNcj</a> <a href="https://t.co/Qq9Gb20icw">pic.twitter.com/Qq9Gb20icw</a></p>
— Institute for the Study of War (@TheStudyofWar) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheStudyofWar/status/1851452376185520352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>There are several reasons for this.</p>

<p>For one, the two sides cannot get past a couple of main sticking points. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has resolved to eliminate Hamas completely, ruling out a <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-news-06-24-2024-f5de2ed8288ac3cdb02c4e9e2fbaeda1">temporary truce</a>. Hamas is demanding a complete end to the fighting and total Israeli military withdrawal from Gaza.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Washington has failed to play a meaningful role in the talks. While repeatedly emphasising its desire for a ceasefire, the Biden administration did not at any point put tangible pressure on Israel beyond diplomatic rhetoric.</p>

<p>It has also refused to cut off military aid to Israel. Instead, it <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-gaza-20-billion-weapons-us-aid-b6a99129c88a5dcc4a4753e20b5e19ec">approved a US$20&nbsp;billion</a> (A$30&nbsp;billion) arms sale to Israel in August. This means Netanyahu has had no compelling reason to divert from his mission.</p>

<h2>A possible ceasefire in Lebanon</h2>

<p>As the chances of a Gaza ceasefire have faded, hopes have been raised about a Lebanon ceasefire.</p>

<p>Washington has reportedly <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c14ln6kkkg7o">engaged</a> in intensive diplomatic efforts to get Israel and Hezbollah to reach a common ground to end the fighting there.</p>

<p>Israel wants Hezbollah to be disarmed and pushed back at least beyond the Litani River in southern Lebanon – about 30km north of the Israeli border – with a security zone to be established between the two. Israel <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c14ln6kkkg7o">wants to maintain</a> the right to strike Hezbollah if necessary, which Lebanese authorities are likely to reject.</p>

<p>Israel has considerably weakened Hezbollah in its bombing and ground invasion of southern Lebanon at the expense of <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-lebanon-hezbollah-news-10-16-2024-f18b2e0f5e05eb11a3c2ee29c16ed867">massive civilian casualties</a>.</p>

<p>However, just as Israel has not been able to wipe out Hamas, it has so far <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/targeted-killings-wont-destroy-hezbollah">not succeeded in crippling Hezbollah</a> to the extent it would be forced to accept a ceasefire on Israel's terms. The militant group continues to possess sufficient political and military prowess to remain resilient.</p>

<h2>Changing regional dynamics</h2>

<p>Now, Trump re-enters the scene.</p>

<p>His electoral triumph has comforted Netanyahu's government to the extent that his finance minister, Bezalel Smotrich, has <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/smotrich-says-trumps-victory-an-opportunity-to-apply-sovereignty-in-the-west-bank/">asked</a> the relevant authorities to prepare for the formal annexation of Jewish settlements in the West Bank.</p>

<p>Trump has been a committed supporter of Israel for a long time. During his first presidency he <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/06/world/middleeast/trump-jerusalem-israel-capital.html">recognised</a> Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and ordered the US embassy to move there. He also <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-47697717">recognised</a> Israeli sovereignty over the Golan Heights, which Israel seized from Syria in 1967.</p>

<p>He castigated Iran as the real villain in the region and <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/briefings-statements/president-donald-j-trump-ending-united-states-participation-unacceptable-iran-deal/">withdrew</a> the US from the multilateral Iran nuclear agreement. He also instigated the <a href="https://www.state.gov/the-abraham-accords/">Abraham Accords</a>, in which several Arab states normalised relations with Israel.</p>

<p>However, the Gaza and Lebanon wars, as well as the direct military exchanges between Israel and Iran over the past year, have changed the regional texture.</p>

<p>Trump has voiced unwavering backing of Israel against Hamas and Hezbollah, and is likely to resuscitate his “<a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/national-security-daily/2024/11/08/a-sneak-peak-on-trumps-iran-policy-00183727">maximum pressure</a>” campaign against Iran. This could involve strangling Tehran with stringent sanctions and blocking its oil exports, while seeking to isolate it internationally.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President-elect Donald Trump plans to drastically increase sanctions on Iran and throttle its oil sales, according to people briefed on his early plans <a href="https://t.co/43wvCXt5NH">https://t.co/43wvCXt5NH</a></p>
— The Wall Street Journal (@WSJ) <a href="https://twitter.com/WSJ/status/1855081421129367813?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, as a transactional leader, Trump also wants to strengthen America's lucrative economic and trade ties with the Arab governments of the region.</p>

<p>However, these countries have been shaken by the scale of Israel's Gaza and Lebanon operations. Their populations are boiling over with frustration at their leaders' inability to counter Israel's actions. This is nowhere more evident than in <a href="https://www.barrons.com/news/jordanians-boiling-with-anger-at-gaza-spurring-israel-border-attacks-f09c55ae">Jordan</a>.</p>

<p>As a result, Saudi Arabia – America's richest and most consequential Arab ally in the region – has lately <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/11/11/israeli-wars-in-gaza-lebanon-on-arab-islamic-summit-agenda-in-saudi-arabia">taken the lead</a> in voicing strong opposition to Israel. Saudi Arabia's de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, has also made a path toward an independent Palestinian state a <a href="https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/saudi-crown-prince-says-no-normalisation-israel-without-palestinian-statehood">condition</a> of normalising relations with Israel.</p>

<p>Further, Riyadh is strengthening its more than year-long rapprochement with its arch rival, Iran. The two countries' defence ministers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/saudi-armed-forces-general-chief-staff-hold-talks-iran-2024-11-10/">met</a> last weekend, following a <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/iran-and-saudi-arabia-hold-joint-naval-exercise-in-sea-of-oman/">joint military exercise</a> involving their navies.</p>

<p>In addition, Bin Salman has just <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/12/middleeast/saudi-mbs-accuses-israel-genocide-gaza-intl/index.html">convened</a> a meeting of Arab and Muslim leaders in Riyadh to forge a consensual position in dealing with Israel and the incoming Trump administration.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Gulf states wary of return to Trump's ‘maximum pressure' against Iran <a href="https://t.co/CogsazuGbf">https://t.co/CogsazuGbf</a></p>
— Financial Times (@FT) <a href="https://twitter.com/FT/status/1856293825922138268?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h2>Where is it all heading?</h2>

<p>Trump will need to find a balance between his commitment to Israel and upholding America's close relations with its traditional Arab allies. This will be crucial to ending the Middle East wars and rebuffing Iran.</p>

<p>Tehran is no longer as vulnerable to Trump's venom as it may have been in the past. It is more powerful militarily and enjoys strong strategic relations with Russia, China and North Korea, as well as improved relations with regional Arab states.</p>

<p>Given the absence of a Gaza ceasefire, the thin hope of a halt to the Lebanon fighting, Netanyahu's intransigence and Trump's pursuance of an “Israel first” policy, the Middle East's volatility is likely to persist.</p>

<p>It may prove to be as much of a headache for Trump as it was for Joe Biden in a very polarised and unpredictable world.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/243570/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em>(<strong>Author:</strong> <span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amin-saikal-1413547">Amin Saikal</a>, Emeritus Professor of Middle Eastern and Central Asian Studies, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/australian-national-university-877">Australian National University</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> Amin Saikal does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment.)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/donald-trump-fancies-himself-a-skilled-dealmaker-but-middle-east-peace-might-be-beyond-him-243570">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/48oemgp_israel-us-reuters_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has voiced unwavering backing of Israel against Hamas and Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-62-000-dead-in-sudans-civil-war-real-figure-might-be-far-higher-7049900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Least 62,000 Dead In Sudan's Civil War, Real Figure Might Be Far Higher]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-62-000-dead-in-sudans-civil-war-real-figure-might-be-far-higher-7049900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 21:59:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ongoing war in Sudan has often been overlooked amid higher-profile conflicts raging across multiple continents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.cfr.org/global-conflict-tracker/conflict/power-struggle-sudan">ongoing war in Sudan</a> has often been overlooked amid higher-profile conflicts raging across multiple continents. Yet the lack of media and geopolitical attention to this 18-month-long conflict has not made its devastation in terms of human lives any less stark.</p>

<p>Since fighting broke out in April 2023 between the Sudanese Armed Forces and the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, both of which had been part of a power-sharing military government, the country has seen the displacement of <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sudan-war-refugees-displaced-un-8672055b2a23b019662e8005a8c54e77">more than 14 million people</a> and the carving up of the country by geography and ideology.</p>

<p>And while we may never know the exact death toll, the conflict in Sudan is certainly among the deadliest in the world today.</p>

<p>As scholars of <a href="https://pul.uclouvain.be/author/?person_id=5196">public health</a>, conflict and <a href="https://publichealth.berkeley.edu/people/rohini-haar">human rights</a> and <a href="https://sapa-usa.org/team/">Sudanese-American health workers</a>, we are keenly aware of how fraught it can be to estimate mortality in war for a slew of practical and political reasons. But such estimates are of critical importance: They allow us to understand and compare conflicts, target humanitarian aid for those still at risk, trigger investigations of war crimes, bear witness to conflict and compel states and armed groups to intervene or change.</p>

<h2>The difficult work of counting the dead</h2>

<p>A profound humanitarian crisis is occurring in Sudan, characterized by <a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2024/05/09/sudan-ethnic-cleansing-west-darfur">ethnic cleansing</a>, <a href="https://dtm.iom.int/sudan">mass displacement</a>, <a href="https://www.wfp.org/countries/sudan">food scarcity</a> and the <a href="https://www.unicef.org/sudan/press-releases/over-three-million-children-heighted-risk-cholera-and-other-deadly-diseases-sudan">spread of disease</a>, complicated further by flooding in the northern states.</p>

<p>Considering a death toll in such a conflict includes counting not only those who are killed as a direct result of violence – itself a difficult thing to determine in real time – but also those who have died by conflict-exacerbated factors, such as the absence of emergency care, the breakdown of vaccination programs and a lack of essential food and medicine. Estimating this latter death toll, called indirect mortality, presents its own challenge, as the definition itself varies among researchers.</p>

<p>In congressional testimony, U.S. special envoy to Sudan Tom Perriello <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/05/28/sudan-war-genocide-el-fasher-humanitarian-aid-crisis/">recognized the estimation challenges</a> when noting there had been anywhere between 15,000 and 150,000 deaths in Sudan – an exceedingly wide range that was attributable, in part, to the complexity of determining indirect mortality.</p>

<p><a href="https://acleddata.com/">Armed Conflict Location and Event Data</a> (ACLED), a nonprofit specializing in conflict-related data collection, <a href="https://acleddata.com/">has recorded</a> an average of more than 1,200 direct conflict deaths per month in Sudan, with nearly 19,000 deaths in the first 15 months of the conflict. This figure is similar to the 20,000 deaths <a href="https://english.aawsat.com/node/5034313">estimated</a> by the Sudan Doctors Union and the 19,000 <a href="https://reliefweb.int/report/sudan/glance-protection-impacts-conflict-update-no-29-15-july-2024">figure used by</a> the Sudan Protection Cluster, a centralized group of U.N. agencies and NGOs that used World Health Organization data.</p>

<p>ACLED <a href="https://acleddata.com/knowledge-base/faqs-acled-sourcing-methodology/">sources its estimates</a> of deaths from traditional media, reports from international NGOs and local observers, supplemented by new media such as verified Telegram and WhatsApp accounts. The Sudan Doctors Union, on the other hand, gives on-the-ground estimates of conflict deaths.</p>

<p>When available, distinct data sources such as surveys, civil registers and official body counts can make an estimation more accurate. However, this data is often available only in retrospect, after the cessation of conflict. It is therefore critical to use both the available data and precedents from previous conflicts to capture a reasonable estimate of the human costs of an ongoing conflict.</p>

<p>A 2010 article in The Lancet estimated that there are <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20109956/">2.3 indirect deaths for every direct conflict death</a>, based on data from 24 small-scale surveys conducted in Darfur from 2003 to 2005. As such, using ACLED's data of 18,916 direct deaths, we estimate that in the current Sudan conflict, there are an additional 43,507 indirect deaths – or more than 62,000 total deaths.</p>

<p>We believe our estimate is very conservative. When estimating mortality in the ongoing conflict in Gaza, a different group of scholars, <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(24)01169-3/fulltext">also writing in The Lancet</a>, used a multiplier of four indirect deaths for every direct death to estimate the overall mortality there.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a <a href="https://www.refworld.org/reference/research/gds/2008/en/64390">report from the Geneva Declaration Secretariat</a> showed an average of 5.8 indirect deaths for every direct death across 13 armed conflicts from 1974 to 2007.</p>

<p>Using that latter multiplier, the number of indirect deaths in Sudan would jump to nearly 110,000 – meaning the total deaths in the region amount to 130,000 – double our estimate.</p>

<p>This range is wide, but it acknowledges how difficult it can be to estimate indirect deaths and how they can vary significantly with the shape of a conflict.</p>

<h2>The Sudanese conflict in context</h2>

<p>For all the tremendous loss of life these numbers reflect, they surely underestimate the true human costs of the conflict.</p>

<p>Sudan <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10928779/">already had a fragile</a> and <a href="https://doi.org//10.1007/s40475-021-00237-2">underfunded health system</a> before the fighting started. And compared with other ongoing conflicts such as in <a href="https://www.unicef.org/sop/what-we-do/health-and-nutrition">Gaza</a> and <a href="https://data.unicef.org/country/ukr/">Ukraine</a>, there was already a more precarious baseline, with <a href="https://data.unicef.org/country/sdn/">higher child mortality</a> and lower life expectancy.</p>

<p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="w2RzA" scrolling="no" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/w2RzA/1/" style="border: 0;" width="100%"></iframe></p>

<p>Since the <a href="https://reliefweb.int/country/sdn">war in Sudan</a> began, there have been <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2023/08/sudan-war-crimes-rampant-as-civilians-killed-in-both-deliberate-and-indiscriminate-attacks-new-report/">consistent reports</a> of <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/11/10/corpses-on-streets-sudans-rsf-kills-1300-in-darfur-monitors-say">mass killings</a>, forced disappearances, <a href="https://www.un.org/africarenewal/magazine/july-2023/sudan-un-condemns-spike-violence-against-women-and-girls">sexual violence</a>, deliberate blocking of food and medicine, and other forms of <a href="https://www.hrw.org/report/2024/05/09/massalit-will-not-come-home/ethnic-cleansing-and-crimes-against-humanity-el">violence against civilians</a>.</p>

<p>Much of the violence is ethnically targeted, and the Darfur region – where a <a href="https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/famine-confirmed-sudans-north-darfur-confirming-un-agencies-worst-fears">full-scale famine has been declared</a> – has suffered disproportionately.</p>

<p>The destruction of civilian infrastructure and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sudan-darfur-starvation-violence-united-nations-295c2bf7ac311313313dd44d021d8d11">interrupted aid mechanisms</a> are preventing medicine, food, clean water and vaccinations from getting to in-need populations.</p>

<p>Health care workers and facilities, not only in at-risk Darfur but also throughout the country, <a href="https://english.aawsat.com/node/5034313">have been the target of attacks</a>. Nearly 80% of medical facilities have been rendered inoperable. And at least 58 physicians <a href="https://english.aawsat.com/node/5034313">have been killed</a>, in addition to the many that were <a href="https://phr.org/our-work/resources/chaos-and-fire-an-analysis-of-sudans-june-3-2019-khartoum-massacre/">targeted in previous crises</a>.</p>

<p>Given the persistent targeting of health care systems and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/attack-icrc-convoy-sudans-south-darfur-kills-two-drivers-injures-three-2024-05-03/">restricted access to humanitarian corridors</a>, indirect deaths in Sudan are likely to grow as hospitals shut down, even in the capital Khartoum, due to bombardments, ground attacks and a lack of critical supplies.</p>

<p>The costs for Sudanese children are especially alarming. Thirteen children die per day in Zamzam camp in North Darfur, according to Doctors Without Borders, mostly due to <a href="https://www.msf.org/sudan-urgent-response-needed-amid-high-death-rates-and-malnutrition-crisis-north-darfur">undernutrition and food scarcity</a>.</p>

<p>And nearly 800,000 Sudanese children will <a href="https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/famine-confirmed-sudans-north-darfur-confirming-un-agencies-worst-fears">face severe, acute malnutrition</a> through 2024, a condition that requires intensive care and supplemental nutrition merely to prevent death. Even before the conflict, children were severely threatened <a href="https://data.who.int/countries/729">by a lack of access to care</a>, including basic preventive care such as early immunization.</p>

<p>Finally, the transmission of communicable diseases <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33692451/">thrives in conflicts like the one in Sudan</a>, where there has been widespread population displacement, malnutrition, limited water and sanitation, and lack of appropriate sheltering. In August, a <a href="https://www.care.org/news-and-stories/press-releases/care-statement-on-spread-of-cholera-in-sudan/">cholera outbreak</a> led to a <a href="https://www.aa.com.tr/en/africa/death-toll-from-cholera-outbreak-in-sudan-reaches-348/3335522">spiking death rate</a> of more than 31 deaths per 1,000 cholera cases. And instances of such disease effects are likely underestimates in a country lacking health care penetration and monitoring.</p>

<h2>The limitations of estimations</h2>

<p>The massive internal displacement of <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sudan-war-refugees-displaced-un-8672055b2a23b019662e8005a8c54e77">more than 14 million people</a> in Sudan complicates the estimation of death tolls, as shifting populations make establishing baselines nearly impossible.</p>

<p>Moreover, there is typically a <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37193053/">dearth of official information collected and released</a> during conflicts.</p>

<p>So establishing a concrete estimate of the true impact of armed conflict <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/stories/2022/11/forensic-investigators-bring-dr-congo-victims-closer-justice">often comes</a> after the cessation of hostilities, <a href="https://icmp.int/press-releases/icmp-assists-serbia-in-excavation-of-mass-grave-near-raska/">when expert teams</a> <a href="https://www.sapiens.org/archaeology/cyprus-war-missing/">are able</a> <a href="https://www.iclvr.ie/en/iclvr/pages/thedisappeared">to conduct</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoforum.2013.12.011">field studies</a>.</p>

<p>Even then, estimates will require assumptions about direct deaths, indirect-to-direct death ratio and the quality of existing data.</p>

<p>But as scholars working at the intersection of public health and human rights, we believe such work, however imperfect, is necessary for the documentation of conflict – and its future prevention. And while there are many current global conflicts that require our urgent attention, the conflict in Sudan must not be lost in the mix.</p>

<p>_Editor's note: Israa Hassan, a physical medicine and rehabilitation resident at Texas Rehabilitation Hospital-Fort Worth and <a href="https://sapa-usa.org/about-us/">advocacy director at the Sudanese American Physicians Association</a>, contributed to this article.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/242073/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Authors:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/sarah-elizabeth-scales-2246791">Sarah Elizabeth Scales</a>, Post-Doctoral Researcher, Department of Environmental, Occupational, and Agricultural Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-nebraska-medical-center-5675">University of Nebraska Medical Center</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/blake-erhardt-ohren-2247945">Blake Erhardt-Ohren</a>, DrPH Candidate, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-california-berkeley-754">University of California, Berkeley</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/debarati-guha-sapir-2247595">Debarati Guha Sapir</a>, Professor of Public Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/universite-catholique-de-louvain-uclouvain-697">Université catholique de Louvain (UCLouvain)</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/khidir-dalouk-2247625">Khidir Dalouk</a>, Assistant Professor of Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/oregon-health-and-science-university-3386">Oregon Health &amp; Science University</a>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/rohini-j-haar-2241539">Rohini J Haar</a>, Faculty, Epidemiology Division, School of Public Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-california-berkeley-754">University of California, Berkeley</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:&nbsp;</strong></span>Rohini J Haar receives funding from FCDO. Blake Erhardt-Ohren, Debarati Guha Sapir, Khidir Dalouk, and Sarah Elizabeth Scales do not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and have disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/sudans-civil-war-has-left-at-least-62-000-dead-by-our-estimate-but-the-true-figure-could-be-far-higher-242073">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ehg8ip3s_sudan-civil-war-afp_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fighting broke out in April 2023 between the Sudanese Armed Forces and paramilitary Rapid Support Forces]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/carrot-recall-announced-in-us-after-e-coli-outbreak-in-18-states-7049588]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Carrot Recall Announced Across US After E. Coli Outbreak In 18 States]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/carrot-recall-announced-in-us-after-e-coli-outbreak-in-18-states-7049588]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 21:33:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Organic carrots and baby carrots sold in grocery stores across the United States are being recalled after an E. coli outbreak that has left at least one person dead and 15 others hospitalized.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Organic carrots and baby carrots sold in grocery stores across the United States are being recalled after an E. coli outbreak that has left at least one person dead and 15 others hospitalised. The move came after the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) on Sunday flagged the new E. coli outbreak linked to organic carrots sold by Grimmway Farms to big supermarkets-- including Trader Joe's, Whole Foods's 365, Walmart's Marketside, Target's Good &amp; Gather, among others</p>

<p>So far, 39 cases have been reported across 18 states tied the E. coli infections linked with fresh carrots, the CDC said in a statement.</p>

<h2><strong>Health Advisory</strong></h2>

<p>The CDC urged people to not eat any recalled carrots and to wash items and surfaces that may have touched the bagged organic root veggie using hot, soapy water or a dishwasher. The carrots are unlikely to still be on store shelves, but may still be in consumers' homes and should be thrown away, the agency said.</p>

<h3><strong>Carrots Recalled</strong></h3>

<p>As per the US Food and Drug Administration, Grimmway Farms had issued a voluntary recall of the carrots, which were also shipped to stores in Canada and Puerto Rico.</p>

<p>Notably, the recalled whole organic carrots had best-if-used-by dates ranging from August 14 through October 23, while the recalled baby carrots had dates from September 11 through November 12.</p>

<p>Grimmway Farms, which was located in California, said in a Saturday press release that the company is reviewing its growing, harvesting and processing practices and that it is working with suppliers and health authorities on the matter. The previously family-owned company was reportedly sold to private equity firm Teays River Investments in 2020.</p>

<h3><strong>E. coli Poisoning Symptoms</strong></h3>

<p>Most Escherichia coli (E. coli) bacteria reside harmlessly in the intestines of people and animals. But some can cause mild to life-threatening gastrointestinal illnesses if consumed, according to the CDC.</p>

<p>Symptoms of E. coli poisoning, including dehydration, bloody diarrhoea, vomiting, abdominal cramps and fever, appear between two to eight days after exposure.</p>

<p>Most people recover without treatment after five to seven days. In rare cases, especially seen among older adults and children under 5, people may develop a type of kidney failure called hemolytic uremic syndrome (HUS) which is marked by easy bruising, pallor, and decreased urine output. These people should seek emergency medical care immediately.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n7sih2e_carrots-pixabay_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Carrots recalled across the US after an E. Coli outbreak in more than a dozen states (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-bangladesh-ties-dhaka-islamabad-inch-closer-with-historic-sea-link-1st-since-1971-how-it-impacts-india-7048203]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dhaka, Islamabad Inch Closer With Historic Sea Link. How It Impacts India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-bangladesh-ties-dhaka-islamabad-inch-closer-with-historic-sea-link-1st-since-1971-how-it-impacts-india-7048203]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:14:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani cargo ship docked at Bangladeshs Chittagong port last week, marking the first-ever direct maritime contact between the two countries in over five decades. The vessel from Karachi has successfully unloaded its containers at the post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani cargo ship docked at Bangladesh's Chittagong port last week, marking the first-ever direct maritime contact between the two countries in over five decades. The vessel from Karachi has successfully unloaded its containers at Bangladesh's southeastern coast, port officials told news agency AFP on Sunday, as both sides seek to rebuild ties frosty since the 1971 Bangladesh Liberation War.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The direct maritime links between Pakistan and Bangladesh underscores a historic shift in the traditionally complex relationship between India's western and eastern neighbours. It also has implications on New Delhi's security establishment especially due to Bangladesh's proximity to India's northeastern states.</p>

<h2><strong>Docking Of Pakistani Vessel In Bangladesh</strong></h2>

<p>The Panama-flagged Yuan Xiang Fa Zhan, an 182-metre (597-foot) long container ship, had sailed from Pakistan's Karachi to Bangladesh's Chittagong. The ship had offloaded its cargo in Bangladesh on November 11 before leaving port, AFP reported quoting top Chittagong official Omar Faruq.</p>

<p>Chittagong port authorities reportedly said the ship brought goods from Pakistan and the United Arab Emirates, including raw materials for Bangladesh's key garment industry and basic food items.</p>

<p>Pakistani goods were previously transferred onto feeder vessels, usually in Sri Lanka, Malaysia or Singapore, before being transported to Bangladesh. However, in September, Bangladesh, under the new interim government led by Muhammad Yunus, eased import restrictions on Pakistani goods, which previously required a mandatory physical inspection on arrival resulting in long delays.</p>

<p>The opening of the direct maritime link is being seen as an attempt by Bangladesh's interim government to have robust ties with Pakistan.</p>

<p>There has been widespread discussion on social media in Bangladesh after a post by Pakistan's envoy to Dhaka, Syed Ahmed Maroof, about the direct shipping route being "a major step" in boosting trade between the two nations.</p>

<p>The route will "promote new opportunities for businesses on both sides", Mr Maroof wrote on Facebook.</p>

<h3><strong>Bangladesh-Pakistan Relations And Shadow Of 1971 Liberation War</strong></h3>

<p>Pakistan and Bangladesh - once one nation - split in 1971 following Mukti Juddho (Liberation War). The memory of the brutal war, which saw the killing of some 3 million people and the rape and torture of tens of thousands of others, remained deeply imprinted in Bangladesh's national psyche till recently.</p>

<p>Formerly known as East Pakistan, Bangladesh became an independent nation after a nine-month war with West Pakistan in 1971 in which India aided Bengali freedom fighters.</p>

<p>The bilateral ties between Pakistan and Bangladesh have remained sour since the Liberation War, more so under Sheikh Hasina's regime in Dhaka, whose central political agenda had been to seek justice for atrocities committed by Pakistan during the brutal war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who ruled Bangladesh from 1996-2001 and 2009-2024, set up the International Crimes Tribunal in 2010 to prosecute war criminals or <em>razakars</em> for their war crimes in 1971. She also banned the historically pro-Pakistan Jamaat-e-Islami, whose leader Abdul Quader Mollah was convicted by the ICT in 2013 for war crimes. Mollah became the first of many <em>razakars</em> to be executed during Ms Hasina's reign.</p>

<h3><strong>India-Bangladesh Relation Post-1971</strong></h3>

<p>Meanwhile, Ms Hasina kept bringing Bangladesh closer to India over the year. India already held a close bond with Bangladeshis, courtesy of New Delhi's assistance in the Bangladesh Liberation War.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ousted former Prime Minister and her family reportedly enjoyed a close personal relationship with the Nehru-Gandhi family, but her government's clampdown on terrorism and religious extremism proved to be a strategic glue that bound successive Indian governments to her regime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her relationship with New Delhi helped her flee to India on August 5 after a student-led revolution against her regime escalated. But, Bangladesh's ties with New Delhi frayed after the toppling of her autocratic Hasina regime.</p>

<h3><strong>Hasina's Ouster</strong></h3>

<p>For years, Ms Hasina reaped political mileage from her party and family's contribution to Bangladesh's liberation, however, the recent protests across the nation seem to indicate that the sentiment does not echo many.</p>

<p>So, when Ms Hasina branded the protestors as <em>"razakars"</em> in July, it backfired, leading to outrage amidst real social and economic concerns plaguing the country.</p>

<p>Furthermore, there was reportedly resentment among Bangladeshis against Ms Hasina for “cozying up” to New Delhi. As per a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/pakistani-cargo-bangladesh-9671748/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Indian Express</a>, many in Bangladesh felt that India was too involved in the country's matters. The growing “anti-India” sentiment in Bangladesh was on display when a mob in August vandalised and torched the Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre (IGCC), the hub of Indian cultural activity in the Bangladeshi capital for over five decades.</p>

<p>The Jamaat-e-Islami, which opposed the creation of Bangladesh, has a strong presence in the post-Hasina dispensation in Dhaka.</p>

<h3><strong>Growing Pakistan and Bangladesh Ties</strong></h3>

<p>After Ms Hasina's ouster, Mr Yunus' interim government has shown a shift towards closer ties with Pakistan. Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif of Pakistan and Mr Yunus discussed strengthening bilateral cooperation on the sidelines of the United Nations General Assembly in September this year.</p>

<p>“The maritime link is essential for reviving our relations,” Mr Yunus recently said, calling for a “new page” in Pakistan-Bangladesh ties to enhance cooperation in different sectors.</p>

<p>Bangladesh also seems to be going the Pakistan way with the country's Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman calling for removing the words “socialism” and “secularism” from Bangladesh's constitution. The proposal has sparked fears the predominantly Muslim nation could be shifting toward an Islamic state.</p>

<p>Moreover, Bangladesh is also seeking the extradition of ousted Ms Hasina, who remains in exile in India. Dhaka has already issued an arrest warrant for the 77-year-old and has summoned her to appear in court in Dhaka to face charges of "massacres, killings, and crimes against humanity".</p>

<p>Mr Yunus said his administration was focused on ensuring those guilty of cracking down on the protests to oust Ms Hasina faced justice.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old Nobel Peace Prize winner was appointed to lead the government as "chief advisor" on August 9, days after the end of Ms Hasina's 15 years of iron-fisted rule. Mr Yunus, in a speech to the nation marking 100 days in power since a student-led revolution, said he had spoken to Karim Khan, chief prosecutor of the International Criminal Court.</p>

<p>"We will seek the extradition of the ousted autocrat from India," Mr Yunus said, referring to Ms Hasina.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Bangladesh said it would request an Interpol "red notice" alert for fugitive leaders of Ms Hasina's regime. Red notices issued by the global police body alert law enforcement agencies worldwide about fugitives.</p>

<p>India is a member of Interpol, but the red notice does not mean New Delhi must hand Ms Hasina over. Member countries can "apply their own laws in deciding whether to arrest a person", according to the group, which organises police cooperation between 196 member countries.</p>

<h3><strong>Impact On India</strong></h3>

<p>With increasing narcotics trade linked to Pakistan, growing ties between Islamabad and Dhaka could become a national security concern for India&nbsp; Another security concern for New Delhi is the involvement of Pakistan's spy agency ISI in activities that destabilise the region.</p>

<p>Over the years, India has used its relationship with Ms Hasina to keep an eye on the activities at Chittagong port, where in 2004, around 1,500 boxes of Chinese ammunitions were confiscated. The consignment, reportedly worth an estimated USD 4.5-7 million, was allegedly masterminded by Pakistan's intelligence agency, the Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI).</p>

<p>The consignment was allegedly meant to be delivered to banned terrorist outfit ULFA (United Liberation Front of Asom) in India.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus however, has assured that Dhaka-Delhi relations should be "very close" despite the recent regime change in the country, asserting that it is in the interest of both countries.</p>

<p>"Relations between the two countries must be very close. There can be no alternative to this. They need this, we need this. This is essential from any angle, whether it's about economics, security or water," he was quoted as saying by Bengali language daily <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/interview/ox81d7gkfs" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Prothom Alo</a> in October.</p>

<p>When asked for his comments on recent tensions in bilateral ties, Mr Yunus said the recent incidents in Bangladesh might have "disheartened" India and "they were not pleased with the changes." He did not mention the incidents.</p>

<p>"It will be difficult for us to move along without each other. It is only natural that we have close ties and good relations in every sphere,” he said.</p>

<p>India has urged the interim Bangladesh government to ensure peaceful religious events for the Hindu community in the South Asian country. More than 600 persons, including Hindus, were killed during violent protests in Bangladesh following the ouster of Hasina-led government, according to a UN report.</p>

<p>"Things will be clear to them when they see that the entire world is accepting us, how can they not accept us?" he added.</p>

<p>He said as far as South Asian diplomacy was concerned, his interim government placed high importance on strengthening ties with India and "at the same time, strengthening SAARC (South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation".<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h818gimg_merchant-ship-yuan-xiang-fa-zhan_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cargo ship Yuan Xiang Fa Zhan, carring goods from Pak, docked at Bangladesh's Chittagong port]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-ready-to-deliver-on-common-understandings-between-pm-modi-xi-jinping-says-china-7049026]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Ready To Deliver On Common Understandings Between PM Modi-Xi": China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-ready-to-deliver-on-common-understandings-between-pm-modi-xi-jinping-says-china-7049026]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 19:53:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China said it stands ready to deliver on important common understandings reached between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping during the recent BRICS summit leading to a thaw in the relations frozen for over four years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China on Monday said it stands ready to deliver on important common understandings reached between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping during the recent BRICS summit leading to a thaw in the relations frozen for over four years due to a military standoff in Eastern Ladakh.</p>

<p>“Recently, President Xi Jinping met with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on the margins of the BRICS summit held in Kazan,” Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Lin Jian told a media briefing here while responding to a question on the likelihood of a meeting the two leaders on the sidelines of G20 summit in Brazil.</p>

<p>“China stands ready to work with India to deliver on the important common understandings between the leaders of the two countries, step up communication and cooperation and enhance strategic mutual trust,” he said, adding that he has no information on the specifics of the meeting of the leaders and officials.</p>

<p>At their Kazan meeting, the two leaders endorsed the India-China agreement on patrolling and disengagement along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in eastern Ladakh and issued directions to revive various bilateral dialogue mechanisms, signalling attempts to normalise ties that were hit by a deadly military clash in 2020.</p>

<p>In the nearly 50-minute meeting held on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit at Kazan, PM Modi underscored the importance of properly handling differences and disputes and not allowing them to disturb peace and tranquility in border areas and that mutual trust, mutual respect and mutual sensitivity should remain the basis of the relations.</p>

<p>Xi said China-India relations are essentially a question of how the two large developing countries and neighbours, each with a 1.4-billion-strong population, treat each other.</p>

<p>China and India should maintain a sound strategic perception of each other and work together to find the "right and bright path" for big, neighbouring countries to live in harmony and develop side by side, he said.</p>

<p>The ties between the two Asian giants nosedived significantly following the fierce clash in the Galwan Valley in June 2020 that marked the most serious military conflict between the two sides in decades.</p>

<p>On Oct 21, India and China firmed up an agreement on patrolling and disengagement of troops along the LAC in eastern Ladakh, in a breakthrough to end the over four-year standoff.</p>

<p>Both leaders also instructed the Special Representatives on the India-China boundary question to meet at an early date and to continue their efforts to address the issues related to the Line of Actual Control (LAC).</p>

<p>India's Special Representative for the dialogue is NSA Ajit Doval while the Chinese side is headed at the talks by Foreign Minister Wang Yi.</p>

<p>The Special Representatives mechanism was constituted in 2003. The two sides held 20 rounds of talks since then. The last meeting was held in 2019.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mvn5qm1_modi-xi-jinping_625x300_30_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi-Xi had endorsed the agreement on patrolling and disengagement along the LAC.(FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-says-made-mistakes-on-immigration-plans-big-change-7048582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau Says 'Made Mistakes' On Immigration, Plans Big Change]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-says-made-mistakes-on-immigration-plans-big-change-7048582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:55:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a recent video message, Trudeau stated that Canada's population has grown rapidly over the past two years, but this growth has also been accompanied by exploitation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has acknowledged that his government's immigration policy has been exploited by "bad actors" such as “fake colleges” and large corporations, leading to a significant shift in the country's immigration strategy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This comes in amid Trudeau's descending popularity ahead of the General Elections in Canada next year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a recent video message, Trudeau stated that Canada's population has grown rapidly over the past two years, but this growth has also been accompanied by exploitation.</p>

<p>He said "In the last two years, our population has grown really fast, like a baby boom...Increasingly bad actors like fake colleges and big chain corporations have been exploiting our immigration system for their own interests."</p>

<p>The people of Canada have been accusing the Prime Minister and his party of bad management, housing shortages, inflation and the health and transport systems of the country. The opposition has also claimed that he does not prioritise the needs of the Canadian citizens.</p>

<p>"We made some mistakes and that's why we are taking this big turn," he said, giving grounds for the government's action.</p>

<p>To address these issues, Trudeau announced that Canada will reduce the number of immigrants entering the country over the next three years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Immigration Minister Marc Miller outlined the government's plan, which includes admitting approximately 395,000 permanent residents in 2025, a 20% decrease from the previous year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The number of temporary immigrants, including international students and foreign workers, will also decrease to around 446,000 in 2025 and 2026, down from 800,000 this year.</p>

<p>Canada's new immigration plan prioritises permanent residents with skills in healthcare and construction. Trudeau emphasised that the goal is to stabilise population growth while addressing housing shortages and cost-of-living issues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trudeau said Canada's immigration plan is very "straightforward -- lower the number of immigrants -- both permanent and temporary."</p>

<p>The government also ended the popular fast-track study visa program, SDS, which may impact international students, particularly those from India, who make up the largest group of foreign students in Canada.</p>

<p>The immigration system overhaul aims to prevent exploitation by fake colleges and corporations. Trudeau acknowledged that Canada's focus on permanent immigration led to neglect of temporary immigration pathways. The government now seeks to balance economic growth with community needs.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v170vjs8_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trudeau announced that Canada will reduce the number of immigrants entering the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/conservation-expert-warns-earth-is-in-midst-of-sixth-great-extinction-we-dont-have-time-left-7048399]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Expert Says Earth Is In Midst Of Sixth Great Extinction: "We Don't Have..."]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/conservation-expert-warns-earth-is-in-midst-of-sixth-great-extinction-we-dont-have-time-left-7048399]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:31:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The conservationist noted that the crisis, driven largely by human activity, threatens the survival of countless species and the delicate balance of ecosystems worldwide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Renowned primatologist and conservationist Dr Jane Goodall has sounded the alarm on the biodiversity crisis, warning that Earth is in the midst of the "sixth great extinction." Unlike previous mass extinctions caused by natural phenomena, this crisis is almost entirely human-induced. In an exclusive interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c93qvqx5y01o" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC</em></a>, Dr Goodall emphasized the human role in this crisis and the urgent need for action. The conservationist noted that the&nbsp;crisis, driven largely by human activities like deforestation, threatens the survival of countless species and the delicate balance of ecosystems worldwide.</p>

<p>"We're in the midst of the sixth great extinction. The more we can do to restore nature and protect existing forests, the better. Trees have to grow to a certain size before they can really do their work. But all this [tree-planting] is helping to absorb carbon dioxide," Dr Goodall told&nbsp;Victoria Gill during an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b036f7w2" target="_self">interview for BBC Radio 4's Inside Science</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Goodall stressed the importance of taking immediate action to mitigate global warming. She emphasised that there is still a narrow window of opportunity to combat climate change and biodiversity loss, but it is rapidly closing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If we don't get together and impose tough regulations on what people can do to the environment - if we don't rapidly move away from fossil fuel, if we don't put a stop to industrial farming, that's destroying the environment and killing the soil, having a devastating effect on biodiversity - the future ultimately is doomed," she noted.</p>

<p>Even at 90 years old, Dr. Jane Goodall shows no signs of slowing down in her relentless efforts for conservation and environmental advocacy. She firmly believes that if people care about their children's future, they must demand stronger environmental legislation. "Surely people want a future for their children. If they do, we have to get tougher about [environmental] legislation. We don't have much time left to start helping the environment. We've done so much to destroy it," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>What is the sixth mass extinction?</strong></h3>

<p>As per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.worldwildlife.org/stories/what-is-the-sixth-mass-extinction-and-what-can-we-do-about-it">WWF</a>, a&nbsp;mass extinction event is characterised by a significant loss of biodiversity over a relatively short geological period, resulting in the disappearance of a substantial percentage of distinct species across various taxonomic groups, including bacteria, fungi, plants, mammals, birds, reptiles, amphibians, fish, and invertebrates.</p>

<p>Throughout Earth's history, five mass extinctions have occurred, with the most recent one taking place 65.5 million years ago, famously wiping out the dinosaurs from existence. Now, experts warn that we are experiencing a sixth mass extinction event, that is mainly driven by human activities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unsustainable land, water, and energy use, along with climate change, are key factors. Currently, 40% of the Earth's land has been converted for food production, with severe environmental consequences. Agriculture is the primary driver of global deforestation, responsible for 90% of forest clearance. Further, the sector's immense water requirements account for 70% of the planet's freshwater usage. These practices have catastrophic effects on ecosystems, causing widespread habitat destruction and displacement of countless species.</p>

<p>Scientists estimate that around one million species are at risk of extinction in the coming decades unless urgent action is taken. Conservationists are calling for stronger global policies, increased funding for preservation, and individual action to reduce human impact on the planet.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9pk8b4pg_fossil-fuels_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Goodall stressed the importance of taking immediate action to mitigate global warming.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/10-flights-in-3-days-this-reddit-group-is-tracking-elon-musks-private-jet-7047913]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Flights In 3 Days: This Reddit Group Is Tracking Elon Musk's Private Jet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/10-flights-in-3-days-this-reddit-group-is-tracking-elon-musks-private-jet-7047913]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:29:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The group, created in 2022, gained significant attention after the tech billionaire became associated with the Donald Trump administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Reddit group that closely tracks the flight movements of billionaire Elon Musk has gone viral, gaining over 200,000 followers. The group, originally created in 2022, gained significant attention after the tech billionaire became associated with the Donald Trump administration. Similar to Jack Sweeney's famous @ElonJet account, it provides updates on Musk's private jet travels, including destinations, durations, and estimated carbon emissions. Data from the group shows Elon Musk's private jet has been quite busy, making 10 flights in just three days, crisscrossing the United States between Texas, Florida, and New York, following Donald Trump's election win.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Here's a recent post:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="reddit-embed-bq" data-embed-height="740" style="height:500px"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ElonJetTracker/comments/1gta8ip/landed_in_west_palm_beach_florida_united_states/">Landed in West Palm Beach, Florida, United States. Apx. flt. time 1 h 50 min.</a><br />
by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/plane-notify/">u/plane-notify</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ElonJetTracker/">ElonJetTracker</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://embed.reddit.com/widgets.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The tracking has sparked mixed reactions online. Some argued that it holds public figures accountable, particularly regarding environmental concerns. However, some called the monitoring an invasion of privacy, even though the data is legally sourced from public air traffic records.</p>

<p>One user wrote, ''He is now a politician. He has no right to privacy because he is not a private citizen anymore.'' Another commented, "I love this tracker. It's great to see a billionaire's physical presence in politics. How quickly into 2025 does the data become unavailable for this tracker."</p>

<p>A third said, "This is really what amazes me about these billionaires like Elon ever since I followed this sub. I'm annoyed if I have to leave my house more than once a day. This guy just lives on the move constantly, travelling between countries hourly, nonstop."</p>

<p>Notably, Musk has been criticized for his frequent use of private jets, which are known for their high carbon footprint. In June 2020,&nbsp;Jack Sweeney, a tech-savvy college student and programmer, created the now-infamous @ElonJet account on X to track and&nbsp;post real-time updates about the movements of his private jet. The student utilised Automatic Dependent Surveillance-Broadcast (ADS-B) technology, which publicly broadcasts the location, altitude, and speed of aircraft, to gather flight information. This data, which is legally available for public use, allowed Sweeney to pinpoint Musk's jet locations and post updates to the Twitter account.</p>

<p>However, Musk was not pleased with the tracking and reportedly offered Sweeney $5,000 to shut the account down, citing privacy and safety concerns. Sweeney countered by asking for $50,000, or an internship at Tesla, which Musk declined. The account amassed hundreds of thousands of followers before being banned from Twitter in late 2022, following Musk's acquisition of the platform.&nbsp;Since then, Sweeney has expanded his tracking efforts to include other prominent figures like Taylor Swift,&nbsp;who also threatened him with legal action.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gniajb58_elon-musk-wealth_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It provides updates on Musk's private jet travels, including destinations and durations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/im-watching-myself-watch-this-elon-musk-reacts-to-his-viral-lol-moment-7047892]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Viral: As Elon Musk Laughs At Memes, Trump Asks Him To Focus On UFC Match]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/im-watching-myself-watch-this-elon-musk-reacts-to-his-viral-lol-moment-7047892]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:26:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk accompanied Mr Trump, UFC chief executive Dana White, and Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard, country rock artist Kid Rock, RFK Jr, among others. Mr Trump's sons Eric and Don Jr were also in the audience for the bout.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video showing billionaire Elon Musk scrolling through his phone and laughing during an event in New York became a topic of discussion on social media. The video was recorded when Mr Musk was sitting right next to US President-elect Donald Trump at Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trump-elon-musk-in-front-row-seats-at-ufc-event-7039660">heavyweight bout</a> on Saturday. While the high-decibel event was on, the Tesla chief (and soon going to be the head of US' Department of Government Efficiency or DOGE) was seen cracking up while scrolling through his phone. Many social media users said the richest man on the planet is enjoying memes.</p>

<p>Resharing the post on his own timeline, Mr Musk commented, "I am watching myself watch this!" The video also shows Mr Trump gesturing to Mr Musk, encouraging him to focus on the fight.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm watching myself watch this ? <a href="https://t.co/37GMB1EQN9">https://t.co/37GMB1EQN9</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1858007852067000351?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The clip and Mr Musk's comment soon amassed thousands of responses on X (the platform he bought in 2022).</p>

<p>"This guy bought Twitter cause he was bored. Because he has no yacht and his jet is small. No crazy mansion I know of. What else? Just video games and memes. Until someone provoked him into politics," one user commented.</p>

<p>"I love seeing Elon happy, if we can make him laugh with some memes after everything he is going through just for trying to make the world and the West better, it's awesome," said another.</p>

<p>"Bahahaha.. he might fight Zuck by end of tonight," a third user said.</p>

<p>Mr Musk accompanied Mr Trump, UFC chief executive Dana White, and Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard, country rock artist Kid Rock, RFK Jr, among others. Mr Trump's sons Eric and Don Jr were also in the audience for the bout.</p>

<p>After Jon Jones defended his heavyweight title with a third-round technical knockout against fellow American Stipe Miocic in the main event, the fighter celebrated with Trump's trademark 'YMCA' dance.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/djp8n2eo_elon-musk-ufc_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk at the UFC match in New York on Saturday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ocean-plankton-survived-ice-age-but-may-not-cope-with-climate-change-now-7047885]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ocean Plankton Survived Ice Age But May Not Cope With Climate Change Now]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ocean-plankton-survived-ice-age-but-may-not-cope-with-climate-change-now-7047885]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:26:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In our new research, published today in Nature, we explored the ability of tiny marine organisms called plankton to adapt to global warming.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Global temperature records <a href="https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement">are expected</a> to <a href="https://climate.copernicus.eu/year-2024-set-end-warmest-record">exceed the 1.5 °C threshold</a> for the first time this year. This has happened much sooner than predicted. So can life on the planet adapt quickly enough?</p>

<p>In our new research, published today in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08029-0">Nature</a>, we explored the ability of tiny marine organisms called plankton to adapt to global warming. Our conclusion: some plankton are less able to adapt now than they were in the past.</p>

<p>Plankton live in the top few metres of ocean. These algae (phytoplankton) and animals (zooplankton) are transported by ocean currents as they do not actively swim.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg2/downloads/report/IPCC_AR6_WGII_SummaryForPolicymakers.pdf">Climate change is increasing</a> the frequency of heatwaves in the sea. But predicting the future effects of climate change is difficult because some projections depend on <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/downloads/factsheets/IPCC_AR6_WGI_Regional_Fact_Sheet_Ocean.pdf">ocean physics and chemistry</a>, while others consider the effects <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg2/downloads/outreach/IPCC_AR6_WGII_FactSheet_Biodiversity.pdf">on ecosystems and their services</a>.</p>

<p>Some data suggest that current climate change have already altered the marine plankton dramatically. Models project a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-25385-x">shift of plankton</a> towards both poles (where ocean temperatures are cooler), and losses to zooplankton in the tropics but might not predict the patterns we see in data. <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg2/chapter/chapter-3/">Satellite data for plankton biomass</a> are still too short term to determine trends through time.</p>

<p>To overcome these problems, we have compared how plankton responded to past environmental change and modelled how they could respond to future climate changes. As the scientist Charles Lyell said, <a href="https://www.geolsoc.org.uk/PodcastPresentPast">“the past is the key to the present”</a>.</p>

<p>We explored one of the best fossil records from a group of marine plankton with hard shells called <em>Foraminifera</em>. This <a href="https://doi.pangaea.de/10.1594/PANGAEA.873570">comprehensive database</a> of current and past distributions, compiled by researchers at the <a href="https://www.marum.de/en/AG-Micropaleontology-Paleoceanography.html">University of Bremen</a>, has been collected by hundreds of scientists from the seafloor across the globe since the 1960s. We compared data from the last ice age, around 21,000 years ago, and modern records to see what happened when the world has previously warmed.</p>

<p>We used computational models, which combine climate trends with traits of marine plankton and their effect on marine plankton, to simulate the oceanic ecosystems from the last ice age to the pre-industrial age. Comparing the model with the data from the fossil record is giving us support that the model simulated the rules determining plankton growth and distribution.</p>

<p>We found that some subtropical and tropical species' optimum temperature for peak growth and reproduction could deal with seawater warming in the past, supported by both fossil data and model. Colder water species of plankton managed to drift to flourish under more favourable water temperatures.</p>

<p>Our analysis shows that <em>Foraminifera</em> could handle the natural climate change, even without the need to adapt via evolution. But could they deal with the current warming and future changes in ocean conditions, such as temperature?</p>

<h2>Future of the food chain</h2>

<p>We used this model to predict the future under four different degrees of warming from 1.5 to 4 °C. Unfortunately, this type of plankton's ability to deal with climate change is much more limited than it was during past warming. Our study highlights the difference between faster human-induced and slower-paced geological warming for marine plankton. Current climate change is too rapid and is reducing food supply due to ocean stratification, both making plankton difficult to adapt to this time.</p>

<p>Phytoplankton produce around 50% of the world's oxygen. So every second breath we take comes from marine algae, while the rest comes from plants on land. Some plankton eat other plankton. That in turn gets eaten by fish and then marine mammals, so energy transfers further up the food chain. As it photosynthesises, phytoplankton is also a natural carbon fixation machine, storing 45 times <a href="https://essd.copernicus.org/articles/11/1783/2019/">more carbon than the atmosphere</a>.</p>

<p>Around the world, many people depend heavily on food from the ocean as their <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg2/chapter/chapter-3/">primary protein sources</a>. When climate change threatens marine plankton, this has huge knock-on effects throughout the rest of the marine food web. Plankton-eating marine mammals like whales won't have enough food to prey on and there'll be fewer fish to eat for predators (and people). Reducing warming magnitude and slowing down the warming rate are necessary to protect ocean health.</p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author</strong>:&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/rui-ying-2255366">Rui Ying</a>, Postdoctoral Researcher, Marine Ecology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-bristol-1211">University of Bristol</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/daniela-schmidt-429497">Daniela Schmidt</a>, Professor in Palaebiology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-bristol-1211">University of Bristol</a></span></em></p>

<p><em><span><strong>Disclosure Statement</strong>:&nbsp;</span></em><em><span>Rui Ying received funding from China Scholarship Council for this study.</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>Daniela Schmidt received funding from NERC. She is a member of NERC Science Committee and the council of the Palaeontological Association.)</span></em></p>

<p>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/tiny-oceanic-plankton-adapted-to-warming-during-the-last-ice-age-but-probably-wont-survive-future-climate-change-new-study-243317">original article</a>.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/aa902uco_planktons-pixabay_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some data suggest that current climate change have already altered the marine plankton dramatically.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-how-trump-may-bypass-senate-to-install-his-cabinet-picks-7047792]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Trump May Bypass Senate To Install His Cabinet Picks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-how-trump-may-bypass-senate-to-install-his-cabinet-picks-7047792]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:14:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump has said he might install his picks for top administration posts without first winning approval in the U.S. Senate. This would erode the power of Congress and remove a significant check on his authority as president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump has said he might install his picks for top administration posts without first winning approval in the U.S. Senate. This would erode the power of Congress and remove a significant check on his authority as president.</p>

<p><strong>HOW IS A CABINET APPROVED?</strong></p>

<p>According to the U.S. Constitution, the Senate and the president share the power of appointing top administration officials. Typically, senators question nominees for Secretary of Defense and other top posts at public hearings before voting on their fitness for office.</p>

<p>Roughly 1,000 government positions require Senate confirmation through a majority vote in the 100-seat chamber.</p>

<p>Most of Trump's Cabinet picks easily won confirmation during his first 2017-2021 term in office. But the Senate rejected some candidates and others, like Labor Secretary nominee Andrew Puzder, were forced to withdraw after it became clear they would not have enough support to win a confirmation vote.</p>

<p>The process has slowed as partisan divisions have deepened. Democratic President Joe Biden's cabinet appointees took an average of 191 days to win confirmation compared with an average of 85 days for Republican President George W. Bush, according to the Partnership for Public Service, which oversees presidential transitions.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT HAS TRUMP CALLED FOR?</strong></p>

<p>This time around, Trump wants the Senate to give up that gatekeeping role and allow him to make "recess appointments," even though his Republicans will control the chamber next year with at least 52 seats.</p>

<p>He has called for the chamber to adjourn after he takes office in January, which would allow his personnel to take their positions without having to undergo Senate scrutiny.</p>

<p>That would allow boundary-pushing picks like former Representative Matt Gaetz to serve as U.S. attorney general and vaccine skeptic Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to take charge of the Department of Health and Human Services.</p>

<p><strong>HOW DO 'RECESS APPOINTMENTS' WORK?</strong></p>

<p>The U.S. Constitution says the president can make recess appointments to fill vacant positions when the Senate is not in session, though officials appointed in this manner can only serve two years at most.</p>

<p>Past presidents have taken advantage of this clause. Democrat Barack Obama made 32 recess appointments, while Bush made 171, according to the Congressional Research Service.</p>

<p>Since 2007, Congress had increasingly used scheduling tricks to prevent this from happening.</p>

<p>Rather than formally adjourning when it wants to leave town, the Senate now typically holds occasional "pro forma" sessions in which a single lawmaker briefly wields the gavel but no work is done, keeping the chamber technically in session.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court upheld this practice in 2014, ruling that a president can only make a recess appointment when the Senate is out of session for 10 days or longer.</p>

<p>Trump's gambit would require the Senate to adjourn for at least that long, which could be difficult. It's not clear how many Republicans would voluntarily give up one of the Senate's most significant powers.</p>

<p><strong>CAN TRUMP FORCE A RECESS?</strong></p>

<p>Maybe. The Constitution gives the president the power to adjourn Congress when the Senate and the House of Representatives disagree on whether they should leave town. Trump could invoke this power if the Republican-controlled House votes to adjourn and the Senate does not.</p>

<p>That tactic has never been used before, according to conservative scholar Ed Whelan, who called on House Speaker Mike Johnson to reject it. "Johnson can and should immediately put an end to this scheme," he wrote in the Washington Post on Nov. 14.</p>

<p><strong>WILL REPUBLICANS OPPOSE TRUMP?</strong></p>

<p>Republicans will control the House and the Senate by narrow margins next year, giving them little room for error if they want to go along with Trump's proposal.</p>

<p>In the Senate, Trump allies like Florida Senator Rick Scott quickly signaled support while other Republicans have said they are reluctant to surrender such a significant power.</p>

<p>Incoming Senate Republican Leader John Thune has not ruled it out. "All options are on the table, including recess appointments," he said on Fox News on Nov. 14.</p>

<p>Republicans could warm to the idea if Democrats manage to block or slow down some of Trump's nominees next year. A recess appointment could allow them to avoid having to hold up-or-down votes on a divisive nominee like Kennedy, a former Democrat who has spread misinformation on vaccines and supports abortion rights.</p>

<p>In the House, Johnson, a close Trump ally, has not yet publicly said what he thinks of the idea. If he were to pursue it, he would have to keep nearly all of his fellow Republicans on board as he will likely start next year with a majority of fewer than three votes in the 435-seat chamber.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ikkei3j8_us-capitol-dome_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama made 32 recess appointments, according to Congressional Research Service. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-abortion-policy-may-impact-womens-reproductive-rights-globally-7047640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Trump's Abortion Policy May Impact Women's Reproductive Rights Globally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-abortion-policy-may-impact-womens-reproductive-rights-globally-7047640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 16:55:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the aftermath of the US election, much focus has been on the consequences for abortion rights across the US, and whether this will affect state-led initiatives to roll back restrictive legislation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the aftermath of the US election, much focus has been on the consequences for <a href="https://theconversation.com/what-a-second-trump-presidency-means-for-abortion-laws-across-the-us-243437">abortion rights across the US</a>, and whether this will affect state-led initiatives to roll back restrictive legislation.</p>

<p>What has received much less attention is what will happen next to abortion services, sexual and reproductive health, and health more widely across many parts of the world, as a direct result of a decision President Trump is likely to take on his first day in office.</p>

<p>The US is by far the largest donor of aid for global health, providing US$15.8 billion (£7.8 billion) in 2022, compared to the <a href="https://donortracker.org/donor_profiles/united-kingdom/globalhealth">next three largest donors</a> Germany (US$4.4 billion), Japan ($3.2 billion) and the UK (US$2 billion). That means restrictions and reductions on that aid can have enormous consequences around the world.</p>

<p>In 1984, President Reagan implemented the Mexico City Policy (which became widely known as the <a href="https://www.opensocietyfoundations.org/explainers/what-global-gag-rule">global gag rule</a>), under which any organisation providing abortion services (defined widely from actual abortion provision to basic advice) was banned from receiving US aid – even if that funding was not being spent on abortion services. Since then, Democratic administrations have removed this rule, only for succeeding Republican presidents to reinstate it.</p>

<p>Based on his track record in his first presidency, Trump is likely to bring back this kind of restriction on aid when he returns to the White House. His first administration reintroduced this policy and <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/gpr/2020/04/unprecedented-expansion-global-gag-rule-trampling-rights-health-and-free-speech">vastly expanded the scope</a> of its focus well beyond family planning services to include HIV/AIDS treatment, sanitation and public health more widely.</p>

<p>The amount of funding affected by these rules rose from around $600 million under Bush-era workings of the global gag rule to <a href="http://www.msichoices.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/msi-briefing-impact-of-the-ggr-on-reproductive-healthcare.pdf">around US$12 billion</a>. The ruling will apply not just to the organisations directly receiving USAID funding, but to any organisation they work with, even if using non-USAID funds for that work.</p>

<p>The potential impact of these restrictions on how countries can use their public health funding is significant; the performance of the previous Trump administration suggests health organisations are right to be worried about what may be coming.</p>

<p>Research over decades shows that when the global gag rule is in place the health of women and children in particular are put at risk.</p>

<p>A study in <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7888016/">Kenya</a>, for example, found sexual and reproductive health services (which may include abortion services, but also offer critically important services for pregnant and new mothers, infants and children) were closed. Stocks of contraceptives also declined as a consequence of these restrictions on how aid was spent. In <a href="https://pai.org/resources/access-denied-uganda/">Uganda</a>, organisations reportedly stopped providing services designed to reduce death from unsafe abortions, worried even this might fall into the vague definitions of “abortion services”.</p>

<p>Leading international reproductive health charity <a href="https://www.msichoices.org/latest/the-impact-of-the-global-gag-rule-on-frontline-reproductive-healthcare/">Marie Stopes International</a> saw its overall funding fall by 17% in 2017 during Trump's first term, over its refusal to agree to the terms of the global gag rule. In some countries abortion rates rose by <a href="https://www.msichoices.org/latest/the-impact-of-the-global-gag-rule-on-frontline-reproductive-healthcare/">up to 40%</a>, with many expected to be unsafe, as US funding for safe abortion facilities disappeared.</p>

<p>There's likely to be an increase in maternal and child mortality. The death rate from safe abortions is very small (around 1 per 100,000 births). Unsafe abortions, by contrast, are incredibly dangerous, with a death ratio of <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/abortion">200 per 100,000</a> abortions.</p>

<p>This type of restriction on how US aid can be spent doesn't just affect abortion services. It also undermines wider sexual and reproductive health services, including family planning access and information. The result is that unwanted pregnancy rates increase at the same time as abortion service provision is reduced, with the inevitable consequence of pushing many women into dangerous unsafe abortion procedures. One <a href="https://www.aidsmap.com/news/jun-2022/us-gag-rule-leads-90000-additional-hiv-infections-annually">study</a> suggested an additional 30,000 maternal and child deaths occurred annually as a direct result.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://www.kff.org/global-health-policy/issue-brief/impact-of-the-mexico-city-policy-literature-review/">review</a> of research findings on the impact of these public health restrictions carried out by policy organisation KFF, showed declines in usage of modern contraception, increases in pregnancies and rates of unsafe abortions.</p>

<p>The affect on advice on and availability of modern contraception, especially condoms, also brings with it additional health challenges. Best practice has long suggested integrating sexual health services with other health services including HIV testing and treatment, screening for some cancers and antenatal care, can improve health outcomes.</p>

<p>Undermining one aspect of these services has a knock-on effect on all of them. A 2022 <a href="https://www.aidsmap.com/news/jun-2022/us-gag-rule-leads-90000-additional-hiv-infections-annually">study</a> suggested that across highly US-aid dependent countries, there have been an additional 90,000 new HIV infections every year when the global gag rule has been in force.</p>

<h2>Reduced access to contraception</h2>

<p>Nepal, which enshrined the right to abortion and requires all government health facilities to offer free abortion services in its 2018 Safe Motherhood and Reproductive Health Rights Act, is one country that could be particularly badly affected. The US is the <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-relations-with-nepal/">largest bilateral donor</a> for health in Nepal and has provided more than <a href="https://gh.bmj.com/content/bmjgh/7/7/e008752.full.pdf">three-fifths of aid</a> for family planning and reproductive health under President Biden. One <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7888035/">study</a> found maternal and child health services in Nepal as a whole worsened under Trump's last term, not just those parts linked to abortion services.</p>

<p>Contraception services declined and stocks frequently ran out, increasing risks of unwanted pregnancies. Organisations working on abortion were also often excluded from ministry of public health consultations, despite abortion being legal in the country, over government fears of the consequences for <a href="https://gh.bmj.com/content/bmjgh/7/7/e008752.full.pdf">US aid flows</a>.</p>

<p>When these kind of restrictions are in place the number of abortions has increased. And much of that increase is happening in unregulated, dangerous places, adding to the risk of death for pregnant women.</p>

<h2>What might happen next?</h2>

<p>Under previous US presidents, other donors have increased their commitments in order to try and protect sexual and reproductive health services and wider public health from the devastating <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2017/feb/16/uk-to-host-summit-seeking-extra-funds-for-family-planning">impact of US policy</a>.</p>

<p>It is critical that donors, especially those in Europe (including the UK), announce their plans now for how they will step up their support to protect women's health and access to safe abortions, in order to prevent the closure of these vital services. Not just for the next four years but for the longer term.</p>

<p>These restrictions create the precise opposite of what they set out to achieve, resulting in more abortions and more deaths. But more than that, they are deeply harmful and dangerous to women who have no say over a policy that presents a danger to their lives.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/243346/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/michael-jennings-103257">Michael Jennings</a>, Professor in Global Development, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/soas-university-of-london-975">SOAS, University of London</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> </span>Michael Jennings does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-a-second-trump-presidency-is-likely-to-threaten-abortion-rights-and-womens-healthcare-globally-243346">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8iek7258_donald-trump-afp_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's policy on abortion has raised serious concern over women's health in America]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-community-welcomes-modi-with-sanskrit-chants-in-brazil-7047391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Community Welcomes PM Modi With Sanskrit Chants In Brazil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-community-welcomes-modi-with-sanskrit-chants-in-brazil-7047391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 16:27:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["A celebration of Indian culture in Brazil! Gratitude for a memorable welcome in Rio de Janeiro," Mr. Modi said in a post on X.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian community in Brazil on Monday welcomed Prime Minister Narendra Modi with Sanskrit chants after his arrival here.</p>

<p>Cultural performances were also held to welcome him in the country.</p>

<p>"A celebration of Indian culture in Brazil! Gratitude for a memorable welcome in Rio de Janeiro," Mr. Modi said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"Deeply touched by the warm and lively welcome from the Indian community upon arriving in Rio de Janeiro. Their energy reflects the affection that binds us across continents," he said.</p>

<p>Modi arrived in the South American country after wrapping up a "productive" visit to Nigeria, where he held bilateral talks with President Bola Ahmed Tinubu and interacted with the Indian community.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/msd4sl5o_pm-modi-in-brazil-pti_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Indian community in Brazil welcomed PM Modi with Sanskrit chants after his arrival here.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-snl-mocks-donald-trumps-epic-cabinet-picks-after-musk-parody-7047294]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch | SNL Mocks Donald Trump's 'Epic' Cabinet Picks After Musk Parody]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-snl-mocks-donald-trumps-epic-cabinet-picks-after-musk-parody-7047294]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 16:15:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The cold open started with the Trump-Biden meeting as several of the Republican leader's cabinet picks paid him a visit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saturday Night Live (SNL) has mocked President-elect Donald Trump's picks for the cabinet ahead of the inauguration, slated for January 20, 2025. The cold open also poked fun at Trump's highly animated meeting with President Joe Biden at the Oval Office last week which prompted a deluge of reactions on social media. While Trump's character was portrayed by James Austin Johnson, Dana Carvey -- a regular SNL cast member, played Biden with Alex Baldwin also making a cameo appearance as Robert F. Kennedy Jr. -- the new health czar.</p>

<p>The skit started with the Trump-Biden meeting as several of the Republican leader's cabinet picks paid him a visit. Trump said he loved running for the president while hated being one. "Maybe I hate it here too. It's no joke," Carvey's character replied.</p>

<p>"But I can't go back to Mar-a-Lago, Joe, because Elon [Musk] is there, and he will not leave, It's like, What about Bob? He's walking around in his bathing suit, showing me videos of rockets and monkeys with computers in their heads. This guy's cringe," Trump added.</p>

<p>As Biden appears to give his would-be-successor some advice, Trump replies: "I already know how to do president. It's all about surrounding yourself with the best people, and I am very fastly picking the most epic Cabinet of all time."</p>

<p>"They're some of the most dynamic, free-thinking, animal killing, sexually criminal, medically crazy people in the country," he adds, with Carvey's Biden asking: "Who are you thinking about?"</p>

<p>"Well, we've got Elon and Matt Gaetz: that's an Alien versus Predator. We've got, we've got Kristi Noem and RFK Junior. They're killing the dogs; they're killing the bears. And Melania will be working remotely from divorce," Trump replied.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President Biden and President-Elect Trump meet to discuss the transition of power <a href="https://t.co/e2Q9p7icGZ">pic.twitter.com/e2Q9p7icGZ</a></p>
— Saturday Night Live - SNL (@nbcsnl) <a href="https://twitter.com/nbcsnl/status/1858008648339144834?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Gaetz, played by Sarah Sherman, then arrives in a costume mocking the attorney general nominee's appearance. "Of course, I had to resign from Congress because the confirmation process comes at the busiest time of year for me," Gaetz said.</p>

<p>Baldwin's character appears at the end and states: "Americans need someone to teach them how to be healthy, someone like me - a 70-year-old man with movie star looks and a worm in his brain."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bluesky-how-does-it-work-and-why-are-users-leaving-elon-musks-x-7045292" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also read | What Is Bluesky, How Does It Work And Why Are Users Leaving Elon Musk's X</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Musk slams SNL</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier, Elon Musk had slammed SNL for producing a skit that mocked him. The episode hosted by comedian Bill Burr featured Carvey playing the billionaire.</p>

<p>"SNL has been dying slowly for years, as they become increasingly out of touch with reality. Their last-ditch effort to cheat the equal airtime requirements and prop up Kamala before the election only helped sink her campaign further," said Musk in a post on X (formerly Twitter).</p>

<p>Mr Musk has been appointed to Mr Trump's cabinet where he will be co-leading the newly formed Department of Government Efficiency alongside Vivek Ramaswamy.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0k19kg88_snl_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[SNL skit mocked President-elect Donald Trump for his cabinet picks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-owned-cafe-in-indonesias-ultra-conservative-sharia-stronghold-shakes-stigma-7047219]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman-Run Cafe In Indonesia's Conservative Sharia Stronghold Shakes Stigma]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-owned-cafe-in-indonesias-ultra-conservative-sharia-stronghold-shakes-stigma-7047219]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 16:08:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In what claims to be the only woman-run cafe in the capital of Indonesia's most conservative province, owner Qurrata Ayuni says she and her baristas provide an alternative to rowdy, smoke-filled male haunts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In what claims to be the only woman-run cafe in the capital of Indonesia's most conservative province, owner Qurrata Ayuni says she and her baristas provide an alternative to rowdy, smoke-filled male haunts.</p>

<p>The 28-year-old opened Morning Mama cafe last year to create a space that caters to women in Banda Aceh, known as the city of 1,001 coffee shops.</p>

<p>"I thought why not open a place that is comfortable for women?" she said.</p>

<p>While the province has long been known as the site of the world's deadliest tsunami and a decades-long separatist insurgency, Aceh's draw for visitors is often the coffee.</p>

<p>The traditional "sanger" latte, mixed with condensed milk, is a popular staple.</p>

<p>Aceh's strong connection to coffee started hundreds of years ago with Dutch colonial rulers. Now, its farmers cultivate world-renowned beans in lush highlands.</p>

<p>Aceh still catches attention for its ultra-conservative values, including by-laws that require Muslim women to wear hijabs.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dcg89p0s_indonesia-women-run-cafe-in-sharia-district-afp_625x300_18_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>While women are not banned from working in the only region in Muslim-majority Indonesia to impose Islamic law, running a coffee shop is seen as a man's job.</p>

<p>"It's extremely difficult for women in Aceh to pursue education or a career, facing not only legal restrictions but also social bullying," said Andreas Harsono of Human Rights Watch.</p>

<p>Despite widespread criticism, public whipping remains a common punishment for a range of offences in the province, including gambling, alcohol consumption and relations outside marriage.</p>

<p>Independent career paths are mostly viewed as out of reach for Aceh's young women, but Qurrata was undeterred.</p>

<h2><strong>TIME FOR CHANGE</strong></h2>

<p>Qurrata, who owns her cafe without a business partner, saw a demand for a space for women to work or meet friends.</p>

<p>She and her team of baristas pour fresh coffee to mostly hijab-wearing customers, with children's books and menstruation pads on sale nearby.</p>

<p>"There's no cigarette smoke, it's not noisy, it's really cosy," she said, adding that some men also have coffees at her shop.</p>

<p>"It's a statement that women can own businesses, make decisions and lead," she said.</p>

<p>"Now is the time for change."</p>

<p>The entrepreneur says women are stepping up, pointing to at least 1,000 applying for a barista job.</p>

<p>"I want to offer them the chance to change the course of their lives," she said.</p>

<p>Caca, a 23-year-old barista, said it was a "really cool job" rare in Aceh.</p>

<p>The cafe's regulars hail Morning Mama as a spot where women can be themselves.</p>

<p>"I feel more connection if I ask something with a woman barista," said 21-year-old student Meulu Alina. "I don't feel any nervousness. It's more like talking with your sister."</p>

<h3><strong>HELPING OTHERS</strong></h3>

<p>Before starting her business, Qurrata overcame the loss of her parents at the age of eight in the 2004 Indian Ocean tsunami, which killed more than 200,000 people.</p>

<p>Her village near Banda Aceh was completely destroyed, but she survived and was raised by her aunt and uncle.</p>

<p>Qurrata said she wants to channel her grief into helping other women.</p>

<p>"It's a platform to help others find their own resilience, much like I did," she said.</p>

<p>Photography jobs allowed her to build savings and confidence, taking a leap into business after her uncle encouraged her and helped financially.</p>

<p>Other women were still "afraid to start", she said, for fear men will say bad things.</p>

<p>"People here tend to believe that women should stay at home," she said.</p>

<p>But "the older generation understands that times have changed."</p>

<p>Owner of Aceh's popular Solong coffee shop, Haji Nawawi, said he would not employ women but locals had accepted them making coffee elsewhere, calling it "normal" as values "from outside" Aceh had entered the province.</p>

<p>Qurrata employs five women alongside two men.</p>

<p>Revenue fluctuates, but Qurrata says her ultimate aim is to inspire other women.</p>

<p>"Women are capable of so much more than we're often given credit for. We can be leaders, creators, and innovators," she said.</p>

<p>"So don't just sit back. Don't be afraid."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lhjk6c9_indonesia-women-run-cafe-in-sharia-district-afp_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Qurrata Ayuni opened Morning Mama Cafe in Banda Aceh, the lone woman-run cafe in the district.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>