<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 13:10:32 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vances-wife-usha-chilukuri-vance-at-republican-national-convention-says-we-didnt-expect-to-be-in-this-position-6131109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Didn't Expect To Be In This Position": JD Vance's Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vances-wife-usha-chilukuri-vance-at-republican-national-convention-says-we-didnt-expect-to-be-in-this-position-6131109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 13:09:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Neither JD nor I expected to find ourselves in this position, said Usha Chilukuri Vance, the wife of JD Vance, at the Republican National Convention on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Usha Chilukuri Vance, the wife of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vances-wife-usha-chilukuri-vance-describes-him-meat-potatoes-guy-who-cooks-indian-food-6130104">JD Vance</a>, at the Republican National Convention said that neither JD Vance nor she expected to find themselves in this position on Thursday. "But it's hard to imagine a more powerful example of the American Dream," she added, introducing her husband after Donald Trump named him his running mate for the US presidential polls.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Future Second Lady Usha Vance: "Neither J.D. nor I expected to find ourselves in this position — but it's hard to imagine a more powerful example of the American Dream."<br />
<br />
FULL REMARKS: <a href="https://t.co/JJgdJbem0H">pic.twitter.com/JJgdJbem0H</a></p>
— Team Trump (Text TRUMP to 88022) (@TeamTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamTrump/status/1813771787165134881?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Usha, born to immigrant parents from Andhra Pradesh, shared their story from the stage of the RNC. Recounting their first meeting and the journey that led them to this moment, she said “There was only one thing to do, to explain, from the heart, why I love and admire JD, why I stand here beside him today, and why he will make a great Vice President of the United States.”<br />
<br />
She shared how they met at the law school, where JD was a "working-class student" who had "overcome childhood traumas" and served in Iraq as a Marine. "A tough Marine who had served in Iraq but whose idea of a good time was playing with puppies," she said.<br />
<br />
Usha shed light on the Ohio senator's curious and enthusiastic approach to their differences when they first met, including his adaptation to her vegetarian diet and learning to cook Indian food from her mother. “Although he is a meat and potato kind of guy, he adapted to my vegetarian diet and learnt to cook Indian food from my mother,” she said.<br />
<br />
JD and Usha Vance met at Yale Law School and married in 2014. The couple has three children together – Ewan, 6, Vivek, 4, and Mirabel, 2.<br />
<br />
JD Vance also delivered a powerful speech at the RNC, talking about his roots in small-town Ohio and the economic challenges communities across the Rust Belt faced. He spoke about the struggles of small towns in Ohio, Pennsylvania, Michigan and other states, where jobs have been sent overseas and children have been sent to war.<br />
<br />
He vowed to be a champion for these forgotten communities, promising to never forget his humble beginnings. “I promise you this: I will be a vice president who never forgets where he came from," JD said.<br />
<br />
"To the people of Middletown, Ohio, and all the forgotten communities in Michigan, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania, and Ohio, and every corner of our nation, I will fight for you, I will stand with you, and I will never forget the struggles we face."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hrtbmc38_usha-chilukuri-vance-jd-vance-afp_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-issues-advisory-for-nationals-in-bangladesh-amid-unrest-avoid-travel-6131415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Avoid Travel": India Issues Advisory For Nationals In Bangladesh Amid Unrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-issues-advisory-for-nationals-in-bangladesh-amid-unrest-avoid-travel-6131415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 12:58:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian High Commission in Dhaka has issued an urgent advisory for Indian citizens and students in Bangladesh to avoid non-essential travel and minimise movement outside their residences due to the escalating unrest in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian High Commission in Dhaka has issued an urgent advisory for Indian citizens and students in Bangladesh to avoid non-essential travel and minimise movement outside their residences due to the escalating unrest in the country.</p>

<p>The advisory comes in response to recent violent clashes between students and police in Dhaka, following the Bangladeshi government's decision to close all public and private universities.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Advisory on the ongoing situation in Bangladesh. <a href="https://t.co/nSMsw9hWp0">pic.twitter.com/nSMsw9hWp0</a></p>
— India in Bangladesh (@ihcdhaka) <a href="https://twitter.com/ihcdhaka/status/1813822051259658497?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The protests have been driven by demands for reform of the country's quota system for civil service jobs, which reserves positions for specific groups, including descendants of those who participated in the 1971 war of independence against Pakistan.</p>

<p>On Thursday, protests intensified as students clashed with law enforcement in various locations across Dhaka. In Merul Badda, near Brac University, demonstrators blocked roads and engaged in violent confrontations with police, resulting in multiple injuries. By late morning, police deployed tear gas to disperse the crowd, leading to significant traffic disruptions in the area, Dhaka Tribune reported.</p>

<p>Additionally, students obstructed the entrance to the Bashundhara Residential Area on Pragati Sarani and blocked the Dhaka-Chittagong highway in Jatrabari, severely affecting public transportation and causing widespread inconvenience. The Mirpur 10 roundabout and surrounding areas also experienced a heavy police presence, with many local markets and shops remaining closed.</p>

<p>The protests began in response to perceived police brutality and have evolved into a broader demand for justice for those injured or killed in previous demonstrations, as well as a call for a violence-free campus and rational reform of the quota system, as reported by Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>In light of the volatile situation, the High Commission of India in Dhaka and the Indian Assistant High Commissions in Chittagong, Sylhet, and Khulna have established 24-hour emergency contact numbers for Indian nationals and students who require assistance:</p>

<p>High Commission of India, Dhaka: 880-1937400591 (also on WhatsApp)</p>

<p>Assistant High Commission of India, Chittagong: 880-1814654797 / 880-1814654799 (also on WhatsApp)</p>

<p>Assistant High Commission of India, Sylhet: 880-1313076411 (also on WhatsApp)</p>

<p>Assistant High Commission of India, Khulna: 880-1812817799 (also on WhatsApp)</p>

<p>The recent protests have been fueled by dissatisfaction with Bangladesh's quota system, which sets aside a significant number of civil service positions for specific groups. This system has been a contentious issue in Bangladesh for years, with current demonstrations reflecting deep-seated frustrations over both the quota system and the response of law enforcement to peaceful student movements.</p>

<p>The Indian government continues to monitor the situation and advises all citizens in Bangladesh to adhere to the travel advisory and reach out to the High Commission or Assistant High Commissions if they are in need of urgent assistance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1o09bmfo_bangladesh-unrest-afp_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protests have been driven by demands for reform of the country's quota system for civil service jobs.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/keir-starmer-britian-ai-ai-regulation-britains-new-government-aims-to-regulate-most-powerful-ai-models-6130879]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Britain's New Government Aims To Regulate Most Powerful AI Models]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/keir-starmer-britian-ai-ai-regulation-britains-new-government-aims-to-regulate-most-powerful-ai-models-6130879]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 11:17:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK PM Keir Starmer's government said it would seek to establish appropriate legislation to place requirements on those working to develop "the most powerful AI models." Under Sunak, the government avoided introducing targeted AI regulation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's new Labour government has said it will explore how to effectively regulate artificial intelligence models, but stopped short of proposing any specific laws.</p>

<p>King Charles set out newly-elected Prime Minister Keir Starmer's legislative agenda in a speech on Wednesday to open the new session of parliament. It included more than 35 new bills covering everything from housing to cyber security measures.</p>

<p>The government said it would seek to establish the appropriate legislation to place requirements on those working to develop "the most powerful artificial intelligence models."</p>

<p>The country's last prime minister Rishi Sunak had sought to position Britain as a world leader in AI safety, bringing world leaders and company executives together last November for a summit at Bletchley Park to discuss the issue.</p>

<p>He also oversaw the launch of the world's first AI Safety Institute, which has focused on the capabilities of "frontier" AI models, such as those behind OpenAI's highly successful ChatGPT chatbot.</p>

<p>"AI labs will be collectively breathing a sigh of relief at the government's decision not to rush ahead with frontier model regulation," said Nathan Benaich, founding partner of AI-focused investment group Air Street Capital.</p>

<p>Under Sunak, the government avoided introducing targeted AI regulation, opting instead to split responsibility for scrutinising the technology between various regulators.</p>

<p>Starmer has promised to introduce new laws on AI, but his government is taking a careful approach to rolling them out.</p>

<p>"The UK's cautious, sector-based approach to AI regulation remains a crucial competitive advantage versus the EU, and any moves to change this regime should only be taken with the utmost caution," Benaich said.</p>

<p>But some AI experts say the rapid rollout of AI tools over the past 18 months only makes the need for new legislation more urgent.</p>

<p>Gaia Marcus, director of the Ada Lovelace Institute, said the government should bring forward a bill as soon as possible.</p>

<p>"These systems are already being integrated into our daily lives, our public services and our economy, bringing benefits and opportunity, but also posing a range of risks to people and society," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h8dvf8ho_britian-ai_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer has promised new laws on AI but is taking a careful approach to rolling them out]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/more-than-40-of-japanese-companies-have-no-plan-to-make-use-of-ai-reuters-poll-6130727]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[More Than 40% Of Japanese Companies Have No Plan To Use AI: Reuters Poll]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/more-than-40-of-japanese-companies-have-no-plan-to-make-use-of-ai-reuters-poll-6130727]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 10:52:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nearly a quarter of Japanese companies have adopted artificial intelligence (AI) in their businesses, while more than 40% have no plan to make use of the cutting-edge technology]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nearly a quarter of Japanese companies have adopted artificial intelligence (AI) in their businesses, while more than 40% have no plan to make use of the cutting-edge technology, a Reuters survey showed on Thursday.<br />
<br />
The survey, conducted for Reuters by Nikkei Research, pitched a range of questions to 506 companies over July 3-12 with roughly 250 firms responding, on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>About 24% of respondents said they have already introduced AI in their businesses and 35% are planning to do so, while the remaining 41% have no such plans, illustrating varying degrees of embracing the technological innovation in corporate Japan.</p>

<p>Asked for objectives when adopting AI in a question allowing multiple answers, 60% of respondents said they were trying to cope with a shortage of workers, while 53% aimed to cut labour costs and 36% cited acceleration in research and development.</p>

<p>As for hurdles to introduction, a manager at a transportation company cited "anxiety among employees over possible headcount reduction".</p>

<p>Other obstacles include a lack of technological expertise, substantial capital expenditure and concern about reliability, the survey showed.</p>

<p>The poll also showed 15% of respondents have experienced cyberattacks over the past year and 9% had business partners that suffered cyberattacks during the same period.</p>

<p>Asked about damage, 23% of those that suffered cyberattacks themselves or had business partners that were targets said business was temporarily halted, and 4% said they suffered information leak.</p>

<p>On steps to enhance cybersecurity, 47% of respondents said they were outsourcing defence whereas 38% said they had in-house specialists.</p>

<p>Cyberattack victims in recent months included high-profile publisher Kadokawa whose case prompted the government to work towards strengthening cybersecurity measures.</p>

<p>The survey also showed half of firms support changing a law stipulating that spouses must use the same surname. Women take their husband's in more than 9 out of 10 marriages, a practice opponents said takes away part of a woman's identity and burdens them with the masses of paperwork needed to make the change.</p>

<p>The issue came under renewed spotlight after the Keidanren business lobby last month asked the government to allow married individuals to keep their surnames.</p>

<p>In the survey, 50% of respondents said they supported such legislative change compared with 11% that opposed.</p>

<p>"The current system is hurting individuals' - and especially women's - dignity and freedom," a manager at a machinery firm wrote. An official at a steelmaker called change the "natural demand of the times".</p>

<p>In opposition, a manager at a non-ferrous metal manufacturer said allowing separate surnames could "weaken family bonds."</p>

<p>Asked how a change in the law would affect their business, 14% of respondents said employee morale would be boosted and 10% said it would help hiring activity, while 56% said they expected no impact.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kfub7d2_japan-ai_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The survey, conducted for Reuters by Nikkei Research, pitched a range of questions to 506 companies]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-defends-india-on-having-unjustified-pressure-due-to-energy-ties-6130661]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Unjustified": Russia On India Facing "Enormous Pressure" Due To Energy Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-defends-india-on-having-unjustified-pressure-due-to-energy-ties-6130661]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 10:43:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is a great power that determines its national interests and chooses its partners, Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov has said, describing as "completely unjustified" the "enormous pressure" on New Delhi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India is a great power that determines its national interests and chooses its partners, Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov has said, describing as "completely unjustified" the "enormous pressure" on New Delhi due to its energy cooperation with Moscow.</p>

<p>During a press conference here on Wednesday, Lavrov also termed as "insulting" Ukraine's remarks on the recent meeting between President Vladimir Putin and Prime Minister Narendra Modi in Moscow. "I think India is a great power that sets its own national interests, determines its own national interests, and chooses its own partners. And we know that India is being subject to enormous pressure, completely unjustified pressure in the international arena," Lavrov said.</p>

<p>Lavrov was responding to a question about Prime Minister Modi's recent visit to Moscow and the opposition faced by India for its energy cooperation with Russia. With Russia presiding over the UN Security Council for the month of July, Lavrov is in New York to chair meetings of the Council being held under Moscow's presidency.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi paid an official visit to Russia on July 8-9 at the invitation of Russian President Vladimir Putin for the 22nd India - Russia Annual Summit. This was Modi's first trip to Russia since the start of the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>India has not yet condemned Russia's invasion of Ukraine in 2022 and has consistently pitched for a resolution of the conflict through dialogue and diplomacy.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has also criticised Modi's visit to Moscow, saying in a post on X that "A Russian missile struck the largest children's hospital in Ukraine, targeting young cancer patients. Many were buried under the rubble.</p>

<p>"It is a huge disappointment and a devastating blow to peace efforts to see the leader of the world's largest democracy hug the world's most bloody criminal in Moscow on such a day," Zelenskyy had said of the Modi-Putin meeting.</p>

<p>India had conveyed to Kyiv its displeasure over the remarks. It was learnt that India's disappointment over the comments by Zelenskyy was communicated to Ukraine's mission in Delhi.</p>

<p>Referring to Zelenskyy's comments about Modi's trip to Russia being "a stabbing in the back of all peace efforts", Lavrov said, "So that was very insulting and the Ukrainian ambassador was called in" and the Indian Ministry of External Affairs "talked to him about how he should be behaving." "The ambassadors were really behaving as if they were hooligans," he said, referring to remarks made by some other Ukrainian envoys.</p>

<p>"So I think India is doing everything right," he said.</p>

<p>Lavrov noted that External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, after touring Western nations, answered questions including about why India was buying more oil from Russia.</p>

<p>Lavrov said Jaishankar cited statistics that showed that the West has also increased its purchases of gas and oil from Russia, despite some of the restrictions that have been imposed.</p>

<p>Lavrov said Jaishankar "went on to say that India will decide for itself how to trade with whom and how to defend its national interests." "But the fact that the West is exhibiting its displeasure to powers - powers like China, like India - well, it shows their lack of erudition, their inability to partake in diplomacy, and also speak to the failure of political analysts. Because speaking this way, to these great Asian powers... you might dream of that but it's really beneath them. It's really beneath them behaving this way vis-a-vis any and all countries but in particular when they're speaking in this way to these two giants, these two great powers." On India's oil purchases from Russia, Jaishankar earlier said that it is his duty to put the interest of the Indian people first to ensure that they do not pay the cost of some other countries' actions or some other region's actions for fertilizer, food, etc.</p>

<p>"It's not just that we buy oil from one country. We buy oil from multiple sources, but it is a sensible policy to go where we get the best deal in the interests of the Indian people and that is exactly what we are trying to do," Jaishankar has said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2ie9ca7g_pm-modi-putin_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia also termed as "insulting" Ukraine's remarks on the recent meeting between Putin and PM Modi]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/meta-meta-ai-brazil-meta-decides-to-suspend-its-generative-ai-tools-in-brazil-6130616]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Decides To Suspend Its Generative AI Tools in Brazil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/meta-meta-ai-brazil-meta-decides-to-suspend-its-generative-ai-tools-in-brazil-6130616]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 10:36:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta Platforms said on Wednesday it decided to suspend use of generative artificial intelligence tools in Brazil in response to the government's objections to its new privacy policy regarding personal data and AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Meta Platforms said on Wednesday it decided to suspend use of generative artificial intelligence tools in Brazil in response to the government's objections to its new privacy policy regarding personal data and AI.<br />
<br />
<strong>WHY IT'S IMPORTANT</strong></h3>

<p>With more than 200 million people, Brazil is a crucial market for Meta. For example, Brazil has the second-largest user base for Meta's WhatsApp after India.</p>

<p>In June, Meta hosted an event in Sao Paulo to launch its first AI-driven ad targeting program for businesses on the popular chat service.</p>

<h3><strong>CONTEXT</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier this month, Brazil's National Data Protection Authority (ANPD) decided to suspend with immediate effect the validity of Meta's new privacy policy for the use of personal data to train generative artificial intelligence systems in the country.</p>

<p>ANPD ruled that the company would need to adapt its privacy policy to exclude the section related to the processing of personal data for generative AI training, according to the Brazilian authority.</p>

<h3><strong>KEY QUOTE</strong></h3>

<p>In a statement, Meta said it has decided to suspend the tools while it is in talks with ANPD to address the authority's doubts over generative artificial intelligence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/q5pa4s3o_meta-ai_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta suspended the services in response to the Brazilian government]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-17-year-old-granddaughter-kai-trump-said-about-him-6130536]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Donald Trump's 17-Year-Old Granddaughter Said About Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-17-year-old-granddaughter-kai-trump-said-about-him-6130536]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 10:28:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump's granddaughter Kai Trump took to the stage at the Republican National Convention on Wednesday night to share personal stories about her grandfather.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump's granddaughter Kai Trump took to the stage at the Republican National Convention on Wednesday night to share personal stories about her grandfather. With a proud smile, the Republican presidential nominee listened to the 17-year-old, who described him as a "normal grandpa", spoiling her and her siblings with "candy and soda" when their parents weren't looking.</p>

<p>Kai, the eldest of Trump's 10 grandchildren, claimed she wanted to show the country a side of her grandfather that they "don't often see".</p>

<p>“He always wants to know how we're doing in school,” she <a href="https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2024/jul/17/kai-trump-talks-all-about-grandpa-trump-at-republi/ ">said</a>.</p>

<p>Kai shared a heartwarming moment when she made the high honour roll, and her grandfather "printed it out to show his friends how proud he was" of her.</p>

<p>The 17-year-old, the daughter of Donald Trump Jr and his ex-wife, Vanessa Trump, revealed that he often calls her during school to ask about her golf game and shares stories about his own. Kai joked that she has to remind him she's "in school and can't talk."</p>

<p>When they play golf together, Trump tries to get inside her head, but Kai says she doesn't let him get to her. "I remind him, I'm a Trump too," she said with a smile.</p>

<p>Despite his busy schedule, including ongoing court cases, Kai said her grandfather always asks about her well-being and encourages her to push herself to be successful. "Obviously, he sets the bar pretty high, but who knows, maybe one day I will catch him," she said confidently.</p>

<p>Later, Kai shared that she was "shocked" after the recent assassination attempt on her grandfather at a Pennsylvania rally. "A lot of people have put my grandpa through hell, and he's still standing," she stated. Affectionately addressing him, she said, "Grandpa, you are such an inspiration, and I love you."</p>

<p>She also addressed the media's portrayal of her grandfather, saying that they make her "grandpa seem like a different person". "But I know him for who he is," she said. "He's very caring and loving. He truly wants the best for this country, and he will fight every single day to make America great again."</p>

<p>Kai Trump has been a frequent presence at Donald Trump's side during various events over the years. She has been spotted at key events such as his inauguration, the announcement of his candidacy in 2015, and the opening of a Trump golf course. Kai has also been seen at golf tournaments and holidays with her grandfather. Her most recent appearances include attending UFC 303 with her father and playing in the ProAm of the LIV Golf Team Championship at the Trump National Doral Golf Club in 2022.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gvu0cl48_kai-trump-afp_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kai shared a heartwarming moment when she made the high honour roll.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/14-japanese-school-students-taken-to-hospital-after-eating-adult-only-crisps-6130545]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[14 Japanese Students Taken To Hospital After Eating 'Adult Only' Crisps]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/14-japanese-school-students-taken-to-hospital-after-eating-adult-only-crisps-6130545]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 10:24:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The chips, brought by a student and shared among about 30 classmates, caused nausea, stomach pain, and mouth pain.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fourteen students were rushed to the hospital on Tuesday after experiencing nausea, stomach pain, and mouth pain from consuming extremely spicy potato chips at Rokugo Koka High School, according to <em>Japan Today.</em></p>

<p>As per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://japantoday.com/category/national/14-tokyo-students-taken-to-hospital-after-eating-spicy-chips">the news report,</a> the chips, labelled "18+ Curry Chips," were brought to school by a student and shared among a group of about 30 classmates. All the affected students are first-year students and are believed to have only minor symptoms.</p>

<p>The chips are manufactured by Isoyama Corporation, a company based in Ibaraki Prefecture. The company advises against people under 18 consuming their product due to its spiciness and warns spice lovers to exercise caution when eating them. The chips reportedly contain ghost peppers, one of the hottest peppers globally.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-largest-isolated-tribe-makes-rare-appearance-in-new-footage-6130335"><strong>Also Read | World's Largest Isolated Tribe Makes Rare Appearance In New Footage</strong></a></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/07/17/teens-eat-adult-only-crisps-spicy-14-end-hospital-21246656/"><em>The Metro, </em></a>their products are made using the ghost pepper, or bhut jolokia, a chilli pepper recognised as one of the spiciest in the world. It is 170 times hotter than tabasco sauce.</p>

<p>Last year, an American teen died after eating a super-spicy tortilla chip as part of a viral challenge on social media.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/sourav-ganguly-recalls-how-he-learned-leadership-lesson-from-sehwags-defiance-in-2002-natwest-series-6129893#pfrom=home-ndtv_lateststories"><strong>Also Read | Sourav Ganguly Recalls How He Learned Leadership Lesson From Sehwag's Defiance In 2002 NatWest Series</strong></a></p>

<p>Tenth grader Harris Wolobah, 14, died of a cardiopulmonary arrest after participating in the Pacqui 'One Chip Challenge', which involved eating ingredients coated in ingredients from the Carolina Reaper and the Naga Viper, two of the hottest peppers in the world.</p>

<p>The product has since been pulled from the shelves.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rha56tc8_isoyama-corporation_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company advises against consumption by those under 18 due to the extreme spiciness.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-largest-isolated-tribe-makes-rare-appearance-in-new-footage-6130335]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Largest Isolated Tribe Makes Rare Appearance In New Footage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-largest-isolated-tribe-makes-rare-appearance-in-new-footage-6130335]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 09:48:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rare photos and footage of the Mashco Piro, an uncontacted tribe in the Peruvian Amazon, were released by Survival International.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rare photos have captured the Mashco Piro, a previously uncontacted tribe deep in the Peruvian Amazon, emerging from their isolated territory. The images, released by Survival International on Tuesday, show numerous tribe members relaxing by a riverbank. This sighting comes amid growing concerns about the Mashco Piro's well-being.</p>

<p>According to FENAMAD, a local Indigenous rights group, increased logging activity in the area is likely pushing the tribe out of their traditional lands. The Mashco Piro may be venturing closer to settlements in search of food and a safer refuge.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/webstories/feature/mashco-piro-rare-photos-show-uncontacted-amazon-tribe-20752"><strong>Pics: Mashco Piro - Rare Photos Of Uncontacted Amazon Tribe</strong></a></p>

<p>Survival International reports the photos were taken in late June near the banks of a river in Madre de Dios, a southeastern Peruvian province bordering Brazil.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">❗️ New &amp; extraordinary footage released today show dozens of uncontacted Mashco Piro Indigenous people in the Peruvian Amazon, just a few miles from several logging companies.<br />
<br />
Read the news: <a href="https://t.co/g9GrZlf3XB">https://t.co/g9GrZlf3XB</a> <a href="https://t.co/fZv5rryzVp">pic.twitter.com/fZv5rryzVp</a></p>
— Survival International (@Survival) <a href="https://twitter.com/Survival/status/1813263339553964485?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"These incredible images show that a large number of isolated Mashco Piro live alone a few kilometres from where the loggers are about to start their operations," said Survival International director Caroline Pearce.</p>

<p>More than 50 Mashco Piro people appeared in recent days near a village of the Yine people called Monte Salvado. Another group of 17 appeared in the nearby village of Puerto Nuevo, said the NGO, which defends Indigenous rights.</p>

<p>The Mashco Piro, who inhabit an area located between two natural reserves in Madre de Dios, have seldom appeared as a rule and do not communicate much with the Yine or anyone, according to Survival International.</p>

<p>Several logging companies hold timber concessions inside the territory inhabited by the Mashco Piro.</p>

<p>One company, Canales Tahuamanu, has built more than 200 kilometres (120 miles) of roads for its logging trucks to extract timber, according to Survival International.</p>

<p>A Canales Tahuamanu representative in Lima did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The company is certified by the Forest Stewardship Council, according to which it has 53,000 hectares (130,000 acres) of forests in Madre de Dios to extract cedar and mahogany.</p>

<p>The Peruvian government reported on June 28 that local residents had reported seeing Mashco Piro on the Las Piedras river, 150 kilometres (93 miles) from the city of Puerto Maldonado, the capital of Madre de Dios.</p>

<p>The Mashco Piro have also been sighted across the border in Brazil, said Rosa Padilha, at the Brazilian Catholic bishops' Indigenous Missionary Council in the state of Acre.</p>

<p>"They flee from loggers on the Peruvian side," she said. "At this time of the year, they appear on the beaches to take tracajá (Amazon turtle) eggs. That's when we find their footprints on the sand. They leave behind a lot of turtle shells."</p>

<p>"They are a people with no peace, restless because they are always on the run," Padilha said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/a286f9g_mashco-piro_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The images show tribe members near logging concession areas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/republican-vice-president-pick-jd-vance-salutes-donald-trump-ahead-of-key-speech-6130309]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Republican Vice President Pick JD Vance Salutes Trump Ahead Of Key Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/republican-vice-president-pick-jd-vance-salutes-donald-trump-ahead-of-key-speech-6130309]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 09:40:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[JD Vance bashed President Joe Biden, assailed the media and saluted Donald Trump's bravery Wednesday in remarks ahead of a keynote address to grassroots Republicans to accept his nomination as the party's vice-presidential candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>JD Vance bashed President Joe Biden, assailed the media and saluted Donald Trump's bravery Wednesday in remarks ahead of a keynote address to grassroots Republicans to accept his nomination as the party's vice-presidential candidate.</p>

<p>Speaking on the sidelines of the Republican National Convention -- his first campaign stop as Trump's running mate -- the US senator applauded Trump's reaction to cheating death at the hands of a gunman in Pennsylvania at the weekend.</p>

<p>"The contrast between the lie that the media tells about President Trump and the man that all of us actually know, of course, we saw it in stark definition on Saturday," Vance told the audience in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>Vance said he was "terrified that we had just lost a great president" when a volley of gunfire forced Trump to hit the stage floor at the rally in Butler.</p>

<p>"And then of course he stands up a minute later, after they shot him -- they literally shot him -- and he raises his fist in the air and he says, 'Fight! Fight! Fight!"</p>

<p>Vance -- seen by critics as a conspiratorial, divisive firebrand -- didn't explain whom he meant by "they" but he had immediately blamed Democrats in the aftermath of the attack.</p>

<p>Authorities have not suggested any motive for the shooting as they investigate the slain assailant, and there is no suggestion that anyone else was involved.</p>

<h3><strong>'Let's get rid of him'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Vance, 39, took the opportunity to plug the Trump brand, which he described as "synonymous with luxury and with beauty in the real estate world."</p>

<p>And he contrasted the economy under "real president Donald Trump" with inflation under "Fake Scranton Joe Biden," saying that under the Democrat, "the basic trappings of middle-class life have become less and less attainable."</p>

<p>"Let's get rid of him, and let's bring Donald Trump back to the White House," he said.</p>

<p>Vance was to take center stage at the convention later Wednesday as Trump bids for a stunning return to the White House, four years after losing to Biden.</p>

<p>The one-term senator would be the third-youngest vice president in history -- and one of the least experienced -- if 78-year-old Trump prevails in his rematch against Biden in November.</p>

<p>The way the best-selling writer talks about Trump is in marked contrast to the hostility he voiced as he toured television studios in 2016 with a book to sell.</p>

<p>Vance was an uncompromising "Never Trumper" at the time of his new boss's election, labelling the hard-right tycoon "a moral disaster" and comparing him to Adolf Hitler.</p>

<p>He reinvented himself when he entered politics and won Trump's endorsement in the 2022 Ohio Senate race.</p>

<p>Vance has since grown into a cheerleader-in-chief for Trump's anti-immigrant rhetoric and isolationist foreign policy -- including opposition to US support for Ukraine's war against Russian invasion.</p>

<h3><strong>Modest upbringing&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Despite making his name with the 2016 memoir "Hillbilly Elegy," a best-selling account of his Appalachian family and modest Rust Belt upbringing, Vance remains something of an unknown quantity to the wider public.</p>

<p>He is slated to speak for around half an hour from 9.30 pm (0230 GMT), in a speech expected to lean heavily on his biography and relate elements of his life story to the experience of ordinary Americans.</p>

<p>Vance is already a hit with the party faithful in Milwaukee and was rewarded with a rowdy ovation as he stepped on the convention floor Monday with his wife, Usha, who is due to speak just before him.</p>

<p>Some 50,000 Republicans have descended on the shores of Lake Michigan for the four-day convention, where the Pennsylvania shooting -- which killed one bystander and left the ex-president with a bloodied ear -- has dominated proceedings.</p>

<p>The convention has emphasized party unity behind Trump, banishing the torrent of scandals that range from his role in attempts to overturn the 2020 election to his criminal conviction in a New York court this May.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tv9u9rfk_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance has grown into a cheerleader-in-chief for Donald Trump's anti-immigrant rhetoric.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vice-president-pick-jd-vance-urges-voters-to-choose-a-new-path-6130188]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Vice President Pick JD Vance Urges Voters To "Choose A New Path"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vice-president-pick-jd-vance-urges-voters-to-choose-a-new-path-6130188]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 09:18:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's vice presidential pick JD Vance lit up the Republican National Convention Wednesday with a speech leaning heavily on his personal story as he sought to connect his turbulent upbringing with the hardships faced by millions of Americans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's vice presidential pick JD Vance lit up the Republican National Convention Wednesday with a speech leaning heavily on his personal story as he sought to connect his turbulent upbringing with the hardships faced by millions of Americans.</p>

<p>In his first speech since being tapped as Trump's vice presidential nominee on Monday, Vance offered a powerful account of growing up poor in Ohio, with no father at home and a mother hooked on drugs.</p>

<p>He urged voters to "choose a new path" as he accepted his nomination, telling the crowd: "The people who govern this country have failed and failed again."</p>

<p>The story will be familiar to readers of his best-selling memoir "Hillbilly Elegy," an account of his Appalachian family and modest beginnings that gave a voice to rural, working-class resentment in left-behind America.</p>

<p>But it was his first real introduction to many tuning in at home and the Trump campaign is banking on the address chiming with blue-collar voters in the swing states key to winning November's election rematch against President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Vance touched on trade, foreign policy and the drug epidemic -- and on Trump's policies for addressing them -- but he devoted much of the speech to his own experiences.</p>

<p>He emphasized his background as a former Marine, making him the first veteran on a major party ticket since John McCain ran for president in 2008.</p>

<h3><strong>Big moment&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The one-term senator, who will be just 40 on inauguration day, would be the third-youngest vice president in history -- and one of the least experienced -- if 78-year-old Trump defeats Biden.</p>

<p>His effusive praise of Trump is in marked contrast to the hostility he voiced as he toured television studios in 2016 with a book to sell.</p>

<p>Vance was an uncompromising "Never Trumper" at the time of his new boss's election win in 2016, labelling the populist, hard-right tycoon "a moral disaster" and comparing him to Adolf Hitler.</p>

<p>He reinvented himself when he entered politics and ultimately won Trump's endorsement in the 2022 Ohio Senate race.</p>

<p>Vance has since grown into cheerleader-in-chief for Trump's anti-immigrant agenda and isolationist foreign policy -- notably including opposition to US support for Ukraine in its war with Russia.</p>

<p>Even before his big moment, Vance was a hit with the party faithful in Milwaukee's Fiserv Forum arena.</p>

<p>They rewarded him with boisterous applause as he arrived with his wife, Usha, on the opening day Monday to take his place with the Trump family in the front row.</p>

<p>While Vance reinforces Trump's appeal to the hardline base, he offers little chance of broadening the tent to more moderate voters and women.</p>

<p>He is further to the right than Trump on some issues including abortion, where he embraces calls for federal legislation.</p>

<h3><strong>Ultra-loyal&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Some 50,000 Republicans have descended on the shores of Lake Michigan for the four-day convention, which came with the country reeling from the botched attempt by a gunman to assassinate Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday.</p>

<p>The attack -- which killed one bystander and left the ex-president with a bloodied ear -- has dominated proceedings, with the opening day's highlight an appearance from a defiant Trump sporting a bandage on his right ear.</p>

<p>The Republican convention has emphasized party unity behind Trump, banishing the torrent of scandals that range from his role in attempts to overturn the 2020 election to his criminal conviction in a New York court this May.</p>

<p>However, Trump's once ultra-loyal vice president from 2016-2020, Mike Pence, has refused to give his endorsement and was not at the convention.</p>

<p>And while Trump has been calling for unity, Vance is one of the most partisan and divisive members of Congress.</p>

<p>He immediately claimed after the shooting that Democrats' rhetoric had "led directly to President Trump's attempted assassination."</p>

<p>Trump is set to formally accept his party's nomination with the hotly anticipated keynote address on Thursday.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day Vance saluted Trump's bravery in remarks at a finance event -- his first campaign stop as Trump's running mate -- and assailed Biden as a failed leader.</p>

<p>"Let's get rid of him," he said, "and let's bring Donald Trump back to the White House."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qk3g0aog_jd-vance-afp-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance was speaking at the Republican National Convention]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vances-wife-usha-chilukuri-vance-describes-him-meat-potatoes-guy-who-cooks-indian-food-6130104]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Meat And Potatoes Guy Who Cooks Indian Food": Usha Vance On Husband]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vances-wife-usha-chilukuri-vance-describes-him-meat-potatoes-guy-who-cooks-indian-food-6130104]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 08:55:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Usha Chilukuri Vance, wife of JD Vance, Donald Trump's vice-presidential pick, spoke at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee where she revealed her husband's culinary skills in Indian cuisine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Usha Chilukuri Vance, wife of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-jd-vances-wife-usha-vance-said-about-her-hindu-upbringing-its-influence-on-life-6116180">JD Vance</a>, Donald Trump's vice-presidential pick, spoke at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee where she revealed her husband's culinary skills in Indian cuisine.</p>

<p>Describing him as a "meat and potatoes" kind of guy, she mentioned his newfound ability to cook Indian food.</p>

<p>Recalling their meeting at Yale Law School, Ms Vance portrayed their relationship as "a testament to this great country".</p>

<p>"We started as friends," she said. "He was then, as he is now, the most interesting person I knew - a working class guy who had overcome childhood traumas that I could barely fathom to end up at Yale Law School, a tough marine who had served in Iraq, but who enjoys spending his leisure time playing with puppies and watching the movie 'Babe'."</p>

<p>Ms Vance also highlighted the diverse backgrounds they come from.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-donald-trump-picked-jd-vance-as-his-vice-president-candidate-6123635">JD Vance</a> has acknowledged the influence of his Hindu wife, Usha Chilukuri Vance, on his personal and spiritual life.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News, he explained how his wife's Hindu faith had been pivotal in guiding him through challenges and reconciling his Catholic beliefs.</p>

<p>Previously, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-an-honor-jd-vance-after-being-declared-donald-trumps-vice-president-pick-6116429">JD Vance</a> has often credited Usha for supporting his success. During a 2020 interview with The Megyn Kelly Show, Vance described his wife as a "strong female voice" that grounds him. "Usha definitely brings me back to earth. If I get a little too confident or proud, I remind myself that she's way more accomplished than I am," he had said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e30s6508_usha-chilukuri-vance-jd-vance-afp_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Usha Vance also highlighted the diverse backgrounds they come from.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/switzerland-portable-suicide-pods-press-button-to-die-switzerland-to-soon-use-portable-suicide-pods-6130028]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Press Button To Die": Switzerland To Soon Use Portable Suicide Pods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/switzerland-portable-suicide-pods-press-button-to-die-switzerland-to-soon-use-portable-suicide-pods-6130028]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 08:39:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An assisted dying group expects a portable suicide pod to be used for the first time in Switzerland, potentially within months, providing death without medical supervision, it said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An assisted dying group expects a portable suicide pod to be used for the first time in Switzerland, potentially within months, providing death without medical supervision, it said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The space-age-looking Sarco capsule, first unveiled in 2019, replaces the oxygen inside it with nitrogen, causing death by hypoxia. It would cost $20 to use.</p>

<p>The Last Resort organisation said it saw no legal obstacle to its use in Switzerland, where the law generally allows assisted suicide if the person commits the lethal act themselves.</p>

<p>"Since we have people indeed queueing up, asking to use the Sarco, it's very likely that it will take place pretty soon," The Last Resort's chief executive Florian Willet told a press conference.</p>

<p>"I cannot imagine a more beautiful way (to die), of breathing air without oxygen until falling into an eternal sleep," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>'Press this button' to die&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The person wishing to die must first pass a psychiatric assessment of their mental capacity -- a key legal requirement.</p>

<p>The person climbs into the purple capsule, closes the lid, and is asked automated questions such as who they are, where they are and if they know what happens when they press the button.</p>

<p>"'If you want to die', the voice says in the processor, 'Press this button'," said Sarco inventor Philip Nitschke, a leading global figure in right-to-die activism.</p>

<p>He explained that once the button is pressed, the amount of oxygen in the air plummets from 21 per cent to 0.05 per cent in less than 30 seconds.</p>

<p>"Within two breaths of air of that low level of oxygen, they will start to feel disorientated, uncoordinated and slightly euphoric before losing consciousness," Nitschke said.</p>

<p>"They will then stay in that state of unconsciousness for... around about five minutes before death will take place," he added.</p>

<p>The Sarco monitors the oxygen level in the capsule, the person's heart rate and the oxygen saturation of the blood.</p>

<p>"We will be able to see quite quickly when that person has died," said Nitschke.</p>

<p>As for someone changing their mind at the very last minute, Nitschke said: "Once you press that button, there's no way of going back."</p>

<h3><strong>First user&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>No decision has been made over the date and location of the first death, or who the first user might be.</p>

<p>Such details would not be made public until after the event.</p>

<p>"We really don't want a person's desire for a peaceful passing Switzerland to turn into a media circus," said lawyer Fiona Stewart, who is on The Last Resort's advisory board.</p>

<p>She said it would be used "in a very secluded location, in the beauty of nature", though it had to be on private property.</p>

<p>Asked if the first use would be this year, she replied: "I would say yes."</p>

<p>The minimum age limit is set at 50, though if someone over 18 was seriously ill, "we would not want to deny a suffering person based on their age", said Stewart.</p>

<p>The capsule can be reused.</p>

<p>Nitschke's Exit International organisation, which owns the Sarco, is a non-profit group funded by donations.</p>

<p>Stewart said the only cost for the user would be 18 Swiss francs ($20) for the nitrogen.</p>

<h3><strong>Development and debate</strong></h3>

<p>The capsule's potential use has raised a host of legal and ethical questions in Switzerland, reigniting debate on assisted dying.</p>

<p>The Wallis cantonal doctor has banned its use, while other cantons have voiced reservations.</p>

<p>"It's our understanding that there's no legal impediment to the Sarco being used... despite what any canton says," Stewart insisted.</p>

<p>Nitrogen, which forms 78 per cent of the air, is "not a medical product... it's not a dangerous weapon", she added.</p>

<p>"We're looking to de-medicalise assisted suicide because a Sarco doesn't require a doctor to be in close proximity," said Stewart.</p>

<p>Only once a person has died would the Swiss authorities be called.</p>

<p>The 3D-printable capsule cost more than 650,000 euros ($710,000) to research and develop in the Netherlands over 12 years.</p>

<p>Stewart said it had been tested with instruments in a workshop in Rotterdam over the last 12 months. It has not been tested on humans or animals.</p>

<p>The current Sarco could only accommodate someone five feet and eight inches (1.73 metres) tall. The development team is seeking to build a double Sarco so couples could end their lives together.</p>

<p>Future Sarcos could cost around 15,000 euros. The Sarco will never be permitted for use in capital punishment, said The Last Resort.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ps1g567o_sarco-suicide-capsule-afp-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The space-age-looking Sarco capsule replaces the oxygen inside it with nitrogen, causing death by hypoxia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/jaahnavi-kandula-death-case-us-cop-who-laughed-after-indian-students-death-fired-6129895]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Cop Who Laughed After Indian Student Jaahnavi Kandula's Death Fired]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/jaahnavi-kandula-death-case-us-cop-who-laughed-after-indian-students-death-fired-6129895]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 08:03:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Seattle police officer, whose insensitive comments and laughter following the death of an Indian student had caused outrage, has been fired.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US police officer, whose insensitive comments and laughter following the horrific death of a 23-year-old Indian student had caused outrage, has been fired from the Seattle Police Department.</p>

<p>Jaahnavi Kandula was struck by a speeding police vehicle driven by Seattle Police Officer Kevin Dave as she was crossing a street on January 23 last year.</p>

<p>Dave was driving at more than 119 kmph on the way to a report of a drug overdose call. Kandula was thrown 100 feet when she was struck by the speeding police patrol vehicle.</p>

<p>In bodycam footage released by the Seattle Police Department, Officer Daniel Auderer was heard laughing after the deadly crash and had remarked: "Uh, I think she went up on the hood, hit the windshield, and then when he hit the brakes, flew off the car...But she is dead." After making these comments, Auderer "laughed hard for four seconds," the department's Disciplinary Action Report said.</p>

<p>Auderer's body-worn camera also captured him saying, "Yeah, just write a check. Just, yeah (laughter). USD 11,000. She was 26, anyway. She had limited value." When asked at an Office of Police Accountability interview about his comments that Kandula had "limited value", Auderer claimed he was "ridiculing the city attorneys who would be tasked with litigating a potential wrongful death lawsuit." Interim Chief Sue Rahr at the Seattle Police Department said in an internal email, seen by PTI Wednesday, that the hurt Auderer's words have inflicted on Kandula's family "cannot be erased. The actions (of) this individual police officer have brought shame on the Seattle Police Department and our entire profession, making the job of every police officer more difficult." Rahr said that as the leader of the organisation, it is her duty to uphold the high standards necessary to maintain public trust. "For me to allow the officer to remain on our force would only bring further dishonour to the entire department. For that reason, I am going to terminate his employment," she said in the internal email.</p>

<p>Rahr noted that at the root of this case lies an extremely difficult judgment call of how to fairly balance "intent versus impact." "There is no doubt that the named officer's cruel comments and callous laughter about the tragic death caused deep pain to Ms Kandula's family, but also immeasurable damage to the public trust of police in the Seattle community, across the nation, and around the world," she said in the email.</p>

<p>Noting that it is unusual for a Chief to explain a disciplinary decision to an entire organisation, Rahr said this is an unusual enough circumstance and the "case has been covered extensively in the public, has garnered international media and diplomatic attention." Rahr added that it has been "quite striking" to her that a number of people, even those known to be very "pro-police," feel the "dehumanizing laughter heard on the video is more outrageous and disturbing" than Kandula's death.</p>

<p>"Our government gives police officers the authority to deprive people of their liberty and in the most extreme circumstances, their life," Rahr said.</p>

<p>"This authority rests on the public's trust that officers will demonstrate respect for the sanctity of human life. The officer's laughter and callous comments about the "limited value" of Ms. Kandula's life displayed a cruel mockery of the sanctity of her life. That is a betrayal of that sacred trust. Not only did his comments irrevocably break the public's trust in the officer, individually, but they caused extreme damage to the public's trust in the entire Seattle Police Department," Rahr said.</p>

<p>She noted that the impact of Auderer's actions is "so devastating that it cannot be mitigated by his intent to keep his conversation private." In February, the King County Prosecutor's Office had said that they would not move forward with criminal charges against Dave. The Seattle City Attorney had issued a USD 5,000 traffic infraction against him, according to KomoNews.</p>

<p>King County Prosecuting Attorney Leesa Manion had said that she believes they lack the evidence to prove a criminal case beyond a reasonable doubt.</p>

<p>"It is the responsibility of the King County Prosecuting Attorney's Office to review all available evidence relating to the case involving Seattle Police Officer Kevin Dave and the January 2023 collision death of Jaahnavi Kandula. After staffing this case with senior deputy prosecuting attorneys and office leadership, I have determined that we lack sufficient evidence under Washington State law to prove a criminal case beyond a reasonable doubt."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/livp1oog_jaahnavi-kandula_625x300_22_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Daniel Auderer was heard laughing about the deadly crash.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-kamala-harris-vs-jd-vance-debate-donald-trump-campaign-shares-big-update-6129772]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Kamala Harris vs JD Vance Debate, Trump Campaign Shares Big Update]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-kamala-harris-vs-jd-vance-debate-donald-trump-campaign-shares-big-update-6129772]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 07:29:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The campaign for former US president and the Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that it will not commit to vice-presidential debate dates until after the Democratic National Convention, starting August 19.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The campaign for former US president and the Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that it will not commit to vice-presidential debate dates until after the Democratic National Convention, starting August 19.</p>

<p>Vice President Kamala Harris had extended the debate invitation to Senator JD Vance after he was named Trump's running mate earlier this week.</p>

<p>"We don't know who the Democratic nominee for vice president is going to be, so we can't lock in a date before their convention," Trump Campaign Senior Advisor Brian Hughes said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"To do so would be unfair to Gavin Newsom, JB Pritzker, Gretchen Whitmer, or whoever Kamala Harris picks as her running mate," he said, rejecting the offer of Harris to debate Vance.</p>

<p>Biden-Harris 2024 Communications Director for Vice President Harris, Brian Fallon said Trump is the one whose campaign said he would debate "anytime, anyplace" and who picked Vance specifically for his debating skills.</p>

<p>"Now suddenly right after a damning new leak showing his support for a nationwide abortion ban, Vance is backing off a debate against Vice President Harris, who has spent the last two years prosecuting the case on behalf of reproductive freedom," Fallon said.</p>

<p>"This debate has been discussed for two months now. If JD Vance is unwilling to defend the Trump-Vance record on the debate stage, he should just say so," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c69vc5t_kamala-harris-jd-vance-afp_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris had extended the debate invitation to Senator JD Vance earlier this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-covid-case-delivers-latest-blow-to-hard-luck-campaign-6129739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden's Covid Case Delivers Latest Blow to Hard-Luck Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-covid-case-delivers-latest-blow-to-hard-luck-campaign-6129739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 07:16:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden's hopes of counter-programming the Republican National Convention were dashed Wednesday after he learned he had contracted COVID-19, forcing him to cancel an appearance before a key Latino advocacy group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden can't catch a break.</p>

<p>The president's hopes of counter-programming the Republican National Convention were dashed Wednesday after he learned he had contracted COVID-19, forcing him to cancel an appearance before a key Latino advocacy group.</p>

<p>While Biden's symptoms are mild, the diagnosis both removes him from the campaign trail and thrusts his health back into the spotlight - all at a critical moment when he is trying desperately to prove that concerns over his age and mental acuity are overblown.</p>

<p>Earlier Wednesday, Adam Schiff - the California congressman and Democratic candidate in that state's US Senate race - restarted the drumbeat of allies calling for Biden to exit the race, urging him to "pass the torch."</p>

<p>Then came a pair of reports from ABC News and the Washington Post that Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer and House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries had warned Biden in private conversations last week about the risk his continued candidacy posed.</p>

<p>Biden told the leaders he was the nominee of the party and planned to win, White House spokesman Andrew Bates said in a statement. Still, both joined forces in the following days to lobby the Democratic National Committee against a July virtual roll call that would have cemented Biden's nomination and effectively terminated efforts to replace him atop the ticket.</p>

<p>The president stoked the melodrama even more by suggesting in a BET interview taped Tuesday that he would consider dropping out of the race if new health issues emerged. Meanwhile, Senator Bernie Sanders, a defender of the president, conceded in an interview with the New Yorker that Biden had trouble completing sentences.</p>

<p>Even worse, Biden's struggles played out against scenes from the GOP convention, where Republican candidate Donald Trump appeared on stage for a walk-through sporting a bandaged ear from the unsuccessful assassination attempt he survived last weekend.</p>

<p>Trump's defiant, fist-pumping response to the shooting proved instantly iconic, galvanizing voices of doubt within the Republican Party behind his cause. On Tuesday night, former primary foes Nikki Haley and Ron DeSantis took to the stage in Milwaukee to lay out their argument for supporting Trump's candidacy.</p>

<p>The events contributed to a growing sense of two campaigns headed in opposite directions: one on the rise and the other in turmoil.</p>

<p>Public opinion polls underscore reason for Democrats to be concerned.</p>

<p>Nearly two-thirds of Biden's own party say he should withdraw from the race, according to an Associated Press-NORC poll released hours before Biden's Covid diagnosis. Just three in 10 Democrats are extremely or very confident in his ability to serve effectively as president.</p>

<h3><strong>Off the Rails</strong></h3>

<p>Biden had hoped to reverse those perceptions over a three-day trip that quickly flew off the rails.</p>

<p>The president originally planned to travel on Monday to Austin, Texas to deliver remarks marking the 60th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act at the Lyndon Baines Johnson Presidential Library. The White House had seen the address as an opportunity for Biden to link himself to previous Democratic efforts to expand protections for minorities while painting Trump as enabling new restrictions on abortion and voting rights.</p>

<p>But that event was scrapped in the aftermath of Saturday's shooting at the Trump rally, and a planned interview with NBC News was moved to the White House. Without the event as a backdrop, the interview devolved into a tense and combative exchange focused largely on Biden's rhetoric and questions about his age.</p>

<p>"Sometime come and talk to me about what we should be talking about," Biden told NBC anchor Lester Holt at the conclusion. "OK? The issues."</p>

<p>Biden resumed campaign events Tuesday with an appearance at the NAACP's national convention, but quickly bungled the centrepiece of his speech: a new proposal to cap rent increases by corporate landlords at 5% annually.</p>

<p>Instead, Biden appeared to struggle to read his teleprompter, eventually saying the limit would be $55.</p>

<h3><strong>Medical Condition</strong></h3>

<p>After the event, BET News released excerpts from an interview with Biden where he appeared to open the door to reconsidering his reelection bid if doctors advised it.</p>

<p>"If I had some medical condition that emerged, if somebody, if doctors came to me and said, you got this problem and that problem," Biden said.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, things didn't improve. Biden held a call with Jeffrey Katzenberg, the Hollywood executive leading his fundraising effort, and was told that donations were drying up over concerns about his age, Semafor reported. Katzenberg subsequently issued a statement to the outlet calling it a "misread of a private meeting."</p>

<p>The president then went to tape a radio interview with Univision but left it feeling unwell. A Covid test confirmed his infection and the president quickly spirited back to the Las Vegas airport to return to his home in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware.</p>

<p>About the only positive news for the president was that his symptoms were mild, according to the White House: a runny nose, cough, and - appropriately enough - "general malaise."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hhf01ec8_joe-biden-covid-bloomberg-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[While Joe Biden's symptoms are mild, the diagnosis removes him from the campaign trail.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-covid-19-inquiry-to-issue-first-report-on-preparedness-6129568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Covid-19 Inquiry To Issue First Report On Preparedness]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-covid-19-inquiry-to-issue-first-report-on-preparedness-6129568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 06:20:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A public inquiry examining Britain's response to the COVID-19 outbreak will issue its first report on Thursday, focusing on how well prepared the nation was for handling such a pandemic.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A public inquiry examining Britain's response to the COVID-19 outbreak will issue its first report on Thursday, focusing on how well prepared the nation was for handling such a pandemic.</p>

<p>Britain recorded one of the world's highest number of fatalities from COVID with more than 230,000 deaths reported by December 2023.</p>

<p>Former Prime Minister Boris Johnson ordered the inquiry in May 2021, and it was formally launched the following year with former judge Heather Hallett as its chair.</p>

<p>The inquiry was told in early evidence that the government was under-prepared and had failed to anticipate measures needed to protect the vulnerable.</p>

<p>That echoed the findings of the government's spending watchdog which concluded in a 2021 report that the government was not prepared for a crisis like the pandemic, had failed to learn from simulation exercises and was distracted by Britain's departure from the European Union.</p>

<p>"We know that for lives to be saved in the future, lessons must be learnt from the mistakes of the past," said Brenda Doherty on behalf of the campaign group, COVID-19 Bereaved Families for Justice UK. "Sadly, nobody knows the true cost of the government's failure to prepare as we do."</p>

<p>The inquiry's first module has only examined Britain's preparedness. Later reports will provide assessments of the more politically charged issues of governance and decision-making during the pandemic against a backdrop of wide criticism of government incompetence.</p>

<p>Johnson himself was forced from office in July 2022, with revelations of parties during COVID lockdowns among the many scandals that ended his premiership. A parliamentary committee later concluded he had misled lawmakers over the parties.</p>

<p>His later successor as prime minister and the finance minister during the pandemic Rishi Sunak was also fined for breaking lockdown rules.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-12/n9q4att_uk-covid-testing-reuters_625x300_30_December_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 230,000 deaths were reported by December 2023 due to Covid in the UK.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-service-head-to-testify-to-us-house-panel-on-donald-trump-shooting-6129452]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secret Service Head To Testify To US House Panel On Trump Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-service-head-to-testify-to-us-house-panel-on-donald-trump-shooting-6129452]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 05:42:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle has agreed to testify before the U.S. House of Representatives Oversight Committee on July 22 for a hearing related to the shooting of former President Donald Trump at a rally, the panel said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle has agreed to testify before the U.S. House of Representatives Oversight Committee on July 22 for a hearing related to the shooting of former President Donald Trump at a rally, the panel said on Wednesday.</p>

<p><strong>WHY IT IS IMPORTANT</strong></p>

<p>Security at the Republican presidential candidate's rally in Pennsylvania has been under scrutiny after the former president was shot on Saturday at the event. The FBI said it was probing the shooting as an assassination attempt.</p>

<p>The shooting has raised serious concerns about how the suspect was able to access a nearby rooftop with a direct line of sight to where Trump was speaking.</p>

<p>Trump has since said he was doing well and has appeared at the Republican National Convention this week but the shooting left his face streaked with blood after his right ear was hit. A rally attendee was killed in the shooting, two others were wounded and the suspect is dead.</p>

<p><strong>KEY QUOTES</strong></p>

<p>"Americans demand and deserve answers from Director Cheatle about the attempted assassination of President Trump and the Secret Service's egregious failures," the Republican-led House oversight panel said on Wednesday, adding Cheatle agreed to comply with a subpoena issued by the committee's chair.</p>

<p>"The hearing will take place as scheduled on Monday, July 22," the panel added.</p>

<p><strong>CONTEXT</strong></p>

<p>Democratic U.S. President Joe Biden, who will face Republican Trump in November's election, said on Sunday he had ordered an independent review, and Republican lawmakers in Congress have also vowed swift investigations.</p>

<p>Cheatle said on Monday the Trump rally shooting was "unacceptable" and that she would not resign her post. Top Republicans in the U.S. Congress called on Wednesday for her to resign.</p>

<p>The Secret Service is responsible for protecting presidents and former presidents.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b4bmjc0g_donald-trump_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Secret Service is responsible for protecting presidents and former presidents.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-man-arrested-for-making-threats-against-joe-biden-6129397]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Florida Man Arrested For Making Threats Against Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-man-arrested-for-making-threats-against-joe-biden-6129397]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 05:20:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida man has been arrested for making threats against US President Joe Biden, just days after an assassination attempt on his Republican rival Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida man has been arrested for making threats against US President Joe Biden, just days after an assassination attempt on his Republican rival Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Jason Patrick Alday, 39, was arrested on Monday, the US Attorney's Office for the Northern District of Florida said.</p>

<p>Alday, of Quincy, Florida, allegedly "engaged in sending threatening communications, making threats against President Joe Biden and other federal officials," the office said in an announcement Wednesday.</p>

<p>According to the criminal complaint, Alday made threatening statements about Biden while being checked into a mental health facility in Tallahassee, Florida, last month.</p>

<p>He allegedly made further threats in posts on X.</p>

<p>Alday has been ordered detained pending trial.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was wounded in the ear when a gunman opened fire during a campaign rally on Saturday in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>A rally attendee was killed. The 20-year-old gunman, Thomas Matthew Crooks, was shot dead by Secret Service snipers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/q6pll2vo_joe-biden-afp_625x300_03_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Florida man has been arrested for making threats against US President Joe Biden.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-tests-positive-for-covid-as-age-worries-mount-6129310]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Tests Positive For Covid As Age Worries Mount]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-tests-positive-for-covid-as-age-worries-mount-6129310]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 04:51:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden tested positive for Covid on Wednesday, shortly after conceding that he would consider dropping his troubled reelection bid if he was diagnosed with a serious medical condition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden tested positive for Covid on Wednesday, shortly after conceding that he would consider dropping his troubled reelection bid if he was diagnosed with a serious medical condition.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Democrat gave media the thumbs up from his limousine and said "I feel good" as he cut short a campaign trip to Las Vegas following the diagnosis.</p>

<p>The White House said he was suffering from a runny nose, cough and "general malaise," was taking Covid medication, and was flying straight to isolation at his beach house in Rehoboth, Delaware.</p>

<p>The diagnosis came hours after the release of comments by Biden in an interview conducted on Tuesday, in which he said he could step aside as a presidential candidate "if I had some medical condition that emerged."</p>

<p>It was also the latest development over a dramatic few days in the already frenetic and polarized White House race that saw his rival Donald Trump survive an assassination at a campaign rally of his own.</p>

<p>Biden has been fighting for political survival since a disastrous debate against Trump nearly three weeks ago, in which his tired and confused appearance sparked concerns about his age.</p>

<p>White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said Biden had tested positive shortly after the first in a series of events in Las Vegas targeting crucial Latino voters.</p>

<p>"He is vaccinated and boosted and he is experiencing mild symptoms. He will be returning to Delaware where he will self-isolate and will continue to carry out all of his duties fully during that time," Jean-Pierre said.</p>

<p>Biden's doctor said he was suffering from a runny nose and a "non-productive cough" along with "general malaise," the White House said in an accompanying note.</p>

<p>He has received the Covid drug Paxlovid and has already taken his first dose, the statement read.</p>

<p>"His symptoms remain mild, his respiratory rate is normal at 16, his temperature is normal at 97.8 and his pulse oximetry is normal at 97 percent," it added.</p>

<p>- 'I feel good' -</p>

<p>Biden later leaned out of his limousine, dubbed the Beast, as he arrived at a Las Vegas airport to give the thumbs up.</p>

<p>"Good," he said to the press as he walked to Air Force One without a mask. "I feel good."</p>

<p>Janet Murguia, the president of the Unidos union for Latino workers, told the crowd about the diagnosis shortly before the White House announcement.</p>

<p>"I was just on the phone with President Biden, and he shared his deep disappointment at not being able to join us this afternoon," she said.</p>

<p>The furor over Biden's health is now set to go into overdrive, with a growing number of Democrats calling on him to step aside.</p>

<p>Asked what could make him rethink his presidential bid, Biden told the Black media outlet BET in an interview taped Tuesday in Las Vegas: "If I had some medical condition that emerged, if somebody, if the doctors came and said 'you've got this problem, that problem.'"</p>

<p>He suffered a major blow hours earlier on Wednesday when a top Democrat, Representative Adam Schiff of California, urged Biden to "pass the torch."</p>

<p>"A second Trump presidency will undermine the very foundation of our democracy, and I have serious concerns about whether the President can defeat Donald Trump in November," Schiff said in a statement to the Los Angeles Times.</p>

<p>Around 20 House Democrats and one senator have now called on Biden to leave the White House race.</p>

<p>Most polls show Biden trailing the election in a tight race with Trump.</p>

<p>Biden insists that Democratic voters support him, but a poll by the Associated Press and NORC Center for Public Affairs Research said Wednesday that nearly two-thirds want him to step aside.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6v5grhls_joe-biden_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The White House said Biden was suffering from a runny nose, cough and "general malaise.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>