<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 09:19:26 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/400-indigo-passengers-stranded-in-istanbul-without-food-accommodation-7236823]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[400 IndiGo Passengers Stranded In Istanbul Without Food, Accommodation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/400-indigo-passengers-stranded-in-istanbul-without-food-accommodation-7236823]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 08:27:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Around 400 IndiGo passengers, scheduled to travel between New Delhi and Mumbai, and Turkey, have allegedly been stranded at Istanbul airport for 24 hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Around 400 IndiGo passengers, scheduled to travel between New Delhi and Mumbai, and Turkey, have allegedly been stranded at Istanbul airport for 24 hours.</p>

<p>In response to a passenger, the airline said the flight is delayed due to operational reasons.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Passengers took to social media platform X and LinkedIn to claim that the flight was first delayed and then cancelled without notice. One of the fliers Anushri Bhansali said the flight was delayed twice by and hour, then cancelled and finally rescheduled 12 hours later, leaving passengers stranded. While complaining of exhaustion and a fever, she also said fliers were not given any accommodation, meal vouchers or even approached by an IndiGo representative at the airport.</p>

<p>Another passenger Rohan Raja said that after the 6.40 am flight from Delhi was cancelled, people struggled amid the chilly weather as the airline provided no transport to the accommodations they were allegedly provided.</p>

<p>Scheduled to travel to Mumbai's Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport, Parshwa Mehta wrote the 8.15 pm was delayed to 11 pm and then pushed to 10 am the next day. Further, chaos ensued as there was no IndiGo announcement and the information was received from the Turkish Airlines crew.</p>

<p>"We were told we'd get lounge access at Istanbul airport as compensation. But the lounge was far too small to accommodate the huge number of stranded passengers. Many of us were left standing for hours without proper facilities. No alternative flights were offered, no proper communication was made, and to top it all off-no plans for reparations were shared," he wrote in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Mr Mehta, we sincerely apologise for the inconvenience and will connect with you. ~Poulami</p>
— IndiGo (@IndiGo6E) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiGo6E/status/1867335198083625274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 12, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Hitting out at the airline's "blatant failure of basic customer service", Mr Mehta said every passenger is owed an apology and fair compensation.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, the AirHelp Score report 2024 placed IndiGo among the world's worst airlines, ranking it 103rd among the 109 analysed. The report also ranked Air India at 61st and AirAsia at 94th.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/699sg6p_indigo-passengers-stranded-in-istanbul_625x300_13_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Passengers hit out at the airline's "blatant failure of basic customer service".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luigi-mangione-who-killed-unitedhealthcare-ceo-was-not-a-client-of-his-company-7236695]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione, Who Killed US CEO, Was Not A Client Of His Company]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luigi-mangione-who-killed-unitedhealthcare-ceo-was-not-a-client-of-his-company-7236695]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 07:52:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione, who was arrested for allegedly killing UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, was never a client of the medical insurance company, a New York Police Department (NYPD) official said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Luigi Mangione, who was arrested for allegedly killing UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, was never a client of the medical insurance company, a New York Police Department (NYPD) official said. According to the police, the 26-year-old Ivy League graduate may have killed the CEO due to the "size and influence" of the company, reported NBC.</p>

<p>Chief of Detectives Joseph Kenny said that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fingerprints-shell-casings-new-evidence-links-luigi-mangione-to-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompsons-murder-7228754" target="_blank">Mangione</a> was aware of the company holding its annual investor conference at a Manhattan hotel on December 4 - the day of the crime.</p>

<p>"We have no indication that he was ever a client of United Healthcare, but he does mention that it is the fifth largest corporation in the US, which would make it the largest healthcare organisation in the country. So that's possibly why he targeted the company...He had prior knowledge that the conference was taking place on that date, at that location," Kenny told NBC.</p>

<p>Mangione shot the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-luigi-mangione-killed-unitedhealthcare-ceo-a-chronic-back-pain-link-7221725" target="_blank">UnitedHealthcare</a> CEO Brian Thompson on December 4 and was since then on the run. The University of Pennsylvania grad led the police on a five-day manhunt, following which he was arrested from a McDonalds in Pennsylvania. He is currently in custody and is facing multiple charges, including murder. Mangione was denied bail at an extradition hearing at the Blair County Courthouse in Pennsylvania on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The suspect was reportedly arrested with a manifesto where he accused health insurance companies of putting corporate greed over the well-being of people - which led to theories that he may have killed the CEO over disappointment with the insurance provider. The police also reportedly found some of Mangione's writings about wanting to use a gun to target a CEO of a big corporation.</p>

<p>The NYPD found a 3D-printed gun from Mangione - which matched three shell casings found at the crime scene. The 9mm shell casings reportedly had the words "delay", "deny" and "depose" written across them on each bullet - which were the title of a book criticising the insurance industry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/sc3plivg_luigi_625x300_13_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione shot the UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson on December 4.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-launches-plan-to-combat-islamophobia-days-ahead-of-trump-takeover-7236526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Launches Plan To Combat Islamophobia Days Ahead Of Trump Takeover]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-launches-plan-to-combat-islamophobia-days-ahead-of-trump-takeover-7236526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 07:03:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Thursday released a long-awaited strategy for countering anti-Muslim and anti-Arab hate, up sharply since the start of the Israel-Gaza war, calling for urgent, continued work to reduce discrimination and bias.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Thursday released a long-awaited strategy for countering anti-Muslim and anti-Arab hate, up sharply since the start of the Israel-Gaza war, calling for urgent, continued work to reduce discrimination and bias.</p>

<p>The 64-page document comes weeks before the inauguration of former President Donald Trump, who imposed a travel ban on people from some majority Muslim countries during his first term that Biden rescinded on his first day in office.</p>

<p>It mirrors a comprehensive strategy to fight antisemitism released by the White House in September 2023, and comes more than a year after death of six-year-old boy Wadea Al-Fayoume, stabbed by a man who targeted him and his mother because they were Palestinian-American.</p>

<p>In a foreword to the strategy, Biden called the attacks on the Chicago boy and his mother "heinous acts" and noted a spike in anti-Muslim and anti-Arab hate crimes, discrimination and bullying that he called wrong and unacceptable.</p>

<p>"Muslims and Arabs deserve to live with dignity and enjoy every right to the fullest extent along with all of their fellow Americans," Biden wrote. "Policies that result in discrimination against entire communities are wrong and fail to keep us safe."</p>

<p>The Council on American Islamic Relations, a Muslim civil rights group, called the strategy "too little, too late" and faulted the White House for not ending a federal watchlist and "no-fly" list that includes many Arab and Muslim Americans.</p>

<p>The Trump transition team had no immediate comment on the strategy or whether it would support it.</p>

<p>Trump, who won support from some Muslim voters angry about Biden's support for Israel's war in Gaza, has said he will ban entry to the US of anyone who questions Israel's right to exist and revoke visas of foreign students who are "antisemitic."</p>

<p>Tensions between pro-Israel and pro-Palestinian groups surged on some US campuses after the October 7 Hamas attacks in Israel, with human rights advocates warning of rising antisemitism, Islamophobia, and anti-Arab hate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pf7lj7ho_us-president-joe-biden_625x300_27_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The plan mirrors a comprehensive strategy to fight antisemitism.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-imran-khan-wife-bushra-bibi-indicted-in-new-corruption-case-7236176]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Pak PM Imran Khan, Wife Bushra Bibi Indicted In New Corruption Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-imran-khan-wife-bushra-bibi-indicted-in-new-corruption-case-7236176]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 05:09:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan and his wife, Bushra Bibi were indicted in a new corruption case on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan and his wife, Bushra Bibi were indicted in a new corruption case on Thursday. The case, which is the third graft reference against them, revolves around the purchase of an expensive Bulgari jewellery set at a throwaway price, Dawn reported.</p>

<p>This development comes just a week after the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) founder and other leaders of his party were charged in connection with the attack on the army's General Headquarters in Rawalpindi during last year's May 9 protests.</p>

<p>Although Khan was granted bail in the case by the Islamabad High Court last month, he remains in prison due to multiple charges, dating back to his arrest on August 5 last year, as per Dawn.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Special Court Central-I Judge Shahrukh Arjumand presided over the proceedings at Adiala Jail, where Imran was presented. Bushra Bibi, who is on bail in the case, appeared with her counsel.</p>

<p>PTI founder and his wife, Bushra Bibi, have denied corruption charges brought against them. Subsequently, the court summoned the prosecution witnesses on December 18 to record their testimonies.</p>

<p>According to Dawn, this is Imran Khan's seventh indictment, the previous being on May 10, 2023 in the first Toshakhana case against him, in January in a second Toshakhana reference; in February in the Pakistan currency (PKR) 190 million corruption case; and recently over the GHQ attack.</p>

<p>While Khan's sentences in the previous two Toshakhana cases were suspended. He was also indicted in the cipher case on December 13, 2023 and the Iddat case in January, but was later acquitted in both cases.</p>

<p>The trial of Imran Khan and Bushra Bibi in the PKR 190 million case has reached its final stage, with the couple testifying before an accountability court this week.</p>

<p>Notably, in the most recent case, the Federal Investigation Agency (FIA) accused the couple of retaining an expensive Bulgari jewellery set gifted by a foreign leader including a necklace, earrings, bracelets, and rings at a low price, saying it caused significant loss to the exchequer.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jbg3lne_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Imran Khan and his wife, Bushra Bibi were indicted in a new corruption case on Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antony-blinken-asks-turkeys-erdogan-for-protection-of-syria-civilians-7236064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Asks Turkey's Erdogan For Protection Of Syria Civilians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antony-blinken-asks-turkeys-erdogan-for-protection-of-syria-civilians-7236064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 04:21:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken told Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on Thursday that Syrian civilians need to be protected after Ankara-backed Islamists overthrew the Damascus government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken told Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on Thursday that Syrian civilians need to be protected after Ankara-backed Islamists overthrew the Damascus government.</p>

<p>The top US diplomat met late Thursday for more than an hour with Erdogan at a lounge at the airport of the capital Ankara, moments after the Turkish leader saw off Hungary's nationalist prime minister, Viktor Orban.</p>

<p>Blinken "reiterated the importance of all actors in Syria respecting human rights, upholding international humanitarian law, and taking all feasible steps to protect civilians, including members of minority groups", State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said in a statement.</p>

<p>Turkey has emphasised its security concerns following the upheaval in Syria, where it has been fighting a Kurdish-led force that Washington backs as a key player in the fight against Islamic State (IS) group jihadists.</p>

<p>After years of stalemate, the Islamist movement Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS) group last weekend toppled Syria's iron-fisted leader Bashar al-Assad, a secular-oriented member of the minority Alawite community.</p>

<p>Blinken told Erdogan of "the need to ensure the coalition to defeat ISIS (IS) can continue to execute its critical mission", Miller said.</p>

<p>Speaking before his departure to Turkey on a stop in Jordan, Blinken acknowledged "real and clear interests" by Turkey about the PKK, the Kurdish fighters that Ankara links to Syrian Kurdish guerrillas.</p>

<p>"At the same time, again, we want to avoid sparking any kinds of additional conflicts inside of Syria," Blinken told reporters in Aqaba, Jordan.</p>

<p>"And part of that also has to be ensuring that ISIS doesn't rear its ugly head again. And critical to making sure that doesn't happen is the so-called SDF, the Syrian Democratic Forces, that we've been supporting," he said, referring to the Kurdish-led forces.</p>

<p>Blinken, who leaves office next month following Donald Trump's election victory, has called for an "inclusive" process to form Syria's next government, with respect for all communities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/5vvg8bm_antony-blinken_625x300_02_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Antony Blinken reiterated the importance of all actors in Syria respecting human rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-watching-the-situation-in-bangladesh-very-closely-white-house-7235730]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Watching Situation In Bangladesh Very Closely: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-watching-the-situation-in-bangladesh-very-closely-white-house-7235730]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 02:25:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden is closely monitoring the situation in Bangladesh and the US will hold the Bangladeshi interim government accountable for ensuring the protection of religious and ethnic minorities in the country, the White House has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden is closely monitoring the situation in Bangladesh and the United States will hold the Bangladeshi interim government accountable for ensuring the protection of religious and ethnic minorities in the country, the White House has said.</p>

<p>"The security situation in Bangladesh has been difficult following the ouster of the former prime minister. And we have been working closely with the interim government to enhance the capability of their law enforcement and security services to deal with the challenge," White House National Security Communications Advisor John Kirby said at a news conference on Thursday.</p>

<p>"We have been very clear in our engagement with all Bangladeshi leaders that protection of religious and ethnic minorities … security to all Bangladeshis regardless of religion or ethnicity. We want to hold them to that," Kirby said in response to a question.</p>

<p>Over the past few weeks, Indian Americans have held peaceful protests and marches in several cities, including in front of the White House, in Chicago, New York, SFO, Detroit, Houston and Atlanta, urging Biden to help stop alleged brutalities against the minority Hindu community in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Indian-American Congressman Raja Krishnamoorthi urged members of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee to address the issue of violence against minorities, primarily Hindus, in Bangladesh during the confirmation hearing of Senator Marco Rubio for the position of secretary of state.</p>

<p>President-elect Donald Trump has nominated Senator Rubio for the top diplomatic position. The date of his confirmation hearing has not been announced yet.</p>

<p>"As targeted violence against Hindus and other minorities continues amid the disorder in Bangladesh, I urge the members of the Senate's Committee on Foreign Relations to address this crisis directly during the upcoming hearings to confirm Senator Rubio as the next US secretary of state," Krishnamoorthi said.</p>

<p>Over the weekend, a large number of Indian-Americans held a march from the White House to the US Capitol over alleged attacks on Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Raising slogans like "We want Justice" and "Protect Hindus", the demonstrators urged the Biden administration and the incoming Trump administration to ask the new government in Bangladesh to take steps to protect Hindus and also initiate action against those responsible for this.</p>

<p>"The Bangladeshi Hindu community and the larger Hindu diaspora from the Indian subcontinent have come in support of the Bangladesh Hindu community because there is continuing violence going on in Bangladesh, specifically in Chittagong and Rangpur area, as well as in some other parts of the country," said Utsav Chakrabarti of HinduACTion. PTI LKJ IJT IJT</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/lha87bsg_john-kirby_625x300_16_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Security situation in Bangladesh has been difficult following ouster of the former PM, John Kirby said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-fdi-crosses-1-000-billion-since-turn-of-century-biggest-investor-is-7235677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's FDI Hits $1 Trillion Since Turn Of Century. Biggest Investor Is...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-fdi-crosses-1-000-billion-since-turn-of-century-biggest-investor-is-7235677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 02:03:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This week India crossed a major milestone as a top global investment destination. Latest data reveals that Foreign Direct Investment into India crossed a thousand-billion-dollar mark since the turn of the century.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week India crossed a major milestone as a top global investment destination. Latest data reveals that Foreign Direct Investment into India crossed the thousand-billion-dollar mark since the turn of the century, showing how India has been the favoured destination for foreign investors.</p>

<p>The data released by the Department for Promotion of Industry and Internal Trade or DPIIT showed that the cumulative amount of FDI, including equity, reinvested earnings and other capital, stood at USD 1,033.40 billion (or $1 trillion) between April 2000 and September 2024.</p>

<p>To get a perspective of just how gigantic a trillion dollars really is, let's take this simple example - If a person was to earn one dollar (Rs. 84) per second (i.e. a trillion dollars in trillion seconds) - then it would take the person 11.5 days to earn a million dollars. But here's where is gets interesting. Continuing to earn a dollar a second, it would take the person 31.7 years to reach the billion-dollar mark, and a staggering 31,709 years to reach the trillion-dollar figure.</p>

<p>Another thought-provoking way to look at this is that India, which is the fifth largest global economy, has an overall GDP of around $3.89 trillion in 2024. It used to be around $2 trillion in 2014. Now compare that to the FDI inflow of $1 trillion in the last two decades.</p>

<h2><strong>SOURCE OF THE FDI</strong></h2>

<p>So, where did all this investment come from? Which are the countries from which these investments flowed in? One might assume that the top spot would be either the US, which is the largest economy in the world, or perhaps China, which is the second-largest economy globally. But it's neither.</p>

<p>The country which has contributed the most in terms of FDI in India during this period is Mauritius - a massive 25 per cent of all FDI inflows came via this route. Mauritius was closely followed by Singapore at 24 per cent. The United States of America came a distant third with 10 per cent.</p>

<p>Other countries which have invested significantly in India include The Netherlands at 7 per cent, Japan at 6 per cent, The UK at 5 per cent, UAE at 3 per cent, and the Cayman Islands, Germany, and Cyprus all accounting for 2 per cent each.</p>

<h2><strong>SECTORS WHICH SAW BIG INVESTMENT</strong></h2>

<p>The sector which saw the highest investment was the services and allied sector. There was significant investment in computer software and hardware, telecommunications, trading, construction, infrastructure development, automobile, chemicals, and pharmaceuticals.</p>

<h2><strong>FDI INFLOWS ON THE RISE</strong></h2>

<p>Of the 1,033 billion dollars, USD 667.4 billion came in the last ten years between 2014 and 2024 showing a 119 per cent uptick in investment when compared to the previous decade. The data also revealed that FDI inflows have come for nearly 60 sectors across 31 states and union territories in India.</p>

<p>To attract more investment over time, India has also made its investment policies liberal and lucrative. Reforms have resulted in most sectors, barring ones of strategic importance, see 100 per cent FDI under the automatic route.</p>

<p>Giving impetus to the 'Make in India' initiative, the manufacturing sector has seen a 69 per cent rise in FDI in the last ten years as compared to the prior ten.</p>

<h2><strong>WHICH SECTORS ARE OPEN AND WHAT IS THE PROCEDURE</strong></h2>

<p>FDI is allowed through the automatic route in most of the sectors, while in areas like telecom, media, pharmaceuticals and insurance, government approval is required for foreign investors.</p>

<p>Under the government approval route, a foreign investor has to get a prior nod from the ministry or department concerned, whereas, under the automatic route, an overseas investor is only required to inform the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) after the investment is made.</p>

<p>At present, FDI is prohibited in some sectors. They are lottery, gambling and betting, chit funds, Nidhi company, real estate business, and manufacturing of cigars, cheroots, cigarillos and cigarettes using tobacco.</p>

<p><em>(Inputs from PTI)</em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/5hg5edjc_pm-modi-make-in-india-pmo-website_625x300_13_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Of the 1 trillion dollars, USD 667.4 billion came in the last ten years between 2014 and 2024]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-announces-new-arms-aid-package-for-ukraine-7235566]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Announces New Arms Aid Package For Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-announces-new-arms-aid-package-for-ukraine-7235566]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 01:37:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden administration announced another package of weapons aid for Ukraine, White House spokesperson John Kirby said on Thursday, without revealing the amount of contents of the package.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden administration announced another package of weapons aid for Ukraine, White House spokesperson John Kirby said on Thursday, without revealing the amount of contents of the package.</p>

<p>Kirby said the U.S. would continue to provide additional packages for Ukraine "right up to the end of this administration."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/lha87bsg_john-kirby_625x300_16_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Biden administration announced another package of weapons aid for Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frances-emmanuel-macron-to-name-new-prime-minister-today-7235420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France's Macron To Name New Prime Minister Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frances-emmanuel-macron-to-name-new-prime-minister-today-7235420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:42:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron has postponed the nomination of a new prime minister until Friday morning, his office said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron has postponed the nomination of a new prime minister until Friday morning, his office said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Macron said two days ago he wanted to name a new head of government within 48 hours.</p>

<p>The new team is due to replace the one led by Michel Barnier, who resigned last week after far-right and leftist lawmakers voted to topple his government, plunging France into its second major political crisis in six months.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/bpsjabso_emmanuel-macron_625x300_27_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Macron said two days ago he wanted to name a new head of government within 48 hours.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-warns-citizens-to-avoid-travelling-to-the-united-states-and-europe-7235317]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Warns Citizens To Avoid Travelling To The United States And Europe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-warns-citizens-to-avoid-travelling-to-the-united-states-and-europe-7235317]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:10:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia has warned its citizens to not visit the US since relations with Washington are confrontational, claiming that they could risk being "hunted" by American authorities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia-US ties are at an all time low, and probably worse than the time since the 1962 Cuban missile crisis when both the countries were closest to an intentional nuclear war, because of the ongoing war between Ukraine and Russia.</p>

<p>Russia has warned its citizens to not visit the US since relations with Washington are confrontational, claiming that they could risk being "hunted" by American authorities.</p>

<p>Maria Zakharova, the spokeswoman for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs issued the warning through a news briefing on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Trips to the United States of America privately or out of official necessity are fraught with serious risks," she said, and described US-Russia relations as "on the verge of rupture".</p>

<p>She further issued warnings to avoid travelling to Canada and to the US allies in the European Union saying, "We urge you to continue to refrain from trips to the United States of America and its allied satellite states, including, first of all, Canada and, with a few exceptions, European Union countries, during these holidays."</p>

<p>In a similar way, the US has also issued a notice to its citizens on avoiding travel in Russia, saying "they may face harassment or detention by Russian security officials".</p>

<p>The US has backed Ukraine with $62 billion in military aid since the war began in February 2022 and further escalating the issue, last month the US authorised Ukraine to use long-range missiles deep into Russia. This became a watershed moment in the war and the move triggered Moscow to lower its nuclear threshold.</p>

<p>In addition, the US has now handed Ukraine a $20 billion loan, which President Biden said "will be paid back by the interest earned from immobilized Russian sovereign assets".</p>

<p>"These loans will support the people of Ukraine as they defend and rebuild their country. And our efforts make it clear: tyrants will be responsible for the damages they cause," he added.</p>

<p>In any case, the White House states that it is only protecting its own interest by supplying weapons to Ukraine meanwhile Russia says the US is merely using Ukraine to weaken and ultimately destroy Russia.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/kq2sq9ks_maria-zakharova-russia_625x300_30_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has warned its citizens to not visit the US since relations with Washington are confrontational]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-compensate-lgbtq-veterans-sacked-by-army-7234881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK To Compensate LGBTQ Veterans Sacked By Army]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-compensate-lgbtq-veterans-sacked-by-army-7234881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 22:47:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Until a 2000 reform, lesbians, gays, bisexuals and transgender people were barred from military service in Britain. Those who were found out were often harassed, abused and sacked, according to a government-commissioned report last year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British government will allocate 75 million pounds ($96 million) to compensate LGBTQ military veterans sacked by the army over their sexual orientation, the defence ministry announced on Thursday.</p>

<p>Until a 2000 reform, lesbians, gays, bisexuals and transgender people were barred from military service in Britain. Those who were found out were often harassed, abused and sacked, according to a government-commissioned report last year.</p>

<p>Seeking to right "historic wrongs", former armed forces members or employees sacked over their sexuality or gender identity will be eligible to receive £50,000 each, the defence ministry said -- a larger amount than initially expected.</p>

<p>"The historic treatment of LGBT veterans was a moral stain on our nation. Our government is determined to right the wrongs of the past and recognise the hurt that too many endured," Defence Secretary John Healey said in a statement.</p>

<p>Besides losing their jobs and being subjected to public humiliation, the veterans involved were sometimes stripped of their pension benefits, living the rest of their lives in poverty.</p>

<p>"We fully welcome our LGBT veterans back into Defence, and acknowledge their vital contribution to keeping the nation safe," said Minister for Veterans Alistair Carns.</p>

<p>Additional compensation of £1,000 to £20,000 will be offered based on the "suffering" of particular individuals, whether harassment, brutal interrogations or imprisonment, officials said.</p>

<p>Victims will also be able to request the reinstatement of their military rank and medals.</p>

<p>Parliament is due to debate the measure on Thursday, but veterans can already begin filing their compensation requests online.</p>

<p>In July 2023, a report ordered by Britain's then-Conservative Party government revealed the "horrendous" treatment of LGBTQ veterans who had served between 1967 and 2000.</p>

<p>The day it was published, former prime minister Rishi Sunak apologised on behalf of the government. He then set in motion the process that led to Thursday's reparations announcement.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4q0mbtgo_british-army-istock_625x300_12_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The British government will allocate 75 million pounds to compensate LGBTQ military veterans]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anything-can-happen-donald-trump-on-chances-of-war-with-iran-7234705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Anything Can Happen": Donald Trump On Chances Of War With Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anything-can-happen-donald-trump-on-chances-of-war-with-iran-7234705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 22:21:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump said "anything can happen" when asked about the chances of going to war with Iran during his next term.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump said "anything can happen" when asked about the chances of going to war with Iran during his next term in an interview with Time, coinciding with his being named the magazine's Person of the Year.</p>

<p>"Anything can happen. Anything can happen. It's a very volatile situation," Trump said, before going on to say he thinks the most dangerous thing happening now is Ukraine shooting missiles into Russia, which he said was a major escalation.</p>

<p>Trump has previously threatened Iran, whose elite Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps have sought to assassinate him, according to the US government. Iran has denied the claim.</p>

<p>During his first term in office, in 2020, Trump ordered a US air strike that killed Iran's top military commander, Qassem Soleimani.</p>

<p>Trump in 2018 also reneged on a nuclear deal struck by his predecessor Barack Obama in 2015 and re-imposed U.S. economic sanctions on Iran that had been relaxed. The deal had limited Iran's ability to enrich uranium, a process that can yield fissile material for nuclear weapons.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sbpbpa4g_linda-mcmahon_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-garland-worn-by-gandhi-at-dandi-march-fails-to-sell-at-uk-auction-7234684]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Historic Garland Worn By Gandhi-ji At Dandi March Goes Unsold At UK Auction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-garland-worn-by-gandhi-at-dandi-march-fails-to-sell-at-uk-auction-7234684]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 22:20:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The garland, which was worn by Gandhi-ji during the Salt March, was expected to fetch between GBP 20-30,000 but remains open for bids.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A unique and historic tinselled garland presented to Mahatma Gandhi during the iconic Dandi March in 1930 failed to meet its guide price at a recent UK auction. The garland, which was worn by Gandhi-ji during the Salt March, was expected to fetch between GBP 20-30,000 but remains open for bids.</p>

<p>"I am very surprised that the 'Gandhi Garland' did not find a home on the day of the auction," said Kristina Sanne, Head of Sale at the auction house specialising in fine arts and antiques.</p>

<p>"That said, we have had quite a lot of interest since the sale and hope to sell it to the highest bidder. It deserves a great home," she said.</p>

<p>The garland is a significant piece of Indian history, composed of a large teardrop-shaped medallion of pink cloth backed on card, applied with silver and gold thread and sequins. It is edged with gold tinsel and features four smaller rectangular medallions and two triangular medallions similarly decorated.</p>

<p>The garland was presented to Gandhi-ji by Nanduben Kanuga, the wife of Dr Balvantrai N Kanuga, Gandhi-ji's personal physician. It has remained in the Kanuga family collection until now.</p>

<p>While the Gandhi-ji garland failed to sell, other highlight lots in the auction attracted fierce bidding. A fine illustration from a Bhagavata Purana series from Punjab sold for GBP 27,700, exceeding its estimate. A group of six Rajput Equestrian Portraits from Rajasthan fetched GBP 20,160, and an album of Kalighat Paintings sold for GBP 21,420.</p>

<p>According to Kristina Sanne, Head of Sale at the auction house, the Indian Art section saw frantic bidding throughout, with over 90% of lots sold. This demonstrates the continued buoyancy of the Indian Art market.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jtnpk2r8_mahatma-gandhi-garland-pti_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A photograph accompanying the garland shows Nanduben Kanuga placing the garland around Gandhi-ji's neck]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/curious-case-of-ellen-greenbergs-death-us-woman-who-died-from-20-stab-wounds-in-2011-7234671]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Was Ellen Greenberg, US Woman Who Died From 20 Stab Wounds In 2011]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/curious-case-of-ellen-greenbergs-death-us-woman-who-died-from-20-stab-wounds-in-2011-7234671]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 22:18:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ellen Greenberg, a vibrant 27-year-old teacher in the US, was found dead in 2011 with 20 stab wounds and at least 11 bruises. Even after 13 years, her case remains shrouded in controversy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ellen Greenberg, a vibrant 27-year-old teacher in the US, was found dead in 2011 with 20 stab wounds and at least 11 bruises. Her death was initially ruled a homicide. But investigators, following a meeting, would change their minds again and list her death as "suicide". Now, even after 13 years, her case remains shrouded in controversy. In a hearing on Wednesday, lawyers squared before a judge, arguing 13-year-old details surrounding Ms Greenberg's death, <em>The Independent</em> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Joshua Greenberg and his wife, Sandra "Sandee" Greenberg, are convinced that the investigation into their daughter's brutal 2011 stabbing death was botched, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/crime/stabbing-ellen-greenberg-lawsuit-hearing-b2662932.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>. At the hearing, the Greenbergs' attorneys tried to convince a judge to let their case be heard by a jury. They alleged a deep-seated conspiracy, claiming the city's police department and medical examiner's office conspired to "hide" a homicide to effectively cover up a botched investigation into Ms Greenberg's death.</p>

<h3><strong>Ellen Greenberg's death&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Ms Greenberg's body was found in the kitchen of her apartment in January 2011. She was slumped against the cabinets, her legs splayed out in front of her and had been stabbed at least 20 times, with puzzling wounds to her back, neck and the back of her head. A 10-inch knife was also lodged in her chest.</p>

<p>Philadelphia pathologist Marlon Osbourne initially ruled her death a homicide. However, as police began an investigation, they publicly challenged the findings, and her death was reclassified as suicide.</p>

<p>Ms Greenberg's parents are now seeking to have the determination changed back to homicide or underdetermined. They have filed two lawsuits, one seeking to change the ruling on their daughter's death certificate and the other alleging a conspiracy by local officials to cover up a murder. Both lawsuits are still active.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Greenbergs' attorney Joseph Podraza presented the family's arguments in their civil lawsuit against five Philadelphia officials, including the chief medical examiner at the time of the autopsy, detectives on the case, and the city of Philadelphia.</p>

<p>"The police department botched the investigation starting January 26," Mr Podraza said in court, arguing that the crime scene was left unattended and by the time police returned, there was nothing to work with. The lack of progress ultimately triggered a cover-up, he suggested.</p>

<p>"These premises have been compromised. The evidence has been tampered with," Mr Podraza said, adding, "We can't rule out the presence of a third party when Ellen was killed, when she died."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/71-injuries-25-fractures-tragic-story-of-10-year-old-pak-girl-killed-by-father-stepmother-7230329">"71 Injuries, 25 Fractures": Tragic Story Of 10-Year-Old Pak Girl Killed By Father, Stepmother</a></strong></p>

<p>Ms Greenberg's parents have been working for over a decade to get their daughter's case heard in court. On Wednesday, the judge said he would make a decision on whether or not the case could go before a jury by the end of January. In the meantime, the Greenbergs are not giving up.</p>

<p>"I'm glad the public is getting an opportunity to observe the way things work in this city ... the things that have gone down, the mistakes that were made, the lies that have been told," said Sandee Greenberg, per the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, while criminal charges remain inactive for now, Pennsylvania law places no statute of limitations on homicide, leaving a glimmer of hope for Ellen Greenberg's family.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mmegmpdo_ellen-greenberg_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ellen Greenberg's body was found in the kitchen of her apartment in 2011.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-phenomenon-bowel-cancer-is-rising-among-under-50s-worldwide-study-finds-7234221]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bowel Cancer Is Rising Among Under-50s Worldwide, Study Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-phenomenon-bowel-cancer-is-rising-among-under-50s-worldwide-study-finds-7234221]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 21:13:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rates of bowel cancer are rising among younger adults, a new study found that also revealed that rates are rising faster in England than in almost any other country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rates of bowel cancer are rising among younger adults, a new study found that also revealed that rates are rising faster in England than in almost any other country. According to the <em>BBC</em>, global data suggests that doctors are seeing people under-50s develop early-onset bowel cancer. An increase in rates was reported in 27 of the 50 countries examined, with the greatest annual increases seen in New Zealand (4%), Chile (4%), Puerto Rico (3.8%), and England (3.6%), the researchers wrote in the study, published in the journal <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanonc/article/PIIS1470-2045%2824%2900600-4/fulltext" rel="noindex,nofollow">Lancet Oncology</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Experts are still trying to understand the reasons behind the rise. The authors of the study said consumption of junk food, high levels of physical inactivity and the obesity epidemic were likely to be among the factors, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cr4rnzq47z2o" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>. Eating too much-processed meat and not enough fibre can also increase the risk, per the study.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The increase in early-onset colorectal cancer is a global phenomenon," said Hyuna Sung, a senior principal scientist in cancer surveillance research at the American Cancer Society and lead author of the study. "Previous studies have shown this rise in predominately high-income western countries, but now it is documented in various economies and regions worldwide," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The study found bowel cancer rates in people aged between 25 and 49 rose in 27 of the 50 countries studied in the decade to 2017. Young women were found to have faster increases in early bowel cancer rates than men if they lived in England, Norway, Australia, Turkey, Costa Rica or Scotland.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/jwst-uncovers-baby-milky-way-galaxy-actively-shaping-the-early-universe-7230487">James Webb Telescope Uncovers 'Baby Milky Way' Galaxy Actively Shaping The Early Universe</a></strong></p>

<p>Experts said people need to be aware of the early signs and symptoms, such as blood in poo. Other symptoms include a persistent change in bowel habits, abdominal pain, discomfort or bloating.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The global scope of this concerning trend highlights the need for innovative tools to prevent and control cancers linked to dietary habits, physical inactivity and excess body weight," said Mr Sung.</p>

<p>"Ongoing efforts are essential to identify the additional factors behind these trends and to develop effective prevention strategies tailored to younger generations and local resources worldwide," he added.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/1170onj_stomach-pain-generic_625x300_04_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Experts are still trying to understand the reasons behind the rise. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/d-gukesh-is-youngest-ever-world-chess-champ-some-others-who-held-the-title-7234180]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[D Gukesh Is Youngest-Ever World Chess Champ, Some Others Who Held The Title]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/d-gukesh-is-youngest-ever-world-chess-champ-some-others-who-held-the-title-7234180]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 21:09:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[But 2023 was an eventful year for Gukesh when he unleashed himself to the world as the youngest player to reach a rating of 2750. The same year, he outperformed Viswanathan Anand as the top-ranked Indian chess player.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Chess Champion title is a heavy and prestigious one to bear and although there are many great minds in chess, there are only a select few who have found a place in the sun at a young age.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here are the five youngest World Chess Champions in the world:</p>

<h2><strong>Gukesh Dommaraju (India)</strong></h2>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/28sgn528_d-gukesh-fide_625x300_12_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: fide.com</span></em></small></p>
</div>

<p>In a dramatic finale, 18 year old D. Gukesh dethroned Ding Liren of China and became the youngest World Chess Champion in history, in 2024. Gukesh started playing chess at the age of 7, and got his first taste of success at the Under-9 section of the Asian School Chess Championships in 2015.</p>

<p>But 2023 was an eventful year for Gukesh when he unleashed himself to the world as the youngest player to reach a rating of 2750. The same year, he outperformed Viswanathan Anand as the top-ranked Indian chess player and clinched India's first-ever Chess Olympiad gold.</p>

<h3><strong>Garry Kasparov (Russia)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/c4tgiul8_garry-kasparov-_625x300_12_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: kasparov.com</span></em></small></p>
</div>

<p>Garry Kasparov was the youngest World Chess Champion at 22 years of age when he defeated Anatoly Karpov in 1985. He started playing chess at the age of 6 and at the age of 17, he became an international grandmaster in 1980. He was mentored by former world champion Mikhail Botvinnik.</p>

<p>In 1996, famously, Kasparov defeated an IBM custom built chess computer called Deep Blue. However, after an upgrade in 1997, the machine prevailed over Kasparov. He later retired from competitive chess in 2005.</p>

<p>Interestingly, he also started a political organisation called the United Civil Front to oppose President Vladimir Putin of Russia.</p>

<h3><strong>Magnus Carlsen (Norway)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p5q1qlg_magnus-carlsen-fide_625x300_12_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: fide.com</span></em></small></p>
</div>

<p>Magnus Carlsen is a chess superstar who became the highest rated player at the age of 19. He has the highest Elo chess rating ever achieved by a human being - 2882. His father taught him how to play at the age of 5.</p>

<p>He made history by winning the FIDE World Chess Championship at the age of 22 years in 2013. Carlsen was only 13 when he drew Garry Kasparov and defeated Anatoly Karpov at the same event in 2004.</p>

<h3><strong>Mikhail Tal (Latvia-Soviet Union)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/883hmfe8_mikhail-tal-fide_625x300_12_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: fide.com</span></em></small></p>
</div>

<p>At the age of 16, Mikhail Tal became a national master and at the age of 20, he became an international grandmaster.</p>

<p>He became the youngest World Champion at the age of 23 years in 1960. His victory over Mikhail Botvinnik is still considered a key moment in chess history.</p>

<h3><strong>Anatoly Karpov (Russia)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/08es16qo_anatoly-karpov-fide_625x300_12_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: fide.com</span></em></small></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>Anatoly Karpov learned to play chess at the age of four. He became the World Champion in 1975 at the age of 23. His Elo rating was 2780 and was the highest rated player for 100 months.</p>

<p>Later on, he became a politician and served as a member of the State Duma for Tyumen Oblast's Party List.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ebatqfmo_gukesh-dommaraju-afp_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[D. Gukesh dethroned Ding Liren of China and became the youngest World Chess Champion in history]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-india-revisits-one-nation-one-election-7-other-countries-play-a-part-7234178]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As India Revisits 'One Nation, One Election', 7 Other Countries Play A Part]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-india-revisits-one-nation-one-election-7-other-countries-play-a-part-7234178]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 21:08:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India aims to move to a system of holding a singular, unified, gargantuan election in which citizens elect both the Central government and respective state (federal) governments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India aims to move to a system of holding a singular, unified, gargantuan election in which citizens elect both the Central government and respective state (federal) governments.</p>

<p>This will not be the first time India attempts this system of election. When the country earned its Independence in 1947, the founding fathers had planned for this very model of election - simultaneous parliamentary and state assembly polls. From the very first election held in the country - in 1952 - this was the way India voted.</p>

<p>But all that changed in 1967 - when India voted for the last time under the 'One Nation, One Election' format. At the time, all of India voted in a single phase, except for Uttar Pradesh (formerly United Provinces), which voted in four phases. Polling was conducted between the 15th and 21st of February that year. This was India's fourth such election and polling was carried out to elect MPs and MLAs to 520 Lok Sabha seats and 3,563 Assembly constituencies.</p>

<p>Then the era of coalition politics peaked, and ultimately led to the end of simultaneous elections in the country. Till 1967, the Congress was the only party which governed India, but by then it was facing several challenges and setbacks. India's first Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru had died a few year ago, his daughter, Indira Gandhi was facing pressure from key allies; the Congress was facing large-scale anti-incumbency as well as struggling with an internal power tussle, and to top it all, India had lost the 1962 war against China.</p>

<p>Six decades hence, India now looks to resume the 'One Nation, One Election'. The Union Cabinet led by the Prime Minister has cleared the proposal and approved the bills to implement it. It will now likely be tabled in Parliament in the ongoing Winter Session, with an aim to be passed Constitutionally for it to become the norm.</p>

<h2><strong>OTHER NATIONS WITH SIMULTANEOUS ELECTIONS</strong></h2>

<p>Before this stage was reached, a high-level panel had been formed. It was led by former President Ram Nath Kovind. The panel not just studied how India carried out such elections in the past and what the loopholes were at the time, but also carried out extensive research on how such elections are carried out across the world.</p>

<p>During its global research, the panel focused on seven countries - South Africa, Sweden, Belgium, Germany, Indonesia, The Philippines, and Japan - all of which carry out simultaneous elections and have been doing so successfully. The panel then submitted its findings and a proposed working model to the President of India, Droupadi Murmu earlier this year.</p>

<p>In its report, the panel stated that a detailed comparative analysis of countries with similar electoral processes was studied to understand their workings of conducting simultaneous elections. The aim of understanding multiple models from different nations carrying out unified, simultaneous polls was to learn and adopt the best international practices and to ensure fairness and transparency in the electoral process.</p>

<p>"In South Africa, voters cast their ballots for both the National Assembly and Provincial Legislatures simultaneously. However, municipal elections are held separately from provincial ones in a five-year cycle," the report stated.</p>

<p>Sweden, the panel stated, functions on a proportional electoral system. This means that the number of seats a political party is assigned in the elected assembly is based on its share of votes in the election. "They have a system where elections for the Parliament (Riksdag), County Councils, and Municipal Councils all take place at the same time. These elections occur every four years on the second Sunday of September whereas elections to the municipal assemblies occur on the second Sunday of September, once every five years," it stated.</p>

<p>The panel also studied the German model of electioneering. In its report is stated that in Germany, there is a constructive vote of no-confidence in addition to the procedure for the appointment of a Chancellor made by the Bundestag (Germany's Lower House of Parliament). It is a variation on the motion of no confidence that allows a parliament to withdraw confidence from a head of government only if there is a positive majority for a prospective successor.</p>

<p>In Japan, the Prime Minister is firstly appointed by the National Diet and thereafter accepted by the Emperor. According to the report, a key member in the high-level panel had suggested that India should "adopt a model similar to that in Germany and Japan".</p>

<p>Like India, Indonesia also switched to the 'One Nation, One Election' format only recently - in 2019. The President, Vice-President, and members of both national and regional legislative bodies are elected on the same day. According to the report by the high-level panel "Political parties need 4 per cent of votes to qualify for the National Parliament. A Presidential candidate needs more than 50 per cent of votes cast overall and at least 20 per cent of votes in more than half the country's provinces to win."</p>

<p>The report also noted that "On February 14, 2024, Indonesia successfully conducted simultaneous elections. It was termed as the world's largest single day elections since nearly 200 million people voted across all five levels - President, Vice-President, Members of Parliament, Members of Regional Assemblies and Municipal elections."</p>

<p>India, a country of more than 1.4 billion (1,400 million / 140 crore) people, now aims to create the world record by conducting the largest-ever simultaneous elections. Whether that will happen in 2029 is not certain yet. It will first have to pass the test in Parliament.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/v5i53l34_one-nation-one-election-ndtv_625x300_12_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India aims to hold simultaneous Lok Sabha and Assembly polls under One Nation One Election]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-grants-clemency-to-nearly-1-500-criminals-white-house-7233959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Grants Clemency To Nearly 1,500 Criminals: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-grants-clemency-to-nearly-1-500-criminals-white-house-7233959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 20:39:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Outgoing President Joe Biden said Thursday he had commuted the sentences of nearly 1,500 criminals and pardoned 39 others convicted of non-violent crimes, in what the White House called the largest single-day act of clemency in US history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Outgoing President Joe Biden said Thursday he had commuted the sentences of nearly 1,500 criminals and pardoned 39 others convicted of non-violent crimes, in what the White House called the largest single-day act of clemency in US history.</p>

<p>"I am pardoning 39 people who have shown successful rehabilitation," Biden said in a statement, adding that he was also "commuting the sentences of nearly 1,500 people who are serving long prison sentences."</p>

<p>The White House said the nearly 1,500 people granted commuted sentences -- "the most ever in a single day" -- had been serving them at home for at least one year.</p>

<p>"America was built on the promise of possibility and second chances," Biden said. "As President, I have the great privilege of extending mercy to people who have demonstrated remorse and rehabilitation."</p>

<p>Biden this month faced criticism for issuing an official pardon for his son Hunter, who was facing sentencing for two criminal cases, despite earlier assurances that he would not intervene in his son's legal troubles.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pf7lj7ho_us-president-joe-biden_625x300_27_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-who-died-after-barbaric-butt-lift-surgery-did-not-give-informed-consent-probe-finds-7233797]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Woman Who Died After Butt-Lift Op Did Not Give Informed Consent: Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-who-died-after-barbaric-butt-lift-surgery-did-not-give-informed-consent-probe-finds-7233797]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 20:16:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A British woman who died after a Brazilian butt-lift procedure in Turkey had undergone a "frankly barbaric medical practice" in which she gave no informed consent, a coroner ruled, as per the BBC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British woman who died after a Brazilian butt-lift procedure in Turkey had undergone a "frankly barbaric medical practice" in which she gave no informed consent, a coroner ruled, as per the <em>BBC</em>. 26-year-old Demi Agoglia, from Greater Manchester, travelled to Turkey for the procedure in January after seeing social media advertisements for Istanbul-based Comfort Zone. She died in the hospital in Istanbul on January 8 three days after the operation and a catalogue of poor care, an inquest heard.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Bolton Coroner John Pollard found that Ms Agoglia died from a microscopic fat embolism, caused when she was injected fat enters the bloodstream, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjwl2jnvn1wo" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet </a>reported. He ruled that the 26-year-old died as a result of "misadventure contributed to by neglect".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I find there was no proper informed consent in this matter, there was no proper pre-operative care and advice, and no proper post-operative care. All of this meant the care in total fell well below the standard expected of this type of treatment and the lack of care contributed significantly to Demi's death," Mr Pollard said, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/brazilian-butt-lift-turkey-demi-agoglia-b2662921.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Independent</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The coroner also told Ms Agoglia's family that he would write to the Health Secretary, adding, "I do feel something further needs to be done to stop this frankly barbaric medical practice being conducted to such low standards that would certainly not be tolerated in the UK."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Ms Agoglia travelled to Turkey with her partner, Bradley Jones. He said he did not want Ms Agoglia to have the surgery, but she had booked the trip months earlier after "she had seen some celebrity" advertising the procedure. The couple stayed in a shared villa in Istanbul before they were taken by taxi to the hospital.</p>

<p>Following the operation Ms Agoglia was "shaking" and appeared "very, very cold", Mr Jones said. Staff from Comfort Zone were called to the villa after Ms Agoglia complained of a tight chest and they checked her blood pressure but did not inspect the area of the operation or check her heart rate and pulse, the inquest heard.</p>

<p>The 26-year-old collapsed at the villa the following day and was taken back to the hospital where she died. The surgeon who conducted the operation later told Mr Jones they had done everything they could. It later emerged that the Comfort Zone staff who were called out to the villa were not qualified nurses.</p>

<p>A Brazilian butt lift (BBL) is a surgery where a doctor transfers fat from the abdomen, hips, lower back, or thighs to the buttocks. Women get the surgery to achieve an hourglass-shaped figure, with larger buttocks. Doctors remove the fat using liposuction. According to The Independent, the procedure can cost 3,500 pounds (Rs 3,71,049) in Turkey, but up to 10,000 pounds (Rs 10,60,021) in the UK, and carries the highest risk of all cosmetic surgeries.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/f6q620e8_demi-agoglia_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Demi Agoglia died in Istanbul in January.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-influencer-pokes-woman-in-miniskirt-with-a-stick-for-stunt-detained-for-10-days-7233489]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Influencer Pokes Woman In Miniskirt With A Stick For Stunt, Detained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-influencer-pokes-woman-in-miniskirt-with-a-stick-for-stunt-detained-for-10-days-7233489]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 19:34:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It was later revealed that the woman had been hired by Meng to pose as a passerby, according to the police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese influencer with 46 million followers, identified as Meng or Qi Tiandao, was detained for 10 days after harassing a woman during a live-stream. The incident, which took place in Sanya, involved Meng poking a woman's buttocks with a bamboo stick. The woman, later revealed to be hired for the stunt, was part of an act intended to boost online engagement. However, the police condemned the act for its negative societal impact.</p>

<p>The incident happened during a live-streaming session&nbsp;staged in Sanya at the end of November. In the stream, Meng showed a woman wearing a short skirt who was buying milk tea on the street. Meng then picked up a short bamboo stick, squatted down, and discreetly approached the woman. He used the stick to poke her backside, causing her visible distress.&nbsp;The woman turned to Meng and asked, "Why did you touch my bottom?" Meng responded with a cheeky comment, saying, "I'd like to remind you that half of your buttocks are revealed." The woman's response was not captured.</p>

<p>The scene was broadcast live to his followers. However, it was later revealed that the woman had been hired by Meng to pose as a passerby, according to the police.</p>

<p>After receiving numerous complaints from internet users, Kuaishou suspended Meng's account for 15 days, citing a violation of the platform's rules. Meanwhile, local police have stated that the case is still under investigation. The consequences, if any, for the woman involved in the incident remain unclear.</p>

<p>Meng, previously jailed for fraud, is known for provocative and controversial content to attract viewers. The 28-year-old, better known by his online alias Qi Tiandao on the short video platform Kuaishou, boasts an impressive 46 million followers. He is famous for his humorous live-streaming content, often filmed in outdoor locations across mainland China.</p>

<p>He has a history of legal issues, having served a three-year prison sentence for fraud in 2019. Following his release, he began a career as a blogger, but his content frequently included vulgar and harassing behaviour towards women.</p>

<p>Reacting to the stunt, one user wrote, "I wonder who his followers are. What kind of people are they?" Another commented, "The popularity of this individual, who primarily produces sleazy content, indicates a decline in society's moral standards."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/i377sd7g_arrest_625x300_12_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident, which took place in Sanya, involved Meng poking a woman's buttocks with a bamboo stick.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>