<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:28:21 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-to-mark-holiest-jewish-day-yom-kippur-in-shadow-of-war-6762483]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel To Mark Holiest Jewish Day 'Yom Kippur' In Shadow Of War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-to-mark-holiest-jewish-day-yom-kippur-in-shadow-of-war-6762483]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:22:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This week, for the first time in decades, Israel will observe Yom Kippur, its holiest day, while fighting wars on multiple fronts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week, for the first time in decades, Israel will observe Yom Kippur, its holiest day, while fighting wars on multiple fronts.</p>

<p>From sundown on Friday until nightfall on Saturday, markets will close, flights will stop and public transport will halt as most Jews fast and pray on the Day of Atonement.</p>

<p>But Israeli forces will continue operations against Palestinian militant group Hamas in Gaza and Shiite Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>While Israel typically shuts down for Shabbat, some shops, services and even bus lines still operate, and some broadcasters keep providing news bulletins.</p>

<p>Since Hamas's October 7 attack last year, Israeli media has aired live on Shabbat and other religious days, delivering war-related updates.</p>

<p>Given its status as Judaism's holiest day, Yom Kippur is traditionally observed with a complete media silence.</p>

<p>But this time outlets are ready to cover any major developments or updates on the wars.</p>

<p>Several media representatives told AFP they were prepared to go live if necessary.</p>

<p>"We are on high alert this Yom Kippur, but we hope there won't be a need to go live," said Yael Melzer, spokesperson for Keshet 12 News.</p>

<p>"Each situation will be assessed individually" before deciding whether to break the holiday restrictions, she said.</p>

<p><strong>'Silent channel'</strong></p>

<p>Public broadcaster KAN will operate a "silent channel", allowing television and radio stations to remain on air and only interrupting them for urgent developments, said Ilil Shahar, deputy director of the news division.</p>

<p>Broadcasts will continue until the start of Yom Kippur, when Israel's national anthem, the Hatikva, will be played before the airwaves are silenced.</p>

<p>"We have never aired the television news this close to the start of the holiday," Shahar said.</p>

<p>"We will also have a team on standby throughout the day, something we've never done before."</p>

<p>On Thursday, Israel's Home Front Command distributed instructions on how to receive important information during Yom Kippur, highlighting the "silent channel" and its mobile phone emergency app.</p>

<p>The first time Israel was at war on Yom Kippur was during the 1948 Arab-Israeli war.</p>

<p>In 1973, Egypt and Syria surprised Israel by launching an attack on Yom Kippur.</p>

<p>Both sides suffered heavy losses, with thousands of troops killed.</p>

<p>But that war took place long before the emergence of the 24-hour news cycle and constant social media updates.</p>

<p><strong>'Everything affects us'</strong></p>

<p>Paul Frosh, a professor of communications at the Hebrew University in Jerusalem, said mass and social media provided a sense of connection, which is essential during wartime.</p>

<p>"It's not just that we want to know what's happening," he said.</p>

<p>"I think what will be especially challenging this year is the loss of that sense of connection."</p>

<p>Zamira Miara, 67, from the southern city of Ashkelon, said it would be "impossible to disconnect until this war is over."</p>

<p>"We live in Israel, and everything affects and pains us", she said.</p>

<p>For some, like Itai Elgasian, 30, a shopkeeper in Jerusalem, the silence of the mainstream media may be less of an issue due to the proliferation of social media.</p>

<p>"Everyone today has their own Telegram (channel)... they can scan the news there," he said.</p>

<p>"I think on Yom Kippur, those channels will continue to broadcast."</p>

<p>For some, however, the holiday is a break from the relentless news cycle, a welcome respite that offers time to reflect and pray for the year ahead.</p>

<p>"It is escapism that is sure, positive escapism, maybe we will even enjoy it and maybe it will be for the best," said Jacky Kadosh, 72, a resident of Netanya who was visiting Jerusalem.</p>

<p>Liad Ben Moshe, 24, said a break from the constant "beeps of our phones" would allow worshippers to focus on their connection to the "creator of the world".</p>

<p>"Disconnection leads to connection," she said. "When you disconnect from the outside world, you can connect with yourself, and silence the background noise.</p>

<p>"This Yom Kippur will be more powerful because of that."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/50a1voa_yom-kippur-israel_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The first time Israel was at war on Yom Kippur was during the 1948 Arab-Israeli war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-reporter-captured-by-russia-dies-in-detention-says-kyiv-6762436]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Reporter Captured By Russia Dies In Detention, Says Kyiv]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-reporter-captured-by-russia-dies-in-detention-says-kyiv-6762436]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:14:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Ukrainian journalist who was captured by Moscow while reporting from occupied east Ukraine has died in Russian detention, a Ukrainian official said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Ukrainian journalist who was captured by Moscow while reporting from occupied east Ukraine has died in Russian detention, a Ukrainian official said Thursday.</p>

<p>Victoria Roshchyna, who would have turned 28 this month, disappeared in August last year after travelling to Russian-held east Ukraine for a report.</p>

<p>She remained missing until April 2024, when her father received a letter from Moscow's defence ministry saying she was being held in Russian detention, according to Ukraine's main journalist union.</p>

<p>The circumstances of her arrest were not made public and it was not clear where she was being held inside Russia.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, information about Victoria's death has been confirmed," said Petro Yatsenko, a spokesperson for Ukraine's prison of war coordination headquarters on Thursday.</p>

<p>"It is too early to talk about the circumstances of the death, we are working to establish them," he added.</p>

<p>Press rights group Reporters Without Borders said on social media it was "shocked" by Roshchyna's death and offered condolences to her relatives.</p>

<p>Russian news outlet Mediazona reported she died while being transferred to Moscow from a prison in Taganrog, near the Ukrainian border.</p>

<p>Thousands of Ukrainians opposed to Moscow's rule have been detained in occupied territories since Russia's invasion began in 2022, many of whom face torture at the hands of security forces, according to rights groups.</p>

<p>Ukraine said in May more than two dozen Ukrainian media officials were being held in Russian captivity and that negotiations on their return were underway.</p>

<p>Roshchyna worked as a freelancer for various independent news outlets including Ukrainska Pravda and had collaborated with the Ukrainian service of US-funded media outlet Radio Free Europe.</p>

<p>In 2022, she was awarded the Courage in Journalism award by the International Women's Media Foundation for her reporting from east Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o4scsva8_victoria-roshchyna_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Victoria Roshchyna worked as a freelancer for various independent news outlets (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-israel-not-to-repeat-gaza-destruction-in-lebanon-6762379]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Warns Israel Not To Repeat Gaza Destruction In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-israel-not-to-repeat-gaza-destruction-in-lebanon-6762379]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:08:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States urged its ally Israel to avoid Gaza-like military action in Lebanon, after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said it could face "destruction" like the Palestinian territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States urged its ally Israel to avoid Gaza-like military action in Lebanon, after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said it could face "destruction" like the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>Israel's military chief, Herzi Halevi, vowed to keep bombing Hezbollah targets, a campaign that has killed more than 1,200 people since September 23, "without allowing them any respite or recovery".</p>

<p>The comments came after a phone call between Netanyahu and US President Joe Biden, their first in seven weeks. The White House said Biden told Netanyahu to "minimise harm" to civilians in Lebanon, particularly in "densely populated areas of Beirut".</p>

<p>"There should be no kind of military action in Lebanon that looks anything like Gaza and leaves a result anything like Gaza," said State Department spokesman Matthew Miller.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said in a video address to the people of Lebanon on Tuesday: "You have an opportunity to save Lebanon before it falls into the abyss of a long war that will lead to destruction and suffering like we see in Gaza."</p>

<p>He added: "Free your country from Hezbollah so that this war can end."</p>

<p><strong>'Deadly, precise' retaliation</strong></p>

<p>Biden and Netanyahu's call had been expected to focus on Israel's response to last week's missile barrage by Iran.</p>

<p>Iran fired about 200 missiles at Israel in what it said was retaliation for the killing of Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh. Most were intercepted by Israel or its allies.</p>

<p>Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said: "Our attack on Iran will be deadly, precise and surprising. They will not understand what happened and how it happened."</p>

<p>Biden has cautioned Israel against attempting to target Iran's nuclear facilities, which would risk major retaliation, and opposes striking oil installations.</p>

<p>A Lebanese government source told AFP that Hezbollah had accepted a ceasefire with Israel on September 27, the day Israel killed Nasrallah.</p>

<p>But they said Israel's response had torpedoed the plan, backed by Washington and its allies, and the Lebanese government had "had no contact with Hezbollah" since his death.</p>

<p><strong>Hezbollah rockets, Israeli strikes</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah said its fighters were locked in clashes with Israeli troops in southern Lebanon, using rocket-propelled weapons to repel attempts to breach the border.</p>

<p>Two people were killed by suspected Hezbollah rocket fire in the northern Israeli town of Kiryat Shmona, while Israel intercepted two projectiles fired towards the coastal town of Caesarea, officials said.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said at least four people were killed in an Israeli strike on a village southeast of Beirut, an area so far largely spared from Israeli bombing.</p>

<p>Lebanon's state civil defence body said an Israeli strike killed five of its personnel in the southern village of Derdghaiya.</p>

<p>Israel has intensified air strikes on Hezbollah strongholds in Lebanon since September 23, uprooting more than a million people, according to an AFP tally of official figures.</p>

<p>Its ground forces crossed into Lebanon on September 30 in response to Hezbollah rocket and artillery attacks over the past year that have forced tens of thousands of Israelis from their homes.</p>

<p>Israel's military said Wednesday its troops "eliminated terrorists during close-quarter encounters and in aerial strikes" over the previous 24 hours, adding "100 Hezbollah terror targets were destroyed".</p>

<p>Israeli operations have expanded from border areas in the interior to the southern section of Lebanon's Mediterranean coast.</p>

<p>According to a toll from the Israeli army on Wednesday, 13 of its soldiers have died since ground operations inside Lebanon began.</p>

<p>Syrian state media reported an Israeli attack Thursday on the central provinces of Homs and Hama.</p>

<p>Off the coast of Yemen, a ship was struck and damaged by an "unknown projectile", a British maritime agency said, following months of attacks by Hezbollah and Hamas allies, the Huthis.</p>

<p><strong>Civilians trapped in north Gaza</strong></p>

<p>Israel expanded an ongoing military operation around Jabalia in northern Gaza, where about 400,000 people are trapped, according to Philippe Lazzarini, head of the UN agency for Palestinian refugees.</p>

<p>Lazzarini said on X there was "no end to hell" in the area and that "recent evacuation orders from the Israeli authorities are forcing people to flee again &amp; again".</p>

<p>The army surrounded Jabalia and its refugee camp at the weekend and shelled it on Wednesday, preventing the delivery of aid, Gaza's civil defence agency said.</p>

<p>Washington said it was "incredibly concerned" about the humanitarian situation in north Gaza as Israel tightens its siege.</p>

<p>"We have been making clear to the government of Israel that they have an obligation under international humanitarian law to allow food and water and other needed humanitarian assistance to make it into all parts of Gaza," said the State Department's Miller.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 42,010 people in Gaza, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry that the United Nations has described as reliable.</p>

<p><strong>Displaced in Beirut</strong></p>

<p>Israeli police said at least six people were wounded Wednesday, some seriously, in a stabbing rampage in the central Israeli town of Hadera.</p>

<p>In the occupied West Bank, Israeli border police killed at least four Palestinians in the northern city of Nablus, Palestinian health authorities and Israeli security forces said.</p>

<p>In Beirut, many people are sleeping out in the streets after Israeli air strikes.</p>

<p>Ahmad, a 77-year-old who did not want to give his family name for fear of reprisals, said he had a message for Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"If you can't continue to fight, announce you are withdrawing and that you have lost. There is no shame in losing," he said.</p>

<p>But Raed Ayyash, a displaced man from the south of the country, said he hoped Hezbollah would keep fighting.</p>

<p>"We hope for victory, and we will never give up."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/r1f2pcco_biden-netanyahu-_625x300_05_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden has cautioned Israel against attempting to target Iran's nuclear facilities (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-conference-urges-pm-modi-to-broker-peace-in-west-asia-europe-6762325]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[London-Based Group Urges PM Modi To Broker Peace In West Asia, Europe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-conference-urges-pm-modi-to-broker-peace-in-west-asia-europe-6762325]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 22:59:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi has been urged by a London-based delegation to help negotiate peace among countries that are in conflict. The conference, held in London, appealed to Prime Minister Modi to "intensify his efforts" to help resolve conflicts in Europe]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has been urged by a London-based delegation to help negotiate peace among countries that are in conflict. The conference, which was held in London, appealed to Prime Minister Modi to "intensify his efforts" to help resolve conflicts in Europe and Asia.</p>

<p>The two conflicts which have seen a worrying escalation in world are in West Asia and Europe. In West Asia, the Israel-Gaza war has spread to the north and now even involves Lebanon. To make matters worse, with Iran's ballistic missile attack on Israel, the Middle East crisis has taken a dangerous turn, with a possible all-out war between Israel and Iran.</p>

<p>The conflict in Europe is between Russia and a West-backed Ukraine. With the US and UK's move that may allow Kyiv to target areas deep inside Russia with cruise missiles supplied by Britain, Russia has amended its nuclear doctrine. Moscow has warned the NATO and the Western countries that any escalation by Ukraine to bomb territories inside Russia may lead to a nuclear response.</p>

<p>India, which has friendly ties with both Russia and Ukraine, as well as Israel and Iran, has been urging all parties involved in the crises to desist from any further escalation and resolve issues through diplomacy and dialogue. To this outcome, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has met or spoken to the leaders of all four countries and has assured all possible help in order to bring peace to the regions.</p>

<p>Today, the International Conference of Jurists and Writers for World Peace called upon all governments, international organisations and civil societies to work together to resolve conflicts through peaceful means, prioritising diplomacy, negotiation and mediation. The conference made a special appeal to PM Modi, who has close proximity and friendly relations will all the leaders involved in these conflicts.</p>

<p>A resolution adopted at the conference noted that if the escalation in these war zones are not stopped, "The world will be pushed into a third World War, which can possibly consume millions of lives across nations and cause irreversible damage to economies and the environment."</p>

<p>Dr Adish C Aggarwala, President of the International Council of Jurists, London, and International Commission of Writers, said, "There is volatility and strife in West Asia and other places (in Europe), hostile clashes are claiming hundreds of lives each day in different countries, and the international organisations are unable to bring about a ceasefire.</p>

<p>"Human lives have lost their value and the future is looking bleak and dark," he said, adding, "it is at such a time, the Jurists and Writers from across the globe came together to find ways to bring about peace in an increasingly complex world."</p>

<p>Reading out a message from Prime Minister Modi where he had stressed that "Global peace is necessary for a bright future for humanity," the chief of the international conference appealed to him to help achieve this outcome.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vuui97r_narendra-modi-reuters_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A London-based group has urged PM Modi to negotiate peace in West Asia, Europe.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-nuclear-tensions-between-russia-and-the-west-a-top-meeting-in-new-york-6761907]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Nuclear Tensions Between Russia And West, A Top Meeting In New York]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-nuclear-tensions-between-russia-and-the-west-a-top-meeting-in-new-york-6761907]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 21:44:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of five nuclear weapons states will hold a meeting in New York in the next two weeks, Russian state media quoted Deputy Foreign Minister Sergei Ryabkov as saying on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of five nuclear weapons states will hold a meeting in New York in the next two weeks, Russian state media quoted Deputy Foreign Minister Sergei Ryabkov as saying on Thursday.</p>

<p>The group brings together Russia, the United States, China, France and Britain, all of which are nuclear-armed states and permanent members of the United Nations Security Council.</p>

<p>Ryabkov did not announce a specific date or say what level of officials would attend.</p>

<p>The meeting is potentially significant because of a significant escalation in nuclear tensions between Russia and the West since the start of the Ukraine war.</p>

<p>President Vladimir Putin last month announced changes to Russia's nuclear doctrine, saying Moscow was extending the list of scenarios that could prompt it to consider firing a nuclear weapon.</p>

<p>In January 2022, weeks before Putin sent his army into Ukraine, the "nuclear five" issued a joint statement saying they considered the avoidance of war between nuclear powers and the reduction of strategic risks to be their foremost priorities.</p>

<p>"We affirm that a nuclear war cannot be won and must never be fought," they said at the time.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/55ha3a7_russian-nuclear-missiles-russia-nukes-istock_625x300_10_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin last month announced changes to Russia's nuclear doctrine]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-prince-william-attend-1st-public-event-after-chemotherapy-6761848]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton, Prince William's 1st Public Event After Her Chemotherapy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-prince-william-attend-1st-public-event-after-chemotherapy-6761848]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 21:34:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Catherine, Princess of Wales and her husband Prince William on Thursday made their first joint public engagement since she ended a course of chemotherapy for cancer, Kensington Palace announced.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Catherine, Princess of Wales and her husband Prince William on Thursday made their first joint public engagement since she ended a course of chemotherapy for cancer, Kensington Palace announced.</p>

<p>The couple visited Southport, northwest England, "to show support to the community and hear how local people have come together as the town recovers" from a July knife attack that killed three children, the palace said.</p>

<p>Catherine, also known as Kate, and Prince&nbsp;William met members of the emergency services who responded to the stabbing spree at a Taylor Swift-themed summer dance class, which also injured eight other children and two adults.</p>

<p>The couple, both 42, heard "about their experiences of responding to the attack and the impact it has had on their mental health," their office said in a statement.</p>

<p>The royals also met mental health practitioners who have been supporting emergency responders since the attack.</p>

<p>Kate&nbsp;Middleton announced on September 9 that she had finished her chemotherapy treatment and was striving to be cancer-free.</p>

<p>In a highly emotional video message following her shock diagnosis that saw her stay out of the public eye, she said she was on a long road to "full recovery".</p>

<p>A week later, she took a first step towards returning to her work on the early-years development of children, holding a meeting with staff from the Royal Foundation Centre for Early Childhood which she established.</p>

<p>It was seen as a further positive sign that Kate&nbsp;Middleton, a future queen, was making good progress in her cancer battle.</p>

<p>Footage of Thursday's engagement showed Kate&nbsp;Middleton, wearing a long brown coat and heels, arriving at a community centre in Southport after meeting the attack victims' families in private.</p>

<p>She and Prince&nbsp;William spent around half an hour with each of the three family groups and were 45 minutes late arriving at the centre, according to Britain's domestic Press Association news agency.</p>

<p>Prince&nbsp;William could be heard apologising to the waiting guests on arrival, it said.</p>

<p>Unrest and riots erupted in more than a dozen English towns and cities in the week that followed the events in Southport, with authorities blaming misinformation over the identity of the alleged attacker.</p>

<p>Axel Rudakubana, who was aged 17 at the time, has been charged with murder and attempted murder over the stabbing spree.</p>

<p>He is due in court later this month for a hearing.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/l07mhr3o_kate-middleton-prince-william-afp_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kate Middleton announced on September 9 that she had finished her chemotherapy treatment]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-says-2-peacekeepers-injured-in-israeli-fire-on-headquarters-in-lebanon-6761696]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Says 2 Peacekeepers Injured In Israeli Fire On Headquarters In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-says-2-peacekeepers-injured-in-israeli-fire-on-headquarters-in-lebanon-6761696]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 21:10:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN peacekeeping force in Lebanon UNIFIL said Israeli tank fire on its headquarters in the country's south on Thursday wounded two of its members, as Israeli troops battle Hezbollah militants on the border.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN peacekeeping force in Lebanon UNIFIL said Israeli tank fire on its headquarters in the country's south on Thursday wounded two of its members, as Israeli troops battle Hezbollah militants on the border.</p>

<p>"This morning, two peacekeepers were injured after an IDF Merkava tank fired its weapon toward an observation tower at UNIFIL's headquarters in Naqura, directly hitting it and causing them to fall," the force said, using an acronym for the Israeli military.</p>

<p>"The injuries are fortunately, this time, not serious, but they remain in hospital," it said, adding that "UNIFIL's Naqura headquarters and nearby positions have been repeatedly hit".</p>

<p>According to UNIFIL, the Israeli military also hit another position in Ras Naqura on Thursday.</p>

<p>The peacekeeping force said it hit "the entrance to the bunker where peacekeepers were sheltering, and damaging vehicles and a communications system".</p>

<p>"An IDF drone was observed flying inside the UN position up to the bunker entrance," it said.</p>

<p>UNIFIL, which has some 10,000 peacekeepers stationed in south Lebanon, has called for a ceasefire since an escalation between Israel and Hezbollah on September 23.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, "IDF soldiers deliberately fired at and disabled the position's perimeter-monitoring cameras," it added.</p>

<p>"They also deliberately fired on (a site) where regular tripartite meetings were held before the conflict began, damaging lighting and a relay station."</p>

<p>"We remind the IDF and all actors of their obligations to ensure the safety and security of UN personnel and property and to respect the inviolability of UN premises at all times," it said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o5dm9kj8_lebanon_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UNIFIL has some 10,000 peacekeepers stationed in south Lebanon (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-focus-on-act-east-policy-pm-narendra-modi-meets-top-asian-leaders-in-laos-6761194]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[With Focus On 'Act East' Policy, PM Modi Meets Top Asian Leaders In Laos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-focus-on-act-east-policy-pm-narendra-modi-meets-top-asian-leaders-in-laos-6761194]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 19:54:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Giving impetus to India's 'Act East' policy, Prime Minister Narendra Modi attended a series of meetings in Laos, which is where the ASEAN-India and East Asia summits are being held.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Giving impetus to India's 'Act East' policy, Prime Minister Narendra Modi attended a series of meetings in Laos, which is where the ASEAN-India and East Asia summits are being held.</p>

<p>PM Modi, who is on a two-day visit to Laos on the invitation extended by his counterpart Sonexay Siphandone, was given a ceremonial Guard of Honour upon his arrival. He also participated in a blessing ceremony by senior Buddhist monks of Laos.</p>

<p>Hundreds of members from the Indian community in Laos welcomed PM Modi upon his arrival in Vientiane. The prime minister spoke with the diaspora, signed photographs and witnessed the Bihu dance being performed to welcome him.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The welcome in Lao PDR was memorable! The Indian community is clearly very connected with their roots. Also gladdening was the local people speaking in Hindi and doing a Bihu dance! Do watch… <a href="https://t.co/DqcTQmPdNK">pic.twitter.com/DqcTQmPdNK</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1844298428227993780?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote>

<h2><strong>ANCIENT TIES</strong></h2>

<p>India and Laos have a shared heritage and culture and the prime minister today witnessed an episode of Lao Ramayana, which is called Phalak Phalam or Phra Lak Phra Ram in Laos. The performance highlighted the rich and shared links between the two nations.</p>

<p>"Vijaya Dashami is a few days away and today in Lao PDR, I saw a part of the Lao Ramayana, highlighting the victory of Prabhu Shri Ram over Ravan. It is heartening to see the people here remain in touch with the Ramayan. May the blessings of Prabhu Shri Ram always remain upon us!," PM Modi wrote on social media platform X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Vijaya Dashami is a few days away and today in Lao PDR, I saw a part of the Lao Ramayana, highlighting the victory of Prabhu Shri Ram over Ravan. It is heartening to see the people here remain in touch with the Ramayan. May the blessings of Prabhu Shri Ram always remain upon us! <a href="https://t.co/BskmfMYBdm">pic.twitter.com/BskmfMYBdm</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1844312205824872658?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Ramayan continues to be celebrated in Laos for centuries, reflecting the shared heritage and age-old civilisational connection between the two nations. Many other facets of Indian culture were also practised in the Southeastern nation for centuries.</p>

<p>Myanmar, Laos, Cambodia and Thailand are other nations, predominantly led by Theravada Buddhism have many Ramayan traditions with Buddhist reinterpretations and adaptations.</p>

<p>Notably, Laos was known to ancient Indians as the 'Suvarnabhumi' or the 'Land of Gold'.</p>

<p>As per historical records, when Ashoka waged a war against Kalinga, several people moved to Suvarnabhumi and brought with them Hindu and Buddhist beliefs from across the seas.</p>

<p>Laotian Ramayan is believed to be deeply influenced by the Valmikian narrative and is built on the template of Lao's history and ways of life of the people.</p>

<h3><strong>FROM 'LOOK EAST' TO 'ACT EAST'</strong></h3>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today announced a 10-point plan to strengthen India-ASEAN comprehensive partnership and asserted that ties with the regional grouping were critical to guiding Asia's future.</p>

<p>PM Modi noted that India-ASEAN trade had doubled to over USD 130 billion in the past decade and announced a review of the trade in goods agreement to harness the greater economic potential of the partnership.</p>

<p>"I believe that the 21st century - the Asian century - is the century of India and ASEAN nations," the Prime Minister said while addressing the leaders of the ASEAN nations that include Malaysia, Thailand, Brunei, Cambodia, Indonesia, Myanmar, Philippines, Vietnam, Laos and Singapore.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Proposed ten suggestions which will further deepen India's friendship with ASEAN. <a href="https://t.co/atAOAq6vrq">pic.twitter.com/atAOAq6vrq</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1844352235423318397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The Prime Minister said India was commemorating the 10th anniversary of its Act East Policy, which has given new energy, direction and momentum to the historic relationship between India and the ASEAN nations.</p>

<p>"The India-ASEAN Summit was a productive one. We discussed how to further strengthen the Comprehensive Strategic Partnership between India and ASEAN. We look forward to deepening trade ties, cultural linkages and cooperation in technology, connectivity and other such sectors," PM Modi said in a post on X.</p>

<p>The 10-point plan to further strengthen the India-ASEAN partnership includes celebrating the year 2025 as the ASEAN-India Year of Tourism, doubling the number of scholarships at Nalanda University and providing new grants for ASEAN students at Agricultural Universities in India.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi also announced celebrating the decade of Act East Policy through several people-centric activities including Youth Summit, Start-up Festival, Hackathon, Music Festival, ASEAN-India Network of Think-Tanks and Delhi Dialogue.</p>

<h3><strong>REGIONAL TENSIONS</strong></h3>

<p>PM Modi today said the India-ASEAN friendship was very important at a time when parts of the world were facing conflicts and tensions.</p>

<p>The India-ASEAN Summit is taking place at a time when the region is witnessing tensions between the Philippines and China over maritime issues in the South China Sea and the crisis in Myanmar, where ethnic groups are battling the military regime.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT ELSE IS PLANNED</strong></h3>

<p>Besides the 21st ASEAN-India summit, the prime minister will also attend the 19th East Asia Summit. He will also hold several bilateral meetings with heads of states from member countries.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit underscores how the ASEAN member countries are a crucial part of India's 'Act East' policy. It also reflects New Delhi's cooperation with allies and partners with a common vision of the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<p>The prime minister has prioritised east and southeast Asia with his vision for an initiative called SAGAR - Security And Growth for All in the Region.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit to Laos marks important anniversaries of the establishment of India's diplomatic relations with several countries in the region - 75th with Indonesia, 75th with the Philippines, 60th with Singapore and 40th with Brunei.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qq75eaig_pm-modi-asean-india-summit-2024_625x300_10_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi attended the 21st ASEAN-India Summit in Laos today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/the-lurking-china-threat-in-indo-pacific-waters-6760868]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: The Lurking China Threat In Indo-Pacific Waters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/the-lurking-china-threat-in-indo-pacific-waters-6760868]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 19:04:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's phenomenal rise has changed the balance of power in the Indo-Pacific region and well beyond. It is at the centre of geopolitics and security in the region, which is also resource-oriented in part.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b0qp8sng_indo-pacific_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Resource-geopolitics and security in the&nbsp;Indo-Pacific is a subject that is drawing the attention of countries in this region, which accounts for more than half the world's population, 60% of global GDP, as well as two-thirds of global economic growth.</p>

<p>Resource geopolitics and security were central to the colonial project. The prosperity of the West was built largely on access to the vast resources of the colonised countries. However, while the colonial phase of history is over, there is still concern about neo-colonialist policies operating in open or disguised form in relations between developed and developing countries in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Widening Gap</strong></h2>

<p>Non-western countries have generally benefited from globalisation with foreign investment flows, more open markets, participation in supply chains and export-led growth, even if the gap between the rich and poor nations has widened simultaneously. Most importantly, the gap between technology-rich and resource-rich countries remains unbridged.</p>

<p>Many developing countries with vast mineral resources do not have the capital and technology to exploit them on their own. They need foreign capital and technology to develop them. The gap between what they earn from the export of these raw natural resources and what the developed countries earn from processing and value-addition for industrial use is vast.</p>

<p>Critical and emerging technologies, which require a major R&amp;D and industrial base, will largely remain the preserve of the technologically advanced West. The advance they already have from the time of the Industrial Revolution is sought to be preserved to maintain their dominance of the global system.</p>

<p>The critical raw materials required for many of these technologies are largely in the non-Western countries, though a country like Australia possesses large quantities of lithium, iron ore, uranium, coal and natural gas. This is where geopolitics and security come into play.</p>

<h2><strong>Feeding Chinese Manufacturing&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>This broad picture is blurred with a country like China becoming the world's biggest manufacturing power and needing access to natural resources to feed its vast industrial machine, critical raw materials to maintain its dominance in green technologies, for instance, besides access to agricultural resources of other countries in the region to feed its vast population with rising living standards.</p>

<p>It is noteworthy that after Australia sought an investigation into the source of the COVID-19-causing virus in Wuhan and China imposed sanctions on it, iron ore imports were not included in those curbs.</p>

<p>Apart from geopolitics and security per se, resource geopolitics is an element in the strengthening of India-Australia ties. Australia has turned towards India to reduce its over-dependence on China, and India is interested in access to Australia's natural resources such as uranium and coal in particular.</p>

<p>Indonesia, the largest producer of nickel, is trying to transform itself from an exporter into a key player in the global value chain by banning the export of the raw material.</p>

<p>China's phenomenal rise has changed the balance of power in the Indo-Pacific region and well beyond. It is at the centre of geopolitics and security in the region, which is also resource-oriented in part. It is claiming exclusive military and economic rights over large parts of the South China Sea.</p>

<p>The idea behind China's 9 or 10-dash line, which would make the South China Sea ‘Beijing's Lake', as former Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe said, is to change the balance of military power in the region by extending the reach of its aircraft and missiles to challenge US military power in the region.</p>

<p>The US has bases, troops and a large naval presence in the region as part of a military alliance system that includes Japan, South Korea and the Philippines. It also holds the responsibility for the security of Taiwan.</p>

<h2><strong>Threats In South China Sea</strong></h2>

<p>China seeks to strategically control the important shipping lanes that traverse the South China Sea. Some of the most dynamic economies in the world are in this region, besides China itself as the biggest exporting country, and Japan and South Korea as well. These countries trade with all geographies. Over 60% of global maritime trade passes through these waters, amounting to $3.29 trillion, according to a 2016 estimate.</p>

<p>It is believed that the South China Sea has fairly abundant oil and natural gas resources — by one estimate, approximately 11 billion barrels of petroleum and 190 trillion cubic feet of natural gas in proven and probable reserves. But these are largely in uncontested areas close to the coasts.</p>

<p>Underwater exploration for oil has been done off the coasts of Vietnam, the Philippines, Indonesia, and China. There is already conflict between China and Vietnam over oil drilling in contested areas. In the past, China also protested against ONGC drilling in Vietnamese waters that Beijing claims. ONGC is still operating in this area.</p>

<p>For India, too, resource geopolitics in the western Pacific is important. India plans to increase its investment in Russia's far-East to get access to its rich resources, be it coal, oil, natural gas, etc. The projected Vladivostok-Chennai corridor will pass through these waters. As much as 55% of India's trade is done through the South China Sea and the Malacca Strait. This underlines the importance for India of freedom of navigation in the South China Sea.</p>

<p>In the context of the opening of the Arctic route, free and unhindered access through these waters increases their strategic importance further.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The South China Sea is rich in marine life. This heavily fished area is the main source of animal protein for this densely populated zone. Regional countries want to retain or exercise rights to these fishing stocks, but China is claiming sovereignty over the continental shelf of countries like the Philippines and Indonesia, contrary to the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS).</p>

<h2><strong>Risks In The Indian Ocean Region</strong></h2>

<p>In the Indian Ocean, resource geopolitics and security is less of a factor than in the western Pacific Sea as there are no contested maritime territorial claims. There are, however, issues with regard to illegal, unreported and unregulated (IUU) fishing and intrusions into the continental shelf of countries, which requires monitoring. For countries like India, increased Chinese maritime presence has major geopolitical and security implications.</p>

<p>The Indian Ocean holds rich marine resources, and the fisheries sector is vital for the economies and livelihoods of the populations of the littoral states. The scale of IUU fishing in the EEZs of five countries in the Southwest Indian Ocean - Kenya, Madagascar, Mozambique, South Africa and Tanzania - is a major issue.</p>

<p>Here too, China has expanded its maritime footprint through its fishing fleet. It is a major state actor responsible for much of the IUU fishing worldwide. Its Distant Water Fishing (DWF) fleet in size, destructive conduct, and geopolitical purpose stands out. For China, its DWF is an instrument of national power. China encourages its fishing companies to undertake joint ventures and sign bilateral fishing agreements.</p>

<p>According to a report, China has acquired about 75% of the 130 fishing licenses issued by Mozambique. It exploits the gaps in the competence of Regional Fisheries Management Organisations (RFMOs) in the Indian Ocean, resulting in over-fishing. There are also suspicions that its fishing fleets are part of its military surveillance and intelligence networks.</p>

<h2><strong>Exploitation Of Marine Resources</strong></h2>

<p>The Indian Ocean Rim countries are faced with common pressing challenges of over-exploitation of natural marine resources. Fishing in the Indian Ocean grew by 300% from 1950 to 2018, reaching 6.5 million tonnes annually. Most of the countries in the region have formulated their own fisheries regulations, but they lack proper standards, guidelines, coherent regional arrangement and enforcement mechanisms, owing to limited data and capacity constraints.</p>

<p>Sea bed mining will be part of global competition for resources, and this includes the Indian Ocean. Nodules containing nickel, cobalt, iron, and massive sulphide deposits of manganese, copper, iron, nickel, cobalt, iron, zinc, silver and gold are present in sizeable quantities on the sea bed. China is preparing in a big way to mine minerals like nickel, copper, cobalt and manganese. These are critical materials needed in vast quantities to build a green economy. The International Seabed Authority is still figuring out how mining should be regulated, with some environmental groups wanting an outright ban.</p>

<p>Also, the western rim of the Indian Ocean is flush with oil and gas resources. Resource-related geopolitics and security have marked this area for several decades. The volatility of this area because of its hydrocarbon resources remains. As much as 40% of the world's offshore oil production takes place in the Indian Ocean basin. It holds 16.8% of the world's proven oil reserves and 27.9% of proven natural gas reserves. Nearly 80% of India's crude oil requirement is also imported by sea via the Indian Ocean.</p>

<p>Climate change-induced phenomena, such as extreme weather events and rising ocean temperatures, adversely affect the reproductive patterns and quality of aquatic life in the Indian and Pacific oceans. Human security challenges are arising from climate change impacts such as sea-level rise, ocean acidification, and extreme weather events. The negative impacts of climate change extend beyond land-based agriculture to include fishing and aquaculture activities, which are significant components of agricultural output in the Indo-Pacific nations.</p>

<p><br />
As the population of the Indo-Pacific region increases in the coming decades, its impact on food security and the economy from marine resources will become more substantial. In the Indo-Pacific, as elsewhere, the oceans, seas and coastal areas contribute to food security and poverty eradication. And yet, the oceans are under severe threat by human activities.</p>

<p>The lack of regional maritime security architecture has prompted major powers to compete for control over these resources and sea lanes.</p>

<h2><strong>A Blue Economy</strong></h2>

<p>The focus on a ‘Blue Economy' is important for preserving the oceans as a source of human security. In the September 2015 Mauritius Declaration on Blue Economy, the Indian Ocean Rim Association (IORA) recognised the need for urgent action towards improved governance structures to preserve the ocean's resources for future generations. The blue economy aims at the sustainable management of ocean resources in collaborations across borders and sectors through a variety of partnerships. Goal 14 of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) - Life Below Water - outlines the imperative need to increase cooperation for the conservation and sustainable use of the oceans, seas and marine resources.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Island states are concerned with nontraditional security threats from climate change, IUU fishing, piracy and oil spills as the biggest security threats in the Indian and Pacific Oceans. These issues have not been priority security concerns for major powers in the region, but this gap in the approach to Indo-Pacific security is being bridged.</p>

<p>India has proposed a cooperative framework to handle maritime issues in the Indian Ocean. Its objectives, as outlined by Indian Prime Minister Modi in 2015 under the banner of SAGAR (Security and Growth for All in the Region), are to seek a climate of trust and transparency, respect for international maritime rules and norms by all countries, sensitivity to each other's interests, peaceful resolution of maritime issues, and increase in maritime cooperation.</p>

<p><em>(Kanwal Sibal was Foreign Secretary and Ambassador to Turkey, Egypt, France and Russia, and Deputy Chief Of Mission in Washington.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b0qp8sng_indo-pacific_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-geomagnetic-storm-has-hit-earth-heres-what-it-is-and-what-causes-them-6760398]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Geomagnetic Storm Has Hit Earth. Here's What It Is And What Causes Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-geomagnetic-storm-has-hit-earth-heres-what-it-is-and-what-causes-them-6760398]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 18:01:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A geomagnetic storm lit up the night sky in parts of the US during the first weekend in October. South Africas National Space Agency (Sansa) told reporters that the storm had originated from a solar flare "that erupted from sunspot 3842 on October 3]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A geomagnetic storm <a href="https://www.space.com/aurora-alert-northern-lights-far-south-illinois-oregon-g3-geomagnetic-storm-predicted">lit up</a> the night sky in parts of the US during the first weekend in October. <a href="https://www.sansa.org.za/">South Africa's National Space Agency</a> (Sansa) <a href="https://www.engineeringnews.co.za/article/sansa-warns-geomagnetic-storm-will-impact-earth-over-the-weekend-2024-10-04">told reporters</a> that the storm had originated from a solar flare “that erupted from sunspot 3842 on October 3”. It said this was the strongest Earth-facing solar flare recorded by Sansa in the past seven years and that the eruption briefly affected high-frequency radio communications, “resulting in a total radio blackout over the African region which lasted for up to 20 minutes”.</em></p>

<p><em>What is a geomagnetic storm? The Conversation Africa asked Sansa's Amoré Nel, who <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Amore-Nel">researches geomagnetics</a>, to explain.</em></p>

<h2>What is a geomagnetic storm and how common are they?</h2>

<p>A geomagnetic storm is a disturbance in Earth's magnetic field caused by solar activity. There's a reaction called <a href="https://www.space.com/what-is-nuclear-fusion">nuclear fusion</a> that occurs continuously deep within the Sun's core. This generates massive amounts of energy. Some of the energy is released as light (sunlight), some as radiation (solar flares), and some as charged particles.</p>

<p>The Sun also continuously emits a stream of charged particles known as <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/phenomena/solar-wind">the solar wind</a>. Occasionally, the Sun releases larger bursts of energy, called <a href="https://www.space.com/coronal-mass-ejections-cme">coronal mass ejections</a>. It sends clouds of these charged particles, or plasma, hurtling through space. I like to explain it to children this way: the Sun sometimes drinks a soda too fast and then burps. This “burp” is the cloud of plasma which then travels through space. These emissions don't always hit us. But when they do, they collide with Earth's magnetic field, disrupt it, and lead to a geomagnetic storm.</p>

<p>Earth's magnetic field is an invisible force that surrounds our planet, acting like a giant magnet with a north and south pole. It helps protect us from harmful solar radiation by deflecting charged particles from the Sun.</p>

<p>The solar flare from 3842 emitted both X-flares (radiation) and a coronal mass ejection. X-flares are radiation; they travel at almost the speed of light and reach Earth within minutes. That's what caused the brief communications disruption Sansa mentioned on 3 October. But the coronal mass ejection takes much longer to reach us. We'd predicted it would do so over the past weekend but in fact it only reached us on the morning of 8 October.</p>

<p>Geomagnetic storms occur fairly often. Minor ones happen multiple times per year. The severity of a storm depends on how strong the solar event was that caused it. Larger, more intense storms are less common but can happen every few years. Solar events are closely tied to the Sun's 11-year solar cycle, which has periods of high and low activity. During the peak of the cycle, called solar maximum, more sunspots and solar flares occur, increasing the likelihood of <a href="https://www.sdsu.edu/news/2024/05/qa-as-the-sun-nears-its-11-year-solar-maximum-what-can-we-expect-here-on-earth">solar storms</a>.</p>

<p>We are now heading towards the peak of <a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/solarcycle25/2022/07/27/solar-cycle-25-is-exceeding-predictions-and-showing-why-we-need-the-gdc-mission/">Solar Cycle 25</a>, which will be in July 2025. Solar maxima usually last between two and three years.</p>

<h2>Are these storms dangerous? What damage can they cause?</h2>

<p>Geomagnetic storms are not typically harmful to humans directly, but they can pose risks to modern technology and infrastructure. One of the most notable dangers is to power grids. Powerful storms can induce electric currents in power lines, potentially overloading transformers and causing blackouts, <a href="https://www.solarstorms.org/SS1989.html">as happened</a> in Quebec, Canada, in 1989.</p>

<p>Satellites in space are also vulnerable. A strong storm can damage electronics onboard, disrupt communication signals, and shorten the lifespan of the satellites themselves.</p>

<p>In aviation, geomagnetic storms can disrupt radio communication and GPS signals, which are vital for aircraft navigation. This is especially important for flights that pass near the polar regions, where the effects of geomagnetic storms are more pronounced. Astronauts and spacecraft are also at risk – the extra radiation can be dangerous for equipment and human health.</p>

<h2>Are there any upsides to this phenomenon?</h2>

<p>Auroras are a visually stunning aspect of geomagnetic storms. These colourful displays in the night sky occur when charged particles from the Sun get captured in Earth's magnetic field lines, and funnel down towards the poles. Here they interact with Earth's atmosphere, releasing energy that produces shimmering lights.</p>

<p>Auroras can be seen at both the north and south pole, aptly named the northern and southern lights. If storms are big enough, it's possible to see them in regions much further away from the poles. This happened <a href="https://www.sansa.org.za/2024/05/southern-african-skies-light-up-with-aurora-as-historic-solar-storms-collides-with-earth/">in South Africa on 11 May 2024</a>.</p>

<p>Studying geomagnetic storms provides valuable insights into space weather. By understanding how the Sun's activity affects Earth, scientists can better predict future storms and work to protect the technologies we rely on. The study of geomagnetic storms also contributes to our understanding of the Sun and space in general.</p>

<h2>Can monitoring the storms mitigate the risks?</h2>

<p>Geomagnetic storms are monitored using various instruments on Earth and in space. On Earth, magnetometers measure changes in the magnetic field, allowing scientists to track disturbances as they happen. Sansa operates a dense network of Global Navigation Satellite System receivers in Africa, and magnetometer stations in various parts of southern Africa, for this reason. The agency is currently setting up a magnetometer station in Ethiopia, too. This will improve our ability to monitor geomagnetic storms.</p>

<p>In space, satellites equipped with sensors monitor the Sun's activity and detect solar flares or coronal mass ejections before they reach Earth. This data feeds into prediction models used in space weather centres across the globe.</p>

<p>Once a storm is detected, agencies like Sansa issue alerts and forecasts. These warnings help industries such as power grid operators, satellite companies and aviation authorities to prepare for a storm.</p>

<p>For example, power companies can temporarily shut down or reconfigure parts of the grid to avoid overloading during a storm. Satellite operators can place their spacecraft into safer operating modes, such as switching off electronic components, and airlines can reroute flights away from high-risk areas.</p>

<p>Monitoring alone can't prevent all the damage caused by geomagnetic storms. But it can greatly reduce the risks. Thanks to early warning systems we can protect crucial infrastructure and minimise the effect these storms have on our daily lives.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/240737/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amore-elsje-nel-1543902">Amoré Elsje Nel</a>, Applied Geomagnetic Researcher, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/south-african-national-space-agency-5510">South African National Space Agency</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(</span><strong><span>Disclosure Statement:</span></strong><span> </span>Amoré Elsje Nel works for the South African National Space Agency. She receives a Thuthuka Grant (TTK210406592410) from the National Research Foundation)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/a-geomagnetic-storm-has-hit-earth-a-space-scientist-explains-what-causes-them-240737">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/06advnm_geomagnetic-storm-the-conversation-getty_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Geomagnetic storms bring vibrant colours to life. Christopher Mark Juhn/Anadolu via Getty Images]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-overtakes-donald-trump-among-suburban-voters-latest-poll-reveals-6759783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Overtakes Donald Trump Among Suburban Voters, Poll Reveals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-overtakes-donald-trump-among-suburban-voters-latest-poll-reveals-6759783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 16:42:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has erased Republican rival Donald Trump's advantage in the vast middle of American society: suburban residents and middle-income households, an analysis of Reuters/Ipsos polling shows.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris has erased Republican rival Donald Trump's advantage in the vast middle of American society: suburban residents and middle-income households, an analysis of Reuters/Ipsos polling shows.</p>

<p>Since President Joe Biden ended his flagging reelection bid on July 21, Vice President Harris has pulled into the lead in both of these large demographic groups, reinvigorating Democrats' prospects in the Nov. 5 election, though the race remains exceptionally close.</p>

<p>Suburbanites, who make up about half of the U.S. electorate and are as racially diverse as the nation at large, are a key prize. Biden beat Trump in suburban counties by about six percentage points in the 2020 presidential election.</p>

<p>Before Biden dropped out, Trump was leading him 43% to 40% among suburbanites in Reuters/Ipsos polls conducted in June and July, reflecting the Democrat's struggle to energize supporters.</p>

<p>Harris began closing the gap when she launched her campaign in July and led Trump 47% to 41% among suburban voters in polling across September and October. That represents a nine-point swing in the Democrat's favor, according to the analysis of six Reuters/Ipsos polls that included responses from over 6,000 registered voters.</p>

<p>During the same periods, Trump went from leading Biden 44% to 37% among voters in households that earn between $50,000 and $100,000 - roughly the middle third of the nation - to trail Harris 43% to 45%, also a nine-point swing away from Trump. The figures had margins of error of around 3 percentage points.</p>

<p>Trump carried this group 52%-47% in 2020, according to a Pew Research Center analysis of exit polls.</p>

<p>Reuters/Ipsos surveys have shown voters consider the economy the No. 1 issue ahead of the election and in a poll conducted in October, 46% of voters said Trump was the better candidate for the economy, 8 points more than Harris' 38%.</p>

<p>The polls have also shown Trump as the more trusted candidate on immigration and crime. Trump told supporters in August he was the candidate that would keep suburbs safe and ensure that migrants coming across the border illegally are kept "away from the suburbs."</p>

<p>Trump has blamed the Biden administration for inflation that has hurt middle class Americans. Harris, meanwhile, has put considerable focus in her speeches on pledges to increase the size of the middle class. She also is more often picked in polls as the better candidate for protecting democracy and taking a stand against political extremism.</p>

<p>"Her focus on affordability has been highly effective in narrowing Trump's advantage on inflation and the economy," said David Wasserman, a political analyst at the Cook Political Report.</p>

<p>Wasserman said Harris appeared to be performing well among relatively affluent suburbanites who could be growing more optimistic about the economy, while her gains among middle-income voters could be due to her campaign's regular pledges to help middle-class households.</p>

<p>But he noted that voter turnout in Democratic-leaning urban areas and Republican-leaning rural towns could also be critical in deciding the election.</p>

<h2><strong>TUNING IN</strong></h2>

<p>Harris supporters contacted by Reuters for follow-up interviews this week also said they had not paid much attention to her before she became a presidential candidate, and that they became more supportive of her as they learned more about her.</p>

<p>The latest of the six polls, conducted Oct. 4-7, showed Harris up a marginal 3 percentage points over Trump among registered voters overall, 46% to 43%.</p>

<p>Her modest edge in national polling is significant although the winner of the election will likely be determined by the results in seven battleground states - Arizona, Michigan, Pennsylvania, North Carolina, Nevada, Wisconsin and Georgia - where polls have also shown a tight race.</p>

<p>Winning the middle - whether nationally or in the election's key states - won't necessarily crown the victor. Democrat Hillary Clinton, who got nearly 3 million votes more than Trump nationwide in the 2016 election and beat him in suburban counties by about 1 percentage point, still lost the election when Trump flipped six states that had voted Democratic in 2012.</p>

<p>Poll respondent Sheila Lester, an 83-year-old Harris supporter living in Peoria, Arizona, which mostly lies in the state's battleground Maricopa County, said in a phone interview that she had become convinced Trump would beat Biden.</p>

<p>She said she rejoiced when the Democratic Party quickly coalesced around the candidacy of Harris, especially since she could be the first woman U.S. president.</p>

<p>"The response that she has gotten has made me a little bit more proud of this country," said Lester, a retired customer service employee who considers herself part of the middle class. She said she liked Harris' toughness on abortion rights and her pledge to grow the middle class. "I am definitely anti-Trump, but I believe I'm more pro-Harris."</p>

<p>Maricopa County played an important role in Biden's 2020 victory, when the county narrowly flipped Democratic after voting for Trump in 2016.</p>

<p>Karen Davidson, 83, who lives in West Bloomfield, Michigan, a middle-class suburb of Detroit, said she had not been that familiar with Harris before she moved to the top of the ticket.</p>

<p>"I needed to know more about her to form any kind of thought," Davidson said.</p>

<p>"The way she stood up to people who were berating her, I had to respect that having been in the industrial machinery business when women didn't work in it, I know what that's like," Davidson continued. "She had the strength, and that's what's needed to run our country."</p>

<p>In Pooler, Georgia, a suburb of Savannah, grocery store employee Kevin Garcia said he also was relieved Biden had bowed out and preferred Harris' pledges to support small businesses over Trump's promise to tax imported goods.</p>

<p>"I just feel better about the chances," said Garcia, 24, who lives in a single-family home neighborhood in the state that, like Arizona, narrowly flipped Democratic in 2020.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0co3a0fs_kamala-harris-donald-trump-harris-trump-reuters_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[2024 US Elections: Democratic candidate Kamala Harris now leads Republican rival Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-literature-goes-to-south-korean-author-han-kang-6759706]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Prize In Literature Goes To South Korean Author Han Kang]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-literature-goes-to-south-korean-author-han-kang-6759706]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 16:32:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Prize 2024: South Korean writer Han Kang, was awarded 2024 the Nobel Prize in Literature, "for her intense poetic prose that confronts historical traumas and exposes the fragility of human life."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean writer Han Kang, was awarded 2024 the Nobel Prize in Literature, "for her intense poetic prose that confronts historical traumas and exposes the fragility of human life."</p>

<p>The prize is awarded by the Swedish Academy and is worth 11 million Swedish crowns ($1.1 million).</p>

<p>Han Kang was born in Gwangju, South Korea, in 1970. She comes from a literary background, her father being a reputed novelist.&nbsp;She made her literary debut as a poet by publishing five poems, including "Winter in Seoul", in the winter issue of Munhak-gwa-sahoe (Literature and Society) in 1993. She began her career as a novelist the next year by winning the 1994 Seoul Shinmun Spring Literary Contest with "Red Anchor". She published her first short story collection entitled Yeosu (Munji Publishing Company) in 1995. She participated in the University of Iowa International Writing Program for three months in 1998 with support from the Arts Council Korea.</p>

<p>Her <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://han-kang.net/Biography" rel="no follow, no index">publications</a> include a short story collection, Fruits of My Woman (2000), Fire Salamander (2012); novels such as Black Deer (1998), Your Cold Hands (2002), The Vegetarian (2007), Breath Fighting (2010), and Greek Lessons (2011), Human Acts (2014), The White Book (2016), I Do Not Bid Farewell(2021). A poem collection, I Put The Evening in the Drawer (2013) was published as well. Han Kang won the International Booker Prize in 2016 for 'The Vegetarian'.</p>

<p>Her most recent novel 'I Do Not Bid Farewell' was awarded the Medicis prize in France in 2023, the Emile Guimet prize in 2024.</p>

<p>Han Kang's work is characterized by this double exposure of pain, a correspondence between mental and physical torment with close connections to Eastern thinking, the committee said.</p>

<p>Han Kang confronts historical traumas and invisible sets of rules and, in each of her works, exposes the fragility of human life. She has a unique awareness of the connections between body and soul, the living and the dead, and in her poetic and experimental style has become an innovator in contemporary prose, the Nobel Prize committee said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/73c21rtg_nobel-prize-in-literature_625x300_10_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nobel Prize Winner 2024: Han Kang won the International Booker Prize in 2016 for 'The Vegetarian'.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-footage-captures-hurricane-miltons-destructive-path-over-florida-6759184]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Satellite Footage Shows Devastating Path Of Hurricane Milton Over Florida]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-footage-captures-hurricane-miltons-destructive-path-over-florida-6759184]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:26:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meteorologists and emergency management officials are monitoring satellite data to track Milton's trajectory and intensity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) has released dramatic satellite footage capturing Hurricane Milton's landfall in Florida, showcasing the sheer power of the storm from a cosmic perspective. The footage, released Thursday, illustrates the hurricane's spiralling mass over the southeasternmost US state, featuring intense lightning activity that illuminates its centre.</p>

<p>Milton struck Florida's west coast near Siesta Key on Wednesday as a Category 3 hurricane, forming a striking image of its eye encircled by dense cloud bands stretching hundreds of miles. The satellite visuals highlight the storm's massive impact on a wide area of Florida and neighbouring states.</p>

<p>"This imagery from NOAA's GOES-East provides visible cloud imagery every 30 seconds of Hurricane Milton as it pushes closer to Florida. Notice the frequent lightning being detected by the satellite's GLM instrument as well," the caption reads.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA6u2afNkeE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA6u2afNkeE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA6u2afNkeE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA6u2afNkeE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by NOAA Satellites (@noaasatellites)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>One of the most eye-catching aspects of the imagery is the frequent lightning flashes observed in southern Florida, where multiple tornadoes formed during the storm's passage. This captivating light show within the storm system underscores the extreme weather conditions experienced on the ground.</p>

<p>Milton moved across central Florida on Thursday, leaving a trail of destruction. With winds reaching up to 120 miles per hour at landfall, the hurricane caused extensive damage, uprooting trees, destroying homes, and leaving nearly 2 million people without power across the state.</p>

<p>Meteorologists and emergency management officials are monitoring satellite data to track Milton's trajectory and intensity. This information is vital for issuing timely alerts and coordinating emergency response efforts.</p>

<p>Although Milton has since weakened to a Category 1 hurricane, it continues to pose serious risks as it travels further inland.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g2ckco8g_-hurricane-miltons-landfall-in-florida_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Milton moved across central Florida on Thursday, leaving a trail of destruction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/no-biden-doesnt-get-to-moan-over-an-out-of-hand-netanyahu-now-6759097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: No, Biden Doesn't Get To Moan Over An 'Out-Of-Hand' Netanyahu Now]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/no-biden-doesnt-get-to-moan-over-an-out-of-hand-netanyahu-now-6759097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:16:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Last week, the most powerful leader of the most powerful country found himself, shall we say, whining about 'Bibi' - as Netanyahu's nickname goes - almost like a disappointed father admonishing his beloved but mischievous son.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/u1clpiho_biden_625x300_10_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It's not every day a country dares to ignore the mighty America. Most nations know that defying the US President may result in a stern warning, maybe a bit of diplomatic cold shoulder or, in the worst-case scenario, a new set of sanctions. But then again, not every leader is Benjamin Netanyahu. The Israeli Prime Minister seems to have perfected the art of dodging President Joe Biden's advice - without much harm to himself.</p>

<p>Last week, the most powerful leader of the most powerful country found himself, shall we say, whining about 'Bibi' - as Netanyahu's nickname goes - almost like a disappointed father admonishing his beloved but mischievous son. Answering a reporter in the hallowed White House, Biden wore a look of betrayal, complaining, "No administration has helped Israel more than I have. None. None. None. And I think Bibi should remember that." The scene was shocking. Biden must have been so pained that his words felt less like diplomacy and more like a hapless parent wondering why his rebellious son does not listen to him anymore.</p>

<p>The reporter's question was directly related to a nagging suspicion in Democratic Party circles that the Israeli Prime Minister was deliberately dragging his feet on a ceasefire in Gaza, proposed by Biden in May. Biden echoed that view and wondered whether Netanyahu was stalling the proposed ceasefire until the US Presidential election on November 5. The President said, "And whether he is trying to influence the election, I don't know, but I am not counting on it"</p>

<p>Biden really shouldn't have been shocked. After all, back when he was Vice-President under Obama, Netanyahu had the audacity to go right past the White House and address the Republican-dominated Congress to publicly trash the Iran nuclear deal. He was just biding his time, waiting for either Hillary or Trump to step in after the 2016 election and fix things. Then, Trump got elected. And what did he do? He cancelled the deal, handing Netanyahu exactly what he had been waiting for.</p>

<h2><strong>No One Is Sorry For Biden</strong></h2>

<p>Any sympathy for Biden's heartbreak? There appears to be none. How ironic that now that he is on his way out, he is accusing Netanyahu of dragging his feet on a ceasefire. Up until now, Biden had been conveniently ignoring Bibi's stalling tactics, instead pinning the blame squarely on Hamas every time talks broke down. Never mind that his own advisors and party leaders subtly hinted that Netanyahu wasn't interested in any ceasefire deal-at least not until January 2025, when a new President enters the White House. It is obvious that Bibi is betting big on a Trump comeback. Under Trump's Presidency, he believes he could have a free hand in West Asia.</p>

<p>Of course, no one's suggesting that Israel is meddling in the US election. Right or wrong, the meddling accusations are reserved for China, Russia and Iran. But Biden's point was clear: Netanyahu seems to be stalling the ceasefire, hoping to drag things out until the election. If a ceasefire happens earlier, Democratic Party nominee Kamala Harris might get a boost. But if things stay messy, Netanyahu's old buddy Trump could swoop back in-and wouldn't that be a convenient reunion?</p>

<p>Senator Chris Murphy, who is a close friend of President Biden, recently told <em>CNN</em>, "I don't think you have to be a hopeless cynic to read some of Israel's actions, some of Prime Minister Netanyahu's actions, as connected to the American election". Several US mainstream newspapers had carried stories in September quoting US officials as saying that they did not believe a deal would be reached during Biden's Presidency</p>

<h2><strong>American Presidents' Badges Of Honour</strong></h2>

<p>Foreign policy, let's be real, rarely moves the needle in a US election. Yet every presidential candidate somehow convinces himself that if he doesn't stand rock-solid with Israel, his chances of winning will diminish - despite no evidence to back that up. Since the 1973 Arab-Israeli war, every US president has proudly pledged to support Israel and zealously guarded its security. They worked tirelessly to broker peace deals between Israel and Palestinians or Arab nations. And those who succeeded at striking a peace deal wore it like a shiny badge of honour - even though some of those deals were, let's just say, less than groundbreaking, and favoured Israel. A few examples:</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Camp David Accord, 1978</strong>. Jimmy Carter facilitated a historic peace agreement between Egypt and Israel, which led to Egypt recognising Israel and Israel returning the Sinai Peninsula back to Egypt</li>
	<li><strong>Oslo Accord, 1993</strong>. Bill Clinton successfully mediated the first face-to-face agreement between Israel and the Palestinian Liberation Organisation(PLO), resulting in the Oslo Accord in 1993. It created a framework for future peace talks</li>
	<li><strong>Roadmap for peace, 2003</strong>. George W. Bush pushed for a two-state solution through this agreement but he faced difficulties in implementing it</li>
	<li><strong>Abraham Accords, 2020</strong>. Donald Trump brokered normalisation agreements for Israel with the UAE, Bahrain, Sudan and Morocco, which reshaped West Asia relations. The next in line was a deal with Saudi Arabia, but last year's deadly attack by Hamas on Israel derailed the peace process. Many critics of the accords argued that the agreements had completely sidestepped the Palestinians' demands for a state</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Biden's Ironclad Support For Israel</strong></h2>

<p>In recent years, only two presidents - Joe Biden and his old boss Barack Obama - completely missed the peace deal train in West Asia, though Obama managed to strike a nuclear deal with Iran, which was later rescinded by Trump. Obama, in particular, had a famously chilly relationship with 'Bibi'. In fact, it's widely considered the worst personal dynamic ever between a US president and an Israeli prime minister. And that's despite the two countries achieving peak security cooperation.</p>

<p>Biden may have failed to deliver any peace deal in West Asia, but make no mistake, under his presidency, Israel has got the maximum support. He has blindly backed Israel's systematic destruction of Gaza and refused to put conditions on US military aid. Therefore, he was not really wrong when he complained on Friday that "no administration has helped Israel more than I have".</p>

<h2><strong>The US Is Already At War</strong></h2>

<p>For years, the US has maintained the fiction that it is an honest peace broker and a neutral mediator in West Asia. But America's role in the West Asia crisis is a perfect example of mixed signals. On one hand, it is supposedly working tirelessly to broker a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas. On the other hand, it is arming Israel to the teeth, basically giving them the green light to keep pounding away in Gaza and Lebanon. And let's not forget, Biden has made it crystal clear that he will jump to Israel's defence if Iran even thinks about attacking them again. Honestly, many would argue that the US is already knee-deep in this conflict, considering it has helped Israel destroy Iranian missiles not once but twice since April, shares intel with the Israeli military daily, and has warships ready to roll in the Red Sea in defence of the Jewish state. This does not sound like a neutral referee in the region, does it?</p>

<p>The Trump administration finally dropped the mask when it openly sided with Israel against the Palestinians, which led to Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas declaring the US as an untrustworthy peace broker. What infuriated the Palestinians was that they were disregarded in the Abraham Accords signed between Israel and a clutch of Arab states. Additionally, Trump's controversial decision to move the US embassy to Jerusalem also angered the Palestinians.</p>

<p>Today, it is almost sickening to see how Biden is botching his ceasefire efforts by being unassertive. While he is blinded by his love for Israel, the world watches with bated breath, powerless to intervene. The UN Security Council has proven to be toothless. BRICS and G20 are disappointingly muted. It reminds this writer of a couple of lines from a Matthew Arnold poem, "Wandering between two worlds. One dead, the other powerless to be born".&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2pe92s3g_biden_625x300_10_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-dog-left-tied-to-fence-amid-hurricane-milton-rescued-by-cops-in-us-6759073]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Dog, Left Tied To Fence Amid Hurricane Milton, Rescued By Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-dog-left-tied-to-fence-amid-hurricane-milton-rescued-by-cops-in-us-6759073]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:13:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Hurricane Milton made landfall on the Florida coast, a shocking video of a dog abandoned and tied to a fence in deep water has gone viral. The helpless dog was reportedly tied to a chicken-wire fence near Interstate 75 in Tampa on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Hurricane Milton made landfall on the Florida coast, a shocking video of a dog&nbsp; abandoned and tied to a fence in deep water has gone viral. The helpless dog, left by its owners, was tied to a chicken-wire fence near Interstate 75 in Tampa on Wednesday, <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/10/09/hurricane-milton-pet-protection-natural-disaster/75591195007/">USA Today </a>reported.</p>

<p>The viral video, posted on the Florida Highway Patrol in Tampa's X handle, shows an officer approaching the dog that appears to be a bull terrier and standing in water as high as his belly. As the officer came close to the dog, the pup started growling in fear. "It's okay," the officer can be heard saying.</p>

<p>As the dog started barking at the office, he said, "I don't blame you. It's okay buddy. It's okay".</p>

<p>While sharing the 35-second video, the agency wrote, "FHP Troopers rescued a dog left tied to a pole on I-75 near Bruce B Downs Blvd this morning.&nbsp; Do NOT do this to your pets please…"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">FHP Troopers rescued a dog left tied to a pole on I-75 near Bruce B Downs Blvd this morning. Do NOT do this to your pets please… <a href="https://t.co/8cZJOfkJL2">pic.twitter.com/8cZJOfkJL2</a></p>
— FHP Tampa (@FHPTampa) <a href="https://twitter.com/FHPTampa/status/1844036069219574083?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It soon went viral and garnered more than 10 million views. It also caught the attention of Florida Governor Ron DeSantis who said the police would hold anyone accountable who abandoned their pets in the face of the hurricane.</p>

<p>"Thank you, @FHPTampa. It is cruel for anyone to leave a dog tied to a post in the middle of an oncoming storm. FL will hold anyone who mistreats pets accountable," DeSantis said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thank you, <a href="https://twitter.com/FHPTampa?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FHPTampa</a>.<br />
<br />
It is cruel for anyone to leave a dog tied to a post in the middle of an oncoming storm. FL will hold anyone who mistreats pets accountable. <a href="https://t.co/19axr8CLf0">https://t.co/19axr8CLf0</a></p>
— Ron DeSantis (@GovRonDeSantis) <a href="https://twitter.com/GovRonDeSantis/status/1844058578438717589?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles (FLHSMV) later said the dog was finally rescued and safe with police.</p>

<p>"The dog rescued by @FHPTampa is safe and receiving care. Troopers brought him to a vet, where he was examined for injuries and received a clean bill of health," it stated.</p>

<p>In the comments section, several users expressed anger over the "ridiculous" act of leaving the animal behind. Some even demanded legal action against the owners.</p>

<p>"This is ridiculous. The owner needs to face legal consequences," one person wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is ridiculous. The owner needs to face legal consequences.</p>
— Paul A. Szypula ???????? (@Bubblebathgirl) <a href="https://twitter.com/Bubblebathgirl/status/1844046562202366279?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another one added, "People who harm children and pets are the lowest in society and need to be dealt with accordingly."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">People who harm children and pets are the lowest in society and need to be dealt with accordingly.</p>
— Joe (@UFLORIDAJOE) <a href="https://twitter.com/UFLORIDAJOE/status/1844039130323542130?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
According to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/maryroeloffs/2024/10/10/hurricane-milton-live-updates-more-than-3-million-homes-without-power-as-storm-moves-past-florida-east-coast/">Forbes</a>, over three million homes and businesses were left without electricity on Thursday after Hurricane Milton exited Florida as a category 1 storm.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The National Hurricane Center said that it has now shifted past the US state's east coast but continues to produce “damaging hurricane-force winds” and heavy rains.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f4d03378_dog-hurricane-milton_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video has gone viral and garnered more than 10 million views]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/physics-chemistry-nobel-prize-winners-google-links-stir-debate-over-ai-research-6758662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Physics, Chemistry Nobel Winners' Google Links Stir Debate Over AI Research]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/physics-chemistry-nobel-prize-winners-google-links-stir-debate-over-ai-research-6758662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 14:10:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The award this week of Nobel prizes in chemistry and physics to a small number of AI pioneers affiliated with Google has stirred debate over the company's research dominance and how breakthroughs in computer science ought to be recognised.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The award this week of Nobel prizes in chemistry and physics to a small number of artificial intelligence pioneers affiliated with Google has stirred debate over the company's research dominance and how breakthroughs in computer science ought to be recognised.</p>

<p>Google has been at the forefront of AI research, but has been forced on the defensive as it tackles competitive pressure from Microsoft-backed OpenAI and mounting regulatory scrutiny from the US Department of Justice.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Demis Hassabis - co-founder of Google's AI unit DeepMind - and colleague John Jumper were awarded the Nobel prize in chemistry, alongside US biochemist David Baker, for their work decoding the structures of microscopic proteins.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-chemistry-goes-to-scientists-david-baker-demis-hassabis-john-jumper-6751373">3 Scientists Get Nobel Prize In Chemistry For Work On Protein Structures</a></p>

<p>Former Google researcher Geoffrey Hinton, meanwhile, won the Nobel prize for physics on Tuesday, alongside US scientist John Hopfield, for earlier discoveries in machine learning that paved the way for the AI boom.</p>

<p>Professor Dame Wendy Hall, a computer scientist and advisor on AI to the United Nations, told Reuters that, while the recipients' work deserved recognition, the lack of a Nobel prize for mathematics or computer science had distorted the outcome.</p>

<p>"The Nobel prize committee doesn't want to miss out on this AI stuff, so it's very creative of them to push Geoffrey through the physics route," she said. "I would argue both are dubious, but nonetheless worthy of a Nobel prize in terms of the science they've done. So how else are you going to reward them?"</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/nobel-prize-in-physics-goes-to-john-hopfield-geoffrey-hinton-for-work-on-machine-learning-6743213">Nobel Prize In Physics Goes To 2 Scientists For Work On AI</a></p>

<p>Noah Giansiracusa, an associate maths professor at Bentley University and author of "How Algorithms Create and Prevent Fake News", also argued that Hinton's win was questionable.</p>

<p>"What he did was phenomenal, but was it physics? I don't think so. Even if there's inspiration from physics, they're not developing a new theory in physics or solving a longstanding problem in physics."</p>

<p>The Nobel prize categories for achievements in medicine or physiology, physics, chemistry, literature and peace were laid down in the will of Swedish inventor Alfred Nobel, who died in 1895. The prize for economics is a later addition established with an endowment from the Swedish central bank in 1968.</p>

<h2><strong>Dominance</strong></h2>

<p>Regulators in the US are currently circling Google for a potential break-up, which could force it to divest parts of its business, such as its Chrome browser and Android operating system, which some argue allow it to maintain an illegal monopoly in online search.</p>

<p>The profits derived from its leading position have allowed Google and other Big Tech companies to outpace traditional academia in publishing groundbreaking AI research.</p>

<p>Hinton himself has expressed some regrets about his life's work, quitting Google last year so that he could speak freely about the dangers of AI, and warning that computers could become smarter than people far sooner than previously expected.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-proteins-again-nobel-winning-chemistry-explained-6754535">What Are Proteins Again? Nobel-Winning Chemistry Explained</a></p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference Tuesday, he said: "I wish I had a sort of simple recipe that if you do this, everything's going to be okay, but I don't, in particular with respect to the existential threat of these things getting out of control and taking over."</p>

<p>When he quit Google in 2023 over his AI concerns, Hinton said the company itself acted very responsibly.</p>

<p>For some, this week's Nobel prize wins underscore how hard it is becoming for traditional academia to compete. Giansiracusa told Reuters there was a need for greater public investment in research.</p>

<p>"So much of Big Tech is not oriented towards the next deep-learning breakthrough, but making money by pushing chatbots or putting ads all over the internet," he said. "There are pockets of innovation, but much of it is very unscientific."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/iaooaoeg_nobel-prize-replica-in-norway-afp_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Regulators in the US are currently circling Google for a potential break-up.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-milton-destroys-homes-leaves-2-million-without-power-in-florida-6758554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton Destroys Homes, Leaves 2 Million Without Power In Florida]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-milton-destroys-homes-leaves-2-million-without-power-in-florida-6758554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 13:53:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton marched across central Florida on Thursday after making landfall on the state's west coast hours earlier, whipping up deadly tornadoes, destroying homes and knocking out power to nearly 2 million customers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane Milton marched across central Florida on Thursday after making landfall on the state's west coast hours earlier, whipping up deadly tornadoes, destroying homes and knocking out power to nearly 2 million customers.</p>

<p>The storm made landfall around 8:30 p.m. EDT (0030 GMT) on Wednesday as a Category 3 hurricane with maximum sustained winds of 120 miles per hour (195 kph) near Siesta Key, the U.S. National Hurricane Center said.</p>

<p>By early Thursday, wind speeds reduced to a still dangerous 90 mph (150 kph), dropping Milton to a Category 1 hurricane, with heavy rains and damaging storm surges. The hurricane was located about 45 miles (75 km) west-southwest of Cape Canaveral, home to NASA's Space Force Station.</p>

<p>A flash flood emergency was in effect for the Tampa Bay area including the cities of Tampa, St. Petersburg and Clearwater, the hurricane center said, with St. Petersburg already receiving 16.6 inches (422 mm) of rain on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The eye of the storm made landfall in Siesta Key, a barrier island town of some 5,400 off Sarasota about 60 miles (100 km) south of the Tampa Bay metropolitan area, which is home to more than 3 million people.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kk6t0dqg_hurricane-milton_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Governor Ron DeSantis said he hoped Tampa Bay, once seen as the potential bull's eye, could dodge major damage and that the worst of the predicted storm surge could be avoided thanks to the landfall coming before the high tide. Forecasters said seawater could still rise as high as 13 feet (4 meters).</p>

<p>DeSantis reported Milton had also spawned at least 19 tornadoes caused damage in numerous counties, destroying around 125 homes, most of them mobile homes.</p>

<p>"At this point, it's too dangerous to evacuate safely, so you have to shelter in place and just hunker down," DeSantis said upon announcing the landfall.</p>

<p>At least two deaths were reported at a retirement community following a suspected tornado in Fort Pierce on the eastern coast of Florida, NBC News reported, citing St. Lucie County Sheriff Keith Pearson. His department did not immediately respond to a request for details.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/milton-explained-how-milton-became-a-powerful-hurricane-and-why-its-a-concern-6750186">Explained: How Milton Became A Powerful Hurricane And Why It's A Concern</a></p>

<p>Pearson estimated 100 homes were destroyed in the county where some 17 tornadoes touched down, NBC said.</p>

<p>More than 2 million homes and businesses in Florida were without power, according to PowerOutage.us.</p>

<p>The storm was expected to cross the Florida peninsula overnight and emerge into the Atlantic, still with hurricane force, on Thursday.</p>

<p>Milton is forecast to maintain hurricane intensity while crossing Florida later on Thursday morning but after moving into the Atlantic it is likely to gradually lose tropical characteristics and slowly weaken, the Hurricane Center added.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kp0do9qo_hurricane-milton_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>In a state already battered by Hurricane Helene two weeks ago, as many as two million people were ordered to evacuate, and millions more live in the projected path of the storm.</p>

<p>Much of the southern U.S. experienced the deadly force of Hurricane Helene as it cut a swath of devastation through Florida and several other states. Both storms are expected to cause billions of dollars in damage.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden was briefed by emergency authorities on the initial impacts of the hurricane, according to a White House statement.</p>

<p><strong>Zoo Animals Protected</strong></p>

<p>While human evacuees jammed the highways and created gasoline shortages, animals including African elephants, Caribbean flamingos and pygmy hippos were riding out the storm at Tampa's zoo.</p>

<p>Nearly a quarter of Florida's gasoline stations were out of fuel on Wednesday afternoon.</p>

<p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency had moved millions of liters (gallons) of water, millions of meals and other supplies and personnel into the area. None of the additional aid will detract from recovery efforts for Hurricane Helene, the agency's administrator, Deanne Criswell, said earlier on Wednesday.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/monster-hurricane-milton-makes-landfall-in-florida-with-damaging-winds-flooding-rains-and-life-threatening-storm-surge-6756596">Monster Hurricane Milton Makes Landfall In Florida With Damaging Winds</a></p>

<p>Trucks have been running 24 hours a day to clear mounds of debris left behind by Helene before Milton potentially turned them into dangerous projectiles, DeSantis said.</p>

<p>About 9,000 National Guard personnel were deployed in Florida, ready to assist recovery efforts, as were 50,000 electricity grid workers in anticipating of widespread power outages, DeSantis said.</p>

<p>Search-and-rescue teams were prepared to head out as soon as the storm passes, working through the night if needed, DeSantis said.</p>

<p>"It's going to mean pretty much all the rescues are going to be done in the dark, in the middle of the night, but that's fine. They're going to do that," DeSantis said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ud04ha98_hurricane-milton_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A flash flood emergency was in effect for the Tampa Bay area.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-sees-continued-attempts-by-threat-actors-to-use-its-models-for-election-influence-6757697]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Sees Continued Attempts By Threat Actors To Use Its Models For Election Influence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-sees-continued-attempts-by-threat-actors-to-use-its-models-for-election-influence-6757697]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 11:34:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[None of the activities that attempted to influence global elections drew viral engagement or sustainable audiences, OpenAI said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI has seen a number of attempts where its AI models have been used to generate fake content, including long-form articles and social media comments, aimed at influencing elections, the ChatGPT maker said in a report on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Cybercriminals are increasingly using AI tools, including ChatGPT, to aid in their malicious activities such as creating and debugging malware, and generating fake content for websites and social media platforms, the startup said.</p>

<p>So far this year it neutralized more than 20 such attempts, including a set of ChatGPT accounts in August that were used to produce articles on topics that included the U.S. elections, the company said.</p>

<p>It also banned a number of accounts from Rwanda in July that were used to generate comments about the elections in that country for posting on social media site X.</p>

<p>None of the activities that attempted to influence global elections drew viral engagement or sustainable audiences, OpenAI added.</p>

<p>There is increasing worry about the use of AI tools and social media sites to generate and propagate fake content related to elections, especially as the U.S. gears for presidential polls.</p>

<p>According to the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, the U.S. sees a growing threat of Russia, Iran and China attempting to influence the Nov. 5 elections, including by using AI to disseminate fake or divisive information.</p>

<p>OpenAI cemented its position as one of the world's most valuable private companies last week after a $6.6 billion funding round.</p>

<p>ChatGPT has 250 million weekly active users since its launch in November 2022.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hpaeuf2g_openai_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/amazon-unveils-ai-tool-to-help-drivers-find-packages-faster-6757642]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Unveils AI Tool To Help Drivers Find Packages Faster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/amazon-unveils-ai-tool-to-help-drivers-find-packages-faster-6757642]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 11:25:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The tool uses computer-vision technology initially developed in Amazon warehouses to identify products without using barcode scanners]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amazon.com Inc. unveiled a new artificial intelligence tool designed to solve a major pain point in its quick delivery apparatus: drivers rummaging through cluttered vans at each stop searching for packages.</p>

<p>The technology projects a green circle on packages to be delivered at each stop and red Xs on those to be delivered later, Amazon said Wednesday at a Nashville media event focused on its logistics and online shopping initiatives.</p>

<p>Called Vision Assisted Package Retrieval and in development since 2020, the tool will be deployed in 1,000 Amazon vans next year and will shorten the typical delivery route by about 30 minutes, the company said.</p>

<p>The tool uses computer-vision technology initially developed in Amazon warehouses to identify products without using barcode scanners. The technology was adapted for vans' cramped cargo areas and integrated with delivery-route navigation software.</p>

<p>"Delivery drivers will no longer have to spend time organizing packages by stops, reading labels or manually checking key identifiers like a customer's name or address to ensure they have the right packages," Amazon said in a release. "They simply have to look for VAPR's green light, grab and go."</p>

<p>The announcement underscores Amazon's shifting priorities under Chief Executive Officer Andy Jassy, who assumed the role from founder Jeff Bezos in 2021. Bezos wowed the media with grandiose announcements that looked far into the future, such as fleets of autonomous delivery drones - a project still in the testing phase more than a decade after he announced it.</p>

<p>Under Jassy, who steered the company through layoffs and shuttered dozens of moonshot projects, the focus is on near-term efforts to shave costs and make Amazon's low-margin e-commerce business more appealing to Wall Street investors prone to fret about slim profits.</p>

<p>The Seattle-based company relies on a network of small businesses that use 100,000 vans and employ 390,000 drivers to deliver packages. By reducing delivery times, Amazon can limit what it has to pay these delivery service partners, which typically hire drivers paid by the hour.</p>

<p>Amazon announced several other initiatives:</p>

<ul>
	<li>AI Shopping Guides designed to help customers research more than 100 product types, ranging from televisions and dog food to headphones and face moisturizers.</li>
	<li>A next-generation fulfilment center in Shreveport, Louisiana, that uses artificial intelligence and robotics to help workers pick and pack orders.</li>
	<li>An expansion of same-day prescription drug delivery that next year will bring the offering to almost half of the US</li>
</ul><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/iu6t6bs8_amazon-delivery_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The announcement underscores Amazon's shifting priorities under new CEO Andy Jassy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/monster-hurricane-milton-makes-landfall-in-florida-with-damaging-winds-flooding-rains-and-life-threatening-storm-surge-6756596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Monster Hurricane Milton Makes Landfall In Florida]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/monster-hurricane-milton-makes-landfall-in-florida-with-damaging-winds-flooding-rains-and-life-threatening-storm-surge-6756596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 07:50:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton blasted ashore in Florida Wednesday night with furious winds, life-threatening rain and storm surge, as people who endured another hurricane just two weeks ago braced for a long, violent night.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane Milton blasted ashore in Florida Wednesday night with furious winds, life-threatening rain and storm surge, as people who endured another hurricane just two weeks ago braced for a long, violent night.</p>

<p>The "extremely dangerous" Category 3 storm made landfall near Siesta Key, in a densely populated area on the state's western coast, the National Hurricane Center said in an 8:30 pm (0030 GMT Thursday) bulletin.</p>

<p>"So the storm is here. It's time for every one to hunker down," Governor Ron DeSantis told a press conference just before Milton's arrival.</p>

<p>Life-threatening storm surge, extreme winds and flash flooding were happening across the central Florida peninsula, the NHC said.</p>

<p>Tidal surges are expected to inundate western Florida's heavily populated and low-lying Gulf Coast amid fears of widespread chaos and possible fatalities.</p>

<p>Milton is later expected to rip through inland areas to the Atlantic Ocean, with tourist hub Orlando -- home to Walt Disney World -- in its path.</p>

<p>As it hit land Milton was packing sustained winds moving at 120 miles (205 kilometers) per hour, with potential for as much as 13 feet (four meters) of storm surge, the NHC said.</p>

<p>In cities up and down Florida's western coast, the wind howled furiously and torrential rain fell as frightened people took shelter wherever they could.</p>

<p>In the city of Sarasota, near Siesta Key, gusts of wind blew panes of glass from buildings on the waterfront. The streets were deserted. Trees swayed almost horizontal, barely able to withstand the wind. Businesses were shuttered and sandbagged.</p>

<p>On a wooden board fixed against a window of an old red brick building, someone wrote: "Be kind Milton."</p>

<p>Just before landfall DeSantis said it was too late and too dangerous to evacuate anyone so people had to stay put and weather the storm wherever they were.</p>

<p>"Stay inside and stay off the roads. Flood waters and rushing storm surge are very dangerous," the governor said.</p>

<p>The airports in Tampa and Sarasota were closed until further notice.</p>

<p><strong>'The other storm'</strong></p>

<p>Milton hit just two weeks after another major hurricane, Helene, hit Florida and other southeastern states with devastating and deadly effect.</p>

<p>"I am nervous. This is something we just went through with the other storm -- ground saturated, still recovering from that," Randy Prior, who owns a pool business, told AFP.</p>

<p>Prior, 36, says he plans to ride out the storm at home, after recently toughing out Hurricane Helene, which sparked flooding in Florida before wreaking havoc across remote areas further inland such as western North Carolina.</p>

<p>The Weather Channel reported "numerous tornadoes" touching down in central and southern Florida.</p>

<p>With the storm coming immediately after lethal Helene hit the US southeast, presidential candidate Donald Trump has sought political advantage by falsely saying aid is channeled away from residents, many of whom are supporters of his Republican Party, and toward migrants.</p>

<p>At the White House on Wednesday, President Joe Biden slammed the Republican former president and current candidate's "onslaught of lies."</p>

<p>"There's been a reckless, irresponsible and relentless promotion of disinformation and outright lies," Biden said in angry remarks.</p>

<p>Vice President Kamala Harris, who is taking on Trump at the polls, echoed Biden's criticisms in a separate telephone interview with CNN.</p>

<p>"It is dangerous, it is unconscionable, frankly, that anyone who'd consider themselves a leader would mislead desperate people to the point that those desperate people would not receive the aid to which they are entitled," she said.</p>

<p>Across the southeastern United States, emergency workers are still struggling to provide relief after Helene, which killed at least 235 people.</p>

<p>Scientists say global warming has a role in intense storms as warmer ocean surfaces release more water vapor, providing additional energy for storms, which exacerbates their winds.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/denq8t28_hurrican-milton_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The "extremely dangerous" Category 3 storm made landfall near Siesta Key.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>