<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:02:09 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-victim-corey-comperatore-was-a-firefighter-father-of-2-died-shiedling-his-family-6106855]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Victim Was A Firefighter, Died Shiedling His Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-victim-corey-comperatore-was-a-firefighter-father-of-2-died-shiedling-his-family-6106855]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:02:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The spectator who died in the shooting that targeted Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania rally has been identified as Corey Comperatore, a 50-year-old firefighter and father of two.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The spectator who died in the shooting that targeted Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania rally has been identified as Corey Comperatore, a 50-year-old firefighter and father of two.</p>

<p>"We lost a fellow Pennsylvanian last night, Corey Comperatore," the state's governor, Josh Shapiro, told reporters. "I just spoke to his wife and his two daughters."</p>

<p>He said the victim was a churchgoing firefighter and an enthusiastic Trump supporter who "loved his community and most especially...his family."</p>

<p>Josh Shapiro called Saturday's shooting, in which two other spectators were wounded, "shocking, for this Commonwealth (state) and the country."</p>

<p>The other victims have yet to be identified, though NPR news affiliate WESA quoted hospital officials in Pittsburgh as saying both were local men and both remained in critical condition.</p>

<p>The shooter, identified as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks of nearby Bethel Park, was killed by a Secret Service sniper.</p>

<p>One of Corey Comperatore's daughters, Allyson, described her father in a Facebook post as "the best dad a girl could ever ask for," someone always ready to help and quick to "make friends with anyone."</p>

<p>"The media will not tell you that he died a real-life super hero," she said.</p>

<p>"He threw my mom and I to the ground... (and) shielded my body from the bullet that came at us."</p>

<p>Josh Shapiro also described Corey Comperatore as "a hero" who died protecting his family. He said state flags would be flown at half-staff to honor the victim.</p>

<p>"Corey was an avid supporter of the former president," Josh Shapiro added, "and was so excited to be there last night."</p>

<p>A GoFundMe page created to raise money for the Comperatore family had received donations of nearly $330,000 as of 3:00 pm.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b5q03l7g_corey-comperatore_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pennsylvanian Governor described Corey Comperatore as "a hero" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-school-sheltering-displaced-gazans-6106800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[15 Killed In Israeli Strike On School Sheltering Displaced Gazans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-school-sheltering-displaced-gazans-6106800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 03:49:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The civil defence agency in Hamas-run Gaza said Sunday that 15 people were killed in a strike on a school sheltering war displaced where the Israeli military said it had targeted "terrorists".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The civil defence agency in Hamas-run Gaza said Sunday that 15 people were killed in a strike on a school sheltering war displaced where the Israeli military said it had targeted "terrorists".</p>

<p>The strike on the UN-run Abu Araban site in central Gaza's Nuseirat camp was the fifth on a school-turned-shelter in eight days.</p>

<p>The Abu Araban school was housing "thousands of displaced people," civil defence agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP, adding that most of the dead were women and children.</p>

<p>Schools in Nuseirat were the target for two of the earlier school strikes as Israel keeps up its offensive against Hamas Palestinian militants who triggered the war with their October 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its air force "struck a number of terrorists who were operating in the area of UNRWA's Abu Araban school building in Nuseirat".</p>

<p>It said the building had "served as a hideout" and base for "attacks" on Israeli troops.</p>

<p>AFPTV images showed the three-storey complex standing, with clothes and bedding airing out over its railings. A wall bearing the UN logo had been blown out, and rooms inside were damaged.</p>

<p>On July 6, Israeli aircraft hit Al-Jawni school, also run by the United Nations relief agency for Palestinian refugees (UNRWA), in Nuseirat. UNRWA said about 2,000 people were sheltering there at the time.</p>

<p>The following day, four people died in a strike on the church-run Holy Family school in Gaza City, in the territory's north, according to the Civil Defence agency.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israel hit another Nuseirat school, again saying it was targeting "terrorists".</p>

<p>The next day, a hospital source said at least 29 people died in a strike at the entrance to Al-Awda school in the Khan Yunis area, southern Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel says Hamas uses schools, hospitals and other public infrastructure for military purposes. Hamas denies the accusation.</p>

<p>France and Germany on Wednesday called for an investigation into the school strikes.</p>

<p>After the Al-Jawni strike, UNRWA spokesperson Juliette Touma told AFP that when the war began "we closed the schools and they became shelters."</p>

<p>UNRWA is the main relief agency in Gaza but more than half, or 190, of its facilities have been hit -- "some more than once" -- in the military response to the October 7 Hamas attacks, she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dq0ri2g_gaza-school-strike_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Schools in Nuseirat were the target for two of the earlier school strikes]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-pulling-out-of-gaza-truce-talks-as-israel-keeps-up-strikes-6106799]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Says Pulling Out Of Gaza Truce Talks, As Israel Keeps Up Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-pulling-out-of-gaza-truce-talks-as-israel-keeps-up-strikes-6106799]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 03:43:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Hamas official said Sunday that the Palestinian group was withdrawing from Gaza truce talks, as Israeli bombardments hit a school a day after a deadly strike targeting the militant commander Mohammed Deif.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Hamas official said Sunday that the Palestinian group was withdrawing from Gaza truce talks, as Israeli bombardments hit a school a day after a deadly strike targeting the militant commander Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>Speaking after the strike on southern Gaza's Al-Mawasi, which the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory said killed at least 92 people, a senior official from Iran-backed Hamas cited Israeli "massacres" as a reason for suspending negotiations.</p>

<p>A second Hamas official said Deif, commander of the Islamist group's military wing, was "well and directly overseeing" operations despite the Israeli bombing raid that the military said was an attempt to kill him.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Israeli forces struck a UN-run school in the central Nuseirat refugee camp that the military said "served as a hideout" for militants.</p>

<p>The civil defence agency in Gaza said 15 people were killed in the strike, the fifth attack in just over a week to hit a school used as shelter by displaced Palestinians.</p>

<p>The first Hamas official, quoting the group's Qatar-based political chief Ismail Haniyeh, said Israel's "lack of seriousness, continued policy of procrastination and obstruction, and the ongoing massacres against unarmed civilians" were behind the "decision to halt negotiations".</p>

<p>But according to the official, Haniyeh told international mediators Hamas was "ready to resume negotiations" when Israel's government "demonstrates seriousness in reaching a ceasefire agreement and a prisoner exchange deal".</p>

<p>Talks mediated by Qatar and Egypt, with United States support, have for months tried but failed to bring a halt to the war.</p>

<p>Israeli demonstrators, sometimes in the tens of thousands, have stepped up their actions demanding the government reach a deal to free the captives taken by Hamas militants on October 7.</p>

<p>The military's chief of staff Herzi Halevi said in a video message that "continuous... military pressure" could help create "the conditions for an agreement to return the hostages".</p>

<p><strong>Schools turned shelters</strong></p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack that sparked the war, now in its 10th month, resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza including 42 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel responded with a military offensive that has killed at least 38,584 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to data provided by the Gaza health ministry.</p>

<p>In Nuseirat, an AFP photographer saw part of the bombarded school complex damaged. Crowds of Palestinians, some visibly shaken and in tears, gathered in the courtyard.</p>

<p>At the nearby Al-Awda hospital, the wounds of several children were bandaged.</p>

<p>With most of Gaza's 2.4 million people displaced at least once during the war, many have sought refuge in school buildings.</p>

<p>Four previous strikes on schools turned shelters since July 6 killed a total of at least 49 people, according to officials, medics and rescuers.</p>

<p>Israel says Hamas uses schools, hospitals and other public infrastructure for military purposes. Hamas denies the accusation.</p>

<p>Separately on Sunday, rescuers said at least 10 people were killed in strikes on different parts of Gaza City, where the Israeli military said its operations were ongoing in the territory's north.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist at the site of a strike in the city's Tal al-Hawa neighbourhood saw buildings reduced to rubble. The civil defence agency said rescuers had extracted the bodies of "two martyrs".</p>

<p>At the site of Saturday's strike in Al-Mawasi, on the Mediterranean coast, an AFP photographer saw the charred remains of tents as Palestinians searched through the wreckage for salvageable items.</p>

<p><strong>'Right to live'</strong></p>

<p>Al-Mawasi, near the cities of Khan Yunis and Rafah, had in May been declared a safe humanitarian zone by the Israeli military, which told civilians to evacuate to it. However, there have been multiple deadly incidents there blamed on Israeli strikes.</p>

<p>Israel's military on Sunday said one of Deif's associates, Rafa Salama, had been killed by the strike a day earlier "in the area of Khan Yunis".</p>

<p>Israel accused both Salama, commander of Hamas's Khan Yunis brigade, and Deif of helping to "mastermind" the October 7 attack.</p>

<p>Halevi, Israel's army chief, said that Deif was at the site targeted along with "other terrorists and accomplices", but that it was "too early to conclude the results of the strike".</p>

<p>"Very few" civilians "were harmed", he added.</p>

<p>Philippe Lazzarini, head of the UN agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA, said on social media that the Al-Mawasi "attack and the mass casualties are a stark reminder that no one is safe in Gaza, wherever they are".</p>

<p>"The people of Gaza are children, women and men who... have the right to live and hope for a better future."</p>

<p>The deaths drew condemnation from governments across the region.</p>

<p>Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan said Israel did not intend to end the war and committed "new massacres each time there is a positive atmosphere" towards a truce.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jrn4gko_gaza_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The civil defence agency in Gaza said 15 people were killed in a fresh strike]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-was-quiet-lonely-and-bullied-in-school-report-6106636]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooter Was "Quiet", "Lonely" And "Bullied" In School: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-was-quiet-lonely-and-bullied-in-school-report-6106636]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 02:45:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 20-year-old Pennsylvania man, Thomas Matthew Crooks, has been identified as the suspected shooter who tried to assassinate former president Donald Trump at a campaign rally this weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 20-year-old Pennsylvania man, Thomas Matthew Crooks, has been identified as the suspected shooter who tried to assassinate former president Donald Trump at a campaign rally this weekend.</p>

<p>Secret Service snipers killed Crooks on Saturday after he fired multiple shots at the rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, from a nearby rooftop.</p>

<p>As authorities seek to understand his motivations, here is what we know of the alleged gunman:</p>

<p><strong>'Quiet'</strong></p>

<p>Crooks' former schoolmates described him as a "quiet" student who often came across as "lonely," ABC News reported.</p>

<p>But although he seemed "socially reserved," a former schoolmate did not recall hearing him discuss politics or Trump, according to ABC.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was hit in the ear at the rally. A bystander was killed and two spectators critically injured in the worst act of US political violence in decades.</p>

<p>Jason Kohler, who said he attended the same high school as Crooks, said the alleged shooter had often been bullied.</p>

<p>"He was quiet but he was just bullied. He was bullied so much," Kohler told reporters.</p>

<p>He said Crooks had been made fun of for the way he dressed, noting that he would sometimes wear hunting outfits.</p>

<p><strong>No military ties</strong></p>

<p>Following the shooting, investigators found a "suspicious device" in Crooks' car, which was inspected by bomb technicians and is being analysed.</p>

<p>They noted that explosive devices have been collected as evidence.</p>

<p>Authorities are now in the process of searching Crooks' phone.</p>

<p>Kevin Rojek, special agent in charge of the FBI's Pittsburgh field office, told reporters Sunday that the gun used in the shooting was an AR-style semiautomatic rifle which was purchased legally.</p>

<p>Investigators believe the weapon used was purchased by Crooks' father, but it was unclear how he accessed the weapon.</p>

<p>Rojek added that there were no indications so far of any mental health issues.</p>

<p>Crooks also did not have military affiliations, according to Pentagon spokesman Major General Pat Ryder.</p>

<p>The FBI told reporters that they are investigating the incident as an assassination attempt and also potential domestic terrorism act.</p>

<p><strong>Acted alone</strong></p>

<p>The shooter was believed to be working alone, according to the FBI, and officials said they have not identified an ideology associated with him.</p>

<p>His political leanings were not instantly clear.</p>

<p>News reports indicated he was a registered Republican, but also noted that he previously gave money to a Democratic-aligned progressive political action committee.</p>

<p>While social media platform Discord said it had identified an account that appeared linked to the suspect, this was "rarely utilized."</p>

<p>A spokesperson added that "we have found no evidence that it was used to plan this incident, promote violence, or discuss his political views."</p>

<p>The suspect's father Matthew Crooks earlier told CNN that he was trying to establish "what the hell is going on" before speaking about his son.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/os20isd8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An ex schoolmate said Crooks had been made fun of for the way he dressed (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-call-for-unity-after-assassination-attempt-stuns-us-6106463]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Trump Call For Unity After Assassination Attempt Stuns US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-call-for-unity-after-assassination-attempt-stuns-us-6106463]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 01:50:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rivals Joe Biden and Donald Trump urged Americans to show unity Sunday after an assassination attempt on the Republican put the nation on edge in the run-up to the presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rivals Joe Biden and Donald Trump urged Americans to show unity Sunday after an assassination attempt on the Republican that the FBI said was carried out by a shooter with a legally-bought semi-automatic rifle.</p>

<p>The attack put the divided nation on edge in the run-up to the presidential election and was being investigated as a potential act of domestic terrorism, as well as a massive security failure.</p>

<p>President Biden said he would address the nation from the Oval Office later in the day, a step only taken at times of grave crisis, after his 78-year-old predecessor was hit in the ear at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"Unity is the most elusive goal of all, but nothing is more important than that right now," Biden said in brief remarks from the White House, flanked by Vice President Kamala Harris and his homeland security chief.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Democrat said he had a "short but good conversation" on Saturday with Trump, his political nemesis whom he regularly brands as a threat to democracy.</p>

<p>Biden said the motives of the shooter, 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks, remained unknown and urged people not to make assumptions about his "afflations."</p>

<p>A day after being rushed from the stage by Secret Service agents with blood streaked across his face, Trump made a similar call.</p>

<p>"In this moment, it is more important than ever that we stand United," Trump said in a statement on his Truth Social network, adding that Americans should not allow "Evil to win."</p>

<p>The tycoon added that it was "God alone who prevented the unthinkable from happening" and that he would "FEAR NOT."</p>

<p>Trump's wife Melania called the shooter a "monster."</p>

<p><strong>Suspected explosives</strong></p>

<p>Secret Service snipers killed Crooks after he fired multiple shots from a nearby rooftop. A bystander was killed and two spectators critically injured in one of the worst acts of US political violence in decades.</p>

<p>The FBI said that it believed that Crooks acted alone and had no known ideology.</p>

<p>"We located the weapon at the scene, immediately adjacent to the shooter," Kevin Rojek, special agent in charge of the FBI's Pittsburgh field office, told reporters.</p>

<p>"We searched the shooter's car, and we're in the process of searching his phone. During the search of the vehicle, we located a suspicious device, which was inspected by bomb technicians."</p>

<p>Biden said he had ordered a full review of security at the rally, as well as at this week's Republican National Convention in Milwaukee where Trump will be crowned the party's presidential nominee.</p>

<p>Biden praised the victim, named as Corey Comperatore, saying he "was protecting his family from the bullets."</p>

<p>Questions are swirling about shooter Crooks, whose body was seen in television images on a low roof of a building, near a weapon that investigators said was an AR-style semi-automatic rifle legally bought by his father.</p>

<p>Crooks' former schoolmates described him as a quiet student who often came across as lonely.</p>

<p>"He was quiet but he was just bullied. He was bullied so much," Jason Kohler, who said he attended the same high school as Crooks, told reporters.</p>

<p>The shocking incident drew immediate criticism of security, particularly about how a presidential candidate could be targeted by a gunman around 150 meters away despite a huge Secret Service detail.</p>

<p>US Secret Service spokesman Anthony Guglielmi rejected "absolutely false" claims that it had refused additional protection for Trump ahead of the rally.</p>

<p>Some phone footage suggested that people had seen the shooter on the roof before he opened fire.</p>

<p><strong>Political fallout</strong></p>

<p>The attempt on Trump's life sent shock waves around the world, but the effects on a tight US presidential race in a deeply divided country are uncertain.</p>

<p>Trump's family has already been promoting images of the president raising a defiant fist to the crowd after the shooting.</p>

<p>His narrow escape has sparked conspiracy theories and finger-pointing by Republicans.</p>

<p>Possible Trump vice presidential pick J.D. Vance claimed Biden's campaign "rhetoric" had "led directly" to the attack.</p>

<p>US politics have become increasingly hostile, with Trump building his image around inflammatory verbal assaults, and many Democrats expressing fury and disgust at Trump's rise.</p>

<p>World leaders expressed outrage over the assassination attempt, with UN chief Antonio Guterres saying he condemned it "unequivocally."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/svuvbrhc_trump-biden-split-reuters_625x300_06_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said he had a "short but good conversation" on Saturday with Trump (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-bullet-flew-by-his-ear-man-predicted-trump-rally-shooting-4-months-ago-6105912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bullet Flew By His Ear": Man Predicted Trump Rally Shooting 4 Months Ago]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-bullet-flew-by-his-ear-man-predicted-trump-rally-shooting-4-months-ago-6105912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 23:12:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt yesterday evening during a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt yesterday evening during a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. Multiple videos shot by bystanders and video journalists showed what happened before, after and the moment when Mr Trump was shot at. Now, a four-month-old video has resurfaced online that predicted the attack on the former US president.</p>

<p>In a video posted on YouTube on March 14, Bradon Biggs spoke about an alleged divine vision he had about the attempt at Trump's life. Biggs has a YouTube channel where he frequently posts videos on "visions and prophetic warnings".</p>

<p>"I saw an attempt on his (Donald Trump) life. This bullet flew by his ear and it came so close to his head that it busted his eardrum, and I saw he fell to his knees during this timeframe and started worshipping the lord," he said.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old had just begun his speech when shots rang out, hitting his right ear and streaking his face with blood. He dropped to his knees behind the podium. When he emerged about a minute later, he mouthed "Fight! Fight! Fight!" pumping his fist in the air.</p>

<p>Many X users are now posting the clip of Biggs in which he also claim that he saw Trump "winning the presidency".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Recorded on 3/14/24 (verified), Pastor Brandon Biggs recounts a prophecy he saw.<br />
<br />
"I saw an attempt on [Trump's] life that this bullet flew by his ear and it came so close to his head that it busted his ear drum. And I saw, he fell to his knees during this timeframe..." <a href="https://t.co/U9iGpNmN7j">pic.twitter.com/U9iGpNmN7j</a></p>
â€” John Greenewald, Jr. (@blackvaultcom) <a href="https://twitter.com/blackvaultcom/status/1812533859210461417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation has identified 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks as the "subject involved" in the attempted assassination.</p>

<p>One rally attendee was killed and two other spectators were injured in the shooting. The suspect was shot dead by a Security Services agent.</p>

<p>The shooting occurred less than four months before the November 5 election, when Trump faces an election rematch with Democratic President Joe Biden. Most opinion polls including those by Reuters/Ipsos show the two locked in a close contest.</p>

<p>It was the first shooting of a US president or major party candidate since the 1981 attempted assassination of Republican President Ronald Reagan.</p>

<p>The incident has raised immediate questions about security failures by the Secret Service, which provides former presidents including Trump with lifetime protection.</p>]]></content:encoded>
   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooting-victim-identified-as-50-year-old-man-6105524]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooting Victim Identified As 50-Year-Old Man]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooting-victim-identified-as-50-year-old-man-6105524]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 22:00:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The person who died in a shooting at former US President Donald Trump's rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday was identified as 50-year-old Corey Comperatore, according to his family's posting on Facebook.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The person who died in a shooting at former US President Donald Trump's rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday was identified as 50-year-old Corey Comperatore, according to his family's posting on Facebook.</p>

<p>"The PA Trump Rally claimed the life of my brother, Corey Comperatore. The hatred for one man took the life of the one man we loved the most," the victim's sister said in the post on Sunday.</p>

<p>Comperatore previously served as the chief of the Buffalo Township Volunteer Fire Department, according to a report by the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/sngms4q8_trump-rally-shooting-victim_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Corey Comperatore had served as the chief of the Buffalo Township Volunteer Fire Departmen]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-ar-15-one-of-americas-deadliest-most-popular-guns-used-in-trump-attack-6105457]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The AR-15: One Of US's Deadliest, Most Popular Guns Used In Trump Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-ar-15-one-of-americas-deadliest-most-popular-guns-used-in-trump-attack-6105457]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:47:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The attempted assassination of former US president Donald Trump with a semi-automatic rifle illustrates once again how easy it is for shooters in the US to get their hands on inexpensive, easy-to-use, military-style weapons.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The attempted assassination of former US president Donald Trump with a semi-automatic rifle illustrates once again how easy it is for shooters in the US to get their hands on inexpensive, easy-to-use, military-style weapons.</p>

<p>The AR-15-style rifle is one of the most popular guns in the US. It has also been a common denominator in some of the country's worst mass shootings.</p>

<p>Here are some key facts about the weapon:</p>

<p><strong>Why Are AR-15s So Lethal?</strong></p>

<p>The AR-15 is a semi-automatic weapon, meaning a user can fire multiple shots in quick succession.</p>

<p>Its cousin, the M-16, has been used by the US military since Vietnam. While some military assault rifles are fully automatic, civilians are prohibited from owning such weapons in most circumstances.</p>

<p>AR-15s fire high-velocity bullets that travel at triple the speed of a handgun round, are accurate over long distances, and cause expansive, devastating wounds to soft tissue and internal organs.</p>

<p>While handguns account for more deaths per year in the United States, AR-15s have frequently been used in high-profile mass shootings.</p>

<p>In May 2022, a former student used an AR-15 to shoot dead nineteen children and two teachers at Robb Elementary School in Uvalde, Texas.</p>

<p>The weapon was also used in October 2017 in Las Vegas, where a gunman massacred 60 people at a music festival.</p>

<p><strong>Cheap And Easy</strong></p>

<p>Buying an AR-15 is easy. Depending on the state of residence, a prospective owner can walk into a gun shop and, after presenting a valid ID, buy a rifle or shotgun provided they can pass a federal background check.</p>

<p>This process looks at a buyer's criminal history or whether they have ever been committed to a mental institution. But even this cursory check can be flouted in the case of private sales.</p>

<p>The National Rifle Association (NRA) touts the rifles for recreational target practice and home defense, but critics say their lethality means they do not belong in civilian hands.</p>

<p>Part of the reason for the popularity of AR-15s in America is that they are widely customizable, with owners able to add scopes, large-capacity magazines and a plethora of other accessories.</p>

<p>The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives does not know how many assault weapons there are in America -- they are prohibited by federal law from keeping a gun registry database.</p>

<p>A Washington Post poll in 2023 estimated that one in 20 American adults own at least one AR-15.</p>

<p><strong>Banned In Several States</strong></p>

<p>Assault weapons were banned in 1994 under president Bill Clinton, but the restriction lapsed in 2004 amid pressure from the powerful NRA.</p>

<p>Federal efforts at reforms to gun laws have been stymied ever since, with critics arguing that they infringe the constitutional right to own a firearm, enshrined in the Second Amendment.</p>

<p>Several states, like California, Illinois, Maryland, New Jersey and Washington DC, have however banned ownership of assault weapons.</p>

<p>California claims its gun safety laws have helped save 19,000 lives in a decade.</p>

<p>In May, President Joe Biden's administration moved to crack down on firearm sales at gun shows and online that evade federal background checks.</p>

<p>But several Republican-led states quickly sued to block the measure.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/ke9n696o_ar15style-rifles-_625x300_23_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[AR-15s fire high-velocity bullets that travel at triple the speed of a handgun round (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shooting-makes-me-stronger-donald-trump-attack-t-shirts-go-on-sale-online-6105374]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Shooting Makes Me Stronger": Donald Trump Attack T-shirts Go On Sale Online]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shooting-makes-me-stronger-donald-trump-attack-t-shirts-go-on-sale-online-6105374]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:32:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The first batch of the t-shirts went on sale on a popular Chinese e-commerce platform Taobao, owned by Alibaba, within two hours of the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination attempt by a gunman at a campaign rally today in Pennsylvania today, a shocking incident that will fuel fears of instability ahead of the 2024 US presidential election. Several politicians, tech leaders and followers of Mr Trump condemned the attack, stressing that political violence is intolerable.</p>

<p>Shortly after the news broke out, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://twitter.com/ThaDietz_/status/1812289140698026385/photo/3">t-shirts</a> featuring a defiant image of Donald Trump with blood visible on his face and fist in the air went viral online. According to a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/article/3270397/trump-rally-shooting-chinese-online-retailers-quick-mark-souvenir-t-shirts"><em>South China Morning Post</em></a>, within two hours after the attack, the first batch of the t-shirts went on sale on a popular Chinese e-commerce platform Taobao, owned by Alibaba.</p>

<p>Li Jinwei, a 25-year-old Taobao seller, got her T-shirts on her online stores before morning in China. Her factory is located in the northern province of Hebei. To produce new goods, she just needs to download an image and hit the print button. A T-shirt takes the factory half a minute on average to finish. "We put the T-shirts on Taobao as soon as we saw the news about the shooting, though we hadn't even printed them, and within three hours we saw more than 2,000 orders from both China and the US," she said.</p>

<p>"For this year's US presidential election, we only made souvenirs of Trump, as he has a higher chance of winning the election, and he is popular among Chinese netizens," she said.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.politico.eu/article/fight-supporters-donald-trump-shooting-rally-campaign-merch-us-election/"><em>Politico</em></a>, the trend was not confined to China. US content creators HodgeTwins promoted on X <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/CaffeinatedUser/status/1812310079305085274">images of T-shirts</a> that said, "Fight! Fight! Fight!" and said, "100% of profits from this shirt go to Trump's campaign." Another picture featured a man with a shirt that read, "Shooting Makes Me Stronger" while a third said, "I Will Never Stop."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Donald Trump, in his first statement after being shot at the rally, said, "I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear. I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin." He added, "Much bleeding took place, so I realized then what was happening." Earlier in the statement, he stated, "I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/emdr11ag_tshirt_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The t-shirts were also seen on US e-commerce platforms.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shooter-who-fired-at-trump-had-explosives-in-his-car-report-6105229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Shooter Who Fired At Trump Had Explosives In His Car: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shooter-who-fired-at-trump-had-explosives-in-his-car-report-6105229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:06:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman who opened fire at a Donald Trump rally had explosives in his car, US media reported Sunday, as investigators probed the attempted assassination of the Republican presidential candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman who opened fire at a Donald Trump rally had explosives in his car, US media reported Sunday, as investigators probed the attempted assassination of the Republican presidential candidate.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal and CNN said that explosive materials were found in a car belonging to shooter Thomas Matthew Crooks, which was reportedly parked near the campaign event venue in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gjebfnog_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The car was reportedly parked near the campaign event venue in Butler, Pennsylvania.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooter-a-monster-melania-trump-first-reaction-6104987]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooter A "Monster": Melania Trump's First Reaction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooter-a-monster-melania-trump-first-reaction-6104987]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 20:19:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former first lady Melania Trump said Sunday that a gunman who opened fire at a Donald Trump rally was a "monster," as she condemned the assassination attempt in which the Republican presidential candidate was injured.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former first lady Melania Trump said Sunday that a gunman who opened fire at a Donald Trump rally was a "monster," as she condemned the assassination attempt in which the Republican presidential candidate was injured.</p>

<p>"A monster who recognized my husband as an inhuman political machine attempted to ring out Donald's passion -- his laughter, ingenuity, love of music, and inspiration," Melania Trump said in a statement shared on X.</p>

<p>"When I watched that violent bullet strike my husband, Donald, I realized my life, and Barron's life, were on the brink of devastating change," she said, referencing the couple's 18-year-old son.</p>

<p>"I am grateful to the brave secret service agents and law enforcement officials who risked their own lives to protect my husband," Melania Trump said.</p>

<p>Donald Trump said he was hit in the ear when a shooter targeted an election campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania on Saturday.</p>

<p>The shooter and a bystander were killed, while two spectators were critically injured.</p>

<p>Melania Trump said she offered her "sincerest sympathy" to the families of the victims, saying: "Your need to summon your inner strength for such a terrible reason saddens me."</p>

<p>Melania, 54, has barely engaged with her husband's White House campaign, failing to appear at a single Trump rally and rarely joins him in public.</p>

<p>She has also remained largely absent during the former president's multiple court appearances in recent months to fight legal cases against him and as he cranks up his 2024 election campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/ugsvut5g_melania-trump_625x300_17_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Melania Trump posted her statement on X]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beverly-hills-90210-star-shannen-doherty-dies-at-53-after-cancer-battle-report-6104922]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Beverly Hills, 90210' Star Shannen Doherty Dies After Cancer Battle: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beverly-hills-90210-star-shannen-doherty-dies-at-53-after-cancer-battle-report-6104922]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 20:07:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American actor Shannen Doherty, best known for her role as high school student Brenda Walsh on the hit 1990s television drama "Beverly Hills, 90210," has died after years of living with cancer, People magazine reported on Sunday. She was 53.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American actor Shannen Doherty, best known for her role as high school student Brenda Walsh on the hit 1990s television drama "Beverly Hills, 90210," has died after years of living with cancer, People magazine reported on Sunday. She was 53.</p>

<p>"It is with a heavy heart that I confirm the passing of actress Shannen Doherty. On Saturday, July 13, she lost her battle with cancer after many years of fighting the disease," the magazine cited Doherty's publicist Leslie Sloane as saying.</p>

<p>Doherty had been public about her battle with breast cancer, disclosing in 2015 that she was undergoing treatment for the disease. In 2023, she had a brain tumor removed and revealed that the cancer had spread to her bones.</p>

<p>The actress, who had previously starred in the movie "Heathers," gained widespread popularity on "90210" for her portrayal of Brenda, an honor roll student from Minnesota who struggled to fit in with her classmates in the wealthy zip code.</p>

<p>Her character on the show became entwined in a love triangle with Dylan McKay (Luke Perry) and Kelly Taylor (Jennie Garth). In real life, Doherty clashed with Garth and other castmates and left "90210" during its fourth season in 1994. The show continued through 2000 without her.</p>

<p>In 1998, "90210" producer Aaron Spelling cast Doherty in the supernatural series "Charmed" as Prue Halliwell, the oldest of three sisters with magical abilities. The show was a hit, but also subject to reports of behind-the-scenes turmoil.</p>

<p>People magazine called Doherty "the iconic 'bad girl' of the nineties," citing her reputation for partying, turning up late on sets, and feuding with actors - and her bosses.</p>

<p>In 2023, on a podcast called "Let's Be Clear with Shannen Doherty," the actor said she took "full responsibility for her actions" and acknowledged her behavior "would get a little carried away" when she was frequenting nightclubs in her early 20s.</p>

<p>She also said she spoke up more than other women working in television at the time, telling Spelling and others when she thought a script needed improvement.</p>

<p>"I was raised to have an opinion, and that my opinion should be valued, so I just kept on pressing up against that machine, up against men who didn't really want to hear my opinion," she said on the podcast.</p>

<p>Later, "I learned the simple art of diplomacy. I learned that there might be a nicer way to say some things," she said.</p>

<p>The actor reprised the role of Brenda for "90210" reboots in 2008 and 2019 and said she and Garth had reconciled after the two became adults and left their teenage conflicts behind.</p>

<p>Doherty was born in Memphis, Tennessee, on April 12, 1971, and began acting as a child. At age 11, she played Jenny Wilder in the final season of TV classic "Little House on the Prairie."</p>

<p>In 1988, Doherty was cast in the dark comedy film "Heathers," which went on to become a cult classic.</p>

<p>Doherty was married three times, most recently to photographer Kurt Iswarienko. She filed for divorce from him in 2023.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ta1ift9_shannen-doherty-afp_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shannen Doherty was born in Memphis, Tennessee, on April 12, 1971 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-attends-wimbledon-finals-with-daughter-charlotte-amid-cancer-battle-6104854]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton At Wimbledon Finals, Presents Trophy To Winner Alcaraz]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-attends-wimbledon-finals-with-daughter-charlotte-amid-cancer-battle-6104854]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 19:52:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Catherine, Princess of Wales, attended the Wimbledon Men's final in London on Sunday as she continues her cancer recovery, waving to the cheering Centre Court crowd as she took her seat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Catherine, Princess of Wales, attended the Wimbledon Men's final in London on Sunday as she continues her cancer recovery, receiving cheers as she walked onto the court to present the trophy to winner Carlos Alcaraz.</p>

<p>The 42-year-old, wearing a purple dress, was accompanied by her nine-year-old daughter Charlotte as she talked to players before the match.</p>

<p>She was then cheered by onlookers as she made her way to the world-famous Centre Court.</p>

<p>The crowd took to its feet as the princess entered the arena, applauding for around 30 seconds. Catherine waved as she took her seat next to her sister Pippa in the royal box, close to actors Tom Cruise, Zendaya, and Hugh Jackman.</p>

<p>At the end of the match, she walked onto the grass to more cheers, offering consolatory words and a silver plate to runner-up Novak Djokovic and the winner's trophy to Alcaraz.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mqgrfu5_kate-middleton-wimbledon-finals_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>She had earlier sent a social media message to Scottish tennis legend Andy Murray, writing: "An incredible #Wimbledon career comes to an end. You should be so very proud @andy_murray. On behalf of all of us, thank you! C."</p>

<p>Catherine tentatively returned to UK public life last month for the first time since her diagnosis, attending a military parade in London to officially mark King Charles III's birthday.</p>

<p>It came nearly three months after Kate revealed she was receiving chemotherapy treatment. She had not been seen at a public engagement since a Christmas Day service last year.</p>

<p>In a statement at the time, she said she was "making good progress" with her treatment, which is set to last for several more months, but was "not out of the woods yet".</p>

<p>The cancer announcement came just weeks after it was disclosed that British head of state Charles had also been diagnosed with the condition.</p>

<p>Neither has revealed what type of cancer they have.</p>

<p>Charles, 75, was given the green light to resume public duties in April after doctors said they were "very encouraged" by his progress.</p>

<p>He has since attended commemoration events in northern France for the 80th anniversary of the D-Day landings during World War II.</p>

<p>Royal officials are keen to manage expectations about Kate's gradual return to the public eye and have maintained that her appearances will depend on her treatment and recovery.</p>

<p>Kate said in her statement in June that she had "good days and bad days" and was "taking each day as it comes".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hu4oph4g_kate-middleton-wimbledon-finals-afp_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kate Middleton in a purple dress attends Wimbledon finals with her her 9-year-old daughter Charlotte]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-year-old-boy-in-us-dies-after-being-left-in-hot-car-for-7-hours-6104704]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5-Year-Old Boy In US Dies After Being Left In Hot Car For 7 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-year-old-boy-in-us-dies-after-being-left-in-hot-car-for-7-hours-6104704]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 19:24:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The woman, who reportedly cares for five more children, was detained and charged with child abuse by negligence, which resulted in death.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A five-year-old boy in the United States died on Wednesday after his foster mother left him in a hot car for seven hours in extreme heat, as per the police officials. The boy was trapped in 89-degree Fahrenheit (31-degree Celsius) heat, making it the 10th hot car incident in the country, according to a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/13/us-news/5-year-old-boy-dies-after-foster-mom-leaves-him-in-hot-car-for-7-hours-police/"><em>New York Post</em></a>.</p>

<p>Juanita Pinon, aged 40, is accused of abandoning her foster son Dionicio Perez inside a burning SUV in a parking lot outside the beauty salon where she is employed in Omaha, Nebraska, resulting in a tragic incident. Ms Pinon, who has a criminal history that dates back to 2016, according to the prosecution, parked her car and then left for work. However, it remains unclear whether Perez's death was a result of an accident or deliberate action.</p>

<p>Dionicio was declared dead at a nearby hospital when his body temperature rose to 105 degrees. The woman, who reportedly cares for five more children, was detained and charged with child abuse by negligence, which resulted in death. Notably, she could spend up to 20 years in jail if found guilty.</p>

<p>The local NBC affiliate reported that her bond was set at $2 million. Pinon had already been convicted of theft by deception in 2016 after defrauding non-English speaking renters out of $12,000. According to the report, the state government officials told the boy's biological father, Pablo Lopez, and stepmother, Jenny, that their son was in capable hands despite their pursuit of custody.</p>

<p>The five-year-old's twin sister, who turned five in June, is also under Lopez's custody, according to a GoFundMe page set up to raise money for a lawyer and to get "his sister safely home." "The twins were placed in foster care, despite their dad and step mom's efforts to bring the twins home. Their financial situation greatly limited them. The person who was supposed to care for him in foster care, had a criminal history," the GoFundMe page said.</p>

<p>"Dionicio's young life was cut short is the most horrendous way. The world lost such a bright, beautiful, young life far too soon," it added.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/brkgjg7g_gofundme_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boy was trapped in 89-degree Fahrenheit heat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/it-was-god-alone-who-prevented-the-unthinkable-trump-on-assassination-attempt-6104182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["It Was God Alone Who Prevented...": Trump On Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/it-was-god-alone-who-prevented-the-unthinkable-trump-on-assassination-attempt-6104182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 17:50:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Sunday it was divine intervention that helped him survive an assassination attempt during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, and called on Americans to unite.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said Sunday it was divine intervention that helped him survive an assassination attempt during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, and called on Americans to unite.</p>

<p>"It was God alone who prevented the unthinkable from happening," the former US president and White House hopeful said on social media, urging fellow Americans to unite in "not allowing Evil to Win."</p>

<p>Trump was hit in the ear in an assassination attempt by a gunman at a campaign rally Saturday, in a chaotic and shocking incident set to supercharge political tensions ahead of the US presidential election.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old former president was rushed off stage with blood streaked across his face after the shooting in Butler, Pennsylvania, while the shooter and a bystander were killed and two spectators were critically injured.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, who is set to face Trump in November's deeply polarized presidential election, said there was "no place in America for this kind of violence."</p>

<p>"In this moment, it is more important than ever that we stand United, and show our True Character as Americans, remaining Strong and Determined, and not allowing Evil to Win," Trump wrote on his Truth Social platform Sunday morning, confirming that he would attend the Republican National Convention, which begins on Monday in Milwaukee, Wisconsin.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/hnhhqieg_donald-trump-afp_625x300_31_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt in Pennsylvania (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-accuses-biden-administration-of-creating-atmosphere-for-attack-on-trump-6104133]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Accuses Biden Government Of Creating Atmosphere For Attack On Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-accuses-biden-administration-of-creating-atmosphere-for-attack-on-trump-6104133]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 17:43:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin said on Sunday it did not believe the US administration was responsible for Saturday's assassination attempt on US presidential candidate Donald Trump, but that it had created an atmosphere that provoked the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin said on Sunday it did not believe the US administration was responsible for Saturday's assassination attempt on US presidential candidate Donald Trump, but that it had created an atmosphere that provoked the attack.</p>

<p>Trump was shot in the ear during a rally in Pennsylvania, in an attack now being investigated as an assassination attempt. The attacker was shot dead and law enforcement officials said they had not yet identified a motive.</p>

<p>"We do not believe that the attempt to eliminate and assassinate Trump was organised by the current authorities," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told reporters.</p>

<p>"But the atmosphere around candidate Trump ... provoked what America is confronting today."</p>

<p>U.S. President Joe Biden condemned the attack, saying there was no place for that kind of violence in America. Peskov said Russia condemned any violence in the course of the political struggle.</p>

<p>His comments echoed those of some of Trump's Republican allies, who immediately pinned the blame on Biden.</p>

<p>"After numerous attempts to remove candidate Trump from the political arena - using first legal tools, the courts, prosecutors, attempts to politically discredit and compromise the candidate - it was obvious to all outside observers that his life was in danger," Peskov said.</p>

<p>He added that there were no plans for Putin to call Trump in light of the incident.</p>

<p>World leaders, including Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy, rapidly condemned Saturday's attack, expressing shock, denouncing political violence, and wishing Trump a quick recovery.</p>

<p>Russia's foreign ministry used the shooting to urge Washington to stop funding Ukraine's military and concentrate on improving domestic law enforcement instead.</p>

<p>Foreign ministry spokeswoman Maria Zakharova, writing on Telegram, responded to remarks made by independent presidential candidate Robert Kennedy Jr following the shooting.</p>

<p>"Dear Bobby and all those who vote in the United States to supply Zelenskiy with arms," Zakharova said.</p>

<p>"Wouldn't it be better for this money to finance the American police and other services that are supposed to ensure law and order within the United States?"</p>

<p>Moscow's invasion of Ukraine in 2022 has brought Russia's ties with the West to their lowest ebb since the height of the Cold War.</p>

<p>Asked whether the Trump attack could affect the legitimacy of the United States' upcoming election, Peskov said: "It is not for us to judge. We have not the slightest desire to interfere. This is a U.S. matter."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/lslqh9j8_-kremlin-spokesman-dmitry-peskov-650_625x300_21_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dmitry Peskov said there were no plans for Putin to call Trump in light of the incident (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/k-p-sharma-oli-becomes-nepals-prime-minister-for-3rd-time-6104084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[K P Sharma Oli Becomes Nepal's Prime Minister For 3rd Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/k-p-sharma-oli-becomes-nepals-prime-minister-for-3rd-time-6104084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 17:31:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[K P Sharma Oli was appointed Nepal's Prime Minister for the third time on Sunday to lead the new coalition government that faces the daunting challenge of providing political stability in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>K P Sharma Oli was appointed Nepal's Prime Minister for the third time on Sunday to lead the new coalition government that faces the daunting challenge of providing political stability in the country.</p>

<p>K P Sharma Oli, 72, succeeds Pushpa Kamal Dahal Prachanda who lost the vote of confidence in the House of Representatives on Friday, leading to the formation of the new government process as per Article 76 (2) of the Constitution.</p>

<p>President Ram Chandra Paudel appointed K P Sharma Oli as the new Prime Minister of the Communist Party of Nepal-Unified Marxist Leninist (CPN-UML)-Nepali Congress (NC) coalition.</p>

<p>K P Sharma Oli along with the new Cabinet will be sworn in on Monday.</p>

<p>Late on Friday night, K P Sharma Oli staked his claim to become the next Prime Minister with the backing of NC president Sher Bahadur Deuba and submitted the signatures of 165 House of Representatives (HoR) members -- 77 from his party and 88 from the NC.</p>

<p>K P Sharma Oli served as Nepal's Prime Minister from October 11, 2015, to August 3, 2016 and then, from February 5, 2018, to July 13, 2021.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-01/7sf7a9do_kp-sharma-oli-650_625x300_29_January_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[K P Sharma Oli served as Nepal's Prime Minister from October 11, 2015, to August 3, 2016 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-camera-alleged-trump-shooter-lays-on-stomach-with-rifle-on-roof-6104045]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Camera, Alleged Trump Shooter Lays On Stomach With Rifle On Roof]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-camera-alleged-trump-shooter-lays-on-stomach-with-rifle-on-roof-6104045]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 17:26:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A gunman lays on his stomach on a rooftop with a rifle in hand, then screams ring out, a video published by US outlet TMZ on Saturday shows.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A gunman lays on his stomach on a rooftop with a rifle in hand, then screams ring out, a video published by US outlet TMZ on Saturday shows.</p>

<p>US presidential candidate Donald Trump was shot in the ear in an assassination attempt by a gunman at a campaign rally Saturday in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?BREAKING: CLEAREST VIDEO OF THOMAS MATTHEW CROOKS SHOOTING AT PRESIDENT TRUMPâ€¼ï¸<br />
<br />
A newly obtained video from TMZ shows the shooter, identified as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks, firing at former President Donald Trump before being shot. In the background, a woman is heardâ€¦ <a href="https://t.co/UxQTwPOMIU">pic.twitter.com/UxQTwPOMIU</a></p>
â€” Only Mob King ?? (@OnlyMobKing) <a href="https://twitter.com/OnlyMobKing/status/1812342969866850759?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The FBI identified the gunman, who was shot dead by the US Secret Service, as Thomas Matthew Crooks, a 20-year-old from the US state's Bethel Park, according to US media.</p>

<p>The video published by TMZ shows the alleged shooter laying on his belly on a rooftop and aiming a rifle.</p>

<p>"The guy has longer brown hair, and he seems to be wearing a grey shirt/khaki pants -- and as you can see, he's carefully trying to pinpoint a target from afar before pulling the trigger," TMZ reported.</p>

<p>The man is not shown firing in the published footage. But a quick succession of gunshots is heard followed by screams from people off-camera.</p>

<p>"He's turning this way, be careful guys," a man is heard saying.</p>

<p>"Somebody got shot," another voice says. "He's right there, laying down."</p>

<p>"Dude, that's exactly why we need... Trump here," another man is heard saying.</p>

<p>"Secret Service don't (mess) around," another man says.</p>

<p>A second video published by TMZ shows shaky footage of the same rooftop and a blurred body.</p>

<p>"You can see the guy there," a person off-camera says. "I think they hit him because the guy, he looks dead."</p>

<p>Another video posted by a TikTok user shows Trump touching his right ear just after multiple bangs are heard.</p>

<p>In the same frame, a security force sniper, positioned on a roof behind the Republican presidential candidate, is seen taking aim with a rifle mounted on a stand.</p>

<p>AFP did not independently verify the videos, and it is unclear whether the sniper fired the weapon.</p>

<p>Trump then crouches down behind the lectern as Secret Service agents move in around him. Screams are heard in the crowd.</p>

<p>He is later escorted off stage by agents.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/smgpnocg_donald-trump-afp_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was shot in the ear in an assassination attempt (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-how-a-head-tilt-helped-trump-dodge-the-bullet-during-campaign-rally-6103932]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: How A Head Tilt Helped Trump Dodge The Bullet During Campaign Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-how-a-head-tilt-helped-trump-dodge-the-bullet-during-campaign-rally-6103932]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 17:09:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump dodged a bullet, literally. The 78-year-old had just started his speech during a Saturday campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania when the shots rang out and one of the bullets grazed his ear.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump dodged a bullet, literally. The 78-year-old had just started his speech during a Saturday campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania when the shots rang out and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-moment-donald-trump-was-attacked-at-pennsylvania-rally-6100971">one of the bullets grazed his ear.</a></p>

<p>Several video clips showed how Trump was swarmed and covered up by his Secret Service agents moments after the shooting. But now, a slow-motion video establishes how a simple head tilt saved Trump from the assassination attempt. It shows Trump tilting his head just seconds before the shot was fired.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Slow-motion footage shows Trump moving just in time as a bullet clips his ear. <a href="https://t.co/zNHPoRazzS">pic.twitter.com/zNHPoRazzS</a></p>
â€” David Gokhshtein (@davidgokhshtein) <a href="https://twitter.com/davidgokhshtein/status/1812337903692919201?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Another video showed the moments behind the stage just before and after the shooting. Two agents standing behind the stage were seen rushing to the former president's rescue.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Another new video POV from behind the stage moments BEFORE &amp; after shots rang out at the Trump rally. <a href="https://t.co/eO8njBARhH">pic.twitter.com/eO8njBARhH</a></p>
â€” Moshe Schwartz (@YWNReporter) <a href="https://twitter.com/YWNReporter/status/1812367709251772744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>He grabbed his right ear and brought his hand down to look at it before dropping to his knees behind the podium. He emerged about a minute later, his face streaked with blood. Fight! Fight! Fight!" he said, pumping his fist in the air.</p>

<p>One person who attended the rally was killed and two other spectators were critically wounded, the Secret Service said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The attack will likely reshape this year's US presidential race while raising sharp questions about the security provided to the Republican candidate.</p>

<p>Trump left the Butler area under Secret Service protection and later arrived at his golf club in Bedminster, New Jersey.</p>

<p>He was "doing well" and appeared to have suffered no major injury besides a wound on his upper right ear, the Trump campaign said.</p>

<p>20-year-old <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-identifies-shooter-in-donald-trump-assassination-attempt-as-20-year-old-thomas-matthew-crooks-news-agency-reuters-6102245#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a> has been identified by the FBI as the "subject involved" in what it termed an attempted assassination. He was a registered Republican, according to state voter records. He was shot dead by Secret Service agents after he opened fire from the roof of a building about 140 metres from the stage where Trump was speaking. An AR-15-style semiautomatic rifle was recovered near his body.</p>

<p>"I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear. "Much bleeding took place," Trump said later on his Truth Social platform following the shooting in Butler, Pennsylvania, about 30 miles (50 km) north of Pittsburgh.</p>

<p>The attack was the first shooting of a US president or major party candidate since the 1981 attempted assassination of Republican President Ronald Reagan.</p>

<p>The shooting occurred less than four months before the November 5 election, when Trump faces an election rematch with Democratic President Joe Biden. Most opinion polls including those by Reuters/Ipsos show the two locked in a close contest.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/os20isd8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video shows Trump tilting his head just seconds before the shot was fired.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-dead-in-birthday-party-shooting-in-france-6103923]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Dead In Birthday Party Shooting In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-dead-in-birthday-party-shooting-in-france-6103923]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 17:04:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four people, including the shooter, died late Saturday when a man opened fire on a birthday party in a village in France, authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four people, including the shooter, died late Saturday when a man opened fire on a birthday party in a village in France, authorities said.</p>

<p>The man approached a neighbouring house where a 20-year-old was celebrating his birthday with his family in Espinasse-Vozelle, a central French village of around 1,000 inhabitants about 60 kilometres (37 miles) north of Clermont-Ferrand.</p>

<p>He fired shots at the party guests, killing three of them, and then himself, the local prefecture said.</p>

<p>The young man celebrating his birthday and his father were both killed.</p>

<p>Police were still piecing together the "how and the why" of the attack, authorities said. The man appears to have shot at passing motorists before the deadly assault.</p>

<p>Jerome Piques, a local prosecutor, told AFP that the man, who was not among the party guests, approached the neighbouring house via a path linking both properties at around 9:30 pm (1930 GMT) before firing his gun loaded with lead bullets.</p>

<p>Four people were in hospital after being wounded in the shooting, but their injuries were not life-threatening, he said.</p>

<p>Fifteen others, who witnessed the shooting, were under observation by psychologists.</p>

<p>"It's a shock," Michel Marien, the mayor of Espinasse-Vozelle, told AFP. "We don't know what triggered this, how a person loses control and does something like this."</p>

<p>Police said the shooter, in his early 50s, appeared to have no prior convictions. The only trace of any irregularity were documents relating to unpaid family support payments, a source close to the case said.</p>

<p>"The exact sequence of events still needs to be checked," the source said.</p>

<p>A large number of police and emergency services were on site Sunday.</p>

<p>Participants at the village's Bastille Day celebration that was going on nearby were not harmed as police cordoned off the area.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-12/police-car-generic_650x400_81482225957.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A large number of police and emergency services were on site Sunday (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>