<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 07:16:52 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-donald-trump-trump-raised-139-million-in-july-has-327-million-cash-on-hand-6244382]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Raised $139 Million In July, Has $327 Million Cash On Hand]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-donald-trump-trump-raised-139-million-in-july-has-327-million-cash-on-hand-6244382]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 06:49:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential nominee and former president Donald Trump has said that his campaign raised USD 139 million in July and has USD 327 million cash on hand.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential nominee and former president Donald Trump has said that his campaign raised USD 139 million in July and has USD 327 million cash on hand.</p>

<p>"There has never been anything like the MAGA Movement. We raised $139 Million Dollars in July alone. We now have a whopping $327 Million Cash On Hand." Trump said on Truth Social, his social media platform.</p>

<p>"Spectacular support from Great American Patriots who are donating to our Campaign for President of the United States, and helping out in many other ways. Much work to be done, but I will always keep fighting for YOU. Our Country is failing, but we will turn it around, quickly, and MAKE AMERICA GREAT AGAIN!," he said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The Trump Campaign, in a statement, said these numbers reflect continued momentum with donors at every level and provide the resources for the final 96 days until victory on November 5th.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pigc5cvo_donald-trump-_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Our country is failing, but we will turn it around, quickly."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-vadim-krasikov-the-assassin-freed-in-russian-prison-swap-6244346]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Vadim Krasikov, The Assassin Freed In Russian Prisoner Swap]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-vadim-krasikov-the-assassin-freed-in-russian-prison-swap-6244346]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 06:31:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vadim Krasikov, a Russian freed from jail in Germany on Friday in a prisoner swap between Moscow and the West, was convicted of the murder in 2019 of a former Chechen militant as he walked in broad daylight in a park in central Berlin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vadim Krasikov, a Russian freed from jail in Germany on Friday in a prisoner swap between Moscow and the West, was convicted of the murder in 2019 of a former Chechen militant as he walked in broad daylight in a park in central Berlin.</p>

<p>The brazenness of the murder, committed a few minutes' walk from parliament and the office of then-chancellor Angela Merkel, sparked outrage in Germany that has complicated attempts to swap him for the growing list of political prisoners the West would like freed from Russian jails.</p>

<p>The judge called the killing of Georgian citizen Zelimkhan Khangoshvili "state terrorism", adding that the order had almost certainly come from Putin himself.</p>

<p>Among the evidence he cited for Russian state involvement were his official Russian papers containing a false identity and the fact that Russian law empowered Putin to order the murder of state enemies abroad.</p>

<p>The three shots fired from a Glock pistol on a sunny August day were deemed murder "with especially serious aggravating circumstances" - the most serious conviction possible under German law.</p>

<p>Particularly aggravating was the fact that Khangoshvili had long forsworn any violent struggle for Chechen independence, the judge said.</p>

<p>"This was not an act of self-defence by Russia. This was and is nothing other than state terrorism," he said. "Four children lost their father, two siblings their brother."</p>

<p>Krasikov was born in Kazakhstan, then part of the Soviet Union, in 1965, and police mugshots show him with deep, narrow-set eyes and a mournful expression. He worked for Russia's FSB state security service, where, according to open source investigators Bellingcat, he became a specialist assassin.</p>

<p>Krasikov's conviction in December 2021 triggered the expulsion of two of the 101 diplomats then serving in Russia's giant Berlin embassy. Their number has been reduced by another 50 since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>He entered Germany via France with false papers under the name Vadim Sokolov. He was arrested minutes after cycling up behind Khangoshvili and shooting him dead; passers-by spotted him changing his clothes, shaving off his beard and dumping his bicycle in a pond, and alerted police.</p>

<p>While Krasikov pleaded innocent and maintained he was genuinely Sokolov, a St Petersburg construction engineer visiting Berlin as a tourist, Putin has implicitly acknowledged his identity and profession. Last year, without naming Krasikov, he spoke of his desire to secure the release of someone who had "eliminated a bandit in one of the European capitals".</p>

<p>Investigators identified Krasikov with the help of Ukraine's security services, who spotted footage of a man with identical tattoos - seemingly of a demon wearing a crown and a snake - at his second marriage, to a woman from the Ukrainian city of Kharkiv in 2010.</p>

<p>Throughout his trial, he made a show of not recognising the court, often removing the headset relaying the interpretation when witnesses against him were heard.</p>

<p>For Germany, releasing him is legally complex, especially given the seriousness of the crime.</p>

<p>Specialists have suggested that he could be released under a theoretical agreement that he serve his sentence in Russia, even if the Kremlin then chose to renege on this. Alternatively, prosecutors could state that they no longer wish to see his sentence enforced.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4mdgonmo_vadim-krasikov_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He entered Germany via France with false papers under the name Vadim Sokolov.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-indians-arrested-with-drugs-worth-10-million-in-us-6244317]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Indians Arrested With Drugs Worth $10 Million In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-indians-arrested-with-drugs-worth-10-million-in-us-6244317]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 06:25:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US officials have arrested two Indian nationals with drugs worth USD 10 million, the Department of Justice said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US officials have arrested two Indian nationals with drugs worth USD 10 million, the Department of Justice said. Simranjit Singh, 28, and Gusimrat Singh, 19, of Fresno, California were each charged with one count of conspiracy to distribute and to possess with intent to distribute controlled substances, it said.</p>

<p>Both made initial appearances before a federal court in Boston on July 29 and remain in federal custody. They were detained after local police found in the cab of the tractor trailer, over 400-kg bricks of suspected cocaine worth more than USD 10.5 million.</p>

<p>"The sheer amount of drugs seized in this one case is disturbing and dangerous. These defendants allegedly took a cross-country trip to distribute illicit narcotics into Massachusetts communities," said Acting United States Attorney Joshua S Levy.</p>

<p>According to charging documents, on July 29, at 10.15 pm, a white tractor trailer arrived at a planned Andover address to deliver methamphetamine to the undercover agents. The driver and passenger of that tractor trailer, later identified as Gusimrat Singh and Simranjit Singh, allegedly handed off 65 pounds of suspected methamphetamine to the undercover agents. The men were immediately taken into custody.</p>

<p>The charge of conspiracy to distribute and to possess with intent to distribute controlled substances provides for a sentence of up to 20 years in prison, at least three years and up to life of supervised release, and a fine of up to USD 1,000,000.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both made initial appearances before a federal court in Boston on July 29.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-says-it-will-sack-18-000-staff-cut-20-billion-in-expenses-6244314]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Intel Says It Will Sack 18,000 Staff, Cut $20 Billion In Expenses]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-says-it-will-sack-18-000-staff-cut-20-billion-in-expenses-6244314]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 06:23:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US chip maker Intel said Thursday it will slash more than 15 percent of its workforce as it streamlines operations.The plan to cut approximately $20 billion in expenses this year came as Intel reported a loss of $1.6 billion in the recently ended qua]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US chip maker Intel said Thursday it will slash more than 15 percent of its workforce as it streamlines operations.</p>

<p>The plan to cut approximately $20 billion in expenses this year came as Intel reported a loss of $1.6 billion in the recently ended quarter.</p>

<p>"Our Q2 financial performance was disappointing, even as we hit key product and process technology milestones," Intel chief executive Pat Gelsinger said in an earnings release.</p>

<p>"Second-half trends are more challenging than we previously expected."</p>

<p>Second quarter earnings were negatively affected by "headwinds" to the ramp-up of Intel's artificial intelligence PC product and unused capacity at its facilities, according to chief financial officer David Zinsner.</p>

<p>"By implementing our spending reductions, we are taking proactive steps to improve our profits and strengthen our balance sheet," Zinsner said.</p>

<p>Intel reported having 124,800 employees at the end of last year, meaning the layoffs could hit about 18,000 positions.</p>

<p>In June, Intel announced it was halting the expansion of a major factory project in Israel, which was going to pump an extra $15 billion towards a chip plant.</p>

<p>Intel said at the time that "managing large-scale projects, especially in our industry, often involves adapting to changing timelines."</p>

<p>"Decisions are based on business conditions, market dynamics and responsible capital management," the US-based company added.</p>

<p>The belt-tightening came just a month after Intel struck a defiant tone in the face of strong challenges from rivals Nvidia, AMD and Qualcomm, unveiling technologies it said would lead the artificial intelligence revolution.</p>

<p>For decades, Intel has dominated the market for the chips that run everything from laptops to data centres. But in recent years, its competitors -- especially Nvidia -- have soared ahead on specialized AI processors.</p>

<p>During a keynote speech at Taiwan's Computex expo, Gelsinger introduced Intel's latest Xeon 6 processors for servers, and shared more details about its next-gen Lunar Lake chips for AI PCs.</p>

<p>"AI is driving one of the most consequential eras of innovation the industry has ever seen," Gelsinger said.</p>

<p>"The magic of silicon is once again enabling exponential advancements in computing that will push the boundaries of human potential and power the global economy for years to come."</p>

<p>Gelsinger said Intel's latest equipment provides the best available mix of performance, energy efficiency and affordability.</p>

<p>His presentation followed earlier keynote speeches by Nvidia boss Jensen Huang, AMD CEO Lisa Su and Qualcomm's Cristiano Amon -- and they were replete with claims and counterclaims about which firm's products were the best for AI.</p>

<p>Microsoft in June unveiled its Copilot+ AI PCs, which will have artificial intelligence features built into its Windows operating system.</p>

<p>Along with Microsoft, the features will be added by some of the world's biggest computer manufacturers, including Dell, HP, Samsung and Lenovo, offering AI capabilities on the device itself, not just through the internet.</p>

<p>AI computers are expected to be 80 percent of the PC market by 2028, Intel said, citing the Boston Consulting Group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/hl4hnpm4_intel_625x300_29_June_22.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Intel reported having 124,800 employees at the end of last year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-call-with-benjamin-netanyahu-joe-biden-says-us-committed-to-defend-israel-against-all-threats-from-iran-6244250]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says US Committed To Defend Israel Against "All Threats From Iran"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-call-with-benjamin-netanyahu-joe-biden-says-us-committed-to-defend-israel-against-all-threats-from-iran-6244250]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 06:00:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden told Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Thursday that Washington is committed to defending Israel's security "against all threats from Iran," the White House said, after the assassination of a top Hamas leader in Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden told Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Thursday that Washington is committed to defending Israel's security "against all threats from Iran," the White House said, after the assassination of a top Hamas leader in Tehran.</p>

<p>Biden, who was joined on the call by Vice President and Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris, also emphasized the "ongoing efforts to de-escalate broader tensions in the region," the White House said in a statement.</p>

<p>The call between the leaders also came after Israel announced it had "eliminated Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's government has not commented on the slaying of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, but the Palestinian militant group has blamed Israel.</p>

<p>Biden "reaffirmed his commitment to Israel's security against all threats from Iran, including its proxy terrorist groups Hamas, Hezbollah, and the Huthis," the White House said in a readout of the president's call with Netanyahu.</p>

<p>"The president discussed efforts to support Israel's defense against threats, including against ballistic missiles and drones, to include new defensive US military deployments," it said.</p>

<p>Hamas, Hezbollah and Yemen's Houthi rebels all receive backing from Iran.</p>

<p>Israel has been battling Hamas in the Gaza Strip since the group's October 7 attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign against Hamas has killed at least 39,480 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Israel has said the assassination of Shukr was a response to deadly rocket fire from the Lebanese group last week on the annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has exchanged near-daily fire with Israel in south Lebanon since the Gaza war began.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mkjgiug_biden-netanyahu_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden "reaffirmed his commitment to Israel's security against all threats from Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-warns-as-iran-hezbollah-vow-revenge-6243948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Attack In Return": Netanyahu Warns As Iran, Hezbollah Vow Revenge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-warns-as-iran-hezbollah-vow-revenge-6243948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 04:15:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Thursday that Israel was prepared for any "aggression" against it following threats of retaliation for the killings of top Hamas and Hezbollah figures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Thursday that Israel was prepared for any "aggression" against it following threats of retaliation for the killings of top Hamas and Hezbollah figures.</p>

<p>"Israel is at a very high level of preparation for any scenario, both defensive and offensive. We will make any act of aggression against us pay a very high price," Netanyahu said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Those who attack us, we will attack in return."</p>

<p>His comments came as Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah warned Thursday that the Lebanese armed group was bound to respond to Israel's killing of its top military commander, Fuad Shukr, in a strike on Tuesday in a Beirut suburb.</p>

<p>Later on Thursday, Israel's Foreign Minister Israel Katz issued a threat in a statement posted on X.</p>

<p>"Hassan Nasrallah, stop the boasting speeches, threats and lies before you pay a heavy price," Katz said.</p>

<p>"We will act with full force to restore security to the residents of the north."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh was killed in a strike in Tehran, which Iran and Hamas have blamed on Israel. Israel has declined to comment on his killing.</p>

<p>"You do not know what red lines you crossed," Nasrallah said addressing Israel during a speech broadcast at Shukr's funeral.</p>

<p>"The enemy, and those who are behind the enemy, must await our inevitable response."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/ap4d2k3o_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu said that Israel is at a very high level of preparation for any scenario.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-president-vladimir-putin-meets-freed-russian-prisoners-at-moscow-airport-6243864]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Meets Freed Russian Prisoners At Moscow Airport]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-president-vladimir-putin-meets-freed-russian-prisoners-at-moscow-airport-6243864]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 03:49:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin late on Thursday met Russian citizens, who were detained in foreign countries and returned to their homeland after a prisoners' exchange deal, at Vnukovo Airport here.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin late on Thursday met Russian citizens, who were detained in foreign countries and returned to their homeland after a prisoners' exchange deal, at Vnukovo Airport here.</p>

<p>Putin congratulated them and announced that they will be nominated for state awards.</p>

<p>"First of all, I want to congratulate you all on your return to your homeland. Now I want to address those of you who are directly involved in military service. I want to thank you for your loyalty to the oath, your duty and the homeland, which has never forgotten you for a minute - and here you are at home," the President said while addressing them at the airport.</p>

<p>The meeting was also attended by Defence Minister Andrei Belousov, Director of the Foreign Intelligence Service Sergei Naryshkin and Director of the Federal Security Service Alexander Bortnikov.</p>

<p>The prisoner swap deal, mediated by Turkey, involved seven countries -- the US, Norway, Germany, Poland, Russia, Belarus and Slovenia.</p>

<p>The most notable Russian prisoner released in the exchange was Vadim Krasikov, who was jailed for life in Germany for the 2019 murder in Berlin of Zelimkhan Khangoshvili, a former Chechen separatist leader. The Germans were reluctant to release but, according to reports, Biden personally got involved and called Chancellor Olaf Scholz.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/imbnpsc8_putin-met-freed-prisoners_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin congratulated them and announced that they will be nominated for state awards.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-0-earthquake-hits-italy-no-immediate-damage-officials-6243687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5.0 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Italy, No Immediate Damage: Officials]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-0-earthquake-hits-italy-no-immediate-damage-officials-6243687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 02:48:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 5.0-magnitude earthquake struck Italy's southern region of Calabria late Friday, but there were no immediate reports of damage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 5.0-magnitude earthquake struck Italy's southern region of Calabria late Friday, but there were no immediate reports of damage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The quake was centred three kilometres west of Pietrapaola in the province of Cosenza on the Ionian Sea, according to the National Institute of Geophysics and Volcanology (INGV).</p>

<p>Fire officials wrote on X that there had been no reports of damage or calls for help, but checks were ongoing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pietrapaola Mayor Manuela Labonia told RaiNews 24 that "the situation is calm".&nbsp;</p>

<p>But, she said, residents felt "other tremors, less strong ones," after the first quake, and "we are all in the street."</p>

<p>The head of INGV, Carlo Doglioni, told RaiNews 24 there had been various tremors in the area in recent days, and the agency was monitoring the situation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We don't know if this is the maximum (tremor) in the sequence," Doglioni said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On social media, some people reported feeling the earthquake as far away as Bari, Puglia, some 250 kilometres (150 miles) to the north.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/earthquake-generic_650x400_41477031196.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fire officials wrote on X that there had been no reports of damage or calls for help.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-it-fired-dozens-of-rockets-at-israel-amid-rising-tensions-6243601]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Says It Fired Dozens Of Rockets At Israel Amid Rising Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-it-fired-dozens-of-rockets-at-israel-amid-rising-tensions-6243601]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 02:14:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah said it launched rockets at northern Israel Thursday "in response" to a deadly Israeli strike in south Lebanon -- the group's first attack after Israel killed a top commander earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah said it launched rockets at northern Israel Thursday "in response" to a deadly Israeli strike in south Lebanon -- the group's first attack after Israel killed a top commander earlier this week.</p>

<p>The Iran-backed group said in a statement that it "launched dozens of Katyusha rockets... in response to the Israeli enemy's attack on... (the southern village of Shama) that killed a number of civilians".</p>

<p>The Israeli military said that shortly after the rocket fire, the air force "struck the Hezbollah launcher from which the projectiles were launched".</p>

<p>Earlier Thursday, the Lebanese health ministry said four Syrians were killed in an Israeli strike on the south, where Hezbollah and Israel have exchanged near-daily fire since the Gaza war began in October.</p>

<p>"The health ministry announces... four Syrian nationals were martyred" in an "Israeli strike" on the southern village of Shama, it said in a statement.</p>

<p>The ministry said the toll might rise once DNA tests had been carried out.</p>

<p>The strike also wounded five Lebanese nationals, it added.</p>

<p>Emergency services told AFP that the dead were farmer workers and part of the same family.</p>

<p>Plumes of smoke billowed from the site of the strike, which heavily damaged two nearby buildings and burnt a vehicle to a crisp, a photographer contributing to AFP reported.</p>

<p>The attack was Hezbollah's first since an Israeli air strike killed its top commander Fuad Shukr on Tuesday evening, with leader Hassan Nasrallah saying operations would resume on Friday morning.</p>

<p>Nasrallah warned his group was bound to respond to the killing of Shukr.</p>

<p>His death was followed hours later Wednesday, by the killing of Hezbollah ally Hamas's chief Ismail Haniyeh in a strike in Tehran, which Iran and Hamas have blamed on Israel. Israel has declined to comment on his killing.</p>

<p>The violence since October has killed at least 542 people on the Lebanese side, most of them fighters but also including 114 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>At least 22 soldiers and 25 civilians have been killed on the Israeli side, including in the annexed Golan Heights, according to army figures.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t0borbr4_hezbollah_625x300_28_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah said it launched attack on Israel "in response" to a deadly Israeli strike in south Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthi-rebels-vow-military-response-to-israel-escalation-6243361]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthi Rebels Vow "Military Response" To Israel Escalation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthi-rebels-vow-military-response-to-israel-escalation-6243361]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 01:07:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The leader of Yemen's Iran-backed Huthi rebels vowed a "military response" Thursday to the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran in an attack blamed on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The leader of Yemen's Iran-backed Huthi rebels vowed a "military response" Thursday to the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran in an attack blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>"There has to be a military response to these crimes, which are shameless and dangerous, and constitute a major escalation by the Israeli enemy," Abdul Malik al-Huthi said in a televised speech.</p>

<p>The Yemeni rebels have been launching drones and missiles at shipping in the Red Sea since November, saying they are acting in solidarity with Palestinians during the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Last month, a deadly Huthi drone strike on Tel Aviv prompted Israeli air strikes on Hodeida, impoverished Yemen's lifeline port, that killed nine people and triggered a massive inferno.</p>

<p>The rebel leader described the killing of the Hamas chief as "a flagrant violation of all norms and principles".</p>

<p>He also condemned the killing of Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr on Tuesday in a Beirut strike claimed by Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/6l5ssuro_houthi-rebels-_625x300_30_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There has to be a military response to these crimes, a Houthi leader said amid middle east tensions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-us-president-joe-biden-to-hold-call-today-after-hamas-chiefs-killing-6243223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu, Biden To Hold Call Today After Hamas Chief's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-us-president-joe-biden-to-hold-call-today-after-hamas-chiefs-killing-6243223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:26:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and U.S. President Joe Biden will speak by phone on Thursday, the White House said, following the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, the Iranian capital, earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and U.S. President Joe Biden will speak by phone on Thursday, the White House said, following the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, the Iranian capital, earlier this week.</p>

<p>The assassination drew threats of revenge on Israel and fueled concern that the conflict in Gaza was turning into a wider Middle East war. Iran and Hamas have blamed Haniyeh's killing on Israel, which has neither denied nor confirmed a role in the assassination.</p>

<p>Israel did, however, confirm that it killed a senior commander of the Lebanese Hezbollah movement in Beirut on Tuesday.</p>

<p>U.S. national security adviser Jake Sullivan offered little insight into how Haniyeh's death could affect the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"It is too soon to tell what the impact of his death will have on negotiations (for a ceasefire deal in Gaza), and so I'm not going to speculate on that, especially in light of the broader dynamics and set of events unfolding in the region right now," Sullivan said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/r1f2pcco_biden-netanyahu-_625x300_05_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and U.S. President Joe Biden will speak by phone today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-has-been-freed-in-russia-west-prisoner-deal-6243176]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Assassin, Journalist, Critic: Who Were Freed In Russia-West Prisoner Swap]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-has-been-freed-in-russia-west-prisoner-deal-6243176]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:14:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia and the West have released a total of 24 prisoners in the biggest exchange since the end of the Cold War, officials said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia and the West have released a total of 24 prisoners in the biggest exchange since the end of the Cold War, officials said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Here's a snapshot of who has been released:</p>

<p><strong>Freed by Russia</strong></p>

<p>Russia has freed 16 people -- US and German citizens, journalists and domestic dissidents:</p>

<p><strong>Evan Gershkovich:</strong></p>

<p>The 32-year-old Wall Street Journal reporter became the first Western journalist to be jailed in Russia for espionage since the Soviet era. He was sentenced to 16 years in a strict penal colony by a Russian court on July 19, after a fast-track trial.</p>

<p>Russia says that he spied on a tank factory in the Urals region and was working for the US Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), but presented no evidence to support its claims, which were dismissed as bogus by the White House and his employer.</p>

<p>Born in the US state of New Jersey to Soviet Jewish emigres he carried on visiting Russia even after dozens of other Western journalists left following Moscow's Ukraine offensive.</p>

<p><strong>Paul Whelan:</strong></p>

<p>The former US Marine Whelan, 54, who also has British, Irish and Canadian nationalities, has been jailed in Russia since December 2018.</p>

<p>In June 2020 he was sentenced to 16 years in a remote Russian penal colony for espionage.</p>

<p>He was detained in a Moscow hotel in 2018 -- allegedly with a cache of classified documents, when he was the security director of a US automotive parts manufacturer.</p>

<p><strong>Alsu Kurmasheva:</strong></p>

<p>US-Russian journalist Kurmasheva, 47, was sentenced to six years and six months on the same day as Gershkovich in an ultra-secret trial, details of which did not emerge until days later.</p>

<p>An editor with the US-funded Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty outlet, she was accused of violating Russia's strict military censorship laws and arrested while travelling to Russia from her home in Prague to see her sick mother.</p>

<p><strong>Vladimir Kara-Murza:</strong></p>

<p>Fierce Kremlin critic and journalist Kara-Murza, 42, was in April 2023 handed a 25-year term for condemning Moscow's campaign in Ukraine, one of the longest prison terms ever handed down to a Putin critic.</p>

<p>A dual British-Russian national, he was arrested in April 2022 after a speech in the United States where he accused Russia of "war crimes" against Ukraine.</p>

<p>Several investigative media outlets, including Bellingcat, The Insider and Der Spiegel, have backed his claim that he was poisoned by security services under orders from the Kremlin -- attacks which left him with nerve damage.</p>

<p>In May he won a Pulitzer Prize "for passionate columns written at great person risk from his prison cell."</p>

<p><strong>Oleg Orlov:</strong></p>

<p>Veteran rights advocate Orlov, 71, was handed a two-and-a-half-year term in February after calling Russia a "fascist" state and criticising its Ukraine campaign.</p>

<p>A biologist by training Orlov was an instrumental figure in Memorial, the Nobel Prize winning human rights organisation disbanded by Russia in late 2021. Under his guidance, Memorial preserved the memory of victims of communist repression and campaigned against rights abuses in modern Russia.</p>

<p><strong>Lilia Chanysheva:</strong></p>

<p>Chanysheva, 42, who once headed late opposition leader Alexei Navalny's offices in the central Bashkortostan republic, was sentenced to seven and a half years' prison in June 2023 for having created an "extremist organisation", a sentence that was later toughened to nine and a half years in April.</p>

<p>An accountant, she had worked for major companies including Deloitte before joining Navalny's team in 2017, openly protesting corruption in the region.</p>

<p><strong>Ksenia Fadeyeva:</strong></p>

<p>In December 2023 Fadeyeva, 32, who led Navalny's now-banned organisation in the Siberian city of Tomsk, was sentenced to nine years in prison for "extremism".</p>

<p>Fadeyeva headed Navalny's political office in Tomsk, where the opposition leader was poisoned in August 2020 on a visit ahead of elections.</p>

<p>Fadeyeva was elected to the Tomsk city legislature in 2020, a move hailed as a victory for the Russian opposition against President Vladimir Putin's rule.</p>

<p><strong>Ilya Yashin:</strong></p>

<p>Russian liberal opposition politician Yashin, 41, was handed eight and a half years in late 2022 for denouncing Moscow's Ukraine offensive.</p>

<p>A former ally of Navalny and assassinated opposition figure Boris Nemtsov, he was imprisoned for having denounced "murders of civilians" in the Ukrainian town of Bucha.</p>

<p><strong>Alexandra Skochilenko:</strong></p>

<p>Artist Skochilenko, 33, from Saint Petersburg, was arrested in April 2022 and then jailed in November 2023 for seven years for replacing supermarket price tags with messages opposing the Ukraine offensive.</p>

<p>She in particular focused on the bloody battle for the Black Sea port city of Mariupol.</p>

<p><strong>Andrei Pivovarov:</strong></p>

<p>Russian opposition activist Pivovarov, 42, headed the Open Russia foundation, bankrolled by former oligarch Mikhail Khodorkovsky, who himself spent a decade in prison for campaigning against Putin.</p>

<p>He was arrested in 2021, hauled off a plane by FSB agents before he could leave the country, and sentenced to four years for collaborating with an "undesirable" organisation.</p>

<p><strong>Rico Krieger:</strong></p>

<p>German citizen Rico Krieger, a 30-year-old medic, was pardoned by Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko on July 30 after being sentenced to the death penalty on June 24.</p>

<p>Convicted under six articles of Belarus's criminal code in a secretive trial, he was suspected of photographing military sites in Belarus in October 2023 and placing an explosive device on a railway line near Minsk under Ukrainian orders.</p>

<p>According to a LinkedIn profile Krieger, worked as a medic for the German Red Cross and had previously been employed as an armed security officer for the US embassy in Berlin.</p>

<p><strong>Dieter Voronin:</strong></p>

<p>Joint Russian-German citizen Voronin was sentenced to 13 years in prison on "treason" charges after Moscow alleged he received classified military information from another journalist, Ivan Safronov, who remains behind bars.</p>

<p><strong>Kevin Lick:</strong></p>

<p>Lick, who was arrested aged 17 and is another joint Russian-German citizen, became the youngest person ever convicted of treason in Russia when he was sentenced in 2023 to four years for allegedly sending photos of a Russian military facility visible from his apartment window to German security services.</p>

<p><strong>Patrick Schoebel:</strong></p>

<p>German citizen Schoebel, in his late 30s, was arrested earlier this year at Saint Petersburg airport after customs officials found cannabis gummy bears in his luggage.</p>

<p><strong>German Moyzhes:</strong></p>

<p>Moyzhes, a Russian-German migration lawyer, was facing treason charges after he was arrested in Saint Petersburg in May, according to Russian state media.</p>

<p>Almost no details of the case against him had been made public. Moyzhes was well known in Saint Petersburg as an urban activist and pro-cycle campaigner.</p>

<p><strong>Vadim Ostanin:</strong></p>

<p>The former head of another of Navalny's regional branches, Ostanin was sentenced in 2023 to nine years in prison for participating in an "extremist" organisation.</p>

<p><strong>Freed by the West</strong></p>

<p>The United States, Germany, Slovenia, Poland and Norway freed a total of eight people as part of the deal, including alleged spies, hitmen and hackers.</p>

<p><strong>Vadim Krasikov:</strong></p>

<p>Krasikov, an alleged FSB hitman, was sentenced to life in prison in Germany for gunning down a former Chechen separatist in a Berlin Park in 2019.</p>

<p>German judges said the murder was ordered by the Russian state, and the Bellingcat investigative media outlet has linked Krasikov to a secret elite unit of Russia's FSB state security services.</p>

<p>Through his lawyer, Krasikov claimed he had been misidentified and was a Russian construction engineer. Earlier this year Putin, without naming him specifically, said he wanted a Russian "patriot" who had "eliminated a bandit" in a "European capital" freed from prison.</p>

<p><strong>Artem Dultsev and Anna Dultseva:</strong></p>

<p>Slovenia sentenced Dultsev and Dultseva, both 40, to more than a year and half in prison for "spying and falsifying documents."</p>

<p>The pair, alleged Russian secret agents, were living undercover on Argentine passports in the capital Ljubljana, where authorities said they ran an art gallery as part of their cover.</p>

<p><strong>Mikhail Mikushin:</strong></p>

<p>Mikushin, born in 1978, was arrested in Norway in 2022 and accused of posing as a Brazilian researcher at a university in Tromso.</p>

<p>The Bellingcat investigative outlet said he was a colonel in Russia's GRU military intelligence services and Norwegian media reported that he did not speak Portuguese, Brazil's national language.</p>

<p><strong>Pavel Rubtsov:</strong></p>

<p>Polish intelligence alleged Rubtsov, a Russian-born Spanish freelance journalist in Spain, was an agent for Russia's GRU military intelligence service.</p>

<p>Living as Pablo Gonzalez, he was arrested near the Polish border with Ukraine just four days after Russia launched its offensive in February 2022.</p>

<p>He was born in Moscow but moved to Spain at the age of nine and obtained Spanish nationality.</p>

<p><strong>Roman Seleznev:</strong></p>

<p>Seleznev, the son of a Russian lawmaker, was convicted of a string of cybercrimes in the United States, including a 27-year prison sentence for hacking into card payment terminals to steal millions of credit card details.</p>

<p>US officials called his "criminal enterprise ... both sophisticated and expansive, with transnational implications." Dubbed a master hacker, he was arrested in 2014 in the Maldives.</p>

<p><strong>Vladislav Klyushin:</strong></p>

<p>Another Russian convicted of hacking crimes, Klyushin, was sentenced in 2023 to nine years in prison for netting almost $100 million by hacking into corporate systems and then illegally trading shares using the information he had gathered.</p>

<p><strong>Vadim Konoshchenok:</strong></p>

<p>The US Justice Department says Konoshchenok, who it alleges has "ties to Russia's FSB", was a key figure in a scheme to provide US-made ammunition and electronics to Russia to support its offensive in Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/o905bb78_us-prisoner-swap_625x300_02_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has freed 16 people - US and German citizens, journalists and domestic dissidents (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-loses-appeal-of-gag-order-in-hush-money-criminal-case-6243139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Loses Appeal Of Gag Order In Hush Money Criminal Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-loses-appeal-of-gag-order-in-hush-money-criminal-case-6243139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:08:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New York state appeals court on Thursday rejected Donald Trump's challenge to a gag order in his hush money criminal case, where the former US president was convicted in May on charges stemming from hush money paid to a porn star.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York state appeals court on Thursday rejected Donald Trump's challenge to a gag order in his hush money criminal case, where the former US president was convicted in May on charges stemming from hush money paid to a porn star.</p>

<p>The decision by the Appellate Division in Manhattan means the Republican presidential nominee cannot comment publicly about individual prosecutors and others in the case until Justice Juan Merchan sentences him on Sept. 18, seven weeks before the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers have argued that the gag order violated Trump's constitutional free speech rights under the First Amendment.</p>

<p>Steven Cheung, a spokesperson for Trump's campaign, said Trump "continues to forcefully challenge" the gag order.</p>

<p>"The gag order is blatantly un-American as it continues to gag President Trump," Cheung said in a statement.</p>

<p>A Reuters/Ipsos poll released on Tuesday showed Trump locked in a tight race with Vice President Kamala Harris, who is poised to become the Democratic nominee. Harris led Trump 43%-42% among registered voters, within the margin of error.</p>

<p>Merchan imposed the gag order a few weeks before the trial began on April 22, saying Trump's history of making threatening statements could undermine the proceedings.</p>

<p>The original order prevented Trump from commenting on prosecutors, court staff, witnesses and jurors. A separate order against naming the anonymous jurors remains in effect.</p>

<p>Merchan lifted the restrictions on witnesses and jurors following Trump's May 30 conviction.</p>

<p>The Appellate Division, a mid-level appeals court, said threats that Bragg's staff received in the wake of the verdict continue to pose a "significant and immediate" threat.</p>

<p>"Justice Merchan did not act in excess of jurisdiction by maintaining the narrowly tailored protections," the five-judge panel said.</p>

<p>The appeals court upheld Merchan's original gag order in May, citing the need to protect people from "threats, intimidation, harassment, and harm," and rejecting Trump's First Amendment argument.</p>

<p>The order leaves Trump free to speak about Bragg and Merchan.</p>

<p>Jurors found Trump guilty on 34 felony counts of falsifying business records, for having covered up former personal lawyer and fixer Michael Cohen's $130,000 payment to adult film actress Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>The payment was made in exchange for Daniels' silence before the 2016 election about a sexual encounter she says she had with Trump a decade earlier, which Trump denied. Trump won the presidency by defeating Democrat Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>The criminal trial was the first of any US president.</p>

<p>Trump faces up to four years in prison, and can also be fined.</p>

<p>Time behind bars is rare for people convicted in New York for falsifying business records, especially those like Trump with no prior criminal histories.</p>

<p>Trump has vowed to appeal his conviction after he is sentenced.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7s3biquo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_30_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The order leaves Trump free to speak about Bragg and Merchan. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-womens-boxing-match-at-paris-olympics-sparks-gender-row-6241881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Women's Boxing Match At Paris Olympics Sparks Gender Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-womens-boxing-match-at-paris-olympics-sparks-gender-row-6241881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 20:54:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Algerian boxer Imane Khelif, who failed a gender eligibility test last year, knocked their Italian opponent out in 46 seconds in the 66 kg women's boxing category and has drawn the ire of Italian Prime Minister Georgia Meloni.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Algerian boxer Imane Khelif, who failed a gender eligibility test last year, knocked their Italian opponent out in 46 seconds in the 66 kg women's boxing category and has drawn the ire of Italian Prime Minister Georgia Meloni, who said the fight was "not on an equal footing".</p>

<p>The author of Harry Potter, JK Rowling, reacted to the gender row during the match and said, "Explain why you're OK with a man beating a woman in public for your entertainment."</p>

<p>Italian Angela Carini was distraught, she collapsed on her knees and sobbed in the middle of the ring after the defeat and did not shake hands with Khelif, who entered the quarterfinals in the category after the win.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A boxing round lasts 3 minutes and there are three rounds in each but the Algerian boxer landed two strong punches, knocking Carini out in just 46 seconds. The Italian boxer was unable to stand after her nose was hit and began bleeding.</p>

<p>"I have a big pain in my nose and I said, 'Stop'. It's better to avoid keeping going. My nose started dripping (with blood) from the first hit," said the distressed Carini.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Imane Khelif (red) vs Angela Carini (blue)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cofb8qi_imane-khelif-afp_625x300_01_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Imane Khelif (red) vs Angela Carini (blue)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Imane Khelif (red) vs Angela Carini (blue)<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>Italy's Prime Minister said "I think athletes who have male genetic characteristics should not be admitted to women's competitions. And not because you want to discriminate against someone, but to protect the right of female athletes to be able to compete on equal terms."</p>

<p>"I was emotional yesterday when she wrote 'I will fight' because the dedication, the head, and the character, surely also play a role in these things. But then, it also matters to be able to compete on equal grounds and from my point of view it was not an even contest," Ms Meloni added.</p>

<p><strong>What Is The Controversy?</strong></p>

<p>The International Olympic Committee allowed two boxers, who failed the gender eligibility tests for the World Boxing Championships, to be made eligible to compete in the 2024 Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>Last year, the Algerian boxer was disqualified hours before her gold medal match at the women's World Championships in Delhi. Algerian media reported that Khelif was disqualified for a high level of testosterone in her system.</p>

<p>Taiwan's double world champion Lin Yu-ting lost her bronze medal at the same competition after she too failed to meet the criteria.</p>

<p>Umar Kremlev, Amateur Boxing President, told Russian news agency TASS, "DNA tests of two boxers proved they have XY chromosomes and were thus excluded." XY is the male chromosome and XX is for females.</p>

<p>Reem Alsalem, the UN special rapporteur on violence against women and girls, wrote on X that "Angela Carini rightly followed her instincts and prioritized her physical safety, but she and other female athletes should not have been exposed to this physical and psychological violence based on their sex."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Angelacarini?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Angelacarini</a> rightly followed her instincts and prioritized her physical safety, but she and other female athletes should not have been exposed to this physical and psychological<br />
Violence based on their sex.</p>
 Reem Alsalem UNSR Violence Against Women and Girls (@UNSRVAW) <a href="https://twitter.com/UNSRVAW/status/1818973075729170936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The World Championships were organised by the International Boxing Association (IBA) and were not recognised by the International Olympic Committee over financial transparency.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://olympics.com/ioc/news/ioc-statement-on-the-international-boxing-association-iba">The IOC said the source of the prize money</a> at the International Boxing Association was unclear and is one of the reasons why they withdrew its recognition of the IBA.</p>

<p>"The IBA was not prepared to transparently explain the sources of its financing or to explain its full financial dependency, at the time, on a single state-owned company, Gazprom," IOC said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The boxing competition at the Paris Olympics is being organised by the Paris Boxing Unit (PBU), an ad-hoc unit of the IOC's Executive Board.&nbsp;</p>

<p>IOC spokesman, Mark Adams, said "Everyone competing in the women's category is complying with competition eligibility rules. They are women in their passports and it's stated in there that they are female."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Nations Back Their Boxers</strong></p>

<p>As expected, the Algerian and Taiwanese boxers have received backing from their nations' leaders. Taiwan President Lai Ching-te said, "Yu-ting's performances have inspired many Taiwanese players and united Taiwanese people. Now that she is once again on the international stage, we should stand united and cheer for her."</p>

<p>Alegria's Olympic committee called it a "malicious and unethical attack directed against our distinguished athlete, Imane Khelif, by certain foreign media".</p>

<p>The IBA in a statement clarified that Khelif initially appealed the decision of the IBA's ruling at the Court of Arbitration for Sport (CAS) but later withdrew it during the process, making their decision legally binding.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, Lin Yu-ting did not appeal the decision thus rendering it legally binding.</p>

<p>"The IOC's differing regulations on these matters, in which IBA is not involved, raise serious questions about both competitive fairness and athletes' safety. For clarification on why the IOC permits athletes with competitive advantages to compete in their events, we urge interested parties to seek answers directly from the IOC," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iba.sport/news/statement-made-by-the-international-boxing-association-regarding-athletes-disqualifications-in-world-boxing-championships-2023/">the IBA said</a>.</p>

<p><strong>' Explain Why You're Ok With A Man Beating A Woman'</strong></p>

<p>The author of Harry Potter, JK Rowling, voiced her opinion on the gender row during the match and said, "Explain why you're OK with a man beating a woman in public for your entertainment. This isn't sport. From the bullying cheat in red up to the organisers who allowed this to happen, this is men revelling in their power over women."</p>

<p>Kirsty Burrows, the Head of the Safe Sport Unit at the IOC, in a press briefing, said, "Paris Olympics 2024 offers the most comprehensive package of mental health and safeguarding initiatives than any other Olympic or sporting event in history."&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A young female boxer has just had everything she's worked and trained for snatched away because you allowed a male to get in the ring with her. You're a disgrace, your safeguarding' is a joke and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Paris24?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Paris24</a> will be forever tarnished by the brutal injustice done to Carini. <a href="https://t.co/JMKzVljpyr">https://t.co/JMKzVljpyr</a></p>
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) <a href="https://twitter.com/jk_rowling/status/1818993613113634982?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Ms Burrows's comments were unrelated to the boxing match incident but Ms Rowling commented and said, "A young female boxer has just had everything she's worked and trained for snatched away because you allowed a male to get in the ring with her. You're a disgrace, your 'safeguarding' is a joke and Paris 24 will be forever tarnished by the brutal injustice done to Carini."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nfhpgj3_imane-khalif-boxing-match_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A boxing round lasts 3 minutes and there are three rounds in each.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/as-india-vietnam-strengthen-ties-pm-modi-speaks-against-expansionism-6240338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As India, Vietnam Strengthen Ties, PM Modi Speaks Against "Expansionism"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/as-india-vietnam-strengthen-ties-pm-modi-speaks-against-expansionism-6240338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 19:26:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India, Vietnam adopted an action plan to expand strategic ties with PM Modi vowing to work jointly for a rules-based Indo-Pacific and asserting that New Delhi supports development and "not expansionism" in remarks that came amid concerns over China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and Vietnam today adopted an action plan to expand their strategic ties with Prime Minister Narendra Modi vowing to work jointly for a rules-based Indo-Pacific and asserting that New Delhi supports development and "not expansionism" in remarks that came amid concerns over China's military posturing in the region.</p>

<p>The two sides signed six memorandums of understanding (MoUs) and finalised three other documents to broadbase cooperation in a range of areas following wide-ranging talks between PM Modi and Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh.</p>

<p>It was also decided that India will provide USD 300 million credit line to Vietnam primarily to strengthen the Southeast Asian nation's maritime security.</p>

<p>An agreement was sealed between the central banks of the two countries for rolling out digital payment connectivity.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Chinh arrived in New Delhi on Tuesday night on a three-day visit that is aimed at further expanding the comprehensive strategic ties between the two countries.</p>

<p>"In our Act East policy and our Indo-Pacific vision, Vietnam is our important partner... We support development, not expansionism <em>(Hum vistarbad nahi, vikasvad ka samarthan karte hei)</em>," PM Modi said in Hindi in his media statement.</p>

<p>"We will continue our cooperation for a free, open, rules-based and prosperous Indo-Pacific," he said.</p>

<p>PM Modi said that both sides decided that cooperation will be strengthened to deal with terrorism and cyber security issues.</p>

<p>"We believe that 'Developed India 2047' and Vietnam's 'Vision 2045' have accelerated development in both countries. This is opening up many new areas of mutual cooperation," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"And therefore, to further strengthen our Comprehensive Strategic Partnership, today we have adopted a new plan of action," he said.</p>

<p>PM Modi said new steps have been taken for cooperation in the field of defence and security.</p>

<p>The two prime ministers also remotely inaugurated an Army Software Park at Telecommunications University Nha Trang. It has been built with New Delhi's development assistance.</p>

<p>"The agreed USD 300 million credit line will strengthen Vietnam's maritime security," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"We agree that, to realise the mutual trade potential, the review of the ASEAN-India Trade in Goods Agreement should be concluded as early as possible," he said.</p>

<p>Vietnam is a key member of 10-nation ASEAN (Association of Southeast Asian Nations).</p>

<p>"We have decided to focus on the areas of green economy and new emerging technologies. Each other's capabilities in energy and port development will be harnessed for mutual benefit," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>The prime minister also invited people from Vietnam to the Buddhist circuit in India. "And we want the youth of Vietnam to also take advantage of Nalanda University." In his remarks, Modi said India-Vietnam relations have both "expanded and deepened" over the past decade.</p>

<p>"In the last 10 years, we have transformed our relations into a Comprehensive Strategic Partnership. Our bilateral trade has increased by more than 85 percent," he said.</p>

<p>"Mutual cooperation has expanded in energy, technology, and development partnership. Mutual cooperation in defence and security areas has gained new momentum," he said.</p>

<p>"Over the past decade, connectivity has increased. And today we have more than 50 direct flights between us. Along with this, tourism is continuously increasing, and people have also been given the facility of e-visa," PM Modi said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/hfbropu8_india-vietnam-joint-statement-pm-modi-vietnam-pm-pham-minh-chinh_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi and Vietnamese PM Pham Minh Chinh held a joint press statement in New Delhi today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-free-jailed-us-reporter-in-major-prisoner-swap-with-west-report-6241051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Frees US Reporter In Major Prisoner Swap With West, Says Turkey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-free-jailed-us-reporter-in-major-prisoner-swap-with-west-report-6241051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 19:10:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US journalist Evan Gershkovich and former US marine Paul Whelan are expected to be released by Russia as part of one of the biggest East-West prisoner swaps since the Cold War, according to US media Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US journalist Evan Gershkovich and former US marine Paul Whelan were released from Russia Thursday, the Turkish government announced, in one of the biggest East-West prisoner swaps since the Cold War.</p>

<p>A total of 26 people, including two minors, from the United States, Germany, Poland, Slovenia, Norway, Belarus and Russia were involved in the swap "carried out" by Turkey's MIT intelligence service, Turkey's presidency said.</p>

<p>There was no immediate confirmation from US officials, although the swap was widely reported by US television networks. The Kremlin declined to comment on any exchange.</p>

<p>Wall Street Journal reporter Gershkovich, 32, was detained in Russia in March 2023 and convicted in July on spying charges in a fast-track trial denounced as a sham by the United States.</p>

<p>Among those being returned to Russia in exchange, the Turkish government said, is Vadim Krasikov, a Russian citizen imprisoned in Germany for killing a former Chechen rebel commander in a brazen assassination.</p>

<p>Signs of an imminent prisoner swap had picked up momentum earlier Thursday, amid reports a plane used in a previous exchange deal had landed in the Russian exclave of Kaliningrad.</p>

<p>Hopes had also risen in recent days after a number of high-profile prisoners in Russia, including Whelan, went missing from facilities where they were serving long terms, fueling speculation they were being moved ahead of an exchange.</p>

<p>As a rule, swaps can only happen after a conviction in Russia, and the disappearance of several high-profile political prisoners at once is extremely rare.</p>

<p>The exchange would be a victory for US President Joe Biden, whose vice president, Kamala Harris, will face Republican Donald Trump in the November election.</p>

<p>This would be the first prisoner exchange between Russia and the West since star US basketball player Brittney Griner was swapped in return for convicted Russian arms dealer Viktor Bout in December 2022.</p>

<p>It would also be the biggest exchange since 2010, when 14 alleged spies were exchanged between Russia and the West. They included double agent Sergei Skripal, who was sent by Moscow to Britain and undercover Russian agent Anna Chapman, sent by Washington to Russia.</p>

<p>Before then, major swaps involving more than a dozen people had only taken place during the Cold War, with Soviet and Western powers carrying out exchanges in 1985 and 1986.</p>

<p><strong>'Pushing hard'</strong></p>

<p>An aircraft already used in Griner and Bout's exchange flew from Moscow to Kaliningrad early Thursday, according to flight tracking website Flightradar24. The flight was later tracked taking off from Kaliningrad two hours later.</p>

<p>Gershkovich was arrested in the city of Yekaterinburg while on a reporting trip. He, his employer and the US government all strongly denied the espionage allegations against him.</p>

<p>Biden had said after the sentencing that he was "pushing hard for Evan's release and will continue to do so."</p>

<p>Media rights group Reporters Without Borders said it was "hugely relieved."</p>

<p>"The Russian government's continued policy of state hostage-taking is outrageous. Journalists are not spies, and they must never be targeted for political purposes," the group said.</p>

<p>Washington has also been working for the release of Whelan, 54, who was arrested in 2018 in Moscow and charged with espionage.</p>

<p>Whelan was working in security for a US vehicle parts company when he was arrested, and has always asserted that the evidence against him was falsified.</p>

<p>Also among those who disappeared was journalist and activist Vladimir Kara-Murza, a 42-year-old joint Russian and British citizen. His lawyers said on Wednesday that they did not know his location after being twice denied access to the facility where he was meant to be held.</p>

<p>Kara-Murza, who spoke out against the Russian invasion of Ukraine, is serving a 25-year sentence in Siberia for treason and other charges. He suffers from a nerve disease and was moved to a prison hospital earlier this month for medical checks.</p>

<p>Adding to the intrigue was a case in Slovenia, where a court sentenced two Russians suspected of spying for Moscow to more than a year and a half in prison -- but then ordered their expulsion from the country.</p>

<p>Arrests of US citizens in Russia have increased in recent years, in what Washington sees as a Kremlin attempt to secure the release of Russians convicted abroad.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nik4i1vo_evan-gershkovich-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich, 32, was detained in March 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-key-moments-in-israel-hamas-war-6240607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Key Moments In Israel-Hamas War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-key-moments-in-israel-hamas-war-6240607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 18:15:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After members of the Palestinian militant group Hamas carried out the worst attack in Israeli history, on October 7, 2023, Israel responded with a devastating military campaign in the Gaza Strip.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After members of the Palestinian group Hamas carried out the worst attack in Israeli history, on October 7, 2023, Israel responded with a devastating military campaign in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The air and ground operation has killed at least 39,480 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-ruled territory, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>AFP looks back at key moments in the war.</p>

<p><strong>Hamas attacks</strong></p>

<p>At dawn on October 7, hundreds of Hamas fighters infiltrate Israel.</p>

<p>They kill civilians in the streets, in their homes and at a desert music festival, and attack troops in army bases.</p>

<p>They seize 251 hostages and take them back to Gaza, with 111 still detained including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vows to destroy Hamas, which is considered a terrorist organisation by the United States, European Union and Israel.</p>

<p><strong>North Gaza exodus</strong></p>

<p>Israel begins bombing and besieging Gaza. On October 13, it calls on civilians in northern Gaza to move south ahead of an expected ground offensive.</p>

<p>By the end of July only 14 percent of areas in Gaza were not covered by evacuation orders, the head of the UN's agency for Palestinian refugees says, and the UN reports around 90 percent of Gazans are displaced.</p>

<p><strong>Ground invasion</strong></p>

<p>On October 27, Israel launches a ground offensive.</p>

<p>On November 15, Israeli troops raid Al-Shifa hospital, Gaza's biggest medical facility, where Israel claims Hamas has a command centre, something Hamas denies.</p>

<p><strong>Truce and hostage swap</strong></p>

<p>On November 24, a week-long truce between Israel and Hamas goes into effect.</p>

<p>Hamas releases 80 Israeli hostages in return for 240 Palestinians held in Israeli prisons. Twenty-five other hostages, mainly Thai farm workers, are also set free outside the deal.</p>

<p>Israel allows more aid into Gaza during the pause but the humanitarian situation in the besieged territory remains dire.</p>

<p>When the war resumes, Israel expands its actions into southern Gaza.</p>

<p><strong>Call to prevent 'genocide'</strong></p>

<p>In an interim ruling on January 26 in a case brought by South Africa, the International Court of Justice orders Israel to do "everything" to prevent any acts of genocide.</p>

<p><strong>Deadly food stampede</strong></p>

<p>On February 29, Israeli forces open fire on residents of northern Gaza who rush towards a convoy of food aid trucks, saying they believed they "posed a threat".</p>

<p>Gaza's health ministry says 120 people were shot dead and hundreds wounded, calling it a "massacre".</p>

<p>Israel's military says most of the victims were trampled or run over by the trucks.</p>

<p>From early March several countries, including the United States, drop aid over Gaza which the United Nations says faces famine. A first aid ship from Cyprus arrives on March 15.</p>

<p><strong>Aid workers killed</strong></p>

<p>On April 1, seven aid workers from the US charity World Central Kitchen are killed in an Israeli strike, which the military claims was a "tragic mistake".</p>

<p>Netanyahu repeatedly threatens to send ground troops to Rafah, Gaza's southernmost city where a majority of the territory's 2.4 million people have sought shelter.</p>

<p><strong>Iran attacks Israel</strong></p>

<p>Fears of a regional overspill are stoked on April 13 when Iran pounds Israel with drones and missiles in retaliation for a deadly April 1 strike on Iran's Damascus consulate, blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>On April 19, strikes target central Iran, which plays down the incidents without blaming Israel. Israel does not claim responsibility.</p>

<p><strong>Operations in the south</strong></p>

<p>On May 7, Israel's army launches its offensive on Rafah, where the United Nations says up to 1.4 million are sheltering, and takes control of the border crossing with Egypt effectively blocking a key entry point for aid.</p>

<p>A strike overnight May 26-27 is blamed for starting a fire in a tent camp, killing 45 people, Gaza authorities say. Israel says two senior Hamas operatives were targeted.</p>

<p>During eight days in July, Israel's army targets five schools sheltering displaced people, leaving dozens dead, Hamas and Gaza sources say.</p>

<p>On July 13, a strike near Khan Yunis kills 92, and 70 others perish on July 22, Hamas says.</p>

<p><strong>Regional flare up feared&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Yemen's Iran-backed Huthi rebels who have carried out 90 attacks on shipping in the Gulf since November in solidarity with Gaza claim on July 19 a rare drone attack on Tel Aviv that kills one.</p>

<p>The next day Israel bombards Yemen Huthi-controlled port of Hodeida, causing a huge fire at the strategic facility and killing six, the rebels say.</p>

<p>At the Israeli-Lebanon border, almost daily exchanges of gunfire since October between the Israeli army and the Lebanese Islamist group Hezbollah, intensify in July.</p>

<p>On July 27, a rocket strike kills 12 youths in the Druze Arab town of Majdal Shams in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Israel blames the strike on Hezbollah, which denies the claim.</p>

<p>Israel retaliates with several strikes, including one Tuesday on Beirut's southern suburbs that kills Fuad Shukr, a top Hezbollah commander, the group says, and five civilians.</p>

<p>On July 31, Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh is killed in a strike in Iran. The operation is blamed on Israel, which declines comment.</p>

<p>On August 1, Israel confirms that Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif had been killed in a July strike on Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j3it8c9g_gaza_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At dawn on October 7, hundreds of Hamas fighters infiltrated Israel. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/amazon-ai-microsoft-ai-ai-boom-amazon-set-to-join-big-techs-spending-surge-as-ai-race-heats-up-6240427]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Set To Join Big Tech's Spending Surge As AI Race Heats Up]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/amazon-ai-microsoft-ai-ai-boom-amazon-set-to-join-big-techs-spending-surge-as-ai-race-heats-up-6240427]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:52:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As a result of the spending increase, Amazon's gross profit margin growth is expected to have slowed to 1.3% in the April-June quarter, compared with 2.6% in the previous quarter and an average of 2.7% over the past two years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amazon.com is expected to join Google and Microsoft on Thursday in reporting a surge in capital spending on artificial intelligence as Big Tech companies rush to capitalize on the booming technology.</p>

<p>The e-commerce giant's capital investments - mostly for building cloud and generative AI infrastructure - is expected to have risen 43% in the second quarter to $16.41 billion, according to LSEG data. That represents a roughly $1.5 billion increase from the previous three months.</p>

<p>The steep spending is also expected to pressure Amazon's margins, outweighing benefits from cost cuts and supply chain efficiencies that are aiding the retail unit's profitability.</p>

<p>The company's Amazon Web Services (AWS) business has long dominated the cloud-computing market, but it has been facing tough competition from Microsoft in recent quarters after the Windows maker rolled out AI-powered services to its Azure cloud business.</p>

<p>In response, Amazon has partnered with the likes of Anthropic and offered startups free credits that cover the cost of using major AI models to boost the market share of its AI platform Bedrock. It also named a new head for the AWS unit in May.</p>

<p>Microsoft and Google-parent Alphabet also said earlier this month they would plow ahead with investments even as the payoff from AI takes longer than some investors had hoped. This knocked Big Tech stocks whose valuations have soared this year on the promise of AI.</p>

<p>"Amazon's capex spend will certainly be scrutinized closely. It has been slow on the adoption of AI and is skewed towards smaller companies which have struggled in the high interest-rate environment," said Ben Barringer, analyst at Quilter Cheviot.</p>

<p>"We would expect AWS to start speeding things up in its AI development going forward."</p>

<p>Amazon shares have risen about 23% this year. The stock has shed more than 6% since July 8, when it hit a record, part of a broader market selloff led by U.S. megacaps.</p>

<p>Growth at AWS is likely to have stayed similar to the previous quarter at just over 17%, according to LSEG data. But, Morgan Stanley analysts said: "AWS needs to grow 18%+ in order to ... ensure investors of AWS's (AI) positioning and its ability to generate high-teens growth through this heavy capex investment period."</p>

<p>As a result of the spending increase, Amazon's gross profit margin growth is expected to have slowed to 1.3% in the April-June quarter, compared with 2.6% in the previous quarter and an average of 2.7% over the past two years.</p>

<p>Growth in its North American retail business likely slowed to 8% between April and June, from 12.3% in the January-March quarter, amid signs of a wider slowdown in consumer spending and some competition from new and fast-growing Chinese players such as Temu and Tiktok Shop that are enticing more U.S. shoppers.</p>

<p>Amazon's total revenue is expected to have grown 10.6% to $148.56 billion - the slowest rise in five quarters.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3bueir_amazon-ai-reuters_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Amazon's total revenue is expected to have grown 10.6% to $148.56 billion, slowest rise in five quarters]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-now-hunt-second-largest-whale-species-6240349]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan To Now Hunt Second-Largest Whale Species]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-now-hunt-second-largest-whale-species-6240349]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:42:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan has expanded its commercial whaling to include fin whales, the second-largest animal species on the planet, a decision criticised by Australia's government on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan has expanded its commercial whaling to include fin whales, the second-largest animal species on the planet, a decision criticised by Australia's government on Thursday.</p>

<p>One of only three countries to hunt whales commercially, along with Norway and Iceland, Japan added fin whales to a catch list that already includes minke, Bryde's and sei whales.</p>

<p>"Essentially, our rationale is that there are sufficient resources" of fin whales, a fisheries agency official told AFP on Thursday of the plan to hunt 59 of them this year.</p>

<p>Fin whales are deemed "vulnerable" by the International Union for Conservation of Nature and Japan's decision, mooted by authorities for months but only made official on Wednesday, has alarmed animal rights activists.</p>

<p>Australia is "deeply disappointed", environment minister Tanya Plibersek said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Australia is opposed to all commercial whaling and urges all countries to end this practice," she said.</p>

<p>It comes as international drama surrounds prominent anti-whaling activist Paul Watson, who was arrested in Greenland last month.</p>

<p>Watson, the 73-year-old American-Canadian founder of the activist group Sea Shepherd, was detained under an international arrest warrant issued by Tokyo.</p>

<p>Denmark's justice ministry -- Greenland is an autonomous Danish territory -- said on Thursday that it has received a formal extradition request from Japan for Watson.</p>

<p>He was arrested after docking to refuel in Greenland's capital on the way to "intercept" Japan's new whaling factory vessel in the North Pacific, according to the Captain Paul Watson Foundation.</p>

<p>The Kangei Maru, a 9,300-tonne mothership that set off from Japan in May, processes whales caught by smaller vessels and stores their meat for consumption in Japan.</p>

<p>Japan has hunted whales for centuries and the meat was a key source of protein in the years after World War II.</p>

<p>It carried on hunting whales for "scientific" purposes after an International Whaling Commission (IWC) moratorium on commercial whaling, killing hundreds in the Antarctic and North Pacific.</p>

<p>However, after years of tensions that took a toll on its international reputation, Japan quit the IWC in 2019 and resumed commercial whaling inside its territorial waters and exclusive economic zone.</p>

<p>Japan killed 294 whales last year, a number it says is sustainable.</p>

<p>A panel of experts commissioned by the agriculture ministry said in June that Japanese fishermen should be able to hunt fin whales.</p>

<p>Agriculture minister Tetsushi Sakamoto at the time called whales "an important food resource".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dmcsq1vg_fin-whale-generic_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Japan killed 294 whales last year, a number it says is sustainable. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-rains-30-killed-35-missing-after-torrential-rains-in-china-report-6240108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[30 Killed, 35 Missing After Torrential Rains In China: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-rains-30-killed-35-missing-after-torrential-rains-in-china-report-6240108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:16:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 30 people are dead and 35 are missing in central China, state media reported Thursday, following days of torrential rain that lashed the country earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 30 people are dead and 35 are missing in central China, state media reported Thursday, following days of torrential rain that lashed the country earlier this week.</p>

<p>The downpours were triggered by Typhoon Gaemi, which moved on from the Philippines and Taiwan to make landfall in eastern China a week ago, with hilly, landlocked Hunan province hit particularly hard.</p>

<p>More than 11,000 people had been evacuated from the city of Zixing after some areas endured record rainfall of 645 millimetres (25 inches) in just 24 hours, state news agency Xinhua reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Many roads connecting townships in the Zixing area were temporarily cut off by the extreme weather, which also affected the power supply and communications infrastructure.</p>

<p>On Thursday, state broadcaster CCTV said that "the roads, electricity and communications in eight towns in Zixing city that were most severely affected by Typhoon Gaemi have basically opened".</p>

<p>"Initial findings show that there have been 30 deaths and 35 are missing," the report said, adding that search and rescue efforts were still ongoing.</p>

<p>On Tuesday Xinhua said four people had been killed and three people were missing in Zixing.</p>

<p>Three people were killed in Hunan's Yongxing county, Xinhua said Tuesday, while a landslide on Sunday killed 15 people elsewhere in the province.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/80975gg8_china-rains_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Torrential rain hit China earlier this week]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>