<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:37:47 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-years-of-9-11-attacks-how-a-new-approach-is-needed-now-to-fight-terrorism-6548266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[23 Years Of 9/11 Attacks: How A New Approach Is Needed To Fight Terrorism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-years-of-9-11-attacks-how-a-new-approach-is-needed-now-to-fight-terrorism-6548266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:08:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An effective definition of terrorism is necessary to provide the operational rules of engagement to national security agencies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When members of Al-Qaeda flew commercial jetliners into New York's World Trade Center on September 11, 2001, the idea of who was a terrorist crystallised for the world. But, 23 years on, the reality is there is no one "kind" of terrorist. As security forces around the world grapple with myriad threats from all manner of groups, an essential agreement on who the opponent is becomes crucial.</p>

<p>An effective definition of terrorism is necessary to provide the operational rules of engagement to national security agencies and, at an international level, to facilitate combined efforts based on the shared perspective of peace and war, of friends and enemies, of the threat scenarios.</p>

<h3><strong>Good, evil and the terrorist</strong></h3>

<p>A person is a terrorist because of what they do, not because of what they believe, and for their actions, they are prosecuted.</p>

<p>Discussing terrorism on the theoretical level of &nbsp;"good and evil" is counterproductive and pointless. Even if we all agree that terrorism is the expression of evil, it is not possible to reach an agreement on who the terrorists are.</p>

<p>This is because the category of evil, in today's fragmented world, is understandable only at a local level, difficult to share outside one's cultural boundaries. Evil as a concept depends on cultural perspectives and therefore it cannot lead to a definition of terrorism based on an objective assessment of damages and threats.</p>

<p>Furthermore, in a world of conflict, the same effect can be generated by terrorists, insurgents, freedom fighters, and other groups using violence and doing the same thing, for different reasons, with a different label. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The whole question about the "good or evil" of an action depends on the reasons that motivate that action, so again it is a vague criterion. The acceptance or rejection of actions cannot depend on the value of "good or evil", nor on the reasons that generate them.</p>

<p>So this is one more reason to change how we measure terrorism, forgetting "good and evil", instead focusing on the results of terrorism, banning its effects we cannot accept. Those effects, unlike the ideas that constitute motivations, can be counted and measured. &nbsp;When "an act of terrorism is such because of the effects that the act generates, and not because of the causes that drove it", then the way is open for all to agree to a common counter strategy to terrorism.</p>

<h3><strong>Defining terrorism</strong></h3>

<p>Ten years after 9-11, Alex P. Schmid, Distinguished Fellow at the International Centre for Counter-Terrorism (ICCT) and Director of the Terrorism Research Initiative (TRI), collected the opinions of dozens of experts to arrive at a scientific definition of terrorism for the 21st century.</p>

<p>The result has been a long list of characteristics, among which the objective of "terrorising" is emphasised, identifying communication as a specific element of terrorism, and the use of violence, indiscriminately directed towards "civilian" targets.</p>

<p>This plethora of definitions makes it difficult to come up with a common operational perspective for countering terrorism threats. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Unfortunately, too many definitions of terrorism, refer to the experience around this phenomenon gained in a world that no longer exists.</p>

<p>Italy is a fine example of this.</p>

<h3><strong>A history of violence</strong></h3>

<p>Italy is notorious for the violence it experienced during the last 30 years of the 20th century from groups on the far left, such as the Brigate Rosse (Red Brigades) to those on the far right (Nuclei Armati Rivoluzionari) along with the mafia and other organised crime.</p>

<p>Italy experienced violent political terrorism that wanted to change the state to affirm another idea of the state.</p>

<p>Counterterrorism laws that still address the phenomenon were created based on that experience.</p>

<p>However, today's terrorism no longer has anything to do with the terrorism of that time. So old regulatory tools are still used to regulate a phenomenon that has changed.</p>

<p>This means that for an effective, updated response to terrorism, we have to go back to identifying the phenomenon as it appears today, asking the basic question: "What is terrorism?".</p>

<p>In recent years, terrorism has proven to be flexible, adaptable and opportunistic. It is very skilled in exploiting an enemy's vulnerabilities and from this ability it gains strength.</p>

<p>Europol, in the TE-SAT Terrorism Situation and Trend Report 2023, lists current terrorism types and dangerous groups, and warns that "the lines between different types of terrorism, including right-wing, left-wing, anarchist, jihadist, and other ideologies, are likely to become more blurred in the future".</p>

<p>Europol unlights that points of convergence have already been observed among terrorist and violent extremists across the whole ideological spectrum.</p>

<h3><strong>Salad Bar terrorism</strong></h3>

<p>Ideologically today one can talk about Salad Bar terrorism (or Mixed Ideology terrorism), where the ideological dimension is present, but it is articulated according to a personal taste, to justify the choice of violent affirmation of one's ideas.</p>

<p>Yet, the actual reasons for terrorism can be found in terrorism itself as a choice and action. They lie in the conviction terrorists have that only violence can change a situation already irrecoverable, urgent, and dramatic. The personalised ideology terrorists create for themselves is the justification for the terrorist action and not the real motivation.</p>

<p>In this framework, recruitment and propaganda are strategic pieces of the ideological puzzle: ideas are to be reassembled according to a flexible and adaptable image that constitutes the scenario in which the terrorist's violence will be expressed. &nbsp;</p>

<p>This fragmentation is the main feature of terrorism affecting young people's identities (since young people are the main victims of terrorist propaganda and recruitment). &nbsp;A fragmentation where geographical, political and cultural borders are no longer useful, reorganised by the global network of communication technologies. &nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>More than ideology</strong></h3>

<p>The first challenge that comes out is the need to reconsider the meaning of nation and state.</p>

<p>The paths that can lead to terrorism are many and this is why the definition of terrorism based on reasons and motivations does not work: the unpredictable Salad Bar Ideology offers many ways to become a terrorist. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Ideologies no longer provide sufficient analytical categories to identify and, subsequently, prevent threats effectively. The reasons that drive radicalization today are multiple and come from various inputs. &nbsp;</p>

<p>A good example of the failure to adequately address terrorism today is the numerous tools developed by law enforcement to identify potential terrorists are the so-called Terrorist Risk Assessment Instruments. &nbsp;</p>

<p>All these have, so far, led to poor results, because they are based on the wrong assumptions of continuity, linearity, and ideal coherence, while today's Salad Bar Terrorism offers a circular route, rapid and unpredictable, always original for everyone. &nbsp;</p>

<p>For example, the Australian Institute of Criminology recently released a report on the use of four risk assessment tools designed to gauge the threat posed by radicalised offenders and, in some cases, justify them being held behind bars or closely supervised after their sentences have been served. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The AIC report found there was a "relative lack of research into the efficacy of these tools", something it found was a "barrier to their use and undermines confidence in expert assessments that rely on these tools".</p>

<p>There are often no credible signs to identify the "typical terrorist" until it is too late.</p>

<p>Today, a more effective method for identifying a potential terrorist risk could be adopting a so-called "Digital Humint" approach, which analyses both the "real" and "virtual" dimensions together, exploring not only the network of offline relationships and habits but also the social media ecosystem and chat rooms.</p>

<h2><strong>A new approach</strong></h2>

<p>A new approach, abandoning the ideological dimension as a founding dimension of terrorism is pivotal and it means "an act of terrorism is such for the effects that this act generates, not for the causes that drove it". &nbsp;</p>

<p>This approach is not just backed up by the previous empirical results and failures of counterterrorism efforts. It also has a theoretical foundation from the field of crisis management, where a crisis is defined as an event whose effects are not controlled by a system. &nbsp;</p>

<p>It also has a practical basis, in seeking an agreement on "what terrorism is" by referring to the effects, to the damage caused, for which an objective assessment can be agreed. &nbsp;This is in total alignment with the needs of the criminal justice system and legal framework.</p>

<p>In the EU, terrorism is defined by its aims to: "a) seriously intimidating a population; b) unduly compelling a government or an international organisation to perform or abstain from performing any act; c) seriously destabilising or destroying the fundamental political, constitutional, economic or social structures of a country or an international organisation", without any reference to a typology of ideological motivations.</p>

<p>Terrorism is no longer what it used to be, but those who fight terrorism have not realised this. Bold decisions have to be made to abandon obsolete approaches and tools that cannot deliver any more results. &nbsp;</p>

<p>What worked 50 years ago to fight terrorism in the 70s and 80s is irrelevant today, because contemporary terrorism bears little resemblance to its previous expressions. After all, human society has changed.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-09/cr9ec66o_9-11-world-trade-center-attack-anniversary_625x300_11_September_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Members of Al-Qaeda flew commercial jetliners into New York's World Trade Center on September 11, 2001]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-cia-agent-who-spied-for-china-jailed-for-10-years-6548256]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-CIA Agent, Who Spied For China, Jailed For 10 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-cia-agent-who-spied-for-china-jailed-for-10-years-6548256]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:06:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) officer, was sentenced to 10 years in prison for spying for the Chinese government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) officer, was sentenced to 10 years in prison for spying for the Chinese government.</p>

<p>Alexander Yuk Ching Ma, 71, of Honolulu, was arrested in August 2020 after admitting to an undercover FBI agent that he sold US secrets to China, the US Department of Justice said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>He admitted that he had facilitated the provision of classified information to intelligence officers employed by China's Shanghai State Security Bureau (SSSB).</p>

<p>Ma has been sentenced to 10 years in prison followed by five years of supervised release announced Assistant Attorney General Matthew G Olsen of the Justice Department's National Security Division, US Attorney Clare E Connors for the District of Hawaii and Executive Assistant Director Robert Wells of the FBI's National Security Branch.</p>

<p>According to court documents, Ma, a US citizen born in Hong Kong worked for the CIA from 1982 until 1989.</p>

<p>Officials said Ma collaborated with a relative who is now deceased, and who worked for the CIA from 1967 until 1983.</p>

<p>As CIA officers, both Ma and his relative held top secret security clearances that granted them access to sensitive and classified CIA information, and both signed non-disclosure agreements, officials said.</p>

<p>Ma admitted in the plea agreement, in March 2001, over a decade after he resigned from the CIA, that he was contacted by SSSB intelligence officers, who asked him Ma to arrange a meeting between his relative and the SSSB.</p>

<p>During the meetings that were held in a Hong Kong hotel room for three days, Ma's relative provided the SSSB with a large volume of classified US information in return for USD 50,000 in cash.</p>

<p>In March, while living in Hawaii, Ma took up a job as a contract linguist in the FBI's Honolulu Field Office.</p>

<p>"The FBI, aware of Ma's ties to PRC intelligence, hired Ma as part of a ruse to monitor and investigate his activities and contacts with the SSSB," prosecutors said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Ma, they said worked part-time at an offsite location for the FBI from August 2004 until October 2012.</p>

<p>Under the terms of the plea agreement, Ma must cooperate with the United States for the rest of his life, including by submitting to debriefings by US government agencies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/aoq7hlb8_alexander-yuk-ching-ma_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alexander Yuk Ching Ma was arrested in August 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-benjamin-netanyahu-chooses-war-over-peace-6548163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Netanyahu Chooses War Over Peace]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-benjamin-netanyahu-chooses-war-over-peace-6548163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:50:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As protests grow, Benjamin Netanyahu clings to power in what appears to be a gambit to shape his own political and legal future, regardless of the cost.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As protests grow, Benjamin Netanyahu clings to power in what appears to be a gambit to shape his own political and legal future, regardless of the cost.</p>

<p>War-weary and angry, hundreds of thousands of Israelis are taking to the streets week after week, calling for Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to cut a deal and bring the remaining hostages from the October 7 Hamas attack home.</p>

<p>Their calls remain unanswered.</p>

<p>These massive public demonstrations, including the largest nationwide strike in 18 months, are met with renewed conditions for any deal with Hamas and commitments to continuing the war into its second year.</p>

<p>Despite the more than 750,000 protesters calling for his resignation and an end to the war, clinging to power and continuing the fight against Hamas appears to be Netanyahu's only plan for the future. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>What started the protests?</strong></h3>

<p>The protests began after another six Israeli hostages were found dead in Gaza at the beginning of September. &nbsp;</p>

<p>A key demand of the protesters has been for Netanyahu to sign a ceasefire with Hamas that would see the release of the remaining Israelis still held captive since the October 7, 2023 attacks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite increasing public dissent, Netanyahu has refused to sign any ceasefire and continues to add new conditions to any potential deal. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The latest sticking point is Israel's insistence that it retain a permanent military presence in the Philadelphi Corridor - a strip of land on the border between the Gaza Strip and Egypt.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hamas refuses to accept any such stipulation, arguing that all Israeli troops should evacuate the Gaza Strip.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Egypt has also expressed its concern at the prospect of Israeli troops stationed on its border, &nbsp;amid concerns of miscalculation from either Egyptian or Israeli troops.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Adding to the public pressure on Netanyahu is the political pressure from both inside and outside of his ruling coalition.</p>

<p>Externally, his political rivals accuse Netanyahu of lying to the Israeli public and for putting his political survival ahead of any deal to bring the hostages home.</p>

<p>Inside his coalition, there is more pressure to continue the war until all vestiges of Hamas are destroyed and the Palestinians are pacified.</p>

<p>While commentators speculate on how long Netanyahu can survive, perhaps the more relevant question is how he got here in the first place.</p>

<h3><strong>Netanyahu's narrow window</strong></h3>

<p>The root cause of Netanyahu's current dilemma is a series of 2016 allegations of corruption. &nbsp;Subsequent police investigations led to Netanyahu being charged in 2019 with breach of trust, accepting bribes, and fraud.</p>

<p>Since the allegations became public, Netanyahu has tried &nbsp;various political manoeuvres to avoid fronting court and a potential guilty verdict and likely jail sentence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Initially, these involved using parliamentary procedures to impede the judicial process. &nbsp;This included the Attorney General being accused of interfering in the investigation and deliberately delaying the indictment, as well as Netanyahu seeking immunity from prosecution from the Israeli Parliament, the Knesset.</p>

<p>When these efforts failed, Netanyahu's trial began in May 2020. &nbsp;Then, in March 2021, Netanyahu lost the election and the prime ministership, leaving him without any institutional protection - something he covets.</p>

<p>After another inconclusive election in November 2022 Netanyahu made a Faustian bargain with several right-wing nationalist parties to regain the prime ministership. &nbsp;In return for entering his coalition, Netanyahu agreed to pursue the nationalists' political agenda. &nbsp;</p>

<p>One of his government's first acts was to try and enact sweeping judicial reforms that would give the government oversight of Israel's Supreme Court. &nbsp;These reforms could benefit both Netanyahu and his coalition partners.</p>

<h3><strong>Political bargain offers no way out</strong></h3>

<p>Because Israel has just one parliamentary house, the Supreme Court acts as a check and balance on the Knesset's power. &nbsp;The government's intention to ensure it always had a majority on the committee that appoints judges was of particular concern to many Israelis. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Opponents feared these reforms could give Netanyahu the power to appoint sympathetic judges to the Supreme Court and potentially gain immunity from prosecution.</p>

<p>For the nationalists, the proposed reforms would remove many of the institutional checks and balances imposed by the Supreme Court on the expansion of Israeli settlements and the appropriation of Palestinian land in the West Bank - something &nbsp;Israeli nationalists have wanted for years. &nbsp;</p>

<p>If successful, it would mean Israel's 57-year occupation of the West Bank and East Jerusalem would become permanent, sounding the death knell for any future Palestinian state, something that did not go unnoticed by Hamas.</p>

<p>The proposed reforms provoked unprecedented public backlash, with massive weekly protests racking Israel from January to October 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was only when Hamas attacked on October 7 that Netanyahu's government gained some reprieve. &nbsp;</p>

<p>But the attacks posed an additional problem for Netanyahu because they were a massive security failure that resulted in the &nbsp;largest loss of Jewish lives since the Holocaust.</p>

<p>Throughout his political career, Netanyahu has always portrayed himself as being the only politician capable of ensuring the safety and security of Jews and the state of Israel. &nbsp;</p>

<p>This includes refusing to accept the possibility of a Palestinian state, which he deems an existential security threat to Israel. &nbsp;The fact that Netanyahu presided over this massive security failure strikes at the core of his political popularity.</p>

<p>This made him vulnerable politically and increasingly beholden to his coalition partners to remain in power.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If any of these parties left the coalition, it would no longer hold a majority in the Knesset, meaning fresh elections that, &nbsp;given the current political climate, Netanyahu could conceivably lose. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Unable to influence the political and judicial process, Netanyahu would find himself at the mercy of the justice system he sought to undermine. &nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Clinging to power</strong></h3>

<p>Consequently, Netanyahu is determined to do whatever is necessary to remain in power. &nbsp;</p>

<p>This means acceding to the nationalists' demands by advocating for negotiation positions he knows Hamas will reject.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite mounting political pressure, the government's dogmatic approach to negotiations gives the nationalists time to pursue their ideological objectives by altering irrevocably the face of the West Bank and East Jerusalem. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>Since the Hamas attacks, there has been an explosion of Israeli settler outposts throughout the West Bank appropriating Palestinian land.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Israeli military has also recently launched the largest military incursion in the West Bank since October 2023. &nbsp;In addition to the more than 41,000 Palestinians killed in Gaza, more than &nbsp;650 Palestinians have been killed in the West Bank.</p>

<p>While Israel claims it is combating terrorism, the ultimate purpose of these actions, alongside Israel's actions in Gaza, appears to be to crush any organised Palestinian resistance to Israeli occupation and its appropriation of Palestinian land. &nbsp;</p>

<p>If successful, the nationalists' dream of a wholly Jewish state from the river to the sea would be closer than ever. &nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Dr Martin Kear is a lecturer in terrorism and international security at The University of Sydney. His research interests include Middle East politics, the political/electoral participation of Islamist movements, and the role of political violence in the organisational narratives of militant movements.</em></p>

<p><em>(Originally published under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons</a> by <a href="https://360info.org/">360info</a>)</em></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/ti4cukkg_netanyahu-israel-protests_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A key demand of the protesters has been for Netanyahu to sign a ceasefire with Hamas (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-charged-with-drugging-and-assaulting-multiple-women-from-sugar-daddy-dating-sites-6547890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Charged For Secretly Drugging And Assaulting Women He Met Online]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-charged-with-drugging-and-assaulting-multiple-women-from-sugar-daddy-dating-sites-6547890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:17:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 40-year-old New York resident is facing serious charges after allegedly drugging and sexually assaulting women he met through an online sugar daddy' website.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A 40-year-old New York resident is facing serious charges after allegedly drugging and sexually assaulting women he met through an online ‘sugar daddy' website. Andrew J Gallo was arrested on Wednesday and charged with rape by causing impairment, strangulation, drug and alcohol offenses and corruption of minors, reported <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/man-charged-drugging-raping-women-met-sugar-daddy-113601790 ">ABC</a> News. He is currently being held on $500,000 cash bail following his arraignment.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Gallo is accused of drugging at least six women, ages 17 to 30, over the past 15 months. The investigation revealed that Gallo, using the alias “DREWSTER420” on SugarDaddiesMeet.com, laced his victims' drinks with drugs such as methamphetamine, ecstasy and cocaine. Gallo gave his victims alcohol mixed with these substances, leaving them immobile and unable to resist his advances.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Prosecutors revealed that the victims experienced a lack of control during the assaults, with Bucks County District Attorney Jen Schorn noting that Gallo's actions rendered the women so impaired that they were unable to consent to sexual acts.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">One of the earliest known incidents occurred on Christmas Eve last year, when a 24-year-old New Jersey woman met Gallo for dinner. She reported that after drinking a margarita Gallo prepared, she felt unusually disoriented and feared that if she fell asleep, she might not wake up. Authorities believe the drink was laced with methamphetamine, reported the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2024/09/11/andrew-gallo-pennsylvania-drug/ ">Washington Post</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Gallo also allegedly strangled some women until they nearly or completely passed out.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Gallo faces five counts of rape by causing impairment, six counts of drug possession, and four counts of strangulation. Other charges include corrupting and furnishing alcohol to minors.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Reports indicated that the drugs caused extreme effects, including hallucinations and staying awake for long hours. Some of the victims had to seek medical attention after spending time at his home.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Authorities are actively seeking other potential victims who may have met Gallo. As of now, Gallo does not have a listed attorney, and no legal representation appeared during his arraignment.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/011stb1o_andrew-gallo-_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andrew Gallo is accused of drugging at least six women, ages 17 to 30, over the past 15 months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/van-goghs-sunflowers-series-exhibited-side-by-side-in-london-show-6547687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Van Gogh's 'Sunflowers' Series Exhibited Side By Side In London Show]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/van-goghs-sunflowers-series-exhibited-side-by-side-in-london-show-6547687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:45:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A hundred years after acquiring one of Vincent van Gogh's "Sunflowers", Britain's National Gallery in London will bring his vision to life by showcasing three works side-by-side for the first time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A hundred years after acquiring one of Vincent van Gogh's "Sunflowers", Britain's National Gallery in London will bring his vision to life by showcasing three works side-by-side for the first time.</p>

<p>The triptych, which features two from his sunflower series, forms part of a major exhibition dedicated to the Dutch painter and titled "Van Gogh: Poets and Lovers".</p>

<p>The exhibit focuses on the post-impressionist's output during the two years that he spent in the south of France, in Arles and Saint-Remy de Provence, between February 1888 and May 1890.</p>

<p>"His art takes on a new amplitude, a&nbsp;new inventiveness, everything emerges from it," exhibition co-curator Christopher Riopelle told AFP of the period in Van Gogh's life.</p>

<p>"He becomes ever braver and bolder in how he paints, new freedom, new rhythms that enter in," Riopelle added.</p>

<p>The exhibition brings together some fifty paintings and drawings, which testify to Van Gogh's talent for raising emotions thanks to his subtle and intense use of colours.</p>

<p>Many are already well-known masterpieces, such as "Starry Night," but some had never left their original private collections or museums.</p>

<p>In a room with yellow walls, three paintings are notably exhibited: two "Sunflowers", one belonging to the National Gallery since 1924, and the other specially loaned by the Washington museum.</p>

<p>They surround "The Lullaby", a painting representing a woman, seated on an armchair.</p>

<p>"At a certain moment in beginning of 1889 he had five or six of these pictures in his studio, and he began to think, how do I want to show them?" Riopelle explained.</p>

<p>"And he had this wonderful idea that he should flank a 'Sunflowers' with a yellow background, with a 'Sunflowers' with a blue background.</p>

<p>"And in the middle, he should have "La Berceuse" (The Lullaby)... and that the three pictures together would comfort sailors at sea."</p>

<p>Riopelle added that Van Gogh's intention, as explained in letters to his brother Theo, would represent "something consoling in life".</p>

<p>This is the first time that the works have been exhibited together in this way.</p>

<p>Predictably, nature and the landscapes of the south of France are at the heart of the works arousing feelings in the viewer.</p>

<p>He saw this productive period in southern France as "a chance to make a mark," said Cornelia Homburg, co-curator of the exhibition, stressing that the exhibition strives to "be respectful" of Van Gogh's "artistic ambitions".</p>

<p>There is a series on olive trees, another on the mountains around Saint-Remy de Provence, and also the gardens of a psychiatric institution in the same city, where Van Gogh stayed for several months.</p>

<p>"He was not just a person tormented and suffering all of that," concluded Riopelle.</p>

<p>"He was a person deeply committed to the beauty of nature, deeply committed to friends and family and deeply committed to establishing a career as an Avant-Garde artist."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/i3qa3df_vincent-van-goghs-sunflowers-_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The exhibit focuses on the postimpressionist's output during the 2 years he spent in the south of France]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-origin-israeli-soldier-killed-in-car-attack-in-west-bank-6547686]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Israeli Soldier Killed In Car Attack In West Bank]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-origin-israeli-soldier-killed-in-car-attack-in-west-bank-6547686]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:44:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 24-year-old Indian-origin Israeli soldier from the Bnei Menashe community was killed in a vehicle-ramming attack close to the West Bank's Beit El settlement, community members said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 24-year-old Indian-origin Israeli soldier from the Bnei Menashe community was killed in a vehicle-ramming attack close to the West Bank's Beit El settlement, community members said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Staff Sergeant Geri Gideon Hanghal was a resident of Nof HaGalil and a soldier in the Kfir Brigade's Nahshon Battalion, the Israeli Army said.</p>

<p>Community members told PTI that they were "in shock at the news of the loss of a young life" on Wednesday near Asaf Junction.</p>

<p>His funeral will be held on Thursday, they said.</p>

<p>Hanghal immigrated to Israel from northeast India in 2020.</p>

<p>Some 300 Bnei Menashe youngsters are said to be doing Army duty during the current war, most of them serving in combat units.</p>

<p>The Bnei Menashe, hailing from India's north-eastern states of Manipur and Mizoram, are believed to have descended from the Israelite tribe of Menasseh, one of the "lost tribes" of ancient times.</p>

<p>Shlomo Amar, Sephardic Chief Rabbi, declared them descendants of Menasseh in 2005 paving the path for their immigration to Israel as members of a "lost tribe".</p>

<p>Some 5,000 members of the Bnei Menashe community are said to have immigrated to Israel, including almost 1,500 in the past five years. Another 5,500 still live in India and are waiting to immigrate.</p>

<p>Nof HaGalil Mayor, Ronen Plot, was quoted by Ynetnews as saying that "the city of Nof HaGalil mourns and grieves the loss of Staff Sgt. Hanghal. Gideon was a member of the Bnei Menashe community, which is very dear to my heart-good, humble and patriotic people".</p>

<p>Footage from the scene of the attack showed a truck with a Palestinian license plate veering off a busy highway and barrel full speed into an Israel Defence Forces (IDF) guard post adjacent to a bus stop before coming to a halt.</p>

<p>The suspect was named by Israeli security sources as 58-year-old Hayil Dhaifallah, from the central West Bank town of Rafat.</p>

<p>The attack follows a series of attempted suicide bombings and shooting incidents emanating from the West Bank and claimed by Islamic Hamas.</p>

<p>Hamas on October 7 last year launched a dastardly attack on Israel, leading to the ongoing war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel has said that it is stepping up its counter-terrorism operations in the West Bank claiming that Iran-backed groups are smuggling weapons into the area from Jordan and trying to carry out attacks in Israeli territory.</p>

<p>The Palestinian health ministry in the West Bank on Wednesday said that five Palestinians were killed in an Israeli airstrike in Tubas overnight.</p>

<p>Another two people were injured by Israeli fire, one critically, as troops raided Tubas and the neighbouring town of Tammun, Palestinian state agency Wafa reported.</p>

<p>IDF confirmed the airstrikes, once a rare occurrence in the West Bank, saying it targeted members of a terror cell.</p>

<p>The IDF has carried out more than 70 airstrikes in the West Bank since October 7, using drones, attack helicopters, and fighter jets.</p>

<p>Local media reports have been eluding that the Israeli defence brass is increasingly worried that the violence in the West Bank could swell into a major conflagration.</p>

<p>The spiralling violence has also been fuelled by hardline Israeli settlers in the central and northern West Bank who have carried out several attacks on Palestinians in recent weeks, including a fiery rampage on a village last month in which a Palestinian man was killed while trying to confront the rioters.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Authority (PA) health ministry has claimed that more than 670 Palestinians have been killed by Israel in the West Bank, which is under the PA control, since October 7.</p>

<p>The IDF has said that the vast majority of those dead were gunmen killed in exchanges of fire, rioters who clashed with troops, or terrorists carrying out attacks.</p>

<p>Israel is said to have also arrested some 5,000 wanted Palestinians across the West Bank over the last eleven months, including more than 2,000 said to be linked to Hamas.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sctp0rno_indianorigin-idf-soldier-_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hanghal immigrated to Israel from the northeastern part of India in 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jon-bon-jovi-saw-a-woman-trying-to-jump-off-a-bridge-what-happened-next-6547402]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jon Bon Jovi Saw A Woman Trying To Jump Off A Bridge. What Happened Next]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jon-bon-jovi-saw-a-woman-trying-to-jump-off-a-bridge-what-happened-next-6547402]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:08:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Singer Jon Bon Jovi and his team were on a bridge in Tennessee when they saw a woman holding onto the railing while standing on the ledge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Rock legend Jon Bon Jovi has been praised on social media for his heroic actions in helping a woman in distress who was standing on the ledge of a bridge in Nashville, in the US state of Tennessee, on Tuesday night. According to the Metropolitan Nashville Police Department, Bon Jovi, 62, and his team were on the John Seigenthaler Pedestrian Bridge when they noticed the woman standing precariously over the Cumberland River.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">A video released by police shows the woman holding onto the railing while standing on the ledge, before Bon Jovi and another woman approach her. The singer can be seen waving hello and leaning on the railing near her, helping to calm her down. They successfully coaxed her back onto the bridge, preventing a potential tragedy. The rescue was met with relief as Bon Jovi and the other woman embraced the woman in a hug.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NEW: Singer Jon Bon Jovi saves a woman from jumping off a bridge in Nashville, Tennessee while filming a music video.<br />
<br />
Good man.<br />
<br />
Bon Jovi was seen approaching a 62-year-old woman on the John Seigenthaler Pedestrian Bridge.<br />
<br />
The musician leaned over the railing before… <a href="https://t.co/msyGSU3hQW">pic.twitter.com/msyGSU3hQW</a></p>
— Collin Rugg (@CollinRugg) <a href="https://twitter.com/CollinRugg/status/1833998933087191366?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Chief John Drake of the Nashville Police praised Bon Jovi's actions, stating, “It takes all of us to help keep each other safe.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A shout out to <a href="https://twitter.com/jonbonjovi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@jonbonjovi</a> &amp; his team for helping a woman on the Seigenthaler Ped Bridge Tue night. Bon Jovi helped persuade her to come off the ledge over the Cumberland River to safety. "It takes all of us to help keep each other safe,"--Chief John Drake <a href="https://t.co/1YejKJ2WgM">https://t.co/1YejKJ2WgM</a></p>
— Metro Nashville PD (@MNPDNashville) <a href="https://twitter.com/MNPDNashville/status/1833970989354348832?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">The internet has been quick to hail him as a “hero”.</p>

<p dir="ltr">A user wrote on X (formerly Twitter), “Jon Bon Jovi greatest rock star in the world and now hero.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Jon Bon Jovi greatest rock star in the world and now hero. <a href="https://twitter.com/BonJovi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BonJovi</a>.</p>
— Carmine Sabia (@CarmineSabia) <a href="https://twitter.com/CarmineSabia/status/1834019954749788187?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Another commented, “Legend says he said 'Take my hand, we'll make it, I swear',” – a reference to the lyrics from Bon Jovi's hit song&nbsp;<em>Livin' on a Prayer.</em></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Legend says he said “Take my hand, we'll make it, I swear”</p>
— Kendra???? (@Itzkendraa_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Itzkendraa_/status/1834065135322685947?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">This user referred to another one of the Rock legend's hit songs in a comment. “This is awesome. He probably said '<em>I'll be there for you' </em>to get her to come back to safety,” the comment read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is awesome. He probably said “I'll be there for you” to get her to come back to safety</p>
— Chris (@bsting54) <a href="https://twitter.com/bsting54/status/1834006274838593767?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">The incident occurred while Bon Jovi was in Nashville shooting a music video on the bridge. Separate footage posted on social media showed the singer and his team setting up camera equipment in the area, as per BBC.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/l8tukc48_jon-bon-jovi_625x300_12_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bon Jovi was in Nashville shooting a music video on the bridge]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-polaris-dawn-crew-to-make-history-with-first-ever-private-spacewalk-6547350]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Polaris Dawn Crew To Make History With First-Ever Private Spacewalk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-polaris-dawn-crew-to-make-history-with-first-ever-private-spacewalk-6547350]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:56:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After trekking deeper into space than any humans in the last half-century, a pioneering private crew is set to make history Thursday with the first-ever spacewalk by non-professional astronauts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After trekking deeper into space than any humans in the last half-century, a pioneering private crew is set to make history Thursday with the first-ever spacewalk by non-professional astronauts.</p>

<p>The SpaceX Polaris Dawn mission, led by fintech billionaire Jared Isaacman, launched early Tuesday from the Kennedy Space Center in Florida, reaching a peak altitude of 870 miles (1,400 kilometres).</p>

<p>That's more than three times higher than the International Space Station, in a region of space called the inner Van Allen radiation belt -- a zone teeming with dangerous, high-energy particles.</p>

<p>Now, with their Dragon spaceship's elliptical orbit reduced to a low point of roughly 120 miles and a high of 430 miles, the crew of four is gearing up for the mission's centrepiece: an audacious extravehicular activity (EVA) scheduled for 0958 GMT on Thursday, with a backup window on Friday.</p>

<p>SpaceX pushed the time back by a few hours early Thursday, without explaining why. It plans a webcast of the event starting about an hour beforehand, on its website.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>'Bit of a dance'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Prior to the hatch opening, the crew will complete a "pre-breathe" process to purge nitrogen from their blood, preventing decompression sickness caused by nitrogen bubbles. The cabin pressure will then be gradually reduced to match that of space.</p>

<p>After it's opened, Isaacman and crewmate Sarah Gillis, a SpaceX engineer, will take turns peeking out from a structure attached to the hatch dubbed "Skywalker," equipped with hand and footholds.</p>

<p>"It'll look like we're doing a little bit of a dance," Isaacman quipped during a recent press conference.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In reality, they're stress-testing SpaceX's next-generation suits, which boast heads-up displays, helmet cameras and enhanced joint mobility systems.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, they won't float away on a tether like early spacefarers such as Soviet cosmonaut Alexei Leonov or NASA's Ed White did in 1965. Instead, they'll cling to the spacecraft as it orbits Earth at roughly 17,500 mph.</p>

<p>Since the Crew Dragon capsule lacks an airlock, the entire crew will be exposed to the vacuum of space for the duration of the spacewalk, around two hours. After the hatch is closed, the cabin will be repressurized, and oxygen and nitrogen levels will return to normal.</p>

<p>Mission pilot Scott Poteet and SpaceX engineer Anna Menon will monitor vital support systems during the activity, while Isaacman and Gillis are expected to each spend about 15 to 20 minutes partially outside the craft.</p>

<p>"The risk is greater than zero, that's for sure, and it's certainly higher than anything that has been accomplished on a commercial basis," former NASA administrator Sean O'Keefe told AFP.</p>

<p>"This is another watershed event in the march toward commercialization of space for transportation," he added, comparing the crewmates to early aviators who paved the way for modern air travel.</p>

<h3><strong>First of three Polaris missions&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>All four underwent more than two years of training in preparation for the landmark mission, logging hundreds of hours on simulators as well as skydiving, centrifuge training, scuba diving and summiting an Ecuadoran volcano.</p>

<p>Beyond their spacewalk, the crew will test laser-based satellite communications between the spacecraft and the vast Starlink satellite constellation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They'll also carry out 36 scientific experiments, including tests on contact lenses with embedded microelectronics to monitor changes in eye pressure and shape in space.</p>

<p>Polaris Dawn is the first of three missions under the Polaris program, a collaboration between Isaacman and SpaceX.</p>

<p>Financial terms of the partnership remain under wraps, but Isaacman, the 41-year-old founder and CEO of Shift4Payments, reportedly poured $200 million of his fortune into leading the 2021 all-civilian SpaceX Inspiration4 orbital mission.</p>

<p>The final Polaris mission aims to be the first crewed flight of SpaceX's Starship, a prototype next-generation rocket that is key to founder Elon Musk's ambitions of colonizing Mars.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qhfj6sbo_space-x-polaris-dawn-_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The SpaceX Polaris Dawn mission launched early Tuesday from the Kennedy Space Center in Florida.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-warm-hug-with-new-zealand-womens-rugby-team-6547128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles' Warm Hug With New Zealand Women's Rugby Team]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-warm-hug-with-new-zealand-womens-rugby-team-6547128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:25:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles shared a joyful moment with the New Zealand women's rugby union team at Buckingham Palace, where he exchanged hugs with the Black Ferns.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>King Charles shared a joyful moment with the New Zealand women's rugby union team at Buckingham Palace, where he exchanged hugs with the Black Ferns.</p>

<p>The rugby team also clicked a selfie with King Charles, in a memorable moment shared by the Black Ferns on social media.</p>

<p>It was New Zealand's winger Ayesha Leti-I'iga who broke the protocol and asked the King if he was okay to share hugs with the Black Ferns. To which King Charles did not waste any time and immediately agreed to it.</p>

<p>"We all wanted a hug, but only if it's okay with you," Leti-I'iga asked politely.</p>

<p>"A hug? Why not?" King Charles replied.</p>

<p>Currently, The Black Ferns are in the UK to take on England's Red Roses on Saturday at Twickenham.</p>

<p>Ahead of the match, Buckingham Palace hosted the New Zealand women's rugby union team to honour the visiting players.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_ydOX_PBoE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_ydOX_PBoE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_ydOX_PBoE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_ydOX_PBoE/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Black Ferns (@blackferns)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, The Royal Family announced that the King and Queen will travel to Australia and Samoa from October 18 to 26.</p>

<p>"Their Majesties The King and Queen will undertake an Autumn Tour from Friday 18th - Saturday 26th October 2024. This will include a Royal Visit to Australia, State Visit to The Independent State of Samoa and attendance at the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting (CHOGM) 2024," The Royal Family stated in a statement.</p>

<p>King Charles will also attend the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting (CHOGM) which will take place in Samoa.</p>

<p>"The King's visit to Australia will be His Majesty's first to a Realm as Monarch, whilst the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting in Samoa is the first The King will attend as Head of the Commonwealth. In both countries, Their Majesties' engagements will focus on themes designed to celebrate the best of Australia and Samoa, as well as reflecting aspects of The King and Queen's work," it added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/aujpbl7_king-charles-with-rugby-team_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rugby team also clicked a selfie with King Charles.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pwc-to-cut-1-800-us-jobs-in-first-major-layoffs-since-2009-6547009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PricewaterhouseCoopers Fires 1,800 Employees In 1st Major Layoff Since 2009]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pwc-to-cut-1-800-us-jobs-in-first-major-layoffs-since-2009-6547009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:21:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) is set to lay off approximately 1,800 employees in the United States, marking its first major round of layoffs since 2009.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) is set to lay off approximately 1,800 employees in the United States, marking its first major round of layoffs since 2009. The job cuts, affecting about 2.5 per cent of the US workforce, span various roles, from associates to managing directors, and include business services, audit and tax. The cuts are primarily focused on the US advisory and products and technology operations, with about half of the affected employees based offshore.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The restructuring, which includes significant changes to its technology group, comes as the firm faces a slowdown in demand for parts of its advisory services.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">PwC US leader Paul Griggs announced the restructuring and layoffs to staff in a memo, obtained by the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/pwc-laying-off-1-800-employees-plans-restructuring-of-products-business-b5dfe7c1?mod=latest_headlines ">Wall Street Journal</a>, stating that the firm is “positioning our firm for the future, creating capacity to invest, and anticipating and reacting to the market opportunities of today and tomorrow.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">The announcement, made on September 11, also acknowledged the sombre anniversary of the firm's loss of five colleagues in the 2001 attacks.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">This development marks a significant shift for PwC, which had avoided layoffs in the US since 2009, unlike its peers Ernst &amp; Young (EY), Klynveld Peat Marwick Goerdeler (KPMG) and Deloitte.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The restructuring will see PwC's products and technology teams more deeply integrated into individual business lines. The changes come as part of a broader structural overhaul initiated by Paul Griggs, who took over as US leader in May.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Tim Grady, PwC's US chief operating officer (COO), said, “To remain competitive and position our business for the future, we are continuing to transform areas of our firm and are aligning our workforce to better support our strategy,” as per the WSJ report.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, PwC's China office is also facing a crisis after losing a major client, Country Garden Holdings. This loss comes amid scrutiny over PwC's role in auditing China Evergrande Group, which is accused of a $78 billion fraud, Reuters reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr">As a result, PwC China has implemented cost-cutting measures and layoffs. Reuters reported on September 5 that over 50 Chinese firms, including Bank of China, have dropped PwC as their auditor or scrapped plans to rehire it.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Country Garden cited PwC's failure to meet the deadline for publishing its audited 2023 financial statements as the reason for its decision.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/vcjo7f5o_job-generic-_625x300_20_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PwC US leader Paul Griggs announced the restructuring and layoffs to staff in a memo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-to-have-new-privacy-laws-to-prohibit-doxxing-6546879]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian To Have New Privacy Laws To Prohibit Doxxing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-to-have-new-privacy-laws-to-prohibit-doxxing-6546879]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 11:49:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The act of doxxing by releasing someone's personal information without consent will be made a criminal offence in Australia under new government privacy laws.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The act of doxxing by releasing someone's personal information without consent will be made a criminal offence in Australia under new government privacy laws.</p>

<p>Mark Dreyfus, Australia's Attorney-General, on Thursday, introduced legislation to Parliament that would make doxxing illegal and entitle victims of serious invasions of privacy to seek compensation through the court system, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Under the laws, anyone found guilty of the malicious release of personal data online -- a practice known as doxxing -- will face jail time.</p>

<p>The legislation imposes a maximum penalty of six years in jail for publishing someone's personal information with the intent of causing harm.</p>

<p>The maximum prison sentence will be increased to seven years in cases where a person or group is targeted based on their religion, race, gender, disability, nationality or ethnic origin.</p>

<p>The move to criminalise doxxing is part of broader reforms that Dreyfus said would bring the existing Privacy Act into the digital age.</p>

<p>"Strong privacy laws are essential to Australians' trust and confidence in the digital economy and digital services provided by governments and industry," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Australians have got the right to have their privacy respected and when they're asked to hand over their personal data they have a right to expect it will be respected," the statement further read.</p>

<p>Additionally, the legislation introduced on Thursday would give Australians the right to sue for damages if they have been the victim of a serious invasion of privacy.</p>

<p>Dreyfus said the bill is the first stage of the government's commitment to provide Australians with greater control over their personal information.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-09/i0e68jto_prison-generic-unsplash-650_625x300_07_September_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A maximum penalty of 6 years in jail has been imposed for doxxing (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/surfer-to-trump-whisperer-who-can-become-japans-next-prime-minister-6546809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Surfer To 'Trump Whisperer': Who Can Become Japan's Next Prime Minister?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/surfer-to-trump-whisperer-who-can-become-japans-next-prime-minister-6546809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 11:30:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A photogenic political scion, a military model-maker and a hardliner hoping to become Japan's first woman prime minister are among nine candidates vying to lead the world's fourth-largest economy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A photogenic political scion, a military model-maker and a hardliner hoping to become Japan's first woman prime minister are among nine candidates vying to lead the world's fourth-largest economy.</p>

<p>AFP gives a rundown of the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) lawmakers competing to win the ruling party's leadership contest -- and therefore become prime minister -- on September 27:</p>

<h3><strong>The surfer</strong></h3>

<p>Surfing, media-savvy Shinjiro Koizumi is the youthful, photogenic son of the popular former premier Junichiro Koizumi.</p>

<p>As environment minister, Koizumi backed greater use of renewables.</p>

<p>He also took paternity leave in the post, saying he wants to share parenting duties with his television presenter wife.</p>

<p>But this doesn't endear him to LDP elders, who might see Koizumi, 43, as too young and too lightweight to be prime minister.</p>

<h3><strong>Model-maker</strong></h3>

<p>Shigeru Ishiba is a former defence minister who is popular with voters but less so with LDP lawmakers, resulting in four failed attempts to be party leader.</p>

<p>The 67-year-old has questioned the Bank of Japan's maverick interest rate policy while calling for efforts to counter rural depopulation.</p>

<p>He likes making military models -- including one of a Soviet aircraft carrier for the visit of a Russian defence minister -- as well as trains and 1970s pop idols.</p>

<h3><strong>The nationalist</strong></h3>

<p>Sanae Takaichi is a vocal nationalist popular with the LDP's conservative wing. She was close to assassinated ex-premier Shinzo Abe, whose supporters are still powerful.</p>

<p>Takaichi, 63, is a regular visitor to the Yasukuni shrine to Japan's war dead -- including convicted war criminals -- so her nomination would likely rile China and South Korea.</p>

<p>Like Abe, Takaichi, who also ran for the leadership in 2021, backs aggressive monetary easing, active fiscal spending and nuclear power.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But unlike her hero Margaret Thatcher, the former British prime minister, she played drums in a student heavy metal band.</p>

<h3><strong>The liberal</strong></h3>

<p>Taro Kono, currently minister for digital transformation, is an experienced and outspoken reformist who was defeated by Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in the last leadership race in 2021.</p>

<p>US-educated Kono, 61, has held multiple minister jobs and has 2.5 million followers on X. His views are liberal-leaning by LDP standards.</p>

<p>Thirteen years after the Fukushima disaster, he has softened his opposition to nuclear power to meet growing energy demands, including from AI data centres.</p>

<h3><strong>The diplomat</strong></h3>

<p>Harvard-educated former consultant and current foreign minister Yoko Kamikawa is one of two women in the running along with Takaichi.</p>

<p>While justice minister, Kamikawa ordered 16 executions, including that of the head of the Aum doomsday cult responsible for the 1995 sarin gas attack on the Tokyo subway.</p>

<p>As Japan's top diplomat, the 71-year-old has won plaudits, including for a visit to Kyiv, but she reportedly struggled to secure the support needed to run as a candidate.</p>

<h3><strong>'Trump Whisperer'</strong></h3>

<p>With strong English, Abe's former golf partner Toshimitsu Motegi was dubbed the "Trump whisperer" for his deft handling of tricky US-Japan trade talks.</p>

<p>The Harvard-educated LDP secretary-general has been economy and foreign minister, and is respected for his policy knowledge.</p>

<p>But Motegi, 68, is reportedly feared for having a short fuse. Even Trump reportedly told Abe that he thought Motegi was "too tough".</p>

<h3><strong>The others</strong></h3>

<p>Former foreign minister and current chief cabinet secretary Yoshimasa Hayashi, former health minister Katsunobu Kato and former economic security minister Takayuki Kobayashi are also in the running.</p>

<p>Anything could happen, with the race more open this time around after most of the LDP's factions were disbanded in the wake of a funding scandal.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3hmrg3kk_tokyo-generic-japan-generic-pixabay_625x300_12_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nine candidates are vying to lead the world's fourth-largest economy, Japan (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/net-id-to-new-books-xi-jinpings-ideological-grip-on-china-is-tightening-6546778]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: 'Net ID' To New Books, Xi's Ideological Grip On China Is Tightening]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/net-id-to-new-books-xi-jinpings-ideological-grip-on-china-is-tightening-6546778]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 11:28:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Through greater social control, the Party seeks to protect itself from the fate of the erstwhile Soviet Union, whose political model forms the foundation for China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c1d8v888_china_625x300_12_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>China's Cyberspace Administration and its Ministry of Public Security have mooted an initiative to create internet identification for netizens in China. Plans are afoot to issue digital identification that will be used by netizens instead of their real identities when opening online profiles. The justification for this move is to safeguard users from sharing personal data, which may be retained by private digital platforms. While the authorities have maintained that applying for internet identification is voluntary, there is apprehension that the Communist Party of China (CPC) will exercise greater oversight over the Net in future.</p>

<p>These developments point to Chinese President Xi Jinping tightening his grip on civil society. The exercise is not limited to public life but seems to encompass the education sector and the military as well. The Party leadership met in mid-July for its yearly plenary session, which determined the direction of important policy initiatives. The resolution of the session announced plans to work on a unified national population management system.</p>

<h2><strong>Project Of 'National Rejuvenation'</strong></h2>

<p>A new set of regulations was issued recently with respect to educational institutions that seek to improve the pool of educators. The main aim of the Party-state is to uplift the societal status of teachers, enhancing their skills, and paring down their workload. Xi wants teachers to not merely impart lessons but to incubate a high-quality workforce for his vision of a modern Chinese economy. At the same time, the rules seek educators to be in sync with the Party's line on ideological matters, and draw the line with respect to any violations. According to government statistics, China has one of the largest combine of teachers, totalling over 18 million.</p>

<p>Concomitantly, students, too, are in the Party's crosshairs. In what may be seen as the importance of the education sector, China's political elite in its Politburo Standing Committee and officials across provinces attended Xi's address to mark Teachers' Day this month. While Xi made a pitch to expand academic exchanges overseas and research cooperation and sought a greater say in international education governance, he also underscored the need to impart more political training in classrooms.</p>

<p>He emphasised that this ideological guidance would serve as the foundation for his project of 'national rejuvenation', which seeks to build the nation's strength. There is also stress on fostering a 'sense of community' for the Chinese nation through the use of the official script and language.</p>

<h2><strong>Protecting Future Generations From 'Sabotage'</strong></h2>

<p>In an article published in the Communist Party of China's journal, <em>Qiushi</em>, Xi raised the bogey of hostile forces in the West trying to subvert the Party's leadership, and plans of a 'colour revolution' in China. He justifies the moves of the Party at exerting greater control in order to protect the future generation from sabotage, and create 'socialist successors'.</p>

<p>Chinese state-run media builds on Xi's thesis, warning of efforts by intelligence agencies to specifically target young students for recruitment and infiltration through social media. In a damage-control mode, new textbooks have been issued on the theme of national security that seek to wean students away from pop culture's potential for instigating a 'colour revolution'.</p>

<h2><strong>The Ideological Oversight Over PLA</strong></h2>

<p>In the realm of defence, Xi, as the chairperson of the Central Military Commission (CMC), which is tasked with oversight of the People's Liberation Army (PLA), highlighted the need for rectification in the services. China's Ministry of National Defence posted an article that credited Xi for tackling the challenge of "lax discipline" in the PLA ranks that endured during his predecessors' tenures. The commentary supported improved supervision mechanisms, citing Chairman Mao Zedong's Yan'an Rectification campaign. The ministry seeks better discipline within the ranks. The Yan'an campaign of the 1940s sought to improve the Party's ideological moorings with rank-and-file poring over Mao's speeches. Historians state that the rectification campaign's outcome was that cadres critical of Mao were on the Party's sidelines, with the Chairman strengthening his position.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Relying On 'Faithfuls'</strong></h2>

<p>In recent years, the issue of corruption in the armed forces has also come to light. Recently, two former defence ministers - Wei Fenghe and Li Shangfu - were expelled from the Party over accusations of bribery. In a conference of the military brass convened in June, incidentally in Yan'an, Xi stated his intent to come down heavily on corrupt elements and terminate the root causes of corruption. He already supports scrutiny of departments engaged in defence-related manufacturing by anti-corruption officials to unearth corruption.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Xi has underlined that the Party's strength lies in PLA's organisational accord and that the 'gun' (meaning the army) ought to be headed by those faithful to the Party. In line with this, the PLA is increasingly being staffed by "politically reliable" personnel in the upper echelons. For example, He Hongjun, who served as the executive deputy director of the Central Military Commission (CMC) Political Work Department, which is in charge of party-building and political education within the military, was named General.</p>

<h2><strong>A Flailing Economy</strong></h2>

<p>The triggers for Xi calling for greater control citing the bogeyman of a colour revolution lie in conditions that have developed as a result of his own policies. Chinese policymakers targeted a GDP (Gross Domestic Product) growth of around 5% this year but could achieve only up to 4.7% in the April to June quarter. Factory output has stalled and the sale of new flats is at an 18-year low. Unemployment remains high; the Party even stopped publishing the damaging statistics recently.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Second, labour unrest in the form of strikes in factories increased in the January-June period, according to China's official data. Social unrest has caught the Party unawares, as also evidenced by the demonstrations that broke out across China in December 2022 against COVID-19 restrictions. In the same year, protests against the Party took the form of many boycotting paying mortgages on property to financial institutions in light of the worsening economic situation due to the pandemic-induced curbs.</p>

<p>To conclude, as the economic situation worsens in China, Xi is tightening his grip on disparate sectors like military, education, and civil society interactions. Through greater social control, the Party seeks to protect itself from the fate of the Soviet Union, whose political model forms the foundation for China.</p>

<p><em>(The writer is a China Fellow at Observer Research Foundation's Strategic Studies Programme)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gqgvl88o_china_625x300_12_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/perus-ex-president-alberto-fujimori-dies-at-86-6546646]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Peru's Ex-President Alberto Fujimori Dies At 86]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/perus-ex-president-alberto-fujimori-dies-at-86-6546646]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 11:06:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Peru's former president Alberto Fujimori, who ruled his country with an iron fist and then spent 16 years in prison for crimes against humanity, died on Wednesday at age 86 in the capital Lima.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Peru's former president Alberto Fujimori, who ruled his country with an iron fist and then spent 16 years in prison for crimes against humanity, died on Wednesday at age 86 in the capital Lima.</p>

<p>"After a long battle with cancer, our father, Alberto Fujimori, has just departed to meet the Lord," his children Keiko, Hiro, Sachie and Kenji Fujimori wrote on social media platform X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Thank you for so much, Dad!" they added.</p>

<p>Fujimori, who led Peru from 1990 to 2000, was released from prison on humanitarian grounds in December, two-thirds of the way through a 25-year sentence for crimes against humanity during his rule.</p>

<p>He was a key part of Peru's so-called war on terrorism in the form of Shining Path and Tupac Amaru leftist rebels. It left more than 69,000 people dead and 21,000 missing from 1980 to 2000, most of them civilians, according to a government truth commission.</p>

<p>Sources close to his family told AFP earlier Wednesday that Fujimori's health had deteriorated rapidly after completing treatment for tongue cancer in August.</p>

<p>He was last seen in public on Thursday as he was leaving a clinic in the Miraflores district of Lima, where he said he had undergone a CT scan.</p>

<p>As news of his death spread quickly on social media, supporters and detractors quarrelled over his legacy.</p>

<p>Many Peruvians called Fujimori, who was of Japanese descent, "el chino," or the Chinese man.</p>

<p>After his death Wednesday supporters gathered outside his house chanting "El chino did not die! El chino is present!"</p>

<p>Just a month earlier his daughter Keiko had announced that the rightwinger would run for president again in 2026.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Gustavo Adrianzen expressed his condolences to the Fujimori family. "We want his children and relatives to know we feel sorrow," he said.</p>

<p>Adrianzen said he would talk to the family about what kind of funeral they want. It was not clear whether Fujimori would receive a state funeral.</p>

<p>Fujimori was convicted and sent to prison in 2009 over massacres committed by army death squads in 1991 and 1992 in which 25 people, including a child, were killed in what he presented as anti-terrorist operations.</p>

<p>In December 2017, then-president Pedro Pablo Kuczynski pardoned Fujimori due to his ill health.</p>

<p>But the Supreme Court later annulled the pardon and in January 2019, he was returned to jail from hospital.</p>

<h3><strong>Hostage crisis&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>He was released again in December 2023 after a court reinstated his pardon.</p>

<p>He was adored and reviled in equal measures in Peru.</p>

<p>As he turned 80 in 2018, Fujimori sent a message to AFP which read in part: "Let history judge what I got right and what I got wrong."</p>

<p>He also expressed the conviction that he had paved the way for Peru to become one of the leading countries of Latin America.</p>

<p>Supporters credited him with saving the nation from left-wing Shining Path and Tupac Amaru guerrillas and shoring up the economy.</p>

<p>Opponents saw him as a power-thirsty autocrat.</p>

<p>Sociologist Eduardo Toche expressed scathing criticism of Fujimori when he was convicted of crimes against humanity in 2009, saying the Fujimori government represented the lowest, worst point in the history of Peru as he made up his own rules and ignored the country's institutions.</p>

<p>"For him there was no legal framework. The legal framework was that of his will and that of his friends, nothing more," Toche told AFP at the time.</p>

<p>One of the most dramatic episodes of his presidency was a four-month hostage ordeal at the Japanese embassy in Lima in late 1996 and early 1997.</p>

<p>The standoff ended with Fujimori sending in commandos who rescued all 72 hostages and killed 14 rebels.</p>

<p>But the later Fujimori years were dominated by a bribery scandal involving his intelligence chief Vladimiro Montesinos.</p>

<p>Fujimori went into self-imposed exile in Japan and memorably faxed in his resignation but was arrested years later in Chile and sent back to Peru for trial.</p>

<p>His daughter Keiko has made three failed bids for the presidency.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ek0854q_alberto-fujimori-death-afp-_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alberto Fujimori went into self-imposed exile in Japan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/death-count-rises-to-197-in-vietnam-after-typhoon-yagi-6546561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Death Count Rises To 197 In Vietnam After Typhoon Yagi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/death-count-rises-to-197-in-vietnam-after-typhoon-yagi-6546561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:54:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The number of people killed after Typhoon Yagi swept through northern Vietnam bringing flash floods and landslides has risen to 197, the government said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The number of people killed after Typhoon Yagi swept through northern Vietnam bringing flash floods and landslides has risen to 197, the government said Thursday.</p>

<p>About 128 people are still missing and more than 250,000 hectares of crops have also been destroyed, disaster officials under the Ministry of Agriculture said in an official report.</p>

<p>Yagi is the most powerful typhoon to hit northern Vietnam in 30 years, according to meteorologists.</p>

<p>The storm downed bridges, tore roofs off buildings and damaged factories after making landfall on Saturday carrying winds in excess of 149 kilometres (92 miles) per hour.</p>

<p>The north of the country has since been battling severe flooding, with several communities partially underwater.</p>

<p>Thousands have been forced to evacuate their homes, while others are struggling with power cuts.</p>

<p>In one badly hit district on the outskirts of Hanoi, more than 15,000 people have been affected by the floods.</p>

<p>Farmers have also suffered. About 1.5 million chickens and ducks have been killed, as well as 2,500 pigs, buffalo and cows, officials said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3fg2jin_typhoon-yagi-afp_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thousands have been forced to evacuate their homes, while others are struggling with power cuts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harris-trump-battle-for-swing-states-after-fierce-1st-presidential-debate-6546401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris, Trump Battle For Swing States After Fierce 1st Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harris-trump-battle-for-swing-states-after-fierce-1st-presidential-debate-6546401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:30:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and Donald Trump return to the campaign trail Thursday, with the Democrat hoping her dominant display in their first presidential debate will boost her chances in the knife-edge US election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris and Donald Trump return to the campaign trail Thursday, with the Democrat hoping her dominant display in their first presidential debate will boost her chances in the knife-edge US election.</p>

<p>The rivals are heading to crucial battleground states that will decide November's vote, two days after Harris forced Republican Trump onto the defensive in a fiery clash that drew 67 million viewers across the United States.</p>

<p>But it remains unclear whether the vice president's punchy performance will turn the dial with less than two months to go in an agonizingly tight race that will be decided by a handful of undecided voters across the country.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, will seek to capitialize on her debate momentum as she heads to North Carolina on Thursday, holding back-to-back rallies in the cities of Charlotte and Greensboro promising a "new way forward."</p>

<p>Harris has erased a six-point Trump lead over the last month to draw level in North Carolina, where she is aiming to fire up crucial Black and young voters to back her bid to become America's first woman commander in chief.</p>

<p>Amid media reports of turmoil in his camp over the way Harris succeeded in goading him at the debate, the 78-year-old former president is due onstage in Tucson, Arizona to focus on "our struggling economy."</p>

<p>Arizona was one of the most bitterly fought states in the 2020 election, with Joe Biden winning there by around 10,000 votes against Trump, and promises to be closely contested again.</p>

<p>Their return to the swing states at the heart of the election came a day after a brief truce when they attended Wednesday's anniversary of the 9/11 attacks in New York.</p>

<h3><strong>'Missed opportunity'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The debate in Philadelphia was a welcome boost for Harris as the honeymoon from her sudden replacement of the ageing Biden as Democratic candidate seemed to be wearing off.</p>

<p>Trump insisted it was one of his best debates, but snap polls and even allies disagreed as Harris riled him up with taunts about crowd sizes and his 2020 election loss, then scored points on issues like abortion.</p>

<p>Close Trump ally Senator Lindsay Graham told reporters afterwards that it was a "missed opportunity" while US media reported there was discontent among Trump donors.</p>

<p>But while Harris has erased the lead Trump held in polls, the candidates remain neck and neck and she insists she is the underdog in the White House race.</p>

<p>And America's deeply polarized politics mean however that big showpiece events like debates rarely move the polls that much -- even if it was a disastrous debate against Trump that forced Biden to drop his reelection bid.</p>

<p>Both candidates will keep bashing the battlegrounds in the coming days, knowing a few thousand undecided votes in the northeastern "Rust Belt" and the booming southern "Sun Belt" could decide everything.</p>

<p>Harris returns to Pennsylvania, the most crucial and bitterly fought of all the swing states, on Friday for campaign events in Johnstown and Wilkes-Barre before attending an awards dinner Saturday with Second Gentleman Doug Emhoff.</p>

<p>Trump will deliver remarks in Las Vegas on Friday on the cost of living, as he targets Nevada, yet another key swing state. He is also due to give a press conference in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Harris's running mate Tim Walz will travel to Michigan and Wisconsin from Thursday to Saturday as part of the campaign's New Way Forward swing state tour.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/28h27408_trump-harris-debate-2024_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has erased a six-point Donald Trump lead over the last month.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-as-taylor-swift-endorses-kamala-harris-over-donald-trump-in-us-elections-2024-we-admire-her-music-but-6546232]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Disconnected Billionaire": JD Vance As Taylor Swift Backs Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-as-taylor-swift-endorses-kamala-harris-over-donald-trump-in-us-elections-2024-we-admire-her-music-but-6546232]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:03:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taylor Swift endorsed Kamala Harris over Donald Trump in an Instagram post on Tuesday, calling her a "steady-handed, gifted leader."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump's running mate JD Vance today took a dig at American singer-songwriter Taylor Swift after she endorsed Kamala Harris. Swift voiced support for the Democratic candidate in an Instagram post on Tuesday, calling her a "steady-handed, gifted leader."</p>

<p>She signed off her post - which has so far <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swifts-instagram-post-endorsing-kamala-harris-draws-9-million-likes-6545522" target="_blank">drawn nearly 10 million likes</a> - by dubbing herself a "childless cat lady," a swipe at a JD Vance, who in a 2021 interview called some Democrats "a bunch of childless cat ladies." He has since said it was merely a sarcastic remark.</p>

<p>"We admire Taylor Swift's music, but I don't think most Americans, whether they like her music or are fans of hers or not, are going to be influenced by a billionaire celebrity who I think is fundamentally disconnected from the interests and the problems of most Americans," Vance told Fox News.</p>

<p>"When grocery prices go by 20%, it hurts most Americans. It doesn't hurt Taylor Swift. When housing prices become unaffordable, it doesn't affect Taylor Swift or any other billionaire. It does affect middle-class Americans all over our country," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>Taylor Swift Endorses Kamala Harris</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fine-taylor-you-win-elon-musk-after-taylor-swift-backs-kamala-harris-6538352" target="_blank">Taylor Swift endorsed Kamala Harris</a> minutes after the televised presidential debate between the Democrat and Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"I'm voting for Kamala Harris because she fights for the rights and causes I believe need a warrior to champion them," the 34-year-old singer said in a long post on Instagram.</p>

<p>"I believe we can accomplish so much more in this country if we are led by calm and not chaos," she added.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Taylor Swift (@taylorswift)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Swift, who is one of the world's most popular stars, encouraged her followers to "do your research."</p>

<p>&nbsp;"I've done my research, and I've made my choice," she said, and told her fans, "Your research is all yours to do, and the choice is yours to make."</p>

<p>"I will be casting my vote for Kamala Harris and Tim Walz in the 2024 Presidential Election," the singer wrote on Instagram.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shell-pay-for-it-says-donald-trump-after-taylor-swift-endorses-kamala-harris-for-president-6542169" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a>, however, slammed Taylor Swift and said he is "not her fan".</p>

<p>"I was not a Taylor Swift fan... she's a very liberal person. She seems to always endorse a Democrat, and she'll probably pay a price for it in the marketplace," he told Fox News.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fsg68sho_taylor-swift-jd-vance_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taylor Swift also took a dig at JD Vance while endorsing Kamala Harris]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bill-gates-shares-his-no-1-concern-that-keeps-him-up-at-night-another-pandemic-6546094]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bill Gates Shares His No. 1 Concern That Keeps Him Up At Night]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bill-gates-shares-his-no-1-concern-that-keeps-him-up-at-night-another-pandemic-6546094]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 09:39:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For Mr Gates, the key question during a future pandemic would be whether nations are better prepared than they were for the outbreak of Covid-19.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire philanthropist Bill Gates has repeatedly warned the public about pressing issues like climate disasters and devastating cyberattacks. However, the two crises that concern him the most are war and pandemics.</p>

<p>The Microsoft co-founder told CNBC Make It that the current global unrest could potentially trigger "a major war," and even if a large-scale conflict is avoided, "there will be another pandemic, most likely in the next 25 years."</p>

<p>For Mr Gates, the key question during a future pandemic would be whether nations are better prepared than they were for the outbreak of Covid-19. Reflecting on the United States' response, he noted, "The country that the world expected to lead and be the model fell short of those expectations."</p>

<p>In his 2022 book, "How to Prevent the Next Pandemic," Mr Gates criticised various governments for their lack of preparedness in 2020. He also outlined recommendations for countries worldwide, including stronger quarantine measures, enhanced disease monitoring, and increased investment in vaccine research and development.</p>

<p>Speaking about Covid-19, Mr Gates remarked, "Although some lessons from the coronavirus pandemic have been learned, it's been far less than I would have expected, sadly. We're still not fully reflecting on what we did well and where we fell short. Maybe in the next five years, that will improve, but so far, it's quite surprising."</p>

<p>Earlier,&nbsp;Microsoft co-founder said that the rise of artificial intelligence (AI) will be transformative for people in the next five years. Speaking to CNN, he added that there is no need to be scared of the latest technology as it will create new opportunities. The comment comes days after International Monetary Fund (IMF) chief Kristalina Georgieva said that AI will affect 60 per cent of jobs in advanced economies and 40 per cent across the globe.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dq35hr8g_bill-gates_625x300_17_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two crises that concern him the most are war and pandemics.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-9-11-attacks-looked-like-from-space-nasa-shares-haunting-image-6545898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What 9/11 Attacks Looked Like From Space: NASA Shares Haunting Image]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-9-11-attacks-looked-like-from-space-nasa-shares-haunting-image-6545898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 08:55:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On the 23rd anniversary of the September 11 attacks, NASA has released a letter from the only American astronaut in space at the time, Frank Culbertson, who was reflecting on witnessing the tragedy from the International Space Station (ISS).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the 23rd anniversary of the September 11 attacks, NASA released a letter from the only American astronaut in space at the time, Frank Culbertson, who was reflecting on witnessing the tragedy from the International Space Station (ISS).</p>

<p>In the letter, dated September 12, 2001, Culbertson recollects the moment he learned of the attacks while being aboard the International Space Station (ISS). Describing his shock and horror upon hearing about the events, he wrote, "Well, obviously the world changed today. What I say or do is very minor compared to the significance of what happened to our country today when it was attacked by.... by whom? Terrorists is all we know, I guess. Hard to know at whom to direct our anger and fear..."</p>

<p>Culbertson, who was serving as the commander of Expedition Three at that time, captured images of the smoke plume rising from lower Manhattan shortly after the collapse of the Twin Towers. His letter vividly narrates his experience of seeing his country under one of the biggest terrorist attacks of all time that killed 3000 people.</p>

<p>"It's difficult to describe how it feels to be the only American completely off the planet at a time such as this. The feeling that I should be there with all of you, dealing with this, helping in some way, is overwhelming," he wrote.</p>

<p>Culbertson&nbsp;witnessed the smoke rising from New York City as they passed overhead. He captured video footage of the smoke, which he described as having an "odd bloom" at its base. He later learned that the pilot of the plane that hit the Pentagon was his classmate, Captain Charles Burlingame.</p>

<p>Today, 23 years after the attack, a memorial exists where the Twin Towers once stood to remember those who lost their lives in the terror attack. Pew Research in its study said, "It is difficult to think of an event that so profoundly transformed US public opinion across so many dimensions as the 9/11 attacks." Culbertson's photograph and his letter serve as a lasting record of that fateful day in American history, noting that things would "never be the same again" after that.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/16kqsnu_nasa-911-_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Frank Culbertson witnessed the smoke rising from New York City as they passed overhead.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starbucks-new-ceo-shares-his-go-to-career-advice-i-know-its-a-cliche-6545820]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Starbucks' New CEO Shares His Go-To Career Advice: "I Know It's a Cliche"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starbucks-new-ceo-shares-his-go-to-career-advice-i-know-its-a-cliche-6545820]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Sep 2024 08:33:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Niccol, 50, is seen by many as a "dream hire" and a "hall of fame restaurant CEO."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brian Niccol, a seasoned executive with a proven track record of turning around troubled companies, has taken the helm at Starbucks. The coffee giant faces mounting pressure from activist investors, unionization efforts, and sluggish sales in its two largest markets.</p>

<p>Mr Niccol, 50, who previously led Chipotle through a foodborne illness scandal and the pandemic, is seen by many as a "dream hire" and a "hall of fame restaurant CEO."&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a commencement speech, Niccol shared his go-to career advice. "I know it's a cliche, but you absolutely have to believe in yourself and have the grit to not give up, when it at first might not be going your way,” &nbsp;He also shared his strategy of using a beat-up notebook to track his career progress and stay focused on his goals, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/09/09/starbucks-new-ceo-brian-niccol-swears-by-this-cliche-career-advice.html" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>CNBC Make It </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>Mr Niccol's "gut instinct" has played a crucial role in his career decisions, including his move from Taco Bell to Chipotle.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“Whatever it is you need to do to keep yourself focused on your goal, do it, and believe you can do it,” he added.</p>

<p>“There will be times in your career when your gut will be tingling,” he said, noting that he had that feeling when he left Taco Bell to become Chipotle's CEO in 2018. “Make space for that instinctive intelligence and take action. Trust your instincts.”&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Niccol's appointment is critical for Starbucks. The company has been grappling with several challenges, including declining sales, increased competition, and unionization efforts. Niccol's experience in turning around troubled companies could be a valuable asset to Starbucks as it seeks to navigate these challenges.</p>

<p>In addition to his strong leadership skills, Mr Niccol also has a deep understanding of the restaurant industry. He has spent his entire career working in the food service sector, and he has a proven track record of driving growth and profitability.</p>

<p>Mr Niccol's appointment has been met with optimism by many analysts and investors. They believe that he has the potential to turn Starbucks around and restore the company to its former glory. However, it will take time to see whether Niccol can deliver on these expectations.</p>

<p>"When I talked to him I remember him saying, 'I know what to do,'" Hobson, who ceded her position as chair of the Starbucks board to Niccol and is now lead independent director, said in an Aug. 13 appearance on CNBC's "Squawk Box."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hobson continued: "He said, 'This is a speed bump in this company's history. This is not something that I fear going into,' and that was something for our board that was extremely encouraging."&nbsp;</p>

<p>In his new role, Mr Niccol will be getting paid a base salary of $1.6 million annually and supercommuting from his home in Newport Beach, California to Starbucks' Seattle headquarters on a corporate jet.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kmc4mm8o_brian-niccol_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Niccol's "gut instinct" has played a crucial role in his career decisions]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>