<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 12:34:33 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-introduces-porn-passport-to-watch-adult-content-heres-why-6051906]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spain Introduces 'Porn Passport' To Watch Adult Content Online. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-introduces-porn-passport-to-watch-adult-content-heres-why-6051906]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 11:26:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Citing the data on access to adult content by minors, Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez called it "devastating" and told a Spanish newspaper, "Almost half of young people under 15 years of age consume it".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a bid to restrict the access to online pornography by minors, Spain has come up with a new mobile application that will not only require users to verify their age, but also limits the number of credits for viewing adult content.</p>

<p>This comes after Dale Una Vuelta, an anti-pornography group that campaigns for tighter regulations on access to adult content online, earlier released statistics that raised concerns over the alarming spread of adult content among minors.</p>

<p>Calling the data "devastating," Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez told El Pais newspaper, "Almost half of young people under 15 years of age consume it".</p>

<h2>How will the app work?</h2>

<p>The mobile application, officially called the Digital Wallet Beta (Cartera Digital Beta), and locally known as the "pajaporte", will allow platforms to check whether the user is above the age of 18 years or not. To verify their age, the viewers will be asked to use the mobile app.</p>

<p>The application will work as a mobile phone wallet and will verify users' age through one of the five government-issued IDs.</p>

<p>Once verified, the users will then receive 30 "porn credits" with one-month validity. These credits will grant them access to adult content. Further, users will be able to put a request for extra credits.</p>

<h2>Launch date</h2>

<p>The mobile application will be available by the end of the summer, reports said.</p>

<p>Though it is being criticised by a section of activists and experts for its complexity, the Spanish government has defended the move. According to the government, the credit-based model is more privacy-friendly and ensures that the online activities are not easily traceable.</p>

<p>It will be voluntary, as online platforms can rely on other age-verification methods available to keep a check on inappropriate viewers.</p>

<p>The upcoming app is part of the broader effort to align with the European Union law that comes into effect in October 2027. Eventually, the porn passport in Spain will likely get replaced by the EU's own digital identity system (eIDAS2).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/t1fcsu2_laptop-generic_625x300_07_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/injection-twice-a-year-100-effective-in-hiv-treatment-study-6051714]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Injection Twice A Year 100% Effective In HIV Treatment: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/injection-twice-a-year-100-effective-in-hiv-treatment-study-6051714]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 10:50:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A large clinical trial in South Africa and Uganda has shown that a twice-yearly injection of a new pre-exposure prophylaxis drug gives young women total protection from HIV infection.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A large clinical trial in South Africa and Uganda has shown that a twice-yearly injection of a new pre-exposure prophylaxis drug gives young women total protection from HIV infection.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>The trial tested whether the six-month injection of lenacapavir would provide better protection against HIV infection than two other drugs, both daily pills. All three medications are pre-exposure prophylaxis (or <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/hiv/risk/prep/index.html">PrEP</a>) drugs.</p>

<p>Physician-scientist <a href="https://idm.uct.ac.za/contacts/linda-gail-bekker">Linda-Gail Bekker</a>, principal investigator for the South African part of the study, tells Nadine Dreyer what makes this breakthough so significant and what to expect next.</p>

<h2>Tell us about the trial and what it set out to achieve</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://www.purposestudies.com/">Purpose 1</a> trial with 5,000 participants took place at three sites in Uganda and 25 sites in South Africa to test the efficacy of lenacapavir and two other drugs.</p>

<p><a href="https://medicine.yale.edu/news-article/lenacapavir-drug-offers-new-hope-for-multi-drug-resistant-hiv/">Lenacapavir (Len LA)</a> is a <a href="https://clinicalinfo.hiv.gov/en/glossary/capsid-inhibitors#:%7E:text=Capsid%20inhibitors%20are%20a%20class,of%20the%20viral%20life%20cycle.">fusion capside inhibitor</a>. It interferes with the HIV capsid, a protein shell that protects HIV's genetic material and enzymes needed for replication. It is administered just under the skin, once every six months.</p>

<p>The randomised controlled trial, sponsored by the drug developers <a href="https://www.gilead.com/">Gilead Sciences</a>, tested several things.</p>

<p>The first was whether a six-monthly injection of <a href="https://www.gilead.com/news-and-press/press-room/press-releases/2024/6/gileads-twiceyearly-lenacapavir-demonstrated-100-efficacy-and-superiority-to-daily-truvada-for-hiv-prevention">lenacapavir</a> was safe and would provide better protection against HIV infection as PrEP for women between the ages of 16 and 25 years than <a href="https://www.empr.com/home/news/drugs-in-the-pipeline/lenacapavir-superior-to-truvada-for-hiv-prevention-in-cisgender-women/">Truvada F/TDF</a>, a daily PrEP pill in wide use that has been available for more than a decade.</p>

<p>Secondly, the trial also tested whether Descovy <a href="https://www.prepwatch.org/products/oral-prep-f-taf/">F/TAF</a>, a newer daily pill, was as effective as F/TDF. The newer F/TAF has superior <a href="https://www.msdmanuals.com/professional/clinical-pharmacology/pharmacokinetics/overview-of-pharmacokinetics">pharmacokinetic</a> properties to F/TDF. Pharmacokinetic refers to the movement of a drug into, through, and out of the body. F/TAF is a smaller pill and is in use among men and transgender women in high-income countries.</p>

<p>The trial had three arms. Young women were randomly assigned to one of the arms in a 2:2:1 ratio (Len LA: F/TAF oral: F/TDF oral) in a <a href="https://www.news-medical.net/health/What-is-a-Double-Blind-Trial.aspx">double blinded</a> fashion. This means neither the participants nor the researchers knew which treatment participants were receiving until the clinical trial was over.</p>

<p>In eastern and southern Africa, young women are the population who <a href="https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/despite-progress-adolescent-girls-continue-bear-brunt-hiv-epidemic-98000-new">bear the brunt of new HIV infections</a>. They also find a daily PrEP regimen <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8169554/">challenging</a> to maintain, for a number of social and structural reasons.</p>

<p>During the randomised phase of the trial none of the <a href="https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-06-year-women-full-hiv-trial.html">2,134 women</a> who received lenacapavir contracted HIV. There was 100 percent efficiency.</p>

<p>By comparison, 16 of the <a href="https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-06-year-women-full-hiv-trial.html">1,068 women</a> (or 1.5%) who took Truvada (F/TDF) and 39 of <a href="https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-06-year-women-full-hiv-trial.html">2,136</a> (1.8%) who received Descovy (F/TAF) contracted the HIV virus.</p>

<p>The results at a recent <a href="https://www.gilead.com/news-and-press/press-room/press-releases/2024/6/gileads-twiceyearly-lenacapavir-demonstrated-100-efficacy-and-superiority-to-daily-truvada-for-hiv-prevention">independent data safety monitoring board</a> review led to the recommendation that the trial's “blinded” phase should be stopped and all participants should be offered a choice of PrEP.</p>

<p>This board is an independent committee of experts who are put in place at the start of a clinical trial. They see the unblinded data at stipulated times during the trial to monitor progress and safety. They ensure that a trial does not continue if there is harm or a clear benefit in one arm over others.</p>

<h2>What is the significance of these trials?</h2>

<p>This breakthrough gives great hope that we have a proven, highly effective prevention tool to protect people from HIV.</p>

<p>There were <a href="https://www.hiv.gov/hiv-basics/overview/data-and-trends/global-statistics">1.3 million new HIV infections</a> globally in the past year. Although that's fewer than the <a href="https://www.hiv.gov/hiv-basics/overview/data-and-trends/global-statistics">2 million infections</a> seen in 2010, it is clear that at this rate we are not going to meet the HIV <a href="https://www.unaids.org/sites/default/files/Sep2019_2025targets-2ndStComMeeting-Report_en.pdf">new infection target</a> that UNAIDS set for 2025 (fewer than 500,000 globally) or potentially even the goal to end Aids by <a href="https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/publications-data/evidence-brief-progress-towards-reaching-sustainable-development-goals-related#:%7E:text=The%20United%20Nations%20Sustainable%20Development,discrimination%20in%20the%20EU%2FEEA.">2030</a>.</p>

<p>PrEP is not the only prevention tool.</p>

<p>PrEP should be provided alongside HIV self-testing, access to condoms, screening and treatment for sexually transmitted infections and access to contraception for women of childbearing potential.</p>

<p>In addition, young men should be offered <a href="https://www.unaids.org/en/resources/presscentre/featurestories/2007/february/20070228mcpt2#:%7E:text=Scientists%20say%20male%20circumcision%20probably,scratched%20or%20torn%20during%20sex.">medical male circumcision</a> for health reasons.</p>

<p>But despite these options, we haven't quite got to the point where we have been able to stop new infections, particularly among young people.</p>

<p>For young people, the daily decision to take a pill or use a condom or take a pill at the time of sexual intercourse can be <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8169554/">very challenging</a>.</p>

<p>HIV scientists and activists hope that young people may find that having to make this “prevention decision” only twice a year may reduce unpredictability and barriers.</p>

<p>For a young woman who struggles to get to an appointment at a clinic in a town or who can't keep pills without facing stigma or violence, an injection just twice a year is the option that could keep her free of HIV.</p>

<h2>What happens now?</h2>

<p>The plan is that the Purpose 1 trial will go on but now in an “open label” phase. This means that study participants will be “unblinded”: they will be told whether they have been in the “injectable” or oral TDF or oral TAF groups.</p>

<p>They will be offered the choice of PrEP they would prefer as the trial continues.</p>

<p>A sister trial is also under way: <a href="https://www.purposestudies.com/purpose2/">Purpose 2</a> is being conducted in a number of regions including some sites in Africa among cisgender men, and transgender and nonbinary people who have sex with men.</p>

<p>It's important to conduct trials among different groups because we have seen differences in effectiveness. Whether the sex is <a href="https://stanfordhealthcare.org/medical-conditions/sexual-and-reproductive-health/hiv-aids/causes/risk-of-exposure.html">anal or vaginal</a> is important and may have an impact on effectiveness.</p>

<h2>How long until the drug is rolled out?</h2>

<p>We have read in a Gilead Sciences <a href="https://www.gilead.com/news-and-press/press-room/press-releases">press statement</a> that within the next couple of months the company will submit the dossier with all the results to a number of country regulators, particularly the Ugandan and South African regulators.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization will also review the data and may issue recommendations.</p>

<p>We hope then that this new drug will be adopted into WHO and country guidelines.</p>

<p>We also hope we may begin to see the drug being tested in more studies to understand better how to incorporate it into real world settings.</p>

<p>Price is a critical factor to ensure access and distribution in the public sector where it is badly needed.</p>

<p>Gilead Sciences has said it will offer licences to companies that make generic drugs, which is another critical way to get <a href="https://www.webmd.com/hiv-aids/hiv-treatment-cost">prices down</a>.</p>

<p>In an ideal world, governments will be able to purchase this affordably and it will be offered to all who want it and need protection against HIV.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/233295/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><strong><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/linda-gail-bekker-285291">Linda-Gail Bekker</a>, Professor of medicine and deputy director of the Desmond Tutu HIV Centre at the Institute of Infectious Disease and Molecular Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-cape-town-691">University of Cape Town</a></span></em></strong></p>

<p><strong><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/hiv-breakthrough-drug-trial-shows-injection-twice-a-year-is-100-effective-against-infection-233295">original article</a>.</em></strong></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/j927li4s_hiv-generic_625x300_05_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The World Health Organization will also review the data and may issue recommendations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bulldozed-and-shelled-israels-assault-ravages-gazas-farming-sector-6051579]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bulldozed And Shelled": Israel's Assault Ravages Gaza's Farming Sector]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bulldozed-and-shelled-israels-assault-ravages-gazas-farming-sector-6051579]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 10:15:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tank tracks still fresh on his field in southern Gaza's coastal area of Al-Mawasi, Nedal Abu Jazar lamented the damage war has wrought on his trees and crops.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tank tracks still fresh on his field in southern Gaza's coastal area of Al-Mawasi, Nedal Abu Jazar lamented the damage war has wrought on his trees and crops.</p>

<p>"Look at the destruction," the 39-year-old farmer told AFP, holding an uprooted tomato plant.</p>

<p>He pointed to his greenhouse's metal frame and its white plastic sheeting strewn across the plot, inside an area designated a humanitarian zone by the Israeli army.</p>

<p>"People were sitting peacefully on their farmland ... and suddenly tanks arrived and fired at us, and then there were (air) strikes."</p>

<p>Abu Jazar said the Israeli operation in late June destroyed about 40 dunams (10 acres) of land and killed five labourers.</p>

<p>His is not an isolated case. Across Gaza, 57 percent of agricultural land has been damaged since the war began, according to a joint assessment published in June by the UN's agriculture and satellite imagery agencies, FAO and UNOSAT.</p>

<p>The damage threatens Gaza's food sovereignty, Matieu Henry of the Food and Agriculture Organization told AFP, because 30 percent of the Palestinian territory's food consumption comes from agricultural land.</p>

<p>"If almost 60 per cent of the agricultural land has been damaged, this may have a significant impact in terms of food security and food supply."</p>

<p>The Gaza Strip exported $44.6 million worth of produce in 2022, mainly to the West Bank and Israel, with strawberries and tomatoes representing 60 percent of the total, according to FAO data.</p>

<p>That number fell to zero after the October 7 attack on southern Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 38,098 people, also mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>The damage assessment on the agricultural land comes as the UN's hunger monitoring system estimated in June that 96 percent of Gaza faces high levels of acute food insecurity.</p>

<p>Contacted by AFP, the Israeli army said it "does not intentionally harm agricultural land".</p>

<p>In a statement, it said Hamas "often operates from within orchards, fields and agricultural land".</p>

<h3><strong>No work, no income</strong></h3>

<p>The impact is worse in the Palestinian territory's north, where 68 percent of agricultural land is damaged, although the southern area encompassing parts of Al-Mawasi has seen the most significant increase in recent months due to military operations.</p>

<p>UNOSAT's Lars Bromley told AFP the damage is generally "due to the impact of activities such as heavy vehicle activity, bombing, shelling, and other conflict-related dynamics, which would be things like areas burning".</p>

<p>Near the southern city of Rafah, 34-year-old farmer Ibrahim Dheir feels helpless after the destruction of 20 dunams (five acres) of land he used to lease, and all his farming equipment with it.</p>

<p>"As soon as the Israeli bulldozers and tanks entered the area, they began bulldozing cultivated lands with various trees, including fruits, citrus, guava, as well as crops like spinach, molokhia (jute mallow), eggplant, squash, pumpkin and sunflower seedlings," he said, before listing more damage in a testimony of the area's past agricultural abundance.</p>

<p>Dheir, whose family exported its produce to the West Bank and Israel, now feels destitute.</p>

<p>"We used to depend on agriculture for our livelihood day by day, but now there's no work or income."</p>

<h3><strong>Lasting damage</strong></h3>

<p>Farmer Abu Mahmoud Za'arab also finds himself with "no source of income".</p>

<p>The 60-year-old owns 15 dunams (3.7 acres) of land on which crops and fruit trees used to grow.</p>

<p>"The Israeli army passed through the land, completely wiping out all trees and crops," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"They bulldozed and shelled the land, turning it into barren pits."</p>

<p>The harm done to farmland in Gaza will last far beyond tank tracks and explosions, said Bromley of UNOSAT.</p>

<p>"With modern weaponry, a certain percentage is always going to fail. Tank shells won't explode, artillery shells won't explode ... so clearing that unexploded ordnance is a massive task," he said.</p>

<p>It will require "probing every centimetre of the soil before you can allow the farmers back onto it".</p>

<p>Despite the risks, Dheir wants to return to farming.</p>

<p>"We want the war to stop and things to return to how they were so we can farm and cultivate our lands again."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tt2j0rbo_gaza-afp-_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Gaza Strip exported $44.6 million worth of produce in 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/995-crore-passwords-stolen-in-biggest-data-breach-ever-report-6051577]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[995 Crore Passwords Stolen In Biggest Data Breach Ever: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/995-crore-passwords-stolen-in-biggest-data-breach-ever-report-6051577]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 10:14:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As per the researchers, the passwords have been leaked with the help of a mix of old and new data breaches.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A hacker, who goes by the name “ObamaCare”, has leaked 995 crore passwords, as per <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2024/07/05/new-security-alert-hacker-uploads-10-billion-stolen-passwords-to-crime-forum/">Forbes</a>.&nbsp; The information was released under a dataset named Rockyou2024 on Thursday, the report added.</p>

<p>As per researchers, it is considered the largest password data breach of all time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“In its essence, the RockYou2024 leak is a compilation of real-world passwords used by individuals all over the world. Revealing that many passwords for threat actors substantially heightens the risk of credential stuffing attacks,” researchers at <a href="https://cybernews.com/security/rockyou2024-largest-password-compilation-leak/">Cybernews</a> said.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“Threat actors could exploit the RockYou2024 password compilation to conduct brute-force attacks and gain unauthorised access to various online accounts used by individuals who employ passwords included in the dataset,” they added.</p>

<p>As per the researchers, the passwords have been leaked with the help of a mix of old and new data breaches.</p>

<p>“Moreover, combined with other leaked databases on hacker forums and marketplaces, which, for example, contain user email addresses and other credentials, RockYou2024 can contribute to a cascade of data breaches, financial frauds, and identity thefts,” the team said.</p>

<p>But this isn't the first time Rockyou2024 has leaked passwords. Before this, hackers leaked around&nbsp;8.4 billion plain text passwords, the report added.</p>

<p>People are advised to follow cyber hygiene practices to avoid falling prey to online crime. In April, the<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/education/university-body-to-educate-institutions-on-cyber-hygiene-5320664"> University Grant Commission</a> asked&nbsp;all higher educational institutions (HEIs) to participate in a webinar on 'Cyber Hygiene'.</p>

<p>"As per the directions of the Ministry of Home Affairs to promote mass awareness of students in the prevention of cybercrime, all higher education institutions (HEIs) are requested to participate in a 1-hour live webinar on 'Cyber Hygiene' by the Indian Cyber Crime Coordination Centre (l4C), Ministry of Home Affairs, scheduled for April 3, 2024, Wednesday from 2:00 PM to 3:00 pm," read the official notification by UGC.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0d0se9gc_hacker_625x300_07_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-karate-champion-who-escaped-gaza-forges-future-in-egypt-6051207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Palestine Karate Champion, Who Escaped Gaza, Forges Future In Egypt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-karate-champion-who-escaped-gaza-forges-future-in-egypt-6051207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 08:42:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On October 6, 2023, Palestinian karate champion Mais Elbostami went to bed thrilled after winning a competition in the Gaza Strip. She awoke the next day to a different world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On October 6, 2023, Palestinian karate champion Mais Elbostami went to bed thrilled after winning a competition in the Gaza Strip. She awoke the next day to a different world.</p>

<p>"I'd won first place," the shy 18-year-old told AFP from a Cairo suburb, where her family now lives after escaping the war and where she is training in the hope to one day represent her country internationally.</p>

<p>She said she "hadn't even hung up the medals" she won on October 6 before Hamas militants launched an unprecedented attack on Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Immediately, she and her family fled south from their home in the northern Gaza Strip as Israel launched a relentless retaliatory military campaign.</p>

<p>Over the past nine months, the war has reduced much of the besieged Palestinian territory to rubble and killed more than 38,000 people, according to Hamas-run Gaza's health ministry.</p>

<p>Amid the hell of bombing and displacement, "every hour that passed felt like it aged you by a year", said Elbostami.</p>

<p>Death was all around her.</p>

<p>"In the first 10 days alone, I lost my coach Jamal al-Khairy, and his granddaughter who used to train with me," she said.</p>

<p>When the family made it to the Egyptian capital in April, Elbostami had two things on her mind: making sure relatives back home were safe, and getting back to her karate training.</p>

<h3><strong>'Raise the flag'</strong></h3>

<p>Despite being trapped in Gaza, Palestinian national team coach Hassan al-Raiy put her in touch with the Egyptian team, and within two weeks she was back on the mat.</p>

<p>"My coaches here in Egypt have practically adopted me, and they're working with me so I can get good enough to compete in the next championships," she said.</p>

<p>Whenever she can, she spars on the mat. But with limited resources and gym time, Elbostami has also had to train in the streets and gardens around her house.</p>

<p>She often finds her mind wandering to Gaza's Mediterranean shore.</p>

<p>"Training back home was different. Every Friday my teammates and I would go and train by the sea," she said.</p>

<p>Karate is known for its strong focus on discipline and self-control, and this has helped the young karateka to "detach from reality" -- living as a refugee from a brutal war -- even for a little while.</p>

<p>"My emotions sometimes get the best of me. There are times I can't get through a full session" without remembering "fleeing on foot as air strikes fell all around us", she said.</p>

<p>Elbostami tries to focus on her goal -- "to represent my country and raise its flag in international competitions".</p>

<h3><strong>'It's for my country'</strong></h3>

<p>She has a long way to go, and her first stop on that journey is Egypt's own national championships in August.</p>

<p>"It's a tough challenge," she said, because Egyptian karate athletes have historically outperformed their Palestinian counterparts."</p>

<p>"But it will bring my level up, too."</p>

<p>Elbostami's Egyptian coach, Mamdouh Salem, told AFP that the teenager was an "athlete with a lot of potential, dedication and persistence".</p>

<p>"We're working on her technique, but ultimately karate is more a game of skill than talent -- I expect Mais will excel."</p>

<p>He said he wants to help her raise the Palestinian flag around the world.</p>

<p>"If we can't fight with them" in Gaza, "we can at least help them represent their country abroad", he said, echoing widespread Egyptian solidarity with the Palestinian cause.</p>

<p>Her Gazan teammates, coaches and most of her relatives may remain trapped in Gaza -- and she said dozens of them have been killed -- but against all odds, Elbostami has survived.</p>

<p>"So I don't have any excuse to keep me from achieving my goal," she said.</p>

<p>"I'll do everything I can to highlight the Palestinian cause. Every championship and every time I represent Palestine, it's for my country, for the martyrs and for the wounded."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vlkqk73g_mais-elbostami-_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[She and her family fled south from their home in the northern Gaza Strip,]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-is-nato-how-many-countries-are-part-of-it-6051077]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Is NATO, How Many Countries Are Part Of It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-is-nato-how-many-countries-are-part-of-it-6051077]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 08:04:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Born at the start of the Cold War, NATO -- the North Atlantic Treaty Organization -- is the world's biggest collective defence grouping with 32 members in Europe and North America.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Born at the start of the Cold War, NATO -- the North Atlantic Treaty Organization -- is the world's biggest collective defence grouping with 32 members in Europe and North America.</p>

<h3><strong>How many divisions?</strong></h3>

<p>NATO's military forces come from its member countries, put under a unified Allied command each time it launches a mission.</p>

<p>US forces are by far the biggest contingent. In Europe, there are some 79,000 US servicemen and women deployed, more than 48,000 of them in Germany, according to the Pentagon.</p>

<p>The only military equipment NATO itself owns is a fleet of sensor-loaded AWACS planes and drones.</p>

<p>Sweden became its newest member in March, swelling its potential ranks by 50,000 more troops -- around half of them reservists -- to more than three million, according to several specialised institutes.</p>

<h3><strong>Brussels HQ</strong></h3>

<p>NATO was created from a Washington Treaty signed on April 4, 1949. Its mission at the time was to counter the threat posed by the Soviet Union and to affirm the principle of mutual defence of its members.</p>

<p>In a Madrid summit following Russia's all-out invasion of Ukraine in 2022, the alliance adopted a new strategic concept designating Russia as "the gravest threat to Euro-Atlantic security".</p>

<p>Its 12 founding nations (Belgium, Canada, Denmark, France, Iceland, Italy, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Norway, Portugal, the United Kingdom and the United States) have been joined by others over succeeding years, up to Sweden's adhesion.</p>

<p>NATO's first headquarters was in London, then it was moved to Paris before being transferred to Brussels in 1966 where it remains today. Its SHAPE military command is in Mons, also in Belgium.</p>

<p>The alliance's head since 2014 has been Jens Stoltenberg, a 65-year-old former Norwegian prime minister. His term runs to the end of October this year -- when he will be succeeded by former Dutch premier Mark Rutte, 57.</p>

<p>NATO's main decision-making body is the North Atlantic Council.</p>

<h3><strong>Article 5</strong></h3>

<p>The core of NATO is Article 5 of its founding treaty which stipulates that an attack on one member is considered an attack on all.</p>

<p>It has been invoked just once to date: in 2001, in a show of allies' support for the United States the day after it was hit by the September 11 attacks.</p>

<p>NATO has carried out several missions over its history, including one in Afghanistan following the September 11, 2001 attacks. That came to an end with a hasty pull-out in September 2021 of the 10,000 personnel deployed at the time.</p>

<p>NATO is present in Iraq and notably in Kosovo, where it has 4,500 troops in its KFOR stabilisation force sent from 27 countries.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/p2q0add_nato-drill-afp_625x300_17_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NATO was created from a Washington Treaty signed on April 4, 1949.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-donald-trump-joe-biden-invokes-lord-almighty-amid-calls-to-end-reelection-bid-6050959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Invokes "Lord Almighty" Amid Calls To End Reelection Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-donald-trump-joe-biden-invokes-lord-almighty-amid-calls-to-end-reelection-bid-6050959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 07:28:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden on Friday in an ABC News interview refused to commit to an independent medical exam to reassure the public of his mental fitness, even as he insisted he has the stamina to serve another four years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden dismissed calls to end his reelection bid and denied that his debate performance wrought significant damage to his campaign, a defiant posture that risked further alarming Democrats who fear he has not honestly grappled with his biggest political crisis.</p>

<p>Biden on Friday in an ABC News interview refused to commit to an independent medical exam to reassure the public of his mental fitness, even as he insisted he has the stamina to serve another four years.</p>

<p>He did not accept that he trails Donald Trump in the polls, said he had not directly heard discussions among senior Democrats about asking him to step aside, and declared only the "Lord Almighty" would prompt him to even consider ending his bid.</p>

<p>And while the president, 81, avoided a significant gaffe like the ones that bedeviled his disjointed debate performance, the 22-minute prime-time interview with anchor George Stephanopoulos was unlikely to assuage concerns among the voters, donors, and Democratic officials who have spent the past week in a panic that he not only would fail to defeat his Republican opponent, but would not be able to serve another four years even if he managed reelection.</p>

<p>"I'll feel as long as I gave it my all and I did the goodest job as I know I can do, that's what this is about," Biden said when asked how he will feel in January if Trump wins the election, a nightmare scenario for Democrats.</p>

<p>Biden's posture is perhaps the only strategy available for a candidate who is determined to continue his bid to win a second term. After Biden unveiled a revamped stump speech earlier Friday that acknowledged his age and more forcefully attacked Trump, his campaign indicated he plans to soldier on with more events Sunday in battleground Pennsylvania and beyond.</p>

<p>Multiple polls released following the debate showed Biden losing ground to Trump, with several showing him trailing by 6 percentage points. The share of voters in a New York Times/Siena College poll who believe he is too old to be president grew to 74%.</p>

<h3><strong>Dismisses Polls</strong></h3>

<p>When asked if he believes he is not behind, however, Biden said "all the pollsters I talk to tell me it's a tossup."</p>

<p>One Democratic donor, who requested anonymity to speak candidly, said they are angry at those in Biden's orbit for not encouraging him to step down, calling the continued campaign delusional and selfish.</p>

<p>"He is dangerously out-of-touch with the concerns people have" David Axelrod, a former Obama White House adviser who has been critical of Biden, posted on X after the interview.</p>

<p>Before Biden's ABC appearance, Illinois Representative Mike Quigley joined a group of more than half a dozen House Democrats who have either explicitly called on the president to drop out, or said they believe he would lose to Trump in November.</p>

<p>Biden acknowledged Senator Mark Warner, a prominent Democrat from Virginia, was looking to rally other lawmakers to pressure him to drop out. The president said he had heard from others that he should remain in the race.</p>

<p>"Mark and I have a different perspective," Biden told Stephanopoulos.</p>

<p>"If the Lord Almighty came down and said, 'Joe, get out of the race,' I'd get out of the race. The Lord Almighty's not coming down," the president continued.</p>

<h3><strong>'Wasn't In Control'</strong></h3>

<p>Biden chalked up his poor debate performance to a "bad episode" brought on by a severe cold and that there was "no indication of any serious condition." Asked when he realized that he was having a bad night, Biden suggested that at one point he had been distracted by Trump shouting.</p>

<p>"I realized that I just wasn't in control," he said of that moment.</p>

<p>Asked if he had watched his debate performance, which alarmed Democratic allies, Biden said "I don't think I did, no."</p>

<p>The interview came during a trip to Wisconsin in which Biden flatly declared he was not considering dropping out of the race. He said those looking to pressure him were disrespecting the will of Democratic primary voters, and that he still believed he represented the best chance for Democrats of defeating Trump.</p>

<p>The issue will be put to the test over the coming week in the face of growing concern from Democratic lawmakers and donors.</p>

<p>After his trip to Pennsylvania, Biden hosts NATO leaders starting Tuesday at a summit in Washington. The president's ramped-up schedule is a response to panicked Democrats who have demanded he do more to prove to voters he is capable of serving another four years in the White House.</p>

<p>So far, some Democrats remain wary.</p>

<p>Biden met Wednesday behind closed doors with more than 20 Democratic governors in a bid to stem the crisis engulfing his presidency, telling them he is "in it to win it." He received public votes of confidence from several of them, including California's Gavin Newsom and Michigan's Gretchen Whitmer.</p>

<p>But privately, the governors had tough questions for the president and he acknowledged that he needs to get more sleep going forward, according to a person familiar with the discussion.</p>

<p>One of the participants, Massachusetts Governor Maura Healey, issued a statement Friday that stopped short of calling on Biden to drop out but appeared to push him to at least consider the possibility.</p>

<p>"I urge him to listen to the American people and carefully evaluate whether he remains our best hope to defeat Donald Trump," she said.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[So far, some Democrats remain wary.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-nato-turns-75-us-elections-and-ukraine-remain-key-focus-6050926]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As NATO Turns 75, US Elections And Ukraine Remain Key Focus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-nato-turns-75-us-elections-and-ukraine-remain-key-focus-6050926]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 07:17:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NATO's 75th-anniversary summit was meant to showcase the triumph of a larger, stronger alliance. Instead, leaders are coming together in Washington in the shadow of setbacks in Ukraine and electoral headwinds on both sides of the Atlantic.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NATO's 75th-anniversary summit was meant to showcase the triumph of a larger, stronger alliance. Instead, leaders are coming together in Washington in the shadow of setbacks in Ukraine and electoral headwinds on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, fighting for his political life after a disastrous debate against NATO sceptic Donald Trump, will turn his attention away from campaigning to welcome leaders of the 32-nation transatlantic alliance for three days from Tuesday.</p>

<p>Biden has also invited the leaders of Australia, Japan, New Zealand and South Korea, a sign of NATO's growing role in Asia in the face of a rising China.</p>

<p>But the star of the summit is set to be Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky, who is looking for firm signs of support although NATO will not be extending his country an invitation to join.</p>

<p>Founded in 1949 to provide collective defence against the Soviet Union, NATO returned in some ways to its original mission when allies rallied to Ukraine's defence after it was invaded by Russia in 2022.</p>

<p>Ukrainians heartened most of the West by repelling Russia in its push for a quick victory. But Moscow's troops have been grinding on, making advances in the east.</p>

<p>A European official acknowledged the mood ahead of the NATO summit has become "gloomy" with Ukraine slipping on a fragile frontline.</p>

<p>"This summit will be very different from the initial plans because it is happening at a critical juncture for European security," the official said on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>"Russia is today in a situation which is quite comfortable. They think they can simply wait it out," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump casts shadow</strong></h3>

<p>Max Bergmann, director of the Europe, Russia and Eurasia program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, said the summit comes at "the best of times, and the worst of times."</p>

<p>"The best of times, in the sense that the alliance knows what it's about -- deterring Russia. Alliance members are spending more," he said.</p>

<p>"But it's also sort of the worst of times -- obviously because of the war in Ukraine, challenges of ramping up European defence spending, concerns about the reliability of the United States."</p>

<p>Trump, who has voiced admiration in the past for Russian strongman Vladimir Putin, has long criticized NATO as an unfair burden on the United States, which spends far more than any other ally.</p>

<p>The 2024 Republican presidential candidate -- whose first term was marked by an impeachment over his strong-arming of Zelensky -- has insisted he can stop the war, with his advisors floating the possibility of conditioning future US assistance on Ukraine entering negotiations to surrender territory.</p>

<p>Trump has enjoyed a narrow lead against Biden in recent polls. Meanwhile, France -- where President Emmanuel Macron has mulled sending troops to Ukraine -- is also facing a political shift with the strong gains in legislative elections by the far-right, which is historically close to Russia.</p>

<p>Those setbacks come as Putin recently hosted Viktor Orban, the Russia-friendly prime minister of Hungary, which currently holds the EU's rotating presidency.</p>

<p>The NATO summit is also expected to mark a diplomatic debut for a new leader -- British Prime Minister Keir Starmer, after his Labour Party's landslide election victory.</p>

<h3><strong>Finding a path for Ukraine&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>NATO's outgoing secretary-general, Jens Stoltenberg, has led efforts to put the alliance itself, not the United States, in the lead in coordinating military assistance for Ukraine.</p>

<p>Stoltenberg also wants allies to commit to provide at least 40 billion euros ($43 billion) per year in military aid to Ukraine, ensuring reliable and consistent support as Kyiv prepares for a long war against Russia.</p>

<p>Diplomats have dubbed such measures as "Trump-proofing" the alliance, although few believe that NATO or support for Ukraine could endure in the same way without the United States, which under Biden has approved $175 billion for Kyiv in military and other assistance.</p>

<p>The summit also comes on the heels of two more nations joining NATO -- Finland and Sweden -- which both overcame earlier reluctance to formally enter the alliance after witnessing the invasion of Ukraine, which had unsuccessfully sought membership.</p>

<p>Diplomats say that the United States is eager to stage a smooth, drama-free meeting and avoid the bitter recriminations at NATO's summit last year in Lithuania, where Zelensky failed to win firmer commitments for Ukraine to join the alliance.</p>

<p>Ukrainian officials acknowledge there is no chance of a change of heart in Washington. Biden and German Chancellor Olaf Scholz have led opposition to Ukrainian membership, believing that admitting a country already at war would be tantamount to NATO itself confronting nuclear-armed Russia.</p>

<p>Biden instead has reached a 10-year security agreement with Ukraine, with Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin saying the United States will soon announce $2.3 billion in new military assistance.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jehpjoj_zelesnki-nato-_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NATO was founded in 1949.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wwe-legend-john-cena-announces-retirement-after-20-years-in-the-ring-6050893]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WWE Legend John Cena Announces Retirement After 20 Years In The Ring]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wwe-legend-john-cena-announces-retirement-after-20-years-in-the-ring-6050893]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 07:04:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[John Cena, a 16-time WWE Champion, has announced retirement from in-ring competition with effect from 2025. Mr Cena announced his retirement during a surprise appearance at the 'Money in the Bank' event in Toronto today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>John Cena, a 16-time WWE Champion, has announced his retirement from in-ring competitions with effect from 2025. Mr Cena announced his retirement during a surprise appearance at the 'Money in the Bank' event in Toronto today.</p>

<p>The WWE legend, 47, hit the ring carrying a towel with a slightly altered version of his most famous catchphrase, "My Time Is Now", this time reading, "The Last Time Is Now." His shirt simply read, "John Cena Farewell Tour." When Mr Cena began to speak, the Toronto crowd erupted with chants of "No! No! No!".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BREAKING NEWS: John Cena announced at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MITB?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MITB</a> he will retire from in-ring competition in 2025.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThankYouCena?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ThankYouCena</a> <a href="https://t.co/6TPnYI5iU2">pic.twitter.com/6TPnYI5iU2</a></p>
— WWE (@WWE) <a href="https://twitter.com/WWE/status/1809745006644564234?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 7, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Tonight, I officially announce my retirement from WWE," Mr &nbsp;Cena declared. He later clarified that it wouldn't entail immediate retirement but in 2025. Mr Cena said he will compete in the 2025 Royal Rumble, Elimination Chamber and then at Wrestlemania 41 in Las Vegas at Allegiant Stadium.</p>

<p>Mr Cena who made his WWE debut in 2002, has had a storeyed career in wrestling entertainment. He has had memorable rivalries against some of the biggest names in wrestling like The Rock, Triple H, CM Punk, and Randy Orton.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Thank you so much for allowing me the opportunity to play in a house that you guys built for so many years," Mr Cena said, addressing the WWE Universe. "Thank you so much for your voice because it's really loud and for your honesty because it's always brutal."</p>

<p>Besides wrestling, Mr Cena has also appeared in films such as The Suicide Squad. Fast X and The Independent, among others.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-11/n3ne48c_john-cena_625x300_30_November_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[John Cena made his WWE debut in 2002.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jimmy-maladina-senior-papua-new-guinea-minister-arrested-for-assaulting-woman-in-australia-6050703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Senior Papua New Guinea Minister Arrested For Assaulting Woman In Australia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jimmy-maladina-senior-papua-new-guinea-minister-arrested-for-assaulting-woman-in-australia-6050703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 05:52:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Papua New Guinea's influential petroleum minister has been charged with assault following a "domestic dispute" near Sydney's famed Bondi Beach, Australian police said Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Papua New Guinea's influential petroleum minister has been charged with assault following a "domestic dispute" near Sydney's famed Bondi Beach, Australian police said Sunday.</p>

<p>Jimmy Maladina, a crucial player in ongoing international negotiations over a lucrative natural gas project, was arrested on Saturday morning.</p>

<p>Police said they found a "31-year-old woman with facial injuries" after they were called to an address near Bondi, allegedly sustained in an "altercation" with Maladina.</p>

<p>Maladina is listed to appear in a Sydney court on Thursday, court documents show, and has been charged with "assault occasioning actual bodily harm".</p>

<p>The 58-year-old said in a statement he was "committed to handling this situation with integrity and transparency".</p>

<p>Papua New Guinea's vast and untapped deposits of natural gas have attracted considerable interest from foreign prospectors.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/5u9pe4ro_australia-police-generic-afp_625x300_15_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kentucky-mass-shooting-4-killed-in-mass-shooting-at-birthday-pool-party-in-us-suspect-kills-self-6050611]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Killed In Mass Shooting At Birthday Pool Party In US, Suspect Kills Self]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kentucky-mass-shooting-4-killed-in-mass-shooting-at-birthday-pool-party-in-us-suspect-kills-self-6050611]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 05:24:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four people were killed and three others injured in a shooting at a home in Kentucky in the US on Saturday, police said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four people were killed and three others injured in a shooting at a home in Kentucky in the US on Saturday, police said. According to the Florence Police Department, four individuals were declared dead at the location, while three others were taken to a nearby hospital and are currently in critical but stable condition.</p>

<p>Officers responded to the residence at nearly 3 am on Saturday and as they approached the home, they still heard shots being fired, Police Chief Jeff Mallery said at a press conference. People were attending a birthday pool party at that time.</p>

<p>The suspect, described as an adult male, fled the scene in a vehicle prior to police arrival, leading to a police chase. The suspect then drove off the road and crashed into a ditch. Law enforcement found the suspect with a self-inflicted gunshot wound. He was transported to a nearby hospital, where he was later pronounced dead, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Party attendees recognised the suspect and provided his identity to the police. According to Mallery, he had a prior conviction for a sexual offence, though it does not appear to be connected to the shooting.</p>

<p>Officials said that an initial investigation indicated the suspect acted alone, and there was no danger to the public.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aek4ib5o_us-police-generic_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-staying-in-the-race-but-his-us-presidential-reelection-bid-against-donald-trump-hangs-in-balance-6050585]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden "Staying In The Race" But His Reelection Bid Hangs In Balance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-staying-in-the-race-but-his-us-presidential-reelection-bid-against-donald-trump-hangs-in-balance-6050585]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 05:11:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden's presidential reelection bid hung in the balance Saturday, after his latest efforts to put a disastrous debate showing behind him failed to silence voices urging him to quit the White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden's presidential reelection bid hung in the balance Saturday after his latest efforts to put a disastrous debate showing behind him failed to silence voices urging him to quit the White House race.</p>

<p>Murmurs of dissent within his own Democratic Party have -- in the case of five individual House representatives -- morphed into direct calls for him to drop out. And a number of key donors have threatened to cut off funding if Biden insists on staying the course.</p>

<p>"I do not believe that the President can effectively campaign and win against Donald Trump," Angie Craig, the latest House Democrat to break ranks, said Saturday.</p>

<p>The House minority leader, Hakeem Jeffries, has scheduled a virtual meeting of senior Democrat representatives for Sunday to discuss the best way forward, and Democrat Senator Mark Warner is reportedly working to convene a similar forum in the upper chamber.</p>

<p>In what had been billed as a make-or-break TV interview on Friday, Biden's strategy was to flatly deny the falling poll numbers and concerns over his mental and physical fitness triggered by his dismal performance against rival Donald Trump.</p>

<p>He blamed a severe cold for the debate debacle and insisted it was just a "bad night" rather than evidence of increasing frailty and cognitive decline. And the 81-year-old was adamant that he would not be pressured to end his campaign.</p>

<p>"If the Lord Almighty came down and said, 'Joe, get out of the race,' I'd get out of the race," he said. "But the Lord Almighty is not coming down."</p>

<p>Calls for less divine intervention do, however, appear to be strengthening.</p>

<h3><strong>Internal dissent</strong></h3>

<p>Biden's campaign team is pushing ahead regardless, with two events planned in Pennsylvania on Sunday and visits to other battleground states later in the month.</p>

<p>At a rally in Wisconsin before Friday's interview, Biden had delivered a forceful, energetic stump speech, unequivocally declaring, "I'm staying in the race. I'll beat Donald Trump."</p>

<p>Then came the sit-down with the ABC network that appeared unlikely to soothe the concerns of critics who say that -- away from a teleprompter -- Biden can struggle to communicate.</p>

<p>Some of his answers were tentative, meandering and difficult to follow, even as he sought to deflect questions about his mental acuity and dismissed the notion that his party would consider replacing him.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign had another small fire to put out Saturday after it emerged that the White House had provided the questions for interviews the president gave to two Black radio stations on Friday.</p>

<h3><strong>Out of touch?</strong></h3>

<p>Democratic strategist David Axelrod suggested in a CNN op-ed that Biden is engaged in "Denial. Delusion. Defiance."</p>

<p>"The stakes are as great as Biden describes. And if he believes it, as I think he does, he will eventually do what duty and love of country requires, and step aside," Axelrod wrote in the piece published Saturday.</p>

<p>"If he does not, it will be Biden's age, and not Trump's moral and ethical void, that will dominate the rest of this most important campaign and sully the president's historic legacy."</p>

<p>Trump, meanwhile, sarcastically suggested Biden should "ignore his many critics and move forward, with alacrity and strength."</p>

<p>"He should be sharp, precise and energetic, just like he was in The Debate," the Republican challenger said in a social media post Saturday.</p>

<p>For now, Democrats are largely keeping a lid on any simmering discontent with their leader -- at least in public.</p>

<p>But with election day just four months away, any move to replace Biden as nominee would need to be made sooner rather than later, and the meetings of top Congressional Democrats in coming days will be scrutinized for any signs of more open rebellion.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, for Biden and his campaign team, the strategy seems to be to ride it out.</p>

<p>His next major test will be a press conference scheduled for Thursday during the NATO leaders' summit in Washington.</p>

<p>When pressed in the ABC interview on why he doesn't take an independent neurological exam, Biden argued that the role of US president meant being subjected to constant mental assessment.</p>

<p>"I have a cognitive test every single day," he said. "Not only am I campaigning, I'm running the world."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gbfd0cv8_joe-biden_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's latest efforts to put a disastrous debate showing behind him have failed to silence voices]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mars-dune-alpha-four-humans-who-were-living-on-mars-finish-year-long-nasa-mission-6050530]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Four Humans, Who Were Living "On Mars", Finish Year-Long Mission]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mars-dune-alpha-four-humans-who-were-living-on-mars-finish-year-long-nasa-mission-6050530]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 04:59:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anca Selariu, Ross Brockwell, Nathan Jones, and Kelly Haston have spent the past 378 days sealed inside the "Martian" habitat in Houston, Texas, part of NASA's research into what it will take to put humans on the Red Planet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The NASA astronaut knocks loudly three times on a what appears to be a nondescript door, and calls cheerfully: "You ready to come out?"</p>

<p>The reply is inaudible, but beneath his mask he appears to be grinning as he yanks the door open -- and four scientists who have spent a year away from all other human contact, simulating a mission to Mars, spill out to cheers and applause.</p>

<p>Anca Selariu, Ross Brockwell, Nathan Jones and team leader Kelly Haston have spent the past 378 days sealed inside the "Martian" habitat in Houston, Texas, part of NASA's research into what it will take to put humans on the Red Planet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They have been growing vegetables, conducting "Marswalks," and operating under what NASA terms "additional stressors" -- such as communication delays with "Earth", including their families; isolation and confinement.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">LIVE NOW: The first ever CHAPEA crew will exit the ground-based Mars simulated habitat after 378 days. <a href="https://t.co/vFESM9DUyw">https://t.co/vFESM9DUyw</a></p>
— NASA's Johnson Space Center (@NASA_Johnson) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA_Johnson/status/1809693957233717714?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It's the kind of experience that would make anyone who lived through pandemic lockdowns shudder -- but all four were beaming as they reemerged Saturday, their hair slightly more unruly and their emotion apparent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Hello. It's actually so wonderful just to be able to say hello to you," Haston, a biologist, said with a laugh.</p>

<p>"I really hope I don't cry standing up here in front of all of you," Jones, an emergency room doctor, said as he took to the microphone -- and nearly doing just that several moments later as he spotted his wife in the crowd.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The habitat, dubbed Mars Dune Alpha, is a 3D printed 1,700 square-foot (160 square-meter) facility, complete with bedrooms, a gym, common areas, and a vertical farm to grow food.</p>

<p>An outdoor area, separated by an airlock, is filled with red sand and is where the team donned suits to conduct their "Marswalks", though it is still covered rather than being open air.</p>

<p>"They have spent more than a year in this habitat conducting crucial science, most of it nutrition-based and how that impacts their performace ... as we prepare to send people on to the Red Planet," Steve Koerner, deputy director at NASA's Johnson Space Center, told the crowd.</p>

<p>"I'm very appreciative."</p>

<p>This mission is the first of a series of three planned by NASA, grouped under the title CHAPEA -- Crew Health and Performance Exploration Analog.</p>

<p>A year-long mission simulating life on Mars took place in 2015-2016 in a habitat in Hawaii, and although NASA participated in it, it was not at the helm.</p>

<p>Under its Artemis program, America plans to send humans back to the Moon in order to learn how to live there long-term to help prepare a trip to Mars, sometime towards the end of the 2030s.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9hm2755_nasa-mars-mission_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The habitat was dubbed Mars Dune Alpha]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/made-our-city-unliveable-barcelona-residents-protest-against-mass-tourism-in-spain-6050119]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Made City Unliveable": Barcelona Residents Protest Against Mass Tourism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/made-our-city-unliveable-barcelona-residents-protest-against-mass-tourism-in-spain-6050119]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 02:24:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The second most visited country after France, Spain received 85 million foreign visitors in 2023, an increase of 18.7 percent from the previous year, according to the National Statistics Institute.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of protesters marched Saturday in Barcelona to denounce mass tourism and its effect on Spain's most visited city, the latest in a series of similar marches in the country.</p>

<p>Under the slogan "Enough! Let's put limits on tourism", some 2,800 people -- according to police -- marched along a waterfront district of Barcelona to demand a new economic model that would reduce the millions of tourists that visit every year.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Demonstrators hold a sign reading Barcelona is not for sale during a protest against mass tourism in Barcelona" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vfsqgni_barcelona-protest_625x300_07_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Demonstrators hold a sign reading Barcelona is not for sale during a protest against mass tourism in Barcelona" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Demonstrators hold a sign reading 'Barcelona is not for sale' during a protest against mass tourism in Barcelona<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>"I have nothing against tourism, but here in Barcelona we are suffering from an excess of tourism that has made our city unliveable," said Jordi Guiu, a 70-year-old sociologist.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With banners saying "Reduce tourism now!", the protesters chanted slogans such as "Tourists out of our neighbourhood", stopping in front of hotels to the surprise of visitors.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Barcelona's rising cost of housing, up 68 percent in the past decade according to local authorities, is one of the main issues for the movement, along with the effects of tourism on local commerce and working conditions in the city of 1.6 million inhabitants. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Local shops are closing to make way for stores that do not serve the needs of neighbourhoods. People cannot afford their rents," said Isa Miralles, a 35-year-old musician who lives in the Barceloneta district.</p>

<p>The northeastern coastal city, with internationally famous sites such as La Sagrada Familia, received more than 12 million tourists last year, according to local authorities. &nbsp;</p>

<p>To combat the "negative effects of mass tourism", the city council run by the Socialist Jaume Collboni announced 10 days ago that it was banning tourist apartment rentals -- there are now more than 10,000 -- by 2028 so that they can be put back on the local housing market.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The announcement could lead to a legal battle and is opposed by an association of tourist apartments who say it will just feed the black market.</p>

<p>The Barcelona protests come after similar demonstrations in tourist hotspots such as Malaga, Palma de Mallorca and the Canary Islands.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Demonstrators march during a protest against mass tourism in Barcelona" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kceg3fh_barcelona-protest_625x300_07_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Demonstrators march during a protest against mass tourism in Barcelona" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Demonstrators march during a protest against mass tourism in Barcelona<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>The second most visited country after France, Spain received 85 million foreign visitors in 2023, an increase of 18.7 percent from the previous year, according to the National Statistics Institute.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The most visited region was Catalonia, whose capital is Barcelona, with 18 million, followed by the Balearic Islands (14.4 million) and the Canary Islands (13.9 million).&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/n8paq51_barcelona-protest_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Spain's most visited region in 2023 was Catalonia, whose capital is Barcelona]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-strike-kills-16-at-un-school-in-gaza-ahead-of-truce-talks-6049967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strike Kills 16 At UN School In Gaza Ahead Of Truce Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-strike-kills-16-at-un-school-in-gaza-ahead-of-truce-talks-6049967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 01:34:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel carried out deadly airstrikes in Gaza Saturday, including one on a UN-run school that killed 16 people according to the Hamas-run authorities, and as violence also gripped its northern border with Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel carried out deadly airstrikes in Gaza Saturday, including one on a UN-run school that killed 16 people according to the Hamas-run authorities, and as violence also gripped its northern border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>The fighting raged as diplomatic efforts to halt the war, which enters its tenth month on Sunday, continued with Israel saying Friday it would send a delegation next week to continue talks with Qatari mediators.</p>

<p>In a statement announcing the move, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's spokesperson said "gaps" remained with Hamas on how to secure a ceasefire and hostage release deal.</p>

<p>That came after a delegation led by Israel's Mossad intelligence agency chief David Barnea held a first round of talks with mediators in Doha.</p>

<p>"It was agreed that next week Israeli negotiators will travel to Doha to continue the talks. There are still gaps between the parties," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>There has been no truce since a one-week pause in November during which 80 Israeli hostages were freed in return for 240 Palestinians held in Israeli prisons.</p>

<p>The war continued unabated, with Hamas-run Gaza's health ministry saying 16 people were killed in a strike on a school run by UNRWA, the UN agency for Palestinian refugees, that was sheltering displaced people in Nuseirat in central Gaza.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its aircraft had targeted "terrorists" operating around the Al-Jawni school.</p>

<p>The military earlier said it had conducted operations across much of the Gaza Strip, including Shujaiya in the north, Deir al-Balah in central Gaza and Rafah in the south.</p>

<p>Shujaiya is among the areas the military had previously declared to be cleared of Hamas, but where fighting is again taking place.</p>

<p>Paramedics on Saturday reported 10 deaths in a separate air strike on a house in Nuseirat refugee camp.</p>

<p>The Hamas press office and paramedics said four journalists working for local media outlets were killed in strikes overnight, and UNRWA said two of its employees had been killed.</p>

<p>UNRWA, which coordinates much of the aid delivered to Gaza, says 194 of its employees have been killed in the war.</p>

<h3><strong>'Ball in Israel's court'</strong></h3>

<p>The United States, which has mediated talks alongside Qatar and Egypt, has talked up the prospects of a deal saying there is a "pretty significant opening" for both sides.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden announced a pathway to a truce deal in May that he said had been proposed by Israel.</p>

<p>This included an initial six-week truce, Israeli withdrawal from Gaza population centres and the freeing of hostages by Hamas.</p>

<p>Talks subsequently stalled, but a US official said Thursday that a new proposal from Hamas "moves the process forward and may provide the basis for closing the deal".</p>

<p>Senior Hamas official Osama Hamdan told AFP that new ideas from the group had been "conveyed by the mediators to the American side, which welcomed them and passed them on to the Israeli side. Now the ball is in the Israeli court."</p>

<p>Pressure has mounted domestically for a hostage release deal, with regular protests and rallies in Israel.</p>

<p>"It's important that we reach a deal so that all the mothers can embrace their children and husbands, just as I hug my mother every morning now," rescued hostage Almog Mair Jan said in a recorded message to a rally in Tel Aviv Saturday.</p>

<p>The war began with Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on southern Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures. Hamas also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza including 42 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>In response, Israel has carried out a military offensive that has killed at least 38,098 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-ruled territory.</p>

<p>The war has uprooted 90 percent of Gaza's population, destroyed much of its housing and other infrastructure, and left almost 500,000 people enduring "catastrophic" hunger, UN agencies say.</p>

<p>The main stumbling block to a truce deal has been Hamas's demand for a permanent end to the fighting, which Netanyahu and his far-right coalition partners strongly reject.</p>

<p>The veteran hawk demands the release of the hostages and insists the war will not end until Israel has destroyed Hamas's ability to fight or govern.</p>

<h3><strong>Sirens and air strikes</strong></h3>

<p>Israel and Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah movement have exchanged cross-border fire almost daily since the Gaza war began, but attacks have escalated over the past month.</p>

<p>This has raised fears of a major conflagration between the staunch enemies that could draw in others including Iran.</p>

<p>Early Saturday, sirens blared over northern Israel and the military said it had downed a "suspicious aerial target" and two "hostile aircraft" launched from Lebanon hit open ground.</p>

<p>The military said earlier it had attacked "a number of Hezbollah terror targets in southern Lebanon" overnight, all near the border.</p>

<p>A source close to Hezbollah said an Israeli drone strike targeted a vehicle in eastern Lebanon Saturday, killing an official from Hezbollah. Israel said he was part of the group's air defence unit.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/sag66o8o_israelhamas-war_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gaza's health ministry said 16 people were killed in a strike on a school run by UNRWA in Nuseirat]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/navendu-mishra-keir-starmers-labour-party-candidate-with-roots-in-up-wins-uk-general-elections-6049740]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New UK PM's Party Candidate With Roots In UP Wins General Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/navendu-mishra-keir-starmers-labour-party-candidate-with-roots-in-up-wins-uk-general-elections-6049740]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:16:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Labour Party candidate's landslide victory in the UK general elections sparked celebrations thousands of kilometres away in Uttar Pradesh's Kanpur and Gorakhpur.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Labour Party candidate's landslide victory in the UK general elections sparked celebrations thousands of kilometres away in Uttar Pradesh's Kanpur and Gorakhpur.</p>

<p>Navendu Mishra, elected to the House of Commons for a second consecutive term from the Stockport constituency, was born in Kanpur in 1989. His mother's paternal home is in Gorakhpur.</p>

<p>Mr Mishra's maternal uncle Nilendar Pandey, a social worker and businessman who now lives in Lucknow, told PTI that some people in Gorakhpur, Lucknow and Kanpur celebrated his victory by distributing sweets and setting off crackers.</p>

<p>Mr Pandey said Mr Mishra left for the UK with his parents when he was four years old. His father was a marketing manager for Indian Petrochemicals Corporation Limited and moved to the UK after taking charge of a British company.</p>

<p>Mr Mishra grew up in the UK with his brother and a sister.</p>

<p>He entered politics after completing his studies in London and was elected to the House of Commons in the 2019 elections on a Labour Party ticket from Stockport.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's an honour to be officially nominated as the Labour candidate for Stockport constituency.<br />
<br />
Since 2019, I have always put the priorities of local residents first. If re-elected, I will continue to work hard for Brinnington, Edgeley, Davenport, the Heatons and Reddish. <a href="https://t.co/Ctv1CHn58F">pic.twitter.com/Ctv1CHn58F</a></p>
— Navendu Mishra (@NavPMishra) <a href="https://twitter.com/NavPMishra/status/1798363908820079061?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Pandey said Mr Mishra entered politics through the trade union movement.</p>

<p>Mr Mishra is very close to him, Mr Pandey said and added that his nephew called him after winning the election to seek his blessings.</p>

<p>Mr Pandey said, "He (Mishra) likes coming to India. He is always keen on doing something for his country." "He visits India once every year or two and makes it a point to visit relatives from Gorakhpur to Delhi. He is a vegetarian and loves home-cooked food common in eastern Uttar Pradesh," he said.</p>

<p>Praising his nephew, Pandey said, "You can guess his popularity by his victory margin. In the UK, where elections are won by margins of only 1,000-2,000 votes, Mishra won by about 16,000 votes."</p>

<p>Mr Mishra secured 21,787 of the votes cast. His closest contender, Reform UK candidate Lynn Schofield, got 6,517 votes.</p>

<p>Mr Pandey said Mr Mishra returned to India for the first time after about seven years in the UK and spent time at the home of his maternal grandparents in Gorakhpur.</p>

<p>"Mishra used to fly kites and play cricket in the streets with the children of locals, including my two sons and daughter. My children are also ecstatic over his victory," he added.</p>

<p>During a recent visit to India, Mr Mishra led a delegation to meet Gujarat Chief Minister Bhupendra Patel. The delegation also met External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar in Delhi.</p>

<p>Following this, he spent time with his family in Delhi and Lucknow, Mr Pandey said.</p>

<p>Political experts claimed that Mr Mishra's victory and his connection with India would strengthen bilateral relations and cultural, political and social ties between the two nations.</p>

<p>Mr Pandey said Mr Mishra had also planned to visit the Ram temple in Ayodhya but that programme did not materialise.</p>

<p>Ishwar Singh, an associate of Mr Pandey in Gorakhpur, told PTI, "Mishra was inspired to join politics and social service by his maternal uncle Nilendar Pandey."</p>

<p>"When he visited Gorakhpur at a young age, he used to see the crowds gathering to meet Pandey and got inspired," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Mishra's paternal home in Kanpur's Arya Nagar was also teeming with locals, gathered to congratulated the family on his second successive election victory.</p>

<p>Mr Mishra last visited his family home in Arya Nagar about two years ago.</p>

<p>On Friday, Keir Starmer became the UK's new prime minister after his Labour Party secured a landslide victory in a general election in which weary voters inflicted a "sobering verdict" on Rishi Sunak-led Conservatives.</p>

<p>The Labour Party secured 412 seats in the 650-member House of Commons. Mr Sunak's Conservatives won just 121 seats.</p>

<p>Discussing plans to invite his nephew to India, Mr Pandey said, "We have invited Mishra to come here soon and a welcome ceremony will be organised in Lucknow after his arrival."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5h0qd12_navendu-mishra_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Navendu Mishra secured 21,787 of the votes cast]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-accepts-us-proposal-on-talks-over-releasing-israeli-hostages-report-6049297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Accepts US Proposal On Talks Over Releasing Israeli Hostages: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-accepts-us-proposal-on-talks-over-releasing-israeli-hostages-report-6049297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 06 Jul 2024 22:43:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas has accepted a US proposal to begin talks on releasing Israeli hostages, including soldiers and men, 16 days after the first phase of an agreement aimed at ending the Gaza war, a senior Hamas source told Reuters on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas has accepted a US proposal to begin talks on releasing Israeli hostages, including soldiers and men, 16 days after the first phase of an agreement aimed at ending the Gaza war, a senior Hamas source told Reuters on Saturday.</p>

<p>The Hamas group has dropped a demand that Israel first commit to a permanent ceasefire before signing the agreement, and would allow negotiations to achieve that throughout the six-week first phase, the source told Reuters on condition of anonymity because the talks are private.</p>

<p>A Palestinian official close to the internationally mediated peace efforts had said the proposal could lead to a framework agreement if embraced by Israel and would end the nine-month-old war between Israel and Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>A source in Israel's negotiating team, speaking on condition of anonymity, said on Friday there was now a real chance of achieving agreement. That was in sharp contrast to past instances in the nine-month-old war in Gaza, when Israel said conditions attached by Hamas were unacceptable.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Saturday, the Jewish Sabbath. On Friday his office said talks would continue next week and emphasised that gaps between the sides still remained.</p>

<p>The conflict has claimed the lives of more than 38,000 Palestinians, according to Gaza health officials, since Hamas attacked southern Israeli cities on Oct. 7, killing 1,200 people and taking some 250 hostages, according to official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The new proposal ensures that mediators would guarantee a temporary ceasefire, aid delivery and the withdrawal of Israeli troops as long as indirect talks continue to implement the second phase of the agreement, the Hamas source said.</p>

<p>Efforts to secure a ceasefire and hostage release in Gaza have intensified over the past few days with active shuttle diplomacy among Washington, Israel and Qatar, which is leading mediation efforts from Doha, where the exiled Hamas leadership is based.</p>

<p>A regional source said the US administration was trying hard to secure a deal before the presidential election in November.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said on Friday that the head of Israel's Mossad intelligence agency had returned from an initial meeting with mediators in Qatar and that negotiations would continue next week.</p>

<p>Some families of hostages on Saturday gave a statement to reporters ahead of a weekly hostage rally in Tel Aviv, in which they called on Netanyahu to go through with the deal.</p>

<p>"For the first time in many months, we feel hope," said Einav Zangauker, the mother of Matan Zangauker, 24, who was abducted from his kibbutz home on Oct. 7. "This is an opportunity that cannot be missed," she said.</p>

<p><strong>Fighting Rages</strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Israeli forces stepped up military strikes across the enclave, killing at least 29 Palestinians in the past 24 hours, and wounding 100 others, the territory's health officials said.</p>

<p>Among those killed in separate air strikes were five local journalists, raising the death count of journalists since Oct 7 to 158, according to the Hamas-led Gaza government media office.</p>

<p>Israeli forces, which have deepened their incursions into Rafah, near the border with Egypt, killed four Palestinian policemen and wounded eight others, in an air strike on their vehicle on Saturday, health officials said.</p>

<p>A statement issued by the Hamas-run interior ministry said the four included Fares Abdel-Al, the head of the police force in western Rafah neighbourhood of Tel Al-Sultan.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said forces continued "intelligence-base operations" in Rafah, destroyed several underground structures, seized weapons and equipment, and killed several Palestinian gunmen.</p>

<p>Israel said its operations in Rafah aimed to eradicate the last Hamas armed wing battalions.</p>

<p>In the central Al-Nuseirat camp, one of the enclave's eight historic refugee camps, an Israeli air strike on a house killed 10 Palestinians, medics said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it eliminated a Hamas rocket cell that operated from inside a humanitarian-designated area. It said it carried out a precise strike after taking measures to ensure civilians were unharmed. Hamas denies Israeli accusations it uses civilian properties for military purposes.</p>

<p>The armed wings of Hamas and the Islamic Jihad said fighters attacked Israeli forces in several areas of the enclave by anti-tank rockets and mortar bombs.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/2pt0puu_israel-army-reuters_625x300_31_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Efforts to secure a ceasefire in Gaza have intensified over the past few days (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-crushing-defeat-fight-begins-for-survival-of-uks-conservative-party-6049245]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Crushing Poll Defeat, UK's Conservatives Scrambling To Rebuild]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-crushing-defeat-fight-begins-for-survival-of-uks-conservative-party-6049245]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 06 Jul 2024 22:31:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's Conservative Party, thrashed by Labour at the general election, on Saturday faced the task of rebuilding as leading right wingers warned it could face extinction unless it starts listening to its core voters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Conservative Party, thrashed by Labour at the general election, on Saturday faced the task of rebuilding as leading right wingers warned it could face extinction unless it starts listening to its core voters.</p>

<p>A record number of ex-prime minister Rishi Sunak's top team and other prominent Tories lost their seats in Thursday's electoral drubbing.</p>

<p>The anti-immigration Reform UK party led by Brexit firebrand Nigel Farage maximised the damage by splitting the right-wing vote and picking up former Tory supporters in key constituencies.</p>

<p>Even before campaigning had ended, one ex-minister had launched an excoriating attack on the party for not grasping that "our failure to unite the right would destroy us".</p>

<p>Former interior minister Suella Braverman, seen as a leadership contender, correctly predicted the Tories would haemorrhage votes to Reform.</p>

<p>"Why? Because we failed to cut immigration or tax or deal with the net-zero and woke policies we have presided over for 14 years," she wrote in the Daily Telegraph.</p>

<p>Conceding inevitable defeat, she called for a "searingly honest post-match analysis", adding that it would "decide whether our party continues to exist at all".</p>

<p>Major British political parties have seen dramatic downturns in their fortunes before.</p>

<p>In the years after World War I, a divided Liberal Party found itself supplanted by the Labour Party as the main opposition.</p>

<p>The party of 19th century political giant William Gladstone and World War I leader David Lloyd George never again regained its earlier status as a party of government.</p>

<p><strong>'New movement'</strong></p>

<p>Other senior party voices to deliver an early diagnosis of the Conservatives' current predicament included David Frost, chief Brexit negotiator under ex-PM Boris Johnson.</p>

<p>David Frost resigned from government in December 2021, citing Johnson's tax hikes and net zero commitments among other complaints.</p>

<p>To revive traditional Conservative values and electability "after the cataclysm", he called for the creation of a "new movement for "reformed conservatism".</p>

<p>Sunak has said he will stay on as party leader until arrangements are put in place to choose a successor amid fears the party will now descend into bitter infighting.</p>

<p>Potential leadership candidates who managed to hang on to their seats include former home secretaries Braverman and Priti Patel. Former finance minister Jeremy Hunt became the first to rule himself out on Saturday telling GB News that "the time had passed".</p>

<p>"There's going to be a very immediate issue around how to relate to Nigel Farage," Michael Kenny, director of the Bennett Institue for Public Policy at the University of Cambridge, told AFP.</p>

<p>He said there would be a push to find a leadership candidate who could unite the party but "not provide an opening to Farage".</p>

<p>Others may look for someone potentially "more open to the idea of fusing with Reform".</p>

<p>Kenny said what had been unusual about this election was the way the "battle for the soul of the party" had been started before a single vote was cast.</p>

<p>With the Conservatives scoring a record low of just 121 seats, handing Starmer's government a majority in parliament of more than 170, some have predicted Labour could be in power for a generation.</p>

<p><strong>'Civil war'</strong></p>

<p>However, Philip Cowley, professor of politics at Queen Mary University of London, cautioned against too much pessimism.</p>

<p>He said people had been "writing off" one or more of the main parties ever since the early 1960s, when it was claimed demographics meant Labour could never win again "only for them to do so in 1964", he told AFP.</p>

<p>In 1992, after the Conservatives won their fourth consecutive victory, there was again "lots of talk about how Britain was now a one-party state, only for Labour to go on to win their greatest ever landslide five years later", Cowley added.</p>

<p>More recently, he noted, commentators suggested the Conservatives could never win again during the tenures of former Labour leaders Tony Blair and Gordon Brown.</p>

<p>"And yet they did," in 2010 with David Cameron.</p>

<p>London School of Economics political expert Tony Travers said the Conservative Party was the "world's most durable political party" in many ways but that the result was still a "disaster".</p>

<p>While "not a massive amount of difference" stood between Labour and the Conservatives on many policies, Labour had managed to look more centrist and moderate to the electorate, he added.</p>

<p>And divisions that had beset the party could prove a major obstacle to reinventing itself, Travers said.</p>

<p>"They were split after Brexit... there's a civil war going on all the time, which is going to make their life difficult in the coming parliament."</p>

<p>Offering his own analysis in the Daily Mail on Saturday, Tory ex-prime minister Boris Johnson highlighted that Labour's landslide majority was built on fewer votes than it secured in 2019 when the Conservatives under Johnson won an 80-seat majority.</p>

<p>"We are capable of endless regeneration," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2n7un21_rishi-sunak-resignation-speech_625x300_06_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Major British political parties have seen dramatic downturns in their fortunes before. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-die-in-bangladesh-floods-over-2-million-affected-6049150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8 Die In Bangladesh Floods, Over 2 Million Affected]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-die-in-bangladesh-floods-over-2-million-affected-6049150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 06 Jul 2024 22:17:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The death count from floods in Bangladesh this week has risen to eight, leaving more than two million affected after heavy rains caused major rivers to burst their banks, officials confirmed Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The death count from floods in Bangladesh this week has risen to eight, leaving more than two million affected after heavy rains caused major rivers to burst their banks, officials confirmed Saturday.</p>

<p>The South Asian nation of 170 million people, crisscrossed by hundreds of rivers, has seen more frequent floods in recent decades.</p>

<p>Climate change has made rainfall more erratic and melting glaciers upstream in the Himalayan mountains.</p>

<p>Two teenage boys were killed when a boat capsized in flood waters in Shahjadur, the northern rural town's police chief Sabuj Rana told AFP.</p>

<p>"There were nine people in the small boat. Seven swam to safety. Two boys did not know how to swim. They drowned," he said.</p>

<p>Bishwadeb Roy, a police chief in Kurigram, told AFP that three others had been killed in two separate electrocution incidents after their boats became entangled with live electricity wires in flood water.</p>

<p>Another three died in separate flood-related incidents around the country, officials told AFP earlier this week.</p>

<p>The government said it has opened hundreds of shelters for people displaced by the waters and sent food and relief to hard-hit districts in the country's north region.</p>

<p>"More than two million people have been affected by the floods. Seventeen of the country's 64 districts have been affected," Kamrul Hasan, the secretary of the country's disaster management ministry, told AFP.</p>

<p>Hasan said the flood situation may worsen in the north over the coming days with the Brahmaputra, one of Bangladesh's main waterways, flowing above danger levels in some areas.</p>

<p>In the worst-hit Kurigram district, eight out of nine rural towns have been marooned by flood water, local disaster and relief official Abdul Hye told AFP.</p>

<p>"We live with floods here. But this year the water was very high. In three days, Brahmaputra rose by six to eight feet (2-2.5 metres)," Abdul Gafur, a local councillor in the district, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Flood water has inundated more than 80 percent of homes in my area. We are trying to deliver food, especially rice and edible oil. But there is a drinking water crisis."</p>

<p>Bangladesh is in the middle of the annual summer monsoon, which brings South Asia 70-80 percent of its annual rainfall, as well as regular deaths and destruction due to flooding and landslides.</p>

<p>The rainfall is hard to forecast and varies considerably, but scientists say climate change is making the monsoon stronger and more erratic.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v8d765_bangladesh-floods_625x300_06_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The government said it has opened hundreds of shelters for people displaced by the floods (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-donates-digital-equipment-worth-rs-300-million-to-200-sri-lanka-schools-6048854]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Donates Digital Equipment Worth Rs 300 million To Sri Lanka Schools]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-donates-digital-equipment-worth-rs-300-million-to-200-sri-lanka-schools-6048854]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 06 Jul 2024 21:14:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Describing it as "a project for posterity," India on Saturday donated digital equipment, including 2,000 Tabs, worth Rs 300 million for use to 200 schools in the southern province of Sri Lanka.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Describing it as "a project for posterity," India on Saturday donated digital equipment, including 2,000 Tabs, worth Rs 300 million for use to 200 schools in the southern province of Sri Lanka.</p>

<p>A ceremony in the southern district of Galle, attended by President Ranil Wickremesinghe and Indian High Commissioner Santosh Jha, marked a significant step towards educational modernisation, with the provision of 200 Smart Classrooms and 2,000 Tabs to 200 schools in the Southern Province.</p>

<p>"Following a request by the Minister of Health and Industry, Dr Ramesh Pathirana, the Government of India allocated Rs 300 million to the Southern Provincial Council for this project. Of the 200 selected schools, 150 are in the Galle district, while the remaining 50 are in the Hambantota and Matara districts," a statement from the President's Media Division (PMD) said.</p>

<p>Additionally, 2,000 Tabs were distributed, with each of the 200 classrooms receiving 10 Tabs, the statement said.</p>

<p>"We deeply appreciate the support extended by neighbouring India in advancing modern technology. Prime Minister Narendra Modi has expressed interest in establishing an Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) campus in Sri Lanka, which is highly appreciated," Mr Wickremesinghe said.</p>

<p>"Additionally, negotiations to enhance cooperation in the energy sector with India are progressing successfully," he said.</p>

<p>Pathirana and Minister of Education Dr Susil Premajayantha, both appreciated India's assistance in their respective speeches.</p>

<p>Mr Premajayantha also said, "Today, 200 schools in the Southern Province have been equipped with comfortable classrooms and 2,000 Tabs. Moving forward, the schools will undergo digitisation, with 1,250 schools already being connected."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Jha reciprocated by saying: "As India's neighbour, we consistently extend support to Sri Lanka. Sri Lanka holds a crucial position in our foreign policy. India remains steadfast in its commitment to providing essential infrastructure and technical knowledge support to Sri Lanka."&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A project for posterity! President H.E <a href="https://twitter.com/RW_UNP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RW_UNP</a> and High Commissioner <a href="https://twitter.com/santjha?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@santjha</a> handed over digital equipment to various schools in Southern Province, in the presence of Hon.Ministers <a href="https://twitter.com/DrRameshLK?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DrRameshLK</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/SPremajayantha?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SPremajayantha</a> and several other dignitaries today. <a href="https://t.co/nPowKgYE5j">pic.twitter.com/nPowKgYE5j</a></p>
— India in Sri Lanka (@IndiainSL) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiainSL/status/1809538953802064025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"A project for posterity! President H.E. @RW_UNP and High Commissioner @santjha handed over digital equipment to various schools in Southern Province, in the presence of Hon. Ministers @DrRameshLK, @SPremajayantha and several other dignitaries today," the Indian High Commission posted on its X along with the photos from the event.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5s620e5_sri-lanka-schools_625x300_06_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A ceremony in the southern district of Galle was attended by President Ranil Wickremesinghe]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>