<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 09 Oct 2024 03:07:30 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-threatens-more-attacks-if-israel-keeps-bombarding-lebanon-6747482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Threatens More Attacks If Israel Keeps Bombarding Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-threatens-more-attacks-if-israel-keeps-bombarding-lebanon-6747482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:47:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Iran-backed Hezbollah group warned on Tuesday that it would intensify attacks on Israel, including the northern port city of Haifa, if it continues to strike Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Iran-backed Hezbollah group warned on Tuesday that it would intensify attacks on Israel, including the northern port city of Haifa, if it continues to strike Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy's intensifying strikes" mean that "Haifa and other locations will be targeted by our rockets just as much as Kiryat Shmona, Metula, and other" locations, the group said. The Israeli army earlier reported that 85 projectiles were fired from Lebanon at northern Israel, including Haifa.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3sjtnbn8_israel-lebanon_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-it-dismantled-hezbollah-tunnel-that-crossed-into-israel-6747395]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Says It Dismantled Hezbollah Tunnel That Crossed Into Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-it-dismantled-hezbollah-tunnel-that-crossed-into-israel-6747395]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:12:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army said its forces dismantled a Hezbollah tunnel that crossed into the country's territory, as its troops continued to carry out ground operations in southern Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army said its forces dismantled a Hezbollah tunnel that crossed into the country's territory, as its troops continued to carry out ground operations in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>"Tonight we reported that we located and dismantled a tunnel of about 25 metres long, which crossed the border fence about 10 metres ... into Israeli territory," military spokesman Daniel Hagari said in a televised briefing.</p>

<p>"We detected this a few months ago, we identified and investigated it using technological means, we did not let Hezbollah know that we knew about it and now we can confirm that we are also dismantling it."</p>

<p>In a separate statement, the military said the tunnel crossed from the Marwahin area in Lebanon into Israeli territory near the Zarit community.</p>

<p>During the operation, the army located weapons, explosive devices and anti-tank missiles in the tunnel, it said.</p>

<p>Hagari said Israeli troops continue to search for other tunnels along the "entire" border and in villages in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The tunnel was under full operational control until the arrival of the soldiers in the area to prevent its use for terrorist activities," the army said.</p>

<p>"For years, Hezbollah's southern front has built an extensive network of underground infrastructure and command centres in southern Lebanon, aimed at attacking IDF (army) soldiers during combat and executing attack plans against communities in northern Israel," it said.</p>

<p>Israel has intensified its campaign against Hezbollah since late September, launching continuous air strikes against the group's strongholds in southern and eastern Lebanon and in Beirut.</p>

<p>Its troops have meanwhile pressed a ground offensive in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7br9mb6g_israel-lebanon_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli troops continue to search for other tunnels along the "entire" border.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/targets-children-us-states-sue-tiktok-over-privacy-violations-6747058]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Targets Children": US States Sue TikTok Over Privacy Violations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/targets-children-us-states-sue-tiktok-over-privacy-violations-6747058]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 23:44:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of 14 US states on Tuesday filed lawsuits accusing TikTok of ensnaring young users with addictive features, then harming their minds and violating their privacy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of 14 US states on Tuesday filed lawsuits accusing TikTok of ensnaring young users with addictive features, then harming their minds and violating their privacy.</p>

<p>The wave of local court lawsuits demanding corrective measures and financial penalties comes as the popular video-snippet sharing app faces a ban in the United States if it remains owned by China-based ByteDance.</p>

<p>"Our investigation has revealed that TikTok cultivates social media addiction to boost corporate profits," California attorney general Rob Bonta said in a news release issued jointly with officials from other states.</p>

<p>"TikTok intentionally targets children because they know kids do not yet have the defenses or capacity to create healthy boundaries around addictive content."</p>

<p>Bonta contended that features such as beauty filters, endless scrolling, autoplay videos, and "likes" exploit youthful curiosity and lack of will power to stop.</p>

<p>TikTok then hits young users with money-making ads, the lawsuits argue.</p>

<p>TikTok called the claims inaccurate and misleading.</p>

<p>"We've endeavored to work with the Attorneys General for over two years, and it is incredibly disappointing they have taken this step rather than work with us on constructive solutions to industry-wide challenges," TikTok spokesman Michael Hughes said in response to an AFP inquiry.</p>

<p>Hughes cited what he said were TikTok safeguards that include booting users suspected of being younger than 13, default screen time limits and privacy settings for minors using the app.</p>

<p>"Young people are struggling with their mental health because of addictive social media platforms like TikTok," said New York attorney general Letitia James.</p>

<p>"TikTok claims that their platform is safe for young people, but that is far from true," she added.</p>

<p>TikTok is battling the US ban threat in a federal appeals court, arguing that it violates free speech rights.</p>

<p>A law poised to take effect early next year requires the app to divest from its Chinese ownership or be banned in the United States.</p>

<p>The US government alleges that TikTok allows Beijing to collect data and spy on users. It also says TikTok is a conduit to spread propaganda. China and the company strongly deny these claims.</p>

<p>TikTok has until January to find a buyer or face the ban, which would upend the social media business and rile many of the app's 170 million US users.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-12/hae50fi8_tiktok-generic_625x300_24_December_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[TikTok called the claims inaccurate and misleading. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-1000s-of-terrorists-including-nasrallah-his-successor-killed-israeli-pm-6746957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1000s Of Terrorists Including Nasrallah, His Successor Killed: Israeli PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-1000s-of-terrorists-including-nasrallah-his-successor-killed-israeli-pm-6746957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 23:23:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces have killed the would-be successors of late Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Tuesday, without naming them.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces have killed the would-be successors of late Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Tuesday, without naming them.</p>

<p>"We've degraded Hezbollah's capabilities. We took out thousands of terrorists, including Nasrallah himself and Nasrallah's replacement, and the replacement of the replacement," Mr. Netanyahu said in a pre-recorded video message.</p>

<p>Earlier, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said Hashem Safieddine, the man expected to replace, now killed, Nasrallah, had probably been "eliminated". It was not immediately clear who Netanyahu meant by the "replacement of the replacement".</p>

<p>"Today, Hezbollah is weaker than it has been for many, many years," Mr. Netanyahu said in the video message directed at the people of Lebanon.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began firing rockets into Israel last Oct. 8, a day after Hamas Palestinian militants attacked southern Israel from Gaza. Hezbollah cited solidarity with Hamas.</p>

<p>Some 60,000 Israeli citizens in the country's north have been forced to leave their homes, while Israel's stated objective is to make its northern areas safe from Hezbollah rocket fire and allow those displaced residents to return.</p>

<p>"Israel has a right to defend itself. Israel also has a right to win. And Israel will win," Mr. Netanyahu said.</p>

<p>He urged Lebanon to "take back your country" and return it to a path of peace and prosperity and take advantage of an opportunity that hasn't existed in decades.</p>

<p>"If you don't, Hezbollah will continue to try to fight Israel from densely populated areas at your expense. It doesn't care if Lebanon is dragged into a wider war," he added. "Christians, Druze, Muslims - Sunnis and Shiites - all of you are suffering because of Hezbollah's futile war against Israel.</p>

<p>"Don't let these terrorists destroy your future any more than they've already done," Mr. Netanyahu added. "You have an opportunity to save Lebanon before it falls into the abyss of a long war that will lead to destruction and suffering like we see in Gaza. It doesn't have to be that way."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o46p4p8g_netanyahu_625x300_07_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Netanyahu urged Lebanon to return to a path of peace and prosperity. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-sent-covid-kits-to-putin-called-him-7-times-since-2021-claims-book-by-bob-woodward-6746806]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Sent Covid Kits To Putin, Called Him 7 Times Since 2021, Claims Book]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-sent-covid-kits-to-putin-called-him-7-times-since-2021-claims-book-by-bob-woodward-6746806]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 22:58:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump and Russian President Vladimir Putin share a closer relationship than what is known to the public, according to revelations in a forthcoming book by veteran US journalist Bob Woodward.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump and Russian President Vladimir Putin share a closer relationship than what is known to the public, according to revelations in a forthcoming book by veteran US journalist Bob Woodward. The two have talked to each other over phone calls on as many as seven occasions since Trump left office in 2021, according to excerpts from Bob Woodward's book.</p>

<p>The excerpts of Bob Woodward's upcoming book, War, to be released on October 15, were published by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/08/politics/bob-woodward-book-war-joe-biden-putin-netanyahu-trump/index.html">CNN</a> and the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/10/08/bob-woodward-new-book-war-trump-putin-biden/">Washington Post</a> and sheds light on Trump and Putin's bond.</p>

<p>While the world was grappling with the coronavirus outbreak in 2020, Donald Trump sent some COVID test kits, which were scarce and not easily available at the time, to Putin for personal use, says the book. Trump "secretly sent Putin a bunch of Abbott Point of Care Covid test machines for his personal use," Mr Woodward has written.</p>

<p>Putin, who isolated himself during the early days of the outbreak and was concerned about contracting the virus, received the gift but urged his then US counterpart to keep this favour a secret. "Please don't tell anybody you sent these to me," Mr Woodward quotes Putin as telling Trump.</p>

<p>According to the book, Putin asked Trump to not make the gift public to save the latter from a political fallout. While Trump's first reaction was "I don't care," and "Fine" to this request, Putin insisted, "I don't want you to tell anybody because people will get mad at you, not me. They don't care about me," according to the excerpt published in CNN.</p>

<p>In another episode, Mr Woodward says that a close aide of Trump revealed he was asked to leave the room by him so "he could have what he said was a private phone call with Russian President Vladimir Putin." The incident reportedly happened at Trump's Florida club Mar-a-Lago.</p>

<p>The revelations made in the book have drawn rejection by Trump's campaign, according to The Hill. Trump Campaign's communications director Steven Cheung told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://thehill.com/policy/international/4921585-trump-campaign-rejects-woodward-book/">The Hill</a>, "None of these made up stories by Bob Woodward are true" and that Trump did not give access to Mr Woodward for the new book.</p>

<p>Mr Cheung is also quoted as saying that Mr Woodward "suffers from a debilitating case of Trump Derangement Syndrome."</p>

<p>In a similar statement to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-putin-woodward-book-secret-covid-tests-seven-calls-2024-10?IR=T">Business Insider</a>, Mr Cheung said, "Woodward is an angry, little man and is clearly upset because President Trump is successfully suing him because of the unauthorized publishing of recordings he made previously."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-11/trump-putin-afp_650x400_51510472092.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin urged Trump not to reveal that he sent him Covid test kits, says the book (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-a-matter-of-life-and-death-evacuate-now-biden-on-hurricane-milton-6746552]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton May Be "Worst Storm" To Hit Florida In Decades: Joe Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-a-matter-of-life-and-death-evacuate-now-biden-on-hurricane-milton-6746552]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 22:16:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton, the Category 4 storm headed toward the southeastern United States, could be the worst to hit Florida in a century, US President Joe Biden said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane Milton, the Category 4 storm headed toward the southeastern United States, could be the worst to hit Florida in a century, President Joe Biden said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"This could be the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-5-hurricane-milton-approaches-florida-2nd-major-storm-in-weeks-6740696" target="_blank">worst storm to hit Florida</a> in over a century. God willing it won't be, but that's what it's looking like right now," Joe Biden told reporters at the White House.</p>

<p>"You should evacuate now, now, now. You should have already evacuated. It's a matter of life and death, and that's not hyperbole," he said as advisors briefed him on the storm.</p>

<p>Mr Biden said he had postponed a planned trip to Angola and Germany this week because "I just don't think I can be out of the country at this time."</p>

<p>He said he would try to reschedule the visits.</p>

<p>Mr Biden also condemned misinformation that Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and his party have spread about hurricane relief efforts ahead of next month's US election.</p>

<p>"Those who do it, do it to try to damage the administration," Mr Biden said.</p>

<p>He said that "we can take care of ourselves" but expressed concern about the impact that it could have on the ground.</p>

<p>"It's un-American. It really is. People are scared to death. People know their lives are at stake, all that they've worked for, all that they own, all that they value," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o30es1hg_joe-biden-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["People are scared to death," said Joe Biden as he expressed concerns over Hurricane Milton. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discoveries-of-nobel-prize-laureates-in-physics-explained-6746224]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Discoveries Made By Nobel Prize Laureates In Physics Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discoveries-of-nobel-prize-laureates-in-physics-explained-6746224]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 21:25:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Nobel Prize in Physics was awarded to two scientists on Tuesday for discoveries and inventions that enable machine learning with artificial neural networks. Here's what they they all mean.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Nobel Prize in Physics was awarded to two scientists on Tuesday for discoveries that laid the groundwork for the artificial intelligence used by hugely popular tools such as ChatGPT.</p>

<p>British-Canadian Geoffrey Hinton, known as a "godfather of AI," and US physicist John Hopfield were given the prize for "discoveries and inventions that enable machine learning with artificial neural networks," the Nobel jury said.</p>

<p>But what are those, and what does this all mean? Here are some answers.</p>

<h2><strong>What are neural networks and machine learning?</strong></h2>

<p>Mark van der Wilk, an expert in machine learning at the University of Oxford, told AFP that an artificial neural network is a mathematical construct "loosely inspired" by the human brain.</p>

<p>Our brains have a network of cells called neurons, which respond to outside stimuli -- such as things our eyes have seen or ears have heard -- by sending signals to each other.</p>

<p>When we learn things, some connections between neurons get stronger, while others get weaker.</p>

<p>Unlike traditional computing, which works more like reading a recipe, artificial neural networks roughly mimic this process.</p>

<p>The biological neurons are replaced with simple calculations sometimes called "nodes" -- and the incoming stimuli they learn from is replaced by training data.</p>

<p>The idea is that this could allow the network to learn over time -- hence the term machine learning.</p>

<h2><strong>What did Hopfield discover?</strong></h2>

<p>But before machines would be able to learn, another human trait was necessary: memory.</p>

<p>Ever struggle to remember a word? Consider the goose. You might cycle through similar words -- goon, good, ghoul -- before striking upon goose.</p>

<p>"If you are given a pattern that's not exactly the thing that you need to remember, you need to fill in the blanks," van der Wilk said.</p>

<p>"That's how you remember a particular memory."</p>

<p>This was the idea behind the "Hopfield network" -- also called "associative memory" -- which the physicist developed back in the early 1980s.</p>

<p>Hopfield's contribution meant that when an artificial neural network is given something that is slightly wrong, it can cycle through previously stored patterns to find the closest match.</p>

<p>This proved a major step forward for AI.</p>

<h2><strong>What about Hinton?</strong></h2>

<p>In 1985, Hinton revealed his own contribution to the field -- or at least one of them -- called the Boltzmann machine.</p>

<p>Named after 19th century physicist Ludwig Boltzmann, the concept introduced an element of randomness.</p>

<p>This randomness was ultimately why today's AI-powered image generators can produce endless variations to the same prompt.</p>

<p>Hinton also showed that the more layers a network has, "the more complex its behaviour can be".</p>

<p>This in turn made it easier to "efficiently learn a desired behaviour," French machine learning researcher Francis Bach told AFP.</p>

<h2><strong>What is it used for?</strong></h2>

<p>Despite these ideas being in place, many scientists lost interest in the field in the 1990s.</p>

<p>Machine learning required enormously powerful computers capable of handling vast amounts of information. It takes millions of images of dogs for these algorithms to be able to tell a dog from a cat.</p>

<p>So it was not until the 2010s that a wave of breakthroughs "revolutionised everything related to image processing and natural language processing," Bach said.</p>

<p>From reading medical scans to directing self-driving cars, forecasting the weather to creating deepfakes, the uses of AI are now too numerous to count.</p>

<h2><strong>But is it really physics?</strong></h2>

<p>Hinton had already won the Turing award, which is considered the Nobel for computer science.</p>

<p>But several experts said his was a well-deserved Nobel win in the field of physics, which started science down the road that would lead to AI.</p>

<p>French researcher Damien Querlioz pointed out that these algorithms were originally "inspired by physics, by transposing the concept of energy onto the field of computing".</p>

<p>Van der Wilk said the first Nobel "for the methodological development of AI" acknowledged the contribution of the physics community, as well as the winners.</p>

<p>And while ChatGPT can sometimes make AI seem genuinely creative, it is important to remember the "machine" part of machine learning.</p>

<p>"There is no magic happening here," van der Wilk emphasised.</p>

<p>"Ultimately, everything in AI is multiplications and additions."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3s2htn5o_nobel-prize-for-physics-_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Geoffrey Hinton and US physicist John Hopfield won 2024's noble prize in physics. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terror-level-threat-in-norway-amid-escalating-middle-east-conflict-6745879]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Terror Level Threat" In Norway Amid Escalating Middle East Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terror-level-threat-in-norway-amid-escalating-middle-east-conflict-6745879]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:40:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Norway has raised its terrorism threat assessment to the second-highest level due to an increased risk of attacks against Jewish and Israeli targets, the national police directorate said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Norway has raised its terrorism threat assessment to the second-highest level due to an increased risk of attacks against Jewish and Israeli targets, the national police directorate said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Last week police in neighbouring Denmark charged two men suspected of detonating hand grenades near Israel's Copenhagen embassy, while police in Sweden are investigating a suspected shooting near the Israeli diplomatic mission in Stockholm.</p>

<p>Norwegian police officers, who are normally unarmed, will now carry guns nationwide as a result of the decision by the PST security service to raise the threat level, the directorate said.</p>

<p>"PST raises the terror threat level in Norway from moderate to high as a result of the ongoing escalation of the conflict in the Middle East," the police said in a statement.</p>

<p>"It is primarily the threat to Jewish and Israeli targets that has been further intensified," the statement said.</p>

<p>The PST risk assessment was raised from level three (moderate) to level four (high), on PST's five-point scale where the top end of the range would indicate imminent danger.</p>

<p>National Police Commissioner Benedicte Bjoernland said there was an increased likelihood of attempted terrorism.</p>

<p>"...we have a number of measures in place to protect the population," she said in a statement.</p>

<p>Sweden in August last year raised its terrorist alert to the second-highest level after Koran burnings outraged Muslims and triggered threats from jihadists.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/p9rr1c4g_norway-police-bowandarrow-attackreuters_625x300_14_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Norwegian officers will now carry guns nationwide as a result of raised threat level. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-doctor-admits-trying-to-kill-mothers-partner-with-flesh-eating-bacteria-under-guise-of-covid-shot-6745743]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Doctor Admits Trying To Kill Mother's Partner With Fake Covid Shot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-doctor-admits-trying-to-kill-mothers-partner-with-flesh-eating-bacteria-under-guise-of-covid-shot-6745743]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:26:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A doctor in the United Kingdom has admitted trying to kill his mother's long-term partner by injecting him with a fake Covid-19 booster that caused a flesh-eating bacterial disease.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A doctor in the United Kingdom has admitted trying to kill his mother's long-term partner by injecting him with a fake Covid-19 booster that caused a flesh-eating bacterial disease. According to <em>The Guardian</em>, 53-year-old Thomas Kwan had been a respected and experienced General Practioner (GP) in Sunderland when he devised the elaborate plan to kill Patrick O'Hara, 72, at his mother's home on January 22. He injected the 72-year-old with the fake shot under the disguise of a community nurse. The Hong Kong-born doctor wanted to kill Mr O'Hara so he could inherit his mother's estate when she died, a court heard on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Initially, Mr Kwan denied attempted murder but he changed his plea on Monday this week after the prosecution opened the case against him. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2024/oct/07/gp-admits-attempted-of-mothers-partner-with-fake-covid-jab" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Guardian</em></a> reported that over several months, the 53-year-old plotted to get access to his victim using shell companies, counterfeit documents and elaborate disguises.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kwan sent two fake doctor's letters stating that the 72-year-old was due for a home visit for his Covid-19 injections. On the day of the visit, he then checked himself into a hotel under a false name and later headed to his mother Jenny Leung's house posing as a nurse. He allegedly spent 45 minutes at the property as he carried out medical tests and administered the fake booster to Mr O'Hara. Kwan told the court that he administered to Mr O'Hara in an attempt to create "no more than mild pain and discomfort".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/ai-startup-co-founder-works-on-laptop-at-his-own-wedding-internet-calls-it-utterly-bizarre-6743812">AI Startup Co-Founder Works On Laptop At His Own Wedding, Internet Calls It "Utterly Bizarre"</a></strong></p>

<p>The outlet reported that Mr O'Hara felt "terrible pain" after the injection and went to the hospital where doctors diagnosed him with a "rare and life-threatening disease" called necrotizing fasciitis - a flesh-eating disease that can develop very quickly into a life-threatening emergency. Following the injection, he remained in intensive care for weeks as doctor cut flesh from his arm in an attempt to combat the disease.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"From November 2023 at the latest, and probably long before then, [Kwan] devised an intricate plan to kill his mother's long-term partner Patrick O'Hara ... It was a plan to murder a man in plain sight, to murder a man right in front of his own mother's eyes," prosecutor Peter Makepeace said in court.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to The Guardian, jurors were told that Ms Leung named her longtime partner Mr O'Hara in her will so he could remain in her house. This decision put a "strain" on her relationship with her son.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The judge, Mrs Justice Lambert, said Kwan would face a "substantial" prison term at his sentencing on 17 October.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-12/4bk6erl_coronavirus-vaccine-generic-bloomberg_625x300_01_December_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Kwan had been a respected and experienced GP in Sunderland. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/osama-bin-ladens-son-banned-from-returning-to-france-after-deportation-6745653]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Osama Bin Laden's Son Banned From Returning To France After Deportation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/osama-bin-ladens-son-banned-from-returning-to-france-after-deportation-6745653]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:18:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A son of Al Qaeda founder Osama bin Laden has been barred from returning to France, where he lived for years painting landscapes in a Normandy village, after allegedly posting comments on social media deemed to have glorified terrorism.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A son of Al Qaeda founder Osama bin Laden has been barred from returning to France, where he lived for years painting landscapes in a Normandy village, after allegedly posting comments on social media deemed to have glorified terrorism.</p>

<p>Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau said he had signed an order banning Omar Binladin from France after the judiciary confirmed the legality of a prior deportation order issued on grounds of national security.</p>

<p>Retailleau gave no details about the timing of the deportation or where Binladin had been sent.</p>

<p>"Mr Binladin, who has lived in the Orne region for several years as the spouse of a British national, posted comments on his social networks in 2023 that glorified terrorism," Retailleau said on X.</p>

<p>"The administrative ban ensures that Mr Binladin cannot return to France for any reason whatsoever."</p>

<p>Binladin could not be reached for comment.</p>

<p>Pascal Martin, who helped Binladin sell his paintings, described him as a man who opposed Islamist ideology, who earned a living from his artwork and paid his taxes. Binladin was currently in Qatar, Martin said.</p>

<p>"We became friends and I can tell you that nothing that is being said resembles the Omar I know," Martin told Reuters.</p>

<p>According to local weekly newspaper Le Publicateur Libre, Binladin caught the attention of French authorities over a social media post on the anniversary of his father's birthday. Osama bin Laden was killed by U.S. forces in 2011.</p>

<p>Reuters was not immediately able to locate the social media post. Martin said Binladin had told friends his social media account had been hacked.</p>

<p>The paper reported in July 2023 that police had searched for Binladin in the village of Domfort, Normandy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bmsc01gg_omar-bin-laden_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Osama bin Laden was killed by US forces in 2011. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/milton-hurricane-update-if-you-stay-you-will-die-us-state-florida-braces-for-hurricane-milton-6745540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['If You Stay You Will Die': US State Florida Braces For Hurricane Milton]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/milton-hurricane-update-if-you-stay-you-will-die-us-state-florida-braces-for-hurricane-milton-6745540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:03:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Weather-weary Florida girded Tuesday for a hit from Hurricane Milton, a monster storm packing furious winds and the threat of walls of water gushing inland.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Weather-weary Florida girded Tuesday for a hit from Hurricane Milton, a monster storm packing furious winds and the threat of walls of water gushing inland.</p>

<p>As the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-5-hurricane-milton-approaches-florida-2nd-major-storm-in-weeks-6740696" target="_blank">second huge hurricane</a> in as many weeks rumbled toward the state's battered west coast, a sense of looming catastrophe spread as people raced to board up their homes and evacuate to shelters or anywhere they could.</p>

<p>As of Tuesday morning, Milton was generating maximum sustained winds of 145 mph (230 kph) and the threat of as much as 15 feet of storm surge, the National Hurricane Center said, calling it an "extremely dangerous" storm, and urging people to heed evacuation orders.</p>

<p>The Category 4 hurricane was to move just north of Mexico's Yucatan peninsula on Tuesday, it said.</p>

<p>After weakening from a maximum Category 5 overnight, it is forecast to make landfall Wednesday night on the coast of Florida and remain powerful as it churns across the state.</p>

<p>At a press conference Tuesday, Governor Ron Santis ticked off town after town and county after county that are in danger.</p>

<p>"Basically the entire peninsula portion of Florida is under some type of either a watch or a warning," he said.</p>

<p>The mayor of Tampa, a metropolitan area of three million that was hit hard last month by Hurricane Helene, was blunt in her own assessment.</p>

<p>"Helene was a wake-up call. This is literally catastrophic," Mayor Jane Castor said on CNN.</p>

<p>"I can say this without any dramatization whatsoever: If you choose to stay in one of those evacuation areas, you are going to die."</p>

<h2><strong>'Just horrific'</strong></h2>

<p>One Florida TV meteorologist choked back tears as he talked about how Milton had intensified rapidly from a Category 1.</p>

<p>"I apologize," weatherman John Morales said, as he surveyed the data. "This is just horrific."</p>

<p>The National Weather Service said that Milton could be the worst storm to hit the Tampa area in more than 100 years.</p>

<p>Scientists say global warming has a role in these intense storms as warmer ocean surfaces release more water vapor, providing additional energy for storms, which intensifies their winds.</p>

<p>Communities hit by the deadly Hurricane Helene, which slammed Florida late last month, rushed to remove debris that could become dangerous projectiles as Milton approaches.</p>

<p>The back-to-back hurricanes have ignited political bickering ahead of the upcoming US election.</p>

<p>DeSantis, a conservative known to clash with the federal government, came under fire after broadcaster NBC reported he was ignoring phone calls from Vice President Kamala Harris on the Helene recovery.</p>

<p>DeSantis did speak to President Joe Biden about the Milton preparations, the White House said.</p>

<p>Harris slammed the Republican governor for "playing political games."</p>

<p>Former president Donald Trump has tapped into real frustration about the federal response after Helene and fueled it with disinformation, falsely claiming disaster money had been spent instead on migrants.</p>

<p>In Mexico's Yucatan, workers boarded up glass doors and windows, fishermen hauled boats ashore and schools were suspended.</p>

<p>In the southeastern United States, emergency workers are still struggling to provide relief after Helene, which killed at least 230 people across several states.</p>

<p>It hit the Florida coastline on September 26 as a major Category 4 hurricane, causing massive flooding in remote inland towns in states further north, including North Carolina and Tennessee.</p>

<p>Helene was the deadliest natural disaster to hit the US mainland since 2005's Hurricane Katrina, with the death count still rising.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p565m9io_hurricane-milton-florida_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Civilians rushed to remove debris that could become dangerous projectiles as Milton approaches.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-republican-candidate-poses-with-friends-wife-daughters-for-campaign-ad-6745289]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Republican Candidate Poses With Friend's Wife, Daughters For Campaign Ad]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-republican-candidate-poses-with-friends-wife-daughters-for-campaign-ad-6745289]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:30:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Derrick Anderson, an army veteran and a Republican Party candidate running for an open seat in Virginia's seventh district, posted a video which featured a typical 'family photo' of him with a woman and three girls, reported The New York Times.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the highly anticipated US polls are approaching, candidates across parties are gearing up to bag as many votes as possible using unique campaign strategies. One Republican candidate went as far as borrowing his friend's wife and children to pose for what seems like a family photo.</p>

<p>Derrick Anderson, an army veteran and a Republican Party candidate running for an open seat in Virginia's seventh district, posted a video which featured a typical 'family photo' of him with a woman and three girls, reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/27/us/politics/republican-candidates-wives-ads.html">The New York Times</a>. However, the woman and the three girls in the deceptive photo are unrelated to Mr Anderson, who is unmarried and lives with his dog, says his campaign website. In another shot, Mr Anderson can be seen sitting on a dining table with the same woman and the girls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Anderson's campaign later clarified that the woman and girls in the photo are actually the wife and daughters of his friend. He is engaged and has posted videos on social media with his fiancee in the past.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The republican candidate has, however, drawn flak from several social media users for the photos, now in wide circulation on social media. Eugene Vindman, his democratic opponent from the seat, was quick to call him out. "Derrick Anderson invented a fake family so that voters in Virginia's 7th would like him," said Mr Vindman in a post on X.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Derrick Anderson invented a fake family so that voters in Virginia's 7th would like him.<br />
<br />
Derrick will do anything to deceive us, and to hide his extreme agenda to let politicians ban all abortions.<br />
<br />
Derrick faked having a family. Now he wants to control yours. <a href="https://t.co/aO2utKZ0Da">pic.twitter.com/aO2utKZ0Da</a></p>
— Eugene Vindman (@YVindman) <a href="https://twitter.com/YVindman/status/1841576300831453493?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In another post, Mr Vindman said, "The definition of MAGA "family values" now includes borrowing a wife and kids for a political ad thanks to Derrick Anderson. If Derrick deceives you about his family, how can we trust him to stand up to his own party on Project 2025?"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The definition of MAGA "family values" now includes borrowing a wife and kids for a political ad thanks to Derrick Anderson.<br />
<br />
If Derrick deceives you about his family, how can we trust him to stand up to his own party on Project 2025? <a href="https://t.co/G2DeSdnVY4">pic.twitter.com/G2DeSdnVY4</a></p>
— Eugene Vindman (@YVindman) <a href="https://twitter.com/YVindman/status/1843325605422731614?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Anderson's spokesperson however said that "Derrick's opponent and every other candidate in America are in similar pictures and video with supporters of all kinds" when approached by the NYT for a reaction. He also said that the video showed Mr Anderson with "female friends and supporters", according to the NYT.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8a9mpsi_derrick-anderson-viral-photo_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Derrick Anderson is Republican Party candidate running from Virginia's seventh district]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-nasrallahs-successor-likely-killed-says-israeli-minister-6744916]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Chief Nasrallah's Successor Likely Killed, Says Israeli Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-nasrallahs-successor-likely-killed-says-israeli-minister-6744916]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:50:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Tuesday that it appears that the replacement of slain Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been eliminated.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Tuesday that it appears that the replacement of dead Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been eliminated.</p>

<p>Hashem Safieddine, a top Hezbollah official was widely expected to succeed Nasrallah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/g7dminco_yoav-gallant-_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hashem Safieddine was widely expected to succeed Nasrallah. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-broken-since-chief-hassan-nasrallahs-killing-israel-minister-6744790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah "Broken" Since Chief Hassan Nasrallah's Killing: Israel Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-broken-since-chief-hassan-nasrallahs-killing-israel-minister-6744790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:33:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant on Tuesday said Hezbollah had been "battered and broken" following continuous strikes against the group and the killing of its leader Hassan Nasrallah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant on Tuesday said Hezbollah had been "battered and broken" following continuous strikes against the group and the killing of its leader Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>During a briefing with the northern command, Gallant said Hezbollah "is a battered and broken organisation, without significant command and fire capabilities, with a disintegrated leadership following the elimination of Hassan Nasrallah". Earlier on Tuesday the military said about 85 projectiles were fired from Lebanon at northern Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/7kvtbavs_yoav-gallant-1200_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier on Tuesday the military said about 85 projectiles were fired from Lebanon at Israel. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-airbnb-host-hit-with-rs-1-25-lakh-electricity-bill-after-guests-mine-rs-84-lakh-in-crypto-6744514]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Airbnb Bans Crypto Mining After Receiving Rs 1.25 Lakh Electricity Bill]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-airbnb-host-hit-with-rs-1-25-lakh-electricity-bill-after-guests-mine-rs-84-lakh-in-crypto-6744514]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:00:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Airbnb host in the US was forced to add 'no cryptocurrency mining' to the list of instructions after a bizarre guest experience.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Airbnb host in the US was forced to add 'no cryptocurrency mining' to the list of instructions after a bizarre guest experience. According to <em>Business Insider</em>, Airbnb host Ashley Class revealed in a video posted to TikTok that she had banned crypto mining in her short-term rentals after she got a massive electricity bill of $1,500 (approximately Rs 1.25 lakh). The guests initially seemed like model renters. They were "five stars all the way," Ms Class said, with no issues or hiccups during their three-week stay. However, this was until the guests made her rental property a makeshift crypto-mining hub and ran up $1,500 in utility charges.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Class said that after she received the shocking electricity bill, she looked at footage from her outdoor camera. She saw that the guests had hauled in at least 10 computer rigs, which she later figured out were for crypto mining.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It was cheaper for them to rent a house than to pay for that electricity," Ms Class said in the video, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.businessinsider.in/thelife/news/an-airbnb-host-had-to-ban-crypto-mining-after-guests-racked-up-a-1500-electric-bill/articleshow/112427481.cms" rel="noindex. nofollow "><em>Business Insider</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, cryptocurrency mining is a process that involves solving complex mathematical problems to earn digital currency. The whole process requires significant computational power which needs a huge amount of electricity. The practice has even been outlawed in some parts of China due to environmental and financial concerns over the rise of crypto mining.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/ai-startup-co-founder-works-on-laptop-at-his-own-wedding-internet-calls-it-utterly-bizarre-6743812">AI Startup Co-Founder Works On Laptop At His Own Wedding, Internet Calls It "Utterly Bizarre"</a></strong></p>

<p>The Airbnb host stated that she messaged the guests and explained she would be charging them for the exorbitant electricity bill. However, the guests fought her until she got Airbnb involved and shared documentation of the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The guests apparently had the funds to repay her. Ms Class revealed in the comments section that the guests made $100,000 (approximately Rs 84 Lakh) during their three-week stay.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in the comments section of Ms Class' video, a number of Airbnb hosts mentioned that they have also explicitly banned crypto mining in their listings. "I also have in my rules no crypto mining. It's ridiculous we have to do this," one user wrote. "I've never heard of this, but thanks for the heads up! Heading to update my listing," commented another.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/641gr328_airbnb-logo-afp_625x300_24_May_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The guests fought with the host until she got Airbnb involved. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-conflict-all-you-need-to-know-about-hezbollahs-chief-general-sheikh-naim-qassem-6744417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All You Need To Know About Hezbollah's Chief General Sheikh Naim Qassem]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-conflict-all-you-need-to-know-about-hezbollahs-chief-general-sheikh-naim-qassem-6744417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:48:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah's deputy secretary general Sheikh Naim Qassem, who said on Tuesday that the armed group supported efforts to reach a ceasefire for Lebanon, has been a senior figure in the Iran-backed movement for more than 30 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah's deputy secretary general Sheikh Naim Qassem, who said on Tuesday that the armed group supported efforts to reach a ceasefire for Lebanon, has been a senior figure in the Iran-backed movement for more than 30 years.</p>

<p>Speaking in front of curtains from an undisclosed location, Qassem said the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regional-tensions-mount-as-israel-trades-strikes-with-gaza-lebanon-on-anniversary-war-with-hamas-6741677" target="_blank">conflict between Hezbollah and Israel</a> was a war about who cries first, and Hezbollah would not cry first. The group's capabilities were intact despite "painful blows" from Israel.</p>

<p>But he added the group supported the efforts of parliament speaker Nabih Berri - a Hezbollah ally - to secure a ceasefire, for the first time omitting any mention of a Gaza truce deal as a pre-condition for halting the group's fire on Israel.</p>

<p>His 30-minute televised address comes just days after senior Hezbollah figure Hashem Safieddine is thought to have been the target of an Israeli strike and 11 days after the killing of Hezbollah's secretary general Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>Qassem was appointed deputy chief in 1991 by the armed group's then-secretary general Abbas al-Musawi, who was killed by an Israeli helicopter attack the following year.</p>

<p>Qassem remained in his role when Nasrallah became leader, and has long been one of Hezbollah's leading spokesmen, conducting interviews with foreign media including as cross-border hostilities with Israel raged over the last year.</p>

<p>Qassem's televised address on Tuesday was his second since hostilities between Israel and Hezbollah intensified in September.</p>

<p>He was the first member of Hezbollah's top leadership to make televised remarks after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-top-commander-of-quds-force-esmail-qaani-survived-israeli-strike-on-hassan-nasrallahs-likely-heir-6740497" target="_blank">Nasrallah's killing</a> in an Israeli air attack on Beirut's southern suburbs on Sept. 27.</p>

<p>Speaking on Sept. 30, Qassem said Hezbollah would choose a successor to its secretary general "at the earliest opportunity" and would continue to fight Israel in solidarity with Palestinians.</p>

<p>"What we are doing is the bare minimum... We know that the battle may be long," he said in a 19-minute speech.</p>

<p>Born in 1953 in Beirut to a family from Lebanon's south, Qassem's political activism began with the Lebanese Shi'ite Amal Movement.</p>

<p>He left the group in 1979 in the wake of Iran's Islamic Revolution, which shaped the political thinking of many young Lebanese Shi'ite activists.</p>

<p>Qassem took part in meetings that led to the formation of Hezbollah, established with the backing of Iran's Revolutionary Guards in response to the Israeli invasion of Lebanon in 1982.</p>

<p>He has been the general coordinator of Hezbollah's parliamentary election campaigns since the group first contested them in 1992.</p>

<p>In 2005, he wrote a history of Hezbollah seen as a rare "insider's look" into the organisation. Qassem wears a white turban unlike Nasrallah and Safieddine, whose black turbans denoted their status as descendants of the Prophet Muhammad.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nktot3to_-sheikh-naim-qassem_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Naim Qassem was appointed deputy chief in 1991. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-the-nobel-prize-for-physics-co-winner-fears-6744406]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2024 Nobel Prize In Physics Winner Raises Concerns About Tech He Created]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-the-nobel-prize-for-physics-co-winner-fears-6744406]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:45:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Geoffery E Hinton said he was an avid user of AI tools such as ChatGPT, but also conceded that he had concerns about the potential impact of the technology.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Geoffrey E Hinton, known as the Godfather of artificial Intelligence and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-physics-goes-to-john-hopfield-geoffrey-hinton-for-work-on-machine-learning-6743213">co-winner of the Nobel Prize for Physics 2024</a>, raised concerns about the technology he has created.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old University of Toronto professor said machine learning and AI will have a significant influence on humankind's future, comparing it to the Industrial Revolution, but flagged the threat of these systems “getting out of control”. “Instead of exceeding people in physical strength, it will exceed people in intellectual ability. People will be able to do the same amount of work with an AI assistant in much lesser time. But there is always the threat of these things getting out of control,” Mr Hinton said.</p>

<p>He further said that his fear is the systems will become more intelligent that people, and eventually take control.</p>

<p>American John Hopfield and British-Canadian Geoffrey Hinton won the Nobel Prize in Physics on Tuesday for pioneering work in the development of artificial intelligence. The pair were honoured "for foundational discoveries and inventions that enable machine learning with artificial neural networks," the jury said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-an-earthquake-says-gary-ruvkun-2024-nobel-prize-in-medicine-winner-6736827"><strong>"Its An Earthquake," Says Gary Ruvkun, 2024 Nobel Prize In Medicine Winner</strong></a></p>

<p>"These artificial neural networks have been used to advance research across physics topics as diverse as particle physics, material science and astrophysics," Ellen Moons, chair of the Nobel Committee for Physics, told a press conference. Moons also noted that these tools have also become part of our daily lives, including in facial recognition and language translation.</p>

<p>The jury said Hinton, a 76-year-old professor at the University of Toronto, "invented a method that can autonomously find properties in data, and so perform tasks such as identifying specific elements in pictures."</p>

<p>Hinton said he used AI tools such as ChatGPT4 “for almost everything. But it is not a very good expert, and that is good”.</p>

<p>"I'm flabbergasted, I had no idea this would happen," Hinton told reporters via a phone interview as the laureates were announced in Stockholm. Speaking in a lighter vein, he added, “I'm in a cheap hotel in California that doesn't have an internet connection or a very good phone connection. I was going to get an MRI scan today, but I will have to cancel.”</p>

<p>The Nobel Prize in Medicine Prize was awarded on Monday to American scientists Victor Ambros and Gary Ruvkun. The US duo were honoured for their discovery of microRNA and its role in how genes are regulated. The physics prize will be followed by the chemistry prize on Wednesday, with the highly watched literature and peace prizes to be announced on Thursday and Friday respectively. The economics prize wraps up the 2024 Nobel season on October 14.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ns5d2d9g_nobel-prize-physics_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Geofferey E Hinton, professor at University of Toronto, has been awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-bolivia-to-indonesia-deforestation-continues-apace-6743946]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Bolivia To Indonesia, Deforestation Continues Apace]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-bolivia-to-indonesia-deforestation-continues-apace-6743946]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:52:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Deforestation continued last year at a rate far beyond pledges to end the practice by 2030, according to a major study.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Deforestation continued last year at a rate far beyond pledges to end the practice by 2030, according to a major study published Tuesday.</p>

<p>Forests nearly the size of Ireland were lost in 2023, according to two dozen research organisations, NGOs and advocacy groups, with 6.37 million hectares (15.7 million acres) of trees felled and burned.</p>

<p>This "significantly exceeded" levels that would have kept the world on track to eliminate deforestation by the end of the decade, a commitment made in 2021 by more than 140 leaders.</p>

<p>Forests are home to 80 percent of the world's terrestrial plant and animal species and crucial for regulating water cycles and sequestering CO2, the main greenhouse gas responsible for global warming.</p>

<p>"Globally, deforestation has gotten worse, not better, since the beginning of the decade," said Ivan Palmegiani, a biodiversity and land use consultant at Climate Focus and lead author of the "Forest Declaration Assessment" report.</p>

<p>"We're only six years away from a critical global deadline to end deforestation, and forests continue to be chopped down, degraded, and set ablaze at alarming rates."</p>

<p>In 2023, 3.7 million hectares of tropical primary forest -- particularly carbon rich and ecologically biodiverse environments -- disappeared, a figure that should have fallen significantly to meet the 2030 objective.</p>

<p><strong>Soya and nickel</strong></p>

<p>In high-risk regions, researchers pointed to backsliding in Bolivia and in Indonesia.~CHECK~</p>

<p>The report said there was an "alarming rise" in deforestation in Bolivia, which jumped 351 percent between 2015 and 2023.</p>

<p>The "trend shows no sign of abating", it added, with forests largely cleared for agriculture, notably for soya but also beef and sugar.</p>

<p>In Indonesia, deforestation slumped between 2020-2022 but started rising sharply last year.</p>

<p>Ironically, that is partly down to demand for materials often seen as eco-friendly, such as viscose for clothing, and a surge in nickel mining for electric vehicle batteries and renewable energy technologies.</p>

<p>There was better news from Brazil.</p>

<p>While it remains the country with the highest deforestation rates in the world, it has made key progress.</p>

<p>The situation has significantly improved in the Amazon, which has benefited from protective measures put in place by President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva.</p>

<p>However, in the Cerrado, a key tropical savannah below the Amazon, deforestation has increased.</p>

<p><strong>Degraded forests</strong></p>

<p>The report also highlights the role of logging, road building and fires in forest degradation, when land is damaged but not razed entirely.</p>

<p>In 2022, the last year data was available, a forest area twice the size of Germany was degraded.</p>

<p>Erin Matson, senior consultant at Climate Focus, and co-author of the report, said "strong policies and strong enforcement" were needed.</p>

<p>"To meet global forest protection targets, we must make forest protection immune to political and economic whims," she said.</p>

<p>The report comes in the wake of the European Commission's proposal last week to postpone by a year (to the end of 2025) the entry into force of its anti-deforestation law, despite protests from NGOs.</p>

<p>"We have to fundamentally rethink our relationship with consumption and our models of production to shift away from a reliance on over exploiting natural resources," said Matson.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pdji8om8_deforestation_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A man cuts a log that was part of an ancient tree in Sierra Leone's Kambui Hills Forest]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-kills-17-says-gaza-civil-defense-agency-6743945]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strike Kills 17 At Refugee Camp, Says Gaza Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-kills-17-says-gaza-civil-defense-agency-6743945]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:51:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza's civil defence agency on Tuesday said an Israeli strike killed at least 17 people at a refugee camp in the centre of the territory, as Israel's military targets Hamas positions]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency on Tuesday said an Israeli strike killed at least 17 people at a refugee camp in the centre of the territory, as Israel's military targets Hamas positions.</p>

<p>"The civil defence teams recovered 17 martyrs, including children, and several others who were wounded from the three-story home of the Abdul Hadi family, which was bombed by a missile from an (Israeli) warplane in Al-Bureij refugee camp in central Gaza," agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal said in a statement.</p>

<p>Bassal said the bodies of those killed and the wounded were taken to Al-Awda hospital in Nuseirat camp and to Al-Aqsa Martyrs hospital in the city of Deir el-Balah.</p>

<p>Medics at Al-Awda confirmed the death count.</p>

<p>Bassal earlier told AFP that several air strikes rocked central and northern parts of Gaza since the early hours of Tuesday.</p>

<p>Witnesses and rescuers also said Israeli military operations continued in Jabaliya, where troops launched a ground assault in recent days.</p>

<p>Over the past day, Israeli forces killed "approximately 20 terrorists" in air strikes in Jabaliya, the military said in a statement, adding troops also dismantled a weapons storage facility in the area.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the military said troops had encircled Jabaliya in response to indications Hamas was regrouping there despite a year of strikes and hard fighting.</p>

<p>In recent months, troops have returned to several areas across the Palestinian territory where they had previously conducted operations against Hamas, only to find operators rebuilding.</p>

<p>In a separate statement, the military announced it had killed three Hamas operators who had participated in the October 7 attack.</p>

<p>They were killed in an air strike on September 30 that struck a school in Daraj Tuffah area.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/01ddgl88_gaza-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Medics at Al-Awda confirmed the death count. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-top-commander-of-quds-force-esmail-qaani-survived-israeli-strike-on-hassan-nasrallahs-likely-heir-6740497]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Says Top Commander Survived Israeli Strike On Nasrallah's Likely Heir]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-top-commander-of-quds-force-esmail-qaani-survived-israeli-strike-on-hassan-nasrallahs-likely-heir-6740497]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:22:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The top Commander of Iran's Quds Force Esmail Qaani is in 'good health', the force's deputy commander Iraj Masjedi said, after Iranian security sources told Reuters he had been out of contact since strikes on Beirut last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The top Commander of Iran's Quds Force Esmail Qaani is in 'good health', the force's deputy commander Iraj Masjedi said on Monday, after Iranian security sources told Reuters he had been out of contact since strikes on Beirut last week.</p>

<p>"He is in good health and is carrying out his activities. Some ask us to issue a statement... there is no need for this", Masjedi was quoted as saying by state media in reference to Qaani.</p>

<p>One of the officials speaking to Reuters said Qaani was in Beirut's southern suburbs, known as the Dahiyeh, during a strike last week that was reported to have targeted senior Hezbollah official Hashem Safieddine. The official said he was not meeting Safieddine.</p>

<p>Israel has been hitting multiple targets in Dahiyeh as it pursues a campaign against Iran-backed Lebanese group Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Tehran named Qaani the head of the Revolutionary Guards Corps' overseas military-intelligence service after the United States assassinated his powerful predecessor Qassem Soleimani in a drone strike in Baghdad in 2020.</p>

<p>The Quds Force heavily influences its allied armed groups across the Middle East.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i3dt5df_esmail-qaani-reuters-_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The top Commander had been out of contact since strikes on Beirut last week. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>