<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 05:52:52 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-israel-should-hit-irans-nuclear-facilities-6719212]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says Israel Should "Hit" Iran's Nuclear Facilities]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-israel-should-hit-irans-nuclear-facilities-6719212]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 05:05:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican White House hopeful Donald Trump said Friday he believes Israel should strike Iran's nuclear facilities in response to the Islamic republic's recent missile barrage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican White House hopeful Donald Trump said Friday he believes Israel should strike Iran's nuclear facilities in response to the Islamic republic's recent missile barrage.</p>

<p>The former president, speaking at a campaign event in North Carolina, referred to a question posed to Democratic President Joe Biden this week about the possibility of Israel targeting Iran's nuclear program.</p>

<p>"They asked him, what do you think about Iran, would you hit Iran? And he goes, 'As long as they don't hit the nuclear stuff.' That's the thing you want to hit, right?" Trump told a town hall style event in Fayetteville, near a major US military base.</p>

<p>Biden was asked on Wednesday whether he would support strikes against Iranian nuclear sites and the US president told reporters: "The answer is no."</p>

<p>"I think he's got that one wrong," Trump said Friday, in response to a participant's question about the issue. "Isn't that what you're supposed to hit? I mean, it's the biggest risk we have, nuclear weapons," he said.</p>

<p>"When they asked him that question, the answer should have been, hit the nuclear first, and worry about the rest later," Trump added.</p>

<p>"If they're going to do it, they're going to do it. But we'll find out whatever their plans are."</p>

<p>Biden on Wednesday expressed his opposition to such strikes against Iran's nuclear facilities, in response to the firing of nearly 200 Iranian missiles towards Israel.</p>

<p>"We'll be discussing with the Israelis what they're going to do," he said, adding that all G7 members agree Israel has "a right to respond, but they should respond in proportion."</p>

<p>Trump, locked in a tooth-and-nail presidential election battle with US Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic nominee, has spoken little about the recent escalation in tensions in the Middle East.</p>

<p>He issued a scathing statement this week, holding Biden and Harris responsible for the crisis.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-10/gnaai9n8_donald-trump-reuters-650_625x300_22_October_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump said Friday he believes Israel should strike Iran's nuclear facilities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dona-dtrump-promotes-fake-endorsement-from-jpmorgan-ceo-6718904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Promotes Fake Endorsement From JPMorgan CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dona-dtrump-promotes-fake-endorsement-from-jpmorgan-ceo-6718904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 03:18:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Friday promoted a fake endorsement from JPMorgan Chief Executive Jamie Dimon, who has not taken a side in the US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Friday promoted a fake endorsement from JPMorgan Chief Executive Jamie Dimon, who has not taken a side in the US presidential election.</p>

<p>Trump posted to his Truth Social platform a photograph of Dimon with the headline: "New: Jamie Dimon, the CEO of JPMorgan Chase, has endorsed Trump for President."</p>

<p>The item, posted by Trump around 1800 GMT, appeared to be a repost of another social media item.</p>

<p>But a JPMorgan spokesman said the longtime bank head has not taken a side in the race.</p>

<p>"That report was false," said JPMorgan spokesman Joe Evangelisti in an email to AFP. "Jamie has not endorsed a candidate."</p>

<p>Trump in August shared doctored images that purported to show superstar singer Taylor Swift supporting his presidential campaign.</p>

<p>But Swift last month delivered a sweeping endorsement to Trump's opponent, Vice President Kamala Harris. The doctored images shared by Trump "conjured up my fears around AI, and the dangers of spreading misinformation," she wrote in a September 11 Instagram post.</p>

<p>"The simplest way to combat misinformation is with the truth," Swift said.</p>

<p>At 1700 GMT, the fake Dimon endorsement was still posted to Trump's page on Truth Social.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gfbm3a8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Friday promoted a fake endorsement from JPMorgan Chief Executive.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-its-forces-strike-15-houthi-targets-in-yemen-6718580]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says Its Forces Strike 15 Houthi Targets In Yemen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-its-forces-strike-15-houthi-targets-in-yemen-6718580]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 01:24:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US forces on Friday hit 15 targets in Huthi-controlled areas of Yemen, the US military said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US forces on Friday hit 15 targets in Huthi-controlled areas of Yemen, the US military said.</p>

<p>Four provinces were struck, the Iran-backed rebels' Al Masirah television network reported.</p>

<p>The United States and Britain have repeatedly carried out strikes aimed at curbing the Huthis' ability to target shipping, but the rebels' attacks on merchant vessels transiting the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden have persisted.</p>

<p>"US Central Command (CENTCOM) forces conducted strikes on 15 Huthi targets in Iranian-backed Huthi-controlled areas of Yemen today," the military command responsible for US forces in the Middle East said on social media.</p>

<p>"These targets included Huthi offensive military capabilities," CENTCOM said, adding that the strikes were carried out "to protect freedom of navigation and make international waters safer and more secure for US, coalition, and &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; merchant vessels."</p>

<p>Al Masirah -- which said both the United States and Britain struck Yemen on Friday -- had earlier reported four strikes on Sanaa and seven on Hodeida. AFP correspondents heard loud explosions in both cities.</p>

<p>At least one strike each hit Dhamar, south of the capital, and Mukayras, southeast of Sanaa, Al Masirah said.</p>

<p>The Huthis have been hitting shipping since November, saying that attacks, which have disrupted maritime traffic in a globally important waterway, target vessels linked to Israel and are intended to signal solidarity with Palestinians during the Gaza war.</p>

<p>- Huthi attacks on Israel -</p>

<p>Israel has also struck Yemen in response to Huthi attacks. Israeli strikes on Hodeida last month killed at least five people after the rebels said they had targeted Israel's Ben Gurion Airport with a missile.</p>

<p>The US strikes took place a day after the rebels said they carried out a drone attack on Tel Aviv. The Israeli military said it had intercepted "a suspicious aerial target" overnight off central Israel, without giving further details.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the Huthis said they had fired cruise missiles at Israel, following Iran's massive bombardment of the country.</p>

<p>The day before, the Huthis damaged two ships in separate attacks off Yemen's coast.</p>

<p>One ship was hit by a marine drone, puncturing a ballast tank, while a second vessel was damaged by a missile less than three hours later, the United Kingdom Maritime Trade Operations (UKMTO) said.</p>

<p>The Huthis, who have controlled large swaths of war-torn Yemen for a decade, are part of the "axis of resistance" of Iran-linked groups arrayed against Israel and the United States.</p>

<p>The latest strikes came as thousands of people took to the streets of the capital Sanaa to express solidarity with Palestinians and Lebanese amid attacks by Israel.</p>

<p>"The aggression on the capital and Yemeni governorates after the...solidarity marches with Lebanon and Gaza is a desperate attempt to terrorize our people," Huthi official Hashem Sharaf al-Din told Al Masirah.</p>

<p>"Yemen will not be deterred by these attacks and will continue its steadfastness in confronting the enemies with all its strength," he said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US forces on Friday hit 15 targets in Huthi-controlled areas of Yemen, the US military said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-i-dont-know-if-election-will-be-peaceful-6718424]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says "I Don't Know" If Election Will Be Peaceful]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-i-dont-know-if-election-will-be-peaceful-6718424]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:35:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden said Friday he wasn't confident the US election in November would be peaceful, due to previous comments by Republican contender Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden said Friday he wasn't confident the US election in November would be peaceful, due to previous comments by Republican contender Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"I'm confident it will be free and fair. I don't know whether it will be peaceful," Biden told reporters as he made the first appearance of his presidency in the White House briefing room.</p>

<p>"The things that Trump has said and the things that he said last time out when he didn't like the outcome of the election were very dangerous."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o30es1hg_joe-biden-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden said he is confident election will be free and fair.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-israel-should-consider-alternatives-to-striking-iran-oil-fields-6718385]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says Israel Should Consider Alternatives To Striking Iran Oil Fields]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-israel-should-consider-alternatives-to-striking-iran-oil-fields-6718385]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:24:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden on Friday urged Israel against striking Iran's oil facilities, a day after he said the United States was discussing the possibility of such strikes with its ally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;President Joe Biden said on Friday he would think about alternatives to striking Iranian oil fields if he were in Israel's shoes, adding he thinks Israel has not yet concluded how to respond to Iran.</p>

<p>"The Israelis have not concluded what they are going to do in terms of a strike. That's under discussion," Biden said in remarks to reporters at a White House press briefing.</p>

<p>"If I were in their shoes, I'd be thinking about other alternatives than striking oilfields," the president added.</p>

<p>Tensions between Iran and Israel have been high as Israel has been weighing options to respond to Tehran's ballistic missile attack on Tuesday, which Iran had carried out in response to Israel's military action in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Biden was also asked if he thought that by not engaging in diplomacy, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was trying to influence the Nov. 5 U.S. election in which Republican former President Donald Trump faces Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>"Whether he is trying to influence the election, I don't know but I am not counting on that," Biden said in response. "No administration has done more to help Israel than I have."</p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered by Palestinian Hamas militants' Oct. 7, 2023, attack that killed 1,200 and in which about 250 were taken as hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on Hamas-governed Gaza has killed over 41,000 Palestinians, according to Gaza's health ministry, and displaced nearly Gaza's entire population, caused a hunger crisis and led to genocide allegations that Israel denies.</p>

<p>Israel's recent military action in Lebanon has killed hundreds, wounded thousands and displaced over a million. Israel says it is targeting Lebanese Iran-backed Hezbollah militants.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ro6ijdvo_joe-biden_625x300_11_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden urged Israel to avoid striking Iran's oil facilities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/public-allowed-to-see-video-evidence-in-mass-rape-trial-in-france-6718263]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Public Allowed To See Video Evidence In Mass Rape Trial In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/public-allowed-to-see-video-evidence-in-mass-rape-trial-in-france-6718263]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 23:54:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court trying a French man charged with enlisting dozens of strangers to rape his heavily drugged wife ruled on Friday that the public could be present when video evidence is screened, reversing an earlier decision.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court trying a French man charged with enlisting dozens of strangers to rape his heavily drugged wife ruled on Friday that the public could be present when video evidence is screened, reversing an earlier decision.</p>

<p>Lawyers for the victim, Gisele Pelicot -- ex-wife of the main accused, Dominique Pelicot -- hailed as a "victory" the ruling announced by judge Roger Arata.</p>

<p>The screening of images will be preceded by an "announcement allowing people of a sensitive disposition and minors to leave the courtroom," the judge added.</p>

<p>Since the trial started on September 2, the court in the southern city of Avignon has been reserved for members of the court, the parties and the press.</p>

<p>The public has been assigned to an adjoining room where proceedings are screened live.</p>

<p>The screening of video evidence will, however, "not be systematic" and will only take place when it is "strictly necessary for exposing the truth" at the request of one of the parties, added Arata.</p>

<p>Dominque Pelicot filmed much of the abuse against his wife and also took meticulous records of the strangers visiting the family home, unwittingly helping police uncover the crimes.</p>

<p>He was intially investigated when he was caught taking pictures up women's skirts in a supermarket in 2020.</p>

<p>Last month the judge banned the broadcast of images in the presence of the public and the press, saying: "Considering that these images are indecent and shocking, this will only be done in the presence of the parties to the trial and the court."</p>

<p>But lawyers for Gisele Pelicot -- who has insisted on the trial being open to the public to draw attention to the use of drugs to commit sexual abuse -- called for the lifting of the restrictions.</p>

<p>- 'Find meaning in suffering' -</p>

<p>The ruling is a "victory" but "a victory in a fight that should not have been fought," said lawyer Stephane Babonneau, arguing that French law has granted rape victims for over 40 years the right to decide whether or not the proceedings should be public.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot's willingness to highlight her suffering has won widespread praise and made her a feminist icon in France.</p>

<p>"For Gisele Pelicot, it is too late. The harm is done," said Babonneau.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"But if these same hearings, through their publicity, help prevent other women from having to go through this, then she will find meaning in her suffering.".</p>

<p>The trial, which is due to last until December, is currently hearing testimony from the other men facing charges of responding to Dominique Pelicot's call and raping Gisele Pelicot.</p>

<p>Forty-nine other men are accused of raping or attempting to rape Gisele Pelicot. Another has admitted to sedating his own spouse so that he and Dominique Pelicot could sexually assault her.</p>

<p>Some lawyers for the other 50 accused strongly opposed the screening of video evidence.</p>

<p>"Justice does not need that in order to proceed, what is the point of these revolting screenings?" said lawyer Olivier Lantelme.</p>

<p>"We do not have to move from a popular tribunal in the name of the French people to a tribunal of the crowd," added Paul-Roger Gontard.</p>

<p>But for Antoine Camus, another lawyer in Gisele Pelicot's team, these videos "cause the argument of accidental rape to collapse".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They show that these were opportunistic rapes and, beyond that, it was a question of degrading, humiliating, and sullying, it was in reality a question of hatred of women.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"No one (among the defendants) denounced what was happening, each contributed in their own small way to this banality of rape, to this banality of evil", he added.</p>

<p>Beatrice Zavarro, Dominique Pelicot's lawyer, who had previously backed the screening of the videos, did not express an opinion on the issue on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5m5tlorg_gisele-pelicot-french-mass-rape-survivor-afp_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gisele Pelicot's willingness to highlight her suffering has won widespread praise.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-happens-next-in-israel-iran-conflict-6718070]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Happens Next In Israel-Iran Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-happens-next-in-israel-iran-conflict-6718070]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 23:13:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's invasion of Lebanon this week and Iran's missile attack on its regional foe, all while war rages on in Gaza, have heightened the risk of a high-intensity conflict across the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's invasion of Lebanon this week and Iran's missile attack on its regional foe, all while war rages on in Gaza, have heightened the risk of a high-intensity conflict across the Middle East.</p>

<p>The spiralling violence now threatens to engulf more and more of the region despite diplomatic efforts to calm tensions, with UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres warning of a "sickening cycle of escalation after escalation".</p>

<p>AFP spoke to analysts to assess what could happen next:</p>

<p><strong>- Will Israel retaliate? -</strong></p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu swiftly condemned the launch of some 200 missiles at his country on Tuesday, declaring: "Iran made a big mistake tonight and will pay for it."</p>

<p>David Khalfa, a Middle East expert at the Jean-Jaures Foundation, a Paris-based think-tank, said Israel has little choice but to respond to the Iranian attack "because of the scale and the fact that the nature of the targets has changed" to include sensitive military sites.</p>

<p>It was the second time Iran directly attacked Israel. In April, a barrage of around 300 drones and missiles triggered a measured Israeli retaliation that saw a single Iranian air defence radar installation destroyed.</p>

<p>The response this time is expected to be of far greater magnitude, according to analysts.</p>

<p>With many Israelis celebrating the Jewish New Year this week, the holidays may "not be a good time to retaliate", said Danny Citrinowicz, an Iran specialist at the Institute for National Security Studies (INSS) in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"But I don't think it will take much time," he said.</p>

<p><strong>- What are Israel's options? -</strong></p>

<p>Since the Iranian attack, Israeli officials have argued there was a potential "historic opportunity to decisively deal with the Iranian regime", according to Khalfa.</p>

<p>Former prime minister, Naftali Bennett, was one of the first to call for an attack on Iranian nuclear facilities, which Israel regards as an existential threat.</p>

<p>But the most sensitive equipment is believed to be buried deep underground where Israel may be unable to hit.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden has advised against even trying, urging Israel to respond "in proportion" -- although Netanyahu has often ignored his guidance in the past.</p>

<p>Other possible Israeli responses include targeted assassinations, strikes on Iranian industrial sites or cyberattacks, according to experts and Israeli media reports.</p>

<p>Biden has also mentioned ongoing discussions about potential strikes on Iranian oil infrastructure, which sent prices for crude spiking on Thursday.</p>

<p>Khalfa said that after decades of tension, Israel and Iran are now "no longer in a low-intensity confrontation but an open war", which could evolve into a "regional war of attrition".</p>

<p><strong>- Do Iran and Israel want war? -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Iran has "already thought things through, to some extent at least. They are ready," said Citrinowicz, suggesting that Tehran's response to any Israeli retaliation would be "swift".</p>

<p>Sima Shine, another Iran expert at the INSS, said that the Islamic republic possessed "undeniable" destructive capabilities.</p>

<p>"They can launch more than 200, or even 300 missiles, and they also have drones," she said, while also warning about "terrorist operations abroad" that could include attacks on Israeli diplomatic missions or Jewish community centres.</p>

<p>"Everything right now hinges on Israel's response, whether it escalates into a regional war," said Sina Toossi, a senior fellow at the Center for International Policy in Washington.</p>

<p>Both Netanyahu and Iran were "taking huge gambles", he said.</p>

<p>And with each escalation, the risks increase.</p>

<p>However, both Iran and Israel have repeatedly insisted that they do not want to be drawn into a spiral of retaliatory violence.</p>

<p>Israel is already engaged on several military fronts.</p>

<p>In the Gaza Strip, the military is fighting Hamas, aiming to rescue the 97 hostages taken on October 7 who are still held there.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, after days of air strikes against Hezbollah, troops are now battling the Iran-backed militants on the ground.</p>

<p>And elsewhere in the region, Israel confronts armed groups like Yemen's Huthi rebels who have increased their missile and drone attacks.</p>

<p>Ultimately, Citrinowicz said, both Iran and Israel "will look for a political solution" that may be supported by the United States and France, whose influence particularly in Lebanon could play a critical role in restoring calm.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pg9pbpg8_israels-iron-dome-antimissile-system-intercepts-rockets-reuters_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu swiftly condemned the launch of some 200 missiles.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-tests-verified-check-marks-in-search-results-for-certain-companies-6718024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Tests Verified Check Marks In Search Results For Certain Companies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-tests-verified-check-marks-in-search-results-for-certain-companies-6718024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 23:04:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alphabet's Google is testing showing check marks next to certain companies on its search results, a company spokesperson said on Friday, in a move aimed at helping users identify verified sources and steer clear of fake websites.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alphabet's Google is testing showing check marks next to certain companies on its search results, a company spokesperson said on Friday, in a move aimed at helping users identify verified sources and steer clear of fake websites.</p>

<p>Fraudulent websites impersonating official businesses or services could creep up in online search results, leading users to view false information about the business, deceiving users and potentially harming the brand.</p>

<p>"We regularly experiment with features that help shoppers identify trustworthy businesses online, and we are currently running a small experiment showing checkmarks next to certain businesses on Google," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Google already uses automated systems to identify pages with "scammy" or fraudulent content and prevent them from showing up in the search results.</p>

<p>The Verge reported the development earlier on Friday, adding that it spotted blue verified checkmarks next to official site links for companies including Microsoft, Meta and Apple on search results.</p>

<p>Only some users were able to see the feature, the Verge said, indicating Google has not rolled out the test widely yet.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/9eka3s18_google-search_625x300_24_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google has not rolled out the test widely yet.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drone-launched-from-the-east-killed-2-soldiers-says-israel-6717963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drone Launched From "The East" Killed 2 Soldiers, Says Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drone-launched-from-the-east-killed-2-soldiers-says-israel-6717963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 22:50:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army on Friday said a drone launched "from the east" killed two soldiers, with a public broadcaster reporting the strike originated from Iraq and hit a base in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army on Friday said a drone launched "from the east" killed two soldiers, with a public broadcaster reporting the strike originated from Iraq and hit a base in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>The military said the two soldiers died in northern Israel. When asked by AFP for details it said the soldiers were killed in a drone strike launched from the east, without specifying from where.</p>

<p>Israeli army radio said the strike was launched from Iraq overnight Thursday.</p>

<p>Two UAVs were launched from Iraq and crossed into Israeli territory in the Golan Heights area, the radio said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"One UAV was intercepted by the air force, while the second exploded at a military camp north of the Golan Heights," it said.</p>

<p>"As a result of the explosion two soldiers were killed," it said, adding 24 others were wounded.</p>

<p>Public broadcaster Kan also reported the strike originated from Iraq and hit the Golan Heights.</p>

<p>The Islamic Resistance in Iraq group, which is pro-Iran, said it launched a series of drone strikes targeting Israel this week, including three attacks on three different targets in the Golan and Tiberias early Friday.</p>

<p>The Israel-Hamas war in the Gaza Strip, triggered by the Palestinian group's October 7 attack on Israel, has also drawn in Iran-backed militants in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/c5f394lg_drone-generic_625x300_16_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli army radio said the strike was launched from Iraq. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-after-she-was-taken-hostage-israeli-girl-adapts-to-new-family-life-6717083]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Year After She Was Taken Hostage, Israeli Girl Adapts To New Family Life]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-after-she-was-taken-hostage-israeli-girl-adapts-to-new-family-life-6717083]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:35:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli couple Leron and Zoli Mor have identical tattoos on their arms showing a procession of eight elephants, their tails and trunks intertwined.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli couple Leron and Zoli Mor have identical tattoos on their arms showing a procession of eight elephants, their tails and trunks intertwined.</p>

<p>The first two are the parents and the six smaller ones behind them are the calves. The last three are even smaller than the rest and are depicted in fresher ink because they were added later.</p>

<p>The eight elephants represent the Mor family. Leron and Zoli Mor have three children of their own and have adopted three others whose parents - one of them Leron's sister - were killed in the attack by Hamas gunmen on Israel on Oct. 7 last year.</p>

<p>"They were five," Leron Mor said at the family's new home in the northern Israeli village of Bnei Dror, pointing to that tattoo on her arm. "And they were joined by three more."</p>

<p>One of the three who were adopted, Avigail Idan, was among more than 250 people taken hostage during the attack led by the Palestinian militant group. She was released last November though about 100 people are still in captivity as the Israel-Hamas war triggered by the attack rages on.</p>

<p>She was aged three at the time of the attack, in which her parents were among 1,200 people killed. Her older siblings, Michael and Amalia, hid in a cabinet at their home in a kibbutz, their mother lying lifeless on the floor nearby.</p>

<p>The Mors were also living in the kibbutz in southern Israel at the time and were rescued from their home the day after the attack. They now live far away in Bnei Dror, an agricultural village near the Mediterranean coast.</p>

<p>"The conversation here in the house is very open. We talk about their parents. We do not forget about them for one moment," said Leron Mor. "We look at pictures together. And they are present in our lives."</p>

<p>Avigail also has U.S. citizenship, and she and the family met U.S. President Joe Biden at the White House in April.</p>

<p>"He was simply compassionate and warm and caring," Leron Mor said. "We spoke to him about the people, our friends, who are still there and all the hostages. We asked him to make every effort to get them out because that's the only important thing right now. There is nothing more important than that."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/703fchmo_israeli-family_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Mors were also living in the kibbutz in southern Israel at the time and were rescued from their home.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-tests-robot-dogs-armed-with-ai-enabled-guns-at-military-facility-in-middle-east-report-6716933]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Army Tests Robot Dogs Armed With AI-Enabled Guns: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-tests-robot-dogs-armed-with-ai-enabled-guns-at-military-facility-in-middle-east-report-6716933]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:12:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Army is testing robot dogs mounted with AI-enabled guns at a military facility in the Middle East, according to Military.com.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Army is testing robot dogs mounted with AI-enabled guns at a military facility in the Middle East, according to <em>Military.com</em>. Photos shared by the Defense Visual Information Distribution Service (DVIDS) show one such robot dog undergoing "rehearsals" at the Red Sands Integrated Experimentation Center in Saudi Arabia in mid-September as part of a recent counter-unmanned aerial system exercise. The four-legged robot can be seen mounted with what appears to be an AR-15/M16 pattern rifle on a rotating turret and resembles the robot system that the US Army tested at Fort Drum, New York in August.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US Army describes the robot dog as a four-legged unmanned ground vehicle (UGVs) armed with an artificial intelligence-enabled rifle - contributing to innovative unmanned capabilities. Notably, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dvidshub.net/image/8663734/centcom-and-saudi-arabian-armed-forces-conduct-third-iteration-red-sands-counter-s-uas-exercise">DVIDS </a>is an operation run by the US Department of Defence to provide media on its activities across the world.</p>

<p>Speaking to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.military.com/daily-news/2024/10/01/army-has-sent-armed-robot-dog-middle-east-testing.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Military.com</em></a>, a US Army Central spokesman said that the armed robot dog was one of several "non-counter-sUAS" systems tested alongside 15 counter-drone platforms at Red Sands during the September test. The gun engaged several static ground targets, the official said without elaborating on its potential applications.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the US Defence Department has been incorporating robot dogs and other autonomous ground vehicles in its formations over the last few years. Additionally, the Pentagon has increasingly experimented with mounting weapons systems on robot dogs.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/panic-after-bank-of-america-customers-see-zero-balance-in-their-accounts-heres-what-happened-6706966">Panic After Bank Of America Customers See Zero Balance In Their Accounts. Here's What Happened</a></strong></p>

<p>The Marine Corps, in particular, has tested quadrupedal robots outfitted with both Onyx Industries' SENTRY remote weapon system and the M72 LAW anti-tank rocket launcher, while the Army has considered outfitting mechanized canines with the new 6.8mm XM7 rifle the service recently fielded under its Next Generation Squad Weapon program to replace the M4 carbine, the outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the US military isn't the only country pursuing four-legged weapon combat robots. In May, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-military-unveils-rifle-mounted-robot-dog-5764449">Chinese military</a> debuted its own robot dog armed with an assault rifle during a training exercise in Cambodia. The video of the robot dog was released by state broadcaster CCTV.</p>

<p>"It can serve as a new member in our urban combat operations, replacing our (human) members to conduct reconnaissance and identify (the) enemy and strike the target," a soldier named Chen Wei said in the video.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/haftor4g_us-robot-dog_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[DVIDS is an operation run by the US Department of Defense.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-2-000-military-sites-hit-during-ground-incursion-in-lebanon-israel-6716875]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 2,000 "Military Sites" Hit During Ground Incursion In Lebanon: Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-2-000-military-sites-hit-during-ground-incursion-in-lebanon-israel-6716875]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:04:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army on Friday said its forces had hit more than 2,000 sites during its four-day incursion into southern Lebanon targeting Hezbollah positions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army on Friday said its forces had hit more than 2,000 sites during its four-day incursion into southern Lebanon targeting Hezbollah positions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Over 2,000 military targets have been struck," including militants, military buildings, weapons and more, the Israeli military said in a statement.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6vcrm188_lebanon-citizen_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has been conducting an air-land attack on Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-easemytrip-resumes-maldives-bookings-after-improved-ties-6716725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's EaseMyTrip Resumes Maldives Bookings After "Improved Ties"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-easemytrip-resumes-maldives-bookings-after-improved-ties-6716725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 19:43:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Travel tech platform EaseMyTrip - which suspended flight bookings to Maldives in January after a diplomatic row with India - on Friday said it has resumed bookings to the island nation after "improved bilateral ties" between both governments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Travel tech platform EaseMyTrip - which suspended flight bookings to Maldives in January after a diplomatic row with India - on Friday said it has resumed bookings to the island nation after "improved bilateral ties" between both governments.</p>

<p>In June, EaseMyTrip CEO Nishant Pitti responded to the controversy around the resumption of flight bookings to Maldives through the platform, admitting that "some bookings did occur" between May 16-26 but the company acted swiftly and removed them.</p>

<p>The response came after Kerala Congress questioned EaseMyTrip on social media platform X, highlighting the company's earlier decision to remove Maldives from its platform as a show of support for Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>

<p>In a statement on Friday, EaseMyTrip co-founder and CEO Pitti said, "Basis positive developments in mending India-Maldives bilateral ties, by both governments, we are resuming bookings to the Maldives. This decision comes after careful consideration and follows a constructive dialogue with the Ministry of Tourism of Maldives delegation during their recent visit to India and our office".</p>

<p>"Being a nation-first company we are always in alignment with our government and support their vision. It is a progressive step towards the renewed friendship and mutual goals of enhancing tourism."&nbsp;</p>

<p>EaseMyTrip had initially halted bookings to Maldives in January after three Maldivian ministers made derogatory comments about Prime Minister Modi following his visit to Lakshadweep.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/038omrs8_maldives-pixabay_625x300_03_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[EaseMyTrip had initially halted bookings to Maldives.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spanish-f-18-fighter-jet-crashes-while-flying-low-pilot-dies-6716494]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spanish F-18 Fighter Jet Crashes While Flying Low, Pilot Dies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spanish-f-18-fighter-jet-crashes-while-flying-low-pilot-dies-6716494]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 19:15:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Spanish Air Force pilot died when an F18 fighter plane crashed Friday in eastern Spain, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Spanish Air Force pilot died when an F18 fighter plane crashed Friday in eastern Spain, officials said.</p>

<p>The pilot was the only person on the jet when it crashed at around 12:30 pm (1030 GMT) near Peralejos in the province of Teruel, the Air Force said on social network X.</p>

<p>"We regret to inform you that the death of our colleague, Lieutenant Colonel Pablo Estrada Martin, assigned to Wing 12, has been confirmed in the F-18 accident. We share in the grief of his family and friends. Rest in peace, comrade," the Spanish Air Force said in a post.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="es">? ÚLTIMA HORA | Lamentamos comunicar que se ha confirmado en el accidente del F-18 el fallecimiento de nuestro compañero, el teniente coronel Pablo Estrada Martín, destinado en el Ala 12.<br />
<br />
Nos unimos al dolor de sus familiares y amigos. Descansa en paz, compañero. <a href="https://t.co/OUim93TANr">pic.twitter.com/OUim93TANr</a></p>
— Ejército del Aire y del Espacio (@EjercitoAire) <a href="https://twitter.com/EjercitoAire/status/1842178462016057682?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Our most sincere condolences to the family, friends and colleagues of the victim," the defence ministry said in a separate message on X that was accompanied by a photo of the pilot.</p>

<p>Images of the accident broadcast by Aragon TV showed a thick column of smoke moving up from the wooded terrain where the plane crashed.</p>

<p>The aircraft was on an exercise with another F18 fighter and was flying at a low altitude when the accident occurred, according to local newspaper El Heraldo de Aragon.</p>

<p>Both planes had took off from the Torrejon de Ardoz base near Madrid, it added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6nmha4s_lieutenant-colonel-pablo-estrada-martin-spanish-air-force_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lieutenant Colonel Pablo Estrada Martin died in the crash.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysia-man-sets-sons-motorbike-on-fire-after-discovering-his-addiction-to-late-night-racing-6716214]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Malaysia Man Sets Son's Bike On Fire After Discovering His Racing Addiction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysia-man-sets-sons-motorbike-on-fire-after-discovering-his-addiction-to-late-night-racing-6716214]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 18:41:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A father in Malaysia set his son's motorbike ablaze in a desperate attempt to protect him from potentially deadly accidents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A father in Malaysia set his son's motorbike ablaze in a desperate attempt to protect him from potentially deadly accidents. According to the <em>South China Morning Post</em>, the father, whose identity has been revealed, initially bought the motorcycle for his son because he thought it would be more convenient for him to ride it to school. However, after discovering that his son had become dangerously addicted to riding the motorcycle, the father made the drastic decision to burn the two-wheeler, believing it was a better fate than his son dying in an accident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The father discovered that his son, whose age has not been disclosed, began participating in illegal motorbike races, often returning home late at night, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3280310/malaysia-dad-sets-sons-motorbike-fire-driven-concern-his-safety-late-night-races" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>SCMP </em></a>reported. This reckless behaviour raised serious safety concerns for the father, who repeatedly attempted to dissuade his son from engaging in such perilous activities. But his advice fell on deaf ears, leaving him feeling increasingly helpless and desperate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Therefore, faced with the possibility of his son sustaining injuries or worse, the father took the drastic decision of destroying the motorcycle. "I don't want to lose my son forever," the father said in a TikTok video of himself burning the two-wheeler. "I also do not want to receive a call from police officers that my son has been detained for racing the motorcycle," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The father stated that the motorcycle had become the primary source of conflict between him and his son so he felt he had no choice but to destroy it. He defended his action as a desperate measure for his son's well-being. "I did this for the sake of my child. Burning the motorbike is the best medicine for my son before I lose him. With this motorbike, my son is a monster," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/us-based-man-lists-executioner-in-saudi-arabia-as-hobby-on-dating-app-internet-reacts-6715550">US-Based Man Lists "Executioner In Saudi Arabia" As Hobby On Dating App, Internet Reacts</a></strong></p>

<p>The outlet did not disclose the son's reaction to his father burning his vehicle. However, on social media, the incident has sparked discussion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I agree with this father. He did it out of genuine concern for his son's safety. He saved his son's life, and after all, a life cannot be bought with money," wrote one person, per SCMP. &nbsp;"I hope the son can understand his father's love," said another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, some social media users did see the positive side of the father's action.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"His method is violent. You should treat your kid as a friend, not an enemy. You should discuss it with your child. Your behaviour has not solved the problem and will only worsen the relationship between you and your son," commented one user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Why not sell it? You could make some money from the sale," said another.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9b66b1ig_motorcycle-generic_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The outlet did not disclose the son's reaction. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sco-meet-pakistan-external-affairs-minister-s-jaishankar-to-visit-pak-first-foreign-minister-there-since-sushma-swaraj-6715952]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar To Visit Pak, First Foreign Minister There Since Sushma Swaraj]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sco-meet-pakistan-external-affairs-minister-s-jaishankar-to-visit-pak-first-foreign-minister-there-since-sushma-swaraj-6715952]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 18:06:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[S Jaishankar will visit Pakistan later this month to attend the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation, becoming the first External Affairs Minister to do so in nine years. The last visit was by Sushma Swaraj in 2015.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>S Jaishankar will visit Pakistan later this month to attend the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation, becoming the first External Affairs Minister to do so in nine years. The last visit was by Sushma Swaraj in 2015.&nbsp;</p>

<p>External Affairs Ministry Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said on Friday that Mr Jaishankar will lead a delegation to Pakistan to attend a Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) Council of Heads of Government meeting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The External Affairs Minister will lead our delegation to Pakistan to participate in the SCO summit which will be held in Islamabad on October 15 and 16," Mr Jaiswal said, emphasising that the visit will be limited to attending the summit. Pakistan had invited Prime Minister Narendra Modi for the meeting in August.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The decision to send Mr Jaishankar to Pakistan for the summit is being seen as a major one by the Union government given the chill in ties between the two countries since the Pulwama terrorist attack in February 2019, which was followed by the Balakot air strikes, in which India targeted a Jaish-e-Mohammed training camp. The relationship got even more strained after Pakistan vociferously opposed India's removal of Article 370, which granted special status to Jammu and Kashmir.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India has repeatedly slammed Pakistan's interference on the issue and reiterated that it is an internal matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Addressing the United Nations General Assembly last week, Mr Jaishankar had warned Pakistan that its policy of cross-border terrorism could never succeed and also alluded to its economic crisis.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Many countries get left behind due to circumstances beyond their control. But some make conscious choices with disastrous consequences. A premier example is our neighbour, Pakistan. Unfortunately, their misdeeds affect others as well, especially the neighbourhood," the minister said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Display Of Commitment</strong></p>

<p>Given all of this, the fact that Mr Jaishankar will attend the summit in the country is being seen as a display of India's commitment to the SCO which, it believes, has been playing a vital role in boosting regional security cooperation. Sushma Swaraj had visited Pakistan in 2015 to attend a conference on Afghanistan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Apart from India, the SCO has China, Russia, Pakistan, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan as member countries and is an influential economic and security bloc as well as one of the largest transregional international organisations.</p>

<p>The SCO was founded at a summit in Shanghai in 2001 by the presidents of Russia, China, the Kyrgyz Republic, Kazakhstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan and India was an observer country for the first time in 2005. It became a permanent member, along with Pakistan, in 2017.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India was the chair of the organisation in 2023 and hosted the SCO summit in the virtual format in July of that year.</p>

<p>The SCO Council of Heads of Government conclave, which Mr Jaishankar will be attending, is the second-highest platform in the grouping while the Heads of State Summit is the top-most forum and is generally attended by the Prime Minister.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vosli4u8_s-jaishankar_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India became a permanent member of the organisation in 2017.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-days-to-8-months-sunita-williams-barry-wilmores-extended-stay-in-space-6715868]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8 Days To 8 Months: Sunita Williams, Barry Wilmore's Extended Stay In Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-days-to-8-months-sunita-williams-barry-wilmores-extended-stay-in-space-6715868]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:59:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Boeing Starliner lifted off the International Space Station in June with NASA's veteran astronauts, Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore, the mission was intended to last for eight days but a technical failure delayed the astronauts' return.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Boeing Starliner lifted off the International Space Station in June with NASA's veteran astronauts, Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore, the mission was intended to last for eight days but a technical failure delayed the astronauts' return, extending the mission by eight more months.</p>

<p>The Boeing Starliner capsule faced propulsion issues including a Helium leak which resulted in aborting the return. The spacecraft's service module reported several tiny helium leaks making it unsafe for travel. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-helium-leaks-delayed-boeing-starliner-astronauts-return-6509846">Helium </a>is essential to preserving the spacecraft's structural integrity and manoeuvrability. Along with Helium leaks, the spacecraft detected problems in its thrusters and valves.</p>

<p>The mission aimed to demonstrate the Boeing Starliner's capability to take humans to the ISS. Boeing needed to tap into the space Elon Musk's SpaceX has entered to provide crew transportation services to NASA.</p>

<p>Transporting Ms Williams and Mr Bilmore was Starliner's first crewed flight.</p>

<h2><b>SpaceX To The Rescue</b></h2>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/space-x-to-bring-back-sunita-williams-on-way-to-international-space-station-6676224">The NASA-SpaceX spacecraft, carrying Crew-9</a> members NASA astronaut Nick Hague (commander) and Roscosmos cosmonaut Aleksandr Gorbunov (mission specialist), docked at the International Space Station (ISS) last month to bring back Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore.</p>

<p>The Crew-9 members will have two empty seats for NASA astronauts Barry Wilmore and Sunita Williams will fill when the spacecraft returns next year.</p>

<p>The astronauts will now return home in February next year.</p>

<p>Interestingly, the Starliner returned to Earth after weeks of extensive testing but without the crew. The return of Starliner delayed the launch of Crew-9 from mid-August to September since NASA wanted more time to evaluate the reliability of the Starliner.</p>

<p>Hague and Gorbunov will stay in space for five months before coming back home.</p>

<h2><b>Surviving In Space</b></h2>

<p>The extended stay of Williams and Bilmore raised concerns about their survival, particularly regarding food and oxygen supply.</p>

<p>NASA assured that there is no immediate danger to the astronauts and the ISS has sufficient provisions to support the crew for the additional time.</p>

<p>"The space station is well-stocked with everything the crew needs, including food, water, clothing and oxygen," NASA stated. The agency stressed that regular resupply missions will ensure the astronauts' needs are met, citing regular arrivals of cargo spacecraft carrying food, fuel and supplies.</p>

<p>The space station revealed that two spacecraft - one carrying "8,200 pounds of food, fuel, supplies" and another carrying "three tons of cargo" - arrived at the ISS recently.</p>

<p>Living in space for an extended period requires unique arrangements. On the ISS, astronauts can sleep anywhere - floor, ceiling or walls - thanks to zero gravity. They use sleeping stations, similar to phone booths, with sleeping bags and pillows attached to the floor, wall, or ceiling. Astronauts can also make video calls, audio calls or send emails through NASA.</p>

<p>Aboard the ISS, Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore also have access to the Vegetable Production System (Veggie garden) which allows them to grow fresh produce and even flowers in space. During their extended stay, the duo has been experimenting with various techniques to improve crop growth in space.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/be6nk56_butch-wilmore-and-sunita-williams_625x300_30_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Transporting Ms Williams and Mr Bilmore was Starliner's first crewed flight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/antarctica-turning-green-at-an-alarming-rate-says-study-6715700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Antarctica Turning Green At An Alarming Rate, Says Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/antarctica-turning-green-at-an-alarming-rate-says-study-6715700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:38:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From a meagre 0.4 square miles in 1986, the vegetation cover reached almost 5 square miles in 2021, the study found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Icy Antarctica is known for its vast white landscape. But extreme heat events and climate change are turning parts of the continent green, according to a concerning new study. Scientists from universities of Exeter and Hertfordshire used satellite imagery and data to analyse vegetation levels in Antarctica, which has been warming at ana alarming rate, much faster than the global average. As per <em>CNN</em>, the team of researchers found plant life - mostly mosses - and said the green cover has increased 10-fold over the past four decades or 40 years.</p>

<p>The study was published on Friday in the journal <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-024-01564-5">Nature Geoscience</a></em>.</p>

<p>From a meagre 0.4 square miles in 1986, the vegetation cover reached almost 5 square miles in 2021, the study found. In a period of five years - from 2016 to 2021 - accelerated by more than 30 per cent.</p>

<p>"Our findings confirm that the influence of anthropogenic climate change has no limit in its reach," Thomas Roland, a study author and environmental scientist at the University of Exeter, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/04/climate/antarctica-greening-vegetation-satellite-images/index.html">told <em>CNN</em></a>. "Even on the Antarctic Peninsula - this most extreme, remote and isolated 'wilderness' region - the landscape is changing, and these effects are visible from space."</p>

<p>Though the landscape is almost entirely snow, these researchers found that the green cover has grown dramatically.</p>

<p>At a conference in Chile in August, nearly 1,500 academics, researchers and scientists discussed whether the extreme climate events events meant Antarctica had reached a tipping point, or a point of accelerated and irreversible sea ice loss from the West Antarctic ice sheet.</p>

<p>"You might see the same rise in CO2 over thousands of years, and now it's happened in 100 years," said Liz Keller, a paleoclimate specialist from the Victoria University of Wellington in New Zealand.</p>

<p>Antarctica, the coldest place on Earth, has witnessed severe extreme heat events.</p>

<p>In summer months this year, the average temperature in the continent climbed up to 50 degrees Fahrenheit above normal.</p>

<p>In March 2022, temperatures in some parts of Antarctica reached up to 70 degrees Fahrenheit above normal, the most extreme temperature variation ever recorded in the continent.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jeod7c18_antarctica-turning-green_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study found that Antarctica's green cover has grown dramatically.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-to-travel-to-pak-last-foreign-minister-visit-was-in-2015-6715527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar To Travel To Pak, Last Foreign Minister Visit Was In 2015]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-to-travel-to-pak-last-foreign-minister-visit-was-in-2015-6715527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:16:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Friday announced that External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar will travel to Pakistan to attend a conclave of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) in mid-October.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Friday announced that External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar will travel to Pakistan to attend a conclave of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) in mid-October.</p>

<p>The announcement was made by external affairs ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal.</p>

<p>The last Indian external affairs minister to visit Pakistan was Sushma Swaraj. She had travelled to Islamabad in December 2015 to attend a conference on Afghanistan.</p>

<p>Pakistan is hosting the SCO Council of Heads of Government (CHG) meeting on October 15 and 16.</p>

<p>"The external affairs minister will lead our delegation to Pakistan to participate in the SCO summit which will be held in Islamabad on October 15 and 16," Mr Jaiswal said at his weekly media briefing.</p>

<p>The spokesperson clarified that the external affairs minister is travelling to Pakistan only to attend the SCO summit.</p>

<p>In August, Pakistan invited Prime Minister Narendra Modi to the SCO's summit.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar's visit to Pakistan assumes significance as it is seen as a major decision on New Delhi's part.</p>

<p>The decision to send the senior minister is seen as a display of India's commitment to the SCO which has been playing a key role in boosting regional security cooperation.</p>

<p>The ties between India and Pakistan came under severe strain after India's warplanes pounded a Jaish-e-Mohammed terrorist training camp in Balakot in Pakistan in February 2019 in response to the Pulwama terror attack.</p>

<p>The relations further deteriorated after India on August 5, 2019 announced the withdrawal of special powers of Jammu and Kashmir and the bifurcation of the state into two union territories.</p>

<p>India has been maintaining that it desires normal neighbourly relations with Pakistan while insisting that the onus is on Islamabad to create an environment free of terror and hostility for such engagement.</p>

<p>The SCO council of heads of government conclave is the second-highest platform in the grouping.</p>

<p>The SCO heads of state summit is the top most forum in the grouping that is generally attended by the Indian prime minister.</p>

<p>The SCO, comprising India, China, Russia, Pakistan, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan, is an influential economic and security bloc that has emerged as one of the largest transregional international organisations.</p>

<p>India was the chair of the SCO last year. It hosted the SCO summit in the virtual format in July last year.</p>

<p>India's association with the SCO began in 2005 as an observer country. It became a full member state of SCO at the Astana summit in 2017.</p>

<p>India has shown a keen interest in deepening its security-related cooperation with the SCO and its Regional Anti-Terrorism Structure (RATS), which specifically deals with issues relating to security and defence.</p>

<p>The SCO was founded at a summit in Shanghai in 2001 by the presidents of Russia, China, the Kyrgyz Republic, Kazakhstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan.</p>

<p>Pakistan became its permanent member along with India in 2017.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jvjnd69o_dr-s-jaishankar_625x300_17_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar will lead the Indian delegation to Pakistan. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-allies-in-the-region-would-keep-fighting-israel-irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-6715520]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Our Allies In The Region Would Keep Fighting Israel: Iran's Supreme Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-allies-in-the-region-would-keep-fighting-israel-irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-6715520]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:14:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader vowed in a rare address on Friday that his allies around the region would keep fighting Israel, as he defended his country's missile strike on its arch-foe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's supreme leader vowed in a rare address on Friday that his allies around the region would keep fighting Israel, as he defended his country's missile strike on its arch-foe.</p>

<p>Ayatollah Ali Khamenei's address in Tehran was the first since Iran launched its second-ever attack on Israel, and also the first since exchanges of fire pitting Hezbollah fighters against Israeli troops escalated into full-blown war in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Nearly a year after the Palestinian militant group Hamas launched the deadliest attack on Israel in its history on October 7, Israel announced it was shifting its focus to securing its border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel says its objective is to allow 60,000 Israelis displaced by a year of cross-border rocket attacks launched by Hezbollah to return to their homes.</p>

<p>Israel's attacks on Hezbollah strongholds around Lebanon have killed more than 1,000 people since September 23, according to the Lebanese health ministry, and forced hundreds of thousands more to flee their homes in a country already mired in economic crisis.</p>

<p>They have also killed an Iranian general, a host of Hezbollah commanders and, in their biggest blow to the group in decades, assassinated its leader, Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>Speaking to a crowd of thousands in Farsi-speaking Iran, he said in Arabic: "The resistance in the region will not back down with these martyrdoms, and will win."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The address comes as Israel weighs retaliation for Hezbollah backer Iran's missile attack which Tehran said was revenge for the killing of Nasrallah and other top figures.</p>

<p>Khamenei praised Hezbollah, saying that it was providing "a vital service to the entire region and the entire Islamic world".</p>

<p>The escalation has left people in Lebanon fearful that there will be no swift end to the violence engulfing their country.</p>

<p>In Beirut, 35-year-old displaced nurse Fatima Salah said people were "scared for our children, and this war is going to be long".</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant warned that "those who attack the state of Israel, pay a heavy price".</p>

<p>Iran said it would step up its response if Israel counterattacked.</p>

<p>Israel intercepted most of the 200 missiles launched by Iran, though the attack has sparked fear in Israel of more violence to come. In the West Bank, a Palestinian was killed by shrapnel.</p>

<p>Rony Eli-Ya, 37, an Israeli on a pilgrimage to Ukraine's Uman, said it was "a miracle, not a single rocket killed a single Jew" in the attack.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden said the United States was "discussing" possible Israeli strikes on Iranian oil facilities.</p>

<p><strong>- Border crossing closed -</strong></p>

<p>Lebanon said an Israeli strike on Friday cut off the main international road to Syria after Israel said Hezbollah was transporting weapons through the tiny Mediterranean country's principal land border crossing.</p>

<p>The strike comes after 310,000 people, mostly Syrians, have in recent days fled the war pitting Israel against Hezbollah in Lebanon for relative safety in neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its fighter jets struck Hezbollah targets near the border crossing overnight.</p>

<p>It said they included a 3.5 kilometre (two-mile) long tunnel that "enables the transfer and storage of large quantities of weapons underground".</p>

<p>The border with Syria is the only land route out of Lebanon and the strike could leave thousands who are unable to fly out trapped.</p>

<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi meanwhile landed in Beirut for talks with Lebanese officials, Lebanon's official National News Agency reported.</p>

<p>He arrived after an intense night of bombardment of Hezbollah's main bastion in the southern suburbs, with the US and an Israeli news website saying Israel targeted the militant group's potential successor just a week after it killed its Nasrallah.</p>

<p>The strikes destroyed at least five buildings and left a huge crater in the road, an AFP photographer said.</p>

<p>A target of one of Israel's recent Beirut strikes was Hashem Safieddine, a potential successor to Hezbollah chief Nasrallah, US news site Axios said, citing three Israeli officials it did not identify.</p>

<p>Israeli news website Ynet also reported Safieddine had been the target, while the Israeli military told AFP it was looking into the reports.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, a source close to Hezbollah said Nasrallah had been given a temporary burial in a secret location until a public funeral could be held.</p>

<p>Israel announced this week that its troops had started ground raids into parts of southern Lebanon, a stronghold of Hezbollah, after days of heavy bombardment of areas across the country where the group holds sway.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it shelled Israeli troops in a border area of south Lebanon Friday, in the latest such clash on the frontier.</p>

<p>The militant group also said it kept up its rocket fire, with sirens warning of incoming fire blaring in northern Israel Friday.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said that 37 people were killed and 151 wounded by Israeli strikes over the previous 24 hours.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said nine of its soldiers have been killed in combat in Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>- Tulkarem strike -</strong></p>

<p>In the occupied West Bank, a source within the Palestinian security services told AFP that an air raid on the refugee camp of Tulkarem, which killed 18 people, was the deadliest in the territory since 2000.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its strike in the northern West Bank killed Hamas leader Zahi Yaser Abd al-Razeq Oufi, who it accused of participating in numerous attacks.</p>

<p>Calls for restraint have multiplied but months of similar calls to halt fighting in Gaza failed to bring a ceasefire.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 41,788 people, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The United Nations has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3h1k4qe_iran-supreme-leader_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran said it would step up its response if Israel counterattacked.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>