<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:37:35 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-police-use-hologram-to-solve-2009-amsterdam-sex-workers-murder-6992272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dutch Police Use Hologram To Solve 2009 Amsterdam Sex Worker's Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-police-use-hologram-to-solve-2009-amsterdam-sex-workers-murder-6992272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:31:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Netherlands Police are using an innovative life-size hologram of a sex worker, killed in Amsterdam in February 2009, to uncover new information about the cold case and bring her killer or killers to justice.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands Police are using an innovative life-size hologram of a sex worker, killed in Amsterdam in February 2009, to uncover new information about the cold case and bring her killer or killers to justice. The hologram has been placed behind a window in Amsterdam's Red Light district. Sitting on a stool, it looks at people passing by and appears to knock on the window. The glass fogs up, while the word “help” appears on it, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/10/europe/dutch-police-hologram-sex-worker-cold-case-intl/index.html">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>The hologram is modelled on Bernadett Szabó, known as Betty, who was found murdered in the Dutch capital in 2009.&nbsp;Created using 3D visualisation technology, it also features a large dragon tattoo covering Betty's stomach and chest.</p>

<p>A house in the area has been dedicated entirely to Betty's murder, with large stickers on the windows and TV screens showing the crime scene, a documentary and images of the woman.</p>

<p>This holographic has been created to reach out to people, who may have knowledge about the murder case but did not come forward at the time of the incident.</p>

<p>In the official statement, Benjamin van Gogh, coordinator of the Amsterdam Wanted and Missing Persons Team, noted that it was "difficult to determine what it takes to get possible witnesses, in this case, to share their information with us”.</p>

<p>“Betty's hologram may create a certain connection with her and thus convince a person to come forward. In this type of case, we always try to put a face on a victim, so that informants know who they're doing it for, and the hologram is a way of taking this a step further," CNN quoted the official as saying.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Dutch police said that Szabó was born and brought up in poverty in the Hungarian city of Nyíregyháza, before shifting to Amsterdam at the age of 18. After landing in the city, she began earning money as a sex worker in the red light district. After becoming pregnant, she continued to work throughout her pregnancy and later gave birth to a son in November 2008. The child was later placed with a foster family.</p>

<p>Betty was found dead on the night of February 19, 2009, when two of her fellow sex workers reached her workroom on Oudezijds Achterburgwal. They realised they didn't see her or hear the music she usually played. At around 1 AM, they found her body stabbed dozens of times. She was 19,<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/10/dutch-police-use-hologram-to-try-to-solve-2009-sex-worker-killing"> The Guardian </a>reported.</p>

<p>For the past 15 years, police carried out a large-scale investigation into the case, monitoring CCTVs and interviewing witnesses. The case remained unsolved.</p>

<p>The reward for any information related to the case has been hiked to €30,000 (around $32,160).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/scq145k8_amsterdam-sex-workers-murder_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The hologram has been placed behind a window in Amsterdam's Red Light district.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sabae-this-small-city-is-the-eyeglasses-capital-of-japan-why-you-must-visit-6992093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Small City Is The 'Eyeglasses Capital' Of Japan: Why You Must Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sabae-this-small-city-is-the-eyeglasses-capital-of-japan-why-you-must-visit-6992093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:30:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sabae, a small city in Japan's Fukui Prefecture, has earned the title eyeglasses capital' for producing over 90% of the nation's frames.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sabae, a small city in Japan's Fukui Prefecture, has earned the title ‘eyeglasses capital' for producing over 90% of the nation's frames. Sabae offers visitors an opportunity to explore the craft behind its spectacles.</p>

<p>The city's journey into the eyeglass industry began in 1905 when a local government official invited skilled artisans to the city to create new economic opportunities for farmers. This initiative has since flourished, and today, the city is home to over 100 companies specialising in eyeglass production, according to a report on <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/sabae-eyeglasses-capital-of-japan-fukui-hnk-intl/index.htm">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>The process combines cutting-edge technology with the expertise of skilled artisans. That it is still largely manual sets the city apart from so many other parts of the world known for its expertise in the industry. Takeshi Yamae, a frame designer for the Japanese company Boston Club, says a single pair of glasses may need more than 200 steps. “From the time I start designing, to the time I have the perfect product, it takes more than a year. I start by thinking about who I want to wear it. I often get inspiration from very Japanese things, for example, houses, gardens and tableware,” Yamae says.</p>

<p><strong>Why visit Sabae?</strong></p>

<p>Though frames created by Sabae are found across Japan, there's something unique about the city and seeing the process firsthand. Some artisans who work on the frame production process focus exclusively on one expertise throughout their careers, including machine cutting, polishing or nose pad attachment.</p>

<p>“Everyone in factories in Sabae wants to make beautiful, high-quality products that can be used around the world,” Yamae adds.</p>

<p>The Megane Museum in Sabae offers visitors an in-depth look at the craft, with displays illustrating the numerous stages of frame creation. The museum also hosts workshops where tourists can design and create their frames — an ideal souvenir. For those short on time, the museum shop offers thousands of frames from around 50 local manufacturers.</p>

<p>Apart from this, visitors can also explore the city's eyewear-themed street signs, exhibits, and events, further cementing Sabae's reputation as the eyeglasses capital.</p>

<p>Recent upgrades to transportation have made it simpler than ever to visit Sabae. A new bullet train extension, launched in 2024, connects the Hokuriku region with Tokyo, making Sabae and Fukui province more accessible to international tourists. The extension includes a stop at Fukui Station, where visitors can easily reach Sabae.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ga3fabao_sabae-japan_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sabae's journey into the eyeglass industry began in 1905.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-or-canada-which-way-will-trump-look-6992629]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India Or Canada: Which Way Will Trump Look?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-or-canada-which-way-will-trump-look-6992629]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:29:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With Trump's return to the Oval Office just weeks away, some in India are already hoping that he will put New Delhis new adversary, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, in his place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7lgvhhno_trump_625x300_11_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It's no surprise that many Indians—including some former diplomats—are celebrating Donald Trump's reelection. After all, Trump's bond with India, and particularly with Prime Minister Narendra Modi, was the envy of many countries and leaders during his first term. Granted, some might say they were mere optics: remember appearances at rallies like “Howdy, Modi!” and “Namaste, Trump!” in Houston and Ahmedabad?</p>

<p>With Trump's return to the Oval Office just weeks away, some in India are already hoping that he will put New Delhi's new adversary, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, in his place. After all, Trump's past comments on Trudeau range from “weak” to “two-faced", to even “far-left lunatic”—hardly a subtle hint of his opinion of his neighbouring country's leader.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Canadians Are Worried</strong></h2>

<p>For Canadians, though, Trump's second term has sparked more shock than celebration. Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland (also the country's finance minister) held two press conferences post his election to calm Canadian nerves, saying Canada will be “absolutely fine”. Yet, many Canadians remain uneasy over Trump's return to the White House, and for good reason. There are three big areas of anxiety: tariffs, NATO contributions and the looming renegotiation of the US-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA).</p>

<p>First, Trump has hinted at slapping a blanket 10% tariff on all imports to the US, which would hit Canada hard given that more than two-thirds of its exports are US-bound. Then there is Trump's expectation that NATO members chip in a full 2% of their GDP on defence. Canada is currently far behind and contributing only 1.23%—a potential sticking point if Trump insists on the required contributions like he did during the last term. Lastly, there's the USMCA, which Trump himself strong-armed Canada and Mexico into renegotiating in 2020. Trump has hinted that the deal is set for review in 2026. Canadians worry that the President-elect could push for even stricter terms this time around.</p>

<h2><strong>Will Trump Side With India?</strong></h2>

<p>Biden's team and its Western European pals are clearly frustrated with India's refusal to oppose Russia over the Ukraine war. They have not said it out loud, but it's hard not to suspect that they are quietly backing Trudeau behind the scenes in his finger-pointing at India, accusing officials of involvement in the killing of Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar. Let's be real—it wasn't without Big Brother's nod that Trudeau stood in Parliament last year hurling accusations at India. Furthermore, if Canada decides to move forward with these allegations, the possibility is it won't be acting alone. The US and the UK, key members of the Five Eyes alliance, have often helped manage diplomatic and security issues with countries outside the alliance. Since both countries have close ties with India, they may help Canada weigh the strength and possible impact of these accusations before taking any official steps. Still, accusing a powerful country like India could affect important strategic interests.</p>

<p>Moreover, the possible egging on by Big Brother suits Trudeau too, giving him a shot at placating his Sikh voter base and propping up his waning popularity. However, only a rookie diplomat, I would say, can fully trust the self-serving strategy that the US usually follows.</p>

<p>We cannot underplay US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller's blunt statement last month: “When it comes to the Canadian matter, we have made clear that the allegations are extremely serious and they need to be taken seriously. We wanted to see the government of India cooperate with Canada in its investigation. Obviously, they have not chosen that path.” &nbsp;The statement did not reflect India's position that there was complete disregard for New Delhi's request to Ottawa to share evidence. And now, with allegations of India's involvement in an attempted assassination, the Biden administration has another card to play. Nonetheless, India is cooperating with the US on the investigation and neither side wants to blow it out of proportion.</p>

<p>Now, as Trump re-enters his office, his promise to end the war in Ukraine, if fulfilled, will be a game-changer. Without Ukraine in the equation, the US pressure on India to pick a side goes out of the window, and Biden's “cold-shoulder” tactics would become a non-issue. Trump, however, we all know, is a wildcard. While he may want closer ties with India, we know how that “America First” agenda translates: tariffs, immigration restrictions and a hard line on H-1B visas. Fortunately though, Trump's stance on Russia (to end the war) aligns with India's, as does his anti-China focus. It's quite possible he might ask Trudeau to either produce proof in the Nijjar case or drop the offensive. Who knows.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>But Don't Underestimate US-Canada Bond</strong></h2>

<p>Even so, we should never underestimate America's deep-rooted ties with Canada—they are in a league of their own. Sure, Trump and Trudeau have clashed publicly, but Trudeau is not one to be caught off guard. On Thursday, he revealed that his officials had been quietly talking to Trump's campaign team for months, readying for a potential return. Trudeau didn't waste a minute—he reinstated a Cabinet committee on US-Canada relations, led by Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland, to deal with anything Trump 2.0 might throw at them. And he was among the first to call Trump after the win, showing that when it comes to the US, Trudeau is all about pragmatism, or, dare I say, even subservience. His office spelt it out well: “Following the election of President Donald Trump for a second term, the Cabinet Committee will focus on critical Canada-US issues.”</p>

<p>The US-Canada relationship is unlike anything else in the world. The two countries are more like siblings rather than neighbours, no matter who sits in the Oval Office. They are two very prosperous countries: Canada's per capita income is over $58,000, while America's is $81,000. They have got each other's backs on defence, border security, and law enforcement. The overlap is everywhere—from culture and sports to leisure and shared traditions. They have much more in common between them than either of them has with India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Consider this: in 2023, the US-Canada trade hit over a trillion dollars, with $2.8 billion crossing their border every single day. They are each other's biggest trade partners, with Canada sending 78% of its goods and services to the US every year, and over 400,000 people moving across their shared 5,525-mile border daily.</p>

<h2><strong>Canada Has Five Eyes By Its Side&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Let's keep in mind that Canada is a NATO member and the countries in the grouping are quite united and usually back each other against any third party. Then there is the intelligence-sharing bond under the Five Eyes institution. The Five Eyes alliance—a formidable network comprising the US, the UK, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand—has been at the forefront of global intelligence operations for decades. The alliance was built to facilitate intelligence collection and sharing among its members, ensuring a near-seamless flow of critical security information. In light of Canada's recent allegations against Indian officials, the alliance ought to have played a crucial role in sharing information with Canadian intelligence officials.</p>

<p>Also, as a core member of the Five Eyes, Canada has access to intelligence and insights that most nations can only aspire to attain. If Canada believes it has intelligence linking Indian officials to Nijjar's assassination, it is likely benefiting from the information-sharing protocols within the Five Eyes network. Notably, Canada may be leveraging Five Eyes capabilities to cross-reference signals intelligence (SIGINT) and other classified insights, allowing them to build a stronger case against India, should any concrete evidence exist.</p>

<h2><strong>Let Canada's Voters Decide</strong></h2>

<p>Anyway, India might just have to play the waiting game until Canada's next general election, now less than a year away. Trudeau's grip on power since he took office in 2015 is looking shakier than ever today. If he is out of the picture, the new government's stance on India could breathe fresh life into those frosty bilateral ties.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/58f320r_trump-canda_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baltasar-engonga-the-equatorial-guinea-official-involved-in-massive-sex-tapes-row-6992158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Baltasar Engonga: The Equatorial Guinea Official Involved In Sex Tapes Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baltasar-engonga-the-equatorial-guinea-official-involved-in-massive-sex-tapes-row-6992158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:28:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of videos showing Baltasar Ebang Engonga having sex with different women have gone viral.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Baltasar Ebang Engonga, a high-ranking Equatorial Guinea official, has been fired after hundreds of videos showing him having sex with women went viral on social media.</p>

<p>In the videos, Engonga, who is married and is said to be in his 50s, is seen with different partners &nbsp;-- including the wives of prominent officials -- at his office in the finance ministry and other places.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to reports, around 400 of his sex tapes - which were filmed on unknown dates - have been leaked.</p>

<p>Authorities have warned the telecommunications ministry, regulator and telephone companies "to curb the distribution of pornographic videos that are flooding social networks".</p>

<p>#BaltasarEbangEngonga has been trending as one of the most discussed themes online.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Baltasar Ebang Engonga</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/equatorial-guinea-civil-servant-baltasar-ebang-engonga-under-scanner-over-hundreds-of-sex-tapes-6949028">Baltasar Ebang Engonga</a> is the director of the National Financial Investigation Agency (ANIF). He is nicknamed "Bello" because of his good looks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Engonga is the son of Baltasar Engonga Edjo, the current Chairman of the Commission of the Central African Economic and Monetary Community. He is also related to the country's long-serving president.</p>

<p>Tasked to tackle crimes such as money laundering, he himself was arrested on October 25 for embezzling a huge sum of money from state coffers and depositing it in secret accounts in the Cayman Islands.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was taken to the infamous Black Beach prison in the capital, Malabo.</p>

<p>His phones and computers were seized, and a few days later, his sex clips went viral online.</p>

<p>Chief prosecutor Anatolio Nzang Nguema has said that if medical exams revealed that Engonga was "infected with a sexually transmitted disease", he would be prosecuted for an offence against "public health".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3jst2ug8_baltasar-ebang-engonga_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Baltasar Ebang Engonga is the director of the National Financial Investigation Agency]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kai-trump-plays-golf-with-grandpa-donald-trump-bonus-elon-musk-6991962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kai Trump Plays Golf With Grandpa Donald Trump. Bonus: Elon Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kai-trump-plays-golf-with-grandpa-donald-trump-bonus-elon-musk-6991962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:16:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump spent his Sunday afternoon on the golf course with two granddaughters, Kai and Chloe Trump, days after securing a historic win against Democrat rival Kamala Harris in US Election 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump spent his Sunday afternoon on the golf course with two granddaughters, Kai and Chloe Trump, days after securing a historic win against Democrat rival Kamala Harris in US Election 2024.</p>

<p>Kai shared photographs and videos from the family outing on X and Instagram. Her post also featured Tesla CEO Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Sharing an image with her grandfather, she wrote, "Sundays with Grandpa," accompanied by a yellow heart emoji.</p>

<p>In another photograph, Kai, 17, and her sister Chloe, 10, posed with their grandfather.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sundays with Grandpa ???? <a href="https://t.co/UfKdu0RJI7">pic.twitter.com/UfKdu0RJI7</a></p>
— Kai Trump (@KaiTrumpGolfs) <a href="https://twitter.com/KaiTrumpGolfs/status/1855728246253580514?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The family was at the Trump International Golf Club West Palm Beach, a few miles west of the Mar-a-Lago resort, Fox News reported.</p>

<p>Donald Trump, 78, was seen in a white polo t-shirt with his campaign slogan, “Make America Great Again”. He also wore a white hat with the same phrase. His granddaughters wore golf skirts and white sneakers for their session.</p>

<p>Along with the two photographs, Kai also shared a few videos of her golfing skills.</p>

<p>In another post on X, Kai posed with Musk and his 4-year-old son, X Æ A-12.</p>

<p>"Elon achieving uncle status," she captioned the image along with a laughing emoji.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Elon achieving uncle status ???? <a href="https://t.co/vufSffziZN">pic.twitter.com/vufSffziZN</a></p>
— Kai Trump (@KaiTrumpGolfs) <a href="https://twitter.com/KaiTrumpGolfs/status/1855734110062272874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
Musk's son, whom the richest person in the world shared with his ex Grimes, can be seen holding a golf ball over his eye in the image.</p>

<p>Earlier, Kai Trump shared a family photograph of Donald Trump, his five children, five grandchildren as well as Elon Musk. However, Melania Trump was nowhere to be seen in the image.</p>

<p>"The whole squad," read the caption.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The whole squad <a href="https://t.co/5yQVkFiney">pic.twitter.com/5yQVkFiney</a></p>
— Kai Trump (@KaiTrumpGolfs) <a href="https://twitter.com/KaiTrumpGolfs/status/1854274706448199849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Musk is believed to have spent a whopping $119 million to mobilise support for Trump during his presidential bid in 2024. He even actively campaigned for Trump in swing states.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d2e8e4io_kai-trump-donald-trump-twitter_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kai Trump Sharing an image with her grandfather, Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/system-glitch-leads-to-vpn-disruption-across-pakistan-6991859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["System Glitch" Leads To VPN Disruption Across Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/system-glitch-leads-to-vpn-disruption-across-pakistan-6991859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:16:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Internet users across Pakistan faced disruptions in accessing virtual private networks (VPNs) over the weekend, impacting both fixed broadband and mobile data connections, Dawn reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Internet users across Pakistan faced disruptions in accessing virtual private networks (VPNs) over the weekend, impacting both fixed broadband and mobile data connections, Dawn reported.</p>

<p>The report stated citing industry sources, that an "issue with the system" temporarily affected VPN connectivity. However, the Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA) has yet to comment on the matter, with its spokesperson not responding to inquiries on Sunday.</p>

<p>Since the government banned the social media platform X in February, VPN use has grown among users who rely on it to bypass local restrictions. Earlier this year, prolonged internet disruptions also led many to use proxy networks.</p>

<p>Over the weekend, unconfirmed social media reports suggested that the PTA might have banned certain VPNs; however, authorities attributed the disruption to a "brief" glitch in the system rather than any official restriction.</p>

<p>"We have been told by officials that access to VPNs was briefly disrupted for 30 minutes to an hour due to a glitch in the system," an industry insider told Dawn, emphasising that the disruption was short-lived.</p>

<p>Downdetector, a platform that monitors internet disruptions, confirmed complaints from users of VPN Unlimited, with reports peaking at 6:15 pm, and Tunnelbear users logging issues as late as 7:29 pm, reported Dawn.</p>

<p>Enterprises with registered VPNs also experienced connectivity issues, according to two industry sources. PTA has previously asked businesses, including software houses, call centres, freelancers, and foreign missions, to register their VPNs and IP addresses with the authority to maintain "uninterrupted" service during any network disruption.</p>

<p>In a statement issued in September amid complaints of slow internet speeds, PTA emphasised its commitment to supporting the tech industry, noting that "IP addresses for VPNs are being registered for software houses, business and IT companies."</p>

<p>Since 2020, more than 20,000 VPNs and IP addresses have reportedly been registered, according to Dawn.</p>

<p>Digital rights advocate Farieha Aziz criticised the lack of transparency surrounding the interruptions, stating, "It's completely arbitrary, disrupting everyday life and work and no one in the PTA and government has yet given a straight answer."</p>

<p>Another activist, Usama Khilji, expressed concerns that such disruptions align with "the state's plans to clamp down on VPNs" and warned that these actions could adversely affect sectors reliant on VPNs, particularly in finance and tech.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6s4542g8_computer-generic_625x300_02_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[VPN use has grown among users who rely on it to bypass local restrictions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arab-leaders-meet-in-saudi-arabia-likely-to-discuss-donald-trumps-win-6992006]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Arab Leaders Meet In Saudi Arabia, Likely To Discuss Donald Trump's Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arab-leaders-meet-in-saudi-arabia-likely-to-discuss-donald-trumps-win-6992006]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:06:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Arab and Muslim leaders gather in Saudi Arabia Monday for a summit addressing the wars in Gaza and Lebanon, a chance to send a message to US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Arab and Muslim leaders gather in Saudi Arabia Monday for a summit addressing the wars in Gaza and Lebanon, a chance to send a message to US President-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The Saudi foreign ministry announced plans for the summit in late October during a meeting, also in Riyadh, of a new "international alliance" to press for the establishment of a Palestinian state.</p>

<p>It comes one year after a similar gathering in Riyadh of the Cairo-based Arab League and the Jeddah-based Organisation of Islamic Cooperation during which leaders condemned Israeli forces' actions in Gaza as "barbaric".</p>

<p>This time around, Trump's election last week for a second term in the White House is likely to be on leaders' minds, said Anna Jacobs, senior Gulf analyst for the International Crisis Group think tank.</p>

<p>"This summit is very much an opportunity for regional leaders to signal to the incoming Trump administration what they want in terms of US engagement," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The message will likely be one of dialogue, de-escalation and calling out Israeli military campaigns in the region."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The war in Gaza erupted with Hamas's unprecedented attack on southern Israel on October 7 last year, which resulted in 1,206 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed more than 43,600 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to data from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry that the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>Lebanon-based Hezbollah, which like Hamas is backed by Iran, began firing on Israel after the October 7 attack. The regular cross-border exchanges escalated in late September when Israel intensified its air strikes and sent ground troops into southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Despite criticism of the impact Israel's military campaign has had on Gaza civilians, outgoing US President Joe Biden ensured that Washington remained Israel's most important military backer during more than a year of fighting.</p>

<h3><strong>'Rely on the Saudis'</strong></h3>

<p>In his first term, Trump's actions showed him as an even firmer supporter of Israel. He defied international consensus by recognising Jerusalem as Israel's capital and moving Washington's embassy there.</p>

<p>He also endorsed Israeli settlements in the occupied West Bank, which are illegal under international law.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Under the Abraham Accords, Trump oversaw the establishment of diplomatic relations between Israel, the United Arab Emirates and Bahrain, as well as Morocco.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though Saudi Arabia did not join those agreements, Trump cultivated warm ties with the Gulf kingdom while in office and has deepened his business connections to the region during the Biden years.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia has pressed pause on a US-brokered deal where it would recognise Israel in return for security and economic benefits, insisting there will be no diplomatic ties without a Palestinian state.</p>

<p>Umer Karim, an expert on Saudi politics at the University of Birmingham, said Riyadh will use Monday's summit to signal to the incoming Trump team that it remains a strong partner.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The message is that Trump "can rely on the Saudis as being representatives of the Muslim world", and that "if you want to extend American interests in the region, Saudi Arabia is your bet", he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 57-member OIC and 22-member Arab League include countries which recognise Israel and those firmly opposed to its regional integration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last year's summit in Riyadh saw disagreement on measures like severing economic and diplomatic ties with Israel and disrupting its oil supplies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Karim said the post-summit statement on Monday will likely "strongly condemn Israel...while also pushing for greater American leverage and diplomacy on the issue."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The November 2023 meeting featured an appearance by Iran's then-president Ebrahim Raisi, highlighting how regional diplomacy has changed since Trump was last in office.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March 2023, Iran and Saudi Arabia announced a China-brokered rapprochement after seven years of severed ties. The Middle East heavyweights have maintained regular high-level contact as part of efforts to contain the ongoing conflicts.</p>

<p>Iranian state media said the chief of staff of the Saudi armed forces was to arrive in Tehran Sunday for talks, a rare high-level visit.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdrhbtag_arab-leaders_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/musk-to-ackman-the-growing-opposition-to-inclusive-hiring-6991985]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Musk To Ackman, Why Are Companies Opposing 'Inclusive' Hiring?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/musk-to-ackman-the-growing-opposition-to-inclusive-hiring-6991985]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:00:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The whole concept of DEI  which encompasses women, people of colour, and those in the LGBTQ+ community  has come under attack in the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qjip1lco_hiring_625x300_11_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On November 1, US aircraft manufacturer Boeing made the controversial decision to dismantle its DEI (Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion) department. The company's former Vice President of Global DEI, Sara Bowen, announced her resignation on the social media platform LinkedIn.</p>

<p>Boeing has faced significant criticism for its quality and safety practices following two incidents in January this year. In the first, the door plug of a Boeing 737 Max blew off mid-flight, leaving a large hole in the side of an Alaska Airlines plane. In the same month, another Boeing aircraft had its nose wheel fall off just before a Delta flight took off.</p>

<p>Since then, the company has been explicitly targeted on social media by billionaire Elon Musk and other traditional critics, who suggest that some of Boeing's quality issues stem from its decision to include diversity targets in its 2022 bonus plan. After facing these criticisms, Boeing revised its incentive plan to focus more on quality and safety earlier this year.</p>

<p>The whole concept of DEI — which encompasses women, people of colour, and those in the LGBTQ+ community — has come under attack in the US. Detractors argue openly that DEI employees lack the qualifications, skills, or intelligence to contribute to society through jobs, education, or leadership.</p>

<p>One must also consider whether the anti-DEI sentiment has had any impact in India.</p>

<h2><strong>Resentment In US</strong></h2>

<p>Following the Alaska Airlines incident, Elon Musk posted on X: "Do you want to fly in an airplane where they prioritised DEI hiring over your safety? That is actually happening." He added later: "People will die due to DEI."</p>

<p>Reports indicate that investigations into the incidents pointed to other factors, including a lack of quality control, outdated technology, and financial irregularities. However, these findings did not satisfy DEI critics, who celebrated Boeing's November 1 announcement of dismantling its DEI department.</p>

<p>Although the step may seem exaggerated, there is a growing anti-DEI movement in the US. Another American billionaire, Bill Ackman, wrote on X that DEI policies were "inherently racist" and "illegal", despite claims that they work "on behalf of the oppressed". Musk endorsed these views, even as his company Tesla reportedly removed all outreach programmes for minority communities from its annual filing.</p>

<p>This pushback against DEI programmes has led companies like Toyota, Ford, and others to re-evaluate or even close down their DEI departments. Experts attribute this backlash to social tension, largely coming from ‘white Americans' who feel disadvantaged in the job market.</p>

<h2><strong>The Indian Scenario</strong></h2>

<p>In India, DEI was an alien concept until multinational companies (MNCs) introduced it, mostly due to mandates from their foreign parent companies. Since then, the IT and services sectors have implemented formal DEI policies.</p>

<p>In India, DEI initiatives tend to focus on the inclusion of women, queer people, and, to some extent, those with physical disabilities. Given that the policy is largely US-inspired, are Indian companies facing similar challenges?</p>

<p>DEI expert Saundarya Rajesh, founder-president of the Avtar Group, states: “It is unfortunate that some global organisations are choosing to dismantle DEI. However, this is not a phenomenon that has severe local implications in India Inc.”</p>

<p>“Corporate India continues to recognise that inclusion is an integral part of organisational culture and a non-negotiable employee experience that needs to be delivered.” Indian subsidiaries of MNCs and some prominent Indian conglomerates have set diversity hiring as a goal. This is often driven by investor pressure or requirements from global partners, and the easiest way to meet these demands is by reserving roles for women in HR, ESG, finance, digital, communications, and other areas, as talent in these functions is readily available in the local job market.</p>

<p>However, roles in infrastructure and other front-facing sectors rarely see diversity hiring, as companies do not specifically reserve positions for women in these areas. Though diversity in such roles is often selected on merit, some companies aim to prioritise diversity in hiring, which can inadvertently exclude male candidates. This leads to discontent among those who feel overlooked.</p>

<p>“Positive discrimination must always ensure that merit is never compromised. If we can uphold this principle, much of the political hijacking associated with DEI can be addressed. You may still select a DEI nominee, but only if they are on par with the rest. Not one bit less,” says Prabir Jha, founder &amp; CEO of Prabir Jha People Advisory.</p>

<h2><strong>Loss of Talent?</strong></h2>

<p>DEI policies were originally designed to foster inclusivity by ensuring diverse representation in workplaces. However, their implementation has raised concerns about compromising meritocracy, as seen in the US. This has led to the loss of potential talent and opportunity costs.</p>

<p>"Focusing on DEI does not necessitate a compromise on meritocracy. What it requires is an inclusive and equitable strategy, where decisions around hiring and advancement are diversity-sensitive, delivering on the vision of equal opportunities for all,” says Saundarya Rajesh.</p>

<p>In the West, DEI is meant to give a voice to the voiceless. It is also intended to ensure that the views of the most junior employee are heard in meetings.</p>

<p>In India, however, diversity is often viewed narrowly through the lens of ‘female hiring', which means there is a significant opportunity to broaden the focus to policies that promote a truly inclusive workplace. Experts suggest that certain areas remain sacrosanct, where positive discrimination should have no place. Merit should always be the sole criterion for selection, as the impact of an incorrect decision, whether by omission or commission, could have far-reaching consequences.</p>

<p>“Never give away board positions, management roles, promotions, and hire ‘only diversity candidates'. This does more harm to the cause than good. Inclusion must always feel inclusive. If you remain true to the principles of meritocracy, you will eliminate any bias against diversity,” says Jha.</p>

<p>Americans have displayed their resistance to this form of affirmative action, as evidenced by the rejection of Kamala Harris, a Black and South Asian woman, who critics labelled a "DEI hire". Let's hope that India's approach to DEI avoids the pitfalls of unconscious bias.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i371ppl8_hiring_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cheese-heists-on-the-rise-how-organised-crime-is-exploiting-dairy-industry-6991793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cheese Heists On The Rise: How Organised Crime Is Exploiting Dairy Industry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cheese-heists-on-the-rise-how-organised-crime-is-exploiting-dairy-industry-6991793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:51:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A daring heist in the UK in October put the spotlight on the profitable but risky world of luxury cheese.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A daring heist in the UK in October put the spotlight on the profitable but risky world of luxury cheese. The incident, dubbed “the grate cheese robbery,” saw 22 tonnes of premium British cheese disappear after a fraudulent order was placed under the guise of a French supermarket chain. The stolen consignment, valued at over £300,000 (around Rs 3.26 crore), comprised specialty cheese from farms in Somerset, including Hafod, a rare cheddar aged for 18 months.</p>

<p>Patrick Holden, the dairy farmer behind Hafod, was initially thrilled by what he believed to be the largest order his farm had ever received. “It was the biggest order for our cheese we've ever received,” Holden told <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/crmz42pjpnjo">BBC</a>, adding, “And, because it was from France, I thought, ‘finally, people on the continent are appreciating what we do'.”</p>

<p>His excitement waned when the order turned out to be a scam, and the cheese disappeared after being collected by a courier. In late October, a 63-year-old man was arrested in London, he was later released on bail. Since then, there have been no updates, and the 950 truckles of cheese – around the weight of four full-size elephants – disappeared without a trace.</p>

<p>The stolen cheese, including £35,000 (around Rs 38.13 lakh) worth of Hafod, was processed through Neal's Yard Dairy, an upmarket London wholesaler. The heist shocked the cheese industry, which the criminals have targeted due to the rising value of luxury dairy products.</p>

<p>While the scale of the cheese theft was extraordinary, it is part of a broader rise in food-related crimes that cost the global food industry billions each year. Cheese, especially high-end varieties, has become an attractive target for organised criminals. From smuggling and counterfeiting to outright theft, food-related crimes have flourished, with some gangs specialising in stealing valuable products like Parmigiano Reggiano and cheddar.</p>

<p>“Cheesemaking is an energy-intensive business,” the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cje03dq2pyyo">BBC</a> quoted Patrick McGuigan, a dairy sector specialist, as saying. “There was a big price increase following the disruption caused by Russia's invasion of Ukraine,” added McGuigan. The economic impact of the war and ongoing inflation has made cheese increasingly expensive, driving demand among criminals seeking to profit from this lucrative market.</p>

<p>Notably, the price of cheese in the UK has increased of late, with some varieties seeing price hikes of up to 6.5% in just 2024. “Based on price alone, cheese is one of the most desirable foods a criminal can steal,” McGuigan said.</p>

<p>Luxury cheese theft is not only about high prices. Food holds additional appeal for criminal networks. Andy Quinn of the National Food Crime Unit (NFCU) said, “They (criminals) know crimes involving food result in less severe convictions than for importing drugs, but they can still make similar amounts of money.” It's especially true when it comes to premium cheese.</p>

<p>The black market for stolen cheese is global. In 2016, £80,000 worth of Parmigiano Reggiano was stolen in Italy.</p>

<p>“Cheese and wine are two of the most common products being transported illegally into Russia,” says Professor Chris Elliott, founder of the Global Institute for Food Security.</p>

<p>The Parmigiano Reggiano Consortium is tackling black market theft of its prized cheese by embedding tiny tracking chips in the rind. These chips, no bigger than a grain of rice, contain unique digital IDs to verify authenticity and detect stolen cheese. Buyers can scan the cheese to check its legitimacy, though the consortium has not yet released data on the impact of this technology on fraud.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/l19ui3mo_cheese-1200_625x300_24_January_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luxury cheese theft is not only about high prices.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-win-means-for-future-of-heat-pump-ev-incentives-6991884]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Donald Trump's Win Means For Future of Heat Pump, EV Incentives]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-win-means-for-future-of-heat-pump-ev-incentives-6991884]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:47:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has pledged to rescind funding for the Biden administration's signature 2022 climate law, which includes more than $8.5 billion in incentives for individuals and families to decarbonize their lives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you're thinking of buying an electric car or an energy-saving heat pump eligible for federal tax credits and rebates, now might be the time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President-Elect Donald Trump has labeled the US Inflation Reduction Act the "green new scam." He's pledged to rescind funding for the Biden administration's signature 2022 climate law, which includes more than $8.5 billion in incentives for individuals and families to decarbonize their lives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Clawing back funds already dispersed would be difficult, but that doesn't mean the Trump administration won't try," said Romany Webb, deputy director of the Sabin Center for Climate Change Law at Columbia University. "From a strictly legal perspective, there may be more avenues for the administration to withhold funds that haven't been awarded yet."</p>

<p>But "failing to move forward with announced awards may be politically unpopular," she added.</p>

<p>The IRA's benefits are manifold. The law offers up to $14,000 for low- and moderate-income households to install heat pumps, induction stoves and other high-efficiency electric appliances. Wealthier families can receive a $2,000 federal tax credit for replacing a fossil-fuel furnace or water heater with a heat pump. Some electric vehicles qualify for a $7,500 tax credit issued at the time of purchase, and a 30% tax credit is available for homeowners to install solar panels and battery storage systems.</p>

<p>US Representative Ro Khanna, a California Democrat, said on Thursday's Zero podcast that he doubts that the new Trump administration and Congressional Republicans will seek the wholesale repeal of the IRA, given the billions of dollars in benefits it funnels to their constituents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>IRA funding is distributed through the states through US Department of Energy-approved rebate programs. The federal government has paid out $1.4 billion to nine states and the District of Columbia that have begun to offer up to $8,000 for a heat pumps and $1,750 for a heat pump water heaters. They also provide $840 cash back for induction stoves and heat pump clothes dryers and $4,000 for electrical system upgrades.</p>

<p>Another 10 states have received $1.2 billion but have yet to start issuing rebates. Nine more states are awaiting federal review of their applications, which usually takes about 60 to 90 days. The rest of the states are still preparing their applications except for South Dakota, which isn't participating in the program. Florida initially declined $175 million in funding but now has submitted an application.</p>

<p>Short of repealing the IRA, though, taking those lucrative incentives away from taxpayers would prove legally difficult and politically problematic, according to David Friedman, senior policy director for Rewiring America, a nonprofit that advocates for community electrification.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The law is pretty clear that once this money is authorized, this money is required to be spent," said Friedman, a former acting assistant secretary for energy efficiency and renewable energy at the Energy Department. "Politically, it would just be a terrible move to roll these things back as every state and territory but one have applied for these rebates."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The $7,500 EV tax credit is more vulnerable as it may be subject to a law that allows Congress to review and reverse recently enacted regulations, according to a September paper by Webb and her colleagues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If we end up with a Republican-controlled Congress, there may be attempts to repeal or revise the IRA tax credits themselves," Webb said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That too could prove politically perilous. The 30% tax credit for residential solar installations, for instance, dates to 2006 and was set to expire in 2023 before the IRA extended it until 2032. Homeowners claimed $6 billion in tax credits for solar installations and battery storage last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Friedman said now is always a good time for families to take advantage of the IRA and go electric. "Regardless of what's going to happen in the future, you should do it today because it's a great deal."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r92i04ro_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The $7,500 EV tax credit is more vulnerable.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-torture-tactics-reportedly-caught-on-camera-civilians-chained-beaten-6991315]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Torture Tactics Allegedly Caught On Camera: Civilians Chained, Beaten]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-torture-tactics-reportedly-caught-on-camera-civilians-chained-beaten-6991315]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:47:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) has released CCTV footage purportedly showing brutal interrogation tactics and extreme measures Hamas operatives subject Palestinian civilians to control them, reported the New York Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) has released CCTV footage purportedly showing brutal interrogation tactics and extreme measures Hamas operatives subject Palestinian civilians to control them, reported the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/10/world-news/brutal-hamas-torture-tactics-caught-in-cctv-footage-idf/">New York Post</a>. The footage, captured between 2018 and 2020 in northern Gaza, was retrieved from a former Hamas base in Jabalia and sheds light on the terror group's tactics, the IDF said in a statement.</p>

<p>“The materials uncovered, expose Hamas's brutal methods for interrogating civilians, violating human rights, and systematically oppressing residents suspected of opposing the organization's rule,” read the IDF statement.</p>

<p>The nearly 47-minute video compilation, shared by the IDF on X, shows interrogators chaining suspects by their wrists and feet, suspending them from ceilings, covering their heads with sacks, and inflicting beatings during questioning.</p>

<p>Some civilians, bound by their wrists and ankles, can be seen suspended upside down as interrogators strike their soles with sticks. In some visuals, detainees struggle to stand on one foot while the other leg is restrained, adding to the physical torment. The footage also shows detainees in cramped, dark, and unsanitary rooms, often with interrogators ignoring them or casually conversing among themselves.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The same civilians that Hamas outspokenly claimed to be fighting for, are the same civilians being tortured in this video.<br />
<br />
Hamas is not only Israel's enemy—they're Gaza's enemy also. <a href="https://t.co/J4kasDlOCu">pic.twitter.com/J4kasDlOCu</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1855587044421947706?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
Before releasing the footage to the public, the IDF provided the clips to the <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-14063545/gaza-hamas-torture-palestine-israel.html">Daily Mail</a>, which said that it was unable to independently verify the videos.</p>

<p>Hamas has long been accused of targeting civilians suspected of collaborating with Israel or opposing the group's authority. Human rights groups and advocates have reported incidents of arbitrary detention, with allegations of torture and repression.</p>

<p>In 2022, UN Watch highlighted patterns of abuse by Hamas against human rights activists, women, LGBTQ individuals, and political opponents, describing systematic punishments in the form of physical and psychological abuse.</p>

<p>A survivor of such abuses, interviewed by<a href="https://www.i24news.tv/en/news/middle-east/palestinian-territories/1660138495-exclusive-gay-man-who-fled-gaza-speaks-about-experience-with-hamas"> i24News</a> in 2022, recounted the repeated torture he endured after being identified as gay. “They would torture me so badly,” he said, adding his feet were tied and beaten with sticks, alongside further restrictions on food, sleep, and bathroom access. “They made me swear on the Quran that I won't be gay again,” he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dosor9io_hamas-torture_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The footage, captured between 2018 and 2020 in northern Gaza, was retrieved from a former Hamas base.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hypocritical-canadian-journalist-slams-government-over-khalistani-issue-6991786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hypocritical": Canadian Journalist Slams Government Over Khalistani Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hypocritical-canadian-journalist-slams-government-over-khalistani-issue-6991786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:33:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian journalist Terry Milewski has criticized Canada's approach to the Khalistani issue, calling it "hypocritical" and a "national disgrace."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian journalist Terry Milewski has criticized Canada's approach to the Khalistani issue, calling it "hypocritical" and a "national disgrace." Speaking to ANI, Milewski expressed his concerns about Canada's handling of the issue, stating, "I have been saying for 20 years that Canada has been hypocritical in its approach to the Khalistani menace. The Khalistan issue, as it's been treated by Canada over the years, has been a national disgrace."</p>

<p>He disputed claims about Australia Today being blocked and attributed the issue to a long-standing commercial negotiation between Facebook and Canadian regulators, who insist that content creators should be paid.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-cops-arrest-banned-groups-member-over-hindu-temple-attack-6985737">Canada Cops Arrest Banned Group's Member Over Hindu Temple Attack</a></p>

<p>"All you have to do is click on the site and see if it's blocked. I can tell you that it's not; it hasn't been since the very beginning...It hasn't been blocked, it hasn't been banned, it hasn't been censored. Australia Today is an excellent publication. They serve the Indian diaspora in Australia very well. They and their supposed defenders have been fooled," Milewski said.</p>

<p>"The only problem with access to the site is if you insist on getting it only on Facebook. But if you just go to the site, there's no problem. The issue is a long-standing commercial negotiation, a difference of opinion between Facebook and Canadian regulators, who insist that content creators should be paid," he added.</p>

<p>Milewski also condemned the recent Khalistani attack on Hindu Sabha Temple in Brampton, attributing these incidents to the failure of Canadian politicians to address the growing influence of Khalistani separatism over the past 40 years.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/avoiding-mention-of-khalistanis-canadian-mp-chandra-arya-slams-politicians-6981617">"Avoiding Mention Of Khalistanis": Canadian MP Slams Politicians</a></p>

<p>"This is extremely disturbing, and it arises from the utter folly of Canadian politicians over 40 years," he said.</p>

<p>"It is an open aggression by Khalistanis aimed at Hindu temples in this case, and it is extremely worrying," he added.</p>

<p>Milewski also shared his insights on the potential impact of the US presidential election on India-Canada relations. Speaking about Donald Trump's "unpredictability", Milewski noted that Trump has a good relationship with Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who has been praising the incoming administration and looking forward to working with Trump.</p>

<p>"Trump is nothing if not unpredictable. He gets along very well with PM Modi and Modi has been very assiduous in peppering the incoming administration with praise and looking forward to working with his friend Donald Trump," he said.</p>

<p>Diplomatic ties between Canada and India have been strained since Ottawa alleged New Delhi's role behind the killing of Gurpatwant Singh Pannun, an India-designated terrorist. New Delhi has strongly denied the charge, calling it "absurd" and "motivated".</p>

<p>The ties deteriorated further following the Khalistani attack on the Hindu Sabha Temple in Brampton.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/con2p7lg_terry-milewski_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Canadian journalist also condemned the recent attack on a Hindu Sabha Temple.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/when-world-war-1-ended-on-november-11-armistice-day-history-and-significance-6991774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World War I Ended On November 11, Armistice Day: History And Significance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/when-world-war-1-ended-on-november-11-armistice-day-history-and-significance-6991774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:31:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The armistice was an agreement to down the weapons as a precursor to the peace negotiations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On this day, 106 years ago, World War I ended on the 11th hour of the 11th day of the 11th month of 1918. The date is now known as Armistice Day when Axis and Allies signed an agreement for peace, bringing end to a war that had been waging for over four years and led to the death of over 15 million people. An armistice was preferred over a surrender as both sides believed it was the fastest way to end the war's misery and carnage. The armistice was an agreement to down the weapons as a precursor to the peace negotiations that would conclude with the signing of the Treaty of Versailles in June of the subsequent year.</p>

<p>Prior to the armistice, Germans had suffered heavy casualties as British, French and US forces pushed them steadily. Despite the Germans on the back foot and an opportunity to take over Berlin on the cards, the Allies preferred to walk away as an invasion would have required too much in terms of manpower, logistics and resources.</p>

<h3><strong>Armistice negotiations</strong></h3>

<p>Germans knew they had run their race. As early as September of 1918, they started to make overtures about an armistice. The German government approached the US with a request for an agreement and hoped that the finer details would be based on the 'peace without victory' plan laid down by US President Woodrow Wilson in January.</p>

<p>Commander-in-chief of the Allied forces, Marshal Ferdinand Foch led the negotiations from a position of leverage -- ensuring that Germans could not dictate the terms. When the Deutsch side asked if he had an Allied offer, Foch <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.history.com/news/world-war-i-armistice-germany-allies" rel="noindex, nofollow">said</a>: "I have no proposals to make.</p>

<h3><strong>What did Germany give up?</strong></h3>

<p>As part of the armistice, Germans agreed to pull their troops out of France, Belgium and Luxembourg within 15 days, or risk becoming prisoners of the Allies. They were also required to return all the prisoners of war without reciprocity.</p>

<p>The Germans had to hand over their arsenal, which included 5,000 artillery pieces, 25,000 machine guns and 1,700 airplanes, along with 5,000 railroad locomotives, 5,000 trucks and 150,000 wagons.It also had to give up the contested territory of Alsace-Lorraine. And they agreed to the indignity of Allied forces occupying German territory along the Rhine, where they would stay until 1930.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-miyazaki-airport-reopens-after-world-war-ii-bomb-explodes-near-runway-6704271" rel="noindex, nofollow">Also read | Japan Airport Reopens After World War II Bomb Explodes Near Runway</a></p>

<h3><strong>How is it remembered?</strong></h3>

<p>In 1919, King George V of England proclaimed that Armistice Day be marked with two minutes of silence at 11 am, the hour the agreement had gone into effect. "The thoughts of everyone may be concentrated on reverent remembrance of the glorious dead," the king said during the ceremony held in the palace grounds.</p>

<p>Since then, 11 November has been referred to as Remembrance Day in the Commonwealth. In London, a National Service of Remembrance is held each year at the Cenotaph, a war memorial, and bright red paper poppies are worn as a symbol of support for the armed forces. Sporting events also witness teams standing in silence as the military bugle is blasted during this period.</p>

<p>A few days after King George V's announcement, the then-US president, Woodrow Wilson declared that the Americans would also be observing the day with ceremonies across the country.</p>

<p>"With splendid forgetfulness of mere personal concerns we remodelled our industries, concentrated our financial resources, increased our agricultural output, and assembled a great army, so that at the last our power was a decisive factor in the victory," read Wilson's statement.</p>

<p>In 1953, Alvin J. King of Emporia, Kansas, proposed changing the name of the holiday to Veterans Day, to recognise veterans from all wars and conflicts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dr53cgh_world-war-1_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Red paper poppies on crosses in a cemetery]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamy-may-get-senior-role-in-donald-trumps-administration-6990511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy May Get Senior Role In Donald Trump's Administration]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamy-may-get-senior-role-in-donald-trumps-administration-6990511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:18:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has shut the door on Nikki Haley declaring that he won't be inviting her to join his administration, but another Indian American, Vivek Ramaswamy, may get a senior role.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has shut the door on Nikki Haley declaring that he won't be inviting her to join his administration, but another Indian American, Vivek Ramaswamy, may get a senior role.</p>

<p>Out of the blue, in his post on Truth Social, Trump also said that Mike Pompeo, the former secretary of state and Central Intelligence head, won't get a job with him either.</p>

<p>“I will not be inviting former Ambassador Nikki Haley, or former Secretary of State Mike Pompeo, to join the Trump Administration, which is currently in formation”, he said on Truth Social, a social media site for short posts that was started when X (formerly Twitter) banned him.</p>

<p>However, he added, “I very much enjoyed and appreciated working with them previously, and would like to thank them for their service to our Country”.</p>

<p>During a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, Trump praised Ramaswamy as “very smart” and said that “he's going to be a part of something that's going to be really big”.</p>

<p>“I don't want to tell him yet exactly (his position). We're gonna pick the right (one)”, he said.</p>

<p>Trump added, “We can put him in charge of one of these big monsters (in government) and he'll do a better job than anybody you can think of.”</p>

<p>Haley became the first Indian-American to hold a cabinet post when Trump appointed her as the Permanent Representative to the United Nations, a high-level position in the US.</p>

<p>She quit the job after only two years and quietly began building her base beyond South Carolina state, where she had been governor.</p>

<p>Haley made an unsuccessful run for the Republican party's presidential nomination and was the last to drop out of the race and endorse him, angering Trump.</p>

<p>Her appeal was to the moderate Republicans, some of whom defected to Vice President Kamala Harris because of what they saw as character problems of Trump.</p>

<p>Although Haley said that she was on standby to campaign for Trump, she was not invited to speak at his rallies or any event.</p>

<p>After criticising his campaign as "overly masculine", she made a last-minute pitch for Trump in an op-ed article in The Wall Street Journal, but it was laced with criticism of him and not a total acclamation.</p>

<p>“I don't agree with Mr Trump 100 per cent of the time. But I do agree with him most of the time, and I disagree with Ms Harris nearly all the time. That makes this an easy call” to vote for him, she wrote.</p>

<p>However, she added the criticism that while the moderates “like much of what he did as President and agree with most of his policies” they “dislike his tone and can't condone his excesses, such as his conduct on January 6, 2021” when his supporters rioted and invaded the Capitol when Congress was in the process of certifying President Joe Biden's win in the 2020 election.</p>

<p>The multi-millionaire pharmaceutical entrepreneur Ramaswamy also ran against him but folded his campaign early and became his unquestioning supporter, and at one rally compared Trump to George Washington, the Father of the Nation.</p>

<p>Recalling the fight for the party nomination, Trump said, “I had to compete with this guy, and I thought it was going to be easy, but it wasn't. He was nasty. He was quick. He's smart as hell.”</p>

<p>“He did amazingly well, because he started really as a rookie, right? And he got up and he wiped a lot of very smart politicians off the stage”, Trump said.</p>

<p>During a debate of the candidates for the Republican nomination that Trump boycotted, Ramaswamy made the strongest attacks on Haley over her support for aid to Ukraine.</p>

<p>There is also media speculation that Ramaswamy may not take an administration job and instead seek the governorship of Ohio in the 2026 election.</p>

<p>Pompeo had figured in media speculation for a cabinet position, possibly Defence, in Trump's administration. But apparently the former Army captain failed the loyalty test, even though he endorsed Trump, because he had criticised him for holding on to classified documents after leaving the White House for which Trump was being prosecuted.</p>

<p>He and Haley are staunch supporters of Ukraine, while Trump has been ambivalent claiming he would end the invasion by Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/j8qo1in_donald-trump-vivek-ramaswamy-_625x300_15_January_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump praised Vivek Ramaswamy as "very smart".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yuichiro-tamaki-key-japan-opposition-partys-head-admits-to-extra-marital-affair-6991484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Key Japan Opposition Party's Head Admits To Extra-Marital Affair]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yuichiro-tamaki-key-japan-opposition-partys-head-admits-to-extra-marital-affair-6991484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 11:44:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yuichiro Tamaki, the head of the Japanese opposition party that has emerged as kingmaker as lawmakers select the next prime minister on Monday, said a tabloid report about his extra-marital affair with a model was "basically true".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yuichiro Tamaki, the head of the Japanese opposition party that has emerged as kingmaker as lawmakers select the next prime minister on Monday, said a tabloid report about his extra-marital affair with a model was "basically true".</p>

<p>"I apologise for the trouble caused," the Democratic Party for the People (DPP) leader told reporters at a hastily called news conference after tabloid SmartFlash reported the affair on Monday.</p>

<p>"The facts reported this morning are basically true," he said.</p>

<p>Despite the scandal, Tamaki retained the unanimous support of the party's lawmakers to stay on as party leader, DPP Secretary General Kazuya Shimba told reporters.</p>

<p>SmartFlash reported that Tamaki, 55, and a 39-year-old model and entertainer rendezvoused in July and October. It published a photo of Tamaki in a grey hoodie as he emerged from a bar, followed 20 minutes later by the woman.</p>

<p>"My wife had told me, 'you can't protect the country if you can't protect the person closest to you.' I will etch those words in my mind once again, reflect on my action and do my best to work in a way that is in the best interests of the country and to realise policies," Tamaki said.</p>

<p>Japanese lawmakers are set to decide at a special parliamentary session on Monday whether Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba should stay as the country's premier after his scandal-tarnished coalition lost its parliamentary majority in an election last month.</p>

<p>Ishiba is expected to prevail because his coalition retained the biggest block of seats in the election.</p>

<p>Tamaki has previously said his party members would not vote for Ishiba but could offer support to the prime minister's Liberal Democratic Party on a policy-by-policy basis.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lvrulqlg_yuichiro-tamaki_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-woman-dies-after-six-cosmetic-surgeries-in-one-day-family-seeks-compensation-6991400]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Woman Dies After 6 Cosmetic Surgeries In A Day, Family Files Lawsuit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-woman-dies-after-six-cosmetic-surgeries-in-one-day-family-seeks-compensation-6991400]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 11:30:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Liu first underwent double eyelid surgery and a nose job, which lasted five hours, followed by liposuction on her thighs the next morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a tragic incident, a woman in China died after undergoing six cosmetic surgeries in a single day, sparking a lawsuit filed by her family against the clinic involved. Her family sought compensation of USD 168,000, alleging negligence and improper care. However, they received only half of the requested amount in the settlement. This case has sparked discussions about the risks associated with multiple surgical procedures and the growing demand for cosmetic enhancements in China.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3285791/china-woman-dies-after-6-cosmetic-surgeries-day-family-get-half-us168000-requested?module=top_story&amp;pgtype=section" rel="nofollow, noindex">South China Morning Post</a></em>, the woman who has been identified as Liu, belonging to a rural area in Guigang, Guangxi province, southern China visited a clinic in Nanning on December 9, 2020.&nbsp;She also took out a loan of over 40,000 yuan (US$5,600) to finance the procedures.&nbsp;Liu first underwent double eyelid surgery and a nose job, which lasted five hours, followed by liposuction on her thighs the next morning.</p>

<p>The extracted fat was then injected into her face and breasts in another five-hour procedure. However, just as Liu was discharged on December 11, she suddenly collapsed in the clinic's lift.&nbsp;Despite emergency efforts by the clinic staff, Liu's condition deteriorated rapidly. She was rushed to The Second Nanning People's Hospital, where she was pronounced dead later that afternoon. The autopsy report showed that she died from ''acute respiratory failure due to pulmonary embolism after liposuction''.</p>

<p>In the aftermath, Liu's family took legal action, filing a lawsuit against the clinic at Jiangnan District People's Court of Nanning City. They demanded compensation of 1.18 million yuan (US$168,000), alleging negligence and malpractice on the part of the clinic.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">Her husband said, ''The clinic offered me 200,000 yuan as compensation. I said that at least one million yuan should be given for a person's death. Even if we split the responsibility, it should still be at least 500,000 yuan. I refused their private settlement, and I said we should just go to court.''</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The legal battle intensified as the clinic shifted blame to Liu, claiming she should have understood the risks associated with cosmetic surgery. Despite the autopsy report, the clinic argued that malpractice had not been proven. However, when multiple court-commissioned agencies requested the clinic's treatment standards, they refused to comply. In May 2021, the court initially held the clinic fully responsible for Liu's death, ordering compensation of over one million yuan (US$140,000). The clinic appealed, and in August, the court revised the ruling, acknowledging partial responsibility and reducing compensation to 590,000 yuan.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The court-ordered evaluation revealed that Liu's pre-existing physical condition may have played a role in her death, leading to a revised judgment of shared liability between Liu and the clinic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The tragic incident went viral on social media, garnering over 50 million views and unleashing a torrent of public outrage against the clinic. One user wrote, ''Six surgeries in one day? Does the clinic have no common sense? Did they not consider the risk of complications, especially with liposuction, which can easily lead to blood clots?''</p>

<p>Another commented, ''Dying in the pursuit of beauty. This is really beyond extreme.''</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8qd73teg_cosmetic-surgeries_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This case has sparked discussions about the risks associated with multiple surgical procedures.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-crown-prince-mohammed-bin-salman-speaks-to-donald-trump-in-late-night-phone-call-6991333]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Crown Prince Speaks To Donald Trump In Late-Night Phone Call]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-crown-prince-mohammed-bin-salman-speaks-to-donald-trump-in-late-night-phone-call-6991333]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 11:17:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia's Crown Prince Mohammed Bin Salman called Donald Trump in the early hours of Wednesday to express his joy at the Republican's return to power, according to two people with knowledge of the exchange.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia's Crown Prince Mohammed Bin Salman called Donald Trump in the early hours of Wednesday to express his joy at the Republican's return to power, according to two people with knowledge of the exchange.</p>

<p>Trump strengthened US ties with Saudi Arabia during his previous term. The bi-lateral relationship during the administration of President Joe Biden was initially soured by Biden's criticism of the kingdom over the 2018 murder of Washington Post columnist Jamal Khashoggi at the Saudi consulate in Istanbul.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia's 39-year old de facto ruler placed the call shortly after Trump delivered his victory speech in Palm Beach, Florida, said the two individuals, who did not wish to be identified because they were discussing a private matter.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Trump didn't respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Trump told Saudi-owned Al Arabiya news channel last month that one of his priorities would be to expand the Abraham Accords to include normalization of relations between Israel and Saudi Arabia. The Accords were signed in 2020 during Trump's first term and saw diplomatic ties established between Israel and Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump told Al Arabiya that Saudi Arabia's relations with the US "could never be great with a guy like Biden."</p>

<p>"With me, it will be great and I have great respect for Saudi Arabia," he said.</p>

<p>Trump and the Crown Prince have frequently praised one another in public, and Saudi Arabia was the first country Trump visited when he became president in 2017.</p>

<p>After a frosty start under Biden, relations between the two countries began to improve as the two countries started talks over a defense treaty and technological and nuclear cooperation tied to Riyadh's recognition of Israel.</p>

<p>Riyadh has hardened its position on normalizing relations since the Israel-Hamas war and the spread of the conflict to Lebanon. The kingdom says future relations with Israel depend on the establishment of a Palestinian state.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6mvk7u78_mohammed-bin-salman-donald-trump_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump strengthened US ties with Saudi Arabia during his previous term.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-chooses-immigration-official-tom-homan-as-border-czar-6991229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Chooses Immigration Official Tom Homan As "Border Czar"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-chooses-immigration-official-tom-homan-as-border-czar-6991229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 10:56:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Tom Homan will be in charge of "all Deportation of Illegal Aliens back to their Country of Origin".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US president-elect Donald Trump said late Sunday he was bringing back hardline immigration official Tom Homan to oversee the country's borders in the incoming administration. The 78-year-old Republican tycoon has pledged to launch -- on day one of his presidency -- the largest deportation operation of undocumented immigrants in US history.</p>

<p>"I am pleased to announce that the Former ICE Director, and stalwart on Border Control, Tom Homan, will be joining the Trump Administration, in charge of our Nation's Borders ("The Border Czar")," Trump posted on his social network Truth Social.</p>

<p>"I've known Tom for a long time, and there is nobody better at policing and controlling our Borders."</p>

<p>Homan will be in charge of "all Deportation of Illegal Aliens back to their Country of Origin", Trump added.</p>

<p>Trump -- who never conceded his 2020 loss -- sealed a remarkable comeback to the presidency in the November 5 vote, cementing what is set to be more than a decade of US politics dominated by his hardline right-wing stance.</p>

<p>During his campaign, he repeatedly railed against undocumented immigrants, employing violent rhetoric about those who "poison the blood" of the United States.</p>

<p>While the US government has struggled for years to manage its southern border with Mexico, Trump has super-charged concerns by claiming an "invasion" is underway by migrants he says will rape and murder Americans.</p>

<p>In rally speeches, he wildly exaggerated local tensions and misled his audiences about immigration statistics and policy.</p>

<p>Violent crime, which spiked under Trump, has fallen in every year of President Joe Biden's administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Migrants commit fewer crimes proportionately than the native population, though foreign suspects have been named in a few high-profile cases of violent attacks on women and children, infuriating Republicans.</p>

<p>The number of US border patrol encounters with migrants crossing over from Mexico illegally is now about the same as in 2020, the last year of Trump's presidency, after peaking at a record 250,000 for the month of December 2023.</p>

<p>Trump vowed to tackle migrant gangs using the Alien Enemies Act of 1798 -- which allows the federal government to round up and deport foreigners belonging to enemy countries -- as part of a mass deportation drive he christened "Operation Aurora."</p>

<p>Aurora was the scene of a viral video showing armed Latinos rampaging through an apartment block that spurred sweeping, false narratives about the town being terrorised by Latin American migrants.</p>

<p>Trump has similarly promoted the fictitious story that Haitian migrants in Springfield, Ohio, are eating residents' pets.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/o9s2vpv8_tom-homan_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-who-used-to-share-anti-trump-posts-kills-wife-ex-partner-2-sons-6990963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Who Used To Share Anti-Trump Posts Kills Wife, Ex-Partner, 2 Sons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-who-used-to-share-anti-trump-posts-kills-wife-ex-partner-2-sons-6990963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 10:41:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 46-year-old man killed his wife, former partner and his two sons before shooting himself in the US state of Minnesota, authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 46-year-old man killed his wife, former partner and his two sons before shooting himself in the US state of Minnesota, authorities said. The man, identified as Anthony Nephew, would often write social media posts against US President-elect Donald Trump. He even faced a “pattern of mental health issues,” the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/10/us-news/minn-dad-anthony-nephew-ranted-against-trump-killed-family-in-murder-suicide/">New York Post</a> quoted Duluth police chief Mike Ceynowa as saying on Friday.</p>

<p>The five people -- Nephew, his wife, ex-partner and his two sons -- were found dead inside two houses on Thursday.</p>

<p>While Nephew's ex-partner Erin Abramson and their son, Jacob Nephew, were found dead from alleged gunshot wounds inside their home on Thursday afternoon, authorities recovered bodies of his wife Kathryn Nephew, and their 7-year-old son Oliver Nephew inside their family home nearby.</p>

<p>After identifying Nephew as a suspect, they also saw his body inside the home from a self-inflicted gunshot wound. Nephew was sharing anti-Trump posts on his Facebook account, authorities said.</p>

<p>“My mental health and the world can no longer peacefully coexist, and a lot of the reason is religion,” he wrote in a July post.</p>

<p>He further wrote that he was "terrified of religious zealots inflicting their misguided beliefs" on him and his family. "I have intrusive thoughts of being burned at the stake as a witch, or crucified on a burning cross," he added.</p>

<p>In a separate post, Nephew even accused the Republicans of “making it harder for women to leave” abusive relationships.</p>

<p>“Gilead here we come,” he said, about the dystopian novel “The Handmaid's Tale”.</p>

<p>Another post by Nephew features an image of Trump with former President Barack Obama, President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>While the word “hate” was written beneath Trump's face, words like “hope,” “heal” and “grow” were mentioned under the Democratic politicians.</p>

<p>“Not that anyone cares, but as an Independent voter, I would like to see both the political parties in our country pick better candidates,” he wrote in a July post this year.</p>

<p>The Duluth Police are yet to determine the motive behind the murders, noting there was no ongoing threat to the community.&nbsp;</p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s19bcbng_anthony-nephew-facebook_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anthony Nephew would often write social media posts against US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-year-old-girls-could-be-married-off-as-iraq-plans-to-amend-law-report-6990948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[9-Year-Old Girls Could Be Married Off As Iraq Plans To Amend Law: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-year-old-girls-could-be-married-off-as-iraq-plans-to-amend-law-report-6990948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 10:02:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The proposed changes would mark a shift from the 1959 legislation, also known as Law 188.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iraq is closer to amending its marriage laws which would lower the legal age of consent from 18 to nine, allowing old men to marry young girls, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/global-health/women-and-girls/iraq-poised-to-lower-the-age-of-consent-for-girls-to-nine/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Telegraph</em></a>. Dominant Shia Muslim parties in the Iraqi Parliament have proposed an amendment to the country's "personal status law" that could see a Taliban-style rollback of all women's rights. If passed, the legal changes will deprive the Iraqi women of rights to divorce, child custody and inheritance as well.</p>

<p>"It's the closest it's ever been. It has more momentum than it's ever had, primarily because of the Shia parties," Dr Renad Mansour, a senior research fellow at Chatham House was quoted as saying by the publication.</p>

<p>"It's not all Shia parties, it's just the specific ones that are empowered and are really pushing it. Stressing the religious side is a way for them to try and regain some of the ideological legitimacy that has been waning over the last few years."</p>

<p>The proposed changes would mark a shift from the 1959 legislation, also known as Law 188, which was introduced after the fall of the Iraqi monarchy. The law transferred family law authority from religious figures to the state judiciary. The coalition of Shia Muslim parties claims that the proposed move aligns with a strict interpretation of Islamic law and protects young girls from 'immoral relationships'.</p>

<p>While attempts have been made in the past to amend the law, this is the first time it seems that the Iraqi lawmakers might be able to see it through. A second reading of the amendment to the law was passed in September earlier this year.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-political-mission-in-iraq-to-end-by-2025-after-over-20-years-5788564" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | UN Political Mission In Iraq To End By 2025 After Over 20 Years</strong></a></p>

<p>Opponents of the move have slammed the government and MPs for attempting to diminish women's rights. Meanwhile, human rights groups stated that the new law effectively puts young girls at risk of sexual and physical violence.</p>

<p>According to the United Nations children's agency, UNICEF, despite outlawing child marriages in the 1950s, 28 per cent of girls in Iraq are already married before the age of 18. A loophole in the law where religious leaders officiate these marriages, instead of the courts, allows underage girls to be married to older men with permission from the father.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jgmnhh3g_iraq-women-protest_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>