<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 04:14:35 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-if-the-us-election-ends-in-a-trump-kamala-harris-tie-6945029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What If The US Election Ends In A Trump-Kamala Harris Tie?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-if-the-us-election-ends-in-a-trump-kamala-harris-tie-6945029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 03:15:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While not highly likely, such an outcome remains possible, tormenting Americans already perched painfully on the edge of their seats ahead of the November 5 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So what exactly happens if neither Kamala Harris or Donald Trump achieves the Electoral College majority required to win the US election?</p>

<p>While not highly likely, such an outcome remains possible, tormenting Americans already perched painfully on the edge of their seats ahead of the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Under the US system, it is not the national popular vote that decides who becomes president, but a 538-member "Electoral College," in which each state gets as many "electors" as their representation in Congress.</p>

<p>Every state except Nebraska and Maine award all of their electors to whomever comes first in the state-wide popular vote.</p>

<p>If both Harris and Trump fail to reach the majority threshold of 270 electors, the US Constitution says that Congress would play a deciding role.</p>

<p>Specifically, the newly elected House of Representatives would select the president in January, while the Senate would designate the next vice president.</p>

<p>Several possible scenarios could produce a 269-269 Electoral College split.</p>

<p>One example would occur if Democrat Harris prevails in the states of Wisconsin, Michigan and Pennsylvania, while the Republican former president carries Georgia, Arizona, Nevada and North Carolina, plus a single left-leaning district in Nebraska.</p>

<p><strong>- 200 years -</strong></p>

<p>A tie would force a so-called contingent election in Congress -- something which has never happened in modern American history.</p>

<p>The last time a tie forced Congress to pick the president was in the 1800 election, which pitted Thomas Jefferson against incumbent president John Adams.</p>

<p>Lawmakers in a badly divided House struggled mightily to agree, finally selecting Jefferson on their 36th ballot.</p>

<p>The excruciating muddle led to the adoption four years later of the 12th Amendment to the US Constitution, to somewhat clarify procedures around the election.</p>

<p>This time, if such a House vote should be necessary, it would take place on January 6, 2025.</p>

<p>How would that vote proceed?</p>

<p><strong>- One state, one vote -</strong></p>

<p>"Each state, regardless of population, casts a single vote for President in a contingent election," according to the Congressional Research Service (CRS).</p>

<p>In other words, Republican-leaning Wyoming with its city-sized population of 500,000 would have the same influence as Democratic California, where 39 million people live.</p>

<p>Though the US capital city Washington has three Electoral College votes, it would not get a vote in a contingent election, as it is not a state.</p>

<p>States with two or more representatives would need to hold an internal vote to determine which candidate to support, a CRS report said.</p>

<p>A candidate needs to win a majority of the 50 states, or 26 votes. At present, that would likely give Republicans the edge.</p>

<p>Specific rules to govern the process would likely have to be adopted by the House, potentially leading to intense disagreements and a protracted period of constitutional crisis.</p>

<p>It is not hard to imagine how such a process, at the end of a razor-close campaign, would weigh on the already badly frayed nerves of American voters, many of whom are convinced that the vote has been rife with irregularities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tmn8quvo_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_03_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several possible scenarios could produce a 269-269 Electoral College split.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abortion-rights-issue-influencing-indian-american-womens-voting-preference-6944853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Abortion Rights Issue Influencing Indian American Women's Voting Preference]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abortion-rights-issue-influencing-indian-american-womens-voting-preference-6944853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 02:16:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the upcoming US presidential election, the issue of abortion rights is emerging as a significant factor that is influencing Indian American women's voting preferences.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the upcoming US presidential election, the issue of abortion rights is emerging as a significant factor that is influencing Indian American women's voting preferences.</p>

<p>This demographic group, which is a part of the second-largest immigrant community in the United States, is showing a strong inclination towards supporting candidates who advocate for reproductive rights.</p>

<p>Meeta Damani, an Indian American documentary filmmaker living in the New Jersey area, has been working in the community with a particular focus on women and children.</p>

<p>"It is a crucial issue for both men and women in the Indian American community as well. It is interconnected like if there is a woman and the child is going to be born unhealthy, that is going to affect the entire family. At the end of the day, it is about freedom and one's choice. I feel the women voters will make their voice very clear," she said.</p>

<p>Looking at the clarity of thought on this subject among Indian American women, it is not a surprise that abortion and reproductive rights have become a top-tier policy issue in the 2024 election cycle.</p>

<p>Priya, a marketing professional, is also a vocal member of the Indian American diaspora in the New Jersey region. She feels that this shouldn't even have been an issue.</p>

<p>"Who would have thought that after coming to a first world country like America, abortion rights would even be an issue for women. If it is my body, it should be my choice. As simple as that. As women voters, if you have the opportunity to support a party that wants to keep your rights intact you will absolutely do that," she said.</p>

<p>In 2022, the Supreme Court overturned the landmark 1973 Roe v. Wade decision. The ruling ended the constitutional right to abortion, allowing states to ban or restrict abortion access. There were subsequent restrictive abortion laws in various states.</p>

<p>The potential for further limitations on reproductive rights is making it an important issue in the country among women. The majority of the public disapproved of the decision. Many Democratic-led states have taken action to protect abortion rights, and some have become sanctuaries for people seeking care out of state.</p>

<p>Supreet, an IT professional, says that women have been impacted by this in many ways. She also thinks many employers in the US had to find ways to mitigate the challenges that the women workers faced.</p>

<p>"The good part is that a lot of employers are coming up with policies that support women. So even if the company is in a state where it is illegal, they are giving them the means to go to other states. The good part is that corporate America is supportive of women but the government may or may not be. That is why it is important to look at it seriously. I definitely feel the women voters will support the party that is pro-abortion," Supreet said.</p>

<p>The Indian American Attitudes Survey (IAAS) conducted a nationally representative online survey of Indian American citizens between September 18 and October 15. It has identified a new, striking gender gap in voting preferences.</p>

<p>According to the survey, 67 per cent of Indian American women intend to vote for Kamala Harris while 53 per cent of men, a significantly smaller share, say they plan to vote for Harris.</p>

<p>When further disaggregated by age, this gender gap appears starkest with younger voters. In the cohort above the age of 40, more than 70 per cent of women and 60 per cent of men plan to vote for Harris.</p>

<p>Sonal Sharma, an immigration lawyer working with a lot of Indian American population, has a word of caution to offer. She feels that while women do feel strongly about the abortion issue, it is not the only thing that matters to others.</p>

<p>"It is a complex issue, despite abortion being so sensitive the polls are 50-50 divided. So, one can see it is not the only issue important to people. We however saw in states where the legislature tried to bring more strict abortion laws, those were rejected. We will have to see what happens," she said.</p>

<p>The importance of abortion rights for Indian American women has not gone unnoticed by political campaigns. Harris has made abortion rights a central part of her campaign strategy and reproductive rights advocacy groups are actively engaging Indian American voters.</p>

<p>In the United States, there are more than 5.2 million people of Indian origin today. It is the second-largest immigrant group in the United States and has emerged as an important political actor. Women form a very significant subset of this unit and as the election draws near, the abortion rights issue is likely to remain a key factor in mobilising and influencing this important demographic.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/njs5i84o_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the survey, 67 per cent of Indian American women intend to vote for Kamala Harris]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-hit-hezbollah-intel-headquarters-in-syria-strike-6944648]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says Hit Hezbollah Intel Headquarters In Syria Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-hit-hezbollah-intel-headquarters-in-syria-strike-6944648]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 01:12:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's military said its air force struck the intelligence headquarters of Hezbollah's Syrian branch in a strike on Damascus on Monday, an attack a war monitor said killed two people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's military said its air force struck the intelligence headquarters of Hezbollah's Syrian branch in a strike on Damascus on Monday, an attack a war monitor said killed two people.</p>

<p>It was a rare acknowledgement by Israeli authorities of an attack against Syria.</p>

<p>The military has intensified its strikes on targets in Syria since launching its war against Hezbollah in neighbouring Lebanon more than a month ago.</p>

<p>Warplanes "conducted an aerial operation and struck Hezbollah terror targets belonging to Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in Syria", the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Syria branch "includes an independent intelligence gathering, coordination, and assessment network", the military said, adding that the attack aimed to degrade Hezbollah's intelligence capabilities.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a Britain-based war monitor, said Israeli strikes killed two Hezbollah members near the Sayyeda Zeinab area south of Damascus, home to a Shiite sanctuary guarded by pro-Iran groups.</p>

<p>The strikes hit a house "used by members of Hezbollah and the Iranian Revolutionary Guard" at a farm, the Observatory said.</p>

<p>Syria's foreign ministry condemned the attack, saying it targeted "civilian areas" south of Damascus and caused significant material damage.</p>

<p>It did not refer to casualties.</p>

<p>Syrian state media said the strike occurred at approximately 5:18 pm (14:15 GMT) and came "from the direction of the occupied Golan Heights".</p>

<p>Mehdi Mahfouz, a 34-year-old resident of the area, said he "heard three successive explosions, one of which was very strong".</p>

<p>"Then I saw a large black cloud of smoke rising," Mahfouz added. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The blasts were heard in the neighbouring Jaramana suburb of Damascus, an AFP photographer said, as ambulances headed to the area.</p>

<p>Since the Syrian civil war began in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes there, mainly targeting army positions and Iran-backed fighters including from Hezbollah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/264s9o48_israel-hezbollah_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was a rare acknowledgement by Israeli authorities of an attack against Syria.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-ancestral-village-in-india-prays-for-her-election-win-6944069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' Ancestral Village In India Prays For Her Election Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-ancestral-village-in-india-prays-for-her-election-win-6944069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 23:00:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Residents in US Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris' ancestral village in southern India were preparing to hold prayers on election day on Tuesday in a Hindu temple more than 8,000 miles (13,000 km) from Washington.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Residents of US Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris' ancestral village in southern India were preparing to hold prayers on election day on Tuesday in a Hindu temple more than 8,000 miles (13,000 km) from Washington.</p>

<p>Harris' maternal grandfather P.V. Gopalan was born more than a century ago in the leafy village of Thulasendrapuram in what is now Tamil Nadu.</p>

<p>"There will be a special prayer on Tuesday morning at the temple," G. Manikandan, a villager who runs a small store near the temple, said. "Celebrations will follow if she wins."</p>

<p>At the temple, Harris' name is engraved into a stone that lists public donations, along with that of her grandfather. Outside, a large banner wishes "the daughter of the land" success in the election.</p>

<p>Gopalan and his family migrated a few hundred miles to the coastal city of Chennai, where he worked as a high-ranking government official until his retirement.</p>

<p>The village received global attention four years ago when its residents prayed for victory for Harris' Democratic Party in 2020 before celebrating her inauguration as US Vice President by setting off firecrackers and distributing food.</p>

<p>Harris and her Republican rival Donald Trump were scrambling to get supporters to the polls in a historically close contest, which means it could take days for the winner to emerge.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/va1ud0t_kamala-harris-ancestral-village_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At the temple, Kamala Harris' name is engraved into a stone that lists public donations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-new-update-on-x-allows-blocked-users-to-view-your-public-posts-6943791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This New Update On X Allows Blocked Users To View Your Public Posts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-new-update-on-x-allows-blocked-users-to-view-your-public-posts-6943791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 22:16:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk-run X social media platform has started to launch an update that will allow people you've blocked to continue to see your posts and your followers' lists.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk-run X social media platform has started to launch an update that will allow people you've blocked to continue to see your posts and your followers' lists.</p>

<p>According to the company, If your posts are set to public, accounts you have blocked can see your posts.</p>

<p>"We're starting to launch the block function update," said X Engineering in a post.</p>

<p>"However, they cannot engage (like reply, repost, etc.) with your posts," according to X guidelines.</p>

<p>Block is a feature that helps you control how you interact with other accounts on X. This feature helps people restrict specific accounts from following, Direct Messaging, and engaging with them.</p>

<p>The tech billionaire had earlier claimed that stopping people from seeing your public posts "makes no sense."</p>

<p>Now, X is rolling out its controversial update to the block feature, allowing people to view your public posts even if you have blocked them.</p>

<p>"Accounts you have blocked cannot follow you, and you cannot follow an account you have blocked. Blocking an account you are currently following will cause you to unfollow that account (and them to unfollow you). If you decide to unblock that account, you will have to follow that account again," according to X.</p>

<p>Blocked users still can't follow the person who has blocked them, engage with their posts, or send direct messages to them.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, software engineer Tracy Chou has built an app that lets users automate blocking, saying that even though users can get around the block by creating other accounts, friction matters.</p>

<p>"Making it easy for the creeper to creep is not a good thing," she said in a post on X.</p>

<p>The social network has argued that the block feature can be used to share and hide harmful or private information about someone. However, people have protested this change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/x_twitter_logo_1730725137910.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Block is a feature that helps you control how you interact with other accounts on X. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-us-election-by-numbers-6943707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The US Election By Numbers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-us-election-by-numbers-6943707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 22:01:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: Here is the US election, broken down by numbers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: Here is the US election, broken down by numbers.<br />
- Two -</p>

<p>Several independents ran -- and at least one, Robert F. Kennedy Jr, stumbled into a number of eyebrow-raising headlines.</p>

<p>But in the end, the presidential race comes down to a binary choice, with the two candidates from the major parties -- Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump -- seeking to lead a polarized America.</p>

<p>- Five -</p>

<p>November 5 -- Election Day, traditionally held on the Tuesday following the first Monday in November.</p>

<p>- Seven -</p>

<p>The number of swing states -- those which don't clearly favor one party over the other, meaning they are up for grabs.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are courting voters in Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin, concentrating their campaign efforts there in a push to ensure victory.</p>

<p>In a razor-tight election, just a handful of votes in any of those states could decide the outcome.</p>

<p>- 34 and 435 -</p>

<p>Voters won't just decide the White House occupant on Election Day -- they will also hit refresh on the US Congress.</p>

<p>Thirty-four Senate seats and all 435 spots in the House of Representatives are up for grabs.</p>

<p>In the House, members serve a two-year term. Republicans currently have the majority, and Harris's Democrats will be hoping for a turnaround.</p>

<p>In the Senate, 34 seats out of 100 are available, for a six-year term. Republicans are hoping to overturn the narrow Democratic majority.</p>

<p>- 538 -</p>

<p>Welcome to the Electoral College, the indirect system of universal suffrage that governs presidential elections in the United States.</p>

<p>Each state has a different number of electors -- calculated by adding the number of their elected representatives in the House, which varies according to population, to the number of senators (two per state).</p>

<p>Rural Vermont, for example, has just three electoral votes. Giant California, meanwhile, has 54.</p>

<p>There are 538 electors in total scattered across the 50 states and the District of Columbia. To take the White House, a candidate must win 270 votes.</p>

<p>- 774,000 -</p>

<p>The number of poll workers who made sure the 2020 election ran smoothly, according to the Pew Research Center.</p>

<p>There are three types of election staff in the United States.</p>

<p>The majority are poll workers -- recruited to do things like greet voters, help with languages, set up voting equipment, and verify voter IDs and registrations.</p>

<p>Election officials are elected, hired or appointed to carry out more specialized duties such as training poll workers, according to Pew.</p>

<p>Poll watchers are usually appointed by political parties to observe the ballot count -- expected to be particularly contentious this year, thanks to Trump's refusal to agree to unconditionally accept the result.</p>

<p>Many election workers have already spoken to AFP about the pressure and threats they are receiving ahead of the November 5 vote.</p>

<p>- 75 million -</p>

<p>As of November 2, more than 75 million Americans had voted early, according to a University of Florida database.</p>

<p>Most US states permit in-person voting or mail-in voting to allow people to deal with scheduling conflicts or an inability to cast their ballots on election day itself on November 5.</p>

<p>- 244 million -</p>

<p>The number of Americans who will be eligible to vote in 2024, according to the Bipartisan Policy Center.</p>

<p>How many of those will actually cast their ballot remains to be seen, of course. But the Pew Research Center says that the midterm elections of 2018 and 2022, and the presidential vote of 2020, produced three of the highest turnouts of their kind seen in the United States in decades.</p>

<p>"About two-thirds (66 percent) of the voting-eligible population turned out for the 2020 presidential election -- the highest rate for any national election since 1900," Pew says on its website.</p>

<p>That translated to nearly 155 million voters, according to the Census Bureau.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eoi3ebi_us-election_625x300_02_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a razor-tight election, just a handful of votes in any of those states could decide the outcome]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-seven-states-that-will-decide-the-us-presidency-6943603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Seven States That Will Decide The US Presidency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-seven-states-that-will-decide-the-us-presidency-6943603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 21:48:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[And in the handful of critical states framing the 2024 race, there is little daylight between the rivals with barely a week before Election Day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris and former president Donald Trump are hurtling toward their November 5 election showdown, one of the closest contests in modern American history.</p>

<p><br />
And in the handful of critical states framing the 2024 race, there is little daylight between the rivals with barely a week before Election Day.</p>

<p><br />
Under the US Constitution, America's founding fathers established that each of the 50 states would hold its own vote for president.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
Under the complex Electoral College system, each state has a certain number of "electors," based on population. Most states have a winner-take-all system that awards all electors to whoever wins the popular vote.</p>

<p><br />
With candidates needing 270 of the 538 electoral votes to win, elections tend to be decided in the hotly contested "swing states" with a history of alternating between Republican and Democratic candidates.</p>

<p><br />
This year, there are seven such battlegrounds, and every one is a toss-up within the margin of error. Here is a look:</p>

<p><br />
- Pennsylvania (19 Electoral College votes) -<br />
Pennsylvania was once reliably Democratic, but these days, they don't come much tighter than the Keystone State.</p>

<p><br />
Republican Trump won the most populous battleground, with 13 million residents, by 0.7 percentage points in 2016. Joe Biden claimed it by 1.2 percentage points in 2020.</p>

<p><br />
Known for its "Rust Belt" cities like Philadelphia and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania has been blighted for decades by the steady decline of its industrial manufacturing base.</p>

<p><br />
Trump and Harris have campaigned repeatedly in the eastern state, where the pair held their one and only presidential debate. Trump, who survived an assassination attempt at a July rally in Pennsylvania, is courting the rural white population and warning that migrants are overwhelming small towns.</p>

<p><br />
Harris is touting recent infrastructure wins, and in Pittsburgh she outlined plans to invest $100 billion in manufacturing, a key issue for state residents.</p>

<p><br />
- Georgia (16) -<br />
This southeastern state was an election flashpoint at the end of Trump's first term, and the controversy simmers.</p>

<p><br />
Prosecutors in Georgia indicted Trump in an election interference case after he called state officials urging them to "find" enough votes to overturn Biden's narrow 2020 victory.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
But in a boost for Trump, the case is paused until after the election.</p>

<p><br />
Biden was the first Democrat to win the Peach State since 1992. Demographic changes are likely to benefit Harris, who has courted minority voters across Georgia.</p>

<p><br />
- North Carolina (16) -<br />
The southeastern state has voted Democratic only once since 1980, but Harris believes it's back in play.</p>

<p><br />
The population, now over 10 million, is expanding and growing more diverse, benefiting Democrats.</p>

<p><br />
Complicating matters for Trump, a scandal involving the state's Republican gubernatorial candidate has infuriated party officials who worry it could sink Trump in a close race.</p>

<p><br />
As in neighboring Georgia, one wild card is how the devastation from storm Helene, which recently laid waste to towns in western North Carolina, might impact the vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
- Michigan (15) -<br />
Trump flipped Michigan, a former Democratic stronghold, on his way to defeating Hillary Clinton in 2016.</p>

<p><br />
Biden returned it to the blue column in 2020, buoyed by unionized workers and a large Black community.</p>

<p><br />
But this time, Harris risks losing the support of a 200,000-strong Arab-American community that has denounced Biden's -- and by extension her -- handling of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.</p>

<p><br />
- Arizona (11) -<br />
The Grand Canyon state was among 2020's tightest races, with Biden triumphing by just 10,457 votes.</p>

<p><br />
Trump hopes frustrations over the Biden-Harris administration's immigration policy will swing Arizona, which shares a border with Mexico, back in his favor.</p>

<p><br />
Harris visited Arizona's border in September vowing to crack down on migration and work on reviving last year's bipartisan border bill, which she said Trump "tanked" for political purposes.</p>

<p><br />
- Wisconsin (10) -<br />
Clinton lost Wisconsin after giving the state a wide berth during the 2016 campaign.</p>

<p><br />
As with Midwestern neighbor Michigan, it was a different story when Trump's opponent was Biden, who turned a 23,000-vote deficit into a winning margin of 21,000 for Democrats.</p>

<p><br />
Trump considers it winnable, and his party held its summer national convention there.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
While Trump led early against Biden, Harris has made the state race a nailbiter.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
- Nevada (6) -<br />
The Silver State, with a population of 3.1 million, hasn't voted Republican since 2004. Conservatives, buoyed by Trump's headway with Hispanic voters, are convinced they can flip the script.</p>

<p><br />
Trump held a significant lead here against Biden.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
But within weeks of becoming the Democratic nominee, Harris -- promoting her economic plans to help small businesses and combat inflation -- has erased that advantage in the western state, whose largest city Las Vegas is dominated by the hospitality industry.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/17ftfae_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[America's founding fathers established that each of the 50 states would hold its own vote for president.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-trump-harris-showdown-revives-debate-on-americas-electoral-college-6943320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump-Harris Showdown Revives Debate On US' Electoral College]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-trump-harris-showdown-revives-debate-on-americas-electoral-college-6943320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 21:06:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When political outsider Donald Trump defied polls and expectations to defeat Hillary Clinton in the 2016 US presidential election, he described the victory as "beautiful."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When political outsider Donald Trump defied polls and expectations to defeat Hillary Clinton in the 2016 US presidential election, he described the victory as "beautiful."</p>

<p>Not everyone saw it that way -- considering that Democrat Clinton had received nearly three million more votes nationally than her Republican rival. Non-Americans were particularly perplexed that the second-highest vote-getter would be the one crowned president.</p>

<p>But Trump had done what the US system requires: win enough individual states, sometimes by very narrow margins, to surpass the 270 Electoral College votes necessary to win the White House.</p>

<p>Now, on the eve of the 2024 election showdown between Trump and Democrat Kamala Harris, the rules of this enigmatic and, to some, outmoded, system is coming back into focus.</p>

<p><strong>Why an Electoral College?</strong></p>

<p>The 538 members of the US Electoral College gather in their state's respective capitals after the quadrennial presidential election to designate the winner.</p>

<p>A presidential candidate must obtain an absolute majority of the "electors" -- or 270 of the 538 -- to win.</p>

<p>The system originated with the US Constitution in 1787, establishing the rules for indirect, single-round presidential elections.</p>

<p>The country's Founding Fathers saw the system as a compromise between direct presidential elections with universal suffrage, and an election by members of Congress -- an approach rejected as insufficiently democratic.</p>

<p>Because many states predictably lean Republican or Democratic, presidential candidates focus heavily on the handful of "swing" states on which the election will likely turn -- nearly ignoring some large states such as left-leaning California and right-leaning Texas.</p>

<p>Over the years, hundreds of amendments have been proposed to Congress in efforts to modify or abolish the Electoral College. None has succeeded.</p>

<p>Trump's 2016 victory rekindled debate. And if the 2024 race is the nail-biter that most polls predict, the Electoral College will surely return to the spotlight.</p>

<p><strong>Who are the 538 electors?</strong></p>

<p>Most are local elected officials or party leaders, but their names do not appear on ballots.</p>

<p>Each state has as many electors as it has members in the US House of Representatives (a number dependent on the state's population), plus the Senate (two in every state, regardless of size).</p>

<p>California, for example, has 54 electors; Texas has 40; and sparsely populated Alaska, Delaware, Vermont and Wyoming have only three each.</p>

<p>The US capital city, Washington, also gets three electors, despite having no voting members in Congress.</p>

<p>The Constitution leaves it to states to decide how their electors' votes should be cast. In every state but two (Nebraska and Maine, which award some electors by congressional district), the candidate winning the most votes theoretically is allotted all that state's electors.</p>

<p><strong>Controversial institution</strong></p>

<p>In November 2016, Trump won 306 electoral votes, well more than the 270 needed.</p>

<p>The extraordinary situation of losing the popular vote but winning the White House was not unprecedented.</p>

<p>Five presidents have risen to the office this way, the first being John Quincy Adams in 1824.</p>

<p>More recently, the 2000 election resulted in an epic Florida entanglement between Republican George W. Bush and Democrat Al Gore.</p>

<p>Gore won nearly 500,000 more votes nationwide, but when Florida -- ultimately following a US Supreme Court intervention -- was awarded to Bush, it pushed his Electoral College total to 271 and a hair's-breadth victory.</p>

<p><strong>True vote or simple formality?</strong></p>

<p>Nothing in the Constitution obliges electors to vote one way or another.</p>

<p>If some states required them to respect the popular vote and they failed to do so, they were subjected to a simple fine. But in July 2020, the Supreme Court ruled that states could impose punishments on such "faithless electors."</p>

<p>To date, faithless electors have never determined a US election outcome.</p>

<p><strong>Electoral College schedule</strong></p>

<p>Electors will gather in their state capitals on December 17 and cast votes for president and vice president. US law states they "meet and cast their vote on the first Tuesday after the second Wednesday in December."</p>

<p>On January 6, 2025, Congress will convene to certify the winner -- a nervously watched event this cycle, four years after a mob of Trump supporters attacked the US Capitol attempting to block certification.</p>

<p>But there is a difference. Last time, it was Republican vice president Mike Pence who, as president of the Senate, was responsible for overseeing the certification. Defying heavy pressure from Trump and the mob, he certified Biden's victory.</p>

<p>This time, the president of the Senate -- overseeing what normally would be the pro forma certification -- will be none other than today's vice president: Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>On January 20, the new president is to be sworn in.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ntovuvd8_trump-kamala_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The system establishes rules for indirect, single-round presidential elections. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/axe-attack-on-paris-train-leaves-4-teens-injured-6943174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Axe Attack On Paris Train Leaves 4 Teens Injured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/axe-attack-on-paris-train-leaves-4-teens-injured-6943174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 20:48:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four teens were wounded, two of them seriously, by an axe wielded during a fight on Monday on a suburban train outside Paris, police sources said, with the main suspect later arrested.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four teens were wounded, two of them seriously, by an axe wielded during a fight on Monday on a suburban train outside Paris, police sources said, with the main suspect later arrested.</p>

<p>One of the victims -- all aged 16 or 17 -- had a hand cut off and another had their skull split open.</p>

<p>Two others were more lightly injured in the struggle that one police source said had broken out around 8:00 am (0700 GMT) as the teenagers involved were on their way to secondary school.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear what triggered the fight, in which weapons including the axe, a knife, a samurai sword and baseball bats were used.</p>

<p>All the wounded people were brought to hospital and none were in danger for their life, the source added.</p>

<p>The main suspect, a 16-year-old, was later arrested at his home and held in custody, another police source said.</p>

<p>An axe was found and confiscated during the search, they added.</p>

<p>The incident happened while the RER suburban express train was at the station of Ozoir-la-Ferriere southeast of Paris.</p>

<p>Since the train was halted at a station, the violence did not affect traffic on the RER E line, which runs east-west through Paris and its suburbs, state rail operator SNCF said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gdfg1md8_paris-axe-attack_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The main suspect was later arrested at his home and held in custody. (Represebtational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-the-us-presidential-election-a-battle-of-the-sexes-6942826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is The US Presidential Election A Battle Of The Sexes?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-the-us-presidential-election-a-battle-of-the-sexes-6942826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:57:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Historically speaking, women have leaned towards voting for Democrats more than men have, since the 1980s and this gap has only grown wider since.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US presidential election 2024 is a battle of the sexes.</p>

<p>Historically speaking, women have leaned towards voting for Democrats more than men have, since the 1980s and this gap has only grown wider since.</p>

<p>This time around, Democrats have been losing support from key demographics such as Black and Latino men. However, they have gained support in other areas - women voters.</p>

<p>According to the Center For American Women and Politics, "The number of female voters has exceeded the number of male voters in every presidential election since 1964" so voter turnout is crucial for both the parties.</p>

<p>Apart from the major issues, such as economy and employment, two important topics that will heavily impact election results are abortion and immigration, Democrat Kamala Harris is gaining ground with the former and Republican Donald Trump with the latter.</p>

<p>Based on an analysis by Gallup, "Women aged 18 to 29 today are more liberal than young women in the past on specific issues, particularly the environment and abortion" which explains the surge in women voters for the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>Trump has struggled to connect with women voters. In fact, women tend to favor Harris over Trump by a significant margin. This trend is consistent with previous elections, where Trump has failed to win over female voters. In 2020, Joe Biden took a major slice of women voters at 55% while Trump only won 44%. Similarly, in 2016, Hillary Clinton claimed 54% of women voters while Trump won 39%.</p>

<p>Charlie Kirk, a conservative activist posted, "Early vote has been disproportionately female. If men stay at home, Kamala is president. It's that simple. If you want a vision of the future if you don't vote, imagine Kamala's voice cackling, forever. Men need to GO VOTE NOW" urging men to cast their ballot.</p>

<p>Women are of utmost importance in this election because they can make or break the election. "The women's vote will be decisive this election," Katherine Tate, a Brown University political scientist, said. "If Harris wins, it will be because women elected her." She also added that, "Trump has alienated female voters by his abrasive language and aggression."</p>

<p>On that note, Trump touched a nerve when he said, "You will no longer have anxiety from all of the problems our country has today. You will be protected, and I will be your protector. Women will be happy, healthy, confident and free. You will no longer be thinking about abortion." He was posing as the liberator and messiah for women, at a campaign rally in Indiana. It had a patronising tone that snatched agency from the voices of women and took America back several years.</p>

<p>However, according to a CNN report, Trump has been asking his close allies why women don't like him. The gender gap is a serious concern for the Trump campaign. Speaking for the Republican candidate, Karoline Leavitt, the campaign's spokesperson, told The Independent, that he is "loved by millions of women across the country, and those who know him personally, myself included, will tell you he's supportive, generous and kind."</p>

<p>It is also noteworthy that since the 1970s at least 27 women have accused Trump of sexual assault and misconduct, all of which the former president has denied.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/unkf30o8_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Women are of utmost importance in this election because they can make or break the election]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-launch-two-private-iranian-satellites-into-orbit-6942615]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia To Launch Two Private Iranian Satellites Into Orbit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-launch-two-private-iranian-satellites-into-orbit-6942615]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:29:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian rocket will launch two privately built Iranian satellites into orbit early Tuesday, the Iranian embassy in Moscow said, hailing close space cooperation between Moscow and Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian rocket will launch two privately built Iranian satellites into orbit early Tuesday, the Iranian embassy in Moscow said, hailing close space cooperation between Moscow and Tehran.</p>

<p>The two countries have deepened ties and trade amid Russia's military offensive on Ukraine and conflict in the Middle East, with space launches just one aspect of their burgeoning partnership.</p>

<p>"In continuation of the development of Iran-Russia scientific and technological cooperation, two Iranian satellites -- Koswar and Hodhod -- will be launched into 500-kilometre orbit," Iran's ambassador in Moscow, Kazem Jalali, said Monday on social media.</p>

<p>He said the launch will take place at 02:48 Tehran time (2318 GMT on Monday) using a Russian Soyuz rocket.</p>

<p>The imaging and communications satellites were designed and built by Iran's Omid Faza Company, the statement said, and will support agriculture, environmental monitoring and communications in remote areas.</p>

<p>Russia has previously launched some Iranian satellites, but this is the first instance for a private sector initiative, Jalali said.</p>

<p>"There is hope that with the launch of these two satellites, a firm and decisive first step will be taken towards the entry of the private sector of the Islamic Republic of Iran into the space sphere," he said.</p>

<p>The West has raised concerns over Iran's fledgling space programme, fearing the same technology could also be used to launch nuclear-equipped ballistic missiles.</p>

<p>Tehran says its space programme is peaceful and complies with a UN Security Council resolution that aims to restrict Iran's ballistic missile programme.</p>

<p>Moscow has been accused of using Iranian military hardware and technology, most notably self-detonating Shahed drones, throughout its offensive on Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/satellite-generic_650x400_41476444487.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The launch will take place at 02:48 Tehran time using a Russian Soyuz rocket. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-would-not-mind-somebody-shooting-at-him-through-fake-news-6942604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says He Would Not Mind Somebody 'Shooting' At Him Through Fake News]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-would-not-mind-somebody-shooting-at-him-through-fake-news-6942604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:26:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Having survived two assassination attempts this summer, Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Sunday suggested that he would not mind if somebody took a shot at him through fake news.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having survived two assassination attempts this summer, Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Sunday suggested that he would not mind if somebody took a shot at him through fake news.</p>

<p>Addressing his supporters at an election rally at Lititz in the battleground state of Pennsylvania, Trump generated another controversy by saying that he should not have left the White House after his defeat in the 2020 elections.</p>

<p>"I shouldn't have left, I mean, honestly. We did so well," Trump said in his speech but immediately changed the topic. "So now, every polling booth has hundreds of lawyers standing there."</p>

<p>Trump had refused to accept the results of the November 2020 elections. His supporters ended up attacking the US Capitol on January 6, which is considered to be the worst day in American democracy.</p>

<p>The former president, who is now 78, expressed frustration over the enhanced security around him after his recent assassination bids.</p>

<p>"I have a piece of glass over here. I don't have a piece of glass there. And I have this piece of glass here. But all we have really over here is the fake news, right? And to get me, somebody would have to shoot through the fake news. I don't mind that so much. I don't mind. I don't mind that," Trump said, referring the thick bullet proof glass around him and the gap in his protective glass.</p>

<p>"I have a piece of glass here. The problem with that glass is it's - I don't look great on television when you have a four-inch piece of glass that a howitzer can't go through. No, when you see yourself on television, you say, boy, you're really not very recognizable, to be honest with you, which is good. But here's the problem. So I have glass here. I have glass here. Now, I'm not worried about this. Look, what do I have? A couple of people. And they're friends, generally. There are a couple of people I don't like in that group, but that's like," he said.</p>

<p>His remarks were criticized by the Democrats. Harris-Walz Director of Rapid Response Ammar Moussa said as Harris spent today at church in Detroit, talking to voters about her vision to lift up all Americans, Donald Trump was busy violating the Ninth Commandment.</p>

<p>"Trump is spending the closing days of his campaign angry and unhinged, lying about the election being stolen because he's worried he will lose. The American people deserve a leader who tells the truth and will walk into the Oval Office focused on them - that's Vice President Harris," Moussa said.</p>

<p>Steven Cheung, Trump Campaign Communications Director, said Trump was talking about the two assassination attempts on his own life, including one that came within 1/4 of an inch from killing him, something that the media constantly talks and jokes about.</p>

<p>"The President's statement about protective glass placement has nothing to do with the Media being harmed, or anything else. It was about threats against him that were spurred on by dangerous rhetoric from Democrats," he said.</p>

<p>"In fact, President Trump was stating that the Media was in danger, in that they were protecting him and, therefore, were in great danger themselves, and should have had a glass protective shield, also. There can be no other interpretation of what was said. He was actually looking out for their welfare, far more than his own!" Cheung said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bdehpaas_donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump suggested that he would not mind if somebody took a shot at him through fake news]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maldives-recalls-top-diplomat-over-unauthorised-meet-with-afghan-envoy-6942597]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Maldives Recalls Diplomat In Pak Over Unauthorised Meet With Taliban Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maldives-recalls-top-diplomat-over-unauthorised-meet-with-afghan-envoy-6942597]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:22:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Maldives recalled its top diplomat in Pakistan, official sources said Monday, after he had an unauthorised meeting with an Afghan envoy in Islamabad.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Maldives recalled its top diplomat in Pakistan, official sources said Monday, after he had an unauthorised meeting with an Afghan envoy in Islamabad.</p>

<p>The Maldives Foreign ministry said the much publicised meet between the Maldives High Commissioner Mohamed Thoha and Taliban representative Sardar Ahmad Shakeeb on Friday was "not sanctioned" by the government.</p>

<p>"Consequently, appropriate action has been taken by the government of Maldives," the ministry statement said without giving details.</p>

<p>Thoha's name has been taken down from the website of the Maldives mission in Islamabad, and an official source told AFP that he had been recalled.</p>

<p>Since the Taliban ousted the Western-backed administration in 2021 and imposed an austere interpretation of Islamic law, no foreign country has yet officially recognised their government.</p>

<p>But three years into their rule, Taliban authorities have been making diplomatic inroads.</p>

<p>Pakistan, China, Russia, Iran and Central Asian republics have established de facto diplomatic relations with Kabul, while Western embassies in the capital have been closed for over three years.</p>

<p>The Maldives, the smallest Islamic republic in South Asia, does not recognise the Taliban government.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m5i631uo_maldives-taliban-meet_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Maldives, the smallest Islamic republic in South Asia, does not recognise the Taliban government.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-use-of-air-launched-ballistic-missile-on-iran-draws-interest-6942114]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Use Of Air Launched Ballistic Missile On Iran Draws Interest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-use-of-air-launched-ballistic-missile-on-iran-draws-interest-6942114]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 18:19:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's effective use of air-launched ballistic missiles in its airstrikes against Iran is expected to pique interest elsewhere in acquiring the weapons, which most major powers have avoided in favour of cruise missiles and glide bombs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's effective use of air-launched ballistic missiles in its airstrikes against Iran is expected to pique interest elsewhere in acquiring the weapons, which most major powers have avoided in favour of cruise missiles and glide bombs.</p>

<p>The Israel Defense Forces said its October 26 raid knocked out Iranian missile factories and air defences in three waves of strikes. Researchers said that based on satellite imagery, targets included buildings once used in Iran's nuclear programme.</p>

<p>Tehran defends such targets with "a huge variety" of anti-aircraft systems, said Justin Bronk, an airpower and technology expert at London's Royal United Services Institute.</p>

<p>Cruise missiles are easier targets for dense, integrated air defences than ballistic missiles are. But ballistic missiles are often fired from known launch points, and most cannot change course in flight.</p>

<p>Experts say high-speed, highly accurate air-launched ballistic missiles such as the Israel Aerospace Industries Rampage get around problems facing ground-based ballistic missiles and air-launched cruise missiles - weapons that use small wings to fly great distances and maintain altitude.</p>

<p>"The main advantage of an ALBM over an ALCM is speed to penetrate defences," said Jeffrey Lewis, director of the East Asia Nonproliferation Program at the James Martin Centre for Nonproliferation Studies at the Middlebury Institute of International Studies in California. "The downside - accuracy - looks to have been largely solved."</p>

<p>Ground-launched ballistic missiles - which Iran used to attack Israel twice this year, and which both Ukraine and Russia have used since Russia's invasion in 2022 - are common in the arsenals of many countries. So, too, are cruise missiles.</p>

<p>Because ALBMs are carried by aircraft, their launch points are flexible, helping strike planners.</p>

<p>"The advantage is that being air-launched, they can come from any direction, complicating the task of defending against them," said Uzi Rubin, a senior researcher at the Jerusalem Institute for Strategy and Security, one of the architects of Israel's missile defences.</p>

<p>The weapons are not invulnerable to air defences. In Ukraine, Lockheed Martin Patriot PAC-3 missiles have repeatedly intercepted Russia's Khinzhals.</p>

<p>Many countries, including the United States and Britain, experimented with ALBMs during the Cold War. Only Israel, Russia and China are known to field the weapons now.</p>

<p>The US tested a hypersonic ALBM, the Lockheed Martin AGM-183, but it received no funding for the 2025 fiscal year. Because it has a large arsenal of cruise missiles and other types of long-range strike weapons, Washington has otherwise shown little interest in ALBMs.</p>

<p>A US Air Force official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said ALBMs are not used in Air Force operations.</p>

<p>Raytheon's SM-6, an air-defence missile that has been repurposed for air-to-air and surface-to-surface missions, also has been tested as an air-launched anti-ship weapon, said a senior US defence technical analyst, who declined to be identified because the matter is sensitive.</p>

<p>In tests the missile was able to strike a small target on land representing the centre of mass of a destroyer, the analyst said. Publicly, the SM-6 is not meant for air-to-ground strikes.</p>

<p>Because ALBMs are essentially a combination of guidance, warheads and rocket motors, many countries that have precision weapons already have the capability to pursue them, a defence industry executive said on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the matter.</p>

<p>"This is a clever way of taking a common set of technologies and components and turning it into a very interesting new weapon that gives them far more capability, and therefore options, at a reasonable price," the executive said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/foihooq_israeli-air-force-plane_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Because ALBMs are carried by aircraft, their launch points are flexible. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/im-a-product-of-poverty-cardi-b-slams-elon-musk-over-puppet-remark-6942072]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm A Product Of Poverty": Cardi B Slams Elon Musk Over 'Puppet' Remark]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/im-a-product-of-poverty-cardi-b-slams-elon-musk-over-puppet-remark-6942072]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 18:11:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["Another puppet who can't even talk without being fed the words," Mr Musk said in a tweet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the U.S. presidential election approaches, Grammy-winning rapper Cardi B has publicly criticized Elon Musk after he called her a "puppet" supporting Democratic candidate Kamala Harris. Musk, an avid Donald Trump supporter, took a swipe at Cardi B, responding to a Trump fan account's post featuring a clip of her at a rally in Milwaukee for Harris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Another puppet who can't even talk without being fed the words," Mr Musk said in a quote tweet, referring to a teleprompter malfunction that caused Cardi B to stall until she was handed her speech notes on a phone.</p>

<p>Cardi B quickly responded, "I'm not a puppet, Elon. I'm a daughter of two immigrant parents who worked hard to provide for me!" She continued, "I'm a product of welfare, section 8, poverty, and the reality of a system that's set up against you... But you wouldn't know anything about that. You don't understand the American struggle. PS fix my algorithm."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm not a puppet Elon.. I'm a daughter of two immigrant parents that had to work their ass off to provide for me! I'm a product of welfare, I'm a product of section 8, I'm a product of poverty and I'm a product of what happens when the system is set up against you.But you don't <a href="https://t.co/BBYQ2O0KYJ">https://t.co/BBYQ2O0KYJ</a></p>
 Cardi B (@iamcardib) <a href="https://twitter.com/iamcardib/status/1852830829996556310?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Musk, who was born in South Africa to wealthy parents, including his father Errol Musk, who reportedly held a stake in a Zambian emerald mine, has faced criticism for his remarks on socioeconomic issues.</p>

<p>At the rally, Cardi B delivered a powerful speech on women's rights, condemning Donald Trump's alleged sexism. "Just like Kamala Harris, I've been the underdog, underestimated and discredited. Women have to work ten times harder to prove themselves, and still, we're questioned. I can't stand a bully, and like Kamala, I'll always stand up to one."</p>

<p>The 2024 U.S. presidential election is set for November 5.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hhmb9um_elon-and-cardi-b_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk took a swipe at Cardi B]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-ex-pm-imran-khans-wife-breaks-down-in-tears-during-court-proceedings-6942021]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Ex PM Imran Khan's Wife Breaks Down In Tears During Court Proceedings]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-ex-pm-imran-khans-wife-breaks-down-in-tears-during-court-proceedings-6942021]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 18:06:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in Pakistan on Monday witnessed emotional scenes when jailed former premier Imran Khan's wife Bushra Bibi burst into tears, expressing her utter helplessness against the inefficient justice system and her husband's "unjust sentencing".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court in Pakistan on Monday witnessed emotional scenes when jailed former premier Imran Khan's wife Bushra Bibi burst into tears, expressing her utter helplessness against the inefficient justice system and her husband's "unjust sentencing". &nbsp;The former first lady appeared before Islamabad District Magistrate Afzal Majoka's court to acquire bail for her husband in six cases and herself in another case, registered at Tarnol, Karachi Company, Ramna, Secretariat and Kohsar police stations.</p>

<p>During the hearing held at the Adiala Jail in Rawalpindi, Khan was not produced in the court. He was also not allowed to appear through a video link.</p>

<p>When Bushra took to the rostrum to speak, she became emotional.</p>

<p>"I have been facing injustice by those responsible for serving justice for the past nine months. I and the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf founder were unjustly sentenced," she said.</p>

<p>"There is no justice. I haven't come to seek justice," she sobbed, and even blamed lawyers, saying all lawyers, including the one representing her, "only waste the time".</p>

<p>"The person inside [the prison], isn't he a human? Doesn't any judge see this," she said, adding that she would not come to this court again, where "there is no justice".</p>

<p>She told the judge that she had her blanket and other belongings in her car outside the court and that she was ready to go back to jail if ordered.</p>

<p>Bushra was released from jail<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-ex-pm-imran-khans-wife-bushra-bibi-released-on-bail-freed-from-jail-6864928"> last month</a> following the approval of her bail in the new Toshakhana case, but Khan remains incarcerated.</p>

<p>The former first lady was arrested after a court on January 31 convicted and sentenced her and Khan to 14 years in prison after finding them guilty of retaining and selling state gifts in violation of government rules while the PTI founder was in power.</p>

<p>However, they deny all allegations against them.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/nnqp30eo_imran-khan-bushra-bibi_625x300_01_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bushra Bibi was released from jail last month following the approval of her bail. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frenchmans-skeleton-found-in-attic-likely-of-owner-missing-since-2009-6941950]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Skeleton Found In French Home, Likely Of Owner Missing Since 2009]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frenchmans-skeleton-found-in-attic-likely-of-owner-missing-since-2009-6941950]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 17:54:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New owners renovating a house in eastern France made the shock discovery of a human skeleton that are likely that of a former owner who vanished 15 years ago, prosecutors said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New owners renovating a house in eastern France made the shock discovery of a human skeleton that are likely that of a former owner who vanished 15 years ago, prosecutors said Monday.</p>

<p>"A corpse reduced to a skeleton was found on Saturday afternoon" in Erstroff, just across the border from German city Saarbruecken, said Olivier Glady, prosecutor in nearby town Sarreguemines.</p>

<p>The remains were found "in a difficult-to-access spot under the roof whose entrance was almost hidden," Glady told AFP Monday.</p>

<p>The new owners were renovating the home after buying it in 2023 following the death of the former owner's widow.</p>

<p>"While looking for the source of rainwater leaking into the roof structure, one of the owners entered the cubbyhole almost without realising, and found the skeletal remains inside," Glady said.</p>

<p>The body "is very likely" that of the former owner, who disappeared in 2009 when he was aged 81, he added.</p>

<p>Local police are investigating the cause of death, and the remains have been sent to Strasbourg for forensic examination.</p>

<p>Regional newspaper Le Republicain Lorrain reported that the man's disappearance had gone unresolved despite numerous intensive searches of the area.</p>

<p>His wife died in 2020, prompting the sale of the house.</p>

<p>"The scene where the body was found hints at suicide," prosecutor Glady said, adding that a rope was found still hanging in the attic.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/sg8ktf4g_france-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Local police are investigating the cause of death. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-trumps-dance-moves-on-hit-track-ymca-at-georgia-rally-6941721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Trump's Dance Moves On Hit Track 'YMCA' At Georgia Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-trumps-dance-moves-on-hit-track-ymca-at-georgia-rally-6941721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 17:27:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump capped off his rally in Georgia by dancing to the classic hit 'YMCA'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump capped off his rally in Georgia by dancing to the classic hit 'YMCA'.</p>

<p>As he rallied support just ahead of the US Presidential Elections, Trump declared his "commitment to restoring the American Dream," criticising Democratic rival and US Vice President Kamala Harris for allegedly "undermining that dream". He vowed, "I will bring back the American dream, and we'll bring it back stronger than ever before," while promising to address pressing issues like inflation and immigration.</p>

<p>Trump said his leadership would usher in a new era of prosperity, asserting, "America will be bigger, better, bolder, richer, safer and stronger than ever before." His campaign rhetoric contrasted what he termed the "incompetence and failure" of the current administration with the transformative success he claims would follow his return to office.</p>

<p>In a pointed critique of President Joe Biden, Trump expressed scepticism about Biden's visibility leading up to the elections, asking, "Where the hell is he?" He further suggested that Harris had undermined the electoral process, accusing her of stealing the election from Biden. In a provocative statement, Trump called for Biden to "fire Kamala," saying, "You're the worst ever. Kamala, you're fired. Get the hell out of here."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Kamala Harris will continue her rallies on November 5 breezing through Atlanta, Detroit, Las Vegas, Milwaukee, Philadelphia, Phoenix, Raleigh, and Pittsburgh.</p>

<p>"In this election, we need to remind our neighbours and friends that their vote is their voice, and their voice is their power. Don't let anybody take your power from you. When you love something, you fight for it--and I love this country with all my heart, " Harris said in her posts on X.</p>

<p>As the November 5 elections draw near, recent polling data indicates a competitive race, with a New York Times and Siena College survey showing Trump and Harris tied at 48 per cent in the popular vote. With both candidates vying for a historic moment in US politics, the upcoming election promises to be a pivotal event in the nation's future.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/iaal0ilo_donald-trump_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I will bring back the American dream," Trump said at the rally.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-woman-president-vs-second-term-for-donald-trump-how-us-is-set-to-vote-its-president-6941599]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deadlock At The Polls For Trump And Harris: How US Will Vote In 2024?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-woman-president-vs-second-term-for-donald-trump-how-us-is-set-to-vote-its-president-6941599]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 17:11:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States is posed for presidential elections on November 5 (local time) and the race for the White House is down to the wire.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States is posed for presidential elections on November 5 (local time) and the race for the White House is down to the wire.</p>

<p>Over 160 million voters are expected to cast their ballots with the results either delivering a return to power for Republican former President Donald Trump (78) or electing America's first woman in the White House, Vice President and Democratic candidate Kamala Harris (60).</p>

<p>According to polls, both the candidates are deadlocked in the race with an estimated over 75 million voters having already voted. Neither candidate currently holds a polling lead in enough states to reach 270 electoral votes.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden (81) who was the Democratic Party candidate withdrew from the contest in July, a little over three months ago after a televised debate with Trump. Following this Kamala Harris stepped in as the Democratic candidate.</p>

<p>Harris will on Monday (local time) campaign in Pennsylvania, then head to Pittsburgh and Philadelphia.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Trump survived an assassination attempt while addressing a rally near Butler in Pennsylvania where the shooter was killed by the US Secret Service. Images of him pumping his fist in the air and saying "Fight" went viral. The Republican candidate is banking on concerns about the economy, and inflation to help him to the White House.</p>

<p>On Monday (local time) he will visit Raleigh in North Carolina, Reading and Pittsburgh in Pennsylvania, and the Grand Rapids in Michigan- three of the seven battleground states.</p>

<p>As per the final national NBC News poll of the 2024 US presidential campaign, Kamala Harris is being supported by 49 per cent of registered voters same as Donald Trump with merely 2 per cent remaining undecided.</p>

<h3><strong>The process of US elections</strong></h3>

<p>The US Presidential Election takes place every four years on the first Tuesday in November. On Election Day, People in every state across the country go to their polling place and vote for their preferred candidate and their running mates.</p>

<p>In this election Democrat and Minnesota Governor Tim Walz and Republican Ohio Senator JD Vance are the running mates of Harris and Trump respectively.</p>

<p>When people cast their vote, they are actually voting for a group of people called electors. This is unlike the process of electing members of the US Congress, who are directly chosen by voters.</p>

<p>Except in the states of Maine and Nebraska, if a candidate receives the majority of the votes from the people of a state then the candidate will receive all electoral votes of that state.</p>

<p>The presidential nominee with the most electoral votes becomes the President of the United States.</p>

<p>The Electoral college is a process in which electors or representatives from each state, in number proportional to the state's population, cast their vote and determine who will be president.</p>

<p>Each state gets a certain number of electors based on the number of seats they have in the House of Representatives and Senate.</p>

<p>Washington DC gets three electors but other US territories don't get any. In total there are 538 electors (435 House of Representatives seats 100 Senate seats 3 for Washington DC).</p>

<p>A state's number of electors is determined by adding the number of US representatives plus two, the number of senators each state has.</p>

<p>Each elector casts one vote following the general election and the candidate who gets more than half (270) wins. After ballots have been cast, all votes go to a statewide tally.</p>

<p>Washington DC and 48 states use the winner-takes-all procedure where the election winner receives all the electors in that state.</p>

<p>Maine and Nebraska are the exceptions because they have a proportional system.</p>

<p>A candidate has to "win" at least 270 electors in order to become President. Five times in the history of the US, a candidate has won the popular vote but lost the Electoral College.</p>

<p>In 2016, Trump won the presidency over Hillary Clinton despite trailing by nearly three million votes nationwide.</p>

<h3><strong>Projections of polls as of 4 November</strong></h3>

<p>NBC News and Emerson College has projected a 49%-49% tie nationally</p>

<p>Ipsos projects a three-point lead (49%-46%) to Harris</p>

<p>AtlasIntel projects two-point lead (50%-48%) to Trump.</p>

<h3><strong>Voting for House and Senate also on November 5</strong></h3>

<p>The US will also on November 5 vote to hold elections for 13 governors and both houses of Congress. Congress consists of the House of Representatives or the lower chamber, where all 435 seats are up for election. Representatives are elected from small districts in each state</p>

<p>The Senate is the upper chamber where 34 seats are being contested with two representatives from each state. The entire House of Representatives will be re-elected, while one-third of the Senate will be renewed.</p>

<p>Currently, Republicans hold a slim 8-seat majority in the House of Representatives, with 221 seats compared to the Democrats' 214.</p>

<p>As per the Cook Political Report, Democrats are set to win in 205 districts, while Republicans have secured leads in 208 districts. There are 22 "swing" states which will lead to the outcome.</p>

<p>In the Senate, presently Democrats control 47 seats, with four independent senators collaborating with them. Republicans hold 49 seats.</p>

<p>If the number of Democrats and Republicans is equal in the Senate, the decisive vote goes to the Vice President of the United States, who serves as the President of the Senate.</p>

<p>According to CBS News, the outcome will be decided by the Senate elections in 11 states: Ohio, Michigan, Maryland, Nevada, Texas, Arizona, Florida, Montana, Pennsylvania, Wisconsin, West Virginia, and Nebraska. Of these, 5 are "swing" states</p>

<p>Inauguration Day takes place on January 20 at the steps of the US Capitol building in Washington DC.</p>

<p>First, the Vice President is sworn in, followed by the President.</p>

<p><strong>What are Battleground or Swing States?</strong></p>

<p>With most states leaning heavily towards one party or the other, the focus is usually on a dozen or so states, known as a battleground or swing states, where either of them could win.</p>

<p>This election there are 7 swing states -divided into two groups the Sun Belt and the Rust Belt also known as the 'Blue Wall' states</p>

<p>Sun Belt states comprise- Nevada (6), Arizona (11), North Carolina (16), Georgia(16)</p>

<p>Rust Belt states comprise- Wisconsin (10), Michigan (15), Pennsylvania (19)</p>

<p>Between November 6 to December 11, the states certify election results. On December 17 electors meet to cast their official votes. Congress convenes to count and confirm electoral votes on January 6, 2025, and the President elect is sworn in on January 20, 2025.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0co3a0fs_kamala-harris-donald-trump-harris-trump-reuters_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to polls, both the candidates are deadlocked in the presidential race. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-woman-who-stripped-at-university-not-seen-since-what-we-know-6941457]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Woman Who Stripped At University Not Seen Since. What We Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-woman-who-stripped-at-university-not-seen-since-what-we-know-6941457]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two days back, a young Iranian woman took the Internet by storm when she stripped to her underwear on a Tehran university campus, apparently to protest against the country's strict dress code for women.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two days back, a young Iranian woman took the Internet by storm when she stripped to her underwear on a Tehran university campus, apparently to protest against the country's strict dress code for women. Visuals showed her roaming on the campus of Islamic Azad University as others gaped in surprise. Soon after, security guards detained her and took her away. Her current location is not known.</p>

<p><strong>Who Is She?</strong></p>

<p>The identity of the woman, who has emerged as a feminist icon since the visuals went viral, is not known yet. While most posts on social media stress that her move to undress was a form of protest against the dress code, a university spokesperson has claimed that the police have found that she is suffering from a "mental disorder" and was under "severe mental pressure". The spokesperson, Amir Mahjob, said the woman had separated from her partner and was mother to two children.</p>

<p><strong>Claims, Counter Claims</strong></p>

<p>An Iranian student social media channel, Amir Kabir newsletter, reported that the woman stripped to her underwear after members of Basij, a volunteer paramilitary force, harassed her for not following the dress code properly. Amnesty said she was "violently arrested" after she protested the "abusive enforcement" of the dress code. Iran's Fars news agency said two security personnel had "calmly spoken" to her and asked her to follow the dress code. The university spokesperson said there was no face-off between the student and security guards. He claimed that the woman was filming her classmates without their consent and they had objected to this. The security was alerted because of the "violation of the privacy of the students and professors", he said.</p>

<p><strong>Where is she now?</strong></p>

<p>Visuals on social media show a group of people grabbing the woman and putting her into a car. The university spokesperson's remarks suggest she was taken to a police station. He insisted that her health condition was fine. With no clear answers regarding the woman's whereabouts, apprehensions have surfaced over her well-being. The Amir Kabir newsletter has alleged that she was beaten during the arrest, AFP reported. Amnesty International demanded her immediate release and said authorities must protect her from torture and other ill-treatment. The London-based rights group also demanded an independent probe into allegations of violence against her.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/r0q55hv8_mahsa-amini-iran-anti-hijab-protests-afp_625x300_24_September_22.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p><strong>The Mahsa Amini Backdrop</strong></p>

<p>The Iranian woman's move and her subsequent detention have played out against the growing resistance in Iran to the strict dress code for women. Earlier, in 2022, nationwide protests had erupted in the country after an Iranian-Kurdish woman, Mahsa Hamini, died after she was arrested for an alleged breach of the dress code. The protests saw women remove their headscarves and burn them. Thousands were arrested and over 500 protesters were killed as the authorities cracked down hard on the agitation.</p>

<p>Hossein Ronaghi, a prominent Iranian activist who was jailed during the protests, has now praised the "bravery" of the student seen in the video. "The symbolic and protest movement of the research science student is a revolt against government repression; A cry from the bottom of the heart against the oppression that has taken life from people, especially women," he said in a post on X.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tgs33eb8_iran-woman_625x300_04_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman was arrested soon after she stripped down to her underwear on the university campus]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>