<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 10:06:50 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-donald-trump-joe-biden-snipe-about-golf-youre-the-worst-youre-a-whiner-5986997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You're The Worst!"; "You're A Whiner": Trump, Biden Snipe About Golf]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-donald-trump-joe-biden-snipe-about-golf-youre-the-worst-youre-a-whiner-5986997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:53:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A bad tempered and unedifying US presidential debate between the two oldest candidates ever to run for office degenerated into a squabble over golfing prowess on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A bad tempered and unedifying US presidential debate between the two oldest candidates ever to run for office degenerated into a squabble over golfing prowess on Thursday.</p>

<p>The first head-to-head in an already painfully long campaign saw 81-year-old Joe Biden and his 78-year-old challenger Donald Trump trade insults and accusations for 90 minutes on prime time television.</p>

<p>There was name-calling: "You're the worst!" "No, YOU'RE the worst!"</p>

<p>There were accusations: "You're a whiner!"</p>

<p>And then they fought over their golf handicaps.</p>

<p>"He can't hit a ball 50 yards," said Trump, on one of the few occasions the two men directly addressed each other.</p>

<p>"He challenged me to a golf match. He can't hit a ball 50 yards."</p>

<p>Trump's own vitality was never in question, he boasted, insisting "I'm in as good a shape as I was years ago."</p>

<p>Not to be outdone over his putting prowess, Biden insisted he was game on the green.</p>

<p>"I'd be happy to have a driving contest," he said. "I got my handicap when I was the vice president down to a six."</p>

<p>Trump scoffed.</p>

<p>"A six handicap?" he snorted. "I've seen your swing. I know your swing."</p>

<p>The exchange came towards the end of the CNN-hosted debate, which had started without the handshake that is customary on such occasions and gone downhill from there.</p>

<p>The animosity between the two men was palpable, with Biden taking an early swing at a man he said had "the morals of an alley cat."</p>

<p>"How many billions of dollars do you owe in civil penalties for molesting a woman in public... for having sex with a porn star... while your wife was pregnant," he said, in reference to Trump's alleged dalliance with adult film actress Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>The Republican former president again denied adultery, but a New York jury found him guilty of 34 counts of falsifying business records to cover up hush-money payments to her.</p>

<p>Trump wasted few chances to hammer home his claim that Biden was "weak" and not "a leader."</p>

<p>He also took aim at Biden's perceived mental frailties, an issue that polls repeatedly show voters are concerned about.</p>

<p>"I took two tests, cognitive tests. I aced them, both of them, as you know, we made it public," he said.</p>

<p>"He took none. I'd like to see him take one, just one, a real easy one, like go through the first five questions. He couldn't do it."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/gj2f6vr_donald-trump-joe-biden-afp_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential Election: The exchange came towards the end of the debate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-2024-faltering-joe-biden-forceful-donald-trump-clash-in-presidential-debate-5986774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Faltering Biden, Forceful Trump Clash In Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-2024-faltering-joe-biden-forceful-donald-trump-clash-in-presidential-debate-5986774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:06:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A halting Joe Biden struggled Thursday to hold off a forceful offensive from Donald Trump as the two traded personal insults in the fiery first debate of a razor-close presidential race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A halting Joe Biden struggled Thursday to hold off a forceful offensive from Donald Trump as the two traded personal insults in the fiery first debate of a razor-close presidential race.</p>

<p>A bombastic Trump lashed out at his successor, calling him a failure on the economy and the world stage. Biden looked to hit back, but his delivery was hesitant as he spoke rapidly in a soft, trailing-off voice and stumbled on his words several times.</p>

<p>It was the first debate ever between a president and former president -- and each accused each other of being history's worst. Trump and Biden, who were each the oldest president when first elected, even accused each other of being childlike as they argued over their golf swings.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, and Trump, 78, did not shake hands as they walked to their podiums at the CNN headquarters in Atlanta. There was no live audience and their microphones muted as the other spoke -- rules agreed as they open a campaign in a deeply polarized country.</p>

<p>Biden, who was reported to have a cold, hit Trump with clearly rehearsed lines as he sought to remind millions of television viewers that Trump would be the first convicted felon in the White House.</p>

<p>"Think of all the civil penalties you have. How many billions of dollars do you owe in civil penalties for, for molesting a woman in public," Biden said, and "for having sex with a porn star on the night, while your wife was pregnant?"</p>

<p>"You have the morals of an alley cat," Biden said.</p>

<p>Trump, a veteran of rallies and reality television, spoke loudly as he rushed through a long list of complaints about Biden's record.</p>

<p>"It's a shame what's happened to our country in the last four years," Trump said "I'm friends with a lot of people. They cannot believe what happened to the United States of America. We're no longer respected."</p>

<p>Trump sought to seize on Biden's delivery, saying at one point, "I really don't know what he said at the end of that sentence. I don't think he knows what he said either."</p>

<p>Kate Bedingfield, a former Biden communications director, acknowledged that "it was a really disappointing debate performance" from the president.</p>

<p>"I don't think there is any other way to slice it," she told CNN after the debate.</p>

<p><strong>Attack on economic record</strong></p>

<p>Biden immediately attacked Trump when he was asked about stubborn inflation, saying that he inherited an economy in "freefall."</p>

<p>Trump said that he led "the greatest economy in the history of our country."</p>

<p>"We have never done so well. Everybody was amazed by other countries were copying us," he said.</p>

<p>Biden shot back: "Well, look, the greatest economy in the world? He's the only one who thinks that."</p>

<p>In one of the most personal attacks, Biden cited accounts that Trump had described soldiers who died in the Normandy landing as "suckers" and noted his own son Beau, who served in Iraq and later died of cancer.</p>

<p>"My son was not a loser, was not a sucker. You're the sucker. You're the loser," Biden said.</p>

<p>Trump denied the remarks and repeatedly accused Biden of not being coherent.</p>

<p><strong>Clash on world role</strong></p>

<p>On the world stage, Trump accused Biden -- who faces a backlash from parts of his Democratic base over his support for Israel -- of not helping Israel "finish the job" against Hamas.</p>

<p>"He doesn't want to do it. He's become like a Palestinian -- but they don't like him because he's a very bad Palestinian, he's a weak one," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump described Biden's withdrawal from Afghanistan as the "most embarrassing moment in the history of our country" and said it encouraged Russia to invade Ukraine.</p>

<p>Biden, however, noted that he was the first recent president who has not had soldiers at risk overseas.</p>

<p>Trump and Biden also locked horns over abortion and immigration, key issues for their respective bases.</p>

<p>Biden, attacking Trump for appointing justices to the Supreme Court who ended Roe vs. Wade, the decision that allowed abortion rights around the country, said: "It's been a terrible thing, what you've done."</p>

<p>Some Democratic supporters quickly voiced anxiety about Biden's performance.</p>

<p>At a watch party in San Francisco, Hazel Reitz said she would still vote for Biden but added: "I can't understand a word that he says. Isn't it sad?"</p>

<p>Julian Zelizer, a historian at Princeton University, said Biden's supporters will be "extremely concerned."</p>

<p>"Biden fueled the basic perception that has continued to overshadow him," he said.</p>

<p>One candidate not on the stage was Robert F. Kennedy Jr., the member of the storied political dynasty who is running an anti-establishment campaign but failed to meet CNN's standard of reaching 15 percent in four national polls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kennedy instead spent the 90 minutes of the Biden-Trump debate taking questions on a livestream.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tovvvtjg_joe-biden-donald-trump-afp_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential debate 2024: It was the first debate ever between a president and former president]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-vs-trump-live-joe-biden-vs-donald-trump-us-presidential-debate-who-said-what-5986333]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You're The Sucker": Biden vs Trump Presidential Debate - Who Said What]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-vs-trump-live-joe-biden-vs-donald-trump-us-presidential-debate-who-said-what-5986333]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 07:01:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and his Republican challenger, former President Donald Trump, clashed in their first debate of the 2024 presidential election cycle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and his Republican challenger, former President Donald Trump, clashed in their first debate of the 2024 presidential election cycle. With no live audience present, the two candidates did not greet each other with a customary handshake and stood just feet apart at their respective podiums, setting the stage for a night of pointed exchanges.</p>

<h3><strong>On Economy</strong></h3>

<p>President Biden wasted no time in criticising Trump's economic legacy during the latter's tenure in the Oval Office. "Donald Trump left me an economy that was in free fall," Biden stated. He then slammed Trump's handling of the COVID-19 pandemic. "He said things were fine during the pandemic- just inject a little bleach in your arm. I turned our country around," Biden claimed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In another sharp rebuke, Biden highlighted job losses under Trump's administration, stating, "Donald Trump is the only president besides Herbert Hoover who left office with fewer jobs than when he began. Donald Trump had the largest national debt of any US president over a four-year period."</p>

<h3><strong>On Foreign Policy</strong></h3>

<p>The debate took a heated turn when the topic shifted to foreign policy, specifically the withdrawal of US troops from Afghanistan. Trump seized the opportunity to criticise Biden's execution of the withdrawal, calling it "the most embarrassing day in the history of our country's life."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was getting out of Afghanistan, but we were getting out with dignity, with strength, with power" he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden responded by saying, "When he was president they were still killing people in Afghanistan. He didn't do anything about that."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Referring to allegations that Trump had labeled these soldiers as "suckers," Biden invoked the memory of his late son Beau, who served in Iraq and later succumbed to cancer.</p>

<p>"My son was not a loser, was not a sucker. You're the sucker. You're the loser," Biden declared.</p>

<h3><strong>On Immigration</strong></h3>

<p>Immigration was another hot-button issue during the debate. Biden accused Trump of exaggerating and spreading falsehoods about the state of the country's immigration crisis. "The idea that illegal immigrants are being welcomed in the United States is simply not true," Biden said. "There's no data to support what he said. Once again, he's exaggerating. He's lying."</p>

<p>Trump countered by claiming that Biden had failed to secure the southern US border, which he claimed had allowed scores of criminals into the country. "I call it Biden migrant crime," Trump declared.</p>

<h3><strong>On Abortion Rights</strong></h3>

<p>The debate took a heated turn when Biden attacked Trump for being an advocate for abortion ban. He called Trump's actions "a terrible thing" after the Republican boasted of nominating Supreme Court justices that helped overturn Roe v. Wade. "It has been a terrible thing, what you have done," Biden said, in one of his firmer critiques of his presidential predecessor.</p>

<p>Trump defended his position by arguing that returning the issue to the states was the right course of action and accused Biden of not supporting any limits on abortions.</p>

<p>Addressing the plight of women who have been raped and now face greater obstacles in accessing abortion services, Biden added, "It's just ridiculous, and they can do nothing about it. You have the morals of an alley cat."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/d1docuf_biden-trump-afp-_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden wasted no time in criticising Trump's economic legacy during the latter's tenure.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-trump-face-off-in-early-debate-with-age-ability-in-focus-5986145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden And Trump Face Off In Early Debate, With Age, Ability In Focus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-trump-face-off-in-early-debate-with-age-ability-in-focus-5986145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:03:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump take the stage on Thursday night for a debate that will offer voters a rare side-by-side look at the two oldest candidates ever to seek the U.S. presidency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump take the stage on Thursday night for a debate that will offer voters a rare side-by-side look at the two oldest candidates ever to seek the U.S. presidency.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, and Trump, 78, will be under pressure to display their command of issues and avoid verbal stumbles as they seek a breakout moment in a race that opinion polls show has been deadlocked for months.</p>

<p>The 90-minute televised debate, the first between a sitting president and a former one, will air at 9 p.m. ET (0100 GMT on Friday) on CNN and takes place far earlier than normal - more than four months before the Nov. 5 Election Day.</p>

<p>It comes at a moment of profound polarization and deep-seated anxiety among voters about the state of American politics. Two-thirds of voters said in a May Reuters/Ipsos poll that they were concerned violence could follow the election, nearly four years after a mob of Trump supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol.</p>

<p>Trump will take the stage as a felon who still faces a trio of criminal cases, including to his efforts to overturn the 2020 election. The former president, who continues to falsely claim that his defeat was the result of fraud and has suggested he will punish his political enemies if returned to power, will need to convince undecided voters that he does not pose a mortal threat to democracy, as Biden asserts.</p>

<p>Biden arrived in Atlanta on Thursday afternoon under intense pressure to deliver a forceful performance after months of Republican assertions his faculties have dulled with age.</p>

<p>Ahead of the debate, the Biden campaign released a video featuring former Trump aides saying they would not support him this time. "Take it from the people who know Donald Trump best - he is unfit to be president," Biden said on X.</p>

<p>Biden advisers say he will emphasize Trump's role in threatening abortion access, portray him as a danger to democratic norms and remind voters of Trump's often chaotic 2017-2021 term in office.</p>

<p>Trump will focus on the high levels of inflation and record numbers of migrants who have entered the country illegally under Biden's watch, and will also question his world leadership at a time of war in Gaza and Ukraine, Trump advisers said.</p>

<p>Trump, whose plane landed in Georgia about 3-1/2 hours before the debate, posted on social media what appeared to be advice from a former member of his administration about how to respond to attacks on his environmental record. The notes from former Environmental Protection Agency chief Andrew Wheeler urged Trump to say he will lower carbon dioxide emissions and encourage domestic energy production.</p>

<p>A campaign spokesman said the post was not a mistake. "The Biden team has been previewing their attacks -- albeit moronic attacks -- all week," spokesman Stephen Cheung said.</p>

<p><strong>DISLIKED DUO</strong></p>

<p>While national polls show a tied race, Biden has trailed Trump in polls of most battleground states and recently saw his financial edge erased after Trump was criminally convicted over trying to cover up hush money payments to porn star Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>"Biden needs a change in the status quo, and this debate is his best opportunity yet to do it," said Jacob Rubashkin, an elections analyst at the nonpartisan website Inside Elections.</p>

<p>Neither Biden nor Trump is popular and many Americans remain deeply ambivalent about their choices. About a fifth of voters say they have not picked a candidate, are leaning toward a third-party candidate or may sit the election out, the latest Reuters/Ipsos poll showed.</p>

<p>"They're horrible candidates," said Kathy Elder, a 59-year-old sales manager who voted for Trump in 2016 before switching to Biden in 2020.</p>

<p>Elder said she cringes whenever they speak – for different reasons.</p>

<p>When it comes to Biden, she said, "Can he speed this up and actually talk?" As for Trump, she said, "What the hell is going to come out of his mouth?"</p>

<p>Biden and Trump have made little effort to disguise their mutual dislike. During their first debate in 2020, Trump aggressively talked over Biden in a performance that turned off many voters.</p>

<p>CNN will attempt to avoid cross-talk by muting the candidates' microphones when it is not their turn. The debate will take place without an audience, and neither candidate is allowed to bring notes or props, though they will have a pen and paper.</p>

<p>Trump's niece Mary Trump, who has been critical of her uncle, will join Biden's campaign in its media spin room following the debate, a campaign official said.</p>

<p>The second and final debate in this year's campaign is scheduled for September.</p>

<p>See a Reuters photo slide show of previous debates.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/sd77uu9g_biden-trump-split-image_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden-Trump Debate: Biden and Trump have made little effort to disguise their mutual dislike.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-to-vote-today-for-new-president-following-ebrahim-raisis-death-in-helicopter-crash-5985970]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran To Vote Today For New President Following Ebrahim Raisi's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-to-vote-today-for-new-president-following-ebrahim-raisis-death-in-helicopter-crash-5985970]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 05:06:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iranians will vote for a new president on Friday following Ebrahim Raisi's death in a helicopter crash, choosing from a tightly controlled group of four candidates loyal to the supreme leader, at a time of growing public frustration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Iranians will vote for a new president on Friday following Ebrahim Raisi's death in a helicopter crash, choosing from a tightly controlled group of four candidates loyal to the supreme leader, at a time of growing public frustration.</p>

<p>While the election is unlikely to bring a major shift in the Islamic Republic's policies, the outcome could influence the succession to Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Iran's 85-year-old supreme leader, in power for three-and-a-half decades.</p>

<p>Khamenei has called for a "maximum" turnout to offset a legitimacy crisis fuelled by public discontent over economic hardship and curbs on political and social freedoms.</p>

<p>Voter turnout has plunged over the past four years, with a mostly young population chafing at political and social restrictions.</p>

<p>Polls open at 8:00 am local time (0430 GMT) and close at 6:00 pm (1430 pm GMT), but are usually extended until as late as midnight. As ballots are counted manually, the final result is expected to be announced only in two days although initial figures may come out sooner.</p>

<p>If no candidate wins at least 50 percent plus one vote from all ballots cast including blank votes, a run-off round between the top two candidates is held on the first Friday after the election result is declared.</p>

<p>Three of the candidates are hardliners and one a low-profile comparative moderate, backed by the reformist faction that has largely been sidelined in Iran in recent years.</p>

<p>Critics of Iran's clerical rule say the low and declining turnout of recent elections shows the system's legitimacy has eroded. Just 48% of voters participated in the 2021 election that brought Raisi to power, and turnout hit a record low of 41% in a parliamentary election three months ago.</p>

<p>The election now coincides with escalating regional tensions due to war between Israel and Iranian allies Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon, as well as increased Western pressure on Iran over its fast-advancing nuclear programme.</p>

<p>The next president is not expected to produce any major policy shift on Iran's nuclear programme or support for militia groups across the Middle East, since Khamenei calls all the shots on top state matters. However, the president runs the government day-to-day and can influence the tone of Iran's foreign and domestic policy.</p>

<p>A hardline watchdog body made up of six clerics and six jurists aligned with Khamenei vets candidates. It approved just six candidates from an initial pool of 80. Two hardline candidates subsequently dropped out.</p>

<p>Prominent among the remaining hardliners are Mohammad Baqer Qalibaf, parliament speaker and former commander of the powerful Revolutionary Guards, and Saeed Jalili, a former nuclear negotiator who served for four years in Khamenei's office.</p>

<p>The sole comparative moderate, Massoud Pezeshkian, is faithful to the country's theocratic rule but advocates detente with the West, economic reform, social liberalisation and political pluralism.</p>

<p>His chances hinge on reviving the enthusiasm of reform-minded voters who have largely stayed away from the polls for the last four years after previous pragmatist presidents achieved little change. He could also benefit from his rivals' failure to consolidate the hardline vote.</p>

<p>All four candidates have vowed to revive the flagging economy, beset by mismanagement, state corruption and sanctions reimposed since 2018 after the U.S. ditched Tehran's 2015 nuclear pact with six world powers.</p>

<p>The hashtag #ElectionCircus has been widely posted on social media platform X by Iranians in the past few weeks, with some activists at home and abroad calling for an election boycott, arguing that a high turnout would legitimise the Islamic Republic.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/pcm37tm8_iran-vote_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran Vote: Polls open at 8:00 am local time (0430 GMT) and close at 6:00 pm (1430 pm GMT).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-leaders-nominate-von-der-leyen-to-head-commission-for-2nd-term-5985915]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EU Leaders Nominate Von Der Leyen To Head Commission For 2nd Term]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-leaders-nominate-von-der-leyen-to-head-commission-for-2nd-term-5985915]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 04:46:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[European Union leaders agreed on Friday to nominate Ursula von der Leyen of Germany for a second five-year term as president of the European Commission, the EU's powerful executive body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>European Union leaders agreed on Friday to nominate Ursula von der Leyen of Germany for a second five-year term as president of the European Commission, the EU's powerful executive body.</p>

<p>At a summit in Brussels, the bloc's 27 national leaders also picked former Portuguese premier Antonio Costa as the future chair of their European Council meetings and selected Estonian Prime Minister Kaja Kallas as the next EU foreign policy chief.</p>

<p>The leadership package represents continuity for the 27-member bloc, with centrist pro-EU factions keeping hold of top posts despite a far-right surge in elections to the European Parliament earlier this month.</p>

<p>The deal was announced by the current European Council president, Charles Michel, on social media.</p>

<p>The trio won broad backing from leaders but diplomats said right-wing Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni abstained from the vote on von der Leyen and voted against Costa and Kallas.</p>

<p>Von der Leyen's nomination still needs approval from the European Parliament in a secret ballot - widely seen as a trickier proposition than her endorsement by EU leaders.</p>

<p>At the summit, the EU also signed a security agreement with Ukraine, debated how to bolster EU defences against Russia and agreed bloc's strategic priorities for the next five years.</p>

<p>The security deal underlines EU support for Kyiv fighting off Moscow's invasion for a third year, despite gains by the far-right in European elections, uncertainty created by French snap elections and the U.S. presidential vote in November.</p>

<p>The agreement lays out the EU's commitments to help Ukraine in nine areas of security policy - including arms deliveries, military training, defence industry cooperation and demining.</p>

<p>"These commitments will help Ukraine defend itself, resist destabilisation, and deter future acts of aggression - more concrete proof of the EU's unshakeable resolve to support Ukraine for the long haul," Michel said.</p>

<p>The leaders will reiterate their pledge to support Ukraine as long as it takes, stressing that "Russia must not prevail" and that Ukraine must get back the land annexed by Moscow.</p>

<p><strong>DEFENCE DEBATE</strong></p>

<p>The war in Ukraine laid bare the EU's lack of preparedness for a conflict as the bloc struggles to supply Kyiv with enough weapons against Russia, prompting calls for more EU coordination of defence systems and investment in defence industries.</p>

<p>Diplomats said von der Leyen told the summit that between 1999 and 2021, the EU increased defence spending by 20%, China by 600% and Russia by 300%, even before Moscow's massive rise in military spending after its invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</p>

<p>According to diplomats, von der Leyen told leaders the EU needed to invest 500 billion euros ($535.30 billion) in defence over the next 10 years. Financing options ranged from national contributions, dedicated revenue streams - called the EU's own resources - and joint borrowing, von der Leyen said.</p>

<p>Investment in defence is part of the EU's "strategic agenda" that the leaders aim to agree before dinner on Thursday - a document that tells EU institutions what European governments want them to focus on during their 2024-2029 term.</p>

<p>Apart from defence, the agenda calls for a more competitive EU to withstand economic pressure from China and the United States and for preparing the bloc for enlargement that would include Ukraine, Moldova and the Western Balkans.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/ogonc1v_ursula-von-der-leyen_625x300_26_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Von der Leyen's nomination still needs approval from the European Parliament in a secret ballot.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-tells-clients-russian-hackers-viewed-emails-report-5985878]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Tells Clients Russian Hackers Viewed Emails: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-tells-clients-russian-hackers-viewed-emails-report-5985878]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 04:34:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp is informing some of its customers that a Russian state-sponsored hacking group breached its internal systems and accessed their emails, Bloomberg News reported on Thursday, citing a company spokesperson.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Corp is informing some of its customers that a Russian state-sponsored hacking group breached its internal systems and accessed their emails, Bloomberg News reported on Thursday, citing a company spokesperson.</p>

<p>The technology giant is also providing previously notified clients with details of which data was taken, the report said.</p>

<p>Microsoft did not immediately respond to a request emailed by Reuters for comment and calls to spokespersons went unanswered.</p>

<p>The company had said in January, too, that a Russian state-sponsored group had hacked into its corporate systems and stolen some emails and documents from staff accounts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/0qs8jbe8_microsoft_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company had said in January, too, that a Russian hackers had hacked into its corporate systems.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-rockets-at-israeli-base-says-4-fighters-killed-5985469]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Fires Rockets At Israeli Base, Says 4 Fighters Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-rockets-at-israeli-base-says-4-fighters-killed-5985469]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 02:19:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah said it fired "dozens" of rockets Thursday at a military base in northern Israel in retaliation for Israeli strikes on Lebanon, announcing four of its fighters had been killed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah said it fired "dozens" of rockets Thursday at a military base in northern Israel in retaliation for Israeli strikes on Lebanon, announcing four of its fighters had been killed.</p>

<p>Fears of all-out war between Israel and Hezbollah have risen in recent weeks as threats have intensified between the sides, which have traded regular cross-border fire since Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel sparked war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Hamas ally Hezbollah said that "in response to the enemy attacks that targeted the city of Nabatiyeh and village of Sohmor", its fighters bombed "the main air and missile defence base of the (Israeli) northern area command... with dozens of Katyusha rockets".</p>

<p>It said in separate statements that four of its fighters, one from eastern Lebanon's Sohmor, had been killed, and claimed two other attacks on Israeli troops and positions, including one with drones.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement that "approximately 35 launches were identified crossing from Lebanon".</p>

<p>Air defences "successfully intercepted most of the launches. No injuries were reported," it added.</p>

<p>It said air strikes "eliminated" three Hezbollah operatives, one in the Sohmor area and two in the country's south.</p>

<p>The military also said that "two UAVs (drones) that were identified crossing from Lebanon fell" in northern Israel, reporting no injuries.</p>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency reported Israeli attacks in several areas of south Lebanon on Thursday, and said a strike a day earlier in Nabatiyeh wounded "more than 20" people when a two-storey building was targeted.</p>

<p>Fears have grown the Gaza war could become a regional conflagration if the Israel-Hezbollah conflict, which so far has been largely limited to the border area, expands.</p>

<p>France's foreign ministry said Thursday that Paris was "extremely concerned" about the fighting, calling "all sides to exercise the greatest restraint".</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said during a visit to Washington on Wednesday that his country did not want war in Lebanon, but could send it back to the "Stone Age" if diplomacy failed.</p>

<p>Amid Western diplomatic efforts to dial down tensions in recent months, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock on Tuesday visited Beirut and cautioned that "miscalculation" could trigger all-out war, also urging "extreme restraint".</p>

<p>The violence has killed 485 people in Lebanon, most of them fighters but also including 94 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, at least 15 soldiers and 11 civilians have been killed, according to authorities.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t0borbr4_hezbollah_625x300_28_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On the Israeli side, at least 15 soldiers and 11 civilians have been killed, according to authorities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-war-israeli-anti-government-protesters-march-on-benjamin-netanyahus-home-5985376]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid War, Israeli Anti-Government Protesters March On Netanyahu's Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-war-israeli-anti-government-protesters-march-on-benjamin-netanyahus-home-5985376]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 01:53:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anti-government protesters gathered in Jerusalem on Thursday and converged on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's home, lighting a bonfire on the street outside and calling for his resignation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anti-government protesters gathered in Jerusalem on Thursday and converged on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's home, lighting a bonfire on the street outside and calling for his resignation.</p>

<p>"We've been abandoned - Elections now!" read one sign that rose above the crowd. Demonstrators yelled through megaphones, waved flags and banged on snare drums while police officers stood at barricades.</p>

<p>Such demonstrations have grown more frequent as the war against Hamas in Gaza rages on and fighting with Hezbollah in Lebanon threatens to escalate, but they have not reached the fever pitch of a year ago when Netanyahu's government tried to overhaul Israel's justice system.</p>

<p>Many in the crowd, which appeared to number in the thousands, also chanted their support for reaching a deal to free some 120 Israeli hostages being held by Palestinian Islamist group Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>As the sun began to set, protesters blocked traffic and lit a large bonfire on the central Jerusalem street. But there were no reports of major scuffles and police did not use a water cannon to control the crowd, as they have during more rowdy demonstrations.</p>

<p>The protest movement has yet to change the political landscape, and Netanyahu still controls a stable majority in parliament.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/588mi5m8_israel-anti-government-protest_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anti-government protesters gathered in Jerusalem on Thursday and called for Netanyahu's resignation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-arrives-in-georgia-for-presidential-debate-with-donald-trump-5985253]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Trump In Atlanta Ahead Of High-Stakes Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-arrives-in-georgia-for-presidential-debate-with-donald-trump-5985253]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 01:18:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden arrived in Georgia on Thursday for his first debate of the 2024 election cycle with his predecessor Donald Trump -- a high-stakes event for both candidates.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden and Donald Trump square off Thursday in a crucial US presidential debate that carries enormous stakes for both candidates as they battle for any advantage in their tight race for the White House.</p>

<p>Millions of Americans will tune in to the highly anticipated clash -- the opening salvo in what promises to be a bruising summer of campaigning, in a deeply polarized country still scarred by the chaos and violence of the 2020 election.</p>

<p>With only two debates this election cycle and national polls showing the pair locked in the tightest of contests, Thursday's event at CNN headquarters in Atlanta -- starting at 9:00 pm (0100 GMT Friday) -- takes on heightened significance.</p>

<p>For many voters, the choice between the 81-year-old Biden, the oldest ever incumbent, and the 78-year-old Trump, now a convicted felon, is an uninspiring one -- a dynamic both candidates need to counter.</p>

<p>For Trump, an instinctive political pugilist, the challenge will be to rein in the aggressive tendencies he unleashed -- to his detriment -- in their first chaotic debate four years ago.</p>

<p>The Democratic president will be desperate to avoid any major gaffes that could underline concerns about his age.</p>

<p>He also will focus on his key campaign message that Trump poses an existential threat to US democracy.</p>

<p>Biden arrived in Georgia about six hours before the on-air showdown, and took the opportunity to greet supporters outside his hotel in Atlanta.</p>

<p>His challenger touched down later aboard his private jet, pumping his fist to supporters on the tarmac before he ducked into a waiting vehicle.</p>

<p>There is certainly no love lost between the two candidates, and both sides have agreed to a series of debate rules aimed at minimizing the prospect of a shouting match.</p>

<p>There will be no studio audience, depriving them of the momentum that comes from ginning up supporters, and microphones will cut out when a candidate's speaking time is over.</p>

<p>To coincide with the debate, both camps unleashed a series of fresh attack ads, with Trump's team taking out TV spots accusing Biden of mismanaging the economy and encouraging illegal immigration.</p>

<p>In a morning post on his Truth Social platform, Trump argued that Biden was the real threat to democracy, "and a threat to the survival and existence of our country itself."</p>

<p>The Democratic Party, meanwhile, paid for five massive billboards in Atlanta trolling Trump over his legal woes.</p>

<p>"Donald, welcome to Atlanta for the first time since becoming a convicted felon. Congrats – or whatever..." the signs said.</p>

<p><strong>- Neck-and-neck in polls -</strong></p>

<p>Trump enjoys a slight advantage in the all-important swing states, but the overall polling looks extremely close in an election likely to be decided by a few photo finishes in a handful of battlegrounds.</p>

<p>The latest Quinnipiac University poll shows Trump edging ahead of Biden nationally, 49 percent to 45 percent.</p>

<p>The rivals both step onstage for the 90-minute debate seeking to allay fears about serious political liabilities.</p>

<p>Biden faces the most concern about his mental sharpness, with voters much more likely to bring up his age than Trump's, despite the Republican being just three years younger.</p>

<p>Ahead of the debate, both Trump and Biden have had missteps, stumbling over words or appearing muddled.</p>

<p>Trump is also engulfed in controversy over his inflammatory rhetoric, his recent conviction on 34 counts of falsifying business records, and fears he would weaponize the presidency to settle personal scores.</p>

<p><strong>- Fine-tuning or freewheeling -</strong></p>

<p>Biden has spent the last week off the radar at the Camp David retreat near Washington, fine-tuning his attack lines in mock debates under real TV lighting.</p>

<p>Trump's preparation has been more relaxed, eschewing dress rehearsals in favor of informal policy roundtables and workshopping debate strategy with rally crowds.</p>

<p>Aides have encouraged him to focus on his perceived strength on the economy and crime, while Biden will seek to paint Trump as unhinged and unfit for office.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign has repeatedly characterized Biden as feeble and incompetent, but changed tack following warnings that setting low expectations for the Democratic president would only help him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/658hp91_biden-trump_625x300_27_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden arrived in Georgia on Thursday for his first debate with Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-live-joe-biden-and-donald-trump-square-off-in-critical-us-presidential-debate-5985003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Highlights: Trump vs Biden Over Economy, Democracy And Age In US Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-live-joe-biden-and-donald-trump-square-off-in-critical-us-presidential-debate-5985003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:03:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trump-Biden Debate: US President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump faced off in the first presidential debate that offered voters a rare side-by-side look at the two oldest candidates ever to seek the US presidency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump faced off in the first presidential debate that offered voters a rare side-by-side look at the two oldest candidates ever to seek the US presidency.</p>

<p>The two rivals did not shake hands as they took their positions at podiums just feet apart in a studio with no live audience. The leaders battled over economic issues, foreign policy and international crises, the country's immigration crisis, and the state of American democracy.</p>

<p>The debate, which was conducted four months ahead of the US Presidential polls, was hosted by the CNN and broadcasted by all networks across US.&nbsp;There is no studio audience for the 90-minute debate .</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the Highlights on Trump-Biden US Presidential debate:</strong><br />
&nbsp;</h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/rn11s9jo_joe-biden-donald-trump-reuters_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump-Biden Debate: The debate is being conducted four months ahead of US Presidential polls (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-day-one-of-my-new-term-donald-trumps-plan-for-presidency-5984850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["On Day One Of My New Term...": Donald Trump's Plan For Presidency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-day-one-of-my-new-term-donald-trumps-plan-for-presidency-5984850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:35:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mass expulsions? Political revenge? World peace? A new golden age? As Donald Trump vies for another term in the White House, America is abuzz with speculation over how life might look with the ex-president back at the helm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Mass expulsions? Political revenge? World peace? A new golden age? As Donald Trump vies for another term in the White House, America is abuzz with speculation over how life might look with the ex-president back at the helm.</p>

<p>In a series of interviews and campaign rallies, the Republican has offered some clues.</p>

<p>Here are Trump's plans for the United States and the world, as set out by the candidate himself.</p>

<p><strong>Mass deportations</strong></p>

<p>President Joe Biden's rival in November's election has pledged to launch the biggest deportation operation of illegal migrants in US history on his first day in office.</p>

<p>"We're going to get them out as fast as we can," he has said, accusing undocumented migrants of "poisoning the blood of our country."</p>

<p>The 78-year-old, known for his unfinished border wall project, has said he would be happy to "use the military" as part of the effort and would open detention camps to process targets for expulsion.</p>

<p>"On day one of my new term in office, I will sign an executive order making clear to federal agencies that under the correct interpretation of the law, going forward the future children of illegal aliens will not receive automatic US citizenship," he said in a campaign video.</p>

<p>He has confirmed he also plans to reinstate his ban on entries from several Muslim-majority countries, as a means of "keeping terrorists the hell out of our country."</p>

<p><strong>Ukraine, NATO</strong></p>

<p>Trump has been saying for months he could end the war in Ukraine in "24 hours," without explaining how.</p>

<p>Critics suggest his plan would involve pressuring Kyiv to cede territory illegally occupied by Russia in both 2014 and 2022.</p>

<p>"I will have that settled prior to taking the White House," he told a rally in the midwestern city of Detroit recently. "As president-elect, I will have that settled."</p>

<p>The ex-president is highly critical of Washington's shipments of weapons worth billions of dollars to Kyiv, and of the funding requests from Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky.</p>

<p>"It never stops", he told the Michigan crowd.</p>

<p>Asked in a town hall with Fox News whether he would remain committed to NATO during a second term, he replied: "Depends if they treat us properly."</p>

<p><strong>Tariffs v. tax cuts</strong></p>

<p>Trump envisages tariffs of "more than 10 percent" on all imports.</p>

<p>US companies -- and eventually their customers -- pay for import tariffs, not the companies exporting the goods.</p>

<p>Trump insists that the revenue collected will finance a "middle class, upper class, lower class, business class big tax cut."</p>

<p>Having waged a fierce trade war with China during his first term, he also plans to revoke the Asian giant's "most favored nation" status, granted to promote trade.</p>

<p>Trump claims he will "stop inflation by stopping the invasion," arguing that his immigration crackdown will reduce housing costs and other expenses.</p>

<p><strong>Abortion ambiguity</strong></p>

<p>Trump never misses an opportunity to point out that it is partly thanks to him -- and his three conservative Supreme Court appointments -- that abortion rights have been considerably weakened in the United States.</p>

<p>But he is more ambiguous about the future of access to reproductive health care.</p>

<p>Insisting it should be an issue for the individual states, the Republican has balked at pushing a nationwide abortion ban, a commitment that would win him support from the religious right.</p>

<p>"You must follow your heart on this issue but remember, you must also win elections," he said in April.</p>

<p><strong>'Drill, baby, drill!'</strong></p>

<p>Trump slammed the door on the 2015 Paris climate accords during his first term.</p>

<p>If reelected, he said at a rally earlier this month, he "will stop Biden's wasteful spending and rapidly terminate the green new scam" -- a reference to the funding committed by his successor to mitigating climate change.</p>

<p>"I will repeal crooked Joe Biden's insane electric vehicle mandate and we will 'drill, baby, drill,'" Trump told supporters in Wisconsin, using an old Republican slogan.</p>

<p>"Energy costs will come down very quickly," he vowed. "In many cases we'll be cutting your energy costs in half."</p>

<p><strong>Going after Biden</strong></p>

<p>Trump, who was convicted in May of felony business fraud and faces three further indictments, has baselessly and repeatedly claimed his various prosecutions are a political witch hunt by Democrats.</p>

<p>The Republican has pledged to "appoint a real special 'prosecutor' to go after the most corrupt president in the history of the USA, Joe Biden."</p>

<p>No investigation has produced evidence of any wrongdoing by Biden.</p>

<p>He also said he was "absolutely" ready to pardon all the Trump supporters convicted of storming the US Capitol in Washington to prevent Congress from certifying the Republican's 2020 presidential election defeat to Biden.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/dmc10gkg_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has been saying for months he could end the war in Ukraine in "24 hours" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-us-ex-president-on-a-quest-for-revenge-5984766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump: US' Ex-President On A Quest For Revenge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-us-ex-president-on-a-quest-for-revenge-5984766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:21:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four months before US President Joe Biden and his predecessor Donald Trump face off at the polls, they will wage political battle Thursday in the first televised debate of the 2024 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four months before US President Joe Biden and his predecessor Donald Trump face off at the polls, they will wage political battle Thursday in the first televised debate of the 2024 election.</p>

<p>The candidates are polling neck and neck ahead of the November 5 vote as they attempt to woo any Americans still fine-tuning their decision.</p>

<p>Here are some of the major biographical details to know about Trump, a Republican whose supporters remain wildly devoted despite his multiple criminal charges and the first felony conviction against a former president.</p>

<p><strong>Political experience</strong></p>

<p>The bombastic 78-year-old billionaire was a political novice when he successfully ran for president in 2016 against former secretary of state Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>Until that point, Trump had never been up for election in any race involving a popular vote.</p>

<p>However, he had often repeated that he might run for the White House, an assertion that was widely considered a publicity stunt.</p>

<p><strong>Family and religion</strong></p>

<p>Trump was born in 1946 to a wealthy New York family. Contrary to legend, he is not a self-made man, but rather followed in the footsteps of his father, who built a family empire constructing buildings in the area.</p>

<p>Trump was handed the reins to the family business in the 1970s, and later became a fixture in US households via his reality TV show "The Apprentice," which first aired in 2004.</p>

<p>The father of five children via three different wives is hardly a model of Christian piety, yet he has deftly wooed America's evangelical right.</p>

<p>Constantly praising family and religious values, Trump landed conservative Christians a resounding victory with the appointment of Supreme Court justices who helped overturn the national right to an abortion.</p>

<p><strong>Wealth</strong></p>

<p>Trump's finances have been the subject of much speculation over the years. However a judge ruled earlier this year that Trump and his company had unlawfully inflated his wealth and manipulated the value of properties to obtain favorable bank loans or insurance terms.</p>

<p>That said, Trump remains exceedingly rich: He is worth no less than several billion dollars according to Forbes magazine, thanks to his real estate empire and the Trump Media and Technology Group, which includes his social media platform Truth Social.</p>

<p><strong>Vibe</strong></p>

<p>Pugnacious, angry and a populist, Trump stunned the world when he was elected president in 2016.</p>

<p>Worshiped by supporters, he is considered by detractors to be a danger to American democracy and to the country's traditional international alliances.</p>

<p>The former president is combatively thin-skinned, yet relentlessly mocks his political rivals with rhetoric that has become increasingly belligerent as the election approaches.</p>

<p>He labels his opponents "fascists," while saying immigrants are "poisoning the blood of our country."</p>

<p>And he still claims, falsely, to have won the 2020 election.</p>

<p><strong>Legal Troubles</strong></p>

<p>Trump's life is awash with substantial legal allegations, convictions and rulings.</p>

<p>Most recently in May he was convicted in New York on 34 felony counts of falsifying business records to hide a hush money payment to porn star Stormy Daniels during the heat of the 2016 election.</p>

<p>That made Trump the first ever former US president convicted of a felony. He is due for sentencing on July 11.</p>

<p>Trump faces three other pending criminal cases, including charges related to his unprecedented attempts to overturn his 2020 election loss to Biden, both at the federal level and in Georgia -- where he asked officials to "find" enough votes to reverse Biden's victory in the state.</p>

<p>He is additionally accused of illegally retaining secret nuclear and defense documents after leaving the White House at his Florida estate.</p>

<p>Apart from the criminal cases, Trump was found liable in a civil case for sexually abusing former magazine columnist E. Jean Carroll in 1996 and defaming her, with a judge ordering him to pay her $88 million.</p>

<p>He was also fined $355 million plus interest by a New York judge for manipulating the value of properties to obtain favorable loans.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/7un4ctq8_donald-trump_625x300_31_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump was born in 1946 to a wealthy New York family (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-donald-trump-offer-contrasting-global-visions-of-us-5984765]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden, Donald Trump Offer Contrasting Global Visions Of US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-donald-trump-offer-contrasting-global-visions-of-us-5984765]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:21:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ahead of their first presidential debate, Joe Biden and Donald Trump are offering sharply different visions of the US role in the world, both in style and substance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of their first presidential debate, Joe Biden and Donald Trump are offering sharply different visions of the US role in the world, both in style and substance.</p>

<p>The rare matchup between a current and former president puts their stark contrasts on display. Trump during his 2017-2021 presidency vowed to put "America First," with a combative and often isolationist view of the world, while Biden took office in 2021 vowing "America is Back," rekindling relationships with allies.</p>

<p>The two presidents have some core beliefs in common. Both were adamant on pulling US troops out of Afghanistan, seeing America's longest war as not worth the cost to American blood and treasure.</p>

<p>But the two criticized each other on the implementation, in line with their strong public disagreements on most issues.</p>

<p><strong>Russia and Ukraine</strong></p>

<p>Biden has spearheaded international efforts to support Ukraine after Russia invaded the neighboring country -- in defiance of his direct warnings -- in February 2022.</p>

<p>With Biden's encouragement, the US Congress has approved $175 billion in support for Ukraine, including weapons and budgetary support. Biden paid a surprise visit to Kyiv last year and has branded Russian President Vladimir Putin a "brutal tyrant."</p>

<p>Trump has voiced skepticism over aid to Ukraine, saying he expects Russia to win, and his supporters in Congress held up the last military package to Kyiv for months.</p>

<p>Trump has boasted of quickly ending the war. His advisors have spoken of pushing a ceasefire, perhaps by warning Ukraine that aid will dry up unless it compromises on its borders -- a suggestion adamantly rejected by Biden, who says only Ukraine should determine its future.</p>

<p>Trump has previously voiced admiration for Putin and was impeached as president for the first time over delaying military aid to Ukraine as he pressed President Volodymyr Zelensky to dig up dirt on Biden's family.</p>

<p><strong>Middle East</strong></p>

<p>Trump during his presidency was a staunch supporter of Israel, taking landmark steps such as moving the US embassy to Jerusalem, which Palestinians also want as their future capital.</p>

<p>Trump has charged that Biden has "abandoned" Israel. Biden, however, has long cast himself as a defender of Israel and has come under fire from the left of his Democratic Party over his support, including weapons and vetoes at the UN Security Council.</p>

<p>Biden has nonetheless clashed with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu over Palestinian civilian casualties and froze one weapons shipment that included heavy 2,000-pound bombs.</p>

<p>While Trump would be expected to be more hawkish, he has also criticized Netanyahu, faulting him for not preventing the October 7 Hamas attack, in a bitterness tied to Netanyahu's prompt recognition of Biden's 2020 election victory.</p>

<p>Trump and his son-in-law, Jared Kushner, late in his term reached the "Abraham Accords" in which the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain and Morocco normalized ties with Israel -- the first new Arab recognition in decades.</p>

<p>Biden's top diplomat, Antony Blinken, has claimed progress on sealing an even greater prize -- Saudi Arabia. But the Biden administration faults Trump for backing Netanyahu in sidestepping the Palestinian issue in the push for Arab recognition of Israel.</p>

<p>Biden has also accused Trump of worsening Iran's nuclear program by withdrawing from a deal negotiated under former president Barack Obama.</p>

<p>Trump counters that the accord was not strong enough, and Biden largely gave up on reviving it.</p>

<p><strong>China, N.Korea and allies</strong></p>

<p>Both Trump and Biden have described China as the top long-term rival of the United States and have worked to counter Beijing, but they have set different tones.</p>

<p>Biden in some areas has taken tougher action against China, including imposing a sweeping ban on semiconductor exports, but has also spoken of keeping competition from veering into conflict and cooperating in select areas such as climate change. Biden held a cordial summit last year with President Xi Jinping.</p>

<p>Trump has described China as an enemy and vowed to ramp up tariffs sharply. But Trump has also insisted that Xi is a "good friend."</p>

<p>Trump has often praised authoritarian leaders, saying he "fell in love" with North Korean strongman Kim Jong Un. Trump met Kim three times -- unusually personal diplomacy that reduced tension but brought no lasting agreement.</p>

<p>Trump in turn has lashed out at Western democratic allies that he sees as benefiting unfairly from the United States.</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, he suggested he would encourage Russia to "do whatever the hell they want" if NATO allies do not "pay (their) bills" -- a reference to military spending.</p>

<p>Words that could not be more different than those of Deputy Secretary of State Kurt Campbell: "If you ask me what would be the 'Biden Doctrine,' it would be stepping up partnerships with allies and friends.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/svuvbrhc_trump-biden-split-reuters_625x300_06_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two presidents have some core beliefs in common. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-us-president-who-is-seeking-a-second-term-at-81-5984712]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden - US President Who Is Seeking A Second Term At 81]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-us-president-who-is-seeking-a-second-term-at-81-5984712]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:12:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On June 27 Americans will tune in to the first debate of the 2024 US election -- a highly anticipated showdown between President Joe Biden and his predecessor Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On June 27 Americans will tune in to the first debate of the 2024 US election -- a highly anticipated showdown between President Joe Biden and his predecessor Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The televised face-off comes just four months ahead of the November vote, with the candidates running neck and neck in the polls, each vying for a second term.</p>

<p>Here are some of the major biographical details to know about Biden, a Democrat and Washington veteran, ahead of Thursday's big event.</p>

<p><strong>- Political experience -</strong></p>

<p>Mr Biden is no stranger to Washington. The 81-year-old longtime politician served as vice president under Barack Obama from 2009 to 2017.</p>

<p>Before that, he spent 36 years in the Senate. He was first elected by Delaware voters at age 29, making him one of the youngest senators ever.</p>

<p><strong>- Family and religion -</strong></p>

<p>Mr Biden was born in Scranton, Pennsylvania in 1942 and is the eldest of four children. The Democrat often alludes to his Irish-American, middle-class upbringing.</p>

<p>His father worked a number of different jobs, and while his family was not poor, they did experience financial setbacks.</p>

<p>On the religion front, Mr Biden is a devout Catholic who attends mass regularly, but he nonetheless supports abortion rights.</p>

<p>A family man, Mr Biden has been quick to proclaim his love and support for his son Hunter, who was recently convicted on charges stemming from his purchase of a handgun while addicted to crack cocaine.</p>

<p>The president is sometimes referred to as the "mourner-in-chief" for appearing empathetic with constituents during times of tragedy.</p>

<p>His own life has been marked by multiple sorrows. He lost his first wife Neilia and their young daughter Naomi in a car accident in 1972. Hunter along with Mr Biden's other son Beau were also injured in that accident.</p>

<p>Beau then died of cancer in 2015.</p>

<p>Mr Biden has been married to First Lady Jill Biden since 1977. In addition to raising Beau and Hunter, the couple has a daughter, Ashley.</p>

<p><strong>- Wealth -</strong></p>

<p>While Mr Biden is not a billionaire like his Republican rival Trump, he is still rich.</p>

<p>Biden's fortunes are estimated at around $10 million, largely thanks to two homes the family owns in Delaware, according to Forbes magazine.</p>

<p><strong>- Vibe -</strong></p>

<p>Mr Biden is not a profound orator nor does he draw an ecstatic response from his supporters like Trump. Yet he is known for a certain stubborn determination, and cultivates an image of empathy.</p>

<p>The latter trait has recently been tainted, however, by US support for Israel in the war in Gaza, particularly among younger and Arab-Americans.</p>

<p>Mr Biden's advanced years and his increasingly stiff gait have played into Republican taunting and public concern about his age.</p>

<p><strong>- Legal woes -</strong></p>

<p>Mr Biden was cleared early this year of any wrongdoing after keeping classified documents at his home in Wilmington, Delaware.</p>

<p>However in a shock for his campaign, a report from the special counsel overseeing the matter said Biden came across as a "well-meaning, elderly man with a poor memory," a line that Democrats dismissed but Republicans pounced on.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/f6nmtplg_joe-biden-file-afp_625x300_17_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden spent 36 years in the Senate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-mic-cuts-no-audience-no-fact-checking-how-biden-trump-debate-will-work-5984709]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mic Cuts, No Audience, No Fact-Checking: How Biden-Trump Debate Will Work]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-mic-cuts-no-audience-no-fact-checking-how-biden-trump-debate-will-work-5984709]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:11:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There will be no studio audience, depriving candidates of the momentum that comes from ginning up supporters. Microphones will cut out when a candidate's speaking time is over. Thursday night's presidential debate will not be business as usual.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There will be no studio audience, depriving candidates of the momentum that comes from ginning up supporters. Microphones will cut out when a candidate's speaking time is over. Thursday night's presidential debate will not be business as usual.</p>

<p>CNN, which is hosting President Joe Biden and his predecessor Donald Trump for their first debate of the 2024 campaign in Atlanta, wants to avoid the chaos seen when the two men squared off in 2020.</p>

<p>Here are some facts about the 90-minute debate, a key moment in the race for the White House, but one whose impact is difficult to predict.</p>

<p><strong>Averting mayhem</strong></p>

<p>In their first war of words four years ago, Trump repeatedly cut off the veteran Democrat, launched into lengthy diatribes and taunted his rival, who ended up shouting at one point: "Will you shut up, man?"&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was hardly the height of presidential decorum.</p>

<p>To cut down on the hijinks, CNN has set up a series of rules, to which both campaigns agreed.</p>

<p>Among the most notable: When the candidates take the stage at the network's Atlanta studios at 9:00 pm (0100 GMT Friday), there will be no one in the audience.</p>

<p>Microphones will be muted except for the candidate asked to speak. There will be two commercial breaks during the showdown between 78-year-old Trump and 81-year-old Biden, the two oldest presumptive White House nominees in history.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moderators Jake Tapper and Dana Bash, both regular CNN on-air presenters, will "use all tools at their disposal to enforce timing and ensure a civilized discussion," the network said.</p>

<p><strong>Trump gets last word</strong></p>

<p>Biden won the coin toss, allowing him to choose either his podium position or whether he preferred to speak first or second in final statements.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The incumbent chose the podium on the viewers' right, and Trump opted to have the last word.</p>

<p><strong>No live fact-checking</strong></p>

<p>CNN has not revealed the debate themes, and does not plan to fact-check candidate statements in real time -- even if Trump repeats the baseless charge that the 2020 election was stolen from him.</p>

<p>For Kathleen Hall Jamieson, a professor of communication at the University of Pennsylvania, "one problem with a debate that features Donald Trump is that the moderators don't fact check in real time, nor should they."</p>

<p>"It's highly risky to try to do that and it would be disruptive of the debate if they did," she told AFP. "The danger is instead of informing, a debate could actually increase the amount of inaccurate knowledge."</p>

<p>Biden and Trump will not have teleprompters and they cannot bring pre-written notes to the stage, although they will be provided with paper and pen. Consulting with campaign staff during commercial breaks will not be allowed.</p>

<p><strong>Debate airs on all networks</strong></p>

<p>Both candidates rejected the oversight of the nonpartisan Commission on Presidential Debates formed in 1987 to manage such events.</p>

<p>Instead, they made a direct deal with CNN. The news network, now owned by media conglomerate Warner Bros Discovery, afforded its rivals the opportunity to broadcast the debate live in the name of public service, under certain conditions.</p>

<p>The screen must bear the CNN logo and outside commentary is forbidden.</p>

<p>Fox News -- which regularly attacks CNN as biased against Trump -- plans to hit the airwaves two hours before the event, with talk show hosts Jesse Watters and Sean Hannity providing pre-game insights.</p>

<p>In the past, Hannity has called Tapper a "radical left-wing partisan talk show host masquerading as a journalist."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Impact on campaign?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The debate will certainly be a key moment in the campaign, watched by tens of millions: a record 84 million tuned in to watch Trump's first battle with Hillary Clinton in 2016, and 73 million saw Trump and Biden duke it out in 2020.</p>

<p>But it will not necessarily be a game-changer.</p>

<p>This is the first time a debate has been organized so early in the race, more than four months before Election Day, and even before the candidates have been formally nominated by their respective parties.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The worry is that the public in the United States doesn't pay much attention to news in summer," said Jamieson.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In general, presidential debates don't affect a sufficient number of votes to decide the outcome of an election. But when an election is close, as this one may be, debates can play an important role."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/hauu54q8_trump-biden-split-650_650x400_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is the first time a debate has been organized so early in the race (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exercise-caution-india-to-its-citizens-in-lebanon-over-tensions-with-israel-5984630]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Exercise Caution: Centre To Indians In Lebanon Over Tensions With Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exercise-caution-india-to-its-citizens-in-lebanon-over-tensions-with-israel-5984630]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:56:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid escalating tensions and a volatile security landscape in Lebanon, both India and the United States have issued stern travel advisories, urging their citizens to exercise caution and reconsider travel plans to the Middle Eastern nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid escalating tensions and a volatile security landscape in Lebanon, both India and the United States have issued stern travel advisories, urging their citizens to exercise caution and reconsider travel plans to the Middle Eastern nation.</p>

<p>Russia's embassy in Beirut has also called on its citizens to refrain from traveling to Lebanon until the situation settles down in the southern part of the country.</p>

<p>The Indian Embassy in Lebanon advised all Indian nationals to remain vigilant and maintain communication with the Embassy through designated channels.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a statement, the embassy emphasised, "In view of the current situation in Lebanon, all Indian nationals in Lebanon are advised to exercise caution and remain in contact with Embassy of India in Beirut through our Email address: cons.beirut@mea.gov.in or through emergency helpline number 961-76860128."</p>

<p>Similarly, the US Embassy in Lebanon highlighted the unpredictable security environment, warning US citizens to strongly reconsider any plans to visit Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The security environment remains complex and can change quickly," the embassy stated. It specifically cautioned against travel to certain regions, including southern Lebanon, the Lebanon-Syria border area, and refugee settlements.</p>

<p>Both embassies underscored the importance of staying informed about local developments and maintaining awareness of one's surroundings.</p>

<p>Tensions between Israel and Lebanon have risen sharply since the October 7 Hamas attack on Israel and the ensuing military campaign by Israel in Gaza. Lebanon's Iran-backed group Hezbollah has been firing missiles, mortars and drones into Israel, and Israel has returned that fire, CNN reported.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of people on both sides of the mountainous border have fled as concerns intensify about the possible outbreak of another full-fledged war.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/5husnh3_israel-lebanon_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tensions between Israel and Lebanon have risen sharply since the October 7 Hamas attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-maldivian-ministers-arrested-for-black-magic-on-president-mohamed-muizzu-report-5984517]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Maldivian Ministers Arrested For 'Black Magic' On President: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-maldivian-ministers-arrested-for-black-magic-on-president-mohamed-muizzu-report-5984517]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:34:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maldives police have arrested two serving ministers for allegedly performing black magic on President Mohamed Muizzu, local media reported on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maldives police have arrested two serving ministers for allegedly performing black magic on President Mohamed Muizzu, local media reported on Thursday.</p>

<p>Shamnaz Saleem, who was a state minister at the Environment Ministry, her ex-husband Adam Rameez, who was serving as a minister at the President's Office, and two others were arrested, local media said quoting the police, which, however, declined to share any information about the reasons or the alleged performance of black magic.</p>

<p>"Shamnaz, alongside two other individuals, was arrested on Sunday. All three of them have been remanded in custody for seven days. She was suspended from her post on Wednesday as per the Environment Ministry," news portal Sun.mv reported, adding, Rameez too has been suspended on Thursday.</p>

<p>Incidentally, both Shamnaz and Rameez have worked with Muizzu as members of the Male City Council when he was serving as the city's mayor.</p>

<p>Media reported that after Muizzu assumed office as the President in November last year, Shamnaz was appointed as a state minister first at Muliaage, the official residence of the president and then transferred to the Environment Ministry.</p>

<p>"Rameez, during his time at Male City Council, was known as a close aide of Muizzu, who was the mayor at that time," Sun.mv said further and added, "However, he has been absent from the public light in the past five months or so." Neither the Maldives government nor the President's office has made any official comment on the issue.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/bc653e68_mohamed-muizzu_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Minister was suspended from her post on Wednesday as per the Environment Ministry.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-voters-prefer-bidens-democracy-approach-trumps-economy-plan-report-5984509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Voters Prefer Biden's Democracy Approach, Trump's Economy Plan: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-voters-prefer-bidens-democracy-approach-trumps-economy-plan-report-5984509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:33:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US voters see Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump as the better candidate for the economy but prefer his Democratic rival President Joe Biden's approach on preserving democracy, a new Reuters/Ipsos poll found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US voters see Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump as the better candidate for the economy but prefer his Democratic rival President Joe Biden's approach on preserving democracy, a new Reuters/Ipsos poll found.</p>

<p>The three-day poll that concluded on Sunday showed that less than five months before the Nov. 5 election, the electorate is divided on the candidates' approach on the issues that respondents view as the top two problems facing the nation.</p>

<p>Biden's approval rating, measured across all respondents in the poll, rose marginally to 37% from 36% in May when it tied the lowest reading of his presidency. Many Democrats worry Biden could be stung by voter concerns over his age - at 81 he's the oldest U.S. president to hold the office - and disapproval within his party of his support of Israel's war against Hamas.</p>

<p>When asked which of the two candidates had a better approach for the economy - the No. 1 concern for respondents - registered voters picked Trump 43% to 37%. Voters have been stung by several years of fast-rising consumer prices, though inflation has slowed considerably in recent months and the jobless rate has been below 4% for more than two years.</p>

<p>The Republican had a more significant edge - 44% to 31% - on immigration. Immigrants made up 13.9% of the country in 2022, the highest share in over a century. Trump has taken aim at immigrants in the country illegally. Trump was favored 40% to 35% on foreign conflicts and terrorism.</p>

<p>But Biden had the edge over Trump on responding to political extremism and threats to democracy, respondents' No. 2 concern, with registered voters picking the Democrat over Trump by 39% to 33%.</p>

<p>Trump, who was convicted last month on criminal charges he falsified business records, is awaiting three more criminal trials, two of which are tied to his efforts to overturn his 2020 election loss to Biden. Trump, who falsely claims his 2020 election defeat resulted from fraud, included the claim in a fiery speech shortly before hundreds of his supporters rushed into the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021.</p>

<p>Biden also had an edge over Trump on healthcare policy - 40% to 29%. Biden was vice president in 2010 when then-President Barack Obama pushed a landmark health reform through Congress that dramatically increased access to health insurance.</p>

<p>Previous Reuters/Ipsos polls have shown Biden and Trump neck-and-neck in the presidential race, though a number of polls in battleground states have shown Trump ahead in recent months.</p>

<p>The Reuters/Ipsos poll, conducted nationwide and online, collected responses from 1,019 U.S. adults, including 856 registered voters. It had a margin of error of 3.2 percentage points for all respondents and 3.5 percentage points for registered voters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/sd77uu9g_biden-trump-split-image_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden also had an edge over Donald Trump on healthcare policy - 40% to 29%: Report (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-agency-sanctions-boeing-for-sharing-probe-details-of-737-max-incident-5984404]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Agency Sanctions Boeing For Sharing Probe Details Of 737 MAX Incident]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-agency-sanctions-boeing-for-sharing-probe-details-of-737-max-incident-5984404]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:19:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US investigative authority sharply rebuked Boeing for sharing details about an ongoing probe of a near-catastrophic aviation incident that were not supposed to be discussed publicly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US investigative authority sharply rebuked Boeing for sharing details about an ongoing probe of a near-catastrophic aviation incident that were not supposed to be discussed publicly.</p>

<p>The National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) said that as a result, it will block Boeing from reviewing information gathered in its investigation.</p>

<p>Boeing "blatantly violated" investigative regulations under a signed agreement as a party to the probe, NTSB said in a statement late Wednesday.</p>

<p>The agency is also barring Boeing from asking questions of other participants at a two-day investigative hearing on the case which the NTSB will hold in early August in Washington.</p>

<p>The investigation concerns a January 5 Alaska Airlines flight on a Boeing 737 MAX that made an emergency landing after a fuselage panel blew out mid-flight.</p>

<p>Earlier this week, Boeing invited news media to a tour and briefings on its efforts to improve quality control. An AFP reporter attended the gathering, which was held on Tuesday under an agreement to embargo information until Thursday morning.</p>

<p>But NTSB said Boeing disregarded the agreement "by providing non-public investigative information to the media and speculating about possible causes of the Jan. 5 door-plug blowout."</p>

<p>"As a party to many NTSB investigations over the past decades, few entities know the rules better than Boeing," the NTSB said.</p>

<p>Under the party agreement Boeing signed with the NTSB, the company is supposed to refer all comment on the Alaska Airlines probe to the agency.</p>

<p>Boeing apologized to the NTSB, saying it "stands ready to answer any questions as the agency continues its investigation," according to a company statement.</p>

<p>"We conducted an in-depth briefing on our safety &amp; quality plan and shared context on the lessons we have learned from the January 5 accident," Boeing said.</p>

<p>"We deeply regret that some of our comments, intended to make clear our responsibility in the accident and explain the actions we are taking, overstepped the NTSB's role as the source of investigative information."</p>

<p><strong>What went wrong</strong></p>

<p>In a preliminary announcement in February, NTSB officials said four bolts securing the door plug were missing. Part of the NTSB probe centers on what went wrong.</p>

<p>The NTSB has taken issue with comments from Elizabeth Lund, senior vice president for quality at Boeing.</p>

<p>During a session with reporters, Lund discussed aspects surrounding work on the door plug.</p>

<p>She also said Boeing was focused on closing a "gap" over the lack of documentation and that determining who did the work "is the responsibility of the NTSB and that investigation is still going on."</p>

<p>NTSB responded that "in the briefing, Boeing portrayed the NTSB investigation as a search to locate the individual responsible for the door plug work."</p>

<p>"The NTSB is instead focused on the probable cause of the accident, not placing blame on any individual or assessing liability," the agency said.</p>

<p>The NTSB said it was also "coordinating" with the Department of Justice, which plans to soon announce next steps after concluding that Boeing could be prosecuted for violating a 2021 deferred prosecution agreement over two fatal MAX crashes.</p>

<p>The NTSB will provide DOJ "details about Boeing's recent unauthorized investigative information releases in the 737 MAX 9 door plug investigation," the NTSB said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/l5q13kco_alaska-airlines-boeing-737-max-9-afp_625x300_25_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Boeing "blatantly violated" investigative regulations, NTSB said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>