<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 22:55:52 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-in-chef-vikas-khannas-greeting-for-trump-a-hope-to-cook-at-white-house-6959752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Chef Vikas Khanna's Greeting For Trump, A "Hope" To Cook At White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-in-chef-vikas-khannas-greeting-for-trump-a-hope-to-cook-at-white-house-6959752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 22:39:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Many congratulations are coming Donald Trump's way as he secured a historic comeback to the White House as the United States' 47th President. One such greeting came from celebrated Indian chef Vikas Khanna, along with a gentle reminder.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many congratulations are coming Donald Trump's way after he secured a historic comeback to the White House as the United States' 47th President. One such greeting came from celebrated Indian chef Vikas Khanna, along with a gentle reminder.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a post on Instagram, Vikas Khanna shared a picture of him shaking hands with Donald Trump when the latter visited India during his last stint as US President in 2020. Addressing Trump as "Mr President", Vikas Khanna said that he hopes to cook Indian cuisine at the White House and reminded Trump of a promise made by him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Hello Mr. President! Hope to cook Indian cuisine at The White House as you promised the last time we met," he captioned the post.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBiHCixLBj/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBiHCixLBj/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBiHCixLBj/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBiHCixLBj/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Vikas Khanna (@vikaskhannagroup)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The picture was reportedly taken at Rashtrapati Bhavan during a dinner hosted by then President Ram Nath Kovind for Trump. Renowned Indian musician AR Rahman is also seen in the picture alongside Vikas Khanna.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the post quickly went viral on Instagram and has been liked by over 53,000 accounts so far, it received mixed reactions from users in the comments. Some people joined Vikas Khanna in congratulating Trump with one user commenting "Would love to see you cook there".&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, some people found Vikas Khanna's wish for Trump "disgusting". "Well this is disappointing," read a comment. Another user commented, "You're pathetic, I had once hoped to try your restaurant but now I never will."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vikas Khanna, a Michelin-star chef, runs a restaurant in New York City called 'Bungalow' with an extensive Indian menu.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kaf3sr08_vikas-khanna-donald-trump_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The picture was reportedly taken at Rashtrapati Bhavan in 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-day-1-promise-to-shut-clean-energy-projects-send-stocks-tumbling-6959675]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's 'Day 1' Promise To Shut Clean Energy Projects Send Stocks Tumbling]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-day-1-promise-to-shut-clean-energy-projects-send-stocks-tumbling-6959675]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 22:25:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's pledge to stop renewable energy projects on "day one" of his potential presidency has sent shockwaves through the industry, causing renewable energy shares to plummet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's pledge to stop renewable energy projects on "day one" of his potential presidency has sent shockwaves through the industry, causing renewable energy shares to plummet.&nbsp;“We are going to make sure that that ends on day one,” Trump said about offshore wind farms.<br />
According to a Reuters report, the world's largest offshore wind developer Orsted fell as much as 14 per cent while wind turbine makers Vestas and Nordex traded down around 11 per cent and 7.5 per cent respectively.</p>

<p>This isn't Trump's first rodeo with renewable energy; in his previous campaign, he claimed that solar panels require massive spaces, like entire deserts, to generate energy. However, according to the Solar Energy Industries Association, the actual land requirement for solar panels is relatively small, with most utility-scale solar operating today taking up less than 600,000 acres.</p>

<p>If Trump follows through on his promise, it could have significant implications for the renewable energy sector as he might try to eliminate or reduce tax credits for renewable energy projects, which could cripple the industry's growth.</p>

<p>He could dismantle environmental regulations put in place by the Biden administration, making it easier for fossil fuel companies to operate.</p>

<p>A Trump presidency could lead to a shift in energy policy, prioritising fossil fuels over renewable energy sources.</p>

<p>Trump has vowed to end the electric vehicle mandate, which could harm the EV industry and its related infrastructure. Donald Trump's stance on electric vehicles has taken a dramatic turn.</p>

<p>Just last December, he posted on Truth Social that EV supporters should "rot in hell". However, after talks with Elon Musk, Tesla's CEO and the world's richest man, Trump suddenly softened his tone. Now, he claims to be "for electric cars" and thinks they're suitable for "a small slice" of the population.</p>

<p>At a recent rally, Trump admitted that his change of heart was largely due to Musk's endorsement. "I'm for electric cars - I have to be, because Elon endorsed me," Trump said. "I have no choice". This shift is quite surprising, considering Trump's history of criticising electric vehicles, even calling them a "hoax".</p>

<p>It's essential to note that Trump's ability to implement these changes would depend on various factors, including congressional support and potential pushback from states, businesses, and activists. Nevertheless, the uncertainty surrounding Trump's energy policies has already caused concern among renewable energy investors and proponents.</p>

<p>Solar stocks are plummeting due to concerns that a second Trump presidency could jeopardise the Inflation Reduction Act, a crucial legislation that has driven a clean energy surge in the US by offering tax incentives to boost solar power. The act has been instrumental in fuelling growth in the renewable energy sector.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vmdsgqgo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump's presidency could prioritise fossil fuels over renewable energy sources]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-explained-why-kamala-harriss-historic-white-house-bid-fell-short-6959507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Kamala Harris's Historic White House Bid Fell Short]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-explained-why-kamala-harriss-historic-white-house-bid-fell-short-6959507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:56:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a meeting with one of America's most powerful unions in September at its Washington headquarters, Vice President Kamala Harris said she'd protect union jobs and workers' livelihoods better than Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a meeting with one of America's most powerful unions in September at its Washington headquarters, Vice President Kamala Harris said she'd protect union jobs and workers' livelihoods better than Donald Trump.</p>

<p>But leaders of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, long staunchly allied with her Democratic Party, appeared unconvinced. When Harris argued that her Republican rival was no champion of the working class, the union bosses grilled her, questioning whether she and President Joe Biden had done enough for union workers, according to a Teamster leader who recounted the Sept. 16 meeting to Reuters. Within days, the union publicly embarrassed Harris by declining to endorse a Democratic presidential candidate for the first time since 1996.</p>

<p>In the wake of Harris' loss of the 2024 presidential election, her tense exchange with union leaders underscores a critical failure of her campaign: connecting with working-class voters anxious about the economy and high prices.</p>

<p>Following Biden's dramatic withdrawal just months before Election Day, Harris threw her campaign together as if it were an airplane being built while in flight, her advisers told reporters. The 60-year-old former prosecutor and U.S. senator pressed a case that Trump was a threat to democracy and women's rights, while promoting a populist economic platform and reproductive freedoms.</p>

<p>Her entrance upended a race that her party had looked set to lose. She made history as the first woman of color at the top of a major party ticket. She triggered a surge in enthusiasm, broke fundraising records - raising $1 billion in less than three months - and drew endorsements from celebrities ranging from pop star Taylor Swift to actor and former California Governor Arnold Schwarzenegger.</p>

<p>But Harris' campaign ultimately failed to overcome deep-seated voter concerns about inflation and immigration - twin issues that opinion polls showed favored Trump. Her loss underscores a profound shift in American politics over the past decade as blue-collar voters have turned increasingly Republican - a trend Trump appears to have accelerated.</p>

<p>Harris also struggled to counter another Trump-era trend: a torrent of misinformation unprecedented in modern U.S. elections. An avalanche of misrepresentations and falsehoods about her record was spread by the former president and amplified on right-wing websites and media, including conspiracy theories on issues ranging from migrant crime to voter fraud.</p>

<p>When asked by Reuters during the race about misinformation amplified by Trump, his campaign officials typically either repeated the falsehoods or did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>By early Wednesday morning, Trump had won 279 electoral votes to Harris' 223, with several states yet to be counted. This account of how Harris lost is based on Reuters interviews with Harris campaign staffers, White House officials, Democratic Party advisors and close allies.</p>

<p>It was always going to be a heavy lift. The U.S. has only once elected a president - Barack Obama in 2008 and 2012 - who wasn't a white man. As the daughter of an Indian mother and Jamaican father, Harris had risen higher in the country's leadership than any other woman.</p>

<p>The only other woman to get as close as she did - Hillary Clinton, defeated by Trump in 2016 - staked her candidacy in part on becoming the first female president. In the wake of Clinton's loss, Harris resisted putting her identity at the center of her campaign, said close aides and advisors. Instead, she tried to galvanize voters on issues that mattered to women and Black voters in the election - from abortion rights to middle-class tax cuts and housing affordability.</p>

<p>But those messages struggled to break through at a time when many voters were fixated on rising consumer prices during the first three years of the Biden administration.</p>

<p>"Despite fairly strong economic growth, especially after a major global pandemic, most Americans weren't feeling like they were getting ahead economically," said Melissa Deckman, a political scientist and chief executive of Public Religion Research Institute, a nonpartisan research firm. "The Harris campaign did not necessarily do a good job of explaining how her policies would help the middle class, or at least that message wasn't really resonating with a lot of voters."</p>

<p>A majority of voters said they trust Trump more to handle the economy, with 51% saying they did so compared to 47% for Harris, according to a preliminary national exit poll conducted by data provider Edison Research. And the voters who identified the economy as their primary concern voted overwhelmingly for Trump over Harris - 79% to 20%.</p>

<p>The economy proved to be a much bigger concern among voters than reproductive rights, with 31% of voters saying the economy mattered most in deciding how to vote compared with 14% who cited abortion. The election also saw a large gender gap. Harris won 54% of women voters in the country, while Trump won 44%, the preliminary exit polls showed.</p>

<p>The Harris and Trump campaigns and the White House did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>"America has given us an unprecedented and powerful mandate," Trump said early on Wednesday to a roaring crowd of supporters at the Palm Beach County Convention Center.</p>

<p><strong>ELECTORAL GOLD</strong></p>

<p>The election was punctuated by dramatic twists, including two assassination attempts against Trump and the stunning decision by Biden to abandon his re-election bid on July 21.</p>

<p>Democrats coalesced behind Harris with astonishing speed, locking up her party's nomination within two weeks, excited by her potential to flip the generational argument on Trump. Two decades her senior, Trump had successfully cast the 81-year-old Biden as a frail and confused old man. She would turn that on its head, many Democrats hoped.</p>

<p>Some Democratic strategists questioned the wisdom of one of her first big decisions: picking Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as running mate over Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, a deft speaker with proven political strength in a must-win state. Her campaign had hoped the gun-owning Walz, a liberal policy champion and plain-speaking National Guardsman from the Midwest, would help her win over rural white voters.</p>

<p>Walz had generated buzz before Harris picked him by branding Trump and his running mate, Senator JD Vance of Ohio, as "weird" on national television in July, winning Democratic hearts and media attention. Later, though, Walz gained unwelcome attention for misstatements of his biography, including his military service, and for an uneven debate performance against Vance.</p>

<p>Walz and Vance didn't immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Still, the Harris campaign believed her signature issues - reproductive rights and Trump's divisiveness - would energize a coalition of women, Black voters, young Americans, independents and "Never Trump" Republicans, sweeping her to the White House.</p>

<p>Well before the race began, Harris emerged as a spokesperson for abortion rights. When the U.S. Supreme Court in 2022 officially reversed Roe v. Wade, declaring the constitutional right to abortion no longer existed, the setback for women's reproductive rights created an unexpected opening for Harris.</p>

<p>The ruling catapulted her from the political periphery into the heart of America's culture wars. Opinion polls showed most Americans disapproved of the court's decision - and Harris became the face of an issue that Democratic strategists saw as electoral gold.</p>

<p>For the first time in Biden's presidency, he handed a decisive issue entirely to his vice president. She went on the road, speaking forcefully on a subject that played an outsized role in helping Democrats stave off an expected bloodbath in the 2022 congressional elections. After the midterms, with the Democrats having held the Senate and swung to a slight minority in the House of Representatives, Harris was now seen as a viable future leader in the party.</p>

<p>Still, even after Biden stepped aside, concerns lingered among some top White House aides over the former San Francisco district attorney's political skills - including a perception that she hadn't made a mark as VP, her short-lived campaign for the 2020 Democratic nomination and her limited experience courting conservative voters in battleground states. Some also questioned whether she could overcome the long history of racial and gender discrimination in the U.S.</p>

<p>After securing the nomination, Harris initially put many of those concerns to rest. She revitalized a beleaguered Democratic campaign, attracting record-high funding and a groundswell of support. She soon moved ahead of Trump in the polls, a sign she was sparking enthusiasm among voters, particularly among women. Trump had previously been seen as the front-runner, partly based on his perceived strength on the economy after several years of high inflation under Biden.</p>

<p>She aced her first big test - a Sept. 10 televised debate against Trump.</p>

<p>As Harris's team prepared for what would be her only in-person face-off with Trump, they focused on ways to unnerve the former president and draw attention to his frequent falsehoods on policies, according to several aides involved in the preparations. Harris holed up in Pittsburgh with advisers and conducted mock debates for the prime-time showdown, the aides said.</p>

<p>The strategy paid off. Harris appeared to get under her rival's skin during the debate. She pressed Trump on the economy, Ukraine, healthcare, the January 2021 Capitol riots and abortion, leaving him rattled and struggling to respond.</p>

<p>Fundraising spiked: Her campaign said it raised $47 million in the 24 hours after the debate. Most voters thought Harris had won, polls showed. Trump shot down offers for another debate, claiming he'd already beaten her.</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, Harris mocked Trump's debate performance, including his comment that he had "concepts of a plan" to replace a federal health care law. As she gained in polls, Harris' campaign believed she was opening up states that had been out of reach for Biden, including North Carolina, where the president had his narrowest loss against Trump in 2020 and where she was drawing even in the polls with Trump.</p>

<p><strong>'IT COULD COST US THE ELECTION'</strong></p>

<p>North Carolina was the scene of her next big test, the late September Hurricane Helene, one of the deadliest storms to hit the U.S. in the last 50 years. The storm shifted focus from messages at the foundation of Harris' campaign to the handling of the disaster by the Biden-Harris administration.</p>

<p>It hit just as her lead was narrowing. Trump went on the attack, criticizing the Democratic administration's response to the disaster and tying it to his strongest issue, immigration. As the death count rose and swathes of North Carolina lay devastated, Trump amplified and spread falsehoods, including a claim that Harris spent disaster-assistance money on housing illegal migrants.</p>

<p>In response to a recent request for comment by Reuters about false claims about how disaster funds were being used, the Trump campaign repeated accusations that money had been spent on housing migrants in the country illegally.</p>

<p>Harris cut short a campaign swing and flew to Washington on Sept. 30 for a briefing on Biden's emergency response. On her plane, three staffers sat on the floor, ripping apart briefing books, replacing the pages with new notes, a Reuters reporter witnessed.</p>

<p>The disaster, which killed more than 200 people, marked a shift in the race, as misinformation around the administration's response and Trump's hard-line rhetoric on immigration gained traction. The baseless claims included that the government covered-up deaths, confiscated charitable donations and diverted disaster funds to help immigrants. Harris' campaign struggled to address both the false claims and voters' concerns about an uptick in illegal border crossings during Biden's presidency.</p>

<p>One jurisdiction that illustrated the risks for Harris was Buncombe County, a North Carolina Democratic stronghold of about 280,000 people hammered by the storm. In its aftermath, Democrats stopped targeting potentially persuadable Republican voters there because of concerns they had become too hostile amid the misinformation, Kathie Kline, Buncombe County Democratic chair, told Reuters. In the end, Trump won the state.</p>

<p>As the race tightened through October, and polls indicated a toss-up, alarm spread among Democratic strategists.</p>

<p>They focused on shoring up the so-called Blue Wall of Democratic states: Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin. Eight years ago, when Trump beat Hillary Clinton, he breached the Blue Wall by winning all three states, each by less than a percentage point. In 2020, Biden won them back. Holding the Blue Wall now was Harris' best path to the White House, the strategists reasoned. But they had a problem: Michigan and the Gaza War.</p>

<p>Michigan's large population of Arab Americans and Muslims helped cement Biden's 2020 victory in the state. Trump turned off many of these voters in his first term, in part by banning immigration to the U.S. from a number of Muslim countries early in his tenure.</p>

<p>In the race's final stretch, Muslim and Arab-American voters told Reuters they were disappointed Harris did not distance herself more from Biden's unwavering support of Israel during the Gaza war. In the final weeks, Trump aggressively courted their vote. Many said they would sit out the election or vote Republican.</p>

<p>Harris staffers knew that disillusioned Muslim and Arab-American Democrats were a risk. "It could cost us the election," said a senior Michigan operative for Harris in July.</p>

<p>The campaign ultimately concluded it was impossible to fully win back those voters. To offset their loss, campaign officials said they focused in the final weeks on marshaling enough support from union workers and Black voters in Detroit, the nation's largest Black-majority city.</p>

<p><strong>ECONOMIC THREATS</strong></p>

<p>But few issues threatened Harris like inflation.</p>

<p>Her campaign had hoped the economic recovery from the pandemic would be a winning issue. Growth is markedly more robust in the U.S. than in other major industrial nations. Stock-market indexes are near record highs.</p>

<p>Instead, the issue eroded Democratic support throughout much of 2024 as union workers and non-college-educated white voters broke for Trump, polls showed. Sharp increases in housing and food costs frustrated voters, overshadowing a strong job market. Trump blamed Harris for the spike during her and Biden's time in office.</p>

<p>While most unions have long supported Democratic candidates, rank-and-file workers in recent years have moved behind Trump, proving a decisive factor in his victory. There were some positive signs for Harris. The AFL-CIO, the largest federation of unions, saw a surge in female members supporting Harris and willing to volunteer for her, AFL-CIO President Liz Shuler told Reuters.</p>

<p>In the final weeks of the race, Harris' momentum appeared to have stalled, with polls showing her edge over Trump narrowing. By mid-October, the race was a dead heat in crucial states.</p>

<p>A pronounced gap in polling between men and women had emerged, too. While Harris cut away at the Republicans' longstanding edge with white voters overall by gaining ground with white women, Trump appeared to be boosting his advantage with men.</p>

<p>Harris shifted strategy in an attempt to win over more men and Republicans. The campaign dispatched running mate Walz on a tour in mid-October to reach male voters. Harris also held campaign events with former lawmaker Liz Cheney, one of Trump's fiercest Republican critics and one of the most prominent conservatives to endorse the Democrat. Days later, Trump suggested Cheney should face gunfire in combat, drawing outrage among Democrats and pundits.</p>

<p>The vice president also sharpened her attacks on Trump. In an Oct. 29 speech billed as her closing argument, Harris warned of the dangers of another Trump presidency. He was "unstable" and sought "unchecked power," she told a rally held at the spot in Washington where Trump addressed his supporters before they attacked the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021. With a well-lit White House behind her, she cast herself as a defender of democracy, unity and freedom.</p>

<p>She also sought to reassure voters about the cost of living. Trump's proposals to raise tariffs would amount to "a 20% national sales tax" on imported goods, she said. She vowed to "protect hard-working Americans who aren't always seen or heard."</p>

<p>In the end, not enough of those Americans believed her.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/moclu93o_kamala-harris_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A majority of voters said they trust Donald Trump more to handle the economy. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-concede-defeat-early-tomorrow-as-trump-returns-to-oval-office-6959364]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris To Concede Defeat To Trump Early Tomorrow]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-concede-defeat-early-tomorrow-as-trump-returns-to-oval-office-6959364]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:35:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President and Democratic nominee Kamala Harris will deliver a speech conceding defeat in the US presidential election to Republican candidate Donald Trump, the White House said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President and Democratic nominee Kamala Harris will deliver a speech conceding defeat in the US presidential election to Republican candidate Donald Trump, the White House said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris will deliver the speech at 4 pm local time (2.30 am IST on Thursday) at Howard University in Washington.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the vice president had cancelled her election night speech after it became clear that former president Trump would cross the magic mark of 270 electoral college votes and return to the White House as the 47th president of the United States.</p>

<p>Despite polls predicting that the election was too close to call, Trump steamrolled Harris and went on to pick up key swing states, including Pennsylvania, Georgia and Wisconsin, setting the stage for his return to the Oval Office.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He also won the popular vote, becoming the first Republican to do so in 20 years, after George W Bush in 2004.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Delivering a victory speech to a room full of roaring supporters in Florida, Trump said "America has given us an unprecedented and powerful mandate"&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Powerful, Unsuccessful Campaign</strong></p>

<p>Harris, who had 224 electoral college votes as of Wednesday night against Trump's 280, ran a powerful campaign in her bid to become the first woman president of the United States. The 60-year-old former prosecutor also made history as the first black woman and the first South Asian woman to get the presidential nomination from a major party. She raised $1 billion in less than three months and was endorsed by celebrities like Taylor Swift, Beyonce and Oprah as well as several Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But her campaign failed to overcome Trump and his MAGA (Make America Great Again) movement's messaging around the economy and immigration, which proved to be key concerns for voters going into this year's elections. Several polls showed that people felt they were better off under Donald Trump during his presidency (2016-2020) than they were under the Joe Biden-Harris administration.</p>

<p>Experts said that as the vice president in an unpopular administration, Harris could not successfully portray herself as the candidate of change, which is something Trump did very effectively. Asked during a daytime show about what she would do differently from Biden, Harris had said, "Not a thing comes to mind".</p>

<p>Many felt Harris was also handicapped by the fact that she had only a few weeks to campaign after Biden dropped out of the race in July. Trump, on the other hand, had been getting his message out to voters since before the 2016 elections and continued to occupy a space in the national consciousness in the US even after leaving office in 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Record Setter</strong></p>

<p>At 78, Trump is the oldest person to be elected the president of the US and only the second to be elected for two non-consecutive terms - after Grover Cleveland in 1897. The former president survived an assassination attempt during the campaign and, after the victory, described the political movement helmed by him as the greatest of all time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are going to help our country heal, fix our borders, we made history for a reason tonight. We have achieved the most incredible political win. I want to thank the American people. I will fight for you and your family with every breath in my body," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Stock markets surged in the US and several other countries, including India, after his victory.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(With inputs from Reuters)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gumnefag_kamala-harris_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris had endorsements from many celebrities and even some Republicans.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-prince-william-says-wife-kate-doing-really-well-after-chemotherapy-6959200]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Prince William Says Wife Kate Doing "Really Well" After Chemotherapy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-prince-william-says-wife-kate-doing-really-well-after-chemotherapy-6959200]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:13:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's Prince William said today that his wife Kate was doing "really well" and had been amazing in a year when she has undergone preventative chemotherapy for cancer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Prince William said today that his wife Kate was doing "really well" and had been amazing in a year when she has undergone preventative chemotherapy for cancer.</p>

<p>The British heir to the throne is currently in South Africa where he will later host the annual awards ceremony for his multi-million-dollar Earthshot Prize. He made the trip without Kate who is still recovering from her treatment.</p>

<p>He said she would be cheering him on from their home in Britain.</p>

<p>"She's doing really well thanks," he told the BBC ahead of his environmental prize's awards ceremony in Cape Town. "She's been amazing this whole year. I know she will be really keen to see tonight be a success."</p>

<p>As well as Kate, he said he hoped their three children George, 11, Charlotte, 9, and Louis, 6, would also be watching on proudly, saying they as a family did what they could to help the environment.</p>

<p>"We go through all the basics of recycling and making sure we minimise water use and turning off lights when we leave the house and stuff like that," he said.</p>

<p>William set up the Earthshot prize to find innovations to combat climate and other green issues in 2020, inspired by U.S. President John F. Kennedy's 1960s "moonshot" project which led to the 1969 lunar landing. Five winners receive 1 million pounds ($1.3 million) every year to drive their projects.</p>

<p>Asked how he could convey his Earthshot message during a tough political climate for environmental causes, he told the BBC: "I think everyone wants some hope and wants some optimism."</p>

<p>He said the young people of Africa who would attend the awards would show how important the issue was to them.</p>

<p>"Without them, you know, the future is looking pretty bleak," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/l07mhr3o_kate-middleton-prince-william-afp_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Britain's Prince William said today that his wife Kate was doing "really well".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-us-woman-ages-34-slower-her-longevity-routine-costs-just-12-a-day-6958933]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This US Woman Ages 34% Slower. Her Longevity Routine Costs Just $12 A Day]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-us-woman-ages-34-slower-her-longevity-routine-costs-just-12-a-day-6958933]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:32:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ms Clark's progress was validated by the Dunedin PACE blood test, which examines biomarkers associated with ageing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US woman was recently recognized by the "Rejuvenation Olympics" for achieving a slower ageing rate than billionaire Bryan Johnson, known for using his son's blood to maintain a youthful appearance. Julie Gibson Clark, a dedicated biohacking enthusiast, has managed to slow her ageing process by an impressive 34% compared to the average person. As the daughter of a NASA astronaut, Ms Clark has drawn on both discipline and innovation, sharing that her daily longevity routine costs just $12 a day.</p>

<p>Ms Clark's progress was validated by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.publichealth.columbia.edu/news/epidemiologists-develop-state-art-tool-measuring-pace-aging" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Dunedin PACE blood test</em></a>, which examines biomarkers associated with ageing.</p>

<p>Her commitment to health began in childhood, inspired by her father, a former NASA astronaut from the 1970s Skylab missions, who taught her to view food as fuel and prioritize nutrition for optimal performance. Although Ms Clark, now 56 and a professional recruiter, embraced these principles more earnestly in adulthood, her focus has since turned to longevity and stress reduction, aiming to stay active and healthy to fully enjoy life and time with her teenage son, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.businessinsider.in/science/health/news/a-56-year-old-recruiter-sets-aside-12-a-day-for-her-longevity-routine-to-slow-aging-heres-how-she-spends-it-/amp_articleshow/114990175.cms" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Business Insider</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Over the past 25 years, Clark has steadily refined her personal health regimen. Starting with dietary supplements and home-cooked meals in her 30s to address chronic acid reflux, her approach eventually expanded. She eliminated alcohol and phased out antidepressants, crediting her improvements to dietary and lifestyle changes. Clark keeps her routine flexible, making adjustments that align with her core intention- a long, fulfilling life centred on travel, learning, and family.</p>

<p>"You've got to figure out your 'why,' your intention, and your resources," Clark told Business Insider, emphasizing the importance of a clear, sustainable goal in biohacking.</p>

<p>Ms Clark's method prioritizes affordability and simplicity, diverging from high-cost interventions. Rejecting short-term "beach body" trends, she views her practices as lifelong. Her routine builds slowly, adding new habits one at a time until they feel as natural as brushing one's teeth.</p>

<p>Her daily routine includes morning prayer, a 7 AM workout followed by a sauna and cold shower, and a meditation break in the afternoon. Clark describes her post-workout sauna and cold shower as a "mini spa" experience, a cornerstone of her wellness routine.</p>

<p>Diet plays a central role, with Clark aiming for a pound of vegetables each day, focusing on a colourful mix from purple carrots to sweet potatoes. She balances this with lean proteins like chicken, eggs, and locally sourced meats.</p>

<p>She particularly enjoys spinach, which she keeps on hand for easy summer meals and blends into a mid-morning "greens latte" in colder months. Rich in fibre, vitamins, and phytochemicals, Clark's vegetable-heavy diet supports longevity, providing a range of health benefits backed by science.</p>

<p>Medical professionals endorse her choices. Dr Dean Sherzai, an expert in dementia prevention, recommends leafy greens for brain health. Clark's diet, which includes Omega-3s and B vitamins for brain function and energy, is further bolstered by leafy greens to address common magnesium deficiencies.</p>

<p>New research also suggests that hormone therapy and vitamin D supplementation could support healthy ageing in postmenopausal women. Studies have associated vitamin D and calcium intake with a reduced risk of certain cancers in women, adding further benefits to Clark's nutritional approach.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l53hpb88_julie-gibson-clark_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Clark's method prioritizes affordability and simplicity, diverging from high-cost interventions]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-trumps-election-win-could-mean-for-abortion-laws-in-us-6958907]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Trump's Election Win Could Mean For Abortion Laws In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-trumps-election-win-could-mean-for-abortion-laws-in-us-6958907]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:30:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's second presidential term could herald a new wave of attacks on abortion access across the United States -- with or without a Republican-controlled Congress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's second presidential term could herald a new wave of attacks on abortion access across the United States -- with or without a Republican-controlled Congress.</p>

<p>Here's a closer look at the legal tools available to a future administration intent on curtailing the right -- and how abortion rights defenders are preparing to fight back.</p>

<p><strong>- Federal actions -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>For advocates of abortion rights, the nightmare scenario is a Republican-controlled Congress enacting sweeping national restrictions or an outright ban.</p>

<p>But even without that, Trump could "do a lot of damage to abortion access" through federal actions and judicial appointments, American University law professor Lewis Grossman told AFP.</p>

<p>The Republican former president's Supreme Court picks were pivotal in dismantling decades of legal precedent protecting the national right to abortion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While Trump has at times hinted at moderation during the 2024 campaign -- even suggesting he might veto any anti-abortion "ban" that lands on his desk -- some fear Project 2025 as the real battle plan.</p>

<p>Published by the ultra-conservative Heritage Foundation, the document offers a roadmap for harsher executive branch restrictions, developed with input from former Trump officials. Trump has publicly distanced himself from the document.</p>

<p><strong>- New conditions on abortion pills -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Experts predict abortion pills could be Trump's first target.</p>

<p>Mifepristone, which prevents pregnancy progression, and misoprostol, which empties the uterus, accounted for nearly two-thirds of US abortions last year, according to the Kaiser Family Foundation.</p>

<p>Medical abortion used to require in-clinic visits. However, President Joe Biden's government made prescription by telehealth and pills in the mail permanent in 2021.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A Trump administration might reinstate in-person requirements or roll back other eased regulations, said George Washington University law professor Sonia Suter -- a simpler step than rescinding approval, though that is also possible.</p>

<p><strong>- Reviving obscenity law -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Anti-abortion activists are eyeing the Comstock Act, a 19th-century law prohibiting the mailing of "obscene" materials, including items for "producing abortion."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US Justice Department under Biden currently interprets this law as inapplicable to approved abortion pills.</p>

<p>But Suter told AFP that a broad interpretation could apply to "anything used to produce an abortion -- materials for surgical abortions -- which could effectively create a national ban."</p>

<p>This could disrupt the supply chain in clinics and hospitals across states where abortion is currently legal -- or where it may soon be permitted through state-level referendums on November 5.</p>

<p>"There is nothing nefarious or 'backdoor' about enforcing the laws that Congress has enacted and repeatedly reaffirmed," conservative lawyer and scholar Josh Craddock told AFP.</p>

<p><strong>- Judicial appointments and more -</strong><br />
&nbsp;<br />
A Trump administration could also seek to undo the stringent patient privacy protections put in place by Biden for women seeking abortions out-of-state, said Suter, paving the way for possible prosecutions when they return home.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although the Supreme Court's conservative majority has already overturned Roe v Wade, experts say the power to appoint federal judges remains paramount.</p>

<p>Courts may soon be called on to decide the fate of state laws that make it harder for women to access care in more abortion-friendly states, Grossman explained.</p>

<p><strong>- Fightback begins -</strong></p>

<p>Abortion rights advocates swiftly branded Trump's election victory a "deadly threat."</p>

<p>A second Trump administration would compound the "harms" of the first "with new, potentially far worse ones," warned Nancy Northup, president of the Center for Reproductive Rights in a statement Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We will vigorously oppose any and all attempts to roll back progress," she said, vowing to "take the fight to them at every turn."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1oqbsaio_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For advocates of abortion rights, the nightmare scenario is a Republican-controlled Congress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-explained-impact-of-donald-trumps-white-house-return-on-world-economy-6958803]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Impact Of Donald Trump's White House Return On World Economy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-explained-impact-of-donald-trumps-white-house-return-on-world-economy-6958803]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:19:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's return to the White House with his protectionist policies poses threats for the global economy, with the prospect of new trade wars, resurgent inflation and slower growth, experts say.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's return to the White House with his protectionist policies poses threats for the global economy, with the prospect of new trade wars, resurgent inflation and slower growth, experts say.</p>

<p><strong>Global trade threatened?</strong></p>

<p>During his first term in office from 2017 to 2021, Trump often resorted to punitive tariffs in disputes with trade partners.</p>

<p>In this 2024 campaign, he pledged to impose an additional 60 percent import tariff on Chinese products and an extra 10 percent tariff on products from the rest of the world.</p>

<p>Taking into account the probable retaliatory measures from Beijing and Brussels, the impact on the European Union economy will be $533 billion through 2029, $749 billion for the United States and $827 billion for China, according to a study by the Roland Berger consulting firm.</p>

<p>A separate study by the London School of Economics estimated that the impact on emerging market nations such as India, Indonesia and Brazil would be much less.</p>

<p>Jamie Thompson, head of macroeconomic forecasting at London-based Oxford Economics, said he sees little shot-term economic impact due to the delays in implementing policies, but they could be positive for growth.</p>

<p>"While the outlook for 2025 is essentially unchanged, global growth is likely to be a little stronger in 2026 and 2027 on the back of the election result, as the impact of looser US fiscal policy more than offsets the drag from targeted tariff measures," he told AFP.</p>

<p>But if across-the-board tariffs are imposed it "could leave the global economy around 0.75 percent smaller -- and global trade down some three percent -- by the end of the decade," he added.</p>

<p>The prospects for international cooperation, which can boost trade and growth, will also be dimmer under a second Trump administration, said Tara Varma, a visiting fellow at the Brookings Institution, a US think tank.</p>

<p>"The multilateral world of the 1990-2000s will no longer exist," she said, adding that she anticipates a brutal change in US policies.</p>

<p><strong>A surge in inflation?</strong></p>

<p>Donald Trump's policies could also rekindle inflation, which cooled following a series of interest-rate hikes that the Federal Reserve began to unwind this year.</p>

<p>The Peterson Institute for International Economics, a US think tank, estimated it could add between two and four percentage points to China's inflation rate.</p>

<p>The impact of "immigration policy is as important as global trade" on inflation, noted for his part Gilles Moec, chief economist at insurer Axa.</p>

<p>If Trump follows through with talk of a massive expulsion of unauthorised immigrants it could aggravate the labour shortage in the United States.</p>

<p>The Pew Research Center estimated that 8.3 million unauthorised workers could be affected.</p>

<p>The Peterson Institute for International Economics estimated this could add more than two percentage points to the US inflation rate next year, 0.2 percentage points in Europe and 0.6 percentage points in China.</p>

<p>Moec noted the surge in inflation would force central banks to hit the brakes on the cycle of interest rate cuts they began earlier this year as inflation subsided.</p>

<p>Analysts had been looking at lower interest rates to spur consumers to spend and companies to invest and put some more wind into the sails of the global economy.</p>

<p><strong>Trade war to snuff out growth?</strong></p>

<p>The trade war that Trump has threatened to wage against China risks sapping global growth.</p>

<p>Asia accounts for 60 percent of global growth, but would be hit hard by a trade war between the United States and China, the International Monetary Fund warned earlier this month.</p>

<p>The United States has also been one of the fastest growing developed economies but Trump's policies risk shaving two percentage points off US GDP per year between 2027 and 2031 from baseline estimates, according to a forecast from the Peterson Institute.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1oqbsaio_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's policies could also rekindle inflation (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-us-election-result-donald-trump-criminal-cases-trump-still-facing-2020-capitol-riots-cases-returns-in-2024-6958491]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Still Facing 2020 Capitol Riots Cases, Returns In 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-us-election-result-donald-trump-criminal-cases-trump-still-facing-2020-capitol-riots-cases-returns-in-2024-6958491]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:37:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of Americans on Wednesday celebrated Donald Trump's remarkable return to the White House - the 78-year-old defied pre-poll predictions to become the first Republican in 20 years to win the popular vote en route to the presidency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of Americans on Wednesday celebrated <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/78-year-old-donald-trump-oldest-person-to-be-elected-us-president-6957306#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Donald Trump's remarkable return to the White House</a> - the 78-year-old defied pre-poll predictions to become the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-us-elections-donald-trump-set-to-become-first-republican-to-win-popular-vote-in-20-years-6955598" target="_blank">first Republican in 20 years to win the popular vote</a> en route to the presidency. But not everyone was quite so happy.</p>

<p>Among his critics was Vanity Fair, a monthly magazine on popular culture and current affairs, which featured Mr Trump on the cover of its newest digital issue, with a sequence of numbers highlighting the legal disputes that still surround the President-elect.</p>

<p>At the top of the list is the&nbsp;<strong>34</strong>&nbsp;<strong>felony charges</strong> the incoming American President faced in a criminal case in the State of New York. The court ruled Mr Trump altered business records to hide over $400,000 in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/he-should-be-adult-star-stormy-daniels-breaks-silence-on-donald-trumps-conviction-in-hush-money-trial-5802000" target="_blank">payments made to Stormy Daniels</a>, an adult film actor, to try and conceal details of their sexual encounter. He was convicted - the next number, <strong>1 conviction</strong> - on all counts in May.</p>

<p>Mr Trump - who slammed the entire case as a "witch hunt" and protested his innocence - is the first felon to be elected as President of the United States. He has said he will appeal the verdict.</p>

<p>Sentencing was delayed till after the result of this election; it will be held on November 26, while a separate hearing on immunity for the incoming President is expected on November 12.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBuuWzOo0W/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBuuWzOo0W/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBuuWzOo0W/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCBuuWzOo0W/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Vanity Fair (@vanityfair)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>If the latter hearing goes as Mr Trump will want - i.e., if the court rules he enjoys immunity as a former President - then the former will be dismissed, since the guilty verdict will be overturned.</p>

<p>Even if there is to be no immunity, Mr Trump can now surely postpone any sentencing, although he cannot, as President, pardon himself since this is a state and not federal case.</p>

<p>In the extremely unlikely case the sentencing goes through, Mr Trump could face a maximum of four years in prison, but sentencing a President-elect days before he takes oath (on January 20) would be unprecedented. Mr Trump has also asked for the case to move to a federal court.</p>

<p>The next number - <strong>2&nbsp;cases pending</strong>.</p>

<p>In the first pending case are four charges in a Washington, D.C. court accusing Donald Trump of spreading false claims of election fraud to try and block collection and certification of votes cast in the 2020 election. This is, perhaps, the big one, since it deals with the January 2021 attack on the Capital.</p>

<p>The attack - by a mob of Donald Trump's supporters - was widely seen as being precipitated by incendiary speeches from the outgoing President, claiming, as he had for weeks earlier without any evidence, that his election win had been "stolen by emboldened radical-left Democrats".</p>

<p><strong>FROM THE ARCHIVE |</strong> <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-capitol-violence-donald-trump-summoned-supporters-to-wild-protest-and-they-did-2348901" target="_blank">Trump Summoned Supporters To "Wild" Protest. They Came</a></p>

<p>The US Supreme Court offered some relief for Mr Trump after ruling some of his actions had immunity, but prosecutors then revised charges to name him as a private citizen instead.</p>

<p>Trump pleaded not guilty to all charges and cast the prosecutions as politically motivated.</p>

<p><strong>FROM THE ARCHIVE |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-calls-his-speech-before-us-capitol-siege-totally-appropriate-2351514" target="_blank">"Appropriate": Trump Defends Speech Before Capitol Violence</a></p>

<p>The trial date for this has not yet been set, and with Mr Trump's election win now, it is unclear if and when this will move forward. As President, Mr Trump can pardon himself for these charges.</p>

<h3><strong>The Georgia Case</strong></h3>

<p>In the second case, the President-elect and 18 others are accused of criminal conspiracy in trying to overturn his defeat in Georgia in 2020; he lost the state's 16 electoral votes to Democrat Joe Biden, but popular vote loss was less than 0.5 per cent - 49.47 to Mr Biden and 49.24 to Mr Trump.</p>

<p>The investigation hinges on a call Mr Trump allegedly made, asking a senior George polling official to "find 11,780 votes" - which would have put him a single vote ahead of his rival.</p>

<p>Mr Trump pleaded not guilty, but the trial itself has been delayed by his team seeking to disqualify the public prosecutor for a romantic relationship with a man she hired to work on the case.</p>

<p>Oral arguments on that matter are scheduled for December 5, but Mr Trump's lawyers are already looking ahead and have said they will ask the court for a suspension of proceedings based on the argument a President ought not to face a criminal prosecution while in office.</p>

<p>As with the New York case, Mr Trump cannot pardon himself as this is a state case, and he also cannot shut down these proceedings as he could the Washington, D.C. charges.</p>

<p>However, this case has also been paused with no certainty on when it will resume.</p>

<p>The other numbers on the Vanity Fair cover pertain to Mr Trump's <strong>2 impeachments</strong> - one in December 2019 on charges of abuse of power and obstruction of Congress, and the other in 2021, after the Capitol attack. In both cases Donald Trump was acquitted by the Senate.</p>

<p>The Vanity Fair cover also mentions Mr Trump's <strong>6 bankruptcy filings</strong>, and conclude on a sharply scathing note: "<strong>4 more years</strong>... the 47th American President."</p>

<p>But these numbers are trumped by another - 280, the number of electoral college votes in Mr Trump's pocket and which confirm that he will be the next President of the United States, despite a spirited (and hopeful) but ultimately futile challenge by Democrat Kamala Harris.</p>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ba83q7j8_donald-trump_625x300_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-elections-20204-indian-village-proud-as-donald-trump-claims-victory-in-us-elections-6958425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why This Andhra Village Is Celebrating Donald Trump's Election Victory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-elections-20204-indian-village-proud-as-donald-trump-claims-victory-in-us-elections-6958425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:29:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Far from Republican festivities as Donald Trump claimed US election victory, residents of a sleepy Indian village celebrated that their descendant would be the next "Second Lady", hoping to benefit from her success.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Far from Republican festivities as Donald Trump claimed US election victory, residents of a sleepy Indian village celebrated that their descendant would be the next "Second Lady", hoping to benefit from her success.</p>

<p>Academic highflyer and successful lawyer Usha Vance, the child of Indian immigrants, is the wife of Trump's running mate J.D. Vance.</p>

<p>While 38-year-old Usha Vance was born and brought up in suburban San Diego, those in the village of her paternal ancestors in India's southern Andhra Pradesh state prayed that historic ties would bring improvements to their land.</p>

<p>"We feel happy," said Srinivasa Raju, 53, a resident of Vadluru, a village of white-washed homes scattered amongst palm trees, more than 13,450 (8,360 miles) from the White House in Washington. "We support Trump."</p>

<p>Villagers had offered prayers for a Trump win, and Hindu priest Appaji said he hoped Usha Vance would do something in return.</p>

<p>"We expect her to help our village," the 43-year-old priest said, dressed in flowing saffron robes, after lighting a candle at the idol of Hindu elephant-headed deity Ganesh for Trump.</p>

<p>"If she can recognise her roots and do something good for this village, then that would be great."</p>

<p><strong>'Very fine'</strong></p>

<p>Usha Vance's great-grandfather moved out of Vadluru and her father Chilukuri Radhakrishnan -- a PhD holder -- was brought up in the Indian city of Chennai, before going on to study in the United States.</p>

<p>"Every Indian -- not just myself, every Indian -- we feel proud of Usha, because she is of Indian origin," said 70-year-old Venkata Ramanayy. "We hope she will develop our village."</p>

<p>She has never visited the village, but the priest said her father came around three years ago and checked on the temple's condition.</p>

<p>"We have already seen the governance of Trump -- very good," Ramanayy said. "Indian and American relations were very fine during the presidency of Trump."</p>

<p>Little is known about Radhakrishnan's initial years in the United States, but the film of J.D. Vance's memoirs, Hillbilly Elegy, refers to him coming to the country with "nothing".</p>

<p>Millions of Indians have made similar journeys as the Chilukuris, and according to the most recent US census, Indians have become the country's second-largest Asian ethnicity, growing 50 percent to 4.8 million in the decade to 2020.</p>

<p>Usha, a practising Hindu who studied at Yale and Cambridge Universities, married J.D. Vance in Kentucky in 2014. They have three children.</p>

<p><strong>'Inspiring'</strong></p>

<p>But the story was different around 730 kilometres (454 miles) to the southwest, in Thulasendrapuram, once home to Kamala Harris's grandfather.</p>

<p>T.S. Anbarasu, 63, said the Democrat's "struggle" had encouraged girls to stay in school.</p>

<p>"She is inspiring this village," he said. "Any school in the surrounding area, students know about Kamala Harris."</p>

<p>Harris, 60, was born in California, but was often taken to India by her mother.</p>

<p>"If she comes here, we'll treat her like the president of the United States," Anbarasu said.</p>

<p>"We are still proud of her. She is like family to us. If our family members fail, we don't discriminate against them, or treat them as a loser, right?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/or1krfkg_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Villagers had offered prayers for Donald Trump's win (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-influencer-adopts-pig-feed-diet-to-save-money-sparking-health-concerns-6958416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Woman Adopts Pig Feed Diet to Save Money, Sparking Health Concerns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-influencer-adopts-pig-feed-diet-to-save-money-sparking-health-concerns-6958416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:27:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Popular Chinese influencer Kong Yufeng, known as "King Kong Liuke," has sparked health concerns by revealing her diet of pig feed, costing just 3 yuan (Rs 35) per day, to save money.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A popular Chinese social media influencer has ignited widespread health concerns after revealing she has been consuming a diet of pig feed to save money, according to <em>The South China Morning Post. </em>Kong Yufeng, known online as "King Kong Liuke," claims that the 3 yuan (Rs 35) per day diet is healthier than takeaway food.</p>

<p>Yufeng, a well-known handicraft influencer on Douyin with 2.8 million followers and a graduate of the Sichuan Fine Arts Institute, has revealed details of her peculiar diet on social media. Although some fans have praised her thrifty way of living, many others have voiced grave worries about the possible health hazards of eating pig feed, which is not meant for human consumption.</p>

<p>On October 30, Kong posted a video in which she expressed her intention to live on as little money as possible, although she did not disclose her reasons for this challenge. She adopted the top-ranked money-saving suggestion from Zhihu, a popular Chinese forum: eating pig feed, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3285245/china-kol-adopts-pig-feed-diet-costing-40-us-cents-save-money-raising-health-concerns?module=top_story&amp;pgtype=section"><em>SCMP.</em></a></p>

<p>A diet like this could result in severe malnutrition and other health issues, according to health experts. They stress how crucial it is to have a well-balanced diet full of different nutrients in order to stay healthy.</p>

<p>Kong spent 100 yuan (US$14) on a bag of pig feed, which she described as having a "milky oatmeal smell" upon opening. The video revealed that the pig feed contains ingredients such as soybeans, peanuts, sesame, corn, and added vitamins.</p>

<p>"It's all high-protein, low-fat, and completely natural. Isn't this healthier than takeaway food?" she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ll9m69q_kong-yufeng-known-online-as-king-kong-liuke_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Health experts warn the diet could lead to severe malnutrition.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-if-theres-one-person-on-earth-gautam-adani-congratulates-trump-6958361]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If There's One Person On Earth...": Gautam Adani Congratulates Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-if-theres-one-person-on-earth-gautam-adani-congratulates-trump-6958361]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:19:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Adani Group Chairman Gautam Adani in a post on X congratulated Donald Trump for winning the race to the White House for a second time, calling the new US President an "embodiment of unbreakable tenacity".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adani Group Chairman Gautam Adani in a post on X congratulated Donald Trump for winning the race to the White House for a second time, calling the new US President an "embodiment of unbreakable tenacity".</p>

<p>Mr Trump won a sweeping victory in the US presidential election, defeating Kamala Harris in a stunning political comeback. World leaders swiftly pledged to work with Mr Trump, led by Israel and Ukraine <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-what-donald-trump-said-about-wars-in-trump-2-0-victory-speech-6956202">where the course of wars</a> could depend on the new US President's isolationist "America First" foreign policy.</p>

<p>In his congratulatory post, Mr Adani said, "If there is one person on Earth who stands as the embodiment of unbreakable tenacity, unshakeable grit, relentless determination and the courage to stay true to his beliefs, it is Donald Trump."</p>

<p>"Fascinating to see America's democracy empower its people and uphold the nation's founding principles. Congratulations to the 47th POTUS-elect Donald Trump," Mr Adani said, referring to the President of the United States, or POTUS.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">If there is one person on Earth who stands as the embodiment of unbreakable tenacity, unshakeable grit, relentless determination and the courage to stay true to his beliefs, it is Donald Trump. Fascinating to see America's democracy empower its people and uphold the nation's... <a href="https://t.co/oCztiexw4b">pic.twitter.com/oCztiexw4b</a></p>
— Gautam Adani (@gautam_adani) <a href="https://twitter.com/gautam_adani/status/1854145439492157665?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The post is accompanied by a photo of Mr Trump with blood-stained ears following a failed assassination attempt by a sniper during a campaign stop. The photo which showed Mr Trump raising his fist in the air in a 'stay-strong' gesture as two Secret Service personnel tried to drag him away to safety had become one of the defining photos of the US election.</p>

<p>Mr Trump is the first president in more than a century to win a non-consecutive second term.</p>

<p>The campaign pointed to a nail-bitingly close contest, but the results came surprisingly fast, delivering a crushing victory that included wins in the swing states of Georgia, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>Gloom descended on Kamala Harris' campaign after she cut short a planned watch party and cancelled a speech.</p>

<p><strong>What Trump 2.0 Holds For India</strong></p>

<p>Earlier today, Congress leader Shashi Tharoor, who heads the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs, told NDTV Mr Trump is a familiar politician who India has engaged with before, and so the Trump 2.0 administration should not have any surprises for India.</p>

<p>In a short conversation with NDTV, the diplomat-turned-politician from Kerala explained briefly the areas that India already understands about Mr Trump's style of working, and how India can keep those in mind while engaging with him again.</p>

<p>"We know him very well. He has already been president for four years. I don't think there will be any surprise as to what kind of politics he will do. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-transactional-leader-no-surprises-shashi-tharoor-on-donald-trump-2-0-for-india-6956500">He's a transactional politician</a>, 'what can you do for me, and what can I do for you' type of leader," Mr Tharoor, the Congress MP from Thiruvananthapuram, told NDTV.</p>

<p><strong>With inputs from AFP</strong></p><br />
<br />
<p><i>(Disclaimer: New Delhi Television is a subsidiary of AMG Media Networks Limited, an Adani Group Company.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qrddf6n_donald-trump-melania_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump and wife Melania Trump in Palm Beach County Convention Centre]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-kamala-harris-isnt-1st-woman-us-president-but-she-has-other-firsts-to-her-name-6958216]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris Isn't 1st Woman US President, But She Has Other Firsts To Her Name]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-kamala-harris-isnt-1st-woman-us-president-but-she-has-other-firsts-to-her-name-6958216]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 18:58:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than a decade ago, a journalist called Kamala Harris "female Obama". However, the daughter of Indian and Jamaican immigrants failed to match the achievement of first African-American president Barack Obama.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than a decade ago, a journalist called Kamala Harris "female Obama". However, the daughter of Indian and Jamaican immigrants failed to match the achievement of first African-American president Barack Obama.</p>

<p>The Democratic leader's defeat to her Republican rival Donald Trump in a bitterly contested election shattered her dream to become the first woman President of the US. But her nomination enthused women that this door in public life is not closed to them.</p>

<p>Harris, 60, has known other firsts, though. She has been the district attorney for San Francisco -- the first woman, first African-American and first Indian-origin person to be elected to the position.</p>

<p>As vice president, she is the first woman to hold the post. Also, she happens to be the first African-American or Indian-American person to make it there.</p>

<p>In an Op-ed published three days before the November 5 election, Harris recollected her frequent visit to India as a child and remembered her late mother, Shyamala Gopalan, a cancer researcher and civil rights activist.</p>

<p>"Growing up, my mother raised my sister and me to appreciate and honour our heritage. Nearly every other year, we would go to India for Diwali. We would spend time with our grandparents, our uncles, and our 'chitthis' (aunts)," Harris said in the article for The Juggernaut, an online South Asian publication.</p>

<p>She said she believes Americans want a president who works for all American people. "And that has been the story of my entire career," she said.</p>

<p>Harris got her big chance when President Joe Biden abandoned his own bid for reelection in July following his poor performance in a nationally televised debate with Trump. Biden endorsed Harris as the party nominee in the election.</p>

<p>Her nomination fulfilled her presidential dreams, which she abandoned before the primaries in 2019 due to a lack of funds to continue her campaign.</p>

<p>Biden picked her as his running mate in 2016. She was just the third woman to be picked as the vice president nominee on a major party ticket.</p>

<p>And she was one of only three Asian Americans in the Senate and the first Indian-American ever to serve in the chamber.</p>

<p>She has been likened to Barack Obama, the country's first Black President.</p>

<p>More than a decade ago, journalist Gwen Ifill called Harris "the female Barack Obama" on the "Late Show With David Letterman". Later, a small businessman from Willoughby, Tony Pinto, called her "a young, female version of the president".</p>

<p>She is considered close to Obama, who endorsed her in various elections, including that for the US Senate in 2016, Vice President in 2020 and the presidential election in 2024.</p>

<p>Harris was born to two immigrant parents: a Black father and an Indian mother. Her father, Donald Harris, is from Jamaica, and her mother, Shyamala Gopalan, migrated to the US from Chennai in 1958. She, however, defines herself simply as "American".</p>

<p>After her parents divorced, Harris was raised primarily by her Hindu mother. She says that her mother adopted Black culture and immersed her two daughters -- Kamala and her younger sister Maya -- in it. Harris grew up embracing her Indian culture but living a proudly African American life.</p>

<p>"My mother understood very well that she was raising two black daughters," she wrote in her autobiography 'The Truths We Hold'. "She knew that her adopted homeland would see Maya and me as black girls and she was determined to make sure we would grow into confident, proud black women." Harris was born in Oakland and grew up in Berkeley. She spent her high school years living in French-speaking Canada -- her mother was teaching at McGill University in Montreal.</p>

<p>"Harris was raised in a middle-class family by a working mother who taught her to believe in the promise of America. Her mother also taught her the value of hard work, bringing Kamala to her breast cancer research lab and showing her how to clean test tubes as a child," according to the Harris campaign website.</p>

<p>She attended college in the US, spending four years at Howard University, which she has described as among the most formative experiences of her life. After Howard, she went on to earn her law degree at the University of California, Hastings and began her career at the Alameda County District Attorney's Office.</p>

<p>She became the top prosecutor for San Francisco in 2003 before being elected the first woman and the first Black person to serve as California's attorney general in 2010, the top lawyer in America's most populous state.</p>

<p>In her nearly two terms in office as attorney general, Harris gained a reputation as one of the rising stars of the Democratic Party. In 2017, she was sworn into the US Senate, where she championed legislation to fight hunger, provide rent relief, improve maternal health care, expand access to capital for small businesses, revitalise America's infrastructure, and combat the climate crisis.</p>

<p>Harris is married to Douglas Emhoff, a lawyer, for the past 10 years. She is the stepmother of two children, Ella and Cole, who are her "endless source of love and pure joy." Her role as vice president was more than just symbolic. Unlike her predecessors, she wielded considerable power during Biden's presidency.</p>

<p>As president of the Senate, she set a new record for the most tie-breaking votes cast by a Vice President in history - surpassing one that had stood for nearly 200 years. And her votes have been consequential.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dkob4plg_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As vice president, Kamala Harris is the first woman to hold the post (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-us-airport-will-offer-llama-therapy-to-reduce-passengers-travel-anxiety-6958183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This US Airport Will Offer Llama Therapy To Ease Nervous Passengers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-us-airport-will-offer-llama-therapy-to-reduce-passengers-travel-anxiety-6958183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 18:51:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The llamas, dressed in adorable "I heart PDX" neckerchiefs, are part of a larger effort to create a more relaxing airport experience]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Portland International Airport is taking a unique approach to passenger comfort. Their newest employees aren't humans, but rather a herd of therapy llamas! These fluffy friends, provided by Mountain Peaks Therapy Llamas and Alpacas, wander the airport concourse, offering comfort and joy to stressed travellers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The llamas, dressed in adorable "I heart PDX" neckerchiefs, are part of a larger effort to create a more relaxing airport experience, alongside other calming features like natural light and live trees. These llamas are part of a non-profit run by Lori Gregory and Shannon Joy, a mother-daughter team that provides therapeutic visits with their five llamas and six alpacas. The duo brings their llamas to Portland's airport to offer comfort to anxious travellers, providing pets, head scratches, and occasional cuddles for those needing a bit of calm before their flights.</p>

<p>Dressed in "I heart PDX" neckerchiefs, cosy coats, and pompom headbands, these "fluffy professionals" wander through the airport terminal, offering a smile to everyone they meet. Alongside therapy dogs, the llamas are part of the airport's initiative "just to make you smile" and make air travel less stressful.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C3gm9QExsBd/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C3gm9QExsBd/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C3gm9QExsBd/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C3gm9QExsBd/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Portland International Airport (@pdxairport)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Therapy animals differ from service animals in that they don't perform specific tasks but provide a calming presence to those experiencing stress or anxiety. According to UMass Chan Medical School, these animals bring a sense of comfort that can alleviate some symptoms of anxiety and mental health challenges.</p>

<p>The llamas only visit the concourse for as long as is healthy for them. "It's just pure joy," says airport spokesperson Allison Ferre. "Travellers' faces say it best."</p>

<p>The llamas are part of a larger effort by the airport to create a peaceful environment, including a recent terminal redesign featuring natural light, live trees, and other soothing accents. "Being in nature is a stress reliever," Ferre told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2024/11/03/nx-s1-5173755/therapy-animals-portland-airport-llama-alpaca" rel="nofollow, noindex">NPR</a></em>, explaining that the therapy animals are one way to enhance travellers' experiences.</p>

<p>Choosing the right therapy llama, however, isn't easy. Only about one in 15 llamas has the temperament and confidence needed to thrive in busy environments, says Shannon Joy.</p>

<p>These therapy llamas aren't the first animal companions to gain popularity in airports. Duke, a 14-year-old cat in San Francisco International Airport's "Wag Brigade," is one of the most famous. Duke made a splash on social media when he was seen wearing a tiny pilot's hat and shirt collar, joining the team to soothe anxious flyers. And in some cases, travelers have even brought their own emotional support animals on board, finding comfort in their presence during flights.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/07ssdrd8_llama_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Therapy animals differ from service animals]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-donald-trump-s-critic-to-vice-president-jd-vance-signals-new-era-for-republican-party-6957981]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Once A Donald Trump Critic, JD Vance Is Now His Vice-President-Elect]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-donald-trump-s-critic-to-vice-president-jd-vance-signals-new-era-for-republican-party-6957981]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 18:28:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At just 40 years old, JD Vance has become the third-youngest Vice-President in American history and the first millennial to ever appear on a major party's presidential ticket.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has made an extraordinary political comeback, securing his victory as the 47th President of the United States, He defeated his Democratic opponent, Kamala Harris. This marks an extraordinary return for a former president who, just four years ago, refused to accept his election defeat, leading to the violent January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol.</p>

<p>With him comes to the White House Ohio Senator JD Vance, once an outspoken critic of Trump. The new Vice-President-elect's arrival also offers a preview of the direction the Grand Old Party (GOP) is headed ahead in 2028 Trump completes his second term.</p>

<p>At just 40 years old, Vance has become the third-youngest Vice-President in American history and the first millennial to ever appear on a major party's presidential ticket. His political journey, which culminates in his current role as Trump's running mate, provides an intriguing window into the evolving dynamics of the GOP.</p>

<h3><strong>Vance's shifting allegiance from detractor to Trump ally</strong></h3>

<p>Before aligning himself with Trump, Vance was a vocal critic of the former president. In 2016, as Trump prepared for his first presidential run, the senator questioned whether he was “America's Hitler” and later labelled him a “moral disaster.” At the time, Vance publicly condemned Trump as a “total fraud” indifferent to the struggles of ordinary Americans.</p>

<p>But Vance's stance shifted dramatically by 2020. Through several personal meetings at Mar-a-Lago and appearances on Fox News, Vance gradually embraced Trump's politics, culminating in his endorsement during the 2022 Ohio Senate race, which he won.</p>

<p>Vance was one of several Republican figures and potential vice-presidential candidates who publicly expressed their loyalty to Donald Trump by standing with him during his criminal trial related to the hush money case earlier this year in New York.</p>

<h3><strong>Vance's path to the vice presidency</strong></h3>

<p>Trump, known for his flair for drama, delayed his choice of Vice-President until after a highly publicised assassination attempt in Butler, Pennsylvania. Two days following the incident, Trump reached out to Vance, offering him the position, and announced the decision on social media.</p>

<p>Supporters of Vance, including Trump's son Donald Trump Jr and media figure Tucker Carlson, said that Vance was the most loyal of the potential candidates, with a strong connection to Trump. His working-class background, growing up in a struggling Rust Belt town in Ohio, made him a powerful figure to attract crucial battleground voters. Vance's wife, Usha Vance, the daughter of Indian immigrants, was also seen as an added factor in appealing to minority voters.</p>

<h3><strong>Controversies and campaign challenges</strong></h3>

<p>Vance's selection has not been without its controversies. As a public figure, he has been known to make provocative statements -- some resurfaced during the campaign. In a 2021 podcast, he made inflammatory comments about the Democratic Party being led by “childless cat ladies,” which drew a lot of backlash from critics who accused him of promoting a misogynistic agenda. Vance attempted to clarify that the remarks were aimed at the Democratic Party's “anti-family” stance rather than an attack on individuals without children.</p>

<p>Further, controversy erupted when Vance repeated unverified claims about Haitian immigrants allegedly eating pets in Ohio. Despite the lack of evidence to support these claims, Vance defended his comment, saying it was necessary to draw attention to pressing issues such as immigration. “If I have to create stories so that the American media pays attention to the suffering of the American people, then that's what I'm going to do,” Vance had told CNN.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7ihuer48_jd-vance_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vance was a vocal critic of Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/were-better-off-together-german-chancellor-tells-donald-trump-6957957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We're Better Off Together": German Chancellor Tells Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/were-better-off-together-german-chancellor-tells-donald-trump-6957957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 18:21:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on Wednesday congratulated US presidential election winner Donald Trump and urged continued close trans-Atlantic ties, telling him in English: "We're better off together".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on Wednesday congratulated US presidential election winner Donald Trump and urged continued close trans-Atlantic ties, telling him in English: "We're better off together".</p>

<p>"Together we can achieve much more than against each other," added the centre-left leader of Europe's biggest economy.</p>

<p>"Both sides benefit from the trans-Atlantic partnership," Scholz said in a statement to media. "The EU and the USA are two similarly large economic areas, linked by the closest economic relations in the world."</p>

<p>In an earlier message posted on X, Scholz said that "Germany and the USA have long been working together successfully to promote prosperity and freedom on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>

<p>"We will continue to do so for the benefit of our citizens."</p>

<p>The messages amounted to a pledge for a fresh start after Trump's last term in the White House, when he berated the NATO ally on what he deemed insufficient defence spending as well as on trade and other issues.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, just back from a visit to war-torn Ukraine, said that "Germany will be a close, reliable ally for the future American government, that is what we are offering".</p>

<p>"As in any good partnership, where there are undoubtedly political differences, an honest and above all intensive exchange is more important than ever."</p>

<p>She said that during her visit to Ukraine as it continues to fight against Russian forces, "I have felt more clearly than ever before how much depends on Europeans and Americans standing up together for freedom, international law and democracy."</p>

<p>Concern has risen in Ukraine and across Europe as Trump has criticised the scale of US defence spending for Kyiv, and many fear his pledge to bring peace "in 24 hours" could amount to a deal on Moscow's terms.</p>

<p>Baerbock said a just peace "will only be possible with the Ukrainians, with the Europeans and with the USA".</p>

<p>"For me, for us, it is clear: We Europeans will now have to take on even more responsibility for security policy."</p>

<p>Norbert Roettgen, a veteran foreign policy expert from the conservative German opposition party CDU, described Trump's victory in less diplomatic terms.</p>

<p>"Trump is unpredictable," he told the Rheinische Post daily. "If there were further support for Ukraine under him, that would be a surprise. He believes that the Europeans should do it themselves, and this position is popular in the USA."</p>

<p>He predicted a "period of stress in trans-Atlantic relations" and said it would be up to Europe "to do our part much more quickly and comprehensively for the trans-Atlantic partnership."</p>

<p>One of the first German politicians to congratulate Trump was Alice Weidel of the far-right Alternative for Germany, who wrote on X early Wednesday: "Congratulations to Donald J. Trump on becoming the 47th President of the United States!"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/qkhj7ntg_olaf-scholz_625x300_05_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Together we can achieve much more than against each other," said Olaf Scholz. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-you-can-win-against-china-if-key-remarks-made-by-donald-trump-about-china-6957880]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You Can Win Against China If...": Key Remarks Made By Trump About China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-you-can-win-against-china-if-key-remarks-made-by-donald-trump-about-china-6957880]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 18:13:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Wednesday won the US presidential election over Kamala Harris, and world leaders were swift in congratulating the Republican.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Wednesday won the US presidential election over Kamala Harris, and world leaders were swift in congratulating the Republican.</p>

<p>Donald Trump vowed strict trade measures against China on the campaign trail for the White House, and the relationship between Washington and Beijing will be one of the key themes of his tenure.</p>

<p>Here is a selection of comments made by Trump about China:</p>

<p>-- "The concept of global warming was created by and for the Chinese in order to make US manufacturing non-competitive," Trump tweeted in November 2012.</p>

<p>-- "I beat the people from China. I win against China. You can win against China if you're smart. But our people don't have a clue. We give state dinners to the heads of China. I said, 'why are you doing state dinners for them? They're ripping us left and right. Just take them to McDonald's and go back to the negotiating table," Trump said at a July 2015 rally.</p>

<p>-- "We can't continue to allow China to rape our country, and that's what we're doing," Trump told a campaign rally in May 2016, insisting that the United States had "a lot of power with China."</p>

<p>-- "China is letting us down in that they have not been buying the agricultural products from our great Farmers that they said they would," Trump tweeted in July 2019.</p>

<p>-- "For the people that are now out of work because of the important and necessary containment policies, for instance the shutting down of hotels, bars and restaurants, money will soon be coming to you. The onslaught of the Chinese Virus is not your fault! Will be stronger than ever!" he wrote in a tweet in March 2020.</p>

<p>-- "China's pattern of misconduct is well known. For decades, they have ripped off the United States like no one has ever done before. Hundreds of billions of dollars a year were lost dealing with China, especially over the years during the prior administration," he said in May 2020.</p>

<p>-- "As we pursue this bright future, we must hold accountable the nation which unleashed this plague onto the world: China," Trump told the United Nations in September 2020, referring to the coronavirus pandemic.</p>

<p>-- "Think of President Xi: central casting, a brilliant guy. You know, when I say he's brilliant, everyone says, 'Oh that's terrible'... Well, he runs 1.4 billion people with an iron fist. Smart, brilliant, everything perfect. There's nobody in Hollywood like this guy," he said in July 2023 at a Fox News town hall.</p>

<p>-- "I had a very strong relationship with him," Trump said of President Xi to the Wall Street Journal in October 2024. "He was actually a really good, I don't want to say friend -- I don't want to act foolish, 'he was my friend' -- but I got along with him great."</p>

<p>Trump added: "He's a very fierce person."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/t02kgsi_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["China's pattern of misconduct is well known," Donald Trump said on May 2020. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-streak-of-no-woman-president-in-us-continues-kamala-harris-fails-to-create-history-6957707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Woman President For US Yet Again. Kamala Harris Stumbles At Final Hurdle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-streak-of-no-woman-president-in-us-continues-kamala-harris-fails-to-create-history-6957707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:52:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For the second time in eight years, a woman has won the Democratic nomination for US president, only to come up short in a campaign where gender was a central issue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the second time in eight years, a woman has won the Democratic nomination for US president, only to come up short in a campaign where gender was a central issue.</p>

<p>Like Hillary Clinton in 2016, Kamala Harris had a shot at becoming the first woman to occupy the Oval Office but stumbled at the final hurdle.</p>

<p>While the charisma of their opponent -- Donald Trump, in both cases -- clearly played a role in these historic defeats, many observers also saw misogyny as a factor.</p>

<p>In their dueling campaigns, Harris and Trump laid out starkly different visions for women's status and rights.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-leaders-pledge-to-work-with-trump-as-he-claims-us-election-in-6957090">Trump</a>, who has faced multiple accusations of sexual assault he denies, sought to broadcast a hypermasculine image, appearing alongside mixed martial artists and offering praise for autocratic world leaders.</p>

<p>He and his campaign surrogates also made multiple comments that were criticized as insulting or contemptuous of women.</p>

<p>He called<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-people-from-kamala-harris-indian-ancestral-village-in-tamil-nadu-express-disappointment-6957062"> Harris</a> "crazy" and "mentally disabled", and claimed she would be "like a play toy" for other world leaders if elected.</p>

<p>His running mate, Ohio Senator J.D. Vance, doubled down on a quip he made in 2021 about "childless cat ladies" running the country, saying "I've got nothing against cats."</p>

<p>Trump also presented himself as a "protector" of women, saying he would protect them whether they "like it or not."</p>

<h3><strong>Defender of women's rights</strong></h3>

<p>Harris by contrast relied heavily on female celebrities such as Beyonce, Jennifer Lopez, Lady Gaga and Oprah Winfrey, betting that they would help her reach even conservative women voters.</p>

<p>Harris did not campaign openly on the fact that she would have been the first female president of the United States.</p>

<p>But she made the defense of women's rights, and abortion in particular, one of the cornerstones of her campaign.</p>

<p>But this appears not to have won over enough moderately conservative women.</p>

<p>At a campaign rally last month, former first lady Michelle Obama denounced the apparent double standard by which the two White House candidates were judged.</p>

<p>"We expect her to be intelligent and articulate, to have a clear set of policies, to never show too much anger, to prove time and time again that she belongs," she said of Harris.</p>

<p>"But for Trump, we expect nothing at all. No understanding of policy, no ability to put together a coherent argument, no honesty, no decency, no morals."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gumnefag_kamala-harris_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris relied heavily on female celebrities during campaigns.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-who-is-usha-vance-1st-indian-origin-woman-set-to-become-second-lady-of-us-6957638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Usha Vance, 1st Indian-Origin Woman Set To Become Second Lady Of US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-2024-who-is-usha-vance-1st-indian-origin-woman-set-to-become-second-lady-of-us-6957638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:44:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Moments into his victory speech on Tuesday, Trump lauded his running mate JD Vance and his Indian-American wife, Usha Chilukuri Vance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the Palm Beach County Convention Center in Florida, it was midnight when Donald Trump and his entourage appeared on stage to a resounding applause from a crowd eagerly waiting to catch a glimpse of their President-elect. Moments into his victory speech on Tuesday, Trump lauded his running mate JD Vance and his Indian-American wife, Usha Chilukuri Vance.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-live-now-i-can-say-vice-president-donald-trumps-shoutout-to-jd-vance-his-wife-6955555 ">Trump defeated Democratic rival Kamala Harris</a> by a margin of 53 electoral votes. “I want to be the first to congratulate - now I can say Vice President-elect JD Vance. And his remarkable and beautiful wife, Usha Vance,” Trump said, drawing loud cheers from the audience.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Who is Usha Vance?</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Born to Indian parents who emigrated from Andhra Pradesh to the US in 1986, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-india-origin-usha-chilukuri-vance-wife-of-trumps-vice-president-pick-6114615">Usha Chilukuri Vance</a> was raised in a suburb of San Diego, California.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>She earned a bachelor's degree in History from Yale University and went on to complete a Master of Philosophy at the University of Cambridge as a Gates Scholar.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The would-be Second Lady of the United States also held editorial roles at the Yale Journal of Law &amp; Technology and The Yale Law Journal, where she served as Managing Editor and Executive Development Editor, respectively.</li>
	<li>Usha met JD Vance at Yale Law School and got married in 2014 in a ceremony that included a Hindu ritual. Together, they have three children. Throughout JD Vance's political career, Usha has been a supportive partner, often appearing alongside him during his Ohio Senate campaign. Her insights also contributed to JD Vance's well-known memoir, Hillbilly Elegy, which sheds light on the struggles of rural America and was later adapted into a movie directed by Ron Howard.</li>
	<li>She works as a corporate litigator at a&nbsp;firm in San Francisco. Her legal career also includes clerking for US Supreme Court Chief Justice John Roberts and Justice Brett Kavanaugh.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/po369gmg_usha-vance-jd-vance_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Usha Vance works as a corporate litigator at a firm in San Francisco]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-defies-all-odds-wins-2024-election-amid-legal-battles-6957552]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Defies All Odds, Wins 2024 Election Amid Legal Battles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-defies-all-odds-wins-2024-election-amid-legal-battles-6957552]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 17:34:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump touted his ability to "get away with it" as a defining theme of his life story when he first ran for president in 2016 -- boasting that he could shoot someone on New York's Fifth Avenue without losing a single vote.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump touted his ability to "get away with it" as a defining theme of his life story when he first ran for president in 2016 -- boasting that he could shoot someone on New York's Fifth Avenue without losing a single vote.</p>

<p>Fast-forward eight years and America's incoming 47th president looks like Nostradamus, winning the keys to the White House on Wednesday despite incredible odds.</p>

<p>He is the most controversial man in the country, narrowly avoided being killed in an assassination attempt, and at 78 will become the oldest person to take the Oval Office in US history.</p>

<p>And that's before throwing in the fact that he's out on bail in three criminal jurisdictions and fighting gigantic civil penalties for sexual assault and fraud. Despite victory, he faces sentencing in just a few weeks on nearly three-dozen felonies related to his 2016 presidential campaign.</p>

<p>Yet in defeating Democrat Kamala Harris, Trump has once more shown he can defy all political and legal gravity.</p>

<p>Many thought this time he wouldn't manage.</p>

<p>He'd closed out November of last year with a 47.4 percent average in opinion polls -- a number that only shifted by one point upward in the intervening year.</p>

<p>Far from moving to the center, he continued to publicly praise foreign dictators, while threatening fellow Americans with military reprisals. He re-upped his once unprecedented, now trademark, claims that Democrats were trying to rig the election against him.</p>

<p>Trump's longest-serving chief-of-staff called him a "fascist."</p>

<p>For most candidates, any of these controversies, let alone the legal issues, would have been career-ending.</p>

<p>Yet for Trump, controversy is all part of the show.</p>

<p>Even an assassination attempt at a Pennsylvania rally that left him bloodied could not keep down the man whose self-branded persona as the ultimate deal-maker has embedded itself in the American psyche.</p>

<p>Now, Trump is about to be reinstalled as the commander in chief of the most powerful military in history, despite a criminal record that would bar him from serving as a private in the army.</p>

<p>And his legal troubles could disappear as the new president -- emboldened by presidential immunity from prosecution -- issues pardons, fires federal prosecutors and gets backing from a Supreme Court dominated by his allies.</p>

<p><strong>'Enemy from within'</strong></p>

<p>Born wealthy and growing up as a playboy real estate entrepreneur, Trump astonished the world by winning the presidency on a hard-right platform in 2016 against Democratic heavyweight Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>The Republican's first term began with a dark inaugural address evoking "American carnage."</p>

<p>It ended in mayhem when he refused to accept his defeat by Joe Biden, then rallied supporters before they rushed into Congress on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p>In office, Trump upended every tradition, ranging from the trivial (what got planted in the Rose Garden) to the fundamental (relations with NATO).</p>

<p>Journalists became the "enemy of the people" -- a phrase he would later tweak to the "enemy from within" as he called for reprisals against all political opponents.</p>

<p>On the world stage, Trump turned US alliances into transactions as friendly partners like South Korea and Germany were accused of trying to "rip us off."</p>

<p>By contrast, he repeatedly praised -- and continues to praise -- the likes of Russian President Vladimir Putin, China's Xi Jinping and North Korean dictator Kim Jong Un.</p>

<p>Throughout, he increasingly dominated the Republican Party, which dropped all opposition and ended up winning him acquittal in two impeachment proceedings.</p>

<p>That loyalty to Trump only deepened after he left the White House, with senior Republicans regularly trooping to see him at his palatial Florida residence and in the dingy Manhattan courthouse where he was tried for fraud this year.</p>

<p><strong>Autocratic drift</strong></p>

<p>Before he rode down the golden escalator of Trump Tower in New York to announce his 2016 White House bid, Trump was best known as a TV personality.</p>

<p>He was famous mostly for the ruthless character he played on reality show "The Apprentice," as well as for developing luxury buildings and golf resorts, and for his wife Melania, a former fashion model.</p>

<p>The political rise was meteoric. But academics have noted parallels between his evolution and those of autocrats in countries where democratic institutions exist only as facades, allowing populist strongmen to take power.</p>

<p>Millions were thrilled by his attacks on politics, his coarse language, his promises to expel illegal immigrants, and the gaudy glamour that he brought to blue-collar Americans beaten down by globalization and deindustrialization.</p>

<p>At the same time, more than half the country agrees with Trump's top White House aide John Kelly that the tycoon is a fascist, according to a recent ABC poll.</p>

<p>In office, he relished the daily controversy, joking about changing the US Constitution to stay in power indefinitely. As he campaigned to return to power in 2024, he again called for termination of the founding document.</p>

<p>Trump's allies dismiss such talk as mere rhetoric.</p>

<p>But Trump broke all precedent when he refused to concede his 2020 loss, ultimately unleashing a mob on the US Capitol, while his vice president, Mike Pence, went into hiding.</p>

<p>Unprecedented -- but forgiven by just enough US voters to allow the showman to get away with it again.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/annlfduo_donald-trump_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's longest-serving chief-of-staff called him a "fascist."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>