<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 19:06:50 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/youll-leave-through-chimney-inmates-at-nazi-death-camp-in-france-were-told-7072784]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You'll Leave Through Chimney": Nazi Death Camp Inmates In France Were Told]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/youll-leave-through-chimney-inmates-at-nazi-death-camp-in-france-were-told-7072784]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 18:44:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When American soldiers liberated the only Nazi concentration camp in France almost exactly 80 years ago, they found it utterly deserted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When American soldiers liberated the only Nazi concentration camp in France almost exactly 80 years ago, they found it utterly deserted.</p>

<p>Thousands of people were worked to death or murdered in the Natzweiler-Struthof camp in the eastern Alsace region on the German border during World War II.</p>

<p>But when the Americans arrived on November 25, 1944 "they found a totally intact, totally empty camp", historian Cedric Neveu told AFP.</p>

<p>"There wasn't a single SS guard or a single prisoner. The camp was in perfect condition... the Germans probably thought they would return," he added.</p>

<p>Of the 50,000 or so people that were held in Struthof and its satellite camps, "17,000 died or went missing, especially in the death marches of spring 1945," Neveu said.</p>

<p>"You entered here by the big gate. You will leave through the chimney" of the crematorium, the camp commander told prisoners arriving in 1943, according to 100-year-old Henri Mosson -- one of the last surviving French inmates.</p>

<h3><strong>'Night and Fog'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Struthof was opened in 1941 near the village of Natzwiller, 800 metres (2,6000 feet) up in the Vosges mountains.</p>

<p>New waves of prisoners began arriving from 1943 after "Nacht und Nebel" ("Night and Fog") operations, Nazi roundups of political opponents they wished to disappear without trace.</p>

<p>Mosson, a member of the French Resistance, had been arrested in June 1943 and condemned to death.</p>

<p>In November that year, he was brought by train to Rothau, near the camp.</p>

<p>Prisoners were forced into trucks and cars "with blows from rifle butts and dog bites", he said.</p>

<p>"There wasn't enough space, so some had to stand for the final eight kilometres (five miles). One man died" on the way, Mosson recalled.</p>

<p>Prisoners were stripped, had their heads shaved and showered with water heated by the crematorium furnace before going through disinfection.</p>

<p>Mosson got work disinfecting the prisoners' clothes, giving him a chance of survival despite the biting winter cold, summer heat and starvation conditions.</p>

<p>"By the end we had nothing but boiled nettles" to eat, he said, adding that he weighed just 38 kilos (84 pounds) by the time he returned home.</p>

<p>Men from around 30 nationalities were held in Struthof, mostly Poles, Russians and French.</p>

<p>Among the detainees were Jews and Roma as well as Jehovah's Witnesses and regular convicts.</p>

<h3><strong>'Subhumans'</strong></h3>

<p>Political prisoners rounded up in the "Night and Fog" actions were "right at the bottom of the ladder", said Michael Landolt, who runs the European Centre for Deported Resistance Members located close to Struthof.</p>

<p>"They were given the hardest labour and had a higher death rate," he added.</p>

<p>Soviet and Polish prisoners were "considered by the Nazis to be 'Untermenschen' ("subhumans") and very badly mistreated" as well, Landolt said.</p>

<p>Beyond the harsh conditions, Struthof was also the scene of executions and medical experiments.</p>

<p>In August 1943, 86 Jewish prisoners were killed in a gas chamber so their remains could be added to a collection of Jewish skeletons.</p>

<p>Even as Allied forces pushed across France in 1944 and reached the camp, the inmates' suffering was not at an end.</p>

<p>They were forcibly evacuated to other camps on the other side of the Rhine River.</p>

<p>Struthof "continued to exist, like a cancer that has metastasized," historian Neveu described.</p>

<p>Its final end came when those satellite camps were evacuated in the spring of 1945.</p>

<p>After the war, Struthof was used to hold people who had collaborated with the Nazis until 1949, then became a prison.</p>

<p>Only later did it become a memorial site that is now visited by more than 200,000 people each year.</p>

<p>President Emmanuel Macron is among leaders expected to pay tributes to the camp's victims at a commemoration at the site on Saturday.</p>

<p>Most of the prisoners' shacks have long been dismantled, but they are still marked out on the ground.</p>

<p>Visitors can still see the crematorium buildings, the prison and the gas chamber below, as well as walk the avenues of the cemetery where more than one thousand inmates are buried.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6ifjbkho_natzweilerstruthof-nazi-camp-_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[86 prisoners were killed in a gas chamber so as to add their remains to a collection of Jewish skeletons.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-clashes-continue-amid-truce-talks-7072517]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel-Hezbollah Clashes Continue Amid Truce Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-clashes-continue-amid-truce-talks-7072517]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 18:11:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel and Lebanon's Hezbollah traded deadly blows on Thursday as their war raged on despite signs of progress in US ceasefire efforts, with airstrikes pounding Beirut's southern suburbs and rockets flying into northern Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel and Lebanon's Hezbollah traded deadly blows on Thursday as their war raged on despite signs of progress in US ceasefire efforts, with airstrikes pounding Beirut's southern suburbs and rockets flying into northern Israel.</p>

<p>US mediator Amos Hochstein was in Israel for talks with Israeli officials to try to secure a ceasefire which he said was "within our grasp" during a visit to Beirut earlier this week.</p>

<p>The diplomacy marks the most serious attempt yet to end the conflict between Israel and the heavily armed, Iran-backed Hezbollah, part of the regional spillover of the Gaza war that erupted more than a year ago.</p>

<p>In southern Lebanon, an Israeli airstrike killed three people in the village of Chaaitiyeh, some 10 km (6 miles), from the border, the Lebanese health ministry said.</p>

<p>In Israel, a 30-year-old man was killed when shrapnel from a rocket struck a playground in the northern town of Nahariya, Israel's MDA medical service said.</p>

<p>"The Israeli government is not safeguarding my security, my residents or the residents of the north (of Israel). It is not possible to live in such a situation like this," Nahariya Mayor Ronen Marelly told public broadcaster Kan.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said about 10 rockets were launched from Lebanon towards Nahariya. "Most of the projectiles were intercepted and fallen projectiles were identified," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>Channel 12 said three rockets hit the coastal town.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's al-Manar television station, citing its correspondent, confirmed rocket fire towards Nahariya and the surrounding area.</p>

<p>Airstrikes on Beirut's Hezbollah-controlled southern suburbs shook the capital, sending up thick clouds of debris.</p>

<p>The Israeli military issued a statement on X ahead of strikes warning residents they were near Hezbollah targets against which it would soon take action. Residents have largely fled the area since Israel went on the offensive in September.</p>

<p>White House envoy Hochstein left for Israel after declaring progress during two days of talks in Lebanon with officials including Parliament Speaker Nabih Berri, endorsed to negotiate by the Iran-backed Hezbollah. Speaking before he left Beirut, Hochstein said he was going to Israel to try to close an agreement if possible.</p>

<p>The diplomacy aims to end a conflict that has inflicted massive devastation in Lebanon since Israel began its offensive, mounting airstrikes across wide parts of the country and sending in troops.</p>

<p>Footage broadcast by Al Jazeera showed thick smoke rising from the town of Khiyam in southern Lebanon, some 6 km (4 miles) from the border, a focal point of ground battles between Hezbollah fighters and Israeli troops.</p>

<p>Israel says its aim is to secure the return home of tens of thousands of people evacuated from its north due to rocket attacks by Hezbollah, which opened fire in support of Hamas at the start of the Gaza war in October 2023.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has suffered major blows since Israel began its offensive in September, has kept up rocket fire into Israel, attacking Tel Aviv this week. Its fighters are battling Israeli troops on the ground in the south.</p>

<p>The casualty toll since Oct. 2023 stands at 3,558 people killed in Lebanon, the Lebanese health ministry says, most of them killed during the Israeli offensive since September. The figures do not distinguish between combatants and civilians. The ministry said 14 fatalities were reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Hezbollah strikes have killed more than 100 people in northern Israel and the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights. They include more than 70 soldiers killed in strikes in northern Israel and the Golan Heights and in combat in southern Lebanon, according to Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f20pqih_israel-hezbollah-reuters_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military said about 10 rockets were launched from Lebanon towards Nahariya.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-arrest-warrant-icc-live-world-court-issues-arrest-warrant-against-netanyahu-for-war-crimes-7072372]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli PM Netanyahu Faces Arrest For War Crimes After World Court Ruling]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-arrest-warrant-icc-live-world-court-issues-arrest-warrant-against-netanyahu-for-war-crimes-7072372]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:53:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An arrest warrant has been issued today against Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and his Defence Minister Yoav Gallant by the International Criminal Court.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An arrest warrant has been issued today against Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and his Defence Minister Yoav Gallant by the International Criminal Court. The world court at The Hague has charged the Israeli leaders for war crimes committed during the conflicts in Gaza and Lebanon where Israel is at war with Hamas and Hezbollah respectively.</p>

<p>The International Criminal Court or ICC has also charged Hamas's military head Mohammed Deif as a war criminal and has ordered for his arrest.</p>

<p>In an official statement the world court stated that "The Chamber issued warrants of arrest for two individuals, Mr Benjamin Netanyahu and Mr Yoav Gallant, for crimes against humanity and war crimes committed from at least 8 October 2023 until at least 20 May 2024, the day the Prosecution filed the applications for warrants of arrest."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8npvqse8_benjamin-netanyahu-yoav-gallant_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An arrest warrant has been issued against Netanyahu and his Defence Minister Yoav Gallant]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-court-issues-arrest-warrant-against-hamas-chief-benjamin-netanyahu-and-yoav-gallant-7072320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Court Issues Arrest Warrant Against Hamas Chief, Israel PM Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-court-issues-arrest-warrant-against-hamas-chief-benjamin-netanyahu-and-yoav-gallant-7072320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:49:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The International Criminal Court in The Hague said on Thursday that it had issued warrants for the arrest of Hamas leader Mohammed Diab Ibrahim Al-Masri and Israel's President Benjamin Netanyahu and Yoav Gallant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The International Criminal Court in The Hague said on Thursday that it had issued warrants for the arrest of Hamas leader Mohammed Diab Ibrahim Al-Masri (also known as Mohammed Deif) and Israel's President Benjamin Netanyahu and its former defence minister Yoav Gallant.</p>

<p>The ICC said Israel's acceptance of the court's jurisdiction was not required.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a0t7q98o_netanyahu-reuters_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Arrest warrants have been issued against Benjamin Netanyahu and Yoav Gallant.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-firing-of-icbm-on-ukraine-is-weapons-1st-combat-use-in-history-7072318]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia's Firing Of ICBM On Ukraine Is Weapon's 1st Combat Use In History]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-firing-of-icbm-on-ukraine-is-weapons-1st-combat-use-in-history-7072318]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:48:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia reportedly launched an inter-continental ballistic missile (ICBM) on Ukraine, marking the first combat use of the weapon since its inception.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia reportedly launched an inter-continental ballistic missile (ICBM) on Ukraine, marking the first combat use of the weapon since its inception almost six decades ago. Moreover, Moscow used the Multiple Independently Targetable Re-entry Vehicles (MIRV) technology to target "critical infrastructure" in Ukraine's Dnipro, the first-ever use of the technology too.</p>

<p>ICBMs have a range of over 5,500 kilometres and are built to carry nuclear, chemical and biological warheads. It can also <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-launches-icbm-at-ukraine-for-the-first-time-says-kyiv-7071206">carry a conventional warhead</a>, which Russia reportedly used on the RS-26 Rubezh, ballistic missile. The missile was launched from the Astrakhan region of Russia, over 1,000 km away from the damage site in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Videos have surfaced on social media and Telegram handles, where at least warheads re-entering and targeting infrastructure in Ukraine. Russia has "denied to comment" on the launch of ICBMs though Kyiv has confirmed its use.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCoR_xzs2I7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCoR_xzs2I7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCoR_xzs2I7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCoR_xzs2I7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Russian-Ukrainian War (@ukraine_defence)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The launch comes just a day after Putin signed off on changes to the nuclear doctrine. The changes in the doctrine say that an attack from a non-nuclear state backed by a nuclear state will be viewed by Russia as a joint attack on it. Recently, the US has allowed Ukraine to use long-range ATACMS missiles to strike deep into Russia.</p>

<h3><strong>ICBM And The MIRV Tech</strong></h3>

<p>Rubezh is a solid-fueled ICBM equipped with MIRV technology. It was developed in 2011 and was successfully tested for the first time in 2012, hitting a target 5,800 km away from the launch site.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Solid-fuel missiles do not need to be fuelled immediately after launch and are often easier to operate. It's a mixture of fuel and an oxidizer that are bound together by a hard rubbery material and packed in a metal casing.</p>

<p>When solid-propellant in RS-26 burns, the oxygen from the fuel element generates enormous energy, creating thrust and helping in lif-off.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A ballistic missile follows a parabolic trajectory with a boost, mid-course and terminal stage. The highest point where the missile reaches is called apogee and for ICBMs, it is over 4,000 km. During atmospheric re-entry or terminal stage, kinetic energy coupled with the missile's speed reaches over Mach 10, making interception of the missile difficult.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/3bjebl4g_mirv-technology_625x300_11_March_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>ICBMs with MIRV technology, allow multiple targets located at different locations to be engaged from the same missile with several warheads. These warheads could be nuclear or non-nuclear.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These bombs can target locations that are several hundred kilometres apart with the help of the technology and some MIRVed missiles can even hit targets separated by a distance of 1,500 kilometres.</p>

<p>In Dnipro, at least six bombs or warheads were dropped over the region and anti-ballistic missiles (ABM) have to engage with such weapons separately. Therefore, the ABM systems seek to destroy the missile before the separation of the warhead stage.</p>

<p>The US was the first country to develop MIRV technology, deploying a MIRVed Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) in 1970 and a MIRVed Submarine-Launched Ballistic Missile (SLBM) in 1971. The Soviet Union quickly followed suit and by the end of the 1970s had developed their MIRV-enabled ICBM and SLBM technology.</p>

<p>The signing of the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty was significant in cooling down tensions between the US and the Soviets during the Cold War. It required the United States and the Soviet Union to eliminate and permanently forswear all of their nuclear and conventional ground-launched ballistic and cruise missiles with ranges of 500 to 5,500 kilometres. This was the first time the two blocs agreed to reduce their nuclear arsenals.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a result of the INF Treaty, the United States and the Soviet Union destroyed a total of 2,692 short, medium, and intermediate-range missiles by the treaty's implementation deadline of June 1, 1991. In 2019, the United States formally withdrew from the treaty, which now ceases to exist.</p>

<h3><strong>India's ICBMs and MIRV Tech</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/all-about-mission-divyastra-single-missile-can-deploy-multiple-warheads-5218773">This year, India successfully</a> conducted the first flight test of Multiple Independently Targetable Re-entry Vehicles (MIRV) with the Agni-5 Intercontinental Ballistic Missile. The Defence Research and Development Organisation (DRDO) conducted a successful test of the MIRV technology which was in development for several years, putting India on an elite list of nations that have the capability.</p>

<p>The Agni-5 missile has an operational range of at least 5,000 km that can target cities, the MIRV technology puts many cities within that range under the target, providing a broader safety net and several locations under the missile's reach. The true range of missiles is always unknown.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1aoupuag_russia-icbm_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[ICBMs have a range of over 5,500 kilometres.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shocked-by-abduction-of-uganda-opposition-leader-un-human-rights-chief-7072232]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Shocked By Abduction Of Uganda Opposition Leader": UN Human Rights Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shocked-by-abduction-of-uganda-opposition-leader-un-human-rights-chief-7072232]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:40:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN rights chief on Thursday urged the Ugandan government to release opposition politician Kizza Besigye after his apparent kidnapping in Kenya, demanding an investigation into "the circumstances of his abduction".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN rights chief on Thursday urged the Ugandan government to release opposition politician Kizza Besigye after his apparent kidnapping in Kenya, demanding an investigation into "the circumstances of his abduction".</p>

<p>United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Turk said in a statement that he was "shocked by the abduction of Ugandan opposition politician Kizza Besigye on 16 November 2024 in Kenya and his forcible return to Uganda".</p>

<p>"I urge the government to release him, and to ensure any further steps taken on allegations are conducted fully in line with international human rights law," Turk said.</p>

<p>"There also must be full investigations into the circumstances of his abduction."</p>

<p>Besigye, 68, a medical doctor and longtime critic of President Yoweri Museveni, had first been "held in incommunicado detention" before appearing in a military court in Kampala on Wednesday, he said.</p>

<p>Turk warned that the charges against him of illegal firearms possession and security offences "could attract the death penalty".</p>

<p>Besigye appeared in the dock with another opposition figure, Hajji Lutale Kamulegeya, who was also snatched in Nairobi, his lawyer Erias Lukwago told AFP.</p>

<p>The prosecution alleged they were in possession of two pistols and had "solicited logistical support in Uganda, Greece and other countries with the aim of compromising the country's national security", Lukwago said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Besigye, a retired army colonel, denied the charges and insisted he was now a civilian and should not be tried in a military tribunal.</p>

<p>He was remanded to Luzira prison until December 2.</p>

<p>Once Museveni's trusted personal physician, Besigye has been repeatedly targeted by the authorities since falling out with the president in the late 1990s and running unsuccessfully against him in four elections.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His wife Winnie Byanyima, executive director of UNAIDS, the United Nations Programme on HIV and AIDS, first sounded the alarm on X saying her husband was kidnapped while in Nairobi for a book launch by Kenyan opposition politician Martha Karua.</p>

<p>In fresh posts on Thursday, she insisted that he had "not owned a gun in the last 20 years", and should not be tried in a military court.</p>

<p>Turk highlighted that Besigye's forced return to Uganda "follows the abduction from Kenya in July of 36 other members of the party who were subsequently returned to Uganda and charged with terrorism".</p>

<p>"Such abductions of Ugandan opposition leaders and supporters must stop, as must the deeply concerning practice in Uganda of prosecuting civilians in military courts," he said.</p>

<p>He pointed to findings by the UN Human Rights Committee that "civilians tried in Uganda's military courts do not receive the same due process guarantees as those in civilian courts", and its recommendation "that Uganda remove, without further delay, the jurisdiction of military courts over civilians".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vlcsdb1g_volker-turk-on-kizza-besigye-kidnapping-split-_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volker Turk said that Kizza Besigye's forced return to Uganda follows the abduction from Kenya in July.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/worlds-tallest-and-shortest-women-meet-in-london-for-guinness-world-records-day-7072183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tallest And Shortest Women Meet To Celebrate Guinness World Records Day]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/worlds-tallest-and-shortest-women-meet-in-london-for-guinness-world-records-day-7072183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:31:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The worlds tallest woman, Rumeysa Geligo from Turkey, and shortest woman, Jyoti Amge from India, met in London to celebrate Guinness World Records Day 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's not often that the world's tallest and shortest people cross paths, and it's always a spectacular moment when they do. On November 13th, 2024, the official Guinness World Records Day, the tallest and shortest ladies in the world got together for afternoon tea in London in a touching moment.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2024/11/tallest-and-shortest-women-meet-in-london-to-celebrate-gwr-day-2024-with-iconic-afternoon-tea"><em>GWR,</em></a> Jyoti Amge and Rumeysa Gelgi (respectively the shortest and tallest women living) celebrated their first meeting with a lush afternoon tea at The Savoy Hotel, in the heart of London. The two women, who embody some of the most loved and iconic titles at Guinness World Records, were looking forward to spending a lavish "girls' day out" together. They got to know each other during a relaxing morning, enjoying delicious tea and pastries.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCoE8BCMQy6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCoE8BCMQy6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCoE8BCMQy6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCoE8BCMQy6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by NDTV (@ndtv)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Rumeysa is known worldwide as the tallest woman living, standing at 215.16 cm (7 ft 0.7 in), while Jyoti is the shortest woman living (mobile), a title she has proudly held for over a decade, measuring 62.8 cm (2 ft 0.7 in). Despite a whopping height gap of 152.36 cm (five feet), the two became fast friends as they sipped traditional English tea and bonded over life experiences and a shared love for fashion and self-care, as per the British reference book.</p>

<p>"Meeting Jyoti for the first time was wonderful," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2024/11/tallest-and-shortest-women-meet-in-london-to-celebrate-gwr-day-2024-with-iconic-afternoon-tea">Rumeysa told GWR</a> about the encounter."She's the most gorgeous lady. I was waiting to meet her for a long time."</p>

<p>"I'm used to looking up and seeing people taller than me," Jyoti added, "but I was so happy to look up today and see the world's tallest woman."</p>

<p>Rumeysa added they had a fabulous time talking about their shared hobbies and exchanging make-up and self-care tips.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vviqhmko_guinness-world-record-icons_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The pair have been honoured as Guinness World Record icons in the book's 70th edition.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-abandons-wife-after-her-late-stage-cancer-diagnosis-faces-jail-after-her-death-7072069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Man Jailed For Abandoning Terminal-Cancer Wife 2 Months After Wedding]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-abandons-wife-after-her-late-stage-cancer-diagnosis-faces-jail-after-her-death-7072069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:19:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Feng initially cared for her but soon used out-of-town work commitments as a pretext to desert her.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a recent case in China, a man was jailed after abandoning his newlywed wife, who was diagnosed with terminal cancer, just two months after their wedding. The court labelled his actions as "vicious" and ruled that his neglect and emotional abuse violated his legal duties as a spouse. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3287286/vicious-man-china-jailed-deserting-terminal-cancer-wife-2-months-after-wedding">South China Morning Post</a></em>, the man, identified only by his surname Feng, married his wife, surnamed Wang, in 2022. Two months later, Wang was diagnosed with intestinal cancer, which had already progressed to its terminal stage.</p>

<p>Feng initially cared for her but soon used work commitments in another city as an excuse to evade his responsibilities and desert her. Despite Wang's and her family's frantic efforts to contact him, Feng remained unresponsive. Left to face her ordeal alone, Wang struggled financially, accumulating substantial hospital debt. Heartbreakingly, she died&nbsp;after spending more than 200 days in hospital.</p>

<p>After Feng's abandonment, Wang's family took legal action, filing a lawsuit against him at the Shitai County People's Court. The suit targeted Feng's refusal to provide care and financial support during Wang's battle with terminal cancer.&nbsp;Feng had also proposed divorce twice while Wang was gravely ill.</p>

<p>Wang's father denounced Feng's "vicious behaviour," revealing his futile attempts to reach him through phone calls, messaging apps, and even police interventions. After being summoned back to court, Feng eventually settled with Wang's family and secured their forgiveness.</p>

<p>Feng's shocking actions ignited a firestorm of outrage on mainland Chinese social media, with internet users condemning his callous abandonment of his terminally ill wife. Many called for stricter laws to protect vulnerable family members and hold accountable those who abandoned their loved ones. One user said, "He is not a human being. He abandoned his wife when she needed him the most."</p>

<p>Another remarked, "What a cold-blooded person. This crosses all moral boundaries."</p>

<p>In a strikingly similar case, a man from southern Hunan province faced severe consequences for abandoning his ailing wife in 2018. After she was diagnosed with uremia, he refused to return home to care for her or cover her medical expenses. Following her death, the man's indifference continued, as he failed to arrange or attend her funeral. The court took swift action, handing down a one-year jail sentence, suspended for two years.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d75igmb_patient_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Feng's shocking actions ignited a firestorm of outrage on mainland Chinese social media]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-australia-sign-deal-for-air-to-air-refuelling-of-military-aircraft-7071939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, Australia Sign Deal For Air-To-Air Refuelling Of Military Aircraft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-australia-sign-deal-for-air-to-air-refuelling-of-military-aircraft-7071939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:01:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia and India have signed an arrangement to enable the Royal Australian Air Force (RAAF) and India's armed forces to conduct air-to-air refuelling. This will greatly enhance interoperability between the air forces of the two friendly nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia and India have signed an arrangement to enable the Royal Australian Air Force (RAAF) and India's armed forces to conduct air-to-air refuelling. This will greatly enhance interoperability between the air forces of the two friendly nations.</p>

<p>Air-to-air refuelling helps extend the range of fighter jets and other military aircraft to conduct operations far away from their base.</p>

<p>Australia's Minister for Defence Industry and Capability Delivery Pat Conroy MP and Defence Minister Rajnath Singh announced the arrangement during bilateral discussions today.</p>

<p>Under the arrangement, RAAF's air-to-air refuelling aircraft, the KC-30A multi-role tanker transport, will be able to refuel aircraft of India's armed forces.</p>

<p>Australia's Deputy Chief of Air Force Air Vice-Marshal Harvey Reynolds signed the arrangement on November 19 in New at the Australia-India Air Staff Talks, a statement said.</p>

<p>Air Vice-Marshal Reynolds welcomed the arrangement, saying it strengthens the defence relationship between Australia and India.</p>

<p>"India is a top-tier security partner for Australia, and through our Comprehensive Strategic Partnership we are continuing to prioritise practical and tangible cooperation that directly contributes to Indo-Pacific stability," Air Vice-Marshal Reynolds said in the statement.</p>

<p>"The ability to conduct air-to-air refuelling with the Indian Armed Forces elevates our interoperability and enables us to cooperate more effectively in a range of different scenarios. This arrangement is a significant step forward in our relationship with India, and will provide valuable opportunities for our personnel to work closely together, share knowledge and expertise, and build trust and understanding," he said.</p>

<p>The RAAF also conducts training and engagement activities with Indian Navy P-8I Neptune surveillance aircraft. The signing of this arrangement is the first step towards KC-30A refuelling the P-8I, increasing India's reach and persistence in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ib0qgi88_kc30a_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[RAAF KC-30A aircraft takes off from RAAF Base Amberley during Exercise Pitch Black 24]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/fresh-start-you-will-soon-be-able-to-reset-your-instagram-algorithm-heres-how-7071742]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[You Will Soon Be Able To Reset Your Instagram Algorithm. Here's How]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/fresh-start-you-will-soon-be-able-to-reset-your-instagram-algorithm-heres-how-7071742]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 16:38:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While the algorithm reset is only in a testing phase now, Instagram plans to roll it out globally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Instagram is rolling out a new groundbreaking feature that will allow users to reset the algorithm that determines what they see in their feeds. According to Meta, Instagram's parent company, this update was specifically designed with teen safety in mind. "We want to make sure everyone on Instagram, especially teens, has safe, positive, age-appropriate experiences and feels the time they're spending on Instagram is valuable," a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://about.fb.com/news/2024/11/introducing-recommendations-reset-instagram/" rel="nofollow, noindex">company blog post </a>on November 19, said.</p>

<h3><strong>How will it work?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>The new feature will allow users to manually reset recommended content across Explore, Reels, and Feed tabs, providing a "fresh start".</li>
	<li>Once reset, the app will provide recommendations tailored to new preferences, breaking away from previously suggested topics.</li>
	<li>Users will also have greater control over their experience by marking content as "interested"&nbsp;or "not interested,"&nbsp;helping refine algorithmic suggestions over time.</li>
</ul>

<p>"That's why we've started testing the ability for everyone on Instagram  including teens  to reset their recommendations. In just a few taps, you'll be able to clear your recommended content across Explore, Reels and Feed and start fresh.&nbsp;Your recommendations will start to personalize again over time, showing new content based on the content and accounts you interact with. When resetting, you'll also have the option to review the accounts you're following and unfollow any that share content you no longer want to see," the blog added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The blog post states this new feature builds upon tools that Instagram already offers users to curate their content recommendations. However, the reset cannot be undone once started. While the algorithm reset is only in a testing phase now, Instagram plans to roll it out globally.</p>

<p>The update comes amidst growing concerns over social media's impact on teens' mental health. Research, including a study by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/fullarticle/2749480">Journal of the American Medical Association</a>, has highlighted the risks associated with excessive social media use. For instance, teens spending over three hours a day on these platforms face double the risk of depression and anxiety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meta hopes this new feature will help "give teens new ways to shape their Instagram experience, so it can continue to reflect their passions and interests as they evolve."</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k0imb0o8_instagram_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to Meta, this update was specifically designed with teen safety in mind.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-ellen-degeneres-moving-countries-after-donald-trump-win-will-stay-7071734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Where Ellen DeGeneres, Moving Countries After Trump Win, Will Stay]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-ellen-degeneres-moving-countries-after-donald-trump-win-will-stay-7071734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 16:37:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On another note, DeGeneres was also a high-profile donor for Vice President Kamala Harris - contributing about $3,300 to her campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the majority, staying in a place that aligns with one's political views would top their priority list. Many A-list celebrities have expressed their wishes to leave the country post Donald Trump's election as the President of the United States.</p>

<p>However, Ellen DeGeneres has already made that a reality with her wife Portia de Rossi. The couple moved to Cotswolds, a rural area in south central England after listing their massive Montecito Estate north of Los Angeles.</p>

<p>According to entertainment website, TMZ, which cited sources with "direct knowledge", the driving force behind their relocation was Trump's win apart from other motivating factors. They were "very disillusioned" with Trump's victory and decided "to get the hell out".</p>

<p>On another note, DeGeneres was also a high-profile donor for Vice President Kamala Harris - contributing about $3,300 to her campaign. She also went ahead and endorsed Harris on her Instagram saying, "There's nothing more powerful than a woman whose time has come!! I can't wait for @KamalaHarris to be our next president."</p>

<p>On October 8th 2024, DeGeneres had reposted a photo from actress Jamie Lee Curtis which said, "You can't tell someone you love them and then vote for someone who will hurt them" captioning it as, "This is beyond politics. It is about love and inclusion vs hate and violence."&nbsp;<br />
She caught heavy flak because of the post with most comments supporting Trump. But she is one to frequently back the Democrats, and very vocally so.</p>

<p>However, apart from Degeneres and Rossi, there have been other celebrities who have voiced their desire to leave the country. Sharon Stone has told The Daily Mail, "I am certainly considering a house in Italy. I think that's an intelligent construct at this time. This is one of the first times in my life that I've actually seen anyone running for office on a platform of hate and oppression."</p>

<p>According to The Guardian, Cher had been horrified by the possibility of Trump coming back to office and said, "I almost got an ulcer the last time. If he gets in, who knows? This time I will leave [the country]."</p>

<p>Ironically, even Elon Musk's daughter Vivian Jenna Wilson, plans to leave the United States after Trump's election win. She posted on Threads, "I've thought this for a while, but yesterday confirmed it for me. I don't see my future being in the United States. Even if he's only in office for 4 years, even if the anti-trans regulations magically don't happen, the people who willingly voted this in are not going anywhere anytime soon."</p>

<p>In the wake of ending her popular talk show, DeGeneres has focussed on gardening and raising chickens and has kept her personal life private. She has also not announced any upcoming projects.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ktvm9ht8_ellen-degeneres-x-photo_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple moved to Cotswolds, a rural area in south central England.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/ellen-degeneres-and-partner-portia-de-rossi-leave-us-after-trumps-win-report-7071397]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ellen DeGeneres, Partner Portia de Rossi Leave US After Trump's Win: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/ellen-degeneres-and-partner-portia-de-rossi-leave-us-after-trumps-win-report-7071397]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:53:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After Trump's win, Ellen and Portia put their Montecito mansion up for sale and plan to list another California property.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ellen DeGeneres and her partner, Portia de Rossi, have reportedly left the United States following Donald Trump's victory in the 2024 US presidential election. The couple, who were strong supporters of Kamala Harris, decided to "get the hell out" of the country as they were "very disillusioned" with Trump's victory.&nbsp;According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.tmz.com/2024/11/20/ellen-degeneres-and-portia-de-rossi-move-to-england-after-trump-election-win/#continued">TMZ,</a></em> they've relocated to the Cotswolds, a region in South West England, about two hours from London, where they had already purchased a home before the election. This move isn't just a temporary departure, as sources claim they won't return to the States.</p>

<p>DeGeneres, a longtime comedian and TV show host, had endorsed Kamala Harris, expressing her excitement for Harris to become the next president. In August, she publicly endorsed Harris on Instagram. "There's nothing more powerful than a woman whose time has come!! I can't wait for @KamalaHarris to be our next president," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-_1EZcxtj0/">she wrote&nbsp;in the caption.</a></p>

<p>&nbsp;After Trump's win, the couple put their Montecito mansion up for sale and plan to list another California property.</p>

<p>Not just DeGeneres and Rossi, Donald Trump's victory in the 2024 presidential election has prompted several Hollywood celebrities to publicly declare their intention to leave the United States. Many are criticising Trump's policies and expressing fears about the country's future, leading them to seek refuge abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Some of these celebrities include Eva Longoria, who has already divided her time between Spain and Mexico, citing America's transformation into a "dystopian country". Jimmy Kimmel jokingly announced his departure during a late-night show, while Guillermo Rodriguez quipped about returning to Mexico.</p>

<p>Sharon Stone, a Hollywood A-lister, has also expressed interest in purchasing a home in Italy. Meanwhile, music icon Cher had previously threatened to take drastic measures if Donald Trump were to secure the presidency again.</p>

<p>America Ferrera, Barbra Streisand, Laverne Cox, Minnie Driver and Raven-Symone are the other celebrities who are&nbsp;considering leaving the United States. The United Kingdom, particularly London's cosmopolitan charm, and Italy with its rich culture and breathtaking landscapes have emerged as top choices for relocation. Canada, another favoured destination, offers proximity to the US, familiarity, and progressive policies that appeal to many.&nbsp;Other countries, such as Spain, Mexico, Australia, and New Zealand, are also being considered by celebrity expats.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6mj1jit8_ellen-degeneres-and-portia-de-rossi_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ellen, a longtime comedian and TV show host, had endorsed Kamala Harris]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-launches-icbm-at-ukraine-for-the-first-time-says-kyiv-7071206]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Launches ICBM At Ukraine In Stern Message To Kyiv, Western Allies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-launches-icbm-at-ukraine-for-the-first-time-says-kyiv-7071206]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:27:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia has fired an Inter-Continental Ballistic Missile or ICBM at Ukraine a day after Vladimir Putin changed Moscow's nuclear doctrine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia has fired an Inter-Continental Ballistic Missile or ICBM at Ukraine a day after Vladimir Putin changed Moscow's nuclear doctrine. The firing of the ICBM with a conventional (non-nuclear) warhead is a stern warning to Ukraine and its Western allies that Moscow's red lines must be respected.</p>

<p>Inter-Continental Ballistic Missiles, popularly referred as ICBMs are traditionally designed to carry a nuclear warhead, however it may also be used for conventional warheads. The concept, technology, design, and research behind ICBMs were to cater to a country's response in a nuclear event.</p>

<p>Moscow's strong response comes days after US President Joe Biden and UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer allowed Ukraine to use western long-range cruise and ballistic missiles to target deep within Russian territory. Within hours of those approvals from Washington and London, Kyiv fired a US-made ATACMS missile and a UK-made 'Storm Shadow' missile targeting Russian territories.</p>

<p>This is the first time Moscow has fired an ICBM, said Kyiv, as both sides saw major escalations in the war that marked its 1,000th day on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian Air Force released a statement today in which it said that Russian forces had launched various types of missiles at the central Ukrainian city of Dnipro this morning. The aim, they said, was to cripple Ukrainian infrastructure.</p>

<p>The statement went on to say that "In particular, an intercontinental ballistic missile was launched from the Astrakhan region of the Russian Federation." According to a news report by AFP, a source in the Ukrainian Air Force has confirmed that it was the first time since the beginning of the war in Ukraine that an ICBM was fired.</p>

<p>When questioned about the ICBM launch, Moscow evaded the question. Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov said he had "nothing to say on this topic."</p>

<p>The Kremlin, however, did claim it was making "maximum effort" to avoid a nuclear conflict after it updated its nuclear doctrine this week. The new policy allows Moscow to use nuclear weapons against non-nuclear states and Russia said it should be seen as a warning to the West.</p>

<p>"We have stressed in the context of our doctrine that Russia is taking a responsible position to make maximum effort not to allow such a conflict," the Russian spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Ukraine's Air Force said in its statement that it had successfully downed six missiles fired by Moscow, however it did not specify whether the Russian ICBM was one of them. Russian aerial bombardment has reportedly damaged several homes in Dnipro, while also causing wide-scale destruction across the city. An industrial complex and a rehabilitation centre was also destroyed.</p>

<p>Moscow too, said its air defence systems had downed two Storm Shadow missiles, but did not specify if they were downed within Ukrainian airspace or on Russian territory.</p>

<p>The more than two-and-a-half-year long war between Russia and Ukraine has moved further away from the diplomacy and dialogue table with a massive escalation by both sides, especially after crossing the grim and unfortunate 1,000th-day mark.</p>

<p>Both sides have used deadly long-range missiles to show its muscular posturing, even as several world leaders have urged Putin and Zelensky to resort to diplomacy to find an agreeable outcome to the war.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jnf8l4sk_russia-nuclear-missile-drill-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has fired an Inter-Continental Ballistic Missile or ICBM at Ukraine today. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/squirrel-cage-jail-the-haunted-prison-where-anmol-bishnoi-is-now-incarcerated-7070715]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chilling History Of Squirrel Cage Jail, Where Anmol Bishnoi Is Lodged]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/squirrel-cage-jail-the-haunted-prison-where-anmol-bishnoi-is-now-incarcerated-7070715]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:04:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anmol Bishnoi, the younger sibling of gangster Lawrence Bishnoi, was arrested in the US a few days ago for entering that country with illegal documents, sources told NDTV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anmol Bishnoi, the younger sibling of gangster Lawrence Bishnoi, was arrested in the US a few days ago for entering that country with illegal documents, sources told <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/gangster-lawrence-bishnois-brother-anmol-bishnoi-arrested-in-us-sources-7048663">NDTV</a>. The 26-year-old is wanted in several high-profile cases, including the 2022 murder of Punjabi singer Sidhu Moosewala. He is also accused in last month's killing of ex-Maharashtra minister Baba Siddique and the firing incident outside actor Salman Khan's Mumbai home in June 2024.</p>

<p>Bishnoi is currently at the Pottawattamie County Jail in Iowa, a facility known as the Squirrel Cage Jail.'<br />
<br />
<strong>All about the Squirrel Cage Jail</strong><br />
<br />
The Squirrel Cage Jail, an architectural marvel with a chilling history, was constructed in 1885 on the grounds of a former church morgue. One of the only three remaining revolving jails in the US, it is renowned for its eerie and unsettling design. The jail is unique for its rotating cells that revolve within a circular structure to align with a single door. This peculiar design allowed jailers to rotate the cells to reach the desired prisoner, an architectural feature that continues to intrigue and unsettle visitors.</p>

<p>The facility was used as a jail until 1969. In 1971, it was acquired by the Council Bluffs Park Board for preservation and transformed into a museum by the Historical Society of Pottawattamie County (HSPS). Since its conversion, the jail has attracted considerable attention, particularly for its paranormal reputation. Reports of strange occurrences, such as unexplained footsteps and whispers, have surfaced for decades, particularly from staff and visitors to the site.</p>

<p>Many of the jail staff and volunteers have heard footsteps, voices, whispers and doors moving. Some have even seen dark shadows moving across the stairs or past doorways, an article on the Council Bluffs website quoted Kat Slaughter, the museum's manager, as saying.</p>

<p>The haunting at the jail has been linked to a series of tragic events over the years. At least four known deaths occurred within the building. A prisoner died of a heart attack, another fell from a great height while attempting to carve his name on the ceiling, a third died by suicide and a guard was fatally shot during a mishap with riot training equipment.</p>

<p>Paranormal experts have conducted multiple investigations at the site, with some capturing unexplained phenomena, including Electronic Voice Phenomena (EVPs) and visual evidence of shadows. Slaughter notes that investigators have recorded electromagnetic field (EMF) anomalies in areas where there should be none, further adding to the jail's mystique.</p>

<p>According to the HSPS, the walls of this jail bear the scratched signatures and dates of many of its infamous prisoners. These markings stand as proof of the jail's grim past, which is unlikely to be replicated in a modern facility, stated HSPS on its website.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/e3po5sdg_squirrel-jail-facebook-_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oldest-known-human-has-fascinating-secrets-even-50-years-after-discovery-7070824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oldest Known Human Has Fascinating Secrets Even 50 Years After Discovery]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oldest-known-human-has-fascinating-secrets-even-50-years-after-discovery-7070824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:31:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lucy was often described as "the grandmother of humanity", but more recent discoveries suggest she may have been more like an aunt or a cousin, experts say.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>She was, for a while, the oldest known member of the human family. Fifty years after the discovery of Lucy in Ethiopia, the remarkable remains continue to yield theories and questions.</p>

<p>In a non-descript room in the National Museum of Ethiopia, the 3.18-million-year-old bones are delicately removed from a safe and placed on a long table.</p>

<p>They consist of fossilised dental remains, skull fragments, parts of the pelvis and femur that make up the world's most famous Australopithecus afarensis, Lucy.</p>

<p>The hominid was discovered on November 24, 1974, in the Afar region of northeast Ethiopia by a team of scientists led by Maurice Taieb, Yves Coppens, Donald Johanson, Jon Kalb, and Raymonde Bonnefille.</p>

<p>The 52 bone fragments, amounting to some 40 percent of Lucy's skeleton, was, at the time, the most complete ever found, and revolutionised the understanding of our ancestors.</p>

<p>The skeleton was initially called A.L-288-1, in reference to Afar and its geolocation.</p>

<p>But the researchers nicknamed it Lucy after The Beatles' song "Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds", which they listened to after celebrating their discovery.</p>

<p>Lucy walked on two legs and is thought to have died aged between 11 and 13 -- considered an adult for this species. She was 1.10 metres tall (3.6 feet) and weighed 29 kg (64 pounds).</p>

<p>For Sahleselasie Melaku, the 31-year-old head of the palaeontology department, Lucy's discovery represented an emergence from a "dark age" in our understanding of human ancestors.</p>

<p>"The impact of the discovery was very big in the discipline and even the whole world," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Lucy showed that members of the human family existed beyond three million years ago, and she also provided a template for fitting together later bone discoveries.</p>

<p>The amount of information that can be gleaned from the bones has allowed some highly detailed theories about Lucy's life.</p>

<p>A slightly deformed vertebra, for instance, "means she probably had back problems", said Melaku.</p>

<p><strong>'Exceptional'</strong></p>

<p>Jean-Renaud Boisserie, a paleonthologist specialised in Ethiopia and the research director at the French National Centre for Scientific Research said it was an "exceptional" breakthrough for the discipline.</p>

<p>"We basically knew very little about the period of three million years ago, and we had nothing as complete," he said.</p>

<p>Lucy was often described as "the grandmother of humanity", but more recent discoveries suggest she may have been more like an aunt or a cousin, experts say.</p>

<p>Skeletal finds in places like Ethiopia, South Africa and Kenya have complicated the picture and led to much debate about when different species of hominid emerged and which should be classified as part of the human or chimpanzee families.</p>

<p>The discovery of "Toumai" in Chad in 2001 -- a skull dated to six or seven million years old -- suggested the human family may go much further back than previously thought.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Lucy has yet to reveal all her secrets.</p>

<p>A study published in 2016 argued she spent a third of her time in trees, where she nested, and had highly developed upper limbs.</p>

<p>Another study that year in the American journal Plos One theorised that she died after falling from a tree.</p>

<p>A 2022 study in Nature, focused on Lucy's pelvis, concluded that newborn members of Australopithecus had a very immature brain, like human newborns today, and required parental support to survive.</p>

<p>"There are a lot of unanswered questions," said Melaku with a smile. "Especially, we don't know much more about the early livelihoods of these early human ancestors."</p>

<p>The museum receives frequent requests to study it, but the iconic skeleton no longer leaves Ethiopia.</p>

<p>Wider scientific progress and advanced equipment are opening up new avenues for research.</p>

<p>"The studies that can be carried out on her, on her peers, pose the scientific questions of tomorrow," said Boisserie.</p>

<p>"Material as exceptional as this plays a driving role in the evolution of research."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/675l3ci8_fossil-skeleton-of-lucy_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bone fragments of the fossil skeleton of 'Lucy' displayed at the National Museum of Ethiopia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jeff-bezos-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-was-telling-everyone-elon-musks-claim-about-amazon-ceo-7070783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Jeff Bezos Was Telling Everyone...": Elon Musk's Claim About Amazon CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jeff-bezos-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-was-telling-everyone-elon-musks-claim-about-amazon-ceo-7070783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:27:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[X boss Elon Musk, who is set to take over as co-chair of the proposed Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) in the second Donald Trump administration, has claimed that Amazon head Jeff Bezos had advised people to sell Tesla and SpaceX stocks]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>X boss Elon Musk, who is set to take over as co-chair of the proposed Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) in the second Donald Trump administration, has claimed that Amazon head Jeff Bezos had advised people to sell their Tesla and SpaceX stocks because he expected the Republican leader to lose the US election.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Just learned tonight at Mar-a-Lago that Jeff Bezos was telling everyone that <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a> would lose for sure, so they should sell all their Tesla and SpaceX stock ?</p>
 Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1859483544612913376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Just learned tonight at Mar-a-Lago that Jeff Bezos was telling everyone that @realDonaldTrump would lose for sure, so they should sell all their Tesla and SpaceX stock," Musk, who is the CEO of both Tesla and SpaceX, wrote in a post on X today.</p>

<p>Bezos, who also owns The Washington Post and aerospace giant Blue Origin, has not responded to the remark yet.</p>

<p>After the US election results showed a triumphant Trump victory, Bezos had put out a post congratulating the 78-year-old leader.&nbsp;"Big congratulations to our 45th and now 47th President on an extraordinary political comeback and decisive victory. No nation has bigger opportunities. Wishing @realDonaldTrump all success in leading and uniting the America we all love," he said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Big congratulations to our 45th and now 47th President on an extraordinary political comeback and decisive victory. No nation has bigger opportunities. Wishing <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a> all success in leading and uniting the America we all love.</p>
 Jeff Bezos (@JeffBezos) <a href="https://twitter.com/JeffBezos/status/1854184441511571765?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Earlier, the Amazon CEO made headlines after The Washington Post decided to stop making presidential endorsements. The news organisation's move sparked a wave of criticism. In response, Bezos argued that the decision could help improve credibility. He wrote in an op-ed article that presidential endorsements created the "perception of bias" and did not "tip the scales" of an election.</p>

<p>"No undecided voters in Pennsylvania are going to say, 'I'm going with Newspaper A's endorsement'. None," Bezos wrote, defending the move. "What presidential endorsements actually do is create a perception of bias. A perception of non-independence. Ending them is a principled decision, and it's the right one."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/p2hnndpo_elon-and-jeff_625x300_22_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has claimed Jeff Bezos was sure that Donald Trump would lose]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-usage-quickly-broadens-from-it-to-hr-and-marketing-survey-shows-7070778]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Usage Quickly Broadens From IT To HR And Marketing, Survey Shows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-usage-quickly-broadens-from-it-to-hr-and-marketing-survey-shows-7070778]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:25:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[About 72% of decision makers reported that generative AI is used at least once a week, up from 37% in 2023, the first year of the survey.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The use of generative artificial intelligence has quickly become ubiquitous across various types of jobs over the past year, spreading from information technology to areas like human resources, according to a survey of 800 business leaders at <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/article/how-are-companies-really-using-ai-a-new-report-has-answers/" rel="nofollow,noindex">large corporations</a>.</p>

<p>About 72% of decision makers reported that generative AI is used at least once a week, up from 37% in 2023, the first year of the survey, according to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/2024-ai-adoption-report/" rel="nofollow,noindex">report</a> by the Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania and marketing consulting firm GBK Collective.</p>

<p>Adoption picked up in areas that had a slow start last year, including HR but also marketing and operations. In legal and finance, which were added this year to the survey, weekly usage is almost as prevalent as in IT.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2fk56d8g_artificial-intelligence_625x300_21_November_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Firms have moved beyond the initial hype and amazement around generative AI toward more practical usage, the report found.</p>

<p>The most-cited uses include document and proposal writing and editing, with 64% of total respondents, followed closely by data analyses and analytics, at 62%. Other functions cited by more than half of the decision makers include customer service and support, fraud detection and prevention, and financial forecasting and planning.</p>

<p>Many questions about generative AI remain unanswered, including how many people might lose their jobs as a result of widespread adoption and how many new jobs will be created.</p>

<p>Almost all respondents working in purchasing and procurement said that generative AI will enhance their employees' skills, while almost nine in 10 in finance think it will replace skills, according to the survey,</p>

<p>Overall, the survey shows a small shift in perception compared with last year. A slightly higher percentage of business leaders say generative AI will enhance skills, while a slightly lower share think it will replace skills in some tasks.</p>

<p>The survey shows that the gap is closing between the two extreme beliefs about AI being either a harbinger of doom or a gateway to utopia, said Wharton marketing professor Stefano Puntoni, co-author of the report and faculty co-director of AI at Wharton.</p>

<p>Organizations will keep experimenting with AI to figure out how it works best for them, Puntoni said in a post about the report. This is only the beginning.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/llqnvhlg_ai-usage-it_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The use of generative AI has quickly become ubiquitous across various types of jobs over the past year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/c-a-r-i-c-o-m-spells-out-7-key-pillars-of-india-caribbean-cooperation-pm-modi-7070707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[C-A-R-I-C-O-M Spells Out 7 Key Pillars Of India-Caribbean Cooperation: PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/c-a-r-i-c-o-m-spells-out-7-key-pillars-of-india-caribbean-cooperation-pm-modi-7070707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:18:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Leading the India-Caricom summit as the co-chair, Prime Minister Narendra Modi outlined a seven-pillar programme of action playing on the acronym C-A-R-I-C-O-M.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leading the India-Caricom summit as the co-chair, Prime Minister Narendra Modi outlined a seven-pillar programme of action playing on the acronym C-A-R-I-C-O-M.</p>

<p>Having made progress in working towards the goals set at the first summit five years ago, he said the Seven Key Pillars packed into the group's name could transfer resources and expertise from India to the Caribbean, he said on Wednesday as the group's leaders thanked India for its leadership of the Global South and its "selfless" assistance to them.</p>

<p>"C", he said is for Capacity Building. He promised 1,000 information technology scholarships and proposed expanding the technology centre that India is setting up in Belize to accommodate all CARICOM members. He also suggested a forensic centre for the region and civil servants' online training.</p>

<p>"A" is for Agriculture and Food Security. India has benefited from developing technology for agriculture and can help in this area, like deploying drones. Also, he said, it can propagate millets that can help with nutrition.</p>

<p>"R" is for Renewable Energy and Climate Change. He invited the CARICOM countries to join initiatives India has promoted, the International Solar Alliance, the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure, Mission Life for Sustainable Lifestyles, and the Global Biofuel Alliance.</p>

<p>"I" is for Innovation and Technology. India has revolutionised the way technology is used to serve the people and the economy through "Stack" which has created the needed infrastructure. The Universal Payment Interface has revolutionised digital payments and it could be adopted by CARICOM countries. There is also the eMarketplace that helps small and medium enterprises.</p>

<p>"C", the other "C" is for Cricket and Culture. PM Modi said cricket can be a vehicle for women's empowerment and India would give 11 scholarships to each of the CARICOM nations to coach women in cricket. He also proposed cultural exchanges and Festivals of India in the group's countries. With the popularity of Bollywood, India can also organise film festivals.</p>

<p>"O" is for Ocean Economy and Maritime Security. India did not consider Caribbean countries as small island countries but as large ocean countries. This gives them great potential resources that India can help them develop. India can also help build connectivity for the region through cargo ships and ferries. Another area of cooperation is security where CARICOM nations have a blueprint for fighting piracy, drug trafficking and human smuggling.</p>

<p>"M" is for Medicines and Healthcare. India places a high priority on health in the CARICOM countries. India has developed affordable medicines and healthcare through its Janaushadi scheme. India can help develop similar centres in the CARICOM. Technology developed by India for health like telehealth programmes and machines used in cancer treatment are available. Adoption of the Indian Pharmacopeia by all the CARICOM countries could help make available less costly Indian medicines.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9pujqq2_modi-at-caricom-summit_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Narendra Modi outlined a seven-pillar programme of action playing on the acronym C-A-R-I-C-O-M.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/four-tourists-die-after-suspected-laos-methanol-poisoning-7070694]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Four Tourists Die After Suspected Laos Methanol Poisoning]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/four-tourists-die-after-suspected-laos-methanol-poisoning-7070694]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four foreign tourists have died after a suspected mass methanol poisoning from drinking tainted alcohol at a backpacker hotspot in Laos, Western government officials and media said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four foreign tourists have died after a suspected mass methanol poisoning from drinking tainted alcohol at a backpacker hotspot in Laos, Western government officials and media said Thursday.</p>

<p>A young Australian woman was the latest confirmed death, and her friend was fighting for her life, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said.</p>

<p>Two Danish citizens and an American had also died, officials said, after what media said was a night out in Vang Vieng where they drank possibly tainted alcohol.</p>

<p>The group of about a dozen tourists became ill after going out on November 12, according to British and Australian media.</p>

<p>"Tragically, Bianca Jones has lost her life. Our first thoughts at this moment are with her family and friends who are grieving a terrible and cruel loss," Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese told parliament.</p>

<p>"We also take this moment to say that we are thinking of Bianca's friend Holly Bowles who is fighting for her life," he said, without giving further details.</p>

<p>Holly was on "life support" in a hospital in Bangkok, her father Shaun Bowles told Australia's Nine News on Wednesday.</p>

<p>At the Bangkok hospital where Bowles was reportedly receiving treatment, staff said they could not confirm whether she was receiving treatment there.</p>

<p>Denmark's foreign ministry said in a statement Wednesday that two Danish citizens had died in Laos, without providing further information.</p>

<p><strong>'Unimaginable time'</strong></p>

<p>The US State Department also confirmed the "death of a U.S. citizen in Vang Vieng, Laos," and said it was "closely monitoring the situation and providing consular assistance."</p>

<p>It did not give details on the date or cause of death.</p>

<p>New Zealand's embassy in Bangkok said it had been contacted by one of its citizens "who was unwell and may be a victim of methanol poisoning in Laos".</p>

<p>The young Australian's family said in a statement to Australia's Herald Sun newspaper that they "are comforted by the knowledge that her incredible spirit touched so many lives during her time with us,"</p>

<p>"The kindness shown to our family during this unimaginable time has been truly humbling."</p>

<p>Vang Vieng has been a fixture on the Southeast Asia backpacker trail since Laos' secretive communist rulers opened the country to tourism decades ago.</p>

<p>The town was once notorious for backpackers behaving badly at jungle parties and has since re-branded as an eco-tourism destination.</p>

<p>On their travel advice websites for Laos, UK and Australia authorities warn their citizens to beware of methanol poisoning while consuming alcohol in Laos.</p>

<p>Methanol can be added to liquor to increase its potency, but can cause blindness, liver damage and death.</p>

<p>In neighbouring Thailand at least six people died and more than 20 were hospitalised after drinking methanol-laced bootleg alcohol in August.</p>

<p><strong>Backpacker hostel</strong></p>

<p>Bowles and Jones, both aged 19 from Melbourne, became unwell while staying at the Nana Backpackers Hostel in Vang Vieng last week, Australian media reported.</p>

<p>The women drank at the hostel's bar before they went out for the evening, the Sydney Morning Herald newspaper reported.</p>

<p>They failed to check out on November 13, when hostel staff rushed the pair to the hospital.</p>

<p>The Facebook and Instagram pages of the hostel had been deactivated as of Thursday and it was no longer taking bookings on booking websites.</p>

<p>AFP was unable to reach the hostel for comment.</p>

<p>UK media reported one British woman was also in hospital in Bangkok after drinking in Vang Vieng.</p>

<p>AFP has contacted the UK's embassies in Thailand and Laos for comment.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vlpvv6t8_laos_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[2 Denmark citizens, a young Australian woman and an American died in Laos.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/k-drama-for-mental-health-binge-on-one-expert-says-7070679]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[K-Drama For Mental Health? Binge On, One Expert Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/k-drama-for-mental-health-binge-on-one-expert-says-7070679]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:12:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[If you've ever binge-watched an entire season of a K-drama like "Squid Game" or "Crash Landing On You", one Korean-American expert has good news: it's likely improved your mental health.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you've ever binge-watched an entire season of a K-drama like "Squid Game" or "Crash Landing On You", one Korean-American expert has good news: it's likely improved your mental health.</p>

<p>High production values, top-notch acting and attractive stars have helped propel South Korean TV shows to the top of global viewership charts, but therapist Jeanie Chang, says there are deeper reasons so many people are hooked.</p>

<p>With soap-like plotlines that tackle everything from earth-shattering grief to the joy of new love, watching K-dramas can help people reconnect with their own emotions or process trauma, she says, giving the shows a healing power that transcends their cultural context.</p>

<p>"We all have family pressures and expectations, conflict, trauma, hope," she said, adding that watching heavy topics being successfully managed on screen can change people's ability to navigate real-world challenges.</p>

<p>For Chang, who was born in Seoul but raised in the United States, K-drama was particularly helpful in allowing her to reconnect with her roots -- which she rejected as a child desperate to assimilate.</p>

<p>But "the messages in Korean dramas are universal," Chang said.</p>

<p>"Mental health is how you're feeling, how you relate to others, psychologically, how your brain has been impacted by things. That's mental health. We see that in a Korean drama."</p>

<p><strong>'Soften my heart'</strong></p>

<p>Global K-drama viewership has exploded in the last few years, industry data shows, with many overseas viewers, especially in major markets like the United States, turning to Korean content during the pandemic.</p>

<p>Between 2019 and 2022, viewership of Korean television and movies increased six-fold on Netflix, its data showed, and Korean series are now the most watched non-English content on the platform.</p>

<p>American schoolteacher Jeanie Barry discovered K-drama via a family funeral, when a friend recommended a series -- 2020's "It's Okay to Not Be Okay" -- she thought could help her after a difficult time.</p>

<p>"There was something about it, the way that this culture deal with trauma, mental depression, just really struck a chord for me," Barry, who had travelled to South Korea as part of a K-drama tour organised by therapist Chang, told AFP.</p>

<p>"I started to grieve when I had not been. It was a lot of tears during that drama, but it also made me see that there is a light at the end of the tunnel," she said.</p>

<p>Immediately hooked, Barry said she had watched 114 K-dramas since discovering the genre, and effectively given up watching English-language television.</p>

<p>"They let me soften my heart," she said.</p>

<p>Fellow tour member and American Erin McCoy said she had struggled with depression since she was a teenager, but K-drama helped her manage her symptoms.</p>

<p>With depression, "when you live with it that long, you're just numb and so you don't really feel bad necessarily but you don't ever feel good either," she said.</p>

<p>"You just don't feel anything," she said, adding that K-drama allowed her to experience emotions again.</p>

<p>"There're so many highs and lows in every one of them, and as I felt the characters' emotions, it just helped me relate to my own more," she said.</p>

<p>"I feel like I was able to express and experience emotion again."</p>

<p><strong>'Art therapy'?</strong></p>

<p>The idea that a K-drama binge can help with mental health may seem far-fetched, but it chimes with decades-old psychotherapy ideas, one expert said.</p>

<p>"Watching Korean dramas can be beneficial for anxiety and depression from the viewpoint of art therapy," Im Su-geun, head of a psychiatry clinic in Seoul, told AFP.</p>

<p>First used in the 1940s, art therapy initially involved patients drawing, but evolved to incorporate other artistic activities.</p>

<p>"Visual media like Korean dramas have significant strengths that align well with psychotherapy," he said.</p>

<p>K-drama -- or television and cinema generally -- can help viewers "gain insights into situations from a new perspective, fostering healthy values and providing solutions to their issues," he said.</p>

<p>It is unlikely to be prescribed by a doctor, he said, but if a therapist were to recommend a specific drama that related to the patient's case, it could be helpful.</p>

<p>For example, it can provide a roadmap for patients "facing specific situations, such as breakups or loss," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5oqrsgi_s_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>