<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:50:12 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-threatens-to-launch-civil-disobedience-movement-7190085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jailed Ex-Pak PM Imran Khan Threatens To Launch Civil Disobedience Movement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-threatens-to-launch-civil-disobedience-movement-7190085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:41:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's jailed former prime minister Imran Khan has issued a warning of a civil disobedience movement following massive protests led by his party that were forcibly dispersed by the police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Pakistan's jailed former prime minister Imran Khan has issued a warning of a civil disobedience movement following massive protests led by his party that were forcibly dispersed by the police.</p>

<p>In a post on X on Thursday, the 72-year-old Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf chief announced a five-member committee to address political prisoners' release and push for a judicial probe into the May 9 violence and the alleged killings of his party workers during the November 26 protest.</p>

<p>He said the negotiation committee will include Leader of the Opposition Umar Ayub Khan and Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Chief Minister Ali Amin Gandapur.</p>

<p>"If these two demands are not accepted, civil disobedience movement will be started from December 14. The government will be responsible for the results of this movement," Khan said.</p>

<p>In a post on Friday, he said that in case of a failure to meet the demands, "civil disobedience, reduction of remittances and boycott movement will be initiated." On November 14, Khan issued a "final call" for nationwide protests, demanding the restoration of the PTI's electoral mandate, the release of detained party members, and the reversal of the 26th Amendment, which he said had strengthened a "dictatorial regime".</p>

<p>His PTI party launched the protest on November 24 to give a sit-in at D-Chowk in Islamabad's Red Zone, where most government buildings are located. His supporters were forcibly dispersed on the night of November 26 when they reached close to D-Chowk.</p>

<p>The PTI claims that at least 12 party workers were killed and hundreds injured due to the direct firing by law enforcers in Islamabad during the protest.</p>

<p>The government, however, insists that no PTI worker was killed from bullet wounds.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4bfbj58o_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_19_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[he government will be responsible for the results of this movement," Imran Khan said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-could-be-frances-new-prime-minister-7189981]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Could Be France's New Prime Minister?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-could-be-frances-new-prime-minister-7189981]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:18:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron has vowed to name a new prime minister in the "coming days" to replace Michel Barnier, who was toppled by a no confidence vote after just three months in office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron has vowed to name a new prime minister in the "coming days" to replace Michel Barnier, who was toppled by a no confidence vote after just three months in office.</p>

<p>Macron did not announce a name in an address to the nation late on Thursday and the appointment is no longer expected before Monday, multiple sources told AFP.</p>

<p>Barnier was Macron's fifth prime minister since coming to power in 2017. Each successive premier has served for a shorter period than their predecessor and given the composition of the National Assembly, there is no guarantee that Barnier's successor will last any longer than he did.</p>

<p>Here, AFP looks at the four names seen as the most likely contenders.</p>

<p>All the possible candidates so far are men and all were already in the running in September when Barnier was eventually appointed.</p>

<p>But it is far from ruled out that another candidate could emerge, with Barnier himself only coming into contention at the last moment back then.</p>

<p><strong>Sebastien Lecornu</strong></p>

<p>The ultimate Macron loyalist, Lecornu was the only key minister to stay on from the previous government in the last cabinet reshuffle in September, a measure of the importance of his job in the third year of Russia's invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>A career politician, Lecornu, still only 38, started out as a parliamentary assistant aged just 19. He has held ministerial posts ever since Macron came to power in 2017 and was promoted to defence minister in May 2022.</p>

<p>He has worked staunchly to keep up assistance for Ukraine, while carefully remaining in the shadows with infrequent media appearances.</p>

<p>Some French media, including BFM-TV, reported that Macron had been close to naming Lecornu in his address on Thursday but decided to take more time after some within the presidential camp said the minister was too right-wing.</p>

<p><strong>Francois Bayrou</strong></p>

<p>A heavyweight politician who has been allied to Macron since he swept to power in the 2017 election campaign, Bayrou heads the MoDem party which is allied to, but not part of, Macron's centrist force.</p>

<p>Bayrou, 73, was acquitted in February after a seven-year-long case over the fraudulent employment of parliamentary assistants by his party, with the judge ruling that he was owed the "benefit of the doubt".</p>

<p>A three-time presidential candidate, Bayrou was named justice minister by Macron when he took the presidency in 2017.</p>

<p>He resigned the same year when the legal case was opened against him but he remained a key behind-the-scenes ally, with his acquittal opening up a potential return to government.</p>

<p><strong>Xavier Bertrand</strong></p>

<p>Bertrand, 59, is the right-wing head of the northern Hauts-de-France region and previously served as labour and health minister between 2005 and 2012 under presidents Jacques Chirac and Nicolas Sarkozy.</p>

<p>An articulate media performer, Bertrand unsuccessfully sought the nomination of the right-wing Republicans (LR) party to fight the 2022 presidential elections.</p>

<p>He remains close to Sarkozy who, despite criminal convictions in trials since leaving office, wields considerable influence over the traditional right.</p>

<p><strong>Bernard Cazeneuve</strong></p>

<p>Former Socialist Party grandee Bernard Cazeneuve, 61, held the post of prime minister for less than half a year under the presidency of Francois Hollande from 2016-2017.</p>

<p>He is better known for his much longer stint as interior minister under Hollande, which coincided with the radical Islamist attacks on Paris in November 2015.</p>

<p>Cazeneuve quit the Socialists in 2022 in protest at the party's broad left-wing pact with factions including the hard-left France Unbowed (LFI) and still has a tense relationship with his former colleagues.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/i8k1tjkc_france-generic_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[All the possible candidates so far are men and all were already in the running in September. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-could-deploy-hypersonic-missiles-in-belarus-next-year-says-vladimir-putin-7189976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Could Deploy Hypersonic Missiles In Belarus Next Year, Says Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-could-deploy-hypersonic-missiles-in-belarus-next-year-says-vladimir-putin-7189976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:14:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia could deploy its newly developed hypersonic Oreshnik missiles in Belarus next year as it begins to ramp up their production, President Vladimir Putin said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia could deploy its newly developed hypersonic Oreshnik missiles in Belarus next year as it begins to ramp up their production, President Vladimir Putin said on Friday.</p>

<p>Putin unveiled the nuclear-capable weapon last month after using it to strike the city of Dnipro in central Ukraine, sharply escalating tensions in the almost three-year-long conflict.</p>

<p>"As for the possibility of deploying, to put it bluntly, such formidable weapons as Oreshnik on Belarusian territory... it will become possible, I think, in the second half of next year," Putin said in a televised meeting with Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko in Minsk.</p>

<p>He said this would happen as "serial production" of the missile is "ramped up in Russia".</p>

<p>Russia had already deployed tactical nuclear weapons in Belarus in 2023.</p>

<p>Experts believe the new missile flies at 10 times the speed of sound and may be able to strike targets up to 5,500 kilometres (3,400 miles) away.</p>

<p>Moscow is Belarus's closest ally, with the two countries strengthening their military cooperation throughout the Kremlin's offensive in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Tactical nuclear weapons, designed for use on the battlefield, are smaller than the strategic nuclear weapons used to wipe out whole cities but are still extremely destructive.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ban05v8o_vladimir-putin-reuters_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia had already deployed tactical nuclear weapons in Belarus in 2023. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-now-the-most-popular-name-for-a-baby-in-great-britain-data-shows-7189889]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Now The Most Popular Name For A Baby In Great Britain, Data Shows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-now-the-most-popular-name-for-a-baby-in-great-britain-data-shows-7189889]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:53:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[427 years after Shakespeare wrote it for the first time in the great "tragedy" Romeo & Juliet, England is asking the quintessential question - "What's in a name?" - And this time wondering what significance it might hold in another 42.7 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>427 years after William Shakespeare wrote it for the first time in the great "tragedy" Romeo &amp; Juliet, England is asking the quintessential question - "What's in a name?" - And this time wondering what significance that question might hold in another 42.7 years.</p>

<p>The Department of Statistics in the United Kingdom has revealed in its latest dataset that Muhammad is officially the most popular name for a newborn boy in England and Wales. More than 4,600 babies were registered with that name in 2023 - the highest for a boy. Muhammad was the second-most popular name in 2022 as well.</p>

<p>Noah, once the most popular name in UK, came a distant second this year, according to the Office for National Statistics or ONS.</p>

<p>But the staff at Great Britain's statistical office has in-fact been observing the trend for a while now. Jotting down the most popular names in the UK, besides other important statistics, it revealed that Muhammad has been among the top 10 names for baby boys since 2016.</p>

<p>Adding to the cheer, the Department of Statistics said that other spellings of the name Muhammad - namely Mohammed and Mohammad - also made the top 100 list for England and Wales. This, the ONS explained, is because it considers each spelling as a separate name.</p>

<p>George, Harry, and Charlotte are no longer popular names for children in the UK, the data showed, adding that Elizabeth and Charles are also not a favourite among young parents.</p>

<p>The nine other top names for newborn boys in Britain are - Noah, Oliver, George, Leo, Arthur, Luca, Theodore, Oscar, and Henry.</p>

<p>For newborn girls, the ten most popular names in Britain in 2023 were - Olivia, Amelia, Isla, Lily, Freya, Ava, Ivy, Florence, Willow, and Isabella. The top three names for girls have remained unchanged for a third consecutive year.</p>

<p>The statistical office also said that new entries to the list of top 100 baby names include Hazel, Lilah, Autumn, Nevaeh and Raya for girls, and Jax, Enzo, and Bodhi for boys.</p>

<p>It further noted that the time of year also played an important part in parents choosing a name. In the month of December, Holly, Robyn and Joseph were more popular, whereas names like Summer and Autumn were popular in their respective seasons.</p>

<p>Data revealed that pop culture also played a big part in how baby names were chosen. The most popular celebrity names for babies include music artists Billie Eilish and Lana Del Rey, baby names from the Kardashian-Jenner family such as Reign and Saint, and movie stars such as Margot Robbie and Cillian Murphy.</p>

<p>The statistical office said that the top names for boys had much higher counts than those for girls. This is because, there are many more unique names for baby girls as compared to baby boys. The pool of unique names for girls are over 35,000 in count, while for boys the pool, including variations of the same name, stands at 29,560.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dbvl0gto_baby-generic-istock_625x300_06_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad is officially the most popular name for a newborn boy in England. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shows-strong-and-deep-support-for-pete-hegseth-amid-controversies-7189052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Shows "Strong And Deep" Support For Hegseth Amid Controversies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shows-strong-and-deep-support-for-pete-hegseth-amid-controversies-7189052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:29:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hegeth had spent the week meeting senators and trying to gain some support amid the flurry of backlash he has been facing for the sexual assault, alcohol abuse and financial mismanagement accusations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>President-elect Donald Trump has decided not to leave behind his Pentagon pick Pete Hegseth and reiterated his "strong and deep" support for the former Fox News presenter.</p>

<p>In a post on his social media platform Truth Social, Trump wrote, "Pete Hegseth is doing very well. His support is strong and deep, much more so than the Fake News would have you believe. He was a great student - Princeton/Harvard educated - with a Military state of mind. He will be a fantastic, high energy, Secretary of Defense Defense, one who leads with charisma and skill. Pete is a WINNER, and there is nothing that can be done to change that!!!"</p>

<p>In response, Hegseth wrote, "Thank you Mr. President. Like you, we will never back down."</p>

<p>Hegeth had spent the week meeting senators and trying to gain some support amid the flurry of backlash he has been facing for the sexual assault, alcohol abuse and financial mismanagement accusations.</p>

<p>Although Trump is backing Hegseth publicly, he has been looking for more options for the role of Defence secretary, and Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis has been on his radar. But Hegseth seems confident about Trump's reliability on him and said, "As long as Donald Trump wants me in this fight, I'm going to be standing right here in this fight," on Thursday.</p>

<p>Hegseth is one of the many controversial picks by Trump, including Matt Gaetz who recently withdrew his name from the post of attorney general after days of debate regarding whether the congressional report about his sexual misconduct should be released.</p>

<p>Apart from the President-elect, he also has the Vice-President-elect backing him. He wrote on X, "Led by President Trump, we're fighting for Pete Hegseth. And we're doing so because Pete Hegseth will fight for our troops. For too long, the Pentagon has been led by people who lose wars. Pete Hegseth is a man who fought in those wars. We've got his back."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/007jab6g_pete-hegseth-donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has decided not to leave behind Pete Hegseth and reiterated his "strong and deep" support for him]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-dramatically-hiking-amount-of-enriched-uranium-nuclear-body-chief-7189011]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran "Dramatically" Hiking Amount Of Enriched Uranium: Nuclear Body Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-dramatically-hiking-amount-of-enriched-uranium-nuclear-body-chief-7189011]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:20:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran is "dramatically" increasing the amount of uranium enriched to up to 60% purity, close to the roughly 90% of weapons grade, that it is able to produce, the watchdog's chief Rafael Grossi told Reuters in an interview.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran is "dramatically" increasing the amount of uranium enriched to up to 60% purity, close to the roughly 90% of weapons grade, that it is able to produce, the watchdog's chief Rafael Grossi told Reuters in an interview.</p>

<p>The move is certain to cause even greater alarm in Western capitals already arguing that there is no civil justification for Iran's enrichment to that level as no other country has done so without producing nuclear bombs, which Iran denies pursuing.</p>

<p>Iran already has enough material enriched to up to 60%, its most highly enriched stock, for four nuclear weapons in principle if it enriched it further, according to an IAEA yardstick. It has enough for more at lower enrichment levels.</p>

<p>"Today the agency is announcing that the production capacity is increasing dramatically of the 60% inventory," International Atomic Energy Agency chief Grossi said on the sidelines of the Manama Dialogue security conference in Bahrain's capital.</p>

<p>He added that it was set to rise to "seven, eight times more, maybe, or even more" than the previous rate of 5-7 kg a month.</p>

<p>The move is also a setback for Grossi since he said after a trip to Iran last month that Tehran had accepted his "request" that it cap its stock of uranium enriched to up to 60% to ease diplomatic tensions, calling it "a concrete step in the right direction".</p>

<p>Diplomats said at the time, however, that Iran's step, which included preparing to implement that cap, was conditional on the IAEA's 35-nation Board of Governors not passing a resolution against Iran over its insufficient cooperation with the agency, which the Board then did regardless.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ucag87k_rafael-grossi_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran already has enough material enriched to up to 60%, according to an IAEA yardstick (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/57-year-old-italian-nun-arrested-over-links-to-powerful-mafia-network-7188902]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[57-Year-Old Italian Nun Arrested Over Links To Powerful Mafia Network]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/57-year-old-italian-nun-arrested-over-links-to-powerful-mafia-network-7188902]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:08:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A nun in Italy has been arrested on suspicion of being part of a criminal gang which had links to the country's most powerful mafia network, the 'Ndrangheta.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A nun in Italy has been arrested on suspicion of being part of a criminal gang which had links to the country's most powerful mafia network, the 'Ndrangheta. According to the <em>BBC</em>, the nun, named Sister Anna Donelli, was among 24 people who were arrested in northern Italy in connection with the mafia investigation. She was arrested for allegedly acting as a go-between for the 'Ndrangheta mafia and its jailed gang members, Italian police said. The arrests are a result of a four-year investigation into the 'Ndrangheta, which is one of Europe's most influential and dangerous criminal organisations, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gzx7wzdk9o" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet </a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the statements released by the coalition of law enforcement agencies, the 57-year-old nun leveraged her position as a volunteer at the prison. The Brescia Carabinieri said she was an unsuspecting figure, whose religious role allowed her "free access to the penitentiary facilities".</p>

<p>Officials accused her of being an intermediary, "exploiting the very spiritual role she carried out" to pass messages and orders between bosses on the inside and foot soldiers tied to Italy's notorious 'Ndrangheta organized crime syndicate based in Calabria, in the south of the country.</p>

<p>"She carried orders, directives, moral and material aid to associates, receiving in turn from the prisoners useful information to better plan criminal strategies," said prosecutor Francesco Prete, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/12/05/europe/catholic-nun-25-arrested-italy-intl-latam/index.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>CNN</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He added that Donelli, who is currently under house arrest, was "at the disposal of the criminal association to guarantee the connection with the associates detained in prison and those outside."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-dior-handbag-caused-one-of-south-koreas-biggest-political-scandals-7185360">How A Dior Handbag Caused One Of South Korea's Biggest Political Scandals</a></strong></p>

<p>Along with Donelli, two politicians have also been arrested. Cops also seized 1.8 million euros ($1.9 million) worth of assets in raids across several towns in the Lombardy and Veneto regions, as well as Calabria in the south.</p>

<p>The operation is ongoing, with police officers conducting searches across northern Italy. Investigators allege the group primarily used scrap metal trade businesses as a front to launder money, totalling approximately &amp;#8364;12m in laundered cash, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Notably, the 'Ndrangheta is considered one of the world's most dangerous criminal organisations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/0jqc9sc_nun-generic_625x300_08_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The nun is currently under house arrest. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-unveils-new-700-km-range-rocket-drone-to-strike-deeper-into-russia-7188807]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Unveils New 700 Km Range "Rocket-Drone" To Strike Deeper Into Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-unveils-new-700-km-range-rocket-drone-to-strike-deeper-into-russia-7188807]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:51:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine showed off a new locally-produced "rocket-drone" on Friday which it said could fly 700 km (430 miles) - more than twice the longest range attributed to missiles supplied by Western allies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine showed off a new locally-produced "rocket-drone" on Friday which it said could fly 700 km (430 miles) - more than twice the longest range attributed to missiles supplied by Western allies.</p>

<p>The unmanned craft, called "Peklo" - which means hell in Ukrainian - is the second such "rocket drone" unveiled by Kyiv as it tries to increase its ability to strike deep into Russia, which invaded 33 months ago.</p>

<p>The drones could reach speeds of 700 kph, a representative from Ukraine's state arms manufacturer Ukroboronprom told reporters at a ceremony where they were officially handed over to the armed forces.</p>

<p>No other details were provided and no evidence was given of the drone's range or speed. Ukraine has released few details of its arms industry, citing concerns about giving useful information to Moscow.</p>

<p>Ukraine's arms production minister told Reuters in November the "rocket-drone" could be viewed as something akin to a cruise missile, which flies low on a guided path to its target, usually below the speed of sound.</p>

<p>The drones were more than a metre long, with small wings on either side and two tail fins. US-supplied ATACMS missiles have a declared range of just over 300 km.</p>

<p>Russia has used thousands of long-range missiles and drones to hit military and infrastructure targets all over Ukraine.</p>

<p>Kyiv has sought the ability to strike back, but its allies until last month resisted calls to allow use of their missiles on targets deep inside Russia.</p>

<p>Ukraine has sought to balance the long-range strike gap throughout the war by launching explosive-laden propeller drones at targets up to 1,000 km inside Russia.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy, who was at Friday's ceremony, said last month that Ukraine was developing four different missiles.</p>

<p>However, despite successful launches already having taken place, the missile programme has been plagued by global supply chain issues, Ukraine's arms minister previously told Reuters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/esg9hlro_ukraine-rocket-drone_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The drones were more than a metre long, with small wings on either side and two tail fins.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-replaces-kursk-governor-cites-need-for-crisis-manager-7188712]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Replaces Kursk Governor, Cites Need For "Crisis" Manager]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-replaces-kursk-governor-cites-need-for-crisis-manager-7188712]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:39:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin has replaced the governor of the Kursk region -- partly controlled by Ukraine -- saying it needs a "crisis" manager, after residents voiced anger at the handling of the incursion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin has replaced the governor of the Kursk region -- partly controlled by Ukraine -- saying it needs a "crisis" manager, after residents voiced anger at the handling of the incursion.</p>

<p>Ukrainian troops launched a shock offensive into Kursk in August, forcing thousands to flee border areas. Ukraine's army said in November it controls 800 square kilometres (310 square miles) of territory in the region.</p>

<p>Putin appointed Alexander Khinshtein -- a prominent pro-Kremlin lawmaker -- as acting Kursk governor late on Thursday.</p>

<p>"There is a need for crisis management there," Putin said in a meeting with Khinshtein.</p>

<p>"The most important thing is to organise work on helping people," he added.</p>

<p>Acknowledging communications failures, Khinshtein told Putin: "We have to do all we can so that all residents of Kursk region fully feel that they are part of our one big country."</p>

<p>The previous regional chief, Alexei Smirnov, became acting governor in May and was inaugurated in September. He left voluntarily, according to the Kremlin and wrote on Telegram he has a new post.</p>

<p>Smirnov had drawn criticism over his appearances at televised meetings after the incursion, appearing formulaic and lacking a personal touch.</p>

<p>Putin considers Khinshtein "can better deal with this role", said Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov, denying there was any "grievances" against Smirnov.</p>

<p>Since August, Kursk locals have taken to social media to voice anger at the lack of warnings over the incursion and the handling of the crisis.</p>

<p>Some have created video messages to Putin pleading for help, though discontent is rarely shown on official media.</p>

<p>Some residents of Olgovka, about 17 kilometres (10 miles) from the border, said their village looks "like a scene from a horror film" and "we have found ourselves homeless".</p>

<p>"Some of our fellow villagers were killed, some are missing, since evacuation was not announced and some did not have time to leave," a village spokesman said.</p>

<p>At a public meeting last month, former Kursk governor Roman Starovoit, now transport minister, acknowledged the Russian military had looted in a district under their control, after official media blamed Ukrainians.</p>

<p>Starovoit told a Life News journalist Friday: "I hope (Khinshtein) will have enough experience to organise communications, first and foremost," calling it a "shortcoming" of the ousted Smirnov.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7qdt4gog_putin-with-kursk-governor_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["There is a need for crisis management there," Putin said in a meeting with Khinshtein. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-links-synagogue-attack-in-australia-to-anti-israel-sentiment-7188655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Links Synagogue Attack In Australia To "Anti-Israel Sentiment"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-links-synagogue-attack-in-australia-to-anti-israel-sentiment-7188655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:30:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Friday linked an arson attack on a synagogue in Australia to what he called Canberra's "anti-Israel sentiment".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Friday linked an arson attack on a synagogue in Australia to what he called Canberra's "anti-Israel sentiment".</p>

<p>Police in the Australian city of Melbourne said mask-wearing arsonists attacked a synagogue before dawn on Friday. They were still searching for the suspects and said they did not know why the premises had been targeted.</p>

<p>In a statement, Netanyahu said that "this heinous act cannot be separated from the anti-Israel sentiment emanating from the Australian Labor government."</p>

<p>He cited Canberra's "outrageous decision" to vote for a United Nations General Assembly resolution that demanded the end of Israel's "unlawful presence in the Occupied Palestinian Territory".</p>

<p>Netanyahu argued that "anti-Israel sentiment is anti-Semitism".</p>

<p>Australia's was among 157 votes in favour of the resolution on December 3, after it abstained in a similar vote in September.</p>

<p>No serious injuries were reported in the fire which eviscerated much of the synagogue building. Congregants were only beginning to gather for morning prayers as the attack took place, a board member said.</p>

<p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said federal police would help their state counterparts to investigate. He condemned the attack and said he had "zero tolerance" for anti-Semitism.</p>

<p>"This violence and intimidation and destruction at a place of worship is an outrage," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>Netanyahu called the attack "a vile, classic anti-Semitic act, and I expect the authorities in Australia to use the full extent of their power to prevent such anti-Semitic attacks in the future".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdpp60fk_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu called the attack "a vile, classic anti-Semitic act". (Files)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-william-to-attend-notre-dame-cathedral-reopening-in-paris-7188614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Prince William To Attend Notre Dame Cathedral Reopening In Paris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-william-to-attend-notre-dame-cathedral-reopening-in-paris-7188614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:24:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK's Prince William will attend Saturday's re-opening of Notre Dame cathedral in Paris, Kensington Palace said on Friday, but his wife, Catherine, will not accompany him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK's Prince William will attend Saturday's re-opening of Notre Dame cathedral in Paris, Kensington Palace said on Friday, but his wife, Catherine, will not accompany him.</p>

<p>"The Prince of Wales will travel to Paris tomorrow to attend the ceremony marking the reopening of the Notre Dame Cathedral," the palace said in a statement.</p>

<p>"His Royal Highness is travelling at the request of His Majesty's Government on behalf of the United Kingdom," it added.</p>

<p>Around 50 heads of state and government are expected in the French capital for the ceremony. US president-elect Donald Trump is also to attend.</p>

<p>Buckingham Palace did not immediately reply to an AFP request on whether King Charles III would attend. Kensington Palace said that Catherine would not be in Paris.</p>

<p>Charles, who is the head of the Church of England, is currently undergoing treatment for cancer. Catherine, also known as Kate, has gradually begun resuming public engagements after also being diagnosed with cancer earlier this year.</p>

<p>Charles's wife, Queen Camilla, recently fell ill with pneumonia and has had to cancel some of her appearances.</p>

<p>France last week showed off to the world the gleaming restored interior of the 850-year-old mediaeval cathedral, which was hit by a huge fire in 2019.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rtk6ki3_prince-william_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Around 50 heads of state and government are expected in the French capital for the ceremony. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-nasa-pick-elon-musks-business-partner-may-face-political-challenges-7188569]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's NASA Pick, Musk's Business Partner, May Face Political Challenges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-nasa-pick-elon-musks-business-partner-may-face-political-challenges-7188569]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:19:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's pick to helm NASA, a private astronaut and close ally of Elon Musk's SpaceX, is a central figure of a speedy, commercial-focused side of the space industry who would face unfamiliar political challenges as an administrator.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump's pick to helm NASA, a private astronaut and close ally of Elon Musk's SpaceX, is a central figure of a speedy, commercial-focused side of the space industry who would face unfamiliar political challenges as an administrator.</p>

<p>Jared Isaacman, the CEO of payment processing company Shift4 Payments, has made landmark visits to space on two ambitious SpaceX missions, including the first-ever privately funded spacewalk in September.</p>

<p>In accepting Trump's decision, he envisioned a "thriving space economy" and vowed to "usher in an era where humanity becomes a true spacefaring civilization."</p>

<p>But the path to pursuing a faster, more privatized human spaceflight agenda is expected to involve a delicate political tango of trimming costly, entrenched programs and wooing lawmakers to increase the space agency's $25 billion budget.</p>

<p>"He's going to definitely push NASA, but he'll do it in a positive way," said Garrett Reisman, a retired NASA astronaut who has been an adviser to SpaceX.</p>

<p>Musk had recommended Trump pick Isaacman and has since told associates he sees the tech billionaire as someone who will get things done at NASA, according to two people familiar with the discussions.</p>

<p>"He is a man (of) high ability and integrity," Musk said Wednesday of Isaacman on his X platform.</p>

<p>Targets at NASA for Trump and Musk's cost-cutting agenda that Isaacman is expected to eye include the agency's over-budget, $24 billion Space Launch System rocket and the in-development Gateway space station poised to sit in a lunar orbit, according to people familiar with the transition team's space plans.</p>

<p>Other projects expected to face scrutiny include the agency's goal to return soil samples from Mars - another top NASA priority alongside its Artemis moon program.</p>

<p>While likely to face pushback from lawmakers, cuts to expensive NASA programs could mean boosts to companies such as SpaceX that have embraced cheaper and faster means of getting to space and offering rockets to the government as a privately owned service.</p>

<p>That approach has contrasted with the space agency's traditional method of company contracting where companies like Boeing and Lockheed Martin build spacecraft that the agency itself owns, controls and fully funds.</p>

<p>Trump's first NASA administrator, former Oklahoma congressman Jim Bridenstine, proved adept at navigating those political challenges. He was instrumental in winning budget boosts for NASA's flagship crewed space exploration program and upping its dependence on private companies.</p>

<p>Bridenstine in a statement Wednesday night urged for Isaacman's Senate confirmation, saying his "vision for pushing boundaries, paired with his proven track record of success in private industry, positions him as an ideal candidate to lead NASA into a bold new era of exploration and discovery."</p>

<p>Since Trump's first term, NASA has focused heavily on returning humans to the moon. But the Artemis program using NASA's powerful Space Launch System (SLS) rocket to send astronauts to space and Musk's Starship rocket to land them on the moon has faced budget blowouts and delays, pushing the planned landing back to 2027.</p>

<p>NASA's reliance on SpaceX's Crew Dragon capsule, providing astronaut rides to the International Space Station at a cheaper price than previous options, has reinforced the agency's commercial cost-savings strategy. It has also galvanized a industry culture that threatens the future of NASA's older and far more expensive SLS rocket, built mainly by Boeing and Northrop Grumman with a countrywide workforce of 28,000.</p>

<p>"Administrator-nominee Isaacman, if confirmed, will face challenges as he leads NASA into the future," said Dan Stohr, CEO of the industry group Coalition for Deep Space Exploration, which counts Boeing and Lockheed Martin as members.</p>

<p>"Budget limitations, workforce, and infrastructure needs will all play a role in shaping NASA's future," Stohr added.</p>

<p>NASA's current administrator, Bill Nelson, said he spoke with Isaacman to congratulate his tentative nomination and feels "basically optimistic" about the future of NASA under Trump.</p>

<p>"I think the relationship between Elon Musk and the president-elect is going to be a benefit to making sure that the funding for NASA is there, so I see that as a positive," Nelson told a press conference on Thursday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p4kgqo6g_jared-isaacman_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["He is a man (of) high ability and integrity," Musk said Wednesday of Isaacman on his X platform. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/masood-azhars-speech-exposes-paks-duplicity-indias-stern-response-7188561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Masood Azhar's Speech Exposes Pak's Duplicity": India's Stern Response]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/masood-azhars-speech-exposes-paks-duplicity-indias-stern-response-7188561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:18:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Friday demanded that Pakistan act against terrorist Masood Azhar, chief of banned terrorism group Jaish-e-Mohammed and the mastermind behind terror strikes like the 2011 Parliament attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>India on Friday demanded that Pakistan act against terrorist <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/masood-azhar" target="_blank">Masood Azhar</a>, chief of banned terrorism group <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/jaish-e-mohammed" target="_blank">Jaish-e-Mohammed</a> and the mastermind behind terror strikes like the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/2011-parliament-attack" target="_blank">2011 Parliament attack</a>.</p>

<p>The strong statement followed reports of a public speech by Azhar - his first in 21 years - at an Islamic seminary in Bahawalpur in Pakistan's Punjab province, in which he reportedly vowed to continue attacks on India and used a derogatory word for Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>

<p>Referring to reports of Azhar's speech, External Affairs Ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal, at a scheduled press briefing, also pointed out that it, if true, "had exposed Pakistan's duplicity" in containing terrorist outfits and terrorists operating from its soil to launch cross-border attacks.</p>

<p>"Masood Azhar is involved in cross-border terror attacks in India. We demand strong action be taken against him, so he is brought to justice. There has been a denial that he is not there in Pakistan... but, if the reports are correct, then it exposes the duplicity of Pakistan," Mr Jaiswal told reporters.</p>

<p>In his outrageous speech Azhar reportedly also called Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu as a "mouse", and declared his intention to step up terror attacks in Jammu and Kashmir.</p>

<p>The speech was reportedly delivered sometime in November.</p>

<p>Azhar is among India's most-wanted terrorists.</p>

<p>In September 2019 India branded Azhar and another Pak-based terrorist, Lashkar-e-Taiba founder Hafiz Muhammad Saeed, as 'individual terrorists' under the stringent anti-terror law UAPA.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/hafiz-saeed-masood-azhar-declared-terrorists-under-new-anti-terror-law-2095571" target="_blank">Masood Azhar Branded A Terrorist Under New Anti-Terror Law</a></p>

<p>Apart from the attack on Parliament in 2001, in which two security personnel were killed, he is also linked to strike on Central Reserve Police Force personnel in Jammu and Kashmir's Pulwama in 2019.</p>

<p>He also orchestrated an attack on the Indian consulate in Afghanistan's Mazar-e-Sharif in 2016.</p>

<p>In August 2020, after more than a year of demanding Pak admit its responsibility for the Pulwama terror attack, the Indian government slammed its neighbour for continuing to shelter Azhar.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-slams-pakistan-for-evading-responsibility-for-pulwama-terror-attack-2286368" target="_blank">India Slams Pak For Evading "Responsibility" For Pulwama Terror Attack</a></p>

<p>Anurag Srivastava, then the MEA spokesperson, had said, "Jaish-e- Mohammed claimed responsibility for the Pulwama attack. The organisation and its leadership are in Pakistan and it is regrettable Masood Azhar, the first accused, continues to find shelter in that country."</p>

<p>In January of this year, social media posts - apparently from Pakistan-based users - declared that Masood Azhar had died in a bomb blast while returning from a mosque.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/is-indias-most-wanted-masood-azhar-dead-a-fact-check-4786780" target="_blank">Is India's Most Wanted Terrorist Masood Azhar Dead? A Fact-Check</a></p>

<p>A fact-check, however, confirmed the news as fake. The photo of the blast that allegedly killed Azhar was found to have first been posted five years ago in an unrelated explosion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ellfio8g_masood-azhar_625x300_01_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-bjp-says-us-state-department-behind-deep-state-targeting-india-7188320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In A 1st, BJP Says US State Department Behind "Deep State" Targeting India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-bjp-says-us-state-department-behind-deep-state-targeting-india-7188320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:41:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[BJP, which leads the coalition of parties currently in Government in India, has directly accused the US State Department of trying to "destabilise India". It also claimed that the US "deep state" is working to "target Prime Minister Narendra Modi".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Bharatiya Janata Party or BJP, which leads the coalition of parties currently in Government in India, has directly accused the US State Department of trying to "destabilise India". It also claimed that the US "deep state" is working to "target Prime Minister Narendra Modi".</p>

<p>In a press conference, the BJP spokesperson said, "It has always been the US State Department behind this agenda"</p>

<h2><strong>BJP CLAIMS THERE'S A NEXUS</strong></h2>

<p>Sambit Patra, the spokesperson of the ruling BJP, claimed that elements in the US deep state have colluded with a group of journalists and with India's opposition leader Rahul Gandhi to put a spoke in the wheel of India's growth story with unsubstantiated allegations and malicious reports without a "shred of evidence". He suggested at a press conference that all this is in conjunction with the "US State Department".</p>

<p>The BJP also slammed Rahul Gandhi for using reports by the Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project or OCCRP that "singularly focused" on targeting the Adani Group and its alleged closeness to the government to undermine PM Modi - all "baseless charges", and without a "shred of evidence".</p>

<p>The BJP spokesperson then cited a French media report that showed that OCCRP was funded by the US Agency for International Development and "other deep state figures" like George Soros. "The Deep State had a clear objective to destabilise India by targeting Prime Minister Modi," the BJP said.</p>

<p>It added that "It has always been the US State Department behind this agenda...OCCRP has served as a media tool for carrying out a deep state agenda."</p>

<p>"A French investigative media group has revealed that 50% of OCCRP's funding comes directly from the US State Department," Mr Patra said.</p>

<p>The BJP spokesperson then accused Rahul Gandhi of being a "traitor of the highest order". He also said that "some agencies of America" and billionaire George Soros make a "dangerous triangle trying to destabilise India".</p>

<p>Sambit Patra's charge was then repeated by his party colleague Nishikant Dubey in Parliament. Mr Dubey accused the Congress of "conspiring with foreign forces" to derail the government because of their "hatred" for PM Modi.</p>

<p>Mr Dubey called for opposition leader Rahul Gandhi to be thoroughly investigated for meeting with controversial business tycoon George Soros, who he claimed "routinely conspires to derail economies of other countries" and American lawmakers like Ilhan Omar, who have strongly opposed Prime Minister Modi and his administration. "The Congress must answer... what transpired in meetings with those who have a history of peddling anti-India agenda on Rahul Gandhi's foreign tours," he said.</p>

<h2><strong>CONGRESS RESPONDS, DEMANDS APOLOGY</strong></h2>

<p>This resulted in a sharp reaction from the Congress, which called it the "most unfortunate incident". Congress MP Shashi Tharoor slammed Mr Dubey and his "outrageous statement".</p>

<p>"No 1, you cannot attack people in a defamatory manner. No 2, you cannot take anyone's name without giving them notice in writing in advance, and No 3, you cannot assault parliamentary privilege. He violated all those three rules and he was allowed to go on speaking and ranting for quite some time... so we objected to that. The House was initially adjourned. We went to see the Speaker and we said this has to be expunged from the record. The person must apologise," Mr Tharoor said.</p>

<p>OCCRP admitted to "some funding" by the US government. The media group said in a statement that it was an independent media outlet and not associated with any political party. "The US government, while providing some funding to OCCRP, has no say in our editorial processes and no control over our reporting," it said, according to a report in news agency Reuters.</p>

<p>The US State Department has not yet responded to these charges.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/u0sg7io_us-state-department_625x300_13_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[BJP accused the US State Department of being involved with "deep state" to destabilise India]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-it-means-for-bangladesh-to-drop-sheikh-mujibur-rahman-from-currency-notes-7188098]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What It Means For Bangladesh To Drop Mujibur Rahman From Currency Notes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-it-means-for-bangladesh-to-drop-sheikh-mujibur-rahman-from-currency-notes-7188098]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:13:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This is a big decision taken by the Bangladesh government because Rahman has been a part of the currency since the country's inception on March 4th, 1972.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangabandhu (friend of Bangladesh) - the name by which Sheikh Mujibur Rahman had been known, seems quite ironic to what's happening there, since the country identifies him as a nemesis now. Bangladesh is set to erase the image of Rahman, the iconic founding father of the country, from its currency notes.</p>

<p>"We aim to release the new notes within the next six months," said Husneara Shikha, Executive Editor of Bangladesh Bank.</p>

<p>This is a big decision taken by the Bangladesh government because Rahman has been a part of the currency since the country's inception on March 4th, 1972.</p>

<p>Since Hasina fled Bangladesh after the student-led protests, Muhammad Yunus, a Nobel laureate, took charge as the Chief Adviser of an interim government.</p>

<p>Months after ousting Sheikh Hasina as the Prime Minister, Bangladesh is set to remove her father, from the face of Bangladesh currency and print new notes Taka 20, 100, 500, and 1,000 - as Bangladesh Bank has confirmed. This takes place just weeks after Rahman's portrait was taken down from Yunus' office as a "concession" given to the student protesters from the caretaker government.</p>

<p>Mahfuz Alam, an adviser to the government, said "Photo of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman- Post '71 Fascist, is removed from Darbar Hall. It is a shame for us that we couldn't remove his picture from Bangabhaban after the 5th August. Apologies. But, he won't be seen anywhere till people's July spirit lives on."</p>

<p>The central bank has further added that the "graffiti" drawn during the July protests, with some religious structures and Bengali traditions will be included in the designing of the new notes.</p>

<p>This move can be perceived as the country trying to make a shift from its identity and the legacy of Bangabandhu. It is also interesting to note that a national holiday on August 15th has been cancelled, since that day marked the assassination of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman. Along with this, several institutions have been renamed, removing Hasina and Rahman from their legacy.</p>

<p>In her recent remarks, Hasina accused Yunus of being "involved in genocide" and failing to protect minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>However, Bangladesh's International Crimes Tribunal has termed her comments as "hate speech", and the country's leaders said a smear campaign is going on against the Yunus government.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3fhdj358_bangladesh-currency-istock_625x300_06_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh is set to erase the image of Rahman, the founding father, from its currency notes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-school-teacher-claims-she-was-fired-over-anti-trump-post-on-facebook-7188025]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US School Teacher Claims She Was Fired Over Anti-Trump Post On Facebook]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-school-teacher-claims-she-was-fired-over-anti-trump-post-on-facebook-7188025]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:01:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US high school teacher has claimed that she was fired over a Facebook post she made criticising president-elect Donald Trump and his followers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US high school teacher has claimed that she was fired over a Facebook post she made criticising president-elect Donald Trump and his followers. According to <em>The Independent,</em> Joanie Garratt was an AP History teacher with over 30 years in the Beverly Hills Unified School District (BHUSD). She says she was fired from the school on November 13, less than a month before her planned retirement on December 5. Her lawyer claims she was terminated because of an anti-Trump post, which also involved her reaction to a group of pro-Trump students who gathered on November 6 to celebrate Trump's re-election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In her post, Ms Garratt wrote she was "disheartened" by a march at Beverly Hills High School in support of President-elect Donald Trump, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/beverly-hills-teacher-trump-facebook-b2659610.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet </a>reported. She also claimed that during the demonstration, Trump supporters "harassed and intimidated many other non-MAGA students and specifically targeted the class where Black Student Union was meeting, telling all kinds of racial slurs".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Some students arrived at school truly upset &amp; even crying only to be bullied later by their classmates. And don't blame the administration for this. They are dealing with it. This comes from their leader, His Majesty, King Trump," Ms Garrat wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her lawyer said that following the Facebook post, the district's superintendent called her to let her know that her social media post led to her dismissal. The official did not cite any other explanation, the attorney said, in a news release.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Garratt never discussed Trump, the election or the pro-Trump students' demonstration in her classes. Her comment was made on her own Facebook account, on her own time, and is a prime example of political speech that's protected under the First Amendment and California labour and education codes," the release stated.</p>

<p>"Joanie's post, which criticized harassment at the rally and attributed student conduct to political rhetoric whipped up as part of Donald Trump's re-election strategy, is constitutionally protected speech," the attorney added.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-colombian-hitwoman-arrested-for-multiple-murders-including-her-ex-boyfriend-7184470">Colombian Hitwoman, Known As 'The Doll,' Arrested For Multiple Murders</a></strong></p>

<p>However, Superintendent Michael Bregy disagreed with that characterisation. "Ms Garratt retired from full-time teaching in BHUSD years ago and was serving and remains a substitute teacher in the District. No action was taken to dismiss her or any other employee in the last month," he wrote in a statement, per the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our focus remains on fostering an educational environment where students and staff are respected and valued. We encourage meaningful discussions that prioritize mutual understanding, respect, and accountability. BHUSD will continue to uphold its standards and policies to ensure that our schools are spaces where all voices can be expressed thoughtfully and responsibly. We trust these facts will clarify this matter," he added.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ncepoq1g_donald-trump_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Garratt spent over 30 years teaching at Beverly Hills Unified School District.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ship-carrying-norwegian-arms-for-ukraine-aid-runs-aground-7187723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ship Carrying Norwegian Arms For Ukraine Aid Runs Aground]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ship-carrying-norwegian-arms-for-ukraine-aid-runs-aground-7187723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:28:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A cargo ship loaded with Norwegian weapons destined to protect a Polish logistics hub that distributes military aid to Ukraine has run aground off Norway's coast, authorities said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A cargo ship loaded with Norwegian weapons destined to protect a Polish logistics hub that distributes military aid to Ukraine has run aground off Norway's coast, authorities said Friday.</p>

<p>The civilian vessel Finlandia Seaways was transporting some of the weapons Oslo announced Monday to protect the hub when it ran aground off southwestern Norway on Thursday.</p>

<p>"The vessel hit a shoal and suffered damage to the rudder and propeller. It had to be tugged to a dock," a spokesman for the Sola rescue centre, Thomas Breivoll, told AFP.</p>

<p>"There was nothing dramatic about it," he added.</p>

<p>Norway's defence ministry is sending F-35 jet fighters, NASAMS surface-to-air missiles and around 100 soldiers to protect the Rzeszow hub in Poland as part of a NATO member state rotation.</p>

<p>A large part of Western military aid to Ukraine, which has been fending off Russia's invasion since 2022, transits through the logistical hub in southeastern Poland.</p>

<p>According to Hanne Olafsen, a spokeswoman for the Norwegian armed forces, the ship was transporting "elements of the anti-air materiel destined for Poland".</p>

<p>"This will undoubtedly lead to a slight delay" in the contingent's deployment, she told AFP.</p>

<p>The military equipment will be transferred from the Finlandia Seaways to another vessel, and the area around the ship has been secured.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-04/790joid_cargo-ship-generic_625x300_01_April_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The vessel hit a shoal and suffered damage to the rudder and propeller. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-to-expect-as-doors-to-notre-dame-reopens-in-paris-after-5-years-of-restoration-7187613]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What To Expect As Doors To Notre-Dame Reopens In Paris After 5 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-to-expect-as-doors-to-notre-dame-reopens-in-paris-after-5-years-of-restoration-7187613]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:16:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Paris' Notre-Dame Cathedral reopens on Saturday, December 7, five and a half years after fire destroyed its roof and spire and caused major damage throughout.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paris' Notre-Dame Cathedral reopens on Saturday, December 7, five and a half years after fire destroyed its roof and spire and caused major damage throughout.</p>

<p>Here is what you need to know:</p>

<p><strong>WHAT IS NOTRE-DAME?</strong></p>

<p>A medieval Gothic masterpiece, Notre-Dame de Paris (Our Lady of Paris) is one of the French capital's most beloved and visited monuments, celebrated for its rib vaulting, flying buttresses, stunning stained-glass windows and carved stone gargoyles.</p>

<p>The first stone was laid in 1163, and construction continued for much of the next century, with major restoration and additions made in the 17th and 18th centuries.</p>

<p>Victor Hugo helped make the cathedral a symbol of both Paris and France when he used it as a setting for his 1831 novel, "The Hunchback of Notre-Dame". Quasimodo, the main character, has been portrayed in Hollywood movies, an animated Disney adaptation and in musicals.</p>

<p><strong>WHY AND HOW DID IT BURN?</strong></p>

<p>On the evening of April 15, 2019, the cathedral's roof burst into flames. Soon, the fire had engulfed the spire and almost toppled the main bell towers. Around the world, TV viewers watched with horror.</p>

<p>Much of the roof collapsed but the bell towers and facade held.</p>

<p>It remains unclear what exactly caused the fire. Authorities have ruled out arson and said an electrical fault or a burning cigarette may have been responsible.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT WILL HAPPEN AT THE OPENING CEREMONY?</strong></p>

<p>Scheduled to begin around 7 p.m. (1800 GMT), the non-religious part of the ceremony will take place in a big tent in the cathedral's forecourt. It will start with the screening of a documentary on the reconstruction, followed by live classical music.</p>

<p>President Emmanuel Macron, who is embroiled in a political crisis after the collapse of the French government, will give a brief speech. Participants will then sing La Marseillaise, the national anthem, after which Paris' Archbishop Laurent Ulrich will knock on the cathedral's heavy doors with his crozier.</p>

<p>From within the cathedral, a psalm will be sung three times and the doors will then open. Ulrich will bless the ancient organ before it starts playing. This will be followed by a religious service.</p>

<p>US President-elect Donald Trump will be among the guests, as will President Joe Biden's wife Jill and dozens of heads of state and government.</p>

<p>The religious ceremony is due to end around 2000 GMT, with a concert outside the cathedral starting shortly afterwards.</p>

<p><strong>FIRST MASS IN RESTORED NOTRE-DAME TO BE HELD ON SUNDAY</strong></p>

<p>The archbishop will celebrate a Mass, starting at 10:30 a.m. (0930 GMT), the first of eight days of Masses devoted to the reopening and open to specific groups of the faithful and of guests, such as donors on December 11 and firefighters on December 15. Some of the Masses, including on the evening of Dec. 8, at 6:30 p.m. (1730 GMT), will be open to the general public.</p>

<p><strong>WHEN CAN YOU VISIT?</strong></p>

<p>If you're lucky, you can visit on the evening of Dec. 8 from 5:30 p.m. to 8 p.m. but there is at first likely to be fierce competition - and long queues - to visit the cathedral.</p>

<p>The cathedral says that from Dec. 7, visitors will be able to book a free ticket online, on its website, social media or a dedicated app, to get into the building on the same day or one or two days after booking. There will also be a queue on the spot for those who want to enter without a booking.</p>

<p>The cathedral has also created an app to help self-guide visits.</p>

<p>Groups will only get access next year - from February 1 for religious groups or from June 9th for tourists with guides.</p>

<p>The cathedral expects to welcome 14 to 15 million visitors every year. There is a huge debate in France over whether visitors should pay to get in. The Church is against it, and for now visiting remains free.</p>

<p><strong>HOW WAS THE CATHEDRAL REBUILT?</strong></p>

<p>Money poured in from all over the world, including from French luxury sector billionaires Francois Henri Pinault and the Arnault family. So much money has been donated - more than 840 million euros ($888 million), according to Macron's office - that there will even be funds left over for further investment in the building.</p>

<p>The damage has needed five years' worth of restoration work.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT HAS CHANGED?</strong></p>

<p>Officials say the cathedral is more beautiful than ever, not only because its spire, roof and anything else destroyed by the fire was rebuilt by thousands of expert craftspeople, but also because the stone and paintings, which had blackened over the years, have been thoroughly cleaned. The furniture was also renovated and cleaned, or replaced.</p>

<p>Not everything was damaged in the fire. For instance, emergency workers formed a human chain to whisk gem-studded chalices and other priceless artefacts out of harm's way.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tmt6hlig_notre-dame_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Groups will only get access next year - from June 9th for tourists with guides.(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/watch-influencer-stages-prank-to-test-dubais-safety-leaves-gold-jewellery-on-car-bonnet-7187607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Influencer Leaves Jewellery On Car Bonnet To Test Dubai's Safety]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/watch-influencer-stages-prank-to-test-dubais-safety-leaves-gold-jewellery-on-car-bonnet-7187607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:14:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video showcasing Dubai's safety is going viral on social media, sparking a lively discussion among netizens. In the clip, influencer Leyla Afshonkar stages a prank to test the city's safety.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video showcasing Dubai's safety is going viral on social media, sparking a lively discussion among netizens. In the clip, influencer Leyla Afshonkar stages a prank to test the city's safety. She leaves her gold jewellery on the hood of a parked car and observes from a distance how passersby react. To her astonishment, pedestrians walk by without so much as glancing at the gold. At one point, a woman even picks up a fallen piece of jewellery and places it back on the car.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The video opens with Ms Afshonkar placing a gold necklace and earrings on the bonnet of a blue BMW. She then steps inside a nearby shop, leaving the valuable items exposed. To her surprise, the gold jewellery remains untouched throughout. "It's been half an hour, and literally no one has touched the gold. And tell me Dubai is not the safest country in the world," she says in the clip.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEp52ZPxg-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEp52ZPxg-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEp52ZPxg-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEp52ZPxg-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Leyla Afshonkar (@leylafshonkar)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Ms Afshonkar shared the video a few days back. Since then, it has accumulated more than 20 million views and over 1 million likes. The clip sparked a discussion online, with some praising Dubai's safety, and others questioning the authenticity of the stunt.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If you touch it, they will whip you in jail and will deport you back home and ban forever from entering the country. It's not the people and safety, it's the law that dictates safety," commented one user. "Is Dubai really this safe? Or do they pay influencers for such marketing?" asked another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, some users vouched for the city's safety. "It is really safe. People are afraid that if they get caught, the punishment is swift and strict. You must see the service cabbies provide there. If their rating drops below 4.7, they're sent back to Pakistan or India," wrote one user.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/video-spiritual-orator-abhinav-arora-trolled-for-dancing-in-lord-hanuman-attire-7187088">Video: Spiritual Orator Abhinav Arora Trolled For Dancing In Lord Hanuman Attire</a></strong></p>

<p>"I once forgot my handbag with a laptop, passport, and cash. An hour later, I realized it was missing. Two hours after that, I retrieved it from the exact spot where I left it. Nobody touched it!" shared another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You can leave your wallet and phone on a table in a food court, and no one will touch it. Done it multiple times. This is how society should function globally!" commented a third user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Dubai is safe but this video is scripted as (0:16) same girl in white &amp; black spotted (0:38) standing behind this main girl at jewellery store watching all these recorded videos," pointed out one X user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Indeed, Dubai is incredibly safe, which sometimes makes its residents a bit careless, leading to challenges when they travel to countries with different safety standards," remarked another.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ogrbbk28_leyla-afshonkar_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-to-hold-annual-press-conference-on-december-19-says-kremlin-7187424]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin To Hold Annual Press Conference On December 19, Says Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-to-hold-annual-press-conference-on-december-19-says-kremlin-7187424]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:50:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin will hold his annual press conference on December 19, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said in televised comments Friday, saying it will include foreign media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin will hold his annual press conference on December 19, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said in televised comments Friday, saying it will include foreign media.</p>

<p>The televised marathon event will take place a month before US President-elect Donald Trump takes over at the White House and as Russian forces make advances in Ukraine.</p>

<p>The event, during which Putin answers journalists' questions and takes calls from members of the public, will be called "Results of the year with Vladimir Putin", Peskov said.</p>

<p>He confirmed that international media will be able to participate, after Russia imposed restrictions and entry bans on foreign journalists working in Russia over the last year in what it calls reciprocal measures.</p>

<p>"Journalists from federal, regional and international media will be accredited," Peskov said.</p>

<p>Representatives of international media attending "will mainly be foreigners working under current accreditation in Russia," Peskov said, while some other Western media will be present.</p>

<p>The event will start noon Moscow time (0900 GMT), the state TASS news agency reported.</p>

<p>Last year's event took more than four hours.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dhh0nq6k_vladimir-putin-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The event will be called "Results of the year with Vladimir Putin". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>