<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 06:57:52 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-joe-biden-says-dropped-out-of-presidential-race-to-unite-his-party-6182700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dropped Out Of Presidential Race To "Unite My Party": Joe Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-joe-biden-says-dropped-out-of-presidential-race-to-unite-his-party-6182700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 06:52:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden told Americans Wednesday that he had dropped out of the 2024 election to unite his party and his country, saying in a historic Oval Office speech that it was time to pass the torch to "younger voices."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden told Americans Wednesday that he had dropped out of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-us-is-more-powerful-than-any-dictator-or-tyrant-6182537">2024 election</a> to unite his party and his country, saying in a historic Oval Office speech that it was time to pass the torch to "younger voices."</p>

<p>"There is a time and a place for long years of experience in public life. There's also a time and a place for new voices, fresh voices, yes, younger voices," he said, adding that he dropped out of the White House race to "unite my party."</p>

<p>In his first televised address since his stunning decision, the 81-year-old hailed his "tough" and "capable" Vice President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-praises-kamala-harris-shes-experienced-shes-tough-shes-capable-6182671">Kamala Harris</a>, 59, who is set to be the new Democratic presidential nominee.</p>

<p>"The defense of democracy, which is at stake, is more important than any title," Biden said. "I have decided the best way forward is to pass the torch to a new generation. That is the best way to unite our nation."</p>

<p>Biden bowed out of the race later than any other president in US history on Sunday, giving in to weeks of pressure from Democrats after a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump raised concerns about his age and mental acuity.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ij3s7378_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden praised Kamala Harris, who is set to be the new Democratic presidential nominee.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-praises-kamala-harris-shes-experienced-shes-tough-shes-capable-6182671]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["She's Experienced, Tough, Capable": Joe Biden Praises Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-praises-kamala-harris-shes-experienced-shes-tough-shes-capable-6182671]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 06:47:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Biden also told Americans that he had dropped out of the 2024 election to unite his party and his country, saying in a historic Oval Office speech that it was time to pass the torch to "younger voices."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-us-is-more-powerful-than-any-dictator-or-tyrant-6182537#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Joe Biden</a> on Wednesday praised his Vice President Kamala Harris -- presumptive nominee for the Democratic presidential ticket -- as "tough" and "capable" as he addressed the nation from the Oval Office.</p>

<p>"She's experienced, she's tough, she's capable. She's been an incredible partner to me and a leader for our country. Now, the choice is up to you, the American people," he said days after bowing out of the election race and endorsing her.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Join me as I deliver an address from the Oval Office. <a href="https://t.co/MPTTLv6nyn">https://t.co/MPTTLv6nyn</a></p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1816261097399410895?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Biden also told Americans that he had dropped out of the 2024 election to unite his party and his country, saying in a historic Oval Office speech that it was time to pass the torch to "younger voices."</p>

<p>"The defense of democracy, which is at stake, is more important than any title," the 81-year-old&nbsp;said in his first televised address since his stunning decision.</p>

<p>"I have decided the best way forward is to pass the torch to a new generation. That is the best way to unite our nation."</p>

<p>Biden bowed out of the race later than any other president in US history on Sunday, giving in to weeks of pressure from Democrats after a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump raised concerns about his age and mental acuity.</p>

<p>Using the powerfully symbolic setting of the Resolute Desk, Biden's speech called for an end to the divisions in US politics and said the country was more powerful than "any dictator or tyrant."</p>

<p>The veteran Democrat said there was a "time and a place for new voices, fresh voices. Yes, younger voices. And that time and place is now."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/en5kavno_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-one-more-qualified-than-kamala-harris-for-us-presidential-race-white-house-6182670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No One More Qualified Than Kamala Harris For Presidential Race: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-one-more-qualified-than-kamala-harris-for-us-presidential-race-white-house-6182670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 06:44:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[White House Press Secretary, Karine Jean Pierre emphasised that no one is more qualified to step in as the Democratic Party's presidential nominee than US Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>White House Press Secretary, Karine Jean Pierre emphasised that no one is more qualified to step in as the Democratic Party's presidential nominee than US Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre on Wednesday (local time) noted that Kamala Harris has been vice president for more than four years now.</p>

<p>"The vice president (Kamala Harris) has been vice president for more than four years. I do not see anyone more qualified to step in at this moment. She was a senator. She was an attorney general...," she said while addressing the White House briefing.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre noted that Kamala Harris was a partner in that to the president, adding that President Joe Biden is proud to make this decision.</p>

<p>"I've listed out what we've been able to accomplish in the last three and a half, almost four years, an unprecedented record. She was a partner in that with the president. This is a decision that this president made, and I think he (US President Joe Biden) is proud to have made that decision...," she added.</p>

<p>Harris, over the past 3.5 years as vice president, has visited more than 19 countries and met with more than 150 foreign leaders, according to the White House website.</p>

<p>She has visited over 19 countries and met with more than 150 foreign leaders, according to information available on the White House website.</p>

<p>The US presidential election will take place on November 5, and Biden was seeking re-election to the post as the Democratic Party nominee. After his June 27 debate with Republican candidate Donald Trump, Democrats put pressure on him to withdraw from the race.</p>

<p>Following this, on July 21, Biden formally announced that he was abandoning plans for a second term in office and endorsed his running mate, Vice President Kamala Harris for the election.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Harris has quickly consolidated support among Democrats and has already secured the backing of enough delegates to be the likely Democratic nominee. Democrats adopted the rules the party will use to choose their presidential nominee, with voting to officially nominate Harris likely to begin on August 1.</p>

<p>Harris will have to secure the support of the majority of delegates at the Democratic National Convention (DNC) in Chicago in August.</p>

<p>Under the rules approved by the Democratic National Convention's rules panel Wednesday, presidential hopefuls have until Saturday evening to formally declare their candidatures and until Tuesday, July 30, to submit signatures from at least 300 delegates, with not more than 50 from a single state counting towards the threshold, reported CNN.</p>

<p>Voting will be conducted by electronic ballots sent to convention delegates. If only one candidate meets the petition requirements, which is likely considering how quickly the party has coalesced around Harris, voting is expected to begin on August 1, although it will be up to party leaders to set the times for voting to begin and end.</p>

<p>If more than one candidate were to meet the requirements, party leaders can set a period of no more than five days for candidates to make their case to delegates, reported CNN.</p>

<p>The party has said its goal is to nominate its presidential and vice presidential candidates by August 7 to avoid the possibility of litigation over ballot access in Ohio.</p>

<p>While the state has pushed its deadline for political parties to submit their official nominees to September 1, the new law won't take effect until the end of August.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bg80adm8_kamala-harris-reuters-_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has been vice president for more than four years now.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-us-is-more-powerful-than-any-dictator-or-tyrant-6182537]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Passing Torch To Next Generation": Joe Biden On Exiting US President Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-us-is-more-powerful-than-any-dictator-or-tyrant-6182537]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 06:02:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden called the United States the "most powerful idea" in world history Wednesday, in a televised speech from the Oval Office days after announcing he would drop out from the White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden told Americans Wednesday that he had dropped out of the 2024 election to unite his party and his country, saying in a historic Oval Office speech that it was time to pass the torch to "younger voices."</p>

<p>In his first televised address since his stunning decision, the 81-year-old hailed his "tough" and "capable" Vice President Kamala Harris, 59, who is set to be the new Democratic presidential nominee.</p>

<p>"The defense of democracy, which is at stake, is more important than any title," Biden said. "I have decided the best way forward is to pass the torch to a new generation. That is the best way to unite our nation."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Join me as I deliver an address from the Oval Office. <a href="https://t.co/MPTTLv6nyn">https://t.co/MPTTLv6nyn</a></p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1816261097399410895?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Biden bowed out of the race later than any other president in US history on Sunday, giving in to weeks of pressure from Democrats after a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump raised concerns about his age and mental acuity.</p>

<p>Using the powerfully symbolic setting of the Resolute Desk, Biden's speech called for an end to the divisions in US politics and said the country was more powerful than "any dictator or tyrant."</p>

<p>The veteran Democrat said there was a "time and a place for new voices, fresh voices. Yes, younger voices. And that time and place is now."</p>

<h3><strong>'Lunatic'</strong></h3>

<p>Biden also rejected accusations that he will be a lame duck for the remaining six months of his one-term presidency.</p>

<p>"Over the next six months I will be focused on doing my job as president," he said, adding that he would keep trying to lower costs for families and defend freedoms including the right to abortion.</p>

<p>Biden's withdrawal has upended Trump's campaign, which had previously focused on the president's age and mental acuity. Now it is Trump, 78, who is the oldest candidate in US history.</p>

<p>Trump hit back at Harris in a harsh broadside at a rally in North Carolina, his first since she secured enough delegates to become the de facto Democratic nominee on Monday.</p>

<p>"She is a radical left lunatic who will destroy our country," he said, describing her as the "ultra liberal driving force behind every single Biden catastrophe."</p>

<p>Trump also claimed that Harris wanted "abortions in the eighth and ninth month of pregnancy" as well as "right up until birth and even after birth, the execution of a baby."</p>

<p>Saying Democratic Party bosses were behind Biden's decision to step down, he accused Harris of covering up Biden's "mental unfitness."</p>

<h3>'<strong>Ridiculous</strong>'</h3>

<p>Earlier Wednesday, the White House denied it was hiding any possible decline in Biden's health prior to his decision to drop out of the election race.</p>

<p>"It is not a cover up. I know that is the narrative that you all want. It is not," Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre told reporters, adding that Biden's decision has "nothing to do with his health."</p>

<p>Biden returned to the White House on Tuesday after spending nearly a week with Covid at his Delaware beach home, a period of isolation in which he took the decision to step back.</p>

<p>Republicans have called for Biden to step down altogether, saying that if he is not fit to stand for reelection then he is not fit to serve as president.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre dismissed that as "ridiculous" and maintained that Biden is no "lame duck."</p>

<p>Biden insists he still has much to offer, such as targeting a peace deal in the Middle East -- a legacy-defining dream that many US presidents before Biden have chased.</p>

<p>Biden, who has been increasingly critical over Israel's military campaign in Gaza, meets Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu at the White House on Thursday.</p>

<p>But in a sign of how quickly things are changing, Netanyahu will sit down separately that day with Harris as well.</p>

<p>Trump meanwhile is set to meet the Israeli leader Friday at the Republican's Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/lupvhfh8_joe-biden-afp-_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden told Americans that he had dropped out of the 2024 election to unite his party and his country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ceasefire-negotiations-appear-to-be-in-closing-stages-us-6182403]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Ceasefire Negotiations Appear To Be In Closing Stages: US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ceasefire-negotiations-appear-to-be-in-closing-stages-us-6182403]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 05:25:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Negotiations on a ceasefire-for-hostages deal in the Gaza conflict appear to be in their closing stages and U.S. President Joe Biden and Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu will discuss remaining gaps on Thursday, a senior U.S. official said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Negotiations on a ceasefire-for-hostages deal in the Gaza conflict appear to be in their closing stages and U.S. President Joe Biden and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu will discuss remaining gaps on Thursday, a senior U.S. official said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The official, briefing reporters ahead of their talks, said the remaining obstacles are bridgeable and there will be more meetings aimed at reaching a deal between Israel and Hamas over the next week.</p>

<p>Hamas-led fighters stormed into southern Israel on Oct.7, killing 1,200 people and taking 250 captives, according to Israeli tallies, triggering a war in which more than 38,000 people in Gaza have been killed.</p>

<p>Hamas and other militants are still holding 120 hostages; Israel believes around a third of them are dead.</p>

<p>Months of stop-and-start talks have failed to produce a deal to gain release of some of the remaining hostages.</p>

<p>The senior U.S. official said both Israel and Hamas still have some issues to resolve but that a deal is close in which a six-week ceasefire would take place in exchange for the release of women, elderly men and wounded hostages over a 42-day period.</p>

<p>"It's a very different negotiation now than just a month ago when we had some fundamentally unbridgeable issues," the official said.</p>

<p>Biden will hold talks with Netanyahu and then later in the day Vice President Kamala Harris will have a separate meeting with the Israeli leader.</p>

<p>Harris has taken over as the presumed Democratic choice for the November presidential election against Republican Donald Trump, after Biden opted not to seek reelection again under pressure from Democrats concerned about his mental acuity.</p>

<p>The senior U.S. official said both Biden and Harris are "completely aligned" on U.S. policy toward Israel and Gaza.</p>

<p>"The Israelis will hear full alignment," the official said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dq6g1jl_gaza-war_625x300_23_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 38,000 people in Gaza have been killed since war began between Israel and Hamas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-attacker-googled-john-f-kennedy-assassination-details-before-shooting-fbi-6182317]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Attacker Searched Online About John F Kennedy Shooting: FBI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-attacker-googled-john-f-kennedy-assassination-details-before-shooting-fbi-6182317]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 04:59:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman who attempted to assassinate Donald Trump at a campaign rally searched online for details about the November 1963 shooting of US president John F. Kennedy in the days before the attack, the FBI director said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman who attempted to assassinate Donald Trump at a campaign rally searched online for details about the November 1963 shooting of US president John F. Kennedy in the days before the attack, the FBI director said Wednesday.</p>

<p>FBI chief Christopher Wray, testifying before a congressional committee, said the gunman flew a drone over the venue where the former president was scheduled to speak about two hours before he took the stage in Butler, Pennsylvania, on July 13.</p>

<p>Wray told members of the House Judiciary Committee that investigators have not established a motive for the shooting but "we are digging hard because this is one of the central questions for us."</p>

<p>Trump survived the assassination bid, suffering a wound to his right ear, and a Secret Service sniper shot dead the suspected gunman -- named as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks -- less than 30 seconds after he had fired eight shots.</p>

<p>"With respect to former president Trump, there's some question about whether or not it's a bullet or shrapnel that, you know, that hit his ear," FBI chief Wray said.</p>

<p>Two rally attendees were seriously injured and a 50-year-old Pennsylvania firefighter was shot dead.</p>

<p>Wray said Crooks "appears to have done a lot of searches of public figures, in general" but that there was no clear pattern to the research.</p>

<p>"A lot of the usual repositories of information have not yielded anything notable in terms of motive or ideology," he said.</p>

<p>"Starting somewhere around July 6 or so, he became very focused on former president Trump and this rally," the FBI chief said, and he registered that same day to attend the campaign event in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"On July 6, he did a Google search for, quote, 'How far away was Oswald from Kennedy?'" he said, a reference to Kennedy's assassination by Lee Harvey Oswald.</p>

<p>"That obviously is significant in terms of his state of mind."</p>

<p>The FBI director said no evidence has emerged so far that Crooks had any accomplices or co-conspirators and he seems to have been a "loner."</p>

<p>Crooks was perched on the roof of a nearby building and opened fire on Trump with an AR-style assault rifle shortly after 6:00 pm, as the Republican White House candidate was addressing the rally in Butler.</p>

<p><strong>- Drone flight -</strong></p>

<p>US Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle resigned on Tuesday, a day after acknowledging the agency had failed in its mission to prevent the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>Wray said Crooks flew a drone over the rally area for around 11 minutes -- sometime between 3:50 pm and 4:00 pm -- on the day of the attack.</p>

<p>He said it was not flown directly over the stage but about 200 yards (meters) away.</p>

<p>The drone and its controller were recovered in the gunman's car along with two "relatively crude" explosive devices, Wray said.</p>

<p>Another explosive device was found in Crooks's residence.</p>

<p>Wray said the gunman purchased a ladder on the day of the shooting but appears not to have used it. Instead, he climbed onto the roof using some mechanical equipment on the ground and vertical piping.</p>

<p>Wray also said Crooks's AR-style gun had a collapsible stock which may explain why he was not seen by rally-goers or members of law enforcement with the weapon before the shooting.</p>

<p>He said Crooks visited the rally site on at least three occasions: about a week before the shooting, for about 70 minutes on the morning of the rally and again that afternoon.</p>

<p>He purchased 50 rounds of ammunition on the day of the attack and visited a shooting range the previous day.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The FBI director said no evidence has emerged so far that Crooks had any accomplices or co-conspirators.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-campaign-rally-donald-trump-calls-kamala-harris-a-radical-left-lunatic-6182225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Campaign Rally, Trump Calls Kamala Harris A "Radical Left Lunatic"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-campaign-rally-donald-trump-calls-kamala-harris-a-radical-left-lunatic-6182225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 04:22:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump accused US Vice President Kamala Harris of being a "radical left lunatic" Wednesday, in his first rally since she became the de facto Democratic Party nominee in the White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump launched a volley of attacks against US Vice President Kamala Harris Wednesday, calling her a "radical left lunatic" in his first rally since she became the de facto Democratic Party nominee for November's election.</p>

<p>In a speech claiming she was in favor of the "execution" of babies due to her stance on abortions, the former president and Republican nominee said: "She is a radical left lunatic who will destroy our country."</p>

<p>"We're not going to let that happen," he told the crowd in North Carolina.</p>

<p>Trump's speech comes as Harris, 59, hits the campaign trail armed with President Joe Biden's endorsement -- after his historic decision over the weekend not to seek reelection.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Republican repeatedly attacked Biden over his age but has been forced to pivot as he has now become the oldest nominee in history.</p>

<p>Trump called Harris "the ultra liberal driving force behind every single Biden catastrophe."</p>

<p>He claimed that she wanted "abortions in the eighth and ninth month of pregnancy" as well as "right up until birth and even after birth, the execution of a baby."</p>

<p>Saying Democratic Party bosses were behind Biden's decision to step down, he accused Harris of covering up Biden's "mental unfitness."</p>

<p>Earlier Wednesday, the White House denied it had covered up any possible decline in Biden's health prior to his decision to drop out of the election race.</p>

<p>Harris's candidacy has stirred enthusiasm among Democrats after weeks of turmoil over Biden, who came under pressure after a disastrous debate performance against Trump last month.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pigc5cvo_donald-trump-_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said that Kamala Harris will destroy the country if voted to power. 'radical left lunatic']]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salman-rushdie-attacker-indicted-on-terrorism-charges-6182166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Salman Rushdie Attacker Indicted On Terrorism Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salman-rushdie-attacker-indicted-on-terrorism-charges-6182166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 04:06:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man accused of trying to kill the author Salman Rushdie has been charged with terrorism for allegedly acting on behalf of Hezbollah, according to documents unsealed Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The man accused of trying to kill the author Salman Rushdie has been charged with terrorism for allegedly acting on behalf of Hezbollah, according to documents unsealed Wednesday.</p>

<p>Hadi Matar, a 26-year-old American of Lebanese descent who was already charged by the state of New York for the 2022 stabbing attack, has now been indicted by a grand jury on three counts that include attempting to provide material to support a foreign terrorist organization, said the indictment dated July 17 but not unsealed until now.</p>

<p>That organization is Lebanon's Iran-backed movement Hezbollah, the US Justice Department said.</p>

<p>In August 2022 Rushdie, now 77, lost his sight in his right eye after the attack by a knife-wielding assailant, who jumped on stage at an arts gathering in New York state. Rushdie was stabbed about 10 times.</p>

<p>The Indian-born author, a naturalized American based in New York, had faced death threats since his 1988 novel "The Satanic Verses" was declared blasphemous by Iran's supreme leader.</p>

<p>In 1989, that leader, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, issued a fatwa, or religious edict, calling on Muslims anywhere in the world to kill Rushdie.</p>

<p>Hezbollah endorsed the fatwa, the FBI said in a statement Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We allege that in attempting to murder Salman Rushdie in New York in 2022, Hadi Matar committed an act of terrorism in the name of Hezbollah, a designated terrorist organization aligned with the Iranian regime," Attorney General Merrick Garland said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>"The defendant attempted to carry out a fatwa endorsed by Hezbollah that called for the death of Salman Rushdie," said FBI Director Christopher Wray.</p>

<p>Between September 2020 and the summer of the attack Matar sought to provide material support to Hezbollah by trying to carry out the fatwa against Rushie, the Justice Department said.</p>

<p>The other two counts in the indictment charge Matar with engaging in an act of terrorism transcending national boundaries and providing material support to terrorists.</p>

<p>- Life after fatwa -</p>

<p>The award-winning author was stabbed multiple times in the neck and abdomen at the New York literary conference before attendees and guards subdued the assailant.</p>

<p>Matar has told the New York Post newspaper that he had only read two pages of Rushdie's novel but believed he had "attacked Islam."</p>

<p>Rushdie lived in seclusion in London for the first decade after the fatwa but for the past 20 years lived a relatively normal life in New York.</p>

<p>This year Rushdie published a memoir called "Knife" in which he recounted the near death experience.</p>

<p>In an interview with CBS's "60 Minutes" program in April, Rushdie recounted how one of the surgeons who saved his life had said: "First you were really unlucky and then you were really lucky."</p>

<p>"I said, 'What's the lucky part?' and he said, 'Well, the lucky part is that the man who attacked you had no idea how to kill a man with a knife,'" Rushdie said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/jb35l9u_salman-rushdie-afp-_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-useful-idiots-benjamin-netanyahu-slams-anti-israel-protesters-in-us-speech-6181560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Iran's Useful Idiots": Netanyahu Slams Anti-Israel Protesters In US Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-useful-idiots-benjamin-netanyahu-slams-anti-israel-protesters-in-us-speech-6181560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:48:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protesters opposed to the devastating war in Gaza are "Iran's useful idiots," Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in a speech to the US Congress Wednesday, claiming that Tehran is funding the demonstrations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protesters opposed to the devastating war in Gaza are "Iran's useful idiots," Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in a speech to the US Congress Wednesday, claiming that Tehran is funding the demonstrations.</p>

<p>"I have a message for these protesters: When the tyrants of Tehran who hang gays from cranes and murder women for not covering their hair are praising, promoting and funding you, you have officially become Iran's useful idiots," Netanyahu said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/435p3ito_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's Benjamin Netanyahu said that the anti-Israel protester are funded by Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/america-israel-must-stand-together-netanyahu-addresses-us-congress-6181370]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[America, Israel "Must Stand Together": Netanyahu Addresses US Congress]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/america-israel-must-stand-together-netanyahu-addresses-us-congress-6181370]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:59:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu appealed for his country and the United States to stand together in a landmark speech Wednesday aimed at rallying support in a US Congress split over his military campaign in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu appealed for his country and the United States to stand together in a landmark speech Wednesday aimed at rallying support in a US Congress split over his military campaign in Gaza.</p>

<p>"For the forces of civilization to triumph, America and Israel must stand together," Netanyahu said, after arriving to applause and cheers from Republicans and a much more muted reception from Democrats.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-on-6-000-black-women-to-help-power-her-campaign-6181310]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Calls On 6,000 Black Women To Help Power Her Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-on-6-000-black-women-to-help-power-her-campaign-6181310]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:46:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris called on a rally of more than 6,000 Black women on Wednesday to help her revitalize the Democratic presidential campaign, ahead of her Republican rival Donald Trump's return to the campaign trail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris called on a rally of more than 6,000 Black women on Wednesday to help her revitalize the Democratic presidential campaign, ahead of her Republican rival Donald Trump's return to the campaign trail.</p>

<p>Harris has emerged as the Democratic presidential candidate in the Nov. 5 election after President Joe Biden, 81, ended his re-election bid on Sunday in the face of intense opposition from fellow Democrats who questioned his ability to win or to serve for another four years were he to do so.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old vice president, the first Black woman and Asian American to serve as vice president -- who would also be a historic first as president if she prevails over former President Trump, 78 -- has shaken up a staid race and sparked new energy among Democrats.</p>

<p>That surge will not go unanswered on Wednesday, when Trump holds his first rally since Biden ended his campaign -- in the battleground state of North Carolina.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign has insisted it is prepared for Harris' candidacy, arguing she serves as a proxy for Biden on the economic and immigration policies that contributed to his sinking popularity with voters.</p>

<p>Harris spoke at an event in Indianapolis hosted by the Zeta Phi Beta Sorority, which was founded at Howard University, the historically Black college she attended. She hopes to tap sororities' multi-generational network of Black women -- who played an important role in Biden's 2020 victory -- to deliver strong voter turnout for Democrats again in November.</p>

<p>"I thank you. And now, in this moment, our nation needs your leadership once again," Harris said.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are closely competitive, public opinion polls showed this week.</p>

<p>A Reuters/Ipsos poll completed on Tuesday showed Harris with a marginal two-percentage-point lead over Trump, 44% to 42%. A CNN poll conducted by SSRS showed Trump leading Harris, 49% to 46%. Both findings were within the polls' margins of error.</p>

<p>BIDEN TO SPEAK</p>

<p>Biden, who came back to Washington after isolating at his home in Delaware with COVID, will address the nation from the Oval Office on Wednesday night to explain his decision to drop out after a disastrous June debate with Trump raised questions about his ability to win the election, or to serve another four years if he succeeded.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Trump took the unusual step of speaking to reporters on a conference call to underscore his campaign's line of attack on the border, saying Harris was partially responsible for a record flow of migrants.</p>

<p>Biden put Harris in charge of working with countries in Central America to help stem the tide of migration, but she was not made responsible for border security.</p>

<p>"She's a radical left person, and this country doesn't want a radical left person to destroy it," Trump said on the call. "She wants open borders. She wants things that nobody wants."</p>

<p>Harris has not called for the removal of border controls.</p>

<p>Trump, coming off a triumphant week in which his party unified around his presidential bid after a failed assassination attempt two weekends ago, has had to watch as Biden's sudden departure from the race dramatically shifted the narrative and sparked a surge of attention toward Harris at his expense.</p>

<p>Harris campaign chair Jen O'Malley Dillon said in a memo made public on Wednesday that Democrats would aim to compete in the swing states of Michigan, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania, North Carolina, Georgia, Arizona and Nevada, opening up a map that in the final weeks of Biden's campaign had appeared to be more focused on the Midwest.</p>

<p>"This race is more fluid now - the vice president is well-known but less well-known than both Trump and President Biden, particularly among Dem-leaning constituencies," O'Malley Dillon wrote.</p>

<p>Democrats will formally nominate their new ticket at next month's convention in Chicago after an Aug. 7 virtual vote. Roy Cooper, North Carolina's Democratic governor, is considered to be on the short list to serve as Harris' running mate.</p>

<p>Harris and her campaign have worked at breakneck pace to consolidate support among Democrats in Congress and delegates across the country. Candidates who could have been potential rivals for the nomination have fallen in line and endorsed her.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign on Wednesday said it has raised $126 million since Sunday, with 64% of donors making their first contribution of the 2024 campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/95ecpq5o_kamala-harris_625x300_23_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crowdstrike-says-bug-in-content-validator-caused-global-tech-outage-6181267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[CrowdStrike Says 'Bug In Content Validator" Caused Global Tech Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crowdstrike-says-bug-in-content-validator-caused-global-tech-outage-6181267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:38:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[CrowdStrike, the cybersecurity company that caused a global computer outage last week, on Wednesday said that the breakdown stemmed from a flaw in its test software.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CrowdStrike, the cybersecurity company that caused a global computer outage last week, on Wednesday said that the breakdown stemmed from a flaw in its test software.</p>

<p>In an incident report, the company said the glitch was pushed out to millions of Windows computers and that the company will change the way it handles such updates in the future.</p>

<p>"Due to a bug in the content validator, one of two (updates) passed validation despite containing problematic content data," said CrowdStrike.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike's Falcon software is used by businesses around the world to better identify and handle malware and security breaches.</p>

<p>The type of update that caused the crash, which is frequently deployed by the company, will from now on be sent out gradually, so that problems can be detected before they are released at scale.</p>

<p>"A full-blown rollout from a security vendor to every customer within minutes is very dangerous," Dave DeWalt, the former chief executive of cybersecurity company McAfee, told the Wall Street Journal.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike said on Monday that about 8.5 million devices were impacted by the outage, and warned customers that malicious actors were trying to take advantage of the situation.</p>

<p>A wide range of industries were hit by the outage, with users confronted with "blue screens of death" that made rebooting impossible.</p>

<p>The airline industry was hit most visibly by the crash, with US carrier Delta Airlines particularly affected.</p>

<p>The company said on Tuesday that it only expected a full return to normal on Thursday.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike CEO George Kurtz has been summoned by the US Congress to explain the incident.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ahu6f6c8_crowdstrike-afp_625x300_20_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miracle-baby-born-in-gaza-after-israeli-airstrike-kills-pregnant-mother-6181134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Miracle" Baby Born In Gaza After Israeli Airstrike Kills Pregnant Mother]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miracle-baby-born-in-gaza-after-israeli-airstrike-kills-pregnant-mother-6181134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:12:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nine months pregnant, Ola Al-Kurd could not wait to hold her baby and bring new life to Gaza during a war which has killed over 39,000 fellow Palestinians and razed much of the enclave.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nine months pregnant, Ola Al-Kurd could not wait to hold her baby and bring new life to Gaza during a war which has killed over 39,000 fellow Palestinians and razed much of the enclave.</p>

<p>That special moment never came.</p>

<p>An Israeli airstrike smashed into the family home in Al-Nuseirat in central Gaza on July 19, according to her father Adnan Al-Kurd. The blast threw Ola down several floors to her death in the house, whose inhabitants included women, children and the elderly, he said.</p>

<p>Somehow, her baby survived, as did her husband, who was hospitalised.</p>

<p>"It's a miracle that the fetus stayed alive inside of her when she was martyred (died)," Adnan Al-Kurd said, contemplating a photo of his daughter's graduation.</p>

<p>The explosion, like many others, killed several members of a single family, a daily tragedy across Gaza since Israel began its offensive in Gaza in response to a devastating cross-border attack by Palestinian Hamas militants on Oct. 7 last year.</p>

<p>Mediators from the United States, Qatar and Egypt have failed in multiple attempts to secure a ceasefire. So it is highly unlikely that Israeli airstrikes and shelling will end anytime soon.</p>

<p>"She wanted to hold her child and fill our home with his presence," Al-Kurd said. "She would say, 'Mom, hopefully, this will make up for the loss of my martyred brothers and bring life back to our home'."</p>

<p>Entirely against the odds, surgeons at Al Awda hospital in Nuseirat - where Ola was first taken after the strike - managed to deliver the newborn, Malek Yassin. He was then transferred to Al Aqsa Hospital in Deir al-Balah, where an aunt touched the baby's face as he lay in an incubator.</p>

<p>"Thank God, this baby's life was saved and he is now alive and well," doctor Khalil Al-Dakran said at the hospital, where many medical facilities have been destroyed in over nine months of war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Al-Kurd gazes at photos of his three late children killed in the Gaza war. He said baby Yassin is blond like his dead uncle Omar. "I go visit him everyday. He is a part of me," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Babies who survive frequent Israeli bombardment get no relief as the conflict inflicts more destruction in the heavily built-up, densely populated Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>"We are in fact facing very great difficulties in the nursery department," said Al-Dakran, due to a lack of sufficient medication and supplies and fears that the hospital generator could stop at any moment due to fuel shortages.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hospitals across impoverished Gaza have been demolished or seriously damaged during the war, which began when Hamas-led fighters attacked Israel, killing 1,200 people and taking over 250 hostages according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel responded with an air and ground offensive that has killed more than 39,000 Palestinians, according to Gaza's Hamas-run health ministry, and levelled much of the coastal territory.</p>

<p>"What is the fault of this child to start his life under difficult and very bad circumstances, deprived of the most basic necessities of life?" said Dakran.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mio9kbso_miracle-baby-gaza_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Somehow, her baby survived, as did her husband, who was hospitalised]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-attacked-salman-rushdie-faces-federal-terrorism-charges-supporting-hezbollah-6181096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Who Attacked Salman Rushdie Faces Federal Terrorism Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-attacked-salman-rushdie-faces-federal-terrorism-charges-supporting-hezbollah-6181096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:06:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man accused of attempting to kill author Salman Rushdie in New York two years ago now faces federal terrorism charges for his alleged support of Hezbollah, according to an indictment unsealed on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The man accused of attempting to kill author Salman Rushdie in New York two years ago now faces federal terrorism charges for his alleged support of Hezbollah, according to an indictment unsealed on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The grand-jury indictment charges Hadi Matar, the New Jersey man already facing state murder and assault charges for a 2022 knife attack on Rushdie, with three terror charges, including carrying out an act of terrorism and providing material support to Hezbollah, a U.S.-designated terrorist group that was founded by Iran in Lebanon during the early 1980s.</p>

<p>Matar, who has Lebanese roots, has pleaded not guilty on the state murder and assault charges and is awaiting trial. He remains jailed in the Chautauqua County Jail in Mayville, New York.</p>

<p>Matar's public defender, Nathaniel Barone, said that his client plans to plead not guilty to the federal charges.</p>

<p>Matar is expected to be arraigned later on Wednesday in U.S. District Court in Buffalo, New York.</p>

<p>Iran's supreme leader at the time, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, pronounced a fatwa, or religious edict, calling upon Muslims to kill Rushdie upon publication of Rushdie's 1988 book, "The Satanic Verses," considered blasphemous by some Muslims. Rushdie, the acclaimed India-born novelist, then spent a decade in hiding.</p>

<p>Matar is a Shi'ite Muslim. Hezbollah is a Shi'ite Islamist group and shares the ideology of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</p>

<p>While Iran's pro-reform government of President Mohammad Khatami distanced itself from the fatwa in the late 1990s, it was never lifted.</p>

<p>Rushdie was blinded in his right eye and his left hand was badly injured by the stabbing attack in August 2022 on a stage just as Rushdie was to deliver a lecture at an educational retreat near Lake Erie.</p>

<p>Rushdie released this year his memoir on the attack, "Knife: Meditations After an Attempted Murder".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pf957me8_salman-rushdie-attacker_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He remains jailed in the Chautauqua County Jail in Mayville, New York.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-dozens-missing-in-migrant-wreck-as-boat-capsizes-in-africa-6180911]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[15 Killed, Dozens Missing In Migrant Wreck As Boat Capsizes In Africa]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-dozens-missing-in-migrant-wreck-as-boat-capsizes-in-africa-6180911]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:34:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 15 migrants have died and dozens are missing after their boat capsized off Mauritania, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) and local sources said Wednesday, the latest in a string of migrant tragedies off the coast of West Afr]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 15 migrants have died and dozens are missing after their boat capsized off Mauritania, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) and local sources said Wednesday, the latest in a string of migrant tragedies off the coast of West Africa.</p>

<p>"We are deeply saddened by the death of 15 migrants and the estimated disappearance at sea of 195+ people after a boat capsized in Nouakchott," the IOM posted on X.</p>

<p>A Mauritanian coastguard official told AFP on condition of anonymity that at least 25 bodies had been recovered while 103 people were rescued, while several dozen were missing following Monday's disaster.</p>

<p>"Approximately 300 people boarded a pirogue in The Gambia and spent seven days at sea before the boat capsized near Nouakchott on July 22, 2024," the IOM said in a statement.</p>

<p>The UN migration agency added that 120 people had been rescued by Mauritanian Coast Guards, while efforts continued to locate the missing individuals.</p>

<p>"Among the survivors, 10 people were urgently referred to hospitals for medical care, and four unaccompanied and separated children were identified," the IOM said.</p>

<p>The source from the Mauritanian coastguard said the pirogue was carrying 140 to 180 people, mostly Senegalese and Gambian.</p>

<p>The boat had broken up in the middle of the sea and the captain abandoned the vessel, the source said.</p>

<p>Since June, more than 76 boats with more than 6,000 surviving migrants have disembarked in Mauritania, with at least 190 dead and missing migrants, the IOM statement said.</p>

<h3><strong>Perilous crossing</strong></h3>

<p>Every year, thousands of Africans fleeing poverty and unemployment in search of a better future embark on the perilous route to Europe.</p>

<p>But the crossing is fraught with tragedy.</p>

<p>In early July, nearly 90 migrants bound for Europe perished when their boat capsized off the coast of Mauritania.</p>

<p>Twenty-six migrants who set sail from Guinea died when their boat sank off Senegal at the beginning of May.</p>

<p>The Atlantic route to Spain's Canary Islands is particularly dangerous because of strong currents, with migrants travelling in overloaded, often unseaworthy, boats without enough drinking water.</p>

<p>But it has grown in popularity due to increased vigilance by authorities in the Mediterranean.</p>

<p>From January 1 to July 15 alone, more than 19,700 migrants arrived irregularly in the Canary Islands using this route, the IOM said.</p>

<p>That is a 160 percent increase from the same period in 2023, when 7,590 migrants were recorded.</p>

<p>Off the coast of North Africa, the Canary Islands lie 100 kilometres (62 miles) away at their closest point.</p>

<p>More than 5,000 migrants died while trying to reach Spain by sea in the first five months of this year, or the equivalent of 33 deaths per day, according to Caminando Fronteras, a Spanish charity.</p>

<p>That is the highest daily number of deaths since it began collating figures in 2007, and the vast majority were on the Atlantic route.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/vmor07kg_boat-generic-unsplash_625x300_14_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boat had broken up in the middle of the sea (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-protest-netanyahu-outside-us-capitol-call-for-gaza-ceasefire-6180789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Protest Netanyahu Outside US Capitol, Call For Gaza Ceasefire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-protest-netanyahu-outside-us-capitol-call-for-gaza-ceasefire-6180789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:19:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands gathered in Washington on Wednesday to protest Benjamin Netanyahu and call for a ceasefire in the Israel-Hamas war, as the Israeli premier prepared to address the US Congress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands gathered in Washington on Wednesday to protest Benjamin Netanyahu and call for a ceasefire in the Israel-Hamas war, as the Israeli premier prepared to address the US Congress.</p>

<p>Crowds carrying Palestinian flags and signs ranging from left-wing slogans to Bible verses gathered outside the Capitol calling for a ceasefire and the arrest of Netanyahu, as prosecutors seek a warrant for him at the International Criminal Court.</p>

<p>"The hypocrisy of our (US) politicians today has gone beyond any limits," Mo, a 58-year-old protester, told AFP.</p>

<p>Netanyahu will address Congress later Wednesday in a high-profile speech to the US government, Israel's steadfast ally in its war against Hamas.</p>

<p>Relations have grown strained as the civilian death count in Gaza has grown, leading to protests in the United States and increasing criticism from President Joe Biden's administration, though little has changed in the way of US military support.</p>

<p>Protesters gathered Wednesday were calling for a ceasefire while also criticizing Netanyahu's appearance in the United States.</p>

<p>"Seek peace and pursue it," read one sign, quoting a Bible verse, while others were designed as criminal "wanted" signs, with photos of Netanyahu in place of a mugshot.</p>

<p>"Arrest that war criminal," read another.</p>

<p>"We are horrified by the destruction of the health system in Gaza," Karameh Kuemmerle, of the organization Doctors Against Genocide, told AFP.</p>

<p>"And we are here to show our opposition to having the criminal Netanyahu come to our capital and being greeted by the politicians who sent him weapons to kill children in Gaza," the doctor, who traveled to Washington from Boston, said.</p>

<p>Israel has recently intensified its attacks on Gaza and Netanyahu has insisted that only piling on military pressure can free the hostages and defeat Hamas, which launched a shock attack on October 7 that resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza, including 44 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,145 people, also mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ijc8d268_protest-netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has recently intensified its attacks on Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-china-based-network-for-supporting-north-korea-6180677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sanctions China-Based Network For Supporting North Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-china-based-network-for-supporting-north-korea-6180677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:00:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States unveiled sanctions Wednesday against a network of half a dozen people and five firms in China it accuses of supporting North Korea's ballistic missile and space programs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States unveiled sanctions Wednesday against a network of half a dozen people and five firms in China it accuses of supporting North Korea's ballistic missile and space programs.</p>

<p>The network is alleged to have helped North Korea with procuring items for its ballistic missile programs, which the US Treasury Department said were being operated in "flagrant violation" of UN Security Council resolutions.</p>

<p>North Korea's continued development of its ballistic missile technologies "is both irresponsible and destabilizing for both the region and the international community," Treasury under secretary for terrorism and financial intelligence Brian Nelson said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The United States remains committed to using our tools to enforce these international sanctions, including disrupting the illicit procurement networks that provide key inputs for these technologies," he added.</p>

<p>The US Treasury said North Korea's space and ballistic missile programs made use of an "extensive network" of overseas agents to procure the foreign-sourced materials needed, which included personnel at its diplomatic missions and trade offices, "as well as third-country nationals."</p>

<p>It also makes use of foreign firms to purchase the items it needs, the Treasury added.</p>

<p>Among those sanctioned by the Treasury on Wednesday was Shi Qianpei, a Chinese national, whom the Treasury Department accused of working with a previously-designated individual based in Beijing to procure metal sheets used in the production of North Korean missiles.</p>

<p>Other individuals sanctioned include Chen Tianxin, Shi Qianpei's business partner and wife, and two of his employees, all of whom helped with the procurement efforts, the Treasury said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/thjcjens_us-flag-generic_625x300_28_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/musk-launches-poll-asking-if-tesla-should-invest-5-billion-in-his-xai-6180523]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk Launches Poll Asking If Tesla Should Invest $5 Billion In His xAI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/musk-launches-poll-asking-if-tesla-should-invest-5-billion-in-his-xai-6180523]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 21:34:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla CEO Elon Musk has launched a poll asking users on social media platform X whether the electric carmaker should invest $5 billion in his artificial intelligence startup xAI - with early votes showing most in favour of the move.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk has launched a poll asking users on social media platform X whether the electric carmaker should invest $5 billion in his artificial intelligence startup xAI - with early votes showing most in favour of the move.</p>

<p>"Board approval &amp; shareholder vote are needed, so this is just to test the waters," Musk said of the poll which came on the heels of Tesla posting its lowest profit margin in five years on price cuts and increased spending on AI projects.</p>

<p>During Tesla's earning conference call, Musk said xAI would be "helpful in advancing full self-driving and in building up the new Tesla data center," adding that there are opportunities to integrate xAI's chatbot, Grok, with Tesla's software.</p>

<p>Nearly 3 hours after the poll was posted, roughly 386,000 people had participated with 70% voting in favour of the investment.</p>

<p>Tesla did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment, while xAI could not be reached for comment.</p>

<p>Musk, the world's richest person, launched xAI last year, hoping to build an alternative to ChatGPT. The startup raised $6 billion in a series B funding in May, attaining a post-money valuation of $24 billion. Backers include Andreessen Horowitz and Sequoia Capital.</p>

<p>Musk has previously said that he plans for a quarter of xAI to be owned by investors in X, formerly known as Twitter, which he bought for $44 billion although the social media firm's value has plunged since then.</p>

<p>On the earnings call, Musk also dismissed concerns that he may be diverting resources from Tesla to some of his other companies.</p>

<p>In June, CNBC reported that he had ordered Nvidia to ship thousands of AI chips destined for Tesla to xAI and X. Musk said Tesla's data center was full and there was no place to put the chips.</p>

<p>Musk is a frequent poller on X. In 2021, he asked Twitter users about whether he should sell 10% of his Tesla stake and commenced selling shares just days after the poll.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8trrs42_elon-musk_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk, the world's richest person, launched xAI last year]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-ex-pm-imran-khan-refuses-to-undergo-polygraph-test-linked-to-may-9-riots-6180309]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Imran Khan Refuses To Undergo Polygraph Test Linked To May 9 Riots]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-ex-pm-imran-khan-refuses-to-undergo-polygraph-test-linked-to-may-9-riots-6180309]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 21:02:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's jailed former prime minister Imran Khan has refused to undergo polygraph and voice matching tests as part of an investigation by Lahore police in connection with a dozen cases related to the unprecedented May 9 riots last year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's jailed former prime minister Imran Khan has refused to undergo polygraph and voice matching tests as part of an investigation by Lahore police in connection with a dozen cases related to the unprecedented May 9 riots last year.</p>

<p>A 12-member forensic team reached Adiala Jail on Tuesday to conduct the polygraph test on the 71-year-old cricketer-turned-politician.</p>

<p>The May 9 riots in 2023 were triggered across the country after the Pakistan-Tehreek-e-Insaf founder was arrested by the National Accountability Bureau (NAB) in a 190-million-pound corruption case. He faces over 200 cases and has been in jail since August last year.</p>

<p>The Lahore police team, led by a Deputy Superintendent of Police, arrived at the prison premises to conduct the tests, the Express Tribune reported.</p>

<p>They were accompanied by experts from the Punjab Forensic Science Agency (PFSA), the report said.</p>

<p>The PFSA experts were to perform polygraph, voice matching, and photogrammetry tests on the former prime minister.</p>

<p>The PTI founder answered the questions of the police for 15 minutes. However, Imran Khan refused to undergo the polygraph test and other tests planned by the Punjab Forensic Science Agency's team, the Nation newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Imran Khan said he was under investigation by many institutions and he would give time to the police after the completion of his earlier inquiries, it said.</p>

<p>The police officials also questioned him about various aspects of the May 9 riots that targeted the Lahore corps commander's residence, military installations and public properties, the Dawn newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Following their visit, the police team and PFSA experts briefed Lahore DIG Investigation Zeeshan Asghar on Imran Khan's lack of cooperation. The matter will be discussed in a meeting of senior police officers to devise a strategy for a follow-up visit in consultation with the prosecution department, the report said.</p>

<p>During the May 9 protests, alleged PTI workers and supporters attacked and vandalised military installations including the General Headquarters as well as monuments.</p>

<p>After the unprecedented violence, authorities swung into action and initiated a massive crackdown against the PTI while also holding trials of over 100 PTI workers in military courts.</p>

<p>Civil and military authorities have been accusing Imran Khan of planning the May 9 conspiracy ahead of his arrest, a claim vehemently rejected by him and his party.</p>

<p>Imran Khan denied giving orders for vandalising state properties but did acknowledge that he had asked his party to stage a peaceful protest outside the GHQ in case of his arrest.</p>

<p>Imran Khan has been imprisoned at the high-security Adiala Jail in Rawalpindi for almost a year upon his conviction in three cases - the Toshakhana corruption case, the cipher case, and the un-Islamic marriage case -- in which his wife, Bushra Bibi, is also jailed.</p>

<p>Though the former-cricketer-turned-politician had secured bail or his conviction was set aside, he has not been released.</p>

<p>Imran Khan was arrested on August 5 last year after his conviction in the first Toshakhana corruption case filed by the Election Commission of Pakistan. Since then, he has been kept in jail in various cases.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/kmjlqps8_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_03_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Imran Khan has been imprisoned at the high-security Adiala Jail (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-military-intelligence-officer-injured-in-moscow-car-bomb-attack-report-6180239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Military Intelligence Officer Injured In Car Bomb Attack: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-military-intelligence-officer-injured-in-moscow-car-bomb-attack-report-6180239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 24 Jul 2024 20:52:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A car bomb injured an officer from Russia's military intelligence agency in northern Moscow on Wednesday, the Kommersant newspaper reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A car bomb injured an officer from Russia's military intelligence agency in northern Moscow on Wednesday, the Kommersant newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Russia's interior ministry said that two people were injured in a blast caused by the detonation of an unidentified device and said that a criminal case had been opened.</p>

<p>Alexander Bortnikov, head of the Federal Security Service (FSB), told the SHOT Telegram channel that the suspect had fled to Turkey and that the FSB was working to extradite the individual.</p>

<p>Later on Wednesday, Turkish Interior Minister Ali Yerlikaya said in a post on X that a Russian citizen suspected of the attack had been arrested in Bodrum, having arrived from Moscow by plane.</p>

<p>Footage shared by Russian media showed an explosion ripping through a Toyota Land Cruiser shortly after the officer and an unidentified woman got into the vehicle.</p>

<p>Kommersant, one of Russia's leading newspapers, said that the injured man served in the Main Directorate of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation, widely referred to as GRU.</p>

<p>Baza, which has sources in Russia's security services, also said the injured man was a GRU officer.</p>

<p>State news agency TASS said that an officer and his wife had been injured in the blast. The man's feet were blown off, according to TASS. Five other cars were damaged in the blast, the agency said.</p>

<p>Reuters was unable to independently verify the reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/riruhorg_moscow-car-bomb-blast_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia's interior ministry said that two people were injured in a blast]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>