<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 12:55:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secrets-of-palestinians-nablus-soap-making-7214194]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secrets Of Palestinians' Nablus-Soap Making]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secrets-of-palestinians-nablus-soap-making-7214194]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 12:48:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UNESCO has recognised the thousand-year-old traditional practice of Nablus soap-making as an Intangible Cultural Heritage]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Initiated into the thousand-year-old practice of Nablus soap making by a distant relative, Umm al-Abed is now passing on the secrets of the practice newly designated by UNESCO as intangible world heritage.</p>

<p>Umm al-Abed handcrafts soap at her home in the village of Salem, east of Nablus, in one of many small soap workshops across the Israeli-occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>The process is rudimentary, involving a plastic bucket in a concrete courtyard and just three ingredients: olive oil, water and lye.</p>

<p>"The person who taught us to make the soap was an elderly relative from the village of Immatin. A long time ago, around 20 to 30 years, she came here and made soap," Umm al-Abed said.</p>

<p>"When she cooked the oil, I watched how she did it. I learnt the processes and I began to make soap myself. I made it for all the residents" of the village, she said.</p>

<p>Behind Umm al-Abed, the women were hard at work. One poured olive oil from a container, then added the lye. Using a long stick, she stirred the mixture with one hand and poured in water with the other. As she did so, the mixture gradually turned vibrant green.</p>

<p>The cooking is done in an oil drum over a wood fire. When the mixture is ready, it is poured into large, plastic-lined trays and left to cool and harden.</p>

<p>The giant block is then marked by hand before being cut into small bars of soap with a giant metal sheet.</p>

<p>The artisanal process, handed down from generation to generation, was recently added to UNESCO's list of intangible cultural heritage.</p>

<p><strong>'Need to preserve it'</strong></p>

<p>It joins other Palestinian entries like hikaye, a tradition of female storytelling, the traditional dabkeh dance and embroidery.</p>

<p>According to the UN's cultural organisation: "The use of olive oil reflects people's strong relation to nature, and many people use their homemade soap as a personal gift for celebrations such as weddings and birthdays."</p>

<p>"Most families in Palestine share the tradition, with both men and women taking part" in all stages of production and children helping to cut and pack it.</p>

<p>In Nablus, the Tuqan soap factory, established in 1872, continues to churn out bars.</p>

<p>It was founded "in the Ottoman period and has made soap ever since", said Nael Qubbaj, the factory chief.</p>

<p>He sat in his office, surrounded by faded portraits of suit and fez-wearing men, all members of the Abdul Fattah Tuqan family, co-founders of the factory.</p>

<p>The site's output is considerably higher than that of Umm al-Abed's artisanal workshop.</p>

<p>On the factory floor, a layer of soap covered the whole room from wall to wall. A barefoot soap maker slowly walked backwards across the room slicing the vast soap carpet into perfectly sized individual blocks.</p>

<p>The thousands of individual soaps were then stacked into hollow round towers to dry before being individually wrapped.</p>

<p>Recognition by UNESCO of Nablus soap "is an acknowledgement by the global community... of the significance of this craft and the need to preserve it," said Qubbaj.</p>

<p>Doing so was especially important "given the Israeli occupation's efforts to undermine these traditional industries," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/h8rdlop8_nabulsi-soap-bars_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Newly-made 'Nabulsi' soap bars are piled up to dry]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-murder-suspect-luigi-mangiones-social-media-tells-about-him-7213522]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What UnitedHealthCare CEO Murder Suspect's Social Media Tells About Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-murder-suspect-luigi-mangiones-social-media-tells-about-him-7213522]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 12:46:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 26-year-old suspect in the UnitedHealthcare CEO murder case had a history of posting bizarre and extremist views on social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 26-year-old suspect in the UnitedHealthcare CEO murder case had a history of posting bizarre and extremist views on social media. On X,&nbsp; Luigi Mangione's posts ranged from calling for a ban on sex toys in Japan to comparisons between modern America and the fall of the Roman Empire.</p>

<p>In April, he made headlines with a controversial take on Japan's falling population. He argued that the real issue wasn't immigration but rather an overreliance on sex toys and pornography. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/parasites-document-found-with-unitedhealthcare-ceo-murder-suspect-7212733">Mangione suggested Japan</a> ban products such as Tenga Fleshlights and promote “natural human interaction, sex, physical fitness, and spirituality” to combat this trend.</p>

<p>He also criticised the “modern Japanese urban environment,” recommending they shift from automated services such as conveyor belt sushi and vending machines to human interactions, including “real human waiters.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Modern Japanese urban environment is an evolutionary mismatch for the human animal.<br />
<br />
The solution to falling birthdates isn't immigration. It's cultural.<br />
<br />
Encourage natural human interaction, sex, physical fitness and spirituality:<br />
* ban Tenga fleshlights and “Japan Real Hole”… <a href="https://t.co/3OaJLJPwpX">https://t.co/3OaJLJPwpX</a></p>
— Luigi Mangione (@PepMangione) <a href="https://twitter.com/PepMangione/status/1780863519677940189?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>His social media also reveals an admiration for controversial figures such as Aldous Huxley, Ted Kaczynski (the Unabomber), and Jonathan Haidt. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-cops-zeroed-in-on-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompsons-murder-suspect-luigi-mangione-7212656">Mangione frequently</a> quoted Huxley's <em>Brave New World</em>, conveying a disdain for comfort and conformity: “But I don't want comfort. I want God, I want poetry, I want real danger, I want freedom, I want goodness. I want sin.”</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luigi-mangione-man-behind-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-7212585">Mangione also shared</a> a quote on his Goodreads account from Ted Kaczynski, the notorious “Unabomber” who terrorised the US for nearly two decades with deadly bombings before his arrest in 1996. The quote, which <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564">Mangione liked</a>, reads: “Imagine a society that subjects people to conditions that make them terribly unhappy then gives them the drugs to take away their unhappiness.”</p>

<p>The 26-year-old also frequently engaged with the work of blogger Tim Urban, known for his website <em>Wait But Why, </em>which explores artificial intelligence, space exploration, and human productivity.</p>

<p>In a post reposted by Mangione, Urban advocated for restricting cell phone use in children under the age of 16, citing research on the negative effects of screen time on mental health.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It'll soon become ubiquitous among upper class families to restrict kids under 16 from using social media. Hopefully the trend spreads to all families before too long. A hundred times easier to enforce the rule when all parents are doing it.<a href="https://t.co/TuAJvk7DXa">https://t.co/TuAJvk7DXa</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/JonHaidt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JonHaidt</a></p>
— Tim Urban (@waitbutwhy) <a href="https://twitter.com/waitbutwhy/status/1772660199481819205?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>His social media posts frequently talked about masculinity, often romanticising male resilience and the pursuit of “daring feats.” He reposted a tweet that read, “Men are made for impossible situations and daring feats… This is the heart that society is trying so hard to quash.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">If you want to understand men better, just look at all the movies they've made, books they've written, and games they invent when they're young.<br />
<br />
Almost every single one is about a young man being thrust into a position or situation he doesn't know if he can overcome. Many times…</p>
— Daughter of Wolves (@Alicia_Bittle_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Alicia_Bittle_/status/1780584589540335887?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He was also an advocate for weightlifting, describing it as a superior alternative to antidepressants and engaging with fitness influencers for tips.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ilobepl_luigi-mangione-afp_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione studied at the Ivy League University of Pennsylvania.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organe-frances-largest-internet-operator-fined-50-million-euros-for-fake-emails-7213824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France's Largest Internet Operator Fined 50 Million Euros For Fake Emails]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organe-frances-largest-internet-operator-fined-50-million-euros-for-fake-emails-7213824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 11:52:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France's largest internet operator Orange was on Tuesday slapped with a 50-million-euro ($53-million) fine for sending unsolicited ads disguised as emails to customers of its email service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France's largest internet operator Orange was on Tuesday slapped with a 50-million-euro ($53-million) fine for sending unsolicited ads disguised as emails to customers of its email service.</p>

<p>Orange is the successor to France's monopoly telephone operator and remains the leading telecommunications firm with a popular email service.</p>

<p>"Internet access and email service provider Orange used its email service to introduce advertisements between emails" that resembled emails, said Louis Dutheillet de Lamothe, deputy head of France's privacy watchdog CNIL.</p>

<p>Advertisers in France are required to obtain permission before sending material to a person's email address and CNIL considered Orange's actions were equivalent to that even if the email addresses of users were not utilised.</p>

<p>The amount of the fine was unusual except for fines imposed on tech giants, but CNIL said noted that more than 7.8 million users received the unsolicited ads.</p>

<p>CNIL "took into account the fact it was a breach that generated money" for Orange, Dutheillet de Lamothe told AFP.</p>

<p>He said the fine should also serve as a warning for other operators.</p>

<p>CNIL also said the fine took into account that in November 2023 Orange changed its email interface to make ads clear to users.</p>

<p>It also found that Orange users who asked to stop receiving cookies -- code that allows advertisers to track users activities on the Internet -- continued to receive them anyway.</p>

<p>Orange was given three months to correct that problem or face additional fines.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ssvo3jb8_mobile-internet-speed_625x300_06_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Orange users receive cookies despite rejecting them.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-commander-apologises-amid-martial-law-controversy-7213173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm An Incompetent Commander": Korea Military Leader On Martial Law Chaos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-commander-apologises-amid-martial-law-controversy-7213173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 11:37:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kim Hyun-Tae, the head of South Korea's elite 707th Special Missions Group, has publicly apologised for deploying troops to the National Assembly. The act sparked widespread public outrage and scrutiny following an emergency martial law declaration b]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kim Hyun-Tae, the head of South Korea's elite 707th Special Missions Group, has publicly apologised for deploying troops to the National Assembly. The act sparked widespread public outrage and scrutiny following an emergency martial law declaration by President Yoon Suk Yeol on December 3.</p>

<p>During a press briefing at the War Memorial in Yongsan District, Central Seoul, Kim took full responsibility for sending soldiers to prevent lawmakers from entering the assembly, according to <a href="https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2024-12-09/national/socialAffairs/I-am-an-incompetent-and-irresponsible-commander-Special-forces-unit-chief-apologizes-for-sending-troops-to-National-Assembly/2195949" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Korea JoongAng Daily</a>.</p>

<p>“I was the one who ordered the soldiers to head to the National Assembly and break the windows to enter,” Kim said. He expressed deep regret, stating, “I am an incompetent and irresponsible commander. I pushed the unit to the brink. The troops are not at fault. If they are guilty of anything, it is following the orders of an incapable commander.”</p>

<p>Kim, who commanded 197 soldiers to confront barriers set up by those attempting to access the National Assembly, described the troops as “your sons and daughters who love this country” and labelled them as the “most pitiable victims” of former Defence Minister Kim Yong-Hyun, who resigned on December 4 — a resignation accepted by President Yoon the following day.</p>

<p>The political and military fallout from the emergency martial law, which lasted only six hours, has been significant. On December 8, military prosecutors sought emergency travel bans for 10 personnel, including Kim and Army Chief of Staff General Park An-su.</p>

<p>The government also imposed an overseas travel restriction on President Yoon, as prosecutors deliberate over potential charges of insurrection linked to his failed martial law attempt. This measure, confirmed by the Corruption Investigation Office on December 9, adds to the turmoil surrounding Yoon's administration, according to <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/12/08/asia/south-korea-commander-apology-martial-law-intl-hnk/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>The sequence began with President Yoon's announcement on December 3, which was met with nationwide protests. Demonstrators gathered outside the National Assembly, demanding Yoon's resignation and defying the military order. The night culminated in lawmakers forcing their way past almost 300 troops stationed at the assembly and unanimously voting to annul the decree — an act that effectively overturned the president's directive.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/d9kskbgg_south-korea-martial-law-reuters_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The sequence began with President Yoon's announcement on December 3.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-conclude-they-have-no-idea-why-universe-is-growing-the-way-it-is-7213677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Conclude They Have No Idea Why Universe Is Growing The Way It Is]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-conclude-they-have-no-idea-why-universe-is-growing-the-way-it-is-7213677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 11:30:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists cross-checked data from JWT and Hubble and concluded the mismatch in data could only be explained by a new phenomenon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists who analysed the largest sample of James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) data collected over its first two years in space have concluded that a new feature and not a flaw in telescope measurements could be the reason why the universe is expanding faster today than it did in its infancy billions of years ago. The decades-long mystery has kept scientists across the world confused and while some believe that dark energy might be driving the change in acceleration, others state that since we have no clear idea what constitutes dark energy, a conclusive theory is still required.</p>

<p>The conundrum, referred to as the Hubble tension, can change the field of physics altogether. In 2019, the measurements by the Hubble Space Telescope confirmed the problem was real. Fast forward to 2024, and JWT's new data, published in The Astrophysical Journal, offers a crucial cross-check to address the mismatch in measurements of the universe's mysterious expansion.</p>

<p>"The discrepancy between the observed expansion rate of the universe and the predictions of the standard model suggests that our understanding of the universe may be incomplete," said Nobel laureate and lead author Adam Riess.</p>

<p>"With two NASA flagship telescopes now confirming each other's findings, we must take this [Hubble tension] problem very seriously-it's a challenge but also an incredible opportunity to learn more about our universe."</p>

<p>Mr Riess' team used three different methods to verify the Hubble telescope's measure of the expansion rate of the universe. While observations from both telescopes aligned closely, they still produce higher values compared to projections made using the "standard model of cosmology", which calculates the expansion rate using data from cosmic microwave background -- the faint radiation left after the Big Bang.</p>

<p>The standard model yields a Hubble constant of about 67-68 kilometres per second per megaparsec while the data from two telescopes yield a value of 70 to 76, with a mean of 73 km/s/Mpc. Such mismatch in numbers which is too large to be bridged by approximation, has left the scientists perplexed.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/black-holes-might-be-responsible-for-expansion-of-universe-new-study-claims-6919473" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Black Holes Might Be Responsible For Expansion Of Universe, New Study Claims</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Black holes driving the universe's expansion?</strong></h3>

<p>While Mr Reiss and his colleagues search for answers, a study published last month claimed that black holes were driving the expansion of the universe instead of dark energy.</p>

<p>For a long time, scientists have believed in the inflationary universe theory which states that almost 14 billion years ago, at the start of the Big Bang, a mysterious energy, believed to be dark energy, accelerated the expansion of the infant universe.</p>

<p>However, the radical new study challenges this notion. After analysing data from the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI), scientists claimed that the density of dark matter increased over time which agrees with how the amount and mass of black holes increased as the universe aged.</p>

<p>Researchers say the findings of the study could lead to a renewed understanding of the universe and the true composition of black holes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/kias9ndg_colour-of-universe_625x300_24_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The universe is expanding rapidly now than it did at the beginning.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-navy-building-two-ship-walls-in-pacific-says-taiwan-7213526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Sea Deployment in Region Bigger Than 2022 Military Drills, Says Taiwan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-navy-building-two-ship-walls-in-pacific-says-taiwan-7213526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 11:06:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China is deploying its largest navy fleet in regional waters in nearly three decades, posing a threat to Taiwan that is more pronounced than previous Chinese war games, the Taiwanese defence ministry said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China is deploying its largest navy fleet in regional waters in nearly three decades, posing a threat to Taiwan that is more pronounced than previous Chinese war games, the Taiwanese defence ministry said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Speaking in Taipei, defence ministry spokesperson Sun Li-fang said the scale of the current Chinese naval deployment in an area running from the southern Japanese islands down into the South China Sea was the largest since China held war games around Taiwan ahead of 1996 Taiwanese presidential elections.</p>

<p>China's military has yet to comment and has not confirmed it is carrying out any exercises.</p>

<p>China, which views democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory over the island's rejection, had been expected to launch drills to express its anger at President Lai Ching-te's tour of the Pacific that ended on Friday, which included stopovers in Hawaii and the U.S. territory of Guam.</p>

<p>Taiwan's military raised its alert on Monday after saying China had reserved airspace and deployed naval and coast guard vessels.</p>

<p>"The current scale is the largest compared to the previous four," Sun said. "Regardless of whether they have announced drills, they are posing a great threats to us."</p>

<p>Senior ministry intelligence officer Hsieh Jih-sheng told the same press conference there have so far been no live fire drills in China's seven "reserved" air space zones, two of which are in the Taiwan Strait, but there had been a significant increase in Chinese activity to the north of Taiwan over the last day.</p>

<p>The number of China navy and coast guard ships in the region, which a Taiwan security source told Reuters remained at around 90, was "very alarming", and China was taking aim at other countries in the region and not only Taiwan, he added.</p>

<p>China's deployment in the First Island Chain - which runs from Japan through Taiwan, the Philippines and on to Borneo, enclosing China's coastal seas - is aimed at area denial to prevent foreign forces from interfering, Hsieh said.</p>

<h3><strong>INTERNAL SEA</strong></h3>

<p>The ministry said China's navy is building two "walls" in the Pacific, one at the eastern end of Taiwan's Air Defence Identification Zone and the other further out in the Pacific.</p>

<p>"They are sending a very simple message with these two walls: trying to make the&nbsp;Taiwan&nbsp;Strait an internal sea" of China, said Hsieh.</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, the defence ministry said it detected 47 military aircraft operating around the island over the past 24 hours, as well as 12 navy vessels and nine "official" ships, which refers to vessels from ostensibly civilian agencies such as the coast guard.</p>

<p>Of the aircraft, 26 flew in an area to the north of Taiwan off the coast of China's Zhejiang province, six in the Taiwan Strait and a further 15 to the island's southwest, according to a map the ministry provided in its daily morning statement on Chinese activities.</p>

<p>A senior Taiwan security source told Reuters that the Chinese aircraft simulated attacks on foreign naval ships and practised driving away military and civilian aircraft as part of a "blockade exercise".</p>

<p>Lai and his government reject Beijing's sovereignty claims, saying only Taiwan's people can decide their future.</p>

<p>China says the Taiwan issue is the "core of its core interests" and a red line the United States should not cross.</p>

<p>China has held two rounds of major war games around Taiwan so far this year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/o7fglec8_south-china-sea-reuters_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China views democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-regime-change-bashar-al-assad-will-not-hesitate-syria-rebel-leaders-big-warning-to-assads-men-7213509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Not Hesitate...": Syria Rebel Leader's Big Warning To Assad's Men]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-regime-change-bashar-al-assad-will-not-hesitate-syria-rebel-leaders-big-warning-to-assads-men-7213509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 11:01:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Abu Mohammed al-Jolani aka Ahmed al-Sharaa, the Syrian rebel leader who led the lightning offensive that put an end to Bashar al-Assad's rule, has said the new dispensation would go after senior officials responsible for torture]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Abu Mohammed al-Jolani aka Ahmed al-Sharaa, the Syrian rebel leader who led the lightning offensive that put an end to Bashar al-Assad's rule, has said the new dispensation would go after senior officials responsible for torture and abuses under the previous regime.</p>

<p>Sharaa met outgoing prime minister Mohammed al-Jalali "to coordinate a transfer of power that guarantees the provision of services" to Syria's people, a statement posted on the rebels' Telegram channels said.</p>

<p>The statement added that the new government "will not hesitate to hold accountable the criminals, murderers, security and army officers involved in torturing the Syrian people".</p>

<p>The movement against the Bashar al-Assad regime began in 2011, but he cracked down hard, killing about half a million people and forcing many more to flee the country. With support from allies Russia and Iran, Assad managed to stave off any rebel offensive for over a decade. But with his allies occupied in wars in Ukraine and Gaza, Assad was exposed and the rebels did not miss the opportunity.&nbsp;As the rebel tanks rolled into Damascus, Assad fled Syria and curtains came down on the five-decade rule of his clan.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nkfn1s78_syrian-celebrations_625x300_10_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The regime change in Syria came as a rebirth for the thousands of inmates in Syria's prisons and detention centres, many of them jailed for dissent.</p>

<p>According to news agency AFP, thousands gathered outside Saydnaya prison near Damascus, synonymous with the worst atrocities of Assad's rule, to look for their relatives.</p>

<p>Over 1 lakh inmates are believed to have died -- including executions and natural deaths -- in Syrian prisons during the Assad rule, according to a 2021 report by the UK-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights. Of them, more than 30,000 died in Saydnaya alone. An Amnesty International investigation found that "murder, torture, enforced disappearances and extermination carried out at Saydnaya since 2011 have been perpetrated as part of an attack against the civilian population that has been widespread, as well as systematic, and carried out in furtherance of state policy". Such were the tales of torture in Saydnaya that it was known as a "human slaughterhouse".</p>

<p>With Assad gone, the family members of these inmates, many of whom have been detained for years, are looking for them. Among them is Aida Taha, 65, who is looking for her brother, arrested in 2012. "I ran like crazy. But I found out that some prisoners were still in the basements. There are three or four floors underground," she told AFP.</p>

<p>Many of the prisoners who have managed to escape from the now-unmanned prisons roam the streets of Damascus, with unmistakable signs of torture and hunger.</p>

<p>A civil servant at the finance ministry said people were scared to speak out. "It's indescribable. We never thought this nightmare would end. We are reborn. We were afraid to speak for 55 years, even at home. We used to say the walls had ears," Rim Ramadan, 49, told AFP.</p>

<p>Syria's parliament, earlier pro-Assad, has said it supports "the will of the people to build a new Syria towards a better future governed by law and justice". Baath party has said it will support "a transitional phase in Syria aimed at defending the unity of the country."</p>

<p>Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, which led the rebel groups' blitzkrieg, was earlier banned by Western powers for its links with Al-Qaeda. Over the years, the organisation has tried to soften its image.</p>

<p>As Syria looks to rebuild, Germany and France have said they were ready to cooperate with the new leadership "on the basis of fundamental human rights and the protection of ethnic and religious minorities". British Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said HTS must reject "terrorism and violence" before Britain can engage with it. US State Secretary Antony Blinken Washington DC is determined to prevent IS re-establishing safe havens in Syria. "We have a clear interest in doing what we can to avoid the fragmentation of Syria, mass migrations from Syria and, of course, the export of terrorism and extremism," he said.</p>

<p>The UN has said the Assad regime must be held to account. The ousted leader has reportedly fled to Russia, but Kremlin has not confirmed this.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dvn1rde8_al-jolani_625x300_10_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Abu Mohammed al-Jolani led the lightning offensive that put an end to Bashar al-Assad's rule]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/bird-flu-poised-to-spark-the-next-global-pandemic-experts-warn-of-rising-risks-7213390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bird Flu Poised To Spark Next Global Pandemic, Experts Warn Of Rising Risks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/bird-flu-poised-to-spark-the-next-global-pandemic-experts-warn-of-rising-risks-7213390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:45:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists identify mutation that could facilitate H5N1 "bird flu" virus infection and potential transmission in humans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the H5N1 bird flu virus is spreading fast among animals in the United States, scientists are now on high alert for signs of human-to-human transmission. According to new research, the virus might require only one mutation to be able to transmit between humans.</p>

<p>H5N1 is a highly deadly virus, killing 50% of humans who become infected. Experts believe that closely monitoring animal infections is necessary to control the virus, halt its mutation, and prevent it from directly infecting people, thereby preventing a global outbreak.</p>

<p>Normally, bird flu needs several mutations to be a threat to humans. However, scientists at the Scripps Research Institute in California suggest that this time, the virus could adapt faster, raising concerns about the possibility of a pandemic.</p>

<p>The findings-published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt0180"><em>Journal Science </em></a>on December 5, 2024-highlight the need to monitor H5N1's evolution.</p>

<p>As per a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scripps.edu/news-and-events/press-room/2024/20241205-wilson-paulson-h5n1.html"><em>release by Scripps Research Institute, </em></a>currently, there are no documented cases of H5N1 transmitting between people: bird flu cases in humans have been linked to close contact with contaminated environments as well as infected birds (including poultry), dairy cows, and other animals. However, public health officials are concerned about the potential for the virus to evolve to transmit efficiently between humans, which could lead to a new, potentially deadly pandemic.</p>

<p>The flu virus attaches to its host via a protein called hemagglutinin that binds to glycan receptors on the surfaces of host cells. Glycans are chains of sugar molecules on cell surface proteins that can act as binding sites for some viruses. Avian (bird) influenza viruses like H5N1 primarily infect hosts with sialic acid-containing glycan receptors found in birds (avian-type receptors). While the viruses rarely adapt to humans, if they evolve to recognise sialylated glycan receptors found in people (human-type receptors), they could gain the ability to infect and possibly transmit between humans.</p>

<p>"Monitoring changes in receptor specificity (the way a virus recognises host cells) is crucial because receptor binding is a key step toward transmissibility," says Ian Wilson, DPhil, co-senior author and the Hansen Professor of Structural Biology at Scripps Research. "That being said, receptor mutations alone don't guarantee that the virus will transmit between humans."</p>

<p>"The findings demonstrate how easily this virus could evolve to recognise human-type receptors," says first author Ting-Hui Lin, a postdoctoral associate at Scripps Research. "However, our study doesn't suggest that such evolution has occurred or that the current H5N1 virus with only this mutation would be transmissible between humans."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-11/in4q6u44_bird-flu-outbreak-reuters_625x300_15_November_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[New findings highlight the importance of ongoing surveillance for H5N1 mutations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/loud-explosions-heard-in-damascus-as-israel-carries-air-strikes-in-syria-7213327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Loud Explosions Heard In Damascus As Israel Carries Air Strikes In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/loud-explosions-heard-in-damascus-as-israel-carries-air-strikes-in-syria-7213327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:31:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has carried out "about 250 air strikes on Syrian territory" over the last 48 hours to destroy the former regime's military capabilities, according to the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A war monitor said Tuesday that Israel had "destroyed the most important military sites in Syria" with a flurry of air strikes since the fall of president Bashar al-Assad's government.</p>

<p>Israel, which borders Syria, sent troops into a buffer zone on the east of the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights after Assad's fall, in what Foreign Minister Gideon Saar described as a "limited and temporary step" for "security reasons".</p>

<p>It has also carried out "about 250 air strikes on Syrian territory" over the last 48 hours with the aim of destroying the former regime's military capabilities, according to the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.</p>

<p>"Israel destroyed the most important military sites in Syria, including Syrian airports and their warehouses, aircraft squadrons, radars, military signal stations, and many weapons and ammunition depots in various locations in most Syrian governorates," the Britain-based Observatory said in a statement Tuesday.</p>

<p>Near the port city of Latakia, Israel targeted an air defense facility and damaged Syrian naval ships as well as military warehouses.</p>

<p>In and around the capital Damascus, strikes targeted military installations, research centers, and the electronic warfare administration.</p>

<p>Early Tuesday, AFP journalists heard loud explosions in Damascus, hours after the strikes reported by the Observatory.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/t9v3g5no_israeli-airstrikes-syria-_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smoke billows on the outskirts of the Syrian capital Damascus following Israeli airstrikes on December 9.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-syrias-al-assad-flees-to-russia-rebels-work-to-form-interim-government-7213298]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Syria's Al-Assad Flees To Russia, Rebels Work To Form New Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-syrias-al-assad-flees-to-russia-rebels-work-to-form-interim-government-7213298]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:29:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A day after the lightning overthrow of President Bashar al-Assad, Syrian Prime Minister Mohammed Ghazi Jalali on Monday said he has agreed to hand power to the rebel-led Salvation Government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A day after the lightning overthrow of President Bashar al-Assad, Syrian Prime Minister Mohammed Ghazi Jalali on Monday said he has agreed to hand power to the rebel-led Salvation Government. The imminent transfer of power, which follows 13 years of civil war and five decades of iron-fisted Baath rule, has left Syrians, countries in the region and world powers nervous about what comes next as the rebel alliance prepares for government transition.</p>

<p>Syria's Islamist rebel leader Abu Mohammed al-Jolani, who is now using his real name Ahmed al-Sharaa, met with outgoing Prime Minister Al-Jalali on Monday "to coordinate a transfer of power that guarantees the provision of services" to Syria's people, said a statement posted on the rebels' Telegram channels.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a report by Al Jazeera television, the transitional authority would be headed by Mohamed al-Bashir, who has headed the Salvation Government, a de facto unrecognized quasi-state in Syria formed in November 2017 by HTS and other Syrian opposition groups. However the rebel alliance has not communicated plans for Syria's future, and there is no template for such a transition in the fractious region.</p>

<h3><strong>Promise Of Order</strong></h3>

<p>On Tuesday, Sharaa said the incoming authorities would prosecute senior officials in Mr Al-Asaad's government, who were responsible for torture and other abuses of Syrians. We "will not hesitate to hold accountable the criminals, murderers, security and army officers involved in torturing the Syrian people," he said, according to an AFP report.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bashar al-Assad iron-fisted's regime was known for the brutal complex of prisons and detention centres which were used to eliminate dissent by those suspected of stepping out of the ruling Baath party's line. But the autocrat was ousted as the Islamist-led rebels, spearheaded by Sharaa's Islamist Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), swept into the capital Damascus on Sunday, bringing a spectacular end to five decades of brutal rule by his clan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Jolani has vowed to rebuild Syria, and his HTS has spent years trying to soften its image to reassure foreign nations and minority groups within Syria. However, the group is still designated as a terrorist organization by many states and the UN, with its governing credentials uncertain.</p>

<p>"Syrians are looking forward to establishing a state of freedom, equality, rule of law, democracy, and we will join efforts to rebuild our country, to rebuild what was destroyed, and to rebuild the future, better future of Syria," Koussay Aldahhak, Syria's Ambassador to United Nations (UN) told reporters.</p>

<h3><strong>Global Uncertainty&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The United Nations Security Council (UNSC) met behind closed doors late on Monday, and diplomats said they were still in shock at how quickly Mr al-Assad's ouster unfolded over 12 days of rebellion, after several years of stalemate. "Everyone was taken by surprise, everyone, including the members of the council. So we have to wait and see and watch ... and evaluate how the situation will develop," Reuters reported Russian UN Ambassador Vassily Nebenzia as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Over the years, Russia played a major role in supporting al-Assad's government and helping it fight the rebels. The Syrian leader fled Damascus for Moscow on Sunday, ending his family's over 50 years of brutal rule.</p>

<p>Analysts believe that the situation in Syria could raise regional tensions. Meanwhile, The US is looking at ways to engage with Syrian rebel groups and is reaching out to partners in the region such as Turkey to start informal diplomacy.</p>

<p>"Now we're really focused right now on trying to see where the situation goes. Can there be a governing authority in Syria that respects the rights and dignities of the Syrian population," noted Deputy US Ambassador to the UN Robert Wood.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In another major challenge facing Syria, Israel has seized a buffer zone in the country's south, a move condemned by Egypt, Qatar and Saudi Arabia. Saudi Arabia said the move would "ruin Syria's chances of restoring security."</p>

<p>Tel Aviv is concerned over the formation of an Islamist government in Syria that opposes Israel. Israel said its airstrikes would carry on for days but told the UN Security Council that it was not intervening in Syria's conflict. It said it had taken "limited and temporary measures" solely to protect its security.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gqgfj8o_syria-reuter_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rebel fighters pose holding a Syrian opposition flag inside the Umayyad Mosque]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harmeet-dhillon-meet-chandigarhs-harmeet-dhillon-named-assistant-attorney-general-by-trump-7213007]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Chandigarh's Harmeet Dhillon, Named Assistant Attorney General By Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harmeet-dhillon-meet-chandigarhs-harmeet-dhillon-named-assistant-attorney-general-by-trump-7213007]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:55:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has nominated Indian-American Harmeet K Dhillon as Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights at the Department of Justice.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-indian-american-harmeet-dhillon-for-top-civil-rights-post-7212336 ">nominated Indian-American Harmeet K Dhillon</a> as Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights at the Department of Justice.&nbsp;“I am pleased to nominate Harmeet K. Dhillon as Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights at the US Department of Justice,” Trump wrote in a Truth Social post.</p>

<p>Ms Dhillon, an accomplished attorney, has made headlines for her legal battles against big tech companies, her defence of religious freedom during the COVID-19 pandemic, and her challenges to corporate policies she deems discriminatory, Trump said.<br />
<br />
<strong>Who is Harmeet Dhillon?</strong></p>

<ol>
	<li>Born in Chandigarh, Harmeet K Dhillon moved to the US as a child with her family. She graduated from Dartmouth College and the University of Virginia Law School.</li>
	<li>Ms Dhillon clerked for Hon. Paul V. Niemeyer at the United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit. She practised law in New York, London, and the San Francisco Bay Area, focusing on federal and state commercial litigation, arbitration, and intellectual property matters.</li>
	<li>In 2006, she founded her law firm, Dhillon Law Group Inc., specialising in commercial litigation, employment law, First Amendment rights, and election law. She is now the firm's Founding partner. She is also the CEO of the Centre for American Liberty.</li>
	<li>Ms Dhillon gained recognition for her battles against big tech companies for alleged censorship of free speech. She represented clients in election and campaign law matters, including compliance, ballot description contests, and intellectual property disputes related to campaign communications. She also advocated for religious freedoms during the COVID-19 pandemic and challenged corporate policies she considered discriminatory. She unsuccessfully ran for the position of Republican National Committee chairmanship in 2023.</li>
	<li>In 2016, Ms Dhillon became the first Indian-American to appear on the stage of the GOP Convention in Cleveland. She recited ‘Ardas' at the Republican National Convention in 2024, following which she faced racial attacks. She is an active member of the Sikh religious community and a defender of civil rights.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qis5hng8_harmeet-dhillon_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harmeet Dhillon is also the CEO of the Centre for American Liberty.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-atomic-bomb-survivors-group-nihon-hidankyo-to-get-2024-nobel-peace-prize-7213073]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan's Atomic Bomb Survivors' Group Nihon Hidankyo To Get Nobel Peace Prize]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-atomic-bomb-survivors-group-nihon-hidankyo-to-get-2024-nobel-peace-prize-7213073]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:48:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nihon Hidankyo lobbies against the weapons now resurging as a threat 80 years after the Hiroshima and Nagasaki bombings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year's Nobel Peace Prize will be presented Tuesday to Japan's atomic bomb survivors' group Nihon Hidankyo, which lobbies against the weapons now resurging as a threat 80 years after the Hiroshima and Nagasaki bombings.</p>

<p>The three co-chairs of Nihon Hidankyo will accept the prestigious award during a ceremony starting at 1:00 pm (1200 GMT) in Oslo's City Hall, at a time when states like Russia increasingly threaten to break the international taboo on the use of nuclear arms.</p>

<p>"Nuclear weapons and humanity cannot co-exist," one of the three co-chairs, Terumi Tanaka, told a press conference on Monday in the Norwegian capital.</p>

<p>"Humanity may come to its end even before climate change brings its devastating impacts," the 92-year-old said.</p>

<p>Nihon Hidankyo works tirelessly to rid the planet of the weapons of mass destruction, with testimonies from survivors of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, known as "hibakusha".</p>

<p>Around 140,000 people were killed in Hiroshima when the United States detonated an atomic bomb over the Japanese city on August 6, 1945.</p>

<p>A further 74,000 were killed by a US nuclear bomb in Nagasaki three days later.</p>

<p>Survivors suffered from radiation sickness and longer-term effects, including elevated risks of cancer.</p>

<p>The bombings, the only times nuclear weapons have been used in history, were the final blow to imperial Japan and its brutal rampage across Asia. It surrendered on August 15, 1945.</p>

<p>Tanaka was 13 when the bomb was dropped on Nagasaki, killing five members of his family.</p>

<p>On Monday, he expressed alarm at the resurgence of nuclear threats and urged Russian President Vladimir Putin to stop brandishing the threat to prevail in the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"President Putin, I don't think he truly understands what nuclear weapons are for human beings," he said.</p>

<p>"I don't think he has even thought about this."</p>

<p><strong>Firing signals</strong></p>

<p>Putin began making nuclear threats shortly after Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022. He signed a decree in late November lowering the threshold for using atomic weapons.</p>

<p>Russia has the largest nuclear arsenal in the world.</p>

<p>On November 21, Moscow fired its new Oreshnik hypersonic missile on the Ukrainian city of Dnipro in an escalation of the almost three-year war.</p>

<p>The missile is designed to be equipped with a nuclear warhead, but was not in this case.</p>

<p>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said Thursday that Moscow was ready to use "any means" to defend itself.</p>

<p>"It is crucial for humanity to uphold the nuclear taboo, to stigmatise these weapons as morally unacceptable," the chairman of the Norwegian Nobel Committee, Jorgen Watne Frydnes, said on Monday.</p>

<p>"To threaten with them is one way of reducing the significance of the taboo, and it should not be done," he added.</p>

<p>"And of course, to use them should never be done ever again by any nation on Earth."</p>

<p>North Korea, which has increased its ballistic missile tests, and Iran, which is suspected of developing nuclear weapons though it denies this, are also seen as posing a threat to the West.</p>

<p>Nine countries now have nuclear weapons: Britain, China, France, India, North Korea, Pakistan, Russia, the United States, and, unofficially, Israel.</p>

<p>In 2017, 122 governments negotiated and adopted the historic UN Treaty on the Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons (TPNW), but the text is considered largely symbolic as no nuclear power has signed it.</p>

<p>This year's Nobel prizes in the other disciplines -- medicine, physics, chemistry, literature and economics -- will be awarded at a separate ceremony in Stockholm.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/na2n28r_winner-of-the-2024-nobel-peace-prize-terumi-tanaka_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The representative of the winner of the 2024 Nobel Peace Prize, Terumi Tanaka]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-grateful-for-donald-trumps-strong-resolve-to-end-war-in-ukraine-7213011]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Grateful For Donald Trump's "Strong Resolve" To End War In Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-grateful-for-donald-trumps-strong-resolve-to-end-war-in-ukraine-7213011]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:39:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has long claimed he will settle the Russia-Ukraine war in "24 hours" once in power, raising alarm in Ukraine that it will be forced to make huge territorial concessions in exchange for peace.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Tuesday he was grateful for Donald Trump's "strong resolve" to end the war in Ukraine, after meeting the US president-elect in Paris last week.</p>

<p>French President Emmanuel Macron hosted three-way talks with Zelensky and Trump at the Elysee Palace on Saturday, as fears grow in Kyiv about the level of support Ukraine will receive under the incoming US administration.</p>

<p>"The most important thing is to work together on how to end this war -- that is our top priority. During the meeting in Paris, this was exactly what we focused on," Zelensky said in a post early Tuesday on social media platform X.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">There's a lot of discussion in the media about lowering the draft age for Ukrainians to go to the frontlines. We must focus on equipping existing brigades and training personnel to use this equipment. We must not compensate the lack of equipment and training with the youth of…</p>
— Volodymyr Zelenskyy / Володимир Зеленський (@ZelenskyyUa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1866243624356425889?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"I reiterate my gratitude to President Macron for organizing it, as well as my deep gratitude to President Trump for his strong resolve to bring this war to a fair end," the Ukrainian leader added.</p>

<p>Trump has long claimed he will settle the nearly three-year conflict in "24 hours" once in power, raising alarm in Ukraine that it will be forced to make huge territorial concessions in exchange for peace.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the Republican called for an "immediate ceasefire", writing on his Truth Social platform that Zelensky was ready to "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-for-immediate-ukraine-ceasefire-zelenskiy-says-guarantees-needed-7201115" target="_blank">make a deal and stop the madness</a>".</p>

<p>Zelensky also rejected calls to lower the draft age, following reports US officials want Ukraine to expand the pool of fighting-age men to include 18-year-olds.</p>

<p>"We must focus on equipping existing brigades and training personnel to use this equipment. We must not compensate the lack of equipment and training with the youth of soldiers," he said in the same post Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ab1idtb8_trump-zelenskyy-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Sunday, Donald Trump called for an "immediate ceasefire" and negotiations between Ukraine and Russia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/77-nobel-laureates-oppose-rfk-jr-as-donald-trumps-health-secretary-7212939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[77 Nobel Laureates Oppose RFK Jr As Donald Trump's Health Secretary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/77-nobel-laureates-oppose-rfk-jr-as-donald-trumps-health-secretary-7212939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:20:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["Placing Mr Kennedy in charge of DHHS would put the public's health in jeopardy," concludes the letter signed by 77 Nobel recipients in medicine, chemistry, physics and economics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Seventy-seven Nobel prize winners on Monday sent an open letter to the US Senate opposing the nomination of Robert F. Kennedy Jr., President-elect Donald Trump's choice for Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), citing his "lack of credentials" and anti-vaccine beliefs.</p>

<p>"In view of his record, placing Mr. Kennedy in charge of DHHS would put the public's health in jeopardy," concludes the letter signed by 77 Nobel recipients in medicine, chemistry, physics and economics.</p>

<p>Among the signatories is Drew Weissman, who received the 2023 Nobel Prize in Medicine for his work on developing mRNA vaccines, which was a major breakthrough in the fight against Covid-19.</p>

<p>Kennedy, a nephew of assassinated US president John F. Kennedy Jr, made his own White House run earlier this year before throwing his support behind Trump.</p>

<p>In return, Trump has tapped him to oversee the part of the executive branch in charge of health and medicine -- though his selection must be approved by a majority of the US Senate, as outlined by the Constitution.</p>

<p>An environmental lawyer by trade with no medical background, Kennedy has spent years professing conspiracy theories linking vaccines and autism, and most recently spread misinformation about Covid-19 vaccines.</p>

<p>He has said if he is confirmed for the position he will work to remove fluoride from tap water in the US, despite its addition being considered a major victory against bacteria causing tooth decay.</p>

<p>"In addition to his lack of credentials or relevant experience in medicine, science, public health, or administration," the letter reads, "Mr. Kennedy has been an opponent of many health-protecting and life-saving vaccines, such as those that prevent measles and polio."</p>

<p>"We strongly urge you to vote against the confirmation of his appointment," the letter said.</p>

<p>Kennedy is far from the only Trump cabinet nominee to stir controversy.</p>

<p>Among the most notable is Pete Hegseth, a Fox News anchor tapped to lead the Department of Defense, who has seen his nomination derailed with sexual assault allegations and rumors of excessive drinking.</p>

<p>And Trump's first pick for Attorney General, former US Congressman Matt Gaetz, withdrew after further scrutiny emerged of alleged sexual relations he had with a minor.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/h3r1nft8_robert-kennedy-jr_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/nostradamus-predictions-for-2025-asteroid-collision-to-plague-like-outbreak-and-more-7212856]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nostradamus' 2025 Predictions: Asteroid Collision To Plague-Like Outbreak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/nostradamus-predictions-for-2025-asteroid-collision-to-plague-like-outbreak-and-more-7212856]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:05:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Though Nostradamus' prophecies more often than not miss the mark, they do provide a certain thrill to the people reading them.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As 2024 draws to an end, social media users have once again turned to the 'prophet of doom', Nostradamus, for their fill of 2025 predictions. Born Michel de Nostredame, Nostradamus was a French astrologer and physician who lived in the 1500s and predicted some of the modern-day epochal moments such as Adolf Hitler's rise to power, the September 11 attacks and the COVID-19 pandemic. He is best known for his book Les Prophetis (The Prophecies), published in 1555, which contains 942 poetic quatrains that are widely interpreted for global events.</p>

<p>Researchers analysing his work have hinted that 2025 may have some hard-hitting events in store, ranging from an asteroid collision to another plague-like outbreak in the UK. Though Nostradamus' prophecies more often than not miss the mark, they do provide a certain thrill to the people reading them.</p>

<h3><strong>End of Russia-Ukraine war?</strong></h3>

<p>Nostradamus' 2024 prediction included the continuation of a continent-wide war but as per his vague writings, 2025 may witness a potential end to one of the long-running wars. The astrologer said owing to the exhaustion of the war, perhaps referring to the ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict that started in 2022, both sides may call it quits.</p>

<p>"Through long war all the army exhausted,so that they do not find money for the soldiers; instead of gold or silver, they will come to coin leather, Gallic brass, and the crescent sign of the Moon," he wrote.</p>

<p>The mention of "Gallic brass" and "sign of the moon" has led social media users to believe that France and Turkey may get involved in the conflict.</p>

<h3><strong>Plague and war</strong></h3>

<p>Nostradamus has predicted that the new year will weigh heavily on England which will be beset by "cruel wars' and face an "ancient plague" outbreak that would be "worse than enemies". Since his COVID-19 pandemic prediction came true, experts have put a pin on this prophecy.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/living-nostradamus-claims-four-prophecies-fulfilled-predicts-more-unforeseen-events-6564988" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | 'Living Nostradamus' Claims Four Prophecies Fulfilled, Predicts More Unforeseen Events</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Asteroid collision with Earth?</strong></h3>

<p>While other events may not cause civilisation loss, Nostradamus has predicted that 2025 may witness a giant asteroid collodion with the Earth, or coming in dangerous proximity to the planet. Though the prediction might suggest a wipeout of life from Earth, asteroids coming close to the planet is not a new phenomenon. Several hundred asteroids whiz past Earth every year with the majority of them maintaining a safe distance.</p>

<h3><strong>Natural disasters in Brazil</strong></h3>

<p>The prophecy also stated that the South American country of Brazil, which Nostradamus refers to as the "Garden of the World", may face flooding and potential volcanic activity, linked to climate change.</p>

<p>"Garden of the world near the new city, In the path of the hollow mountains: It will be seized and plunged into the Tub, Forced to drink waters poisoned by sulfur," read the eerie piece.</p>

<p>According to reports, Nostradamus' bleak worldview stems from heavy consumption of the Old Testament and the trauma of losing his wife and young children to illness, presumably the plague. Unable to save his loved one, Nostradamus sought solace in predicting doom and gloom that may befall humanity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/28l5ahjo_nostradamus_625x300_31_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nostradamus, referred to as the "prophet of doom".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/104-journalists-killed-in-2024-over-half-in-gaza-international-federation-of-journalists-7212855]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[104 Journalists Killed In 2024, Over Half In Gaza: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/104-journalists-killed-in-2024-over-half-in-gaza-international-federation-of-journalists-7212855]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 09:02:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The toll for 2024 is down on the 129 deaths in 2023 but still makes it "one of the worst years" on record, IFJ general secretary Anthony Bellanger told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year has been "particularly deadly" for journalists with 104 killed worldwide, over half of them being in Gaza, the International Federation of Journalists (IFJ) said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The toll for 2024 is down on the 129 deaths in 2023 but still makes it "one of the worst years" on record, IFJ general secretary Anthony Bellanger told AFP.</p>

<p>According to the figures collated by the press group 55 Palestinian media workers were killed in 2024 in the face of Israel's offensive in Gaza.</p>

<p>"Since the start of the war on 7 October 2023, at least 138 Palestinian journalists have been killed," the federation said.</p>

<p>Bellanger condemned the "massacre that is happening before the eyes of the world".</p>

<p>He said that "many journalists were targeted" in Gaza deliberately, while others had found themselves "in the wrong place, at the wrong time" in the fighting.</p>

<p>After the Middle East, the second most dangerous region for journalists was Asia with 20 killed, including six in Pakistan, five in Bangladesh and three in India.</p>

<p>In Europe, the war in Ukraine continued to claim journalist victims with four killed in 2024.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the IFJ said that across the globe 520 journalists were in prison -- a sharp uptick on the 427 being held behind bars last year.</p>

<p>China topped the list as the worst jailer of reporters with 135 being detained, including in Hong Kong, where the authorities have been criticised by Western nations for imposing national security laws quashing dissent and other freedoms.</p>

<p>The IFJ's count for the number of journalists killed is typically far higher than that of Reporters Without Borders, due to different counting methods.</p>

<p>In 2023 Reporters Without Borders said 54 journalists and two collaborators were killed in the course of their work. The NGO will publish its own figure for 2024 later this week.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/1iirjii8_gaza_625x300_13_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[55 Palestinian media workers were killed in 2024 in the face of Israel's offensive in Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/parasites-document-found-with-unitedhealthcare-ceo-murder-suspect-7212733]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Parasites...": Document Found With UnitedHealthcare CEO Murder Suspect]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/parasites-document-found-with-unitedhealthcare-ceo-murder-suspect-7212733]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 08:34:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione, the 26-year-old Ivy League graduate who is "person of interest" in the Manhattan killing of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, was reportedly carrying a manifesto railing against "corporate America" at the time of his arrest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Luigi Mangione, the 26-year-old Ivy League graduate who is a "strong person of interest" in the Manhattan killing of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, was reportedly carrying a manifesto railing against "corporate America" at the time of his arrest. The two-page handwritten document criticized the healthcare industry for putting profits above care and suggested that violence is the answer, according to senior law enforcement officials.</p>

<p>"I do apologize for any strife and trauma, but it had to be done," a police official who has seen the document told CNN.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the note, Mangione said he acted alone and that he was self-funded. "These parasites had it coming," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The document also included a screed against the healthcare industry, with Mangione lamenting the costs of healthcare, asking why the United States has the most expensive healthcare in the world but is rated poorly for life expectancy.</p>

<p>The US reportedly ranked 49 in life expectancy in 2022, per a report by the Associated Press story from August 2007. However, the country is expected to drop to 66th position globally in 2050, according to the Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the motive of Thompson's killing is still unknown, reports suggest Mangione's alleged actions could have been a political act. If &nbsp;Mangione is found guilty of Thompson's murder, the manifesto would be the second message from him. Earlier, it was found that the killer engraved 'Deny, defend, depose' on the casings of the bullet used in the UnitedHealthcare CEO's killing. &nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Luigi Mangione's Arrest</strong></h3>

<p>In addition to the manifesto, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luigi-mangione-man-behind-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-7212585#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Mangione</a> was also found carrying a gun, and a silencer, among other items at the time of his arrest in an Altoona, Pennsylvania, McDonald's. He has been charged with possession of an illegal weapon, forgery and other crimes in Pennsylvania after being arrested at a McDonald's on Monday morning.</p>

<p>Mangione was caught after an employee at the fast-food chain recognized him and alerted the police. "He was sitting there eating," The Guardian reported Joseph Kenny, the New York City police department's chief of detectives as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was reportedly found carrying identification with his name on it, along with a fake New Jersey ID - the same that police believe the gunman showed when he checked into a hostel on the Upper West Side of Manhattan on 24 November after Thompson's murder.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In last Wednesday's shooting, the gunman walked up behind <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Brian Thompson</a>, a senior executive at UnitedHealthcare -- one of the country's largest medical insurers -- and shot him dead in front of bystanders. The attack was captured by a surveillance camera and the footage seen by millions around the world as interest in the manhunt and mystery over the killer's motives built to a frenzy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After his arrest, Mangione was presented at Pennsylvania court on Tuesday, where he was arraigned. He&nbsp;is next due to appear in court on December 23.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro said that murder charges in New York state would follow, telling a media briefing "We do not kill people in cold blood to resolve policy differences or express a viewpoint."</p>

<h3><strong>About Luigi Mangione</strong></h3>

<p>Mangione social media presence shows that he belongs to a well-to-do family. Per his LinkedIn page, he has a bachelor's and master's degree in science engineering from the University of Pennsylvania. The claims were confirmed by a university spokesperson.</p>

<p>The suspect was reportedly born and raised in Maryland and has lived in San Francisco and Honolulu. As per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/09/unitedhealthcare-ceo-shooting-suspect-arrested" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">The Guardian </a>report, he was a valedictorian at Gilman High School in 2016, where he had expressed his desire to study at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/us/live-news/brian-thompson-unitedhealthcare-death-investigation-12-9-24#cm4hdmno4000b3b6mea2l9cef" rel="No Follow, Ni Index" target="_blank">CNN</a> reported that Mangione is the grandson of Nicholas Mangione, a prominent Baltimore real estate developer. The Mangione family reportedly owns Lorien Health Systems, a nursing home chain in Maryland, where the suspect volunteered in 2014, according to his LinkedIn page.</p>

<p>According to a New York Times report citing friends of Mangione, he lived with serious back pain and underwent surgery for the condition last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A photo on what appeared to be one of his social media accounts included an X-ray of an apparently injured spine.</p>

<p>His family released a joint statement late Monday saying they are "shocked and devastated by Luigi's arrest."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ecntjad8_unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-killer-luigi-mangione-twitter_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione was caught after an employee at the fast-food chain recognized him]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-cops-zeroed-in-on-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompsons-murder-suspect-luigi-mangione-7212656]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Flirting With Receptionist Proves Costly For US Executive's Alleged Killer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-cops-zeroed-in-on-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompsons-murder-suspect-luigi-mangione-7212656]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 08:16:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US detectives have arrested a 26-year-old suspect - a former Ivy League student - from Pennsylvania after a nationwide manhunt over UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson's killing in New York.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US detectives have arrested a 26-year-old suspect - a former Ivy League student - from Pennsylvania after a nationwide manhunt over UnitedHealthcare CEO <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/people/brian-thompson-all-about-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-who-was-shot-dead-in-new-york-7175840">Brian Thompson</a>'s killing in New York. Luigi Mangione was found with a "ghost gun" that was capable of firing 9MM rounds. He has been charged with the possession of fake IDs and a gun. Thompson, 50, was shot dead by the gunman last week when he was attending an investors' conference.</p>

<h3><strong>How the suspect was identified</strong></h3>

<p>The cops obtained his image from a youth hostel where he had stayed before the murder. Reports suggest he had lowered his mask to flirt with a receptionist, during which he got clicked.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564">Ex-Ivy League Student, 26, Arrested For UnitedHealthcare CEO's Murder</a></p>

<p>New York mayor Eric Adams said he matched the description of the suspect they have been looking for. He was also found carrying many items that the cops believe are connected to the murder.</p>

<h3><strong>How cops caught Mangione</strong></h3>

<p>The staff at the Altoona McDonald's branch had tipped off the cops about Mangione. He was wearing a mask and a beanie and working on a laptop at that time.</p>

<p>When the officers approached him, he gave them a fake ID.</p>

<p>Mangione, who studied at the Ivy League University of Pennsylvania, had used one of the fake IDs to check in to a hotel in Manhattan in New York before the murder, the police said.</p>

<p>He "became quiet and started to shake" when the officers asked him if he had been to New York recently, they added.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luigi-mangione-man-behind-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-7212585">Who Is Luigi Mangione, Man Behind UnitedHealthCare CEO's Murder</a></p>

<p>Cops say material recovered from Mangione suggested he had "ill will towards corporate America." Reports suggest the suspect had raised the high cost of healthcare in the US in the two-page note, adding that&nbsp;"these parasites had it coming."</p>

<h3><strong>How he fled crime scene</strong></h3>

<p>The suspect approached Thompson from behind, wearing a hooded top and his lower face covered, and fired at him several times, video footage showed last week. Several bystanders were present during the murder and the attack was captured on CCTV.</p>

<p>As the UnitedHealthcare CEO fell on the ground, the suspect fled on foot and then rode a bike to Central Park. From there, he took a bus and disappeared, sparking a nationwide manhunt.</p>

<p>Murder charges would follow against Mangione in New York state, Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro told reporters, adding that people don't kill others in cold blood to resolve policy differences. He must be extradited to New York to face the murder charges.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/iti216d8_nypd_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione studied at the Ivy League University of Pennsylvania. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-rights-day-2024-know-date-history-theme-and-significance-7212592]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Human Rights Day 2024: Know Date, History, Theme And Significance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-rights-day-2024-know-date-history-theme-and-significance-7212592]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:58:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Human Rights Day 2024: The UN  has decided to dedicate the theme of Human Rights Day this year to "Our Rights, Our Future, Right Now".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Human Rights Day 2024:</strong> Human Rights Day is celebrated every year on December 10 to commemorate the adoption of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR) by the United Nations General Assembly (UNGA) in 1948. The day is intended to celebrate and promote rights that protect against abuses, violations and other harms, ensuring everyone can live in dignity and respect -- irrespective of their race, gender, religion, nationality or any other factor. As per the UN, "upholding human rights is not only about addressing present injustices, it's about reshaping unjust societies and empowering marginalised groups".</p>

<h3><strong>Theme for Human Rights Day 2024</strong></h3>

<p>This year's theme for Human Rights Day is: "Our Rights, Our Future, Right Now" which reinforces how human rights affect people everywhere, every day.</p>

<p>"Human rights have a tangible positive impact and offer practical solutions. By embracing the full power of human rights as the path to the future we want, the world can become more peaceful and equal," the UN said announcing the theme.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-says-us-report-on-alleged-human-rights-abuses-reflects-deep-biases-very-poor-understanding-of-india-5520822" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | "Poor Understanding": India Trashes US Report On Alleged Rights Abuse</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>History and significance</strong></h3>

<p>Human rights are protected by international and national laws and treaties globally. The mission to protect human rights around the world has been tasked to a 47-member grouping known as the Human Rights Council.</p>

<p>These UN member-states are empowered to prevent inequality, abuses and discrimination, protect the most vulnerable, and punish the perpetrators of human rights violations.</p>

<h3><strong>Why are human rights necessary?</strong></h3>

<p>Human rights are necessary and their defence even more so to prevent harm befalling any marginalised individual or group. They have a preventative, protective as well as a transformative role to play in civil society.</p>

<h3><strong>India reaffirms its commitment</strong></h3>

<p>On the eve of Human Rights Day, the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) Acting Chairperson, Vijaya Bharathi Sayani said India remained committed to upholding the human rights of every individual.</p>

<p>"This significant day, observed every year on 10th December since 1950, commemorates the adoption of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR) by the United Nations in 1948. For India, this day holds special significance, as Indian representatives made a pivotal contribution to the drafting of this landmark document, which embodies humanity's shared commitment to dignity, justice, and equality," said Mr Sayani.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dacu54cg_human_625x300_10_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Human Rights Day is celebrated every year on December 10.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luigi-mangione-man-behind-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-7212585]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Luigi Mangione, Man Behind UnitedHealthCare CEO's Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luigi-mangione-man-behind-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-7212585]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:52:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione was detained in Altoona, Pennsylvania on Monday after he was found with a gun without a license, a silencer, and fake ID cards.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Luigi Mangione, a 26-year-old former Ivy League student has been <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564" target="_blank">arrested as a suspect</a> in UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson's murder. Mangione was detained in Altoona, Pennsylvania on Monday after he was found with a gun without a license, a silencer, and fake ID cards.</p>

<p>Brian Thompson, 50, was shot in the chest in New York, last week on December 4. He was shot outside the hotel New York Hilton Midtown on West 54th Street. He was in town to attend his company's annual investor conference when he was shot at least twice - once in the back and once in the right calf. He was taken to the hospital but declared dead.</p>

<h3><strong>Here's what we know about Luigi Mangione:</strong></h3>

<ol>
	<li>Luigi Mangione, arrested by the New York Police as a "strong person of interest" is an Ivy League graduate software engineer.</li>
	<li>Mangione comes from a famous Baltimore family. He is the grandson of Nicholas Mangione, a famed Baltimore real-estate developer and Mary C Mangione, a philanthropist, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/us/live-news/brian-thompson-unitedhealthcare-death-investigation-12-9-24/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">reported CNN</a>.</li>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/luigi-mangione/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Mangione's LinkedIn profile</a> suggests he has a bachelor's and master of science engineering from the University of Pennsylvania. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/09/unitedhealthcare-ceo-shooting-suspect-arrested" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The Guardian</a> confirmed it with a university spokesperson and found the information true.</li>
	<li>The social media profile also states that he has been employed at TrueCar for the past four years. However, in a statement, TrueCar, Inc told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/09/unitedhealthcare-ceo-shooting-suspect-arrested" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The Guardian</a> that Mangione has not been with the company since 2023. "While we generally don't comment on personnel matters, we can confirm that Luigi Mangione has not been an employee of our company since 2023," they said.</li>
	<li>Mangione is registered to vote at his family's address in Cockeysville, Maryland, a Baltimore suburb, reported CNN, basis the state's voter registration lookup website.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rbg97kpg_luigi-mangione_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione, a suspect in UnitedHealthcare CEO's murder.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>