<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 17:19:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-chinese-nationals-among-22-killed-in-massive-fire-at-south-korea-battery-factory-5958702]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[18 Chinese Nationals Among 22 Killed In Fire At S Korea Battery Factory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-chinese-nationals-among-22-killed-in-massive-fire-at-south-korea-battery-factory-5958702]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 15:58:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Twenty-two people were killed -- including 18 Chinese nationals -- in a massive fire at a South Korean lithium battery factory, the fire department said Monday, one of the country's worst factory disasters in years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twenty-two people were killed -- including 18 Chinese nationals -- in a massive fire at a South Korean lithium battery factory, the fire department said Monday, one of the country's worst factory disasters in years.</p>

<p>Over 100 people were working in the factory when workers heard a series of explosions from the second floor, where lithium-ion batteries were being inspected and packaged, firefighter Kim Jin-young told media.</p>

<p>In the massive blaze that ensued, twenty-two people were killed, including 20 foreign nationals -- 18 Chinese, one from Laos, and one of unknown nationality, he said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?? At least 21 people have died in a fire at a lithium battery plant in South Korea. <a href="https://t.co/kzQKnhbOYf">pic.twitter.com/kzQKnhbOYf</a></p>
— Lord Bebo (@MyLordBebo) <a href="https://twitter.com/MyLordBebo/status/1805187422428315651?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Most of the bodies are badly burned so it will take some time to identify each one," he added.</p>

<p>Firefighters are still searching for one more person who remains unaccounted for, he said, adding that they had managed to contain the largest blaze at the plant and get inside.</p>

<p>Firefighters were "doing cooling operations to prevent the fire from expanding to nearby factories," Kim said.</p>

<p>Dozens of fire trucks were lined up outside the factory, an AFP reporter saw, with rescue workers carrying bodies, covered by blue blankets, out of the building on stretchers.</p>

<p>Images shared by Yonhap after the fire broke out showed huge plumes of billowing grey smoke rising into the sky above the factory, with orange flames inside the building.</p>

<p>The vast factory had an estimated 35,000 battery cells on the second floor in storage, with more batteries stored in other areas.</p>

<p>Lithium batteries burn hot and fast, and are difficult to control with conventional fire extinguishing methods.</p>

<p>"Due to fears of additional explosions, it was difficult to enter," Kim said, describing the tricky rescue operation.</p>

<p>"As it is a lithium battery manufacturer, we (had) determined that spraying water will not extinguish the fire, so we (used) dry sand," he added.</p>

<p>The lithium battery plant is owned by Aricell, a South Korean primary battery manufacturer. It is located in Hwaseong city, just south of the capital Seoul.</p>

<p>Shares of Aricell's parent company, S-connect, plunged by over 20 percent on the Seoul exchange by close Monday. S-connect owns 96 percent of Aricell.</p>

<p>Lithium batteries are used in everything from laptops to electric vehicles -- but can be highly explosive, with airlines, for example, imposing strict regulations on checking devices containing them.</p>

<p><strong>'Mobilise all personnel'</strong></p>

<p>South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol issued emergency instructions to authorities, telling them to "mobilise all available personnel and equipment to focus on searching for and rescuing people," his office said.</p>

<p>The president also warned authorities that they should "ensure the safety of firefighters considering the rapid spread of fire".</p>

<p>Authorities in Hwaseong sent out a series of alerts to residents warning them to stay inside.</p>

<p>"There is a lot of smoke due to factory fires. Please pay attention to safety, such as refraining from going out," one alert sent by text message said.</p>

<p>"Factory fire. Please detour to surrounding roads and nearby citizens please close windows," another one read.</p>

<p>South Korea is a major producer of batteries, including those used in electric vehicles.</p>

<p>Its battery makers supply EV makers around the world, including Tesla.</p>

<p>The fire is one of South Korea's worst factory disasters in years.</p>

<p>Previously, it's worst chemical plant accident was in 1989 at the Lucky Chemical factory in Yeosu, Southern Jeolla Province, which resulted in 16 deaths and 17 injuries.</p>

<p>A fire at a warehouse in Icheon in 2020 killed 38 people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nd4q6n9_south-korea-factory-fire-afp_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Twenty foreigners are among the dead", says firefighter Kim Jin-young.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-how-ukraines-special-branch-drone-downed-russian-one-5958674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: How Ukraine's 'Special Branch' Drone Downed Russian One]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-how-ukraines-special-branch-drone-downed-russian-one-5958674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 15:51:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The video has received more than 32,000 views and several users have commented on it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video showing a Ukrainian drone destroying a Russian drone using a stick has gone viral on social media platform X. Posted by the user Special Kherson Cat, it shows the unmanned aerial vehicle hovering a few metres above the ground and another one - claimed to be Russian - moving up. A stick is seen hanging from Ukraine's Mavic drone, which is at a higher altitude. As the Russian drone comes closer, the Ukrainian military piece swings the stick sending the Russian drone crashing to the ground.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Ukrainian Mavic drone downs Russian Mavic using a stick. <a href="https://t.co/JLcbN89GMF">https://t.co/JLcbN89GMF</a> <a href="https://t.co/Nc58muFWRX">pic.twitter.com/Nc58muFWRX</a></p>
— Special Kherson Cat ??? (@bayraktar_1love) <a href="https://twitter.com/bayraktar_1love/status/1805158287693808090?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The video has received more than 32,000 views and several users have commented on it.</p>

<p>"Sustainable warfare, what more could you wish for," commented one user. "This is not exactly what was referred to as fighting with sticks and stones, but here we are," said another.</p>

<p>Others mocked the Ukrainian military for using such primitive weapons to fight a modern warfare.</p>

<p>Drones have become a key piece of technology for both sides in the ongoing Russia-Ukraine war. According to <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/ukraine-focuses-drone-warfare-military-creates-new-unmanned/story?id=111046806"><em>ABC News</em></a>, Ukraine launched its Unmanned Systems Forces, a new branch of its military focused on drone warfare, in April this year.</p>

<p>Colonel Vadym Sukharevskyi was announced as the new branch's commander.</p>

<p>The DJI Mavic drones were initially used for reconnaissance and dropping grenades. But gradually, they switched to first-person view drones to attack enemy personnel and vehicles.</p>

<p>Shortly after announcing the new defence department, the Ukraine's Ministry of Defence</p>

<p>In the last two years, Ukraine has developed a series of different kinds of aerial, land and water drones to help to fight against the Russians when it doesn't have enough heavy weapons, artillery and jets.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/veonrm3_ukraine-drone-stick_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Ukrainian drone readying the stick to attack the Russian military vehicle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-afterlife-industry-rapidly-evolving-heres-how-to-navigate-its-risks-5958423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Digital Afterlife Industry Rapidly Evolving, Know How To Navigate Its Risks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-afterlife-industry-rapidly-evolving-heres-how-to-navigate-its-risks-5958423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 15:10:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The digital afterlife industry is rapidly evolving. Several companies promise to create virtual reconstructions of deceased individuals based on their digital footprints.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine a future where your phone pings with a message that your dead father's “digital immortal” bot is ready. This promise of chatting with a virtual version of your loved one – perhaps through a virtual reality (VR) headset – is like stepping into a sci-fi movie, both thrilling and a bit eerie.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>As you interact with this digital dad, you find yourself on an emotional rollercoaster. You uncover secrets and stories you never knew, changing how you remember the real person.</p>

<p>This is not a distant, hypothetical scenario. The <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2024/05/240508201408.htm">digital afterlife industry</a> is rapidly evolving. Several companies promise to create virtual reconstructions of deceased individuals based on their digital footprints.</p>

<p>From artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots and virtual avatars to holograms, this technology offers a strange blend of comfort and disruption. It may pull us into deeply personal experiences that blur the lines between past and present, memory and reality.</p>

<p>As the digital afterlife industry grows, it raises significant <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41562-018-0335-2">ethical</a> and <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/mind-brain-and-value/202009/the-psychology-the-digital-afterlife">emotional challenges</a>. These include concerns about consent, privacy and the psychological impact on the living.</p>

<h2>What is the digital afterlife industry?</h2>

<p>VR and AI technologies are making virtual reconstructions of our loved ones possible. Companies in this niche industry use data from social media posts, emails, text messages and voice recordings to create digital personas that can interact with the living.</p>

<p>Although still niche, the number of players in the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/digital-afterlife">digital afterlife industry</a> is <a href="https://observer.com/2024/05/generative-ai-griefbot-privacy-issue/">growing</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.hereafter.ai/">HereAfter</a> allows users to record stories and messages during their lifetime, which can then be accessed by loved ones posthumously. <a href="https://www.mywishes.co.uk/">MyWishes</a> offers the ability to send pre-scheduled messages after death, maintaining a presence in the lives of the living.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.hansonrobotics.com/">Hanson Robotics</a> has created robotic busts that interact with people using the memories and personality traits of the deceased. <a href="https://projectdecember.net/">Project December</a> grants users access to so-called “deep AI” to engage in text-based conversations with those who have passed away.</p>

<p>Generative AI also plays a crucial role in the digital afterlife industry. These technologies enable the creation of highly realistic and interactive digital personas. But the high level of realism may blur the line between reality and simulation. This may enhance the user experience, but may also cause emotional and psychological distress.</p>

<figure class="align-center zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="A screenshot of a website advertising, in quotes, Your stories and voice forever." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=380&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=380&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=380&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=478&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=478&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/600763/original/file-20240614-17-vuqzl1.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=478&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">HereAfter is one of several apps in the niche digital afterlife industry.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.hereafter.ai/">HereAfter</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2>A technology ripe for misuse</h2>

<p>Digital afterlife technologies may aid the <a href="https://www.insights.uca.org.au/can-digital-afterlife-technology-help-us-grieve/">grieving process</a> by offering continuity and connection with the deceased. Hearing a loved one's voice or seeing their likeness may provide comfort and help process the loss.</p>

<p>For some of us, these digital immortals could be therapeutic tools. They may help us to preserve positive memories and feel close to loved ones even after they have passed away.</p>

<p>But for others, the emotional impact may be profoundly negative, exacerbating grief rather than alleviating it. AI recreations of loved ones have the potential to cause psychological harm if the bereaved ends up having unwanted interactions with them. It's essentially being subjected to a “<a href="https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/news/call-for-safeguards-to-prevent-unwanted-hauntings-by-ai-chatbots-of-dead-loved-ones">digital haunting</a>”.</p>

<p>Other <a href="https://uni-tuebingen.de/en/university/news-and-publications/university-of-tuebingen-magazine-attempto/digital-afterlife/">major issues</a> and <a href="https://www.devx.com/news/ethical-dilemmas-surface-with-digital-afterlife-technology/">ethical concerns</a> surrounding this tech include consent, autonomy and privacy.</p>

<p>For example, the deceased may not have agreed to their data being used for a “digital afterlife”.</p>

<p>There's also the risk of misuse and data manipulation. Companies could exploit digital immortals for commercial gain, using them to advertise products or services. Digital personas could be altered to convey messages or behaviours the deceased would never have endorsed.</p>

<h2>We need regulation</h2>

<p>To address concerns around this quickly emerging industry, we need to update our legal frameworks. We need to address issues such as digital estate planning, who inherits the digital personas of the deceased, and digital memory ownership.</p>

<p>The European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-4-gdpr/">recognises</a> post-mortem <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-17-gdpr/">privacy rights</a>, but <a href="https://verfassungsblog.de/data-after-life/">faces challenges in enforcement</a>.</p>

<p>Social media platforms control deceased users' data access, often against heirs' wishes, with clauses like “<a href="https://verfassungsblog.de/data-after-life/">no right of survivorship</a>” complicating matters. Limited platform practices hinder the GDPR's effectiveness. Comprehensive protection demands reevaluating contractual rules, aligning with human rights.</p>

<p>The digital afterlife industry offers comfort and memory preservation, but raises ethical and emotional concerns. Implementing thoughtful regulations and ethical guidelines can honour both the living and the dead, to ensure digital immortality enhances our humanity.</p>

<h2>What can we do?</h2>

<p>Researchers have recommended several <a href="https://ora.ox.ac.uk/objects/uuid:c059841d-a702-4218-8c1b-39ff49dc6c65/files/mea9feef37e1943dd8446a4013f81d169">ethical guidelines</a> and <a href="https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202403/1308620.shtml">regulations</a>. Some recommendations include:</p>

<ul>
	<li>obtaining informed and documented consent before creating digital personas from people before they die</li>
	<li>age restrictions to protect vulnerable groups</li>
	<li>clear disclaimers to ensure transparency</li>
	<li>and strong data privacy and security measures.</li>
</ul>

<p>Drawing from ethical frameworks in archaeology, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41562-018-0335-2">a 2018 study</a> has suggested treating digital remains as integral to personhood, proposing regulations to ensure dignity, especially in re-creation services.</p>

<p>Dialogue between policymakers, industry and academics is crucial for developing ethical and regulatory solutions. Providers should also offer ways for users to respectfully terminate their interactions with digital personas.</p>

<p>Through careful, responsible development, we can create a future where digital afterlife technologies meaningfully and respectfully honour our loved ones.</p>

<p>As we navigate this brave new world, it is crucial to balance the benefits of staying connected with our loved ones against the potential risks and ethical dilemmas.</p>

<p>By doing so, we can make sure the digital afterlife industry develops in a way that respects the memory of the deceased and supports the emotional wellbeing of the living.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/231829/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(Author&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/arif-perdana-1294046">Arif Perdana</a>, Associate Professor Digital Strategy and Data Science, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/monash-university-1065">Monash University</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/an-eerie-digital-afterlife-is-no-longer-science-fiction-so-how-do-we-navigate-the-risks-231829">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3akrnrp_phone-generic_625x300_24_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/parasites-defaced-clothing-found-in-north-korea-trash-balloons-claims-south-korea-5958298]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Parasites, Defaced Clothing Found In N Korea Trash Balloons, Claims S Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/parasites-defaced-clothing-found-in-north-korea-trash-balloons-claims-south-korea-5958298]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:55:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Parasites from human faeces and defaced Western clothing were found in the bags of garbage carried by North Korean balloons into the South, Seoul said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Parasites from human faeces and defaced Western clothing were found in the bags of garbage carried by North Korean balloons into the South, Seoul said Monday.</p>

<p>Pyongyang has sent more than a thousand trash-carrying balloons into the South in recent weeks, in retaliation for leaflets sent northwards by activists opposed to North Korean leader Kim Jong Un.</p>

<p>An analysis of the contents of some 70 of the balloons found that they contained soil in which "numerous parasites, such as roundworms, whipworms and threadworms" were detected, South Korea's Ministry of Unification said in a statement.</p>

<p>This is likely because human faeces were used in the soil instead of chemical fertilizers, it added.</p>

<p>It said there was "no risk of land pollution (or) infectious diseases" from the balloons, as the volume of soil sent was relatively low.</p>

<p>The garbage sent by North Korea also revealed the country's woeful economic state, the ministry claimed, pointing to tattered children's clothes and other garments worn to the point of disintegration as evidence.</p>

<p>In addition, it said some clothes from the balloons were previously donated by a South Korean company during an aid drive and were deliberately defaced -- including being slashed with knives.</p>

<p>This appeared to be North Korea "expressing extreme hostility toward the leaflet campaigns and to highlight the adversarial stance against South Korea", a ministry official said.</p>

<p>The two Koreas have been locked in a tit-for-tat "balloon war", with an activist in the South confirming last week that he had floated more balloons carrying propaganda leaflets towards the North.</p>

<p>Immediately after, Kim Yo Jong, leader Kim Jong Un's powerful sister, warned that North Korea is likely to retaliate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nvvcrae_trash-balloons-by-north-korea-afp_625x300_03_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two Koreas have been locked in a tit-for-tat "balloon war"(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-woman-sues-company-that-paid-her-to-do-nothing-for-20-years-5958238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Woman Sues Company That Paid Her To Do Nothing For 20 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-woman-sues-company-that-paid-her-to-do-nothing-for-20-years-5958238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:47:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ms Wassenhove has accused the company of intentionally barring her from working after she tried to get transferred to a different part of the same firm because of her disability.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A French woman has sued her former employer for assigning her no work despite paying her full salary for 20 years. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.local12.com/news/offbeat/lawsuit-business-work-a-woman-is-suing-her-company-for-paying-her-without-making-her-france-international-capital-labor-job-occupation-technology-telecommunications-finance-communications">Laurence Van Wassenhove</a> has filed a lawsuit against Orange, a large telecommunications company,&nbsp; accusing it of intentionally barring her from working after she tried to get transferred to a different part of the same firm because of her disability.</p>

<p>In 1993, Ms Wassenhove reportedly joined the telecommunication company as a secretary and human resources representative, which accommodated her partial paralysis and epilepsy. In 2002, she tried to get a transfer within the company and was approved.<br />
<br />
Ms Wassenhove has alleged that the firm stopped assigning her tasks at the time due to her inadequate performance in the new position. However, despite this, Ms Wassenhove's employer did not stop paying her salary.</p>

<p>A report by <a href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/28564314/i-was-ordered-to-do-no-work-im-suing/">The Sun </a>claimed that now Ms Wassenhove finds her situation “very hard to bear.”</p>

<p>The report claimed that initially, Orange employed her as a civil servant. But due to her condition, Ms Wassenhove was offered a secretary position to accommodate her health needs.</p>

<p>Ms Wassenhove is a mother of two children, of whom one is autistic. In a conversation with The Sun, she claimed that despite being paid her salary, it did not save her from facing eviction notices and struggling to make ends meet.</p>

<p>The company conducted an occupational medicine report, confirming that the position was not suitable for Ms Wassenhove, added the report.</p>

<p>After this, the firm put Ms Wassenhove on standby. And before eventually offering her retirement due to her disability, the company put her on sick leave.</p>

<p>However, the company continued to pay her full salary while Ms Wassenhove was not assigned any work to do.</p>

<p>Calling herself "an outcast secretary", Ms Wassenhive claimed that her firm did this to push her to quit her job. In 2015, she filed a complaint to the government and High Authority for the Fight against Discrimination but not much changed.</p>

<p>The report quoted her as saying, “Being paid, at home, not working is not a privilege. It's very hard to bear.”</p>

<p>The firm, however, claimed it had done everything to ensure she worked in the best conditions possible, according to the report.</p>

<p>They also added that "a return to work in an adapted position" was also planned but never happened as Ms Wassenhove reportedly was regularly on sick leave.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/0fm9ivhg_office-generic_625x300_29_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The firm, however, claimed it had done everything to ensure she worked in the best conditions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tamayo-perry-pirates-of-the-caribbean-actor-killed-in-shark-attack-5958159]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tamayo Perry, 'Pirates Of The Caribbean' Actor, Killed In Shark Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tamayo-perry-pirates-of-the-caribbean-actor-killed-in-shark-attack-5958159]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:35:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 49-year-old had also appeared in Charlie's Angels: Full Throttle and Blue Crush, as per the Sky News report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tamayo Perry, who appeared in the <em>Pirates of the Caribbean</em> franchise, has died after being attacked by a shark. According to <em>Sky News</em>, Mr Perry, an Ocean Safety lifeguard and surfing instructor, was attacked by a shark off Oahu in Hawaii. The attack took place near Goat Island on Sunday and Mr Perry was spotted by a man who alerted the emergency services. When the officials arrived at the scene, they brought Mr Perry to shore by jet ski. But the actor was pronounced dead on the beach.</p>

<p>The 49-year-old had also appeared in <em>Charlie's Angels: Full Throttle</em> and <em>Blue Crush</em>, as per the <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/pirates-of-the-caribbean-actor-tamayo-perry-dies-after-being-attacked-by-shark-while-surfing-in-hawaii-13157896"><em>Sky News</em> report</a>. He also had a role in <em>Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides</em>, the fourth film in the franchise.</p>

<p>Released in 2011, it also featured Penelope Cruz and Geoffrey Rush.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd1117lwlxyo">The <em>BBC</em></a> quoted acting Honolulu Ocean Safety chief Kurt Lager as saying that Mr Perry was "a lifeguard loved by all". He added that Me Perry was well known on Oahu's North Shore as well as around the world.</p>

<p>"Tamayo's personality was infectious, and as much as people loved him, he loved everyone else more. Our condolences go out to Tamayo's family," said Mr Lager.</p>

<p>Mayor Rick Blangiardi echoed similar sentiments, calling Perry's death "a tragic loss", as per the <em>BBC</em> report.</p>

<p>"Tamayo was a legendary waterman and highly respected, he grew up right over here, and just a great member of our ocean safety team," the Mayor further said.</p>

<p>Mr Perry, who worked as a lifeguard on the North Shore, began his career with the Ocean Safety department in July 2016, the <em>Sky News</em> report said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/29ccuif_tamayo-perry-instagram_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tamayo Perry worked as a lifeguard on the North Shore.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-issues-new-guidelines-to-punish-taiwan-separatists-5958107]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Issues New Guidelines To Punish Taiwan "Separatists"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-issues-new-guidelines-to-punish-taiwan-separatists-5958107]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:27:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democracy is not a crime and autocracy is the real "evil", Taiwan President Lai Ching-te said on Monday after China threatened to impose the death penalty in extreme cases for "diehard" Taiwan independence separatists.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democracy is not a crime and autocracy is the real "evil", Taiwan President Lai Ching-te said on Monday after China threatened to impose the death penalty in extreme cases for "diehard" Taiwan independence separatists.</p>

<p>China, which views Taiwan as its own territory, has made no secret of its dislike of Lai, who took office last month, saying he is a "separatist", and staged war games shortly after his inauguration.</p>

<p>On Friday, China ramped up its pressure on Taiwan by issuing new legal guidelines to punish those it says support the island's formal independence, though Chinese courts have no jurisdiction on the democratically governed island.</p>

<p>Asked about China's move at a news conference at the presidential office in Taipei, Lai first reiterated his sympathy for recent flooding in southern China before responding.</p>

<p>"I want to stress: democracy is not a crime; it's autocracy that is the real evil. China has absolutely no right to sanction Taiwan's people just because of the positions they hold. What's more, China has no right to go after Taiwan people's rights across borders," he said.</p>

<p>According to China, anyone who does not uphold "reunification" is therefore a Taiwan independence supporter, Lai added.</p>

<p>"I also want to call on China to face up to the existence of the Republic of China and have exchanges and dialogue with Taiwan's democratically elected, legitimate government," he said, using Taiwan's formal name. "If this is not done, relations between Taiwan and China will only become more and more estranged."</p>

<p>Taiwan said that since Thursday, there has been a sharp increase in Chinese military flights as Beijing carried out a "joint combat readiness patrol" near the island.</p>

<p>Between Thursday and Sunday, Taiwan says it detected 115 Chinese military aircraft operating nearby, getting as close at 31 nautical miles (57 km) from the southern tip of the island.</p>

<p>Taiwan has said that for the past four years, China has carried out regular military activity around the island as part of a "grey zone" pressure campaign.</p>

<p>Taiwan's annual Han Kuang war games next month will aim to mimic actual combat as closely as possible given a rapidly rising "enemy threat" from China, a senior official said.</p>

<p>Lai rejects Beijing's sovereignty claims and says only Taiwan's people can decide their future. He has repeatedly offered talks with China but has been rebuffed.</p>

<p>China says any move by Taiwan to declare formal independence would be grounds to attack the island.</p>

<p>The government in Taipei says Taiwan is already an independent country, the Republic of China, and that it does not plan to change that. The Republican government fled to Taiwan in 1949 after losing a civil war with Mao Zedong's Communists.</p>

<p>Lai also faces domestic challenges, as his Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) lost its majority in parliament in the same election in January that brought him to power.</p>

<p>Speaking at the same news conference, Lai said he would ask the constitutional court to stay a package of contested parliament reforms the opposition has passed and consider whether they comply with the constitution.</p>

<p>The opposition says the reforms, which among other things criminalise contempt of parliament by government officials, are needed to bring more accountability, but the DPP says they were forced through without proper discussion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/vvnhne_taiwans-president-lai-chingte-reuters_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taiwan's President Lai Ching-te says only Taiwan's people can decide their future (file). .]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swedens-youth-homes-a-hub-for-gang-recruitment-amid-rising-gun-violence-5958031]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sweden's Youth Homes: A Hub for Gang Recruitment Amid Rising Gun Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swedens-youth-homes-a-hub-for-gang-recruitment-amid-rising-gun-violence-5958031]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:14:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The killer was only 14 and had lived in youth homes as a ward of the authorities since he was eight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The killer was only 14 and had lived in youth homes as a ward of the authorities since he was eight.</p>

<p>A year ago, a gang helped the boy escape, put him up in a hotel, and gave him cannabis, food, and new clothes. Six days later, gang members told him it was time to repay them for their kindness. They had a job for him.</p>

<p>Together with another youth, the boy, who as a juvenile cannot be identified, shot dead a 33-year-old Hells Angels biker. He was convicted by a court that described the case as a gangland contract killing.</p>

<p>As he was too young to be sentenced, he was handed back to social services and sent to another youth home.</p>

<p>Sweden has long prided itself on one of the world's most generous social safety nets, with a state that looks after vulnerable people at all stages of life.</p>

<p>But these days it also has another distinction: by far the highest per capita rate of gun violence in the EU. Last year 55 people were shot dead in 363 separate shootings in a country of just 10 million people. By comparison, there were just six fatal shootings in the three other Nordic countries - Norway, Finland, and Denmark - combined.</p>

<p>In an increasing number of cases, courts have found the epidemic of violence emerging from Sweden's archipelago of youth homes, built to serve the dual purpose of looking after children in state care and punishing youth offenders.</p>

<p>According to accounts for this story from eight sources including a former gang member, several youth home workers, prosecutors and criminologists, the homes have turned into recruiting grounds for gangs, who use them to enlist killers too young to be jailed.</p>

<h3><strong>TROUBLED TEEN TO 'CAREER CRIMINAL'</strong></h3>

<p>Yayha, now 23, was first sent to a youth home at 16, finding himself bunking with seven other boys in a dormitory wing in Gothenburg, the gritty port city on Sweden's west coast that houses the biggest harbour in Scandinavia.</p>

<p>His father had died a couple of years earlier. He had dropped out of school and was convicted of assault and theft, beating up other kids, and stealing their phones and clothes.</p>

<p>During his year in the home, members of one of Gothenburg's criminal gangs became his new family, he told Reuters in a coffee shop by the harbour in the city where he now works as a carpenter after escaping the gang life.</p>

<p>"I was a troubled teen when I entered and came out a career criminal. I went from fighting and stealing from other kids to selling drugs by the kilo," said Yayha, who asked that his surname not be used to prevent his former gang from finding him.</p>

<p>"You wanted the respect, the clothes, the rings, the money but also friendship. They were the people you hung out with anyway. Later it became more serious and you had to do things that you really didn't want to, but that is the way it works."</p>

<p>The wave of violence has come to overshadow all else in Swedish politics, driving the rise of a rightwing coalition with the support of the far right, which came to power in 2022, ending the latest eight-year period of rule by the Social Democrats, Sweden's dominant political party since the 1930s.</p>

<p>The new government has promised to tackle crime. So far it has further restricted Sweden's previously generous immigration policies, introduced harsher sentences for gun crimes, and given police increased surveillance powers. Even the military has been called on to help out.</p>

<p>"It is obvious that our system wasn't built for this type of criminality," Justice Minister Gunnar Strommer told Reuters.</p>

<p>He said the government was working on a revamp of the entire youth criminality prevention system, including giving more powers to social services. New youth prisons would house the most hardened criminals, keeping them separate from youth homes.</p>

<p>"I think it is clear that in reality, the state-run homes have functioned as a kind of recruitment base from the criminal networks," Strommer said. "It's a monumental failure."</p>

<h3><strong>'LINKEDIN FOR YOUNG CRIMINALS'</strong></h3>

<p>Sweden's youth homes have varying degrees of security, with around 700 of the most troubled youths housed in 21 homes run by a state body, the National Board of Institutional Care (SiS).</p>

<p>Children with social problems can find themselves sleeping in beds next to those who have committed serious crimes. Most children stay for less than a year but some can be held for up to four years.</p>

<p>The homes are often fenced off, with schools and parks on the premises. While the youths are not allowed to leave without permission, security is often lax.</p>

<p>Residents have access to phones and tablets making it possible for gang members to contact them from outside. In one case now being tried, prosecutors have charged a boy of 15 with planning and ordering three murders in Stockholm from inside a youth home.</p>

<p>Birgitta Dahlberg, head of youth care at the SiS, told Reuters it was unfair to blame the homes for their inability to deal with serious violent offenders, which they were not designed to handle.</p>

<p>"When it comes to serious criminality, it is fair to say that the legislation has not given us the right conditions," she said, noting that until regulations were changed just weeks ago staff did not even have sufficient authority to take away residents' mobile phones.</p>

<p>Children as young as 12 are often gang members already by the time they arrive, said Alexander, who works at the Gothenburg home where Yahya stayed. He declined to give his surname as he was not authorised to speak publicly.</p>

<p>"Out of our 40 boys, around half are gang affiliated when they come here," he told Reuters.</p>

<p>"If you put two new kids in a wing where six out of eight inmates are with the Foxtrot gang, it doesn't take a genius to figure out what could happen," he said, referring to one of the largest gangs believed to have hundreds of members.</p>

<p>Two other youth home workers, speaking on condition of anonymity, gave similar accounts of rampant gang membership among their charges.</p>

<p>In theory, the youth homes aim to rehabilitate young offenders to prevent them from becoming adult criminals. But according to a report released weeks ago by the Swedish National Audit Office which supervises the government, nine out of ten gang-affiliated youngsters at youth homes go on to relapse into crime, and almost eight out of ten eventually end up in prison.</p>

<p>The youth homes seem to do more harm than good, said Stockholm prosecutor Lisa dos Santos, who has handled numerous cases of youth gang crimes.</p>

<p>"One police officer described them as LinkedIn for young criminals," she said. "You wonder what effect they have had in spreading gang crime when boys from different parts of the country are put together."</p>

<p>While Swedish law allows criminal prosecution of people as young as 15, those under 18 are very rarely sent to prison even for serious crimes. Dos Santos said gangs are exploiting this, deliberately recruiting children to commit acts that would lead to a long jail sentence for an adult.</p>

<p>Sweden has about 14,000 active gang criminals and an additional 48,000 people loosely affiliated with gangs, according to a police report last year.</p>

<p>Other European countries such as the Netherlands, France, and Belgium are also struggling with violent gangs, but Sweden has outpaced them all in gun violence, by wide margins.</p>

<p>In 2022, there were 73 youths in Sweden aged 15-20 suspected of murder or attempted murder with firearms, up from just 10 a decade earlier, according to the Crime Prevention Board, a government agency.</p>

<p>According to EU statistics agency Eurostat, 25 people aged 15-24 were killed by gun violence in Sweden in 2021, second in the EU only to France, which had 40 such deaths across a population six times the size of Sweden's.</p>

<p>Nils Duquet, director of the Flemish Peace Institute, a leading European gun violence think tank, said the reliance of Sweden's gangs on young recruits to commit violent crimes had created a different culture around guns than elsewhere in Europe.</p>

<p>Elsewhere, criminal gangs tend to reserve access to guns for older and more senior members, he said. In Sweden, the youngest are expected to pull the trigger.</p>

<p>"Because there are so many young criminals with access to guns, that makes it so violent," Duquet said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/m3lfsu7o_gun-violence-reuters_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sweden has by far the highest per capita rate of gun violence in the EU.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/critics-slam-uk-labour-partys-shift-under-starmer-sold-labours-soul-5957766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Sold Labour's Soul": Critics Slam UK Labour Party's Shift Under Starmer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/critics-slam-uk-labour-partys-shift-under-starmer-sold-labours-soul-5957766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 13:36:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sabia Akram has spent most of her life campaigning for Britain's opposition Labour Party but she will not celebrate if it wins the July 4 election, having quit over leader Keir Starmer's handling of issues around the war in Gaza and race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sabia Akram has spent most of her life campaigning for Britain's opposition Labour Party but she will not celebrate if it wins the July 4 election, having quit over leader Keir Starmer's handling of issues around the war in Gaza and race.</p>

<p>The Labour Party holds a commanding lead in opinion polls after Starmer steered it back to the centre ground following a trouncing at the 2019 election under his predecessor, veteran socialist Jeremy Corbyn.</p>

<p>But he has lost the support of some Black and Asian voters who traditionally vote Labour over his support for Israel and for only gradually shifting the party's position towards supporting a ceasefire in Gaza.</p>

<p>Labour's treatment of Diane Abbott, Britain's first Black woman lawmaker, and the blocking of a Muslim candidate has also alienated some voters, according to interviews with voters, a pollster, political activists and academics.</p>

<p>Starmer sought to move the party back to the centre ground, promoting candidates for the election who would vote as a disciplined bloc if they win, and that shift has alienated some ethnic minorities who backed Corbyn and his left-wing vision.</p>

<p>Sofia Collignon, associate professor at Queen Mary University, said while the party revamp was working nationally, it had caused strains among members and voters and Starmer's challenge was to hold all the different strands together.</p>

<p>Critics like Akram say he has sold Labour's "soul in order to seek the keys to No 10", the residence of British prime ministers.</p>

<p>"It's no longer defined by its values and its core principles," she said, adding that the party had become a home for whoever wanted to join, citing a right-wing lawmaker who defected from the ruling Conservatives.</p>

<p>A long-running Ipsos poll of ethnic minority voting intentions found that Starmer, in the second half of 2023, had the lowest net satisfaction rating of any Labour opposition leader since the series began in 1996.</p>

<p>With its 20-point lead in opinion polls, concerns among ethnic minorities may not affect the election result, Keiran Pedley at Ipsos said, but added: "If these trends are lasting - and we don't know if they will - then it's possible it could become more politically significant."</p>

<p>Akram, 43, resigned as a Labour councillor in Slough, west of London, in early June along with six others, citing what she saw as censorship around Gaza which meant she could not criticise Israel. She also cited the treatment of Faiza Shaheen, who was blocked from standing as a Labour candidate in a northeast London seat.</p>

<p>Shaheen said she had been told it was over historic tweets she liked which criticised Israeli supporters. She apologised but told the BBC she also thought it was because she was left-wing. She is standing as an independent.</p>

<p>The Labour Party did not respond to a Reuters request for comment about the allegations.</p>

<p>Last month Starmer, speaking after his party won a parliament seat in northern England and control of several councils across England, acknowledged Gaza had had an impact on Labour support in some areas.</p>

<h3><strong>BALANCING ACT</strong></h3>

<p>Akram also criticised the treatment of Abbott, a close Corbyn ally, who was suspended from Labour for over a year after she said Jewish, Irish and Traveller people did not face racism all their lives.</p>

<p>Media reports initially said she would be blocked from running in the election, sparking anger from some voters, before the party said she was welcome to stand as its candidate again.</p>

<p>Ngozi Fulani, founder and CEO of domestic abuse charity Sistah Space which is based in Abbott's neighbourhood of Hackney, said many Black people had wanted her to run as an independent.</p>

<p>"Most Black people have always voted Labour, that's my experience," she told Reuters. "(But) the Labour Party have been in decline ... we don't feel an association," she said, adding that Starmer's Labour didn't "take too much interest in matters that affect us specifically".</p>

<p>Hackney, a northeast London neighbourhood where 21% of the population is Black, is among the capital's most deprived areas, with more than one in three households living below the poverty line after housing costs are accounted for.</p>

<p>Of the 18 people Reuters interviewed there who have supported Abbott for nearly four decades, 14 said they thought she had been treated badly and that they would vote for her in the upcoming election following her reinstatement.</p>

<p>Starmer, the country's former chief prosecutor, became Labour leader in April 2020, vowing reform after the equalities watchdog said the party had discriminated against Jews.</p>

<p>A 2022 independent investigation also found structural racism, sexism and factionalism in the party, and a "hierarchy of racism" where tackling antisemitism was the priority.</p>

<p>Labour has long been the political home of many ethnic minority voters and according to British Future, a think tank, one in five of its election candidates are from an ethnic minority background. The last census in 2021 said 18% of the population in England and Wales were ethnic minorities.</p>

<p>However, other parties - including Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's Conservatives - have more visible representation in government and party structures than Labour, which might incline voters towards them more in future.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hso7kjv_change-campaign_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-bodies-found-as-fire-breaks-out-in-south-korea-battery-factory-report-5957740]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[20 Bodies Found As Fire Breaks Out In S Korea Battery Factory: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-bodies-found-as-fire-breaks-out-in-south-korea-battery-factory-report-5957740]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 13:31:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Around 20 bodies have been found at a South Korean lithium battery factory after a massive blaze on Monday, the Yonhap news agency said, with firefighters saying they were still searching the building.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Around 20 bodies have been found at a South Korean lithium battery factory after a massive blaze on Monday, the Yonhap news agency said, with firefighters saying they were still searching the building.</p>

<p>Over 100 people were working in the factory when workers heard a series of explosions from the second floor, where lithium-ion batteries are inspected and packaged, firefighter Kim Jin-young told media.</p>

<p>Some 78 people were confirmed safe but many more were still missing, with Yonhap saying that "about 20 bodies (were) found" at the site, after rescue workers finally managed to get inside.</p>

<p>Kim told media that they had managed to put out the largest fire at the factory and were pulling bodies out of the charred building.</p>

<p>"A rescue team has gone inside and is carrying out search and rescue operations," he said.</p>

<p>Images shared by Yonhap after the fire broke out showed huge plumes of billowing grey smoke rising into the sky above the factory, with orange flames inside the building. Dozens of fire engines were seen outside.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The vast factory had an estimated 35,000 battery cells on the second floor in storage, with more batteries stored in other areas.</p>

<p>Lithium batteries burn hot and fast, and are difficult to control with conventional fire extinguishing methods.</p>

<p>"Due to fears of additional explosions, it was difficult to enter," Kim said.</p>

<p>"As it is a lithium battery manufacturer, we determined that spraying water will not extinguish the fire, so we are currently using dry sand," he added.</p>

<p>The lithium battery plant is owned by Aricell, a South Korean primary battery manufacturer. It is located in Hwaseong city, just south of the capital Seoul.</p>

<p>Lithium batteries are used in everything from laptops to electric vehicles -- but can be highly explosive, with airlines, for example, imposing strict regulations on checking devices containing them.</p>

<h3><strong>'Mobilise all personnel'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol issued emergency instructions to authorities, telling them to "mobilise all available personnel and equipment to focus on searching for and rescuing people," his office said.</p>

<p>The president also warned authorities that they should "ensure the safety of firefighters considering the rapid spread of fire".</p>

<p>Firefighting and rescue efforts were ongoing, and the cause of the fire was unknown.</p>

<p>Authorities in Hwaseong sent out a series of alerts to residents warning them to stay inside.</p>

<p>"There is a lot of smoke due to factory fires. Please pay attention to safety, such as refraining from going out," one alert sent by text message said.</p>

<p>"Factory fire. Please detour to surrounding roads and nearby citizens please close windows," another one read.</p>

<p>South Korea is a major producer of batteries, including those used in electric vehicles.</p>

<p>Its battery makers supply EV makers around the world, including Tesla.</p>

<p>South Korea is also one of the world's largest producers of high-end semiconductors, and the government has invested heavily in key technologies including displays and batteries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/72hqlv0g_fire-accident-at-lithium-battery-factory-reuters_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 100 people were working in the factory when workers heard a series of explosions from the 2nd  floor]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/children-starve-as-millions-of-gaza-inhabitants-face-famine-threat-5957537]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Children Starve As Millions Of Gaza Inhabitants Face Famine Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/children-starve-as-millions-of-gaza-inhabitants-face-famine-threat-5957537]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 13:06:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nearly 166 million people worldwide are estimated to need urgent action against hunger, according to the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC), a global partnership which measures food insecurity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nearly 166 million people worldwide are estimated to need urgent action against hunger, according to the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC), a global partnership which measures food insecurity.</p>

<p>That includes nearly everyone in the Gaza Strip, where the Israeli military launched an offensive in October following an attack on Israel by Hamas militants. More than one million of Gaza's inhabitants face the most extreme form of malnutrition - classified by the IPC as 'Catastrophe or Famine.'</p>

<p>Seven-month-old Majd Salem is one of them.</p>

<p>Born on Nov. 1, three weeks after Israel launched the offensive, the child was being treated for a chest infection in the neonatal ICU at Kamal Adwan Hospital in northern Gaza on May 9. The nurse caring for him said he was suffering from severe malnutrition.</p>

<p>Majd was born at a healthy weight of 3.5 kg (7.7 pounds), said his mother, Nisreen al-Khateeb.</p>

<p>By May, when he was six months old, his weight had barely changed to 3.8 kg, she said - around 3 kg less than would be expected for a baby his age.</p>

<p>Majd, whose eyes keenly followed visiting reporters in the ward, had to be given antibiotics for the infection and fortified milk to boost his weight, his mother said. Reuters was unable to trace them after May 21, when the hospital was evacuated following an Israeli raid.</p>

<p>One in three children in northern Gaza are acutely malnourished or suffering from wasting, according to the U.N. children's agency UNICEF, citing data from its partners on the ground. Ismail Al-Thawabta, director of the Hamas-run government media office, said their records showed 33 people had died of malnutrition in Gaza including 29 children, but added that the number could be higher.</p>

<p>COGAT, an Israeli defence ministry agency tasked with coordinating aid deliveries into Palestinian territories, did not respond to a request for comment for this story. Israel's foreign ministry in late May issued a detailed statement questioning the IPC's methods of analysis, which it said omitted measures Israel had taken to improve access to food in Gaza. The IPC declined to comment.</p>

<p>The plight of Gaza's children is part of a bigger trend. Globally last year more than 36 million children under 5 were acutely malnourished, nearly 10 million of them severely, according to the Global Report on Food Crises, a collaborative analysis of food insecurity by 16 international organizations.</p>

<p>The food shortage in Gaza, while particularly widespread, comes amid a broader spike in extreme hunger as conflicts around the world intensify.</p>

<p>Two other countries - South Sudan and Mali - each have thousands of people living in zones listed on the IPC website as facing famine. Another 35 - including Sudan, Nigeria and the Democratic Republic of Congo - have many people in the IPC's next-most acute category of food deprivation.</p>

<p>The IPC, a grouping of United Nations agencies, national governments and non-governmental organizations, is expected to update its assessment of the picture in war-torn Sudan in the coming weeks. A preliminary projection reported by Reuters earlier this month said as many as 756,000 people in Sudan could face catastrophic food shortages by September.</p>

<p>Gaza's hunger crisis is also a product of war. The Israeli military invaded the Strip in response to the Oct. 7 cross-border assault by Hamas on Israel. More than 37,000 Palestinians and nearly 1,500 Israelis have been killed since then, Gazan and Israeli tallies show.</p>

<p>The Israeli assault has destroyed swathes of Gazan farmland. In the early days of the war, Israel imposed a total blockade on Gaza. It later allowed some humanitarian supplies to enter but is still facing international calls to let in more.</p>

<p>The International Criminal Court's prosecutor, in seeking arrest warrants for Israeli and Hamas leaders, last month accused Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Defence Minister Yoav Gallant of using starvation of civilians as a method of warfare, among other alleged crimes. Netanyahu, calling that move "a moral outrage of historic proportions," said Israel is fighting in full compliance with international law and taking unprecedented measures to ensure aid reaches those in need.</p>

<p>Israel has accused Hamas of stealing aid, which Hamas strongly denies. Israel has also said any distribution problems within Gaza are the fault of the international agencies.</p>

<p>Even when children survive, nutrition experts say food deprivation in the early years can do lasting damage.</p>

<p>A child's brain develops at its fastest rate in the first two years of life. So even if they don't starve to death or die from illness due to their weakened immune system, children may face delays in growth and development, said Aashima Garg, adviser on nutrition at UNICEF for the Middle East and North Africa.</p>

<p>"While they may be alive, they may not thrive that well in childhood and beyond," she said.</p>

<p>Three families in Gaza told Reuters about their day-to-day diets, and four global health experts explained how such deprivation affects the growing body. Damage done in weeks manifests over years, they said.</p>

<p>"It can have a long-term impact on their immune system, their ability to absorb good nutrition, and on their cognitive and physical development," said Hannah Stephenson, global head of nutrition and health at Save The Children, a non-profit.</p>

<h3><strong>FIRST DAYS</strong></h3>

<p>Gaza has the most households globally in the most extreme stage of food poverty, according to the IPC, which classifies levels of hunger in five categories, the worst of which is famine.</p>

<p>Households in North Gaza, where Majd lives, are already suffering a full-blown famine, Cindy McCain, Executive Director of the World Food Programme, said on May 5.</p>

<p>It can take months for the international measurement system to declare a famine. But the first damage to a child's body is counted in days.</p>

<p>Nine out of 10 children aged 6 months to 2 years in Gaza live in severe child food poverty, a UNICEF survey in late May found. This means they are eating from two or fewer food groups a day, which UNICEF's Garg said means grains or some form of milk.</p>

<p>This has been the case since December 2023, with only a slight improvement in April 2024, she said. As many as 85% of children of all ages did not eat for a whole day at least once in the three days before the survey was conducted.</p>

<p>The main cause of acute malnutrition in North Gaza is a lack of diversity in the diets of children and pregnant and breastfeeding women, according to a report in February 2024 from the Global Nutrition Cluster, a group of humanitarian agencies led by UNICEF.</p>

<p>This deficient intake, both prior to and during pregnancy and breastfeeding, harms both mothers and infants.</p>

<p>Abed Abu Mustafa, 49, a father of six, was still living in Gaza City in early April. He said people there already had eaten "almost every green plant we could find" and he hadn't had meat or chicken for at least five months.</p>

<p>In Rafah in the south, Mariam, 33, a mother of five, has been living in a school along with two dozen of her relatives. She described a typical meal for her family before the conflict and what they are currently eating, shown below.</p>

<p>Before the war, Majd's mother said an average family meal consisted of rice with chicken or meat, along with vegetables such as okra, cauliflower or peas. During the war, flour scarcity forced the family to make bread from animal feed. Recently, bread and canned goods like tuna and beans started to reappear, but these are not widely available.</p>

<p>Unable to find food to feed herself and forced to flee Israeli bombardment early in the war, Khateeb said she had found great difficulty in breastfeeding Majd.</p>

<p>She said she could find neither good quality baby formula nor clean water to mix it, so she fed him various types of powdered feed mixed with rainwater or brackish water from Gaza's polluted wells, causing diarrhoea.</p>

<p>"There is no chance to get proper food to have breastmilk, there is no meat, no proteins, no calcium, none of the elements that produce good milk for the child," she said.</p>

<p>Garg, the UNICEF adviser, said the nutrition of breastfeeding mothers in Gaza was severely compromised, and with it their ability to produce milk.</p>

<p>"They are not eating fruits and vegetables. They are not eating meat. They are not having much milk," she said. This lack of nutrients translates into poor quality breast milk. Diluted formula is not safe and risks diarrhoea, which itself can be deadly.</p>

<p>Moderately malnourished mothers can still breastfeed, with their bodies effectively sacrificing their own nutritional needs to save the child. But severely malnourished women struggle.</p>

<p>Ahmed al-Kahlout, the nurse who heads the unit, said Majd's infection was due to malnutrition.</p>

<p>"There is no immunity, so any disease that the child catches in the shelters ... afflicts the child with these severe lung infections," he said.</p>

<p>Susceptibility to infections typically increases after two weeks with insufficient food.</p>

<p>The body's consumption of its fat reserves eats away muscle tissue, which is why aid workers in the field use basic tape measures to assess the gravity of children's conditions.</p>

<p>The tapes measuring Mid-Upper Arm Circumference (MUAC) have been used for decades. If the upper arm's circumference is 11.5 cm (4 1/2 inches) or smaller for a child between 6 months and 5 years old, the child is assessed as having severe acute malnutrition, according to standards drawn up by the United Nations.</p>

<p>MUAC screening data across Gaza since mid-January found more than 7,000 children aged 6 months to about 5 years were already acutely malnourished as of May 26, the United Nations humanitarian agency OCHA said.</p>

<p>This is how that looks.</p>

<p>Gaza has the most people at risk of starvation, but according to the IPC classifications, many millions are one step behind the enclave in food poverty.</p>

<p>The IPC categorises the severity and scale of food insecurity and malnutrition. Readings of 3, 4 or 5 on the five-category scale require urgent action.</p>

<p>Households in Phase 3 are in "Crisis," the IPC says. They have high or more than usual acute malnutrition, or can meet their minimum food needs but only by selling assets or through crisis measures.</p>

<p>Phase 4 is an "Emergency." Households have either "very high" acute malnutrition and death rates or are only able to make up for the lack of food by taking emergency measures and selling assets.</p>

<p>Phase 5 is "Catastrophe" or "Famine." Households have an extreme lack of food and/or other basic needs and starvation, death, destitution and extremely critical acute malnutrition levels are evident. An entire area is only classified as in Famine if high food insecurity comes with certain levels of acute malnutrition and mortality.</p>

<p>For the IPC, areas in Famine meet at least two of the following three criteria:</p>

<p>* the area has at least 20% of households facing an extreme lack of food,</p>

<p>* About one in three children there suffer from acute malnutrition,</p>

<p>* Two adults or four children out of every 10,000 die each day due to outright starvation, or to the interaction of malnutrition and disease.</p>

<p>The IPC report issued in March projected that the entire population of the Gaza Strip would fall into Phases 3 to 5 between March and July. U.N. officials told Reuters they expect the next IPC analysis on Gaza to be released on June 25.</p>

<p>South Sudan and Mali are the other two other countries with households projected to fall into the same Phase 5 category as Gaza, based on the IPC's latest published analyses.</p>

<p>Overall, the three countries with the largest numbers of people at Phase 3 and above are Nigeria (25 million), the Democratic Republic of Congo (23.4 million) and Sudan (17.7 million), according to the IPC website.</p>

<p>The IPC said its latest analysis of Sudan, conducted in December, was too outdated to include in the tables Reuters used for this chart.</p>

<p>As a consequence of severe malnutrition, various complications arise.</p>

<p>This is the impact of starvation after just three weeks. Like many children in Gaza, Majd's lack of adequate food dates back months.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/atf5e6eg_majd-salem-gaza-reuters_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[7-month-old Majd Salem is among the million of Gaza's inhabitants who face the most extreme malnutrition.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/concerns-mount-as-hungary-assumes-eu-presidency-under-prime-minister-viktor-orban-5957005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Concerns Mount As Hungary Assumes EU Presidency Under PM Orban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/concerns-mount-as-hungary-assumes-eu-presidency-under-prime-minister-viktor-orban-5957005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 11:45:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hungary takes over the European Union's six-month rotating presidency on July 1, in the face of fears perennial spoiler Prime Minister Viktor Orban could use it to take the bloc hostage at a critical time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hungary takes over the European Union's six-month rotating presidency on July 1, in the face of fears perennial spoiler Prime Minister Viktor Orban could use it to take the bloc hostage at a critical time.</p>

<p>EU leaders and diplomats have years of bitter experience dealing with Budapest's hard-right government on issues ranging from Ukraine aid to migration and the rule of law.</p>

<p>In 14 years as premier, nationalist Orban has become an expert in playing hardball -- critics call it blackmail -- with Brussels and has repeatedly wielded his veto to get more EU funds.</p>

<p>While each EU country fights tooth-and-nail for its own interests, when they take over the presidency they are meant to put their politics aside to take on a more neutral role.</p>

<p>The EU likens heading the European Council, the body comprising the 27 member states, to "someone hosting a dinner", and the powers it carries are limited.</p>

<p>But it does see the country at the helm get to chair meetings, steer the agenda, and steward negotiations.</p>

<p>"It will be a presidency as usual, we'll act as an honest broker," Hungary's EU ambassador Balint Odor insisted, as he unveiled priorities focused on bolstering EU economic competitiveness, strengthening the defence industry, and curbing illegal migration.</p>

<p>But the early signals from Hungary -- the self-styled champion of "illiberal democracy" in the EU -- did not appear positive.</p>

<p>Budapest riled diplomats by unveiling "Make Europe Great Again" as the presidency slogan -- echoing the rallying cry of Orban ally former US president Donald Trump -- in a move seen as clear trolling of Brussels ahead of US elections in November.</p>

<p>"It's trying to annoy people," said one European diplomat. "But it's not clever or funny."</p>

<h3><strong>'Don't be fooled'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Orban's key gripe with Brussels at the moment is the fate of some 19 billion euros in EU funds for Budapest frozen over issues including LGBTQ rights, the treatment of asylum seekers, and public procurement.</p>

<p>"We must not be fooled by Orban's ambitious and soft-spoken programme for the next six months, because at the EU level, the government is primarily pursuing one goal: to free up frozen EU funds," said German MEP Daniel Freund, an Orban critic.</p>

<p>"It is to be feared that he will also abuse the powers of the council presidency to achieve this."</p>

<p>Hungary meanwhile is also facing the threat of proceedings under the EU's Article 7 -- a so-called "nuclear option" to strip countries judged to be contravening the bloc's values of voting rights.</p>

<p>Budapest has faced that threat since 2018 and has said it does not intend to hold any hearings on the issue during its presidency.</p>

<p>But officials and diplomats fret that one major victim of Hungary's six months in charge will be EU support for Ukraine as it battles Russia's invading forces.</p>

<p>Budapest -- Russia's closest ally in the bloc -- has repeatedly held up sanctions on Moscow over the war. For the past year, it has blocked the disbursement of EU funds to help arm Ukraine.</p>

<p>Aware of this, other EU countries have pushed through a flurry of initiatives in the dying days before Belgium, which currently holds the presidency, passes on the baton to Hungary.</p>

<p>That includes launching EU membership negotiations with Ukraine this week, and fresh sanctions on Moscow.</p>

<p>"We talk among ourselves as well that, okay, under the Hungarian presidency there will not be any sanctions package," said a senior European diplomat.</p>

<p>"So let's adopt the sanctions package now, and we'll come back to the issue in six months' time."</p>

<h3><strong>Who's afraid of Orban?&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>But insiders -- long used to blockages from Budapest -- remain sanguine about the threat of Hungary gumming up the EU system.</p>

<p>The country takes the reins just after the EU elections, meaning that much of the next six months will be taken up with installing a new European Parliament and executive arm.</p>

<p>And EU counterparts say they've been war-gaming ways around an obstinate Budapest if needed.</p>

<p>Diplomats say the presidency only affords limited power, and if other countries want an issue discussed they can override the presidency and vote it onto the table.</p>

<p>"Even if the presidency doesn't like it, you can put an item on the agenda," the senior diplomat said.</p>

<p>"So I'm not afraid of Hungary."</p>

<p>Another diplomat argued that it was "in Hungary's interest to make the presidency a success" to avoid political headaches and bad blood that could follow.</p>

<p>"I would say they want a smooth running of the trains," the diplomat said.</p>

<p>"And they know if they don't take that path then of course the other member states, especially the big ones, are not going to sit idly by and let it happen."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/96kjpbh_viktor-orban_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Viktor Orban could use the presidency to take the bloc hostage at a critical time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/advanced-telescope-to-soon-tell-if-theres-planet-nine-5956625]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Solar System May Soon Have A Ninth Planet. Courtesy: An Advanced Telescope]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/advanced-telescope-to-soon-tell-if-theres-planet-nine-5956625]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:45:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As per NASA, the composition of Planet X is like Neptune, but its mass could be 10 times that of Earth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For almost a decade, astronomers have been searching the outer solar system, looking for signs of a <a href="https://www.livescience.com/space/planets/planet-nine-is-the-search-for-this-elusive-world-nearly-over#:~:text=If%20it%20exists%2C%20Planet%20Nine,showing%20that%20this%20is%20possible.">ninth planet</a>.&nbsp;Their search may soon come to an end, courtesy of a state-of-the-art telescope, which will begin scanning the sky next year.</p>

<p>The&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vera-c-rubin-observatory-800-million-camera-car-sized-to-capture-universe-as-never-before-4964809">Vera C Rubin Observatory</a> in Chile, which is set to open in 2025, may finally help scientists find Planet Nine within the next few years, experts told Live Science.</p>

<p>Over the past few years, astronomers have proposed that a ninth world, nicknamed “Planet Nine”, could be hiding in the far reaches of our cosmic neighbourhood.</p>

<p>Planet Nine is sometimes called Planet X. About Planet X, scientists believe it is a gas or ice giant billions of miles away from the rest of the planets.</p>

<p>With the help of the state-of-the-art telescope, Planet Nine could be found within the next two years, Mike Brown, an astronomer who proposed the Planet Nine hypothesis along with a colleague, told Live Science.</p>

<p>The size of a small car and weighing 2.8 metric tons, the sophisticated piece of equipment will reveal views of the cosmos as never before.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The $800 million camera will snap its first photos beginning in early 2025 and&nbsp;the machine will sweep the sky every three days, allowing scientists to reach new heights in their galactic analyses.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-exercise-finds-asteroid-with-72-chance-of-hitting-earth-5950284">There's A 72% Chance That An Asteroid May Hit Earth On This Exact Day</a></strong></p>

<p>According to <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/solar-system/planet-x/">NASA</a>, the composition of Planet X is like Neptune, but its mass could be 10 times that of Earth.</p>

<p>The US space agency also claimed that Planet X “may take between 10,000 and 20,000 Earth years” to complete an orbit around the sun.</p>

<p>This hypothetical Neptune-sized planet orbits the Sun in a highly elongated orbit far beyond Pluto, the report said.</p>

<p>Jim Green, director of NASA's Planetary Science Division, said that the possibility of a new planet is an exciting one for science.</p>

<p>"This is not, however, the detection or discovery of a new planet. It's too early to say with certainty there's a so-called Planet X," Mr Green said, adding it is an early prediction based on modelling from limited observations.</p>

<p>"It's the start of a process that could lead to an exciting result," he further said.</p>

<p>The solar system currently consists of eight planets — Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune.</p>

<p>Pluto was the ninth planet of the solar system before it was demoted from full planetary status to <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-year-old-tells-nasa-to-make-pluto-a-planet-again-you-need-to-fix-this-problem-for-me-1814012#:~:text=The%20International%20Astronomical%20Union%2C%20not,as%20a%20full%2Dsized%20planet.">“dwarf planet”</a> in 2006.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/0v3ko3lo_vera-c-rubin-observatory_625x300_31_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Vera C Rubin Observatory in Chile]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baps-hindu-mandir-in-abu-dhabi-symbol-of-india-uae-friendship-s-jaishankar-visits-uaes-first-hindu-temple-5956265]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Symbol Of India-UAE Friendship": S Jaishankar Visits Abu Dhabi's Temple]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baps-hindu-mandir-in-abu-dhabi-symbol-of-india-uae-friendship-s-jaishankar-visits-uaes-first-hindu-temple-5956265]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 09:37:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Jaishankar visited the BAPS Hindu Mandir in Abu Dhabi, which was inaugurated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on February 14 this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar held "productive and deep" conversations with his United Arab Emirates counterpart Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan on India and UAE's "ever-growing" comprehensive strategic ties and discussed regional and global issues.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar, who was in the UAE on Sunday, visited the iconic BAPS Hindu Mandir in Abu Dhabi and participated in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/universal-practice-s-jaishankar-leads-yoga-day-celebrations-in-abu-dhabi-5954962">10th International Yoga Day celebrations</a> before meeting Al Nahyan.</p>

<p>"Very pleased to meet UAE FM @ABZayed today in Abu Dhabi," he said in a post on X after meeting his UAE counterpart.</p>

<p>"Productive and deep conversations on our ever-growing Comprehensive Strategic Partnership. Appreciated the discussion and his insights on regional and global issues," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar visited the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/explained-how-abu-dhabis-baps-hindu-temple-represents-india-uae-ties-5057457">BAPS Hindu Mandir in Abu Dhabi</a>, which was inaugurated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on February 14 this year.</p>

<p>Taking to X, he called the temple a "visible symbol of India-UAE friendship".</p>

<p>At the temple, the minister interacted with the monks of BAPS, the Bochasanwasi Akshar Purushottam Sansthan, the organisation that built the temple on the land donated by the UAE.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Blessed to visit the BAPS Hindu Mandir in Abu Dhabi today.<br />
<br />
A visible symbol of India-UAE friendship, it radiates a positive message to the world and is a true cultural bridge between our two countries.<br />
<br />
?? ?? <a href="https://twitter.com/AbuDhabiMandir?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@AbuDhabiMandir</a> <a href="https://t.co/6YO7gj3geZ">pic.twitter.com/6YO7gj3geZ</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1804892788732936283?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Jaishankar then inaugurated and participated in the 10th International Day of Yoga celebrations organised by the Indian Embassy in UAE, held at the Louvre, Abu Dhabi museum premises.</p>

<p>The session lasted for almost 30 minutes, with participants from a multitude of countries at the museum that regularly holds yoga classes for diverse backgrounds.</p>

<p>Ahead of his day-long visit to Abu Dhabi, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) in New Delhi said that the visit would provide an opportunity to review the entire spectrum of comprehensive strategic partnership between India and the UAE as well as regional and global developments.</p>

<p>"During the visit, the External Affairs Minister will have a meeting with his UAE counterpart on wide-ranging issues of the partnership," the MEA said in a statement.</p>

<p>About a 3.5-million-strong and vibrant Indian community forms the largest expatriate group in the UAE.</p>

<p>Both countries signed a landmark comprehensive economic partnership agreement (CEPA) in February 2022 to boost economic engagement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/dtl08d8g_s-jaishankar-abu-dhabi-temple_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[BAPS Hindu Mandir in Abu Dhabi was inaugurated by PM Modi in February]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dagestan-shooting-attack-in-makhachkala-derbent-over-15-people-including-cops-and-priest-killed-by-gunmen-in-russia-5955818]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunmen Attack Churches, Synagogues In Russia; Cops, Priest Among 15 Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dagestan-shooting-attack-in-makhachkala-derbent-over-15-people-including-cops-and-priest-killed-by-gunmen-in-russia-5955818]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 07:31:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 15 people, including policemen and a priest, were killed and several others injured after unidentified gunmen opened fire at a synagogue, a church, and a police post in Russia's North Caucasus region of Dagestan on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 15 people, including policemen and a priest, were killed and several others injured after unidentified gunmen opened fire at synagogues, churches, and a police post in Russia's North Caucasus region of Dagestan on Sunday, the region's governor said.</p>

<p>The simultaneous attacks occurred in Dagestan's largest city of Makhachkala and in the coastal city of Derbent with Governor Sergei Melikov calling it a "terrorist attack".</p>

<p>Officials said that the police personnel had killed four gunmen in Makhachkala and two in Derbent.</p>

<p>Melikov said that among the dead, in addition to the police officers, were several civilians, including an Orthodox priest who had worked in Derbent for more than 40 years.</p>

<p>"This evening in Derbent and Makhachkala unknown (attackers) made attempts to destabilise the situation in society,"&nbsp;Melikov wrote on Telegram.</p>

<p>"We know who is behind these terrorist attacks and what objective they are pursuing," he added later, without specifying but referring to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-china-call-for-russia-ukraine-peace-talks-with-both-countries-5732561" target="_blank">Russia-Ukraine war</a>.</p>

<p>"We must understand that war comes to our homes too. We felt it, but today we face it," he said.</p>

<p>Melikov said the "active phase" of operations in Derbent and Makhachkala had ended and that "six bandits have been liquidated".</p>

<p>The authorities will try to find "all the members of these sleeper cells who prepared (the attacks) and who were prepared, including abroad", he added.</p>

<p>He also said that June 24-26 have been declared days of mourning in Dagestan, with flags lowered to half-staff and all entertainment events cancelled.</p>

<p>Russia's Investigative Committee said it had opened criminal probes over "acts of terror" in Dagestan. There, however, was no immediate claim of responsibility for the attacks.</p>

<p>Russia's state media cited law enforcement as saying that among the attackers had been two sons of the head of central Dagestan's Sergokala district, who had been detained.</p>

<p>In Derbent, authorities were quoted as saying that both the synagogue and church were set on fire.</p>

<p>The incident comes three months after 145 people were killed in an attack claimed by the Islamic State on a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-accuses-ukraine-of-direct-involvement-in-deadly-concert-hall-attack-5734004" target="_blank">concert hall near Moscow</a>, Russia's worst terrorist attack in years.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/uu4qbcsg_russia-attack_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Unidentified gunmen opened fire at synagogues and churches in Russia's Dagestan region]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-abortion-rights-to-feature-in-joe-biden-donald-trumps-first-presidential-debate-5955793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Abortion Rights To Feature In Biden-Trump's First Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-abortion-rights-to-feature-in-joe-biden-donald-trumps-first-presidential-debate-5955793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 07:30:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two years after the US Supreme Court stripped constitutional protections for abortion, the explosive issue will feature prominently in Thursday's debate between Joe Biden and Donald Trump -- with the Republican under pressure not to alienate voters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two years after the US Supreme Court stripped constitutional protections for abortion, the explosive issue will feature prominently in Thursday's debate between Joe Biden and Donald Trump -- with the Republican under pressure not to alienate voters.</p>

<p>On June 24, 2022, the high court -- with a super-conservative majority built under Trump's presidency -- overturned the historic ruling in Roe v. Wade that had protected abortion rights, placing the issue in the hands of the states.</p>

<p>That same day, a handful of US states banned abortions, forcing clinics to close in haste or move to more welcoming places.</p>

<p>The nation, already politically polarized, is now split between the states that have banned or significantly restricted access to the procedure -- and the states that have adopted new protections for a woman's right to terminate a pregnancy.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court's decision sent political shockwaves across the country, and had repercussions -- since the ruling, conservatives have lost nearly every referendum or vote revolving around abortion access.</p>

<p>And some of those losses came in states that have recently shifted solidly to the right, such as Ohio, Alabama and Kansas.</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris takes the baton&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Since Roe was overturned, "the abortion rights movement discovered that Americans care more about abortion rights than may have been anticipated," said Mary Ziegler, a professor at the University of California, Davis law school.</p>

<p>"And so they are trying to capitalize on that in ballot initiative fights that have gone mostly the way of the abortion rights movement," she told AFP.</p>

<p>Democrats are making the most of the moment, hoping to win some crucial support from women and young voters.</p>

<p>Biden, a practicing Catholic who was long vexed by the issue, has become a champion of abortion rights and made it a defining part of his re-election bid, winning the backing of several family planning organizations.</p>

<p>Vice President Kamala Harris, the first woman in the job, has crisscrossed the country for months to mobilize her party faithful.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old Harris in March became the first vice president to visit a clinic performing abortions, in Minnesota.</p>

<p>On Monday, she will hold an event in Arizona -- a state seen as a crucial battleground in the November presidential election, and one where the supreme court said a Civil War-era rule banning abortion was valid.</p>

<p>Democratic Governor Katie Hobbs later signed a repeal of the 1864 law.</p>

<p>Across the country, Democrats have also encouraged the organization of mini-referendums on abortion in key states, so that they will coincide with the presidential vote -- and hopefully motivate unenthused voters to cast ballots.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump deliberately vague&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Democrats are right to be confident in their reasoning, if an avalanche of opinion polls are correct.</p>

<p>According to a Fox News poll published Wednesday, 47 percent of voters consider abortion to be "extremely important" in how they decide between Biden and Trump.</p>

<p>The presumptive Republican candidate, who often mentions that he nominated three Supreme Court justices who helped to overturn Roe v. Wade, has lately been decidedly vague on the issue of abortion.</p>

<p>"You must follow your heart on this issue but remember, you must also win elections," Trump said in a video message in early April.</p>

<p>He has not campaigned on any promise to make abortion illegal with federal legislation, as the religious right has lobbied him to do.</p>

<p>"The best you can do if your position is unpopular is to not clarify your position," Ziegler says.</p>

<p>Biden, whose approval rating is less than stellar, will almost certainly attack Trump on the issue when the two take the stage Thursday for their first debate in 2024.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/sd77uu9g_biden-trump-split-image_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden and Donald Trump are supposed to have the first Presidential Debate this Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-caledonia-9-dead-and-many-buildings-torched-as-fresh-unrest-erupts-in-new-caledonia-5955760]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[9 Dead And Many Buildings Torched As Fresh Unrest Erupts In New Caledonia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-caledonia-9-dead-and-many-buildings-torched-as-fresh-unrest-erupts-in-new-caledonia-5955760]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 07:14:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Several buildings, including a police station and a town hall, were set on fire in New Caledonia overnight, authorities said Monday, as the French Pacific territory was hit by a fresh surge of unrest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several buildings, including a police station and a town hall, were set on fire in New Caledonia overnight, authorities said Monday, as the French Pacific territory was hit by a fresh surge of unrest.</p>

<p>"The night was... marked by unrest throughout the mainland and on the island of Pins and Mare, requiring the intervention of numerous reinforcements: with attacks on the police, arson and roadblocks", the High Commission, which represents the French state in the archipelago, said in a press release.</p>

<p>Rioting and looting erupted in New Caledonia in mid-May over an electoral reform plan that Indigenous Kanak people feared would leave them in a permanent minority, putting independence hopes definitively out of reach.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The unrest left nine dead and damage estimated at more than 1.5 billion euros ($1.6 billion).</p>

<p>The French government responded by sending more than 3,000 troops and police to the territory almost 17,000 kilometres (10,600 miles) from Paris.</p>

<p>In Dumbea, north of the capital Noumea, the municipal police station and a garage were set alight. Four armoured vehicles intervened, an AFP journalist said.</p>

<p>Several fires broke out in the Ducos and Magenta districts of Noumea, while police and separatists clashed in Bourail, resulting in one injury, AFP learned.</p>

<p>The High Commission reported "several fires were extinguished", particularly in Ducos and Magenta, adding that "the premises and vehicles of the municipal police and private vehicles" were set on fire.</p>

<p>"Abuses, destruction and attempted fires were also committed in several places in Paita," in the Noumea suburbs, added the High Commission, which said police in Mare had also been attacked.</p>

<p>On Monday morning, many schools were closed due to the renewed unrest.</p>

<p>On Saturday, seven independence activists linked to a group accused of orchestrating the riots last month were indicted and sent to mainland France for pre-trial detention.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/c2q177q_new-caledonia-protests_625x300_16_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rioting and looting erupted in New Caledonia in mid-May over an electoral reform plan (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-north-korea-defence-deal-could-create-friction-with-china-us-officer-5955358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia-N Korea Defence Deal Could Create Friction With China: US Officer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-north-korea-defence-deal-could-create-friction-with-china-us-officer-5955358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 04:52:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin's mutual defence agreement with North Korea has the potential to create friction with China, which has long been the reclusive state's main ally, the top U.S. military officer said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin's mutual defence agreement with North Korea has the potential to create friction with China, which has long been the reclusive state's main ally, the top U.S. military officer said on Sunday.</p>

<p>"We've got someone else who's kind of nudging in now, so that may drive a little bit more friction between (China) and Russia," Air Force General C.Q. Brown, chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, told reporters during an overseas trip.</p>

<p>"So it'll be interesting to see how these three countries -- how this plays out."</p>

<p>Analysts said the pact, signed on Wednesday, could undercut Beijing's leverage over its two neighbors and any heightened instability could be negative for China's global economic and strategic ambitions.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Putin said Russia might supply weapons to North Korea in what he suggested would be a mirror response to the Western arming of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Brown acknowledged U.S. concern about the deal.</p>

<p>But he also tempered those remarks by noting apparent limitations to the accord and expressing doubt Moscow would give North Korea "everything" it wanted.</p>

<p>U.S. officials have said they believe North Korea is keen to acquire fighter aircraft, surface-to-air missiles, armored vehicles, ballistic missile production equipment or materials, and other advanced technologies from Russia.</p>

<p>"The feedback I have on the agreement -- it was a broad agreement that's not overly binding, which gives you an indication (that) they want to work together but they don't want to get their hands tied," Brown said.</p>

<p>The treaty signed by Putin and Kim on Wednesday commits each side to provide immediate military assistance to the other in the event of armed aggression against either one of them.</p>

<p>Putin has said Moscow expected that its cooperation with North Korea would serve as a deterrent to the West, but that there was no need to use North Korean soldiers for the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>The United States and Ukraine say North Korea has already provided Russia with significant quantities of artillery shells and ballistic missiles, which Moscow and Pyongyang deny.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/p5b7lfro_kim-and-putin_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Thursday, Putin said Russia might supply weapons to North Korea]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-man-32-shot-dead-in-texas-came-to-us-8-months-ago-5955245]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Man Shot Dead During Texas Robbery Came To US 8 Months Ago]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-man-32-shot-dead-in-texas-came-to-us-8-months-ago-5955245]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 04:19:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a tragic incident, a 32-year-old Indian-origin man was fatally shot during a robbery at a convenience store in the US state of Texas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a tragic incident, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/32-year-old-man-from-andhra-pradesh-killed-in-us-grocery-store-shooting-5950446">32-year-old Indian man</a> was fatally shot during a robbery at a convenience store in the US state of Texas. Dasari Gopikrishna, who hailed from Bapatla district in Andhra Pradesh, came to the US only eight months ago.</p>

<p>The incident occurred at a gas station convenience store in Pleasant Grove, Dallas on June 21.</p>

<p>Consul General D C Manjunath, who was in Dallas for a Yoga Day event on Sunday, confirmed to news agency PTI that the incident was unrelated to a shooting in Arkansas as previously reported by various sources.</p>

<p>Expressing condolences to Gopikrishna's family, Mr Manjunath said, "We are deeply saddened to learn about the tragic demise of Indian national Gopi Krishna Dasari in a robbery shooting incident at Pleasant Grove, Dallas, TX, and are in touch with local family members."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Consulate, along with support from Indian associations, is providing all possible assistance to facilitate the repatriation of Mr Gopikrishna's body to India following local formalities, including autopsy and death certificates.</p>

<p>Mr Gopikrishna sustained critical injuries during the robbery and was rushed to a nearby hospital, where he tragically succumbed to his injuries on Sunday morning while undergoing treatment.</p>

<p>The incident has deeply affected the Indian community in Dallas and surrounding areas. Mr Gopikrishna is survived by his wife and son.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ogn1mt_dasari-gopikrishna_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dasari Gopikrishna sustained critical injuries during the robbery]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-pins-blame-on-us-for-deadly-missile-attack-on-crimea-that-killed-4-5955211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Pins Blame On US For Deadly Missile Attack On Crimea That Killed 4]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-pins-blame-on-us-for-deadly-missile-attack-on-crimea-that-killed-4-5955211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 24 Jun 2024 04:07:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia on Sunday said the United States had responsibility for a Ukrainian missile attack on Russian-annexed Crimea, which it said killed four people, including two children, and wounded over 100.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia on Sunday said the United States had responsibility for a Ukrainian missile attack on Russian-annexed Crimea, which it said killed four people, including two children, and wounded over 100.</p>

<p>A missile exploded above a beach area of the city of Sevastopol, firing shrapnel at people relaxing there, Russian-appointed officials said.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry said Washington and Kyiv bore "responsibility for a deliberate missile strike on peaceful residents", which it said used US-supplied ATACMS missiles.</p>

<p>Sevastopol governor Mikhail Razvozhayev initially said in a Telegram video the attack had killed three children and two adults, and wounded nearly 120 people.</p>

<p>He later revised the toll to four dead and 151 people requiring medical care, of whom 82 had been hospitalised.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin had called to "offer his condolences", Razvozhayev added.</p>

<p>The Black Sea port city and naval base on the Crimean peninsula was annexed by Russia in 2014 but is still internationally recognised as part of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Sevastopol regularly comes under fire from Ukraine but Sunday's attack was unusually deadly. Razvozhayev said the attack hit Uchkuyevka, an area with sandy beaches and hotels.</p>

<p>Videos posted on social media showed people running from the beach as explosions went off and people in swimming outfits carrying a stretcher. AFP could not verify their authenticity.</p>

<p>A local news channel on Telegram, ChP Sevastopol, cited witnesses as saying that an elderly woman was killed as she swam in the sea.</p>

<p>Washington said in April that it had provided longer-range ATACMS missile systems to Kyiv, which had long urged allies for weapons allowing it to strike Russia farther beyond the front lines.</p>

<p>Neither the United States nor Ukraine had commented on the Sevastopol strike.</p>

<h3><strong>'Terrorist act'</strong></h3>

<p>The investigative committee, which probes major crimes, said it was opening an investigation into "a terrorist act".</p>

<p>The governor said Ukraine had launched five missiles that Russian air-defences intercepted over the sea but fragments fell onto the shore, wounding people.</p>

<p>Razvozhayev said shrapnel hit beach areas in the north of the city and set fire to a house and woodland.</p>

<p>A Russian defence ministry statement said Ukraine had committed a "terrorist attack on the civilian infrastructure of Sevastopol with US-supplied ATACMS tactical missiles loaded with cluster warheads".</p>

<p>The ministry said four missiles were downed but a fifth changed trajectory after being intercepted "with its warhead exploding in the air over the city".</p>

<p>It added that "all flight missions for US ATACMS are entered by US specialists based on the US's own satellite reconnaissance data.</p>

<p>"Such actions will not be left without a response," the ministry said.</p>

<p>Ukraine's military has not commented on the attack, which came a day after a Russian guided bomb strike on the city of Kharkiv hit an apartment building, killing two people and wounding more than 50.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Deaths in Belgorod, Russia</strong></h3>

<p>On Sunday, Russian strikes hit a house and a children's educational facility in Kharkiv, killing one person and injuring 10 including two teenagers, regional governor Oleg Synegubov said.</p>

<p>In the Belgorod region on Sunday, three Ukrainian attack drones struck Graivoron, near the border with Ukraine, said governor Vyacheslav Gladkov, with one hitting a car park near a multi-storey block of flats.</p>

<p>"A peaceful civilian was killed. The man died from his wounds at the spot" and three people were wounded, Gladkov wrote on Telegram.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky in a social media post urged supporter countries to help Ukraine step up attacks on Russian soil.</p>

<p>"We have enough determination to destroy terrorists on their territory -- it is only fair -- and we need the same determination from our partners. We can stop Russia," Zelensky wrote.</p>

<p>In his evening address he added: "The recent approval of strikes on Russian territory -- near the border -- made it possible to destroy part of Russia's terrorist potential."</p>

<p>But, he said, "we need more long-range weapons, we need appropriate weapons for Ukrainians".</p>

<p>Ukraine's energy operator Ukrenergo announced that rolling electricity blackouts would be imposed nationwide throughout Monday because of increased Russian attacks on power stations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nc0b0cg_russian-ministry_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin had called to "offer his condolences"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>