<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 15:15:03 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/southwest-airlines-plane-hit-by-gunfire-on-runway-in-us-7033030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Southwest Airlines Plane Hit By Gunfire On Runway In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/southwest-airlines-plane-hit-by-gunfire-on-runway-in-us-7033030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 14:50:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Southwest Airlines plane was hit by gunfire while taking off from an airport in the US city of Dallas on Friday, the Federal Aviation Administration said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Southwest Airlines plane was hit by gunfire while taking off from an airport in the US city of Dallas on Friday, the Federal Aviation Administration said.</p>

<p>"While taxiing for takeoff at Dallas Love Field Airport, Southwest Airlines Flight 2494 was reportedly struck by gunfire near the cockpit," a statement on the FAA's website said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The Boeing 737-800 returned to the gate, where passengers deplaned."</p>

<p>The incident happened at around 8:30 pm Friday (0230 GMT Saturday), with the flight headed from Dallas, Texas, to Indianapolis, Indiana.</p>

<p>There were no reported injuries, according to a statement from Dallas Love Field Airport on social media platform X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/q0ufej7g_southwest-airlines-unsplash_625x300_21_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were no reported injuries. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-departs-for-5-day-tour-of-nigeria-brazil-guyana-7032839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi Departs For 5-Day Tour Of Nigeria, Brazil, Guyana]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-departs-for-5-day-tour-of-nigeria-brazil-guyana-7032839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 14:25:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi left for his five-day visit to Nigeria, Brazil, and Guyana. He will be on his three-nation tour from November 16 to 21, where he will be attending the G20 Summit in Brazil.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Saturday said he is looking forward to "meaningful" discussions at the upcoming G20 summit in Brazil that built upon its agenda for the grouping on India's presidency of the bloc last year.</p>

<p>Modi made the comments in a statement ahead of his five day visit to Nigeria, Brazil and Guyana.</p>

<p>The prime minister's first destination will be Nigeria from where he will travel to Brazil.</p>

<p>"In Brazil, I will attend the 19th G-20 Summit as a troika member. Last year, India's successful presidency elevated the G-20 to people's G-20 and mainstreamed the priorities of the Global South into its agenda," the prime minister said.</p>

<p>Modi, Chinese President Xi Jinping and US President Joe Biden will be among the leaders to attend the summit in Rio de Janeiro on November 18 and 19.</p>

<p>India is part of the G20 troika along with Brazil and South Africa.</p>

<p>"This year, Brazil has built upon India's legacy. I look forward to meaningful discussions in keeping with our vision of 'One Earth, One Family, One Future'. I will also use the opportunity to exchange views on furthering bilateral cooperation with several other leaders," the prime minister said.</p>

<p>Induction of the 55-nation African Union as a permanent member of the G20 and managing to produce a leaders' declaration overcoming deep divisions over the Ukraine conflict were seen as major milestones of India's presidency of the G20 last year.</p>

<p>On his trip to Nigeria, Modi said it will be an opportunity to "build upon our strategic partnership that is based on shared belief in democracy and pluralism".</p>

<p>The prime minister is travelling to the country on a two-day visit from November 16-17 at the invitation of President Bola Ahmed Tinubu.</p>

<p>This will be my first visit to Nigeria, which is our close partner in the West African region, Modi said.</p>

<p>"I am also eagerly looking forward to meeting the Indian community and friends from Nigeria who have sent me warm welcome messages in Hindi," he said.</p>

<p>In the third and final leg of his trip, Modi will visit Guyana from November 19 to 21 at the invitation of President Mohamed Irfaan Ali.</p>

<p>It will be the first ever visit of an Indian prime minister to Guyana in over 50 years.</p>

<p>"We will exchange views on giving strategic direction to our unique relationship, which is based on shared heritage, culture and values," Modi said.</p>

<p>"I will also pay my respects to one of the oldest Indian diaspora, who migrated more than 185 years ago, and engage a fellow democracy, as I address their Parliament," he added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vhtjlfpg_modi-nigeria-brazil-guyana_625x300_16_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The prime minister's first destination will be Nigeria from where he will travel to Brazil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/editor-in-chief-of-leading-us-magazine-resigns-after-calling-donald-trump-voters-the-most-bigoted-group-7032770]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Editor Of Oldest US Magazine Resigns After Calling Trump Voters "Fascists"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/editor-in-chief-of-leading-us-magazine-resigns-after-calling-donald-trump-voters-the-most-bigoted-group-7032770]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 14:13:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During Laura Helmuths tenure, the magazine made headlines for its rare endorsements, including a significant 2024 endorsement of Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The editor-in-chief of Scientific American, the oldest continuously published magazine in the US, has resigned following backlash over comments she made about Donald Trump voters. Laura Helmuth, who led the renowned publication for over four years, stepped down after posting inflammatory remarks on social media that described Mr Trump's supporters as the "meanest, dumbest, most bigoted" group and labelled them "fascists."</p>

<p>In her resignation statement on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://bsky.app/profile/laurahelmuth.bsky.social/post/3lawlkjh6ns23">Bluesky</a>, a platform rivalling X, Ms Helmuth said she had decided to leave after "an exciting 4.5 years as editor in chief," without addressing the controversy directly. Her now-deleted comments, made on election night, drew intense criticism, particularly from supporters, with many accusing her of compromising her role as a neutral journalist. Some demanded her resignation.</p>

<p>Ms Helmuth later apologised, calling her posts "offensive and inappropriate" and explaining that they were a "mistaken expression of shock and confusion about the election results." She clarified that the views expressed did not reflect her personal beliefs or the position of Scientific American, stressing that she "respects and values people across the political spectrum."</p>

<p>During Ms Helmuth's tenure, the magazine made headlines for its rare endorsements, including a significant 2024 endorsement of Vice President Kamala Harris. Scientific American also has a long history of engaging with political matters, particularly when they intersect with science. Under Ms Helmuth's leadership, the magazine took a strong stance against Mr Trump's handling of the COVID-19 pandemic, issuing its first-ever presidential endorsement in 2020 to support Joe Biden.</p>

<p>In her resignation announcement, Ms Helmuth shared that she planned to "take some time to think about what comes next" and "go bird-watching."</p>

<p>Kimberly Lau, president of Scientific American, confirmed in a statement that Ms Helmuth had "decided to move on from her position," as per the NYT, and expressed gratitude for her leadership during her tenure. "We thank Laura for her four years leading Scientific American, during which time the magazine won major science communications awards and saw the establishment of a reimagined digital newsroom," Ms Lau said as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/15/media/scientific-american-editor-resignation/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>A search for Laura Helmuth's replacement is currently underway.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9f5ih7j_magazine_625x300_16_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A search for Laura Helmuth's replacement is currently underway.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraine-war-would-end-sooner-with-donald-trump-in-office-volodymyr-zelensky-7032640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Ukraine War Would End Sooner With Trump In Office": Volodymyr Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraine-war-would-end-sooner-with-donald-trump-in-office-volodymyr-zelensky-7032640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 13:52:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said that Russia's war against his country will "end sooner" than it otherwise would have done once Donald Trump becomes US president next year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Friday that Russia's war against his country will "end sooner" than it otherwise would have done once Donald Trump becomes US president next year.</p>

<p>"It is certain that the war will end sooner with the policies of the team that will now lead the White House. This is their approach, their promise to their citizens," Zelensky said in an interview with Ukrainian media outlet Suspilne.</p>

<p>"The war will end, but we don't know the exact date," he added.</p>

<p>Zelensky said he had a "constructive exchange" with Trump during their telephone conversation after his victory in the US presidential election.</p>

<p>"I didn't hear anything that goes against our position," he added.</p>

<p>Throughout the election campaign, Trump criticised the tens of billions of dollars in aid provided for Ukraine since the start of the Russian invasion in February 2022, and he promised he would resolve the conflict "in 24 hours", without ever explaining how.</p>

<p>Speaking at his Mar-a-Lago resort in Palm Beach, Florida on Friday, Trump said "we're going to work very hard on Russia and Ukraine. It's got to stop."</p>

<p>Ukraine fears US support will flag just as its troops are struggling on the front, or that it will be forced to make territorial concessions to Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kb55urb_zelensky-afp_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky spoke to Trump after his US Presidential victory.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malcolm-xs-family-accuses-fbi-cia-of-role-in-assassination-files-case-7032418]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Malcolm X's Family Sues FBI, CIA Over His Murder, Seeks $100 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malcolm-xs-family-accuses-fbi-cia-of-role-in-assassination-files-case-7032418]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 13:11:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Malcolm X, a civil rights leader, was assassinated on February 21, 1965, in Upper Manhattan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The daughters of civil rights leader&nbsp;Malcolm X have filed a $100 million lawsuit against the FBI, CIA, and New York Police Department (NYPD), accusing the agencies of playing a role in the assassination of their father in 1965.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The lawsuit, filed on Friday in Manhattan federal court, alleges that these agencies not only knew of the plot but also failed to intervene and prevent the killing, <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/daughters-malcolm-x-sue-fbi-cia-nypd-100m-1965-assassination " rel="nofollow,noindex">Fox News</a> reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Malcolm X, born Malcolm Little, was assassinated on February 21, 1965, while speaking at the Audubon Ballroom in Upper Manhattan.</p>

<p dir="ltr">He was shot 21 times in front of his wife, Betty Shabazz, and their daughters, who were in the audience. While three men were initially convicted of the crime, two were exonerated in 2021 after new evidence surfaced, suggesting that key details had been overlooked or concealed by authorities.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Testimony from Mustafa Hassan, who was part of Malcolm X's security detail at the time, further complicated the case. Mr Hassan claimed that he tried to stop one of the shooters, Thomas Hagan (also known as Talmadge X Hayer), from fleeing the scene. However, police officers allegedly intervened to protect Hayer, with some officers reportedly asking each other, "Is he with us?"</p>

<p dir="ltr">Now, Ben Crump, the civil rights attorney representing the daughters and the Malcolm X estate, said that the lawsuit is an effort to expose the “corrupt, unlawful, and unconstitutional” actions taken by law enforcement and other government agencies leading up to Malcolm X's death. The complaint accuses the government of enabling a network of “ruthless killers,” who operated with impunity, concealing their actions for years.</p>

<p dir="ltr">"The government's fingerprints are all over the assassination of Malcolm X," Mr Crump claimed at a press conference. "We believe we have the evidence to prove it." He added that the Shabazz family has endured decades of uncertainty, without knowing who was truly responsible for the murder or the extent of the government's involvement. "The damage caused to the Shabazz family is unimaginable, immense, and irreparable," the lawsuit says.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Malcolm X's daughter, Ilyasah Shabazz, at a press conference held at the site of his death, spoke about her family's fight for justice. "We fought primarily for our mother, who was here," Ms Ilyasah said, as per <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/malcolm-xs-family-files-100-million-wrongful-death/story?id=115894702 " rel="nofollow,noindex">ABC News</a>. “My mother was pregnant when she came here to see her husband speak; someone who she just admired totally and to witness this horrific assassination of her husband.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Malcolm X's rise to prominence was marked by his role as a spokesperson for the Nation of Islam, where he advocated for Black empowerment and civil rights “by any means necessary.” His eventual split from the organisation led to death threats from former allies, many of whom considered him a traitor.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The case also references the assassination of other Black leaders, such as Fred Hampton, the chairman of the Illinois chapter of the Black Panther Party, who was killed in 1969 by Chicago police officers. It draws a connection between these killings and COINTELPRO, a covert FBI program designed to disrupt and discredit Black political groups.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-11/59nv12p8_malcolm-x-_625x300_18_November_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Malcolm X was shot 21 times in front of his wife and daughters]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-americans-to-urge-trump-administration-for-sanctions-against-bangladesh-7032360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Americans To Urge Trump For Sanctions Against Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-americans-to-urge-trump-administration-for-sanctions-against-bangladesh-7032360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 13:03:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian Americans are working to reach out to the new Trump administration and the Congress next year to seek action against the Bangladeshi regime.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian Americans are working to reach out to the new Trump administration and the Congress next year to seek action against the Bangladeshi regime, including imposing economic sanctions, an influential community leader has said.</p>

<p>Encouraged by the recent statement of President-elect Donald Trump on Bangladesh, Dr Bharat Barai, an Indian American physician, exuded confidence that Trump would act against the South Asian nation over the persecution of the Hindu minority after he is sworn in as the 47th president of the United States.</p>

<p>He (Trump) has made a bold statement about the persecution of Bangladeshi Hindus and the desecration of Hindu temples," Barai told PTI in an interview. "He's a bold person who might consider economic sanctions if the situation doesn't improve," he added.</p>

<p>In Washington to attend the annual Diwali celebrations at the US Capitol, which was attended by over two dozen US lawmakers and Indian Americans from across the country, Barai said community members are actively working to engage the new administration and Congress to take action against the Bangladeshi regime, including potential economic sanctions.</p>

<p>"If their garment exports, which account for 80 percent of their business, are cut off, what will the people of Bangladesh eat?" he asked, alleging that Bangladesh's caretaker government, led by Muhammad Yunus, is merely a puppet controlled by the military. "It is really the army that is in control of the country," he added.</p>

<p>Barai expressed hope that such pressure would lead to a realisation in Bangladesh to stop the persecution of Hindus and other minorities. "We, as Hindu Americans, will also plead with the Congress to act if Bangladesh does not straighten out," he said.</p>

<p>He also urged the Indian government to take up the issue with Bangladesh and consider imposing sanctions if the persecution continues. "If they keep harassing Hindus and minorities, India should also impose sanctions on them," he said.</p>

<p>In a statement days before the November 5 general elections, Trump condemned the attack on Hindus in violence-hit Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"I strongly condemn the barbaric violence against Hindus, Christians, and other minorities who are getting attacked and looted by mobs in Bangladesh, which remains in a total state of chaos," Trump said.</p>

<p>"It would have never happened on my watch. Kamala and Joe have ignored Hindus across the world and in America. They have been a disaster from Israel to Ukraine to our own Southern Border, but we will Make America Strong Again and bring back Peace through Strength," then said.</p>

<p>"We will also protect Hindu Americans against the anti-religion agenda of the radical left. We will fight for your freedom. Under my administration," he said.</p>

<p>Barai said a lot of people are talking about external interference in the overthrow of a democratically elected government in Bangladesh. "Even among the Muslims now, there is a split. Some think that the Democrats engineered this coup in their countries, both Pakistan as well as Bangladesh," he said.</p>

<p>He pointed to figures such as George Soros and Peter Omidyar, suggesting they were part of a broader agenda to undermine Narendra Modi's leadership and promote Rahul Gandhi.</p>

<p>"If you remember that when President Trump visited India about three and a half years ago, riots were engineered, especially in Delhi, to coincide with his visit," he said.</p>

<p>He also expressed frustration with the influence of the "ultra-leftist woke lobby", saying he hoped they would either come to their senses or be sidelined or "put in their proper place".</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/iaal0ilo_donald-trump_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian Americans to urge the new Trump administration to seek action against Bangladesh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-does-spacexs-starship-has-a-banana-sticker-explained-7032302]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Put A Banana Sticker On Its Starship. Heres Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-does-spacexs-starship-has-a-banana-sticker-explained-7032302]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 12:54:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[SpaceX intends to launch Starship on November 19 within a 30-minute window starting at 3.30 am IST.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">SpaceX's sixth test flight on November 19, while promising ground-breaking experiments, also features an unexpected addition. The first stage of the rocket at the launch pad in Boca Chica, Texas bears a sticker, featuring a banana holding a tiny banana.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The sticker is a comical reference to the well-known "banana for scale" meme on the internet, which has been widely used to show the true-to-life size of another object by comparing it to a banana.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Starship moved to the pad at Starbase in advance of our sixth flight test <a href="https://t.co/u6Mbc35ARr">pic.twitter.com/u6Mbc35ARr</a></p>
— SpaceX (@SpaceX) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1856424581948682324?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">The meme is based on the notion that, in situations where measuring instruments are not available, a banana can serve as an approximate sense of scale because it is a widely recognised and reasonably standard-sized object.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">For instance, the rocket consists of the upper stage, known as Starship, and a huge first-stage booster called Super Heavy. With the two elements stacked, the rocket stands nearly 400 feet (122 m) tall. Considering its size, it is understandable why SpaceX chose to use the banana sticker to parody this scale challenge.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Even though the banana meme might get some attention, Starship's sixth test flight has more important goals in mind.</p>

<p dir="ltr">SpaceX intends to launch Starship on November 19 within a 30-minute window starting at 3.30 am IST.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The mission will test a number of important elements, such as a novel method for using a tower to collect the Super Heavy booster and sophisticated heatshield studies intended to enhance the rocket's reentry capabilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Furthermore, Starship will attempt several maneuvers during its atmospheric reentry over the Indian Ocean.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rlvtglao_spacex-banana_625x300_16_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-message-to-us-no-intent-to-assassinate-donald-trump-7031975]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's Message To US: No Intent To Assassinate Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-message-to-us-no-intent-to-assassinate-donald-trump-7031975]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 12:26:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran has sent a message to the Joe Biden administration denying any plans to kill Donald Trump. This development comes after the Biden administration warned Iran in September that any attempt on Mr Trump's life would be considered "an act of war".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Iran has sent a message to the Joe Biden administration denying any plans to kill Donald Trump. This development comes after the Biden administration warned Iran in September that any attempt on Mr Trump's life would be considered “an act of war,” the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/15/world/middleeast/iran-trump-assassinate.html " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">NY Times</a> reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The message, sent in October through an intermediary, was intended to ease tensions between Washington and Tehran. It followed a stern warning from the US, which had expressed grave concerns over potential Iranian retaliation for the killing of Maj. Gen. Qassim Suleimani in 2020, a move ordered by then-President Donald Trump.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Since Donald Trump's election victory on November 5, various Iranian officials, analysts, and media outlets have advocated for a more conciliatory approach with the president-elect, despite ongoing pressure from his allies to renew a hardline stance against Iran.</p>

<p dir="ltr">US officials have suggested that Iran may have sought revenge for Suleimani's death by targeting Mr Trump, citing <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3rd-assassination-attempt-iran-man-charged-with-plotting-to-kill-trump-6977316 ">two indictments related to Iranian plots against the&nbsp;President-elect</a>. Further accusations have surfaced regarding other figures from the Trump administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to the US officials, the Iranian message focused on Tehran's position that the killing of General Suleimani was a criminal act. However, the communication also clarified that Iran had no intention of killing Trump. This message was confirmed by an Iranian official and analyst who engages with both sides. Iran, they said, expressed its desire to pursue justice for Suleimani's death through international legal channels rather than through violent means.</p>

<p dir="ltr">While the US officials noted that the message was not from any specific Iranian official, the Iranian official and analyst revealed that it was, in fact, from Iran's Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei. Iran's mission to the United Nations declined to comment but issued a statement reaffirming Tehran's commitment to addressing Suleimani's killing "through legal and judicial avenues."</p>

<p dir="ltr">Earlier, during the presidential campaign, American officials had warned of a potential Iranian plot to assassinate Donald Trump. Federal prosecutors in Manhattan recently confirmed that discussions among Iranian plotters had included plans to target the former president. However, Iran's Foreign Ministry rejected these claims as unfounded.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Elon Musk, a close ally of Mr Trump, met with Iran's ambassador to the United Nations on Monday at Mr Musk's request. The Iranians described the meeting with Ambassador Amir Saied Iravani, held in New York City at a secret location, as part of an effort to reduce tensions between the US and Iran under the Donald Trump administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The US and Iran have not had official diplomatic relations since the 1979 revolution, during which 52 Americans were taken hostage at the US embassy in Tehran. The Swiss embassy in Tehran serves as the official diplomatic liaison between the two countries, though direct and indirect talks have taken place in recent years on various issues, including Iran's nuclear program and the swapping of detainees.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The messages exchanged between the US and Iran were sent through the Swiss, according to the Iranian official and analyst.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i2utsi1_ayatollah-khamenei-trump-_625x300_16_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk, a close ally of Mr Trump, met with Iran's ambassador to the United Nations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/possibility-of-catastrophic-failure-nasa-worried-about-space-station-leak-problem-7032080]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why A Leak Problem On International Space Station Has NASA Worried]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/possibility-of-catastrophic-failure-nasa-worried-about-space-station-leak-problem-7032080]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 12:15:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The space station having a size equal to a football field must remain pressurised and filled with breathable gases at all times.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A segment of the International Space Station (ISS), controlled by Russia, has been leaking for a few years now, allowing air and pressure to move out.</p>

<p dir="ltr">With the situation reaching a fever pitch, cosmonauts are scrambling to work on the problem areas, while officials from NASA and Roscosmos continue to disagree over the severity of the problem, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/15/science/international-space-station-leak-nasa-russia/index.html">CNN </a>reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The space station having a size equal to a football field must remain pressurised and filled with breathable gases at all times so that the rotating crew of astronauts can continue to survive. It has separate but connected Russian and US sections.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In 2019, the problematic leaks were identified for the first time in a tunnel connecting Zvezda, a Russian module, to the docking port which welcomes spacecraft that carry cargo and supplies. However, this year the rate at which it is bleeding air has hit a new high.</p>

<p dir="ltr">As per the latest report by NASA's Office of Inspector General, oversight officials in the country consider this issue as the most pressing problem that the space station faces, threatening the crew's safety.</p>

<p dir="ltr">During a meeting on the issue on Wednesday, former NASA astronaut Bob Cabana, chair of the US space agency's ISS Advisory Committee, noted that it has "expressed concerns about the structural integrity of the (leaking module) and the possibility of a catastrophic failure”.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Although Roscosmos has asked cosmonauts to address the problematic areas, their team “does not believe catastrophic disintegration... is realistic,” Cabana noted.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Cabana stated that the Russians believe that continued operations are safe, however, they are unable to "prove that to our satisfaction".</p>

<p dir="ltr">"And the US believes that it's not safe, but we can't prove that to the Russian satisfaction," he added.</p>

<p dir="ltr">These disagreements persist even after a meeting that took place in Russia in September this year. The US, meanwhile, is pushing for independent experts from the two sides to evaluate this issue to help them reach a consensus on the root cause.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Cabana claimed that Russia is yet to comply with the recommendation, while the US already has taken steps to create its team of experts.</p>

<p dir="ltr">At the space station, both astronauts and cosmonauts have been asked to adopt precautionary measures like keeping the leaking segment sealed off at all times, except for times when it can open to unpacking cargo from spacecraft arriving at a nearby docking port. But they have to close the hatch that separates the US and Russian portions during this time, NASA astronaut Michael Barratt said on November 8.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In a statement, NASA informed that the cracks are “very small, not visible with the naked eye and have brackets and pipelines near them, making it difficult to get diagnostic tools into these areas”. The leak rate ranges between "2 to 2.5 pounds (of air) per day above space station baseline”.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/ng9r0t5o_international-space-station-reuters_625x300_28_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-suggests-digital-hoarding-may-be-a-sign-of-disorder-7032062]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Storing Excess Digital Data A Sign of Distress, Say Experts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-suggests-digital-hoarding-may-be-a-sign-of-disorder-7032062]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 12:12:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Like physical hoarding, digital hoarding can also be detrimental to your mental health, experts say.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">While many people tend to keep excess stuff in their homes or storage areas, the new phenomenon of "digital hoarding" describes those who can't manage to thin out their online photo albums or clean their inboxes. Like physical hoarding, digital hoarding can also be detrimental to your mental health, experts say.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“It's something that triggers a lot of stress and anxiety, the collection of emails, pictures, open tabs — an overwhelming number of digital items that trigger overload,” said Dr Susan Albers, a clinical psychologist at the Cleveland Clinic in Ohio to <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/15/health/digital-hoarding-clutter-wellness/index.html">CNN</a>.</p>

<p dir="ltr">She added, “What's interesting about it is that this isn't the type of problem that our ancestors have had to face, but when we fast-forward to today, our daily life is really plagued with a lot of digital clutter.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">It's possible that everyone who uses a digital gadget will eventually encounter this kind of clutter. However, occasionally, the typical practice can degenerate into a disorder—digital hoarding—that more academics are attempting to comprehend.</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to Dr. Emanuel Maidenberg, a clinical professor of psychiatry and biobehavioral sciences at UCLA's David Geffen School of Medicine, the urge to hoard may stem from one's wish to preserve memories with photographs or keep unnecessary records and files from previous employment or college courses as a precaution. All of this can be considered digital hoarding.</p>

<p dir="ltr">He said, “It becomes a habit that is motivated by anxiety, and that's when it becomes challenging and difficult. It has to do with the fear of needing this information at some point in the future and yet not having access to it and not knowing where to find it.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to a 2019 study that polled hundreds of adults in the UK, hoarding is a prevalent workplace practice and is thought to be linked to obsessive-compulsive disorder. There are four different sorts of digital hoarding, according to a 2020 follow-up study: organized people, disorganized people, people who hold digital information for their companies, and people who keep it away from people they care about and are frequently afraid of losing it.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Storing digital clutter that crosses over into a disorder depends on the individual, but a key factor is when it causes significant distress or impairment in everyday functioning, said Dr. Sanjaya Saxena, psychiatrist and director of clinical and research affairs at the Boston-based International OCD Foundation.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Dr. Susan Albers believes decluttering is the magic wand for your mental well-being. She suggests setting aside a short period of time every morning to perform a digital audit, eliminating unnecessary emails and other notifications. The remainder of your day will be far more productive if you take a few minutes to tidy up before you begin working.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ivkss2qo_devices_625x300_16_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-students-being-put-off-applying-to-uk-universities-report-7032008]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Students Being Put Off Applying To UK Universities: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-students-being-put-off-applying-to-uk-universities-report-7032008]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 12:05:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian students are being put off applying to UK universities, adding to their financial woes at a time when education institutions are already coping with constrained budgets, a new report into the stability of the higher education sector in England]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian students are being put off applying to UK universities, adding to their financial woes at a time when education institutions are already coping with constrained budgets, a new report into the stability of the higher education sector in England has revealed.</p>

<p>Based on UK Home Office data on confirmation of acceptance for studies (CAS) by UK providers from 2022-23 to 2023-24, an Office for Students (OfS) analysis released on Friday shows a 20.4 per cent drop in Indian student numbers - down from 139,914 to 111,329.</p>

<p>Indian student groups in the UK said the fall was to be expected amid limited job prospects and also safety concerns following recent anti-immigration riots in some cities.</p>

<p>"There has been a considerable decline in student visa applications from prospective non-UK students in some major source countries," notes the report by OfS, a non-departmental public body of the government's Department for Education.</p>

<p>"This data shows an 11.8 per cent decline in the total number of sponsor acceptances issued to international students, as well as considerable variation for students with different nationalities, with the largest declines reported in the number of CAS issued to Indian and Nigerian students, down 28,585 (20.4 per cent) and 25,897 (44.6 per cent) respectively," it said.</p>

<p>It warns that universities with financial models that depend heavily on students from countries such as India, Nigeria and Bangladesh are likely to be significantly affected due to this downward trend.</p>

<p>"The number of international students from certain countries that send significant numbers to study in the UK has decreased significantly," OfS cautions.</p>

<p>"By 2025-26, based on current trends and not taking into account significant mitigating action, we estimate a net income reduction for the sector of GBP 3,445 million, and, without significant mitigating actions, a sector-level deficit of minus GBP 1,636 million, with up to 72 per cent of providers being in deficit, and 40 per cent having low liquidity," it adds.</p>

<p>The Indian National Students' Association (INSA) UK said it was not surprised with the significant decrease in students from India given the government's clampdown on foreign students being allowed to bring along their dependent partners and spouses.</p>

<p>"Students are not allowed to bring their partners to the UK under the new policy and given the economic conditions here and recent rioting stories, unless the government addresses this issue the outlook for UK universities is bleak as they rely heavily on Indian students," said INSA UK President Amit Tiwari.</p>

<p>Indians overtook the Chinese in recent years as the leading nationality granted study visas to the UK and are the largest cohort to access the Graduate Route post-study work visa, which was thrown into disarray due to a review which has since concluded it is here to stay.</p>

<p>"Many reasons contribute to the decline in numbers, including the Conservative ban on dependents, confusion around post-study work visa, increase in skilled worker salary thresholds and an apparent lack of jobs in the UK," said Sanam Arora, chair of the National Indian Students and Alumni Union (NISAU) UK.</p>

<p>"We discovered the scale of misinformation that continues to persist; for the first time, safety is also being raised as a concern... Universities need to ensure that they are communicating the UK offer adequately and at scale in India to address the confusions that persist," she said.</p>

<p>"Universities also need to invest significantly in their employability support in order to stay competitive and provide a wholesome, outcome-oriented offer for students," she added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/eggu3rps_university-of-oxford_625x300_26_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An Office for Students analysis shows a 20.4 per cent drop in Indian student numbers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-fighter-pilots-recall-missiles-running-dry-during-iranian-drone-attack-on-israel-7031826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Ran Out Of Missiles": US Fighter Pilots Recall Iran's Attack On Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-fighter-pilots-recall-missiles-running-dry-during-iranian-drone-attack-on-israel-7031826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 11:35:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The F-15 fighter pilots from the US have recounted how they ran out of air-to-air missiles and switched to guns during the massive Iranian attack on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The F-15 fighter pilots from the US have recounted how they ran out of air-to-air missiles and switched to guns during the massive Iranian attack on Israel. In April this year, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attacks-israel-with-missiles-and-drones-a-timeline-of-the-conflict-5438278">Iran fired more than 300 drones</a>, ballistic and cruise missiles on Israel, a far larger strike than the US military anticipated.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Major Benjamin “Irish” Coffey, an F-15 fighter pilot, has recalled how he was not expecting to run out of missiles while taking on the Iranian attack.</p>

<p dir="ltr">While they were instructed to use every weapon at their disposal to help Israel, Major Coffey and his crew-mate, weapons systems officer Captain Lacie “Sonic” Hester soon came up with a plan when they ran out of air-to-air missiles.</p>

<p dir="ltr">They recalled how they flew as close as they could to an Iranian drone — way below the minimum safe altitude for the F-15 Strike Eagle — and used a gun against a target that was barely visible. This was an extremely dangerous maneuver for the pilots in total darkness. However, they still ended up missing the target.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“You feel the terrain rush, you feel yourself getting closer and closer to the ground. The risk was just too high to try again," Major Coffey told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/15/politics/american-fighter-pilots-describe-taking-down-iranian-drones/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In the end, the US forces, both in the air as well as at sea, were able to intercept 70 drones and three ballistic missiles during the attack, which was largely thwarted.</p>

<p dir="ltr">This was the US Air Force's maiden “real test” against a prolonged and large-scale drone attack as the fighters spent multiple hours in the air that night.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The situation was equally chaotic at the undisclosed US military base in the Middle East as the air defenses there had shot down Iranian missiles and drones overhead, while troops were rushed to bunkers.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The attack by Iran was in retaliation for Israel's attack on the Iranian consulate building in Syria, leaving several members of Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps dead.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Captain Hester said that when they were getting briefed that night, they "had no idea” about what could have happened.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Sharing his thoughts, F-15 pilot Lieutenant Colonel Timothy “Diesel” Causey added that they did not have much time before then to practice. He went on to call the attack drones a "low cost, low risk for the enemy to employ."</p>

<p dir="ltr">The weapons of the fighter jets were depleted quickly as the F-15E Strike Eagle is able to carry only eight air-to-air missiles at a time. “We ran out of missiles pretty quickly…20 minutes maybe," said F-15 pilot Lieutenant Colonel Curtis “Voodoo” Culver.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/np9d7e3o_israel-offensive-against-iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran fired over 300 drones, ballistic and cruise missiles on Israel in April.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-the-challenges-facing-donald-trumps-key-cabinet-picks-7031717]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Challenges Facing Donald Trump's Key Cabinet Picks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-the-challenges-facing-donald-trumps-key-cabinet-picks-7031717]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 11:33:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump is reportedly looking into a clause in the US Constitution that allows a president to make unilateral appointments if the Senate is not in session.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">US President-elect Donald Trump's latest cabinet picks are facing opposition from various quarters, with some of his key hires set to undergo further vetting, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/14/politics/trump-controversial-cabinet-picks/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a> reported. While many of the Republican leader's personnel decisions are immediate, several will need Senate approval, which includes a hearing and the approval of a majority in the chamber.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Now, Trump is reportedly looking into a clause in the US Constitution that allows a president to make unilateral appointments if the Senate is not in session, as per <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg7r5e3gz7o" rel="nofollow,noindex">The BBC</a>.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>How does Senate vetting work?</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">More than 1,000 positions, including the Cabinet, ambassadors, and some lower-level roles, require Senate approval. However, many of Donald Trump's team members, such as those in the White House or as national security advisers, do not need Senate approval but still go through a vetting process, which may involve FBI background checks.</p>

<p dir="ltr">On Thursday, incoming Senate Majority Leader John Thune said on Fox News, "None of this is gonna be easy." The FBI checks nominees for Senate-confirmed roles and other national security positions but does not provide an opinion on the results, leaving that to the president-elect or White House Counsel. Donald Trump's transition team has reportedly <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-s-team-bypasses-fbi-background-checks-for-some-cabinet-picks-7031432">bypassed FBI checks for some cabinet picks</a> and is considering private vetting companies.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The Senate approval process involves submitting financial disclosure forms, completing role-specific questionnaires, and testifying before a Senate committee. The committee votes on the nomination, and the full Senate then votes. Cabinet appointments are usually approved quickly, but political conflicts can lead to intense battles and even rejections. With Republicans controlling both chambers of Congress, some disputes may be less intense, although concerns about nominees like Matt Gaetz for Attorney General have already surfaced.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>What are recess appointments?</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">A recess appointment allows the president to make temporary appointments when Congress is not in session. These appointments are usually temporary, expiring at the end of a congressional session. Donald Trump has expressed interest in using this power to bypass Senate approval, but it is not guaranteed, as Congress would need to agree to a recess.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The recess process was originally intended for emergencies when Congress did not meet as frequently as it does now. The goal was to ensure that presidents could fill important roles without delay.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Donald Trump's plan to use recess appointments and bypass Senate vetting has historical precedent. Former presidents, including George W. Bush (171 recess appointments), Bill Clinton (139), and Barack Obama (32), have employed this method, often to bypass political gridlock.</p>

<p dir="ltr">However, the use of recess appointments was curbed after the Supreme Court struck down several of Obama's appointments in 2014, calling them unconstitutional.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>When can Trump make recess appointments?</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">The President-elect can make recess appointments in two ways. First, if the Senate agrees to a recess of 10 days or more by majority vote. Second, if the House votes for a longer recess, Trump could use a rare constitutional power to adjourn both chambers of Congress.</p>

<p dir="ltr">However, Trump cannot make these appointments until after his inauguration on January 20. This power has never been used before, and it's unclear how it would play out. Trump would need unanimous consent from all 100 senators to force a recess longer than 10 days, which is challenging given that Democrats hold 47 seats. To override opposition, Republicans would need at least seven Democratic votes or a change to the filibuster, which Senate Majority Leader John Thune has opposed.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Donald Trump's Cabinet picks so far</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Secretary of State: Marco Rubio</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Attorney General: Matt Gaetz</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Director of National Intelligence: Tulsi Gabbard</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Secretary of Defense: Pete Hegseth</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Secretary of Homeland Security: Kristi Noem</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">CIA Director: John Ratcliffe</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Secretary of Health and Human Services: Robert F. Kennedy Jr.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Secretary of Veterans Affairs: Doug Collins</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">EPA Administrator: Lee Zeldin</p>
	</li>
</ul>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>White House staff</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Chief of Staff: Susie Wiles</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Border Czar: Tom Homan</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Deputy Chief of Staff for Policy: Stephen Miller</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Deputy Chief of Staff: Dan Scavino</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Deputy Chief of Staff: James Blair</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Deputy Chief of Staff: Taylor Budowich</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">White House Counsel: William McGinley</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Special Envoy to the Middle East: Steven Witkoff</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Ambassador to Israel: Mike Huckabee</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Ambassador to the United Nations: Elise Stefanik</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Press Secretary: Karoline Leavitt</p>
	</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/leckf9eo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamy-indicates-massive-government-job-cuts-in-us-7031780]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy Indicates Massive Government Job Cuts In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamy-indicates-massive-government-job-cuts-in-us-7031780]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 11:28:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Entrepreneur-turned politician Vivek Ramaswamy, who along with Tesla owner Elon Musk has been nominated in-charge of the Department of Government Efficiency, has indicated a massive cut in federal government jobs in the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Entrepreneur-turned politician Vivek Ramaswamy, who along with Tesla owner Elon Musk has been nominated in-charge of the Department of Government Efficiency, has indicated a massive cut in federal government jobs in the United States.</p>

<p>"Elon Musk and I are in a position to start the mass deportations of millions of unelected federal bureaucrats out of the DC bureaucracy. That, too, is how we're going to save this country," Ramaswamy, an Indian American, said at an event in Mar-a-Lago in Florida on Thursday.</p>

<p>"I don't know if you've got to know Elon yet, but he doesn't bring a chisel. He brings a chainsaw. We are going to be taking it to that bureaucracy. It's going to be a lot of fun," he said.</p>

<p>"We've been taught to believe over the last four years that we have become a nation in decline, that we're at the end of the ancient Roman Empire. All we have is to fight over the scraps of some shrinking pie. I don't think we have to stay as that nation in decline. I think with what happened last week, we're back to being a nation in our ascent. A nation whose best days are actually still ahead of us," Ramaswamy said.</p>

<p>"It is going to be morning in America, the start of a new dawn, the start of a country where our kids are going to grow up and we're going to tell them and mean it, that you get ahead in the United States again with your own hard work and commitment and dedication, that you're free to speak your mind at every step of the way, that the best person gets the job regardless of their colour," he said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Musk and Ramaswamy announced that they will livestream every week to update the American public on the progress of the works by the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE).</p>

<p>"Our goal is to shave the size of government and to be as transparent as possible with the public. Weekly 'Dogecasts' will start soon," Ramaswamy said.</p>

<p>"DOGE's job is to create a government of a size and scope that our Founders would be proud of. Elon Musk and I look forward to fulfilling the mandate given to us by President Trump," he said.</p>

<p>Ramaswamy, however, argued that too much bureaucracy means less innovation and higher costs. "That's a real problem with the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA), Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), and countless other 3-letter agencies," he said, adding, "They are utterly agnostic to how their daily decisions stifle new inventions and impose costs that deter growth." "We are assembling the brightest minds in the country. This is the equivalent of a modern Manhattan Project. I think the major problem holding our country back is a federal bureaucracy. Target that cost, save the money, restore self-governance," Ramaswamy said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8458ie5o_vivek-ramaswamy-reuters_625x300_15_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ramaswamy and Musk will head the Department of Government Efficiency.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/long-lost-sea-creature-found-photobombing-tiny-seahorses-7031543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Long-Lost Sea Creatures, That Disappeared 70 Years Ago, Make A Comeback]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/long-lost-sea-creature-found-photobombing-tiny-seahorses-7031543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:47:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The worms were found coexisting with the seahorses in coral colonies from Australia to Japan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A species of marine that scientists lost sight of for almost 70 years recently made its comeback when researchers discovered evidence of a certain ocean worm's existence in images taken by scuba divers. The worms were found coexisting with the seahorses in coral colonies from Australia to Japan, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/15/science/lost-marine-worm-species-photobombs-seahorses/index.html">CNN</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The long-lost worm is Haplosyllis anthogorgicola, a type of polychaete or bristle worm. It burrows inside branching gorgonian corals at a density of up to 15 worms per cubic centimetre, and its usual size is no more than 0.24 inches (6 millimetres). However, scientists noted in the journal Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences that the animal hasn't been seen in the wild since 1956, when Huzio Utinomo, a marine biologist from Kyoto University, first identified it.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Chloé Fourreau, lead study author and a doctoral student in the Molecular Invertebrate Systematics and Ecology, or MISE, Laboratory at the University of the Ryukyus in Okinawa, Japan stated that finding these worms is very difficult because of their small size and near transparency, which make them nearly invisible underwater.</p>

<p dir="ltr">When the coral was collected and sent to the lab, the researchers discovered the coral was full of microscopic worms, each less than 0.2 inches long.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Once upon a time my friend and labmate Ai, who studies pygmy seahorses, brought me a worm she found on the coral host of the seahorse…???????? <a href="https://t.co/VBf69UPirh">pic.twitter.com/VBf69UPirh</a></p>
— Chloé Fourreau (@ChaoticChloeia) <a href="https://twitter.com/ChaoticChloeia/status/1856887221321712102?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">The images were originally taken to study the pygmy seahorses that also live among the coral.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fou1e464_worm_625x300_16_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Finding these worms is very difficult because of their small size and near transparency.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-frontier-airlines-after-scalding-beverage-leaves-his-genitals-disfigured-7031484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Sues Frontier Airlines After Hot Drink Leaves His Genitals Disfigured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-frontier-airlines-after-scalding-beverage-leaves-his-genitals-disfigured-7031484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:33:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Miller had requested hot tea during cabin service when the 'scalding' hot water, filled to the brim, was handed to him in a "negligent fashion".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US man has sued Frontier Airlines for $150,000 in damages after he was left with third-degree burns and 'disfiguring scars' on his penis, testicles and thighs after hot tea was splashed on him, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/frontier-flight-passenger-sues-tea-damages-b2648081.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Independent</em></a>. The man, identified as Sean Miller was flying home from Myrtle Beach, South Carolina when the scalding drink left him injured. He was immediately rushed to the hospital upon landing and later transferred to an area burn centre for specialised treatment due to the severity of the wounds.</p>

<p>As per the lawsuit filed in the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, Mr Miller had requested hot tea during cabin service when the 'scalding' hot water, filled to the brim, was handed to him in a "negligent fashion". The liquid was at an "unsafely and unreasonably high temperature" and "without any form of a lid", the suit added.</p>

<p>As per Adam S. Barrist, Mr Miller's attorney, his client has suffered discolouration on his penis, scrotum along with "significantly decreased sensation in his penis," "post-traumatic stress disorder," and "lack of self-esteem," plus at least one herniated disc.</p>

<p>"Due to the tightly-situated plane seat configuration, Mr Miller was unable to get up from his seat after the spill and, instead, was trapped in agonizing pain while his body was being burnt," Mr Barrist told the publication.</p>

<p>Mr Miller was reportedly forced to take off time from work after the incident and incurred "substantial" medical expenses, which added to his mental trauma, added Mr Barrist.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-girl-awarded-800-000-after-she-was-severely-burned-by-mcdonalds-chicken-nugget-4226834" rel="noindex, nofollow">Also read | US Girl Awarded $800,000 After She Was Severely Burned By McDonald's Chicken Nugget</a></p>

<p><strong>Woman sues EgyptAir</strong></p>

<p>This is not the first instance when a US citizen has sued an airline for spilling a hot beverage. Last week, 35-year-old Esraa Hezain sued EgyptAir for $5 million in damages as she suffered "second-degree burns" from a hot liquid splashed on her.</p>

<p>As per the Brooklyn federal court documents, the incident took place in February earlier this year as the beverage, kept in a "lidless cup" of tea flew off a "defective" seat tray and splashed over her. Hezain's attorney, Abram Bohrer said his client had suffered second-degree burns to her lower abdomen, her right inner thigh and buttocks. "For the price of a lid this didn't have to happen," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/914842qo_frontier-airlines_625x300_07_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Miller is seeking $150,000 in damages for his injuries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-s-win-sparks-user-shift-from-elon-musk-s-x-to-bluesky-created-by-twitter-co-founder-7031439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Millions Leave Musk's X After Trump Win, Shift To Jack Dorsey's Bluesky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-s-win-sparks-user-shift-from-elon-musk-s-x-to-bluesky-created-by-twitter-co-founder-7031439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:28:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With a similar colour scheme and logo, Bluesky is gaining traction as a decentralised alternative to X, attracting around one million new users daily]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">In the wake of Donald Trump's win in the US elections, users are abandoning Elon Musk's X for Bluesky, a rival social media platform. With a similar colour scheme and logo, Bluesky is gaining traction as a decentralised alternative, attracting around one million new users daily.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Currently, the social media platform has 16.7 million users, though this figure is rapidly climbing. But what exactly is Bluesky, and why is it becoming a refuge for those leaving X?</p>

<h3 dir="ltr"><strong>What is Bluesky?</strong></h3>

<p dir="ltr">Bluesky describes itself as "social media as it should be." The platform offers familiar features like search, notifications, and reposting but stands apart with its decentralised design.</p>

<p dir="ltr">This setup allows users to host their data on servers outside the company's control. While most users opt for the standard ".bsky.social" username, the platform also offers the option to create custom domains, adding a layer of personalization.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In functionality, Bluesky mirrors the original Twitter (now X) experience.</p>

<h3 dir="ltr"><strong>Why X users are switching?</strong></h3>

<p dir="ltr">Bluesky's sudden surge in popularity can be traced back to when Republican Donald Trump's election victory spurred political division. Elon Musk's support for the president-elect and his anticipated involvement in his administration have driven many users to seek alternatives.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">it's official — 1,000,000 people have joined Bluesky in just the last day!!!<br />
<br />
welcome ?<a href="https://t.co/x6v5YW0WFT">https://t.co/x6v5YW0WFT</a><a href="https://t.co/ifpjZFpYsf">pic.twitter.com/ifpjZFpYsf</a></p>
— bluesky (@bluesky) <a href="https://twitter.com/bluesky/status/1857225667206939034?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Organisations like&nbsp;The Guardian&nbsp;have also cited separate reasons for leaving X, calling it "a toxic media platform."</p>

<p dir="ltr">Celebrities have further fuelled Bluesky's momentum. Popular figures such as Lizzo, Ben Stiller, Jamie Lee Curtis, and Patton Oswalt have joined the platform, some reducing or ending their presence on X entirely.</p>

<h3 dir="ltr"><strong>Who owns Bluesky?</strong></h3>

<p dir="ltr">Jack Dorsey, the former head of Twitter, founded Bluesky with the vision of creating a decentralised Twitter-like platform. But Mr Dorsey stepped down from the Bluesky board in May 2024 and deleted his account in September.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Today, Bluesky is led by CEO Jay Graber and operates as a US public benefit corporation, as per The BBC.</p>

<h3 dir="ltr"><strong>Bluesky marketing</strong></h3>

<p dir="ltr">Unlike X, Bluesky has avoided traditional advertising. The platform initially raised funds through investors and venture capital and is now exploring paid services like custom domain names for usernames.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Bluesky is rapidly growing but still has a long way to go before challenging X, which Elon Musk claims has 250 million daily active users.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9octtu0g_bluesky-_625x300_16_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bluesky currently has 16.7 million users]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-s-team-bypasses-fbi-background-checks-for-some-cabinet-picks-7031432]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Team Avoids FBI Background Checks For Some Cabinet Picks: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-s-team-bypasses-fbi-background-checks-for-some-cabinet-picks-7031432]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:22:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump and his allies feel that the FBI system is "slow," besides being plagued with issues which might prevent him from immediately starting the work of implementing his agenda, people close to the transition planning said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">US President-elect Donald Trump's transition team has reportedly taken help from private companies to conduct vetting of potential candidates for administrative roles. The team has bypassed the traditional background checks through the FBI for some of Mr Trump's Cabinet picks.</p>

<p dir="ltr">People close to the transition planning told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/15/politics/security-clearances-fbi-gabbard-gaetz/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a> that Donald Trump and his allies feel that the system of the law enforcement agency is "slow," besides being plagued with issues which might prevent him from immediately starting the work of implementing his agenda.</p>

<p dir="ltr">However, critics have said that the intrusive background checks at times bring to the fore embarrassing information that can be used to inflict political damage.</p>

<p dir="ltr">This comes after the President-elect has floated some controversial choices for the high-level positions in the new US government, including Tulsi Gabbard as the new Director of National Intelligence and Matt Gaetz for Attorney General.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In the US, the president, ultimately, has the final authority on whom he/she wants to nominate to share intelligence with, regardless of the established protocol that was set in the wake of the Second World War to ensure the ones selected do not have any unknown foreign ties as well as other issues which may raise national security concerns.</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to CNN, bypassing the background checks could be bucking a long-established norm in Washington as it reflects the deep mistrust Trump has of the national security establishment that he derides as the 'Deep State'.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Sources have said Mr Trump has privately questioned the requirement for law enforcement background checks.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The incoming Trump administration “doesn't want harmony,” said Dan Meyer, a national security attorney in Washington, DC, adding that they “don't want the FBI to coordinate a norm; they want to hammer the norm”.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Before the November 5 presidential election, some advisers of Donald Trump circulated a memo urging him to bypass the traditional background check process for a few appointees, a person briefed on the memo noted.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The memo proposed hiring private researchers rather than taking help of the law enforcement as they could move more quickly to perform the task. However, Trump can always decide to eventually submit these names to the FBI.</p>

<p dir="ltr">A few names announced by Mr Trump for various roles in his administration might get into trouble during the background check, which could pose a potential hurdle during the confirmation process.</p>

<p dir="ltr">For multiple years, Matt Gaetz has been mired in the US Justice Department as well as House ethics investigations in connection with sex trafficking. On his behalf, he has denied any wrongdoing.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, Tulsi Gabbard has often appeared to take position that favour foreign leaders like presidents of Syria and Russia, raising questions from critics.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In 2017, she met with Syrian President Bashar al-Assad in Syria and even said that he was “not an enemy" of the US.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0g874728_donald-trump-afp-_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bypassing the background checks could be bucking a long-established norm in Washington.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-willing-be-partners-friends-with-us-chinese-envoy-7031427]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["China Willing To Be Partners, Friends With US": Chinese Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-willing-be-partners-friends-with-us-chinese-envoy-7031427]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:21:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China is willing to be partners and friends with the United States, China's ambassador to Washington said, seeking to strengthen dialogue between the world's two largest economies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China is willing to be partners and friends with the United States, China's ambassador to Washington said, seeking to strengthen dialogue between the world's two largest economies.</p>

<p>China has no plan to surpass or replace the United States, Xie Feng said in a speech in Hong Kong on Friday, addressing Chinese officials and the U.S. ambassador to China.</p>

<p>The Sino-US partnership is never a zero-sum game, Xie said, adding that the two nations have great potential to work together on areas including trade, agriculture, energy, artificial intelligence, and public health.</p>

<p>"China and the United States have concerns for each side," Xie said. "It is entirely possible to bring issues to the table to communicate frankly, seek solutions on an equal footing."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/ngtoubdg_joe-biden-xi-jinping_625x300_16_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China and the United States have concerns for each side, the envoy said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-jokes-he-may-go-to-space-station-to-rescue-sunita-williams-7031268]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Jokes He May Go To Space Station To Rescue Sunita Williams]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-jokes-he-may-go-to-space-station-to-rescue-sunita-williams-7031268]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:49:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Friday joked about going to space to "bring back" the stranded astronauts - referring to Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore, who have been at the International Space Station (ISS) since June.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Friday joked about going to space to "bring back" the stranded astronauts - referring to Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore, who have been at the International Space Station (ISS) since June due to a Starliner spacecraft malfunction.</p>

<p>Biden made the comments while discussing space exploration with Peru President Dina Boluarte Zegarra at a bilateral meeting.</p>

<p>Stating that the US and Peru are cooperating on space exploration, Biden laughingly said, "Now, that fellow right there...the former senator from Florida (pointing to NASA administrator Bill Nelson) - a very close friend of mine - every time my wife thinks I'm getting out of hand, she says that she is going to call him and have him send me to space."</p>

<p>"And I'm a little concerned he may want to send me to space because we got to get some folks back home," the 81-year-old President said as he laughed.</p>

<p>Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams and her <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-good-health-nasa-amid-reports-of-sunita-williams-declining-health-6966297">NASA</a> counterpart Barry Willmore have been at the ISS for nearly five months. They were launched aboard Boeing's Starliner spacecraft on June 5 for its first crewed flight and landed at the space station on June 6. It was supposed to be an eight-day mission but now has been stretched into months as they faced space debris threats, helium leaks, and technical glitches on the Starliner spacecraft.</p>

<p>According to NASA, it's too risky to bring the duo back to Earth currently on the malfunctioned capsule.</p>

<p>They will now return home in February next year.</p>

<p>Amid this, reports of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/my-body-has-changed-but-sunita-williams-on-her-health-aboard-space-station-7012028">Williams' health</a> deteriorating have been doing rounds after images of her "gaunt" appearance in space went viral. However, earlier this week, she put the rumors to rest in a video interview shared by NASA.</p>

<p>Williams asserted that her weight is the same as when she arrived at the ISS.</p>

<p>"I think my body has changed a little bit but I weigh the same. There are a lot of changes that go on here...It's funny, I think there are some rumours around that I am losing weight and stuff...No, I am actually right at the same amount. We go weigh ourselves, we have a spring mass...Butch and I weigh ourselves the same way that I was when I got up here," she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ouecshfo_biden_625x300_16_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden discussed space exploration with Peru President Dina Boluarte Zegarra at a bilateral meeting.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>