<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:16:51 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-camilla-keeps-prince-william-in-check-if-hes-disrespectful-reveals-new-book-6274241]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Queen Camilla Keeps Prince William In Check If He's Disrespectful, Says Book]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-camilla-keeps-prince-william-in-check-if-hes-disrespectful-reveals-new-book-6274241]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:16:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[These claims came from royal author Rob Jobson in his upcoming book, "Catherine, the Princess of Wales".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Queen Camilla subtly reminds Prince William and keeps him in check whenever she feels that he is not respecting his father, a new book has claimed, as per a report in the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/05/entertainment/queen-camilla-keeps-prince-william-in-check-when-hes-disrespectful-book/">New York Post</a></em>. These claims came from royal author Rob Jobson in his upcoming book, "Catherine, the Princess of Wales".&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an excerpt from his book, Mr Jobson discussed a specific instance in which Prince William and his wife, Kate Middleton, requested to be included in the security convoy of King Charles and Queen Camilla as they headed out of Windsor Castle. However, the younger royals kept the King and Queen waiting. This did not sit well with Queen Camilla, who then took a “subtle” jab at the Cambridges.</p>

<p>The book explains, "When Charles was kept waiting several minutes for the couple, Camilla insisted they go without them. As William and Catherine emerged, all they could see were the blue flashing lights of the motorbikes disappearing in the distance."</p>

<p>According to the <em>BBC</em>, this revelation comes at a time when the 77-year-old Queen Camilla and Prince William have grown “much closer” amid King Charles and Kate's cancer diagnosis. “They have been left, almost literally, nursing the crown while the king and the princess recover,” BBC royal correspondent Jennie Bond told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ok.co.uk/royal/queen-camilla-prince-william-royal-32356261"><em>OK! magazine.</em></a></p>

<p>“Times of adversity often bring people much closer together. For all the progress that has been made in cancer treatment, it is still a scary thing,” she said.</p>

<p>“And while Camilla and William put on a brave face for the world (and no doubt for their spouses, too), there may be times when they confide in one another about how they are dealing with it all,” Ms Bond added.</p>

<p>Further, she said that the 42-year-old Prince and his stepmother developed a close relationship after they saw several hardships together, including the death of Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip. “When the late queen died, William spoke of how (Camilla) had been at his side at ‘the happiest moments' and ‘saddest days of his life'. Now, Camilla is sharing some of those times with him, and it must surely cement their relationship,” the correspondent said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t8d1p53o_william-camilla_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[William and Queen Camilla developed a close relationship after they saw several hardships together.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/centre-not-to-relax-4-billion-tax-demands-for-infosys-report-6274117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Centre Not To Relax $4 Billion Tax Demand To Infosys: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/centre-not-to-relax-4-billion-tax-demands-for-infosys-report-6274117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:07:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The central government is not considering any relaxation over the 320 billion rupees ($4 billion) tax demand it sent to Infosys, according to a government source.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The central government is not considering any relaxation over the $4 billion tax demand it sent to Infosys, according to a government source.</p>

<p>The tax demand on Infosys is in accordance to the good and services tax rules and the country's second-largest IT services firm has sought 10 days to submit its response after meeting tax officials, the source said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/n7u94t2_infosys_625x300_12_January_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Infosys is India's second-largest IT services company (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-nahid-islam-the-student-leader-at-the-centre-of-the-bangladesh-protests-6274106]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Nahid Islam, Student Leader Who Led Protests Against Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-nahid-islam-the-student-leader-at-the-centre-of-the-bangladesh-protests-6274106]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:05:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After nearly a month of anti-quota and anti-government demonstrations that swept across Bangladesh, Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After nearly a month of anti-quota and anti-government demonstrations that swept across Bangladesh, Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country. Her resignation came in the face of countrywide demonstrations led by student leader Nahid Islam. What started as a call for reform in the country's quota policy for the families of freedom fighters slowly morphed into an anti-government movement demanding Sheikh Hasina's resignation. &nbsp;<br />
<br />
On Monday, protesters defied a nationwide curfew, stormed the Prime Minister's residence, and declared victory for the people's movement.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Some facts about student leader Nahid Islam:</strong><br />
<br />
1. Nahid Islam is currently a student in the Sociology Department at Dhaka University.&nbsp; He is known for his work as a human rights defender.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
2. He serves as one of the National Coordinators for the 'Students Against Discrimination' Movement, a student-led protest demanding reforms to the quota system in government jobs in Bangladesh. The movement began after the Supreme Court of Bangladesh reinstated a 30 per cent quota for descendants of war veterans and freedom fighters in June 2024. The movement argued the quota was a discriminatory and politically manipulated system to access government jobs.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
3. Mr Nahid has been vocal against Sheikh Hasina's party, the Awami League, describing them as "terrorists" deployed on the roads. Previously, addressing protesters at Shahbagh, he declared students had "picked up sticks today" and were ready to "take up arms" if sticks didn't work.<br />
<br />
4. On 19 July 2024, <a href="https://www.frontlinedefenders.org/en/profile/nahid-islam ">Nahid Islam was abducted</a> by at least 25 men in plain clothes from a house in Sabujbagh. He was blindfolded, handcuffed and tortured during repeated interrogations about his involvement in the protests. Two days later, he was found unconscious and battered under a bridge in Purbachal.<br />
<br />
5. Nahid Islam was kidnapped a second time on 26 July 2024 from Gonoshasthaya Nagar Hospital in Dhanmondi. Individuals claiming to be from various intelligence agencies, including the Dhaka Metropolitan Police's Detective Branch, took him away. However, the police have denied any involvement.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fk0gu7l_nahid-islam-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nahid Islam is currently a student in the Sociology Department at Dhaka University.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-supporter-who-rioted-at-us-capitol-to-get-his-spear-headdress-back-6273898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Supporter Who Rioted At US Capitol To Get His Spear, Headdress Back]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-supporter-who-rioted-at-us-capitol-to-get-his-spear-headdress-back-6273898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:00:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jacob Chansley, 36, known as the "QAnon Shaman," became one of the faces of the January 6, 2021 assault on the Capitol because of his red, white and blue face paint, bare chest and unusual headgear.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A self-proclaimed "shaman" who was among the Donald Trump supporters who breached the US Capitol can have his horned fur headdress and spear returned to him, a judge ruled on Monday.</p>

<p>Jacob Chansley, 36, known as the "QAnon Shaman," became one of the faces of the January 6, 2021 assault on the Capitol because of his red, white and blue face paint, bare chest and unusual headgear.</p>

<p>Chansley, also known as Jake Angeli, was among the first of hundreds of rioters to break into the Capitol on January 6, 2021 as lawmakers were certifying Democrat Joe Biden's victory over Trump in the 2020 presidential election.</p>

<p>He pleaded guilty to a single felony charge of obstructing an official proceeding and was sentenced to 41 months in prison, although he received an early release in May of last year.</p>

<p>In a lawsuit filed in Washington, Chansley asked a judge for the return of his property seized by the authorities following his arrest.</p>

<p>"Since the government has not established that it still needs these items as evidence and has not sought their forfeiture, the Court will grant Mr Chansley's motion," District Judge Royce Lamberth said.</p>

<p>The items to be returned include Chansley's "horned coyote-tail headdress" and a six-foot pole with a metal spearhead fixed to the top.</p>

<p>Before the January 6 riot, Chansley, a promoter of QAnon conspiracy theories, had traveled the country appearing at rallies in support of Trump, who is running for re election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3jgg4a58_qanon-shaman_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The items to be returned include Chansley's "horned coyote-tail headdress" and a six-foot pole]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-rahul-gandhi-s-jaishankar-rahul-gandhis-pak-question-at-meeting-on-bangladesh-s-jaishankars-reply-6274003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi's Pak Question At Meeting On Bangladesh, S Jaishankar's Reply]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-rahul-gandhi-s-jaishankar-rahul-gandhis-pak-question-at-meeting-on-bangladesh-s-jaishankars-reply-6274003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:40:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Leader of the Opposition Rahul Gandhi fielded two key questions to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar during the all-party meeting on the situation in Bangladesh after Sheikh Hasina's ouster as Prime Minister amid violent protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leader of the Opposition Rahul Gandhi fielded three key questions to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar during the all-party meeting on the situation in Bangladesh after Sheikh Hasina's ouster as Prime Minister amid violent protests.</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi asked what is the government's short-term and long-term strategy in dealing with diplomatic ramifications of the power shift in Dhaka, sources have said. The minister replied that it is a developing situation and the Centre is analysing it closely so that it can fine-tune its next move.</p>

<p>The Congress leader also asked if there could be an involvement of foreign powers, specifically Pakistan, in the dramatic developments in Dhaka over the past few weeks that culminated in Hasina's ouster, the sources said. The Centre replied that it is investigating this angle. A source also pointed out that the government had said that a Pakistan diplomat had been constantly changing his social media display picture to reflect the situation in Bangladesh amid violent protests. The Centre said is probing if this points to anything bigger.</p>

<p>He also asked if New Delhi had foreseen the dramatic turn of events in Bangladesh. To this, the External Affairs Minister replied that India is monitoring the situation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Congress and the other Opposition parties have pledged their full support to the Narendra Modi government in its handling of the neighbourhood crisis.</p>

<p>Following the meeting, External Affairs Minister Jaishankar put out a post on X, appreciating the Opposition's unanimous support. "Briefed an All-Party meeting in Parliament today about the ongoing developments in Bangladesh. Appreciate the unanimous support and understanding that was extended," he wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Briefed an All-Party meeting in Parliament today about the ongoing developments in Bangladesh.<br />
<br />
Appreciate the unanimous support and understanding that was extended. <a href="https://t.co/tiitk5M5zn">pic.twitter.com/tiitk5M5zn</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1820688949305597964?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>At the meeting, also attended by Defence Minister Rajnath Singh and Home Minister Amit Shah, the Centre told MPs from all parties about the background to the crisis in Bangladesh and how it reached this point. They were also briefed about the situation there and how Ms Hasina escaped to India as her residence was stormed by protesters.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina is still in India and is likely to fly to the UK for political asylum. The Centre also told the all-party meet how it plans to respond to Ms Hasina, known to be New Delhi's old friend. Sources said New Delhi wants to give her time to decide her next course of action.</p>

<p>The government also told the meeting that it is in touch with Bangladesh Army, which has announced the formation of an interim government. The government told the Opposition parties that it is watching the developments closely and will take appropriate action at the right time.</p>

<p>There are about 20,000 Indian nationals in Bangladesh and about 8,000 have returned. The government is in touch with them and the high commission is functioning. The Centre, sources said, is also tracking reports of attacks on minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Speaking to NDTV after the meeting, Congress MP Karti Chidambaram said that India's primary concern is the safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh and the situation at the borders. Asked if the Opposition is satisfied with the way the government is handling the situation, he said, "The fact that the External Affairs Minister briefed all party leaders is a very welcome step. And we are with the government as far as national security is concerned."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i0koupbo_rahul-gandhi-s-jaishankar_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar chaired an all-party meeting on Bangladesh today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/googles-default-search-tactics-uphold-illegal-monopoly-rules-us-district-court-judge-amit-mehta-6273849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Court Details How Google Built Illegal Search Monopoly]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/googles-default-search-tactics-uphold-illegal-monopoly-rules-us-district-court-judge-amit-mehta-6273849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:38:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. District Judge Amit Mehta on Monday ruled that Google had violated antitrust law by spending billions of dollars to secure exclusive agreements with developers, carriers and equipment makers to be the default search engine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US District Judge Amit Mehta on Monday ruled that Google had violated antitrust law by spending billions of dollars to secure exclusive agreements with developers, carriers and equipment makers to be the default search engine.</p>

<p>Here are some key statements the judge made in his 277-page ruling:</p>

<p>"Google is a monopolist, and it has acted as one to maintain its monopoly."</p>

<p>"Sure, users can access Google's rivals by switching the default search access point or by downloading a rival search app or browser. But the market reality is that users rarely do so."</p>

<p>"The default is extremely valuable real estate. Because many users simply stick to searching with the default, Google receives billions of queries every day through those access points."</p>

<p>"Google, of course, recognises that losing defaults would dramatically impact its bottom line. For instance, Google has projected that losing the Safari default would result in a significant drop in queries and billions of dollars in lost revenues."</p>

<p>"The distribution agreements have caused a third key anticompetitive effect: They have reduced the incentive to invest and innovate in search."</p>

<p>"There is no genuine 'competition for the contract.' Google has no true competitor."</p>

<p>"Google has not achieved market dominance by happenstance. It has hired thousands of highly skilled engineers, innovated consistently, and made shrewd business decisions. The result is the industry's highest quality search engine, which has earned Google the trust of hundreds of millions of daily users."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lmr52voo_google_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google has no true competitor, rules US District Judge. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-khaleda-zia-jailed-bangladesh-ex-pm-set-to-be-released-amid-turmoil-6273897]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Khaleda Zia, Jailed Bangla Ex-PM Set To Be Released Amid Turmoil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-khaleda-zia-jailed-bangladesh-ex-pm-set-to-be-released-amid-turmoil-6273897]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:21:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fall of the Sheikh Hasina government in Bangladesh points to a big change in the country's political landscape - led by possibilities that the Awami League leader's arch-rival Khaleda Zia may again aim for power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fall of the Sheikh Hasina government in Bangladesh points to a big change in the country's political landscape - led by possibilities that the Awami League leader's arch-rival Khaleda Zia may again aim for power. Ms Zia, the key opposition leader who heads the Bangladesh Nationalist Party, had been elected thrice, though she could run governments for only two terms.</p>

<p>The jailed former premier is now set to leave the prison. Hours after Ms Hasina's ouster yesterday, Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin ordered her release.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are 5 points on the jailed leader:</strong></h2>

<ol>
	<li>Khaleda Zia was born in Jalpaiguri in undivided India. Her husband, Lt Gen Ziaur Rehman, a ruthless military officer, served as the President of Bangladesh from 1977 until he was assassinated I 1981.</li>
	<li>She became the first woman prime minister of Bangladesh in 1991, running the country through a period of serious civil unrest. Falling short of a majority, she had formed the government with the help of the Jamaa-e-Islami.</li>
	<li>Ms Zia went on to win to a second term in 1996, but the elections were boycotted and denounced as unfair by the major opposition parties, including Awami League. Her government lasted only 12 days, after which a caretaker government was installed and fresh elections were called in June. Awami League won the June elections and Ms Hasina went on to became the prime minister for the first time.</li>
	<li>Khaleda Zia returned to power five years later as an alliance of four parties led by her won the elections. She stepped down in 2006 and was arrested for corruption a year later. The former premier had denied the charges and termed the verdict as politically-motivated.</li>
	<li>In 2018, Ms Zia was convicted of corruption charges and jailed for 17 years. Her convicted left her ineligible to contests elections later that year. The BNP leader, who was in poor health, had been largely confined to hospital.</li>
</ol>

<h2><strong>Bangladesh Turmoil</strong></h2>

<p>Bangladesh saw one of its deadliest demonstrations on Sunday with nearly 100 protesters dying in clashes with cops. In the fallout, the protesters breached the Prime Minister's residence on Monday. Ms Hasina avoided a direct confrontation, having already resigned and fled the country in a military plane. The country's army chief called a press conference hours later and declared an interim government would be formed to run the country.</p>

<p>Later in the day, Ms Hasina landed at the Hindon Air Force base in India - about 30 km from capital Delhi. She is likely to leave for London where she may seek asylum, sources told NDTV.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2as3jkt_khaleda-zia_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Khaleda Zia is now set to leave the prison. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-who-is-muhammad-yunus-possible-advisor-of-interim-bangladesh-government-6273576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Muhammad Yunus, Possible Advisor Of Interim Bangladesh Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-who-is-muhammad-yunus-possible-advisor-of-interim-bangladesh-government-6273576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:09:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hours after Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country, the coordinators of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement proposed an interim government headed by Nobel Laureate Dr Muhammad Yunus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hours after <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/unstable-bangladesh-can-lead-to-volcanic-eruption-says-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-6271452">Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina</a> resigned and fled the country, the coordinators of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement proposed an interim government headed by Nobel Laureate Dr Muhammad Yunus. The student movement cited the emergency, including indiscriminate firing, attacks on temples and widespread looting, as the reason for announcing the proposal earlier than expected.</p>

<p>The anti-quota stir, which started roughly a month ago, slowly transformed into anti-government demonstrations. On Monday, the protesters, defying the nationwide curfew, stormed the Prime Minister's home and declared a win for the people of Bangladesh.</p>

<p><strong>Here are some facts about Muhammad Yunus:</strong></p>

<p>1. Muhammad Yunus was born in 1940 in Chittagong, a seaport city in Bangladesh. He pursued his early education at Dhaka University in Bangladesh. Later, he received a Fulbright scholarship to study economics at Vanderbilt University in the United States, where he earned his PhD in economics in 1969.</p>

<p>2. After obtaining his PhD, Mr Yunus became an assistant professor of economics at Middle Tennessee State University. In the mid-1970s, he returned to Bangladesh and took up the position of head of the economics department at Chittagong University. At the time, Mr Yunus started providing small personal loans to destitute basket weavers, and the idea later inspired him to establish the Grameen Bank in 1983.</p>

<p>3. The bank focused on providing tiny loans (as small as Rs 2000) to women in rural Bangladesh to start small businesses – poultry farming, weaving or selling goods. The loans were offered without collateral, and repayment was based on trust and peer pressure. This approach helped millions lift themselves out of poverty, earning Mr Yunus the nickname “Banker to the Poor”. The Grameen Bank model has since been replicated in over 100 countries worldwide.</p>

<p>4. Throughout his life, Mr Yunus received numerous international awards and held several significant positions. From 1993 to 1995, he was a member of the International Advisory Group for the Fourth World Conference on Women, appointed by the UN Secretary-General. He also served on the Global Commission of Women's Health, the Advisory Council for Sustainable Economic Development, and the UN Expert Group on Women and Finance. Notable awards during this period include the Independence Day Award (1987), Bangladesh's highest award; the World Food Prize (1994); and the King Hussein Humanitarian Leadership Award (2000).&nbsp;In 2006, the Nobel Committee jointly awarded the Nobel Peace Prize to Muhammad Yunus and Grameen Bank for their groundbreaking work in microfinance and economic empowerment in the country.</p>

<p>5. In June 2024, Muhammad Yunus was indicted by a Bangladesh court on charges of corruption and embezzlement of 252.2 million taka (Rs 219.4 crore) from the workers' welfare fund of his telecoms company, Grameen Telecom. Grameen Telecom owns a 34.2 per cent stake in Grameenphone, the country's largest mobile phone company. Mr Yunus and 13 others were accused of misappropriating funds and engaging in money laundering. The 83-year-old denied any wrongdoing and claimed the charges were politically motivated. In January, he was also sentenced to six months in prison for labour law violations but got out on bail.</p>

<p>Over the last month, since the beginning of the anti-quota protests primarily led by students, at least 300 people lost their lives after authorities took action against demonstrators across Bangladesh. The protesters argued that the government's job reservation policy for freedom fighters' families favoured the Awami League members. They demanded a merit-based system, instead.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8v0rqhuo_muhammad-yunus-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus has received numerous international awards and held several significant positions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/torture-passengers-struggle-to-breathe-after-ac-malfunctions-on-thai-airways-plane-6273796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Passengers Struggle To Breathe After AC Malfunctions On Thai Airways Plane]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/torture-passengers-struggle-to-breathe-after-ac-malfunctions-on-thai-airways-plane-6273796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:08:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[We were hot and couldn't breathe. At least in a sauna, you can leave when you want," said a passenger on the flight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident, passengers on Thai Airways flight TG 917 flight suffered panic attacks and struggled to breathe when the plane was halted for two hours after the air condition system malfunctioned, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/05/lifestyle/we-got-trapped-in-a-sweltering-sauna-airplane-we-were-so-hot-we-couldnt-breathe/"><em>New York Post</em></a>. The incident took place on July 25 on a Boeing 777. The flight from London to Bangkok was later cancelled entirely.</p>

<p>Due to this, passengers were stuck inside the plane in heat while crew members monitored the situation and attempted to fix it. "People were stuck on the plane and couldn't leave. We were hot and couldn't breathe. At least in a sauna, you can leave when you want," said Warawalan Maksaen, 26, a student at the University of Exeter.</p>

<p>She added, "This was like a form of torture."</p>

<p>According to another passenger, the temperature was so high that passengers began sweating heavily and one even experienced a panic attack. Ms Maksaen claims that throughout this time, neither food nor water was given, which made the situation worse. Two hours later, a flight attendant opened the door to allow in fresh air and provided water in the kitchen area.</p>

<p>However, because of the airport's curfew, no technicians were accessible, and the passengers were forced to disembark at 11 pm after being forced to spend several hours inside the sweltering hot aircraft.</p>

<p>The flight was rescheduled for the next day and passengers were given two options for their accommodation. "We could either sleep in the airport until the rescheduled flight or take a bus to find a hotel. Myself and a lot of the other passengers went to the bus station to wait for transportation to a hotel," the 26-year-old added.</p>

<p>"There was no help from the airline, and the last group of passengers waited aimlessly until the last three buses arrived at 2 am," she told the outlet.</p>

<p>Adding to the horrifying experience, the hotel provided by the airline only had eight rooms available. As families were prioritised, solo travellers like Ms Maksaen were left to sort their lodgings on their own.</p>

<p>Further, the plane's engine did not start when the passengers boarded the flight again the following day at 3:45 pm, forcing them to wait inside the aircraft before disembarking once again. At 6:49 pm, the passengers were eventually permitted to get on the aircraft. "I was so disappointed by Thai Airways. Their service was appalling, and I sent a complaint email after the incident. I have received a compensation offer, either as cash or a discount voucher for my next flight, which I chose as cash because I do not want to fly with this airline again," Ms Maksaen concluded.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b9jaug3g_-thai-airways_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on July 25 on a Boeing 777.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-controversial-us-influencer-gifts-donald-trump-a-tesla-cybertruck-and-rolex-during-interview-6273722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Controversial YouTuber Gifts Donald Trump A Tesla Cybertruck, Musk Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-controversial-us-influencer-gifts-donald-trump-a-tesla-cybertruck-and-rolex-during-interview-6273722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 10:51:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gifts, valued at over $60,000, may pose legal challenges for Trump due to exceeding federal campaign contribution limits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adin Ross, a streamer known for his provocative content and multiple bans from Twitch, recently interviewed former US President Donald Trump and presented him with a customised Tesla Cybertruck,&nbsp;<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fortune.com/2024/08/05/donald-trump-tesla-cybertruck-adin-ross-elon-musk/">Fortune</a></em> reported. Following the 60-minute interview, Mr Ross escorted Donald Trump outside his Mar-a-Lago residence to unveil the customised Tesla Cybertruck.</p>

<p>The vehicle's exterior featured a striking design, showcasing an image of Trump with a bloodied face and raised fist, taken moments after an assassination attempt at a rally, surrounded by numerous American flags and a prominent red "Make America Great Again" logo emblazoned on the front. Mr Ross also gifted Trump a gold Rolex watch during the interview.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The gifts, valued at over $60,000, may pose legal challenges for Trump due to exceeding federal campaign contribution limits.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">JUST IN: Donald Trump gets into a Cybertruck with Kick streamer Adin Ross during Ross' stream at Mar-a-Lago.<br />
<br />
Trump immediately went on the Cybertruck's massive 18.5-inch display to pick out a song.<br />
<br />
Trump decided to go with California Dreamin' before changing the song to play… <a href="https://t.co/622PlviN6Z">pic.twitter.com/622PlviN6Z</a></p>
— Collin Rugg (@CollinRugg) <a href="https://twitter.com/CollinRugg/status/1820527341153792418?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>''That's an Elon,'' Trump joked as he saw the car, referring to Tesla CEO Elon Musk. ''It's beautiful. It's incredible.'' The duo had a&nbsp;lighthearted and entertaining time together in the vehicle, jamming out to a playlist of classic hits from the Beach Boys, Elvis Presley, Michael Jackson, and even the iconic "YMCA" song.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Donald Trump in Tesla Cybertruck.<br />
<br />
<a href="https://t.co/yMbIfNoAu3">pic.twitter.com/yMbIfNoAu3</a></p>
— DogeDesigner (@cb_doge) <a href="https://twitter.com/cb_doge/status/1820531756875083879?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk also reacted to an image of Trump near the Cybertruck with fire emojis.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="qme">??</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1820558416160448691?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>During the interview, the 45th president also revealed that his 18-year-old son is a fan of Mr Ross. ''My son Barron says hello. He's a great young guy but he's a big fan of yours,'' Trump said.</p>

<p>Notably, Adin Ross has been banned from Twitch multiple times for hate speech and inappropriate content and has supported controversial figures like Andrew Tate. He&nbsp;has also displayed pornographic images during his livestreams and promoted gambling to an audience that includes young boys.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This development comes as the Trump campaign seeks to strengthen its appeal among younger voters. Before President Biden's unexpected exit from the race last month, some polls indicated that Trump was making headway with younger men in particular.</p>

<p>Catering to younger audiences, Trump promised to ''save TikTok'' and encouraged users of the popular short-form video platform to support him, despite having advocated for the social media company's ban during his presidency.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5ou3ohc8_-tesla-cybertruck_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Adin Ross has been banned from Twitch multiple times for hate speech and inappropriate content]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protest-bangladesh-updates-india-faces-tightrope-walk-after-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6273466]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's Big Diplomatic Dilemma After Dhaka Shift, Sheikh Hasina's Ouster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protest-bangladesh-updates-india-faces-tightrope-walk-after-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6273466]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 10:09:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The shocking turn of events leading to Sheikh Hasina's ouster as Bangladesh Prime Minister has put India in an extremely tricky situation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The shocking turn of events leading to Sheikh Hasina's ouster as Bangladesh Prime Minister has put India in an extremely tricky situation. Prime Minister Narendra Modi chaired a meeting of the Cabinet Committee on Security last night to discuss the Bangladesh situation that has immense strategic ramifications for New Delhi. The Centre is yet to publicly state how it plans to navigate this neighbourhood crisis and External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar briefed MPs at an all-party meeting today. Here's why the Bangladesh situation is a tightrope for India:</p>

<p><strong>Sheikh Hasina Is In India</strong></p>

<p>After her escape from Dhaka in turmoil, Ms Hasina landed at the Hindon airbase in Delhi and is likely to fly to the UK today to seek political asylum. However, there is no confirmation on whether the UK has offered asylum to her, so it is not clear what happens if the UK does not give her a green signal. In its response to the Bangladesh situation, London has only called for a UN-led probe but has not touched upon the asylum issue. The question then is will Ms Hasina then stay in India or seek another destination. India now faces a diplomatic dilemma and does not want to be seen as overtly backing the ousted leader because that may complicate its relationship with the new dispensation in Bangladesh. Also important is the history of Sheikh Hasina's relationship with India. Long before she became Prime Minister, the Indira Gandhi government had given her refuge after her whole family, including father Mujibur Rahaman, was assassinated during the 1975 unrest in Bangladesh. So abandoning her at this point will also not be an easy decision, considering her equations with Delhi.</p>

<p><strong>A Friend Loses Power</strong></p>

<p>In Sheikh Hasina, New Delhi had a friend in Bangladesh, and her uninterrupted tenure since 2009 saw a major boost in New Delhi-Dhaka ties. From road and rail connectivity to border management to defence cooperation, the ties between India and Bangladesh strengthened during this time. When protests against Ms Hasina gathered steam in Bangladesh, India's response was that it is an "internal matter". With the 76-year-old leader now ousted, India must now build bridges with the new Dhaka dispensation. Bangladesh Army chief Waker-uz-Zaman yesterday said an interim government will be formed to run the affairs of the country. It is not clear what role the Bangladesh Nationalist Party and the Jamaat-e-Islami, who backed the protests in Bangladesh, will play in the new government. Both these parties are no friends of India. The term of BNP chief Khaleda Zia was a rocky phase in Delhi-Dhaka ties. Khaleda Zia, set to be freed from prison after Sheikh Hasina's ouster, has in the past used her anti-India stance as an election plank and pressed that New Delhi has been interfering in Bangladesh's internal politics. The Jamaat on the other hand has close links with Pakistan, and India would be closely watching the developments in Dhaka.</p>

<p><strong>Fear Of Refugee Influx</strong></p>

<p>A big concern for India amid reports of violence against minorities in Bangladesh is a large-scale influx of refugees fleeing atrocities. India and Bangladesh share a 4,096-km border that is very porous. Influx of Bangladesh refugees has been a key issue in India, especially in the Northeast and West Bengal.</p>

<p>Following yesterday's developments in Bangladesh, the Border Security Force (BSF) has issued a high alert across the international border. Pradyot Kishore Manikya Debbarma, leader of Tripura's Tipra Motha, has said that he had spoken to Union Home Minister Amit Shah and has been assured that no infiltration would be allowed.</p>

<p><strong>A Disturbed Neighbourhood</strong></p>

<p>A big challenge staring India in the face is the geopolitical ramifications of the Dhaka turmoil. With Bangladesh slipping out of the control of Awami League, India is watching who takes over. Jamaat-e-Islami and BNP may be more aligned to China, and Beijing would leave no opportunity to fish in troubled waters. This is not good news for India's strategic outlook in the region. The past few years have seen unrest in India's neighbourhood, whether it is Sri Lanka or Myanmar or Afghanistan and now Bangladesh. China and Pakistan have formed a bloc and new dispensation in some countries, the Maldives for example, have suggested that they are aligned more to this bloc than to New Delhi. In Afghanistan, the Taliban's return scuttled India's strong ties with the earlier government. Amid this, the boost in diplomatic relations with Dhaka was a silver lining, but that changed yesterday and India must now return to the drawing board to navigate this new crisis.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-04/pm-narendra-modi-sheikh-hasina-pti_650x400_71491677395.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Sheikh Hasina, India had a strong friend in a hostile neighbourhood. That has changed now]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-year-old-army-officer-crowned-miss-usa-bringing-end-to-months-of-controversy-6273302]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[22-Year-Old Army Officer Crowned Miss USA After Months Of Pageant Controversy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-year-old-army-officer-crowned-miss-usa-bringing-end-to-months-of-controversy-6273302]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 09:35:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Miss USA contest has seen several controversies and scandals in recent years, with multiple allegations of preferential treatment given to certain contestants.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After several months of turmoil and controversy, Miss Michigan Alma Cooper was announced the winner of Miss USA on August 4, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/05/lifestyle/new-miss-usa-crowned-following-year-of-pageant-controversy/"><em>New York Post</em></a>. Ms Cooper, a US Army officer became the third person to hold the title this year after the resignation of 2023's pageant winner.</p>

<p>"As the daughter of a migrant worker, a proud Afro Latina woman and an officer of the United States Army, I am living the American dream," she told judges during a question and answer round at the finale.</p>

<p>She added, "If there's anything that my life and my mother have taught me, it's that your circumstances never define your destiny: You can make success accessible through demanding excellence."</p>

<p>With a master's degree in data science from Stanford University, the 22-year-old defeated 50 other competitors in a pageant that featured swimsuit and evening gown rounds. Connor Perry of Kentucky and Danika Christopherson of Oklahoma were ranked first and second runner-ups. Based on her social media accounts, Ms Cooper is a military intelligence officer who serves as a second lieutenant.</p>

<p>Ms Cooper was crowned live by Miss USA 2023, Hawaii's <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miss-usa-savannah-gankiewicz-receives-death-threats-amid-pageant-controversy-5755463">Savannah Gankiewicz</a>, who inherited the tiara in May following Utah's Noelia Voigt's contentious resignation.</p>

<p>"While this decision was not made lightly, I firmly believe that this opportunity was meant for me and I am ready to make a positive impact with this organization that I hold dear to my heart," the 28-year-old was quoted as saying by CNN in May. She was crowned by the governor of Hawaii Josh Green at a ceremony in Honolulu.</p>

<p>"I am dedicated to taking action and making a difference. With my background as a certified mental health first aid responder and training in anti-bullying suicide prevention. I understand, the importance of prioritising your well-being and advocating for those in need. I believe that the true change starts from within and I am determined to lead by example and empower the class of 2024 and beyond," Ms Gankiewicz further said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Ms Voigt, who was crowned in September 2023, resigned on May 6 and shared the news in an Instagram post. "I realise this may come as a large shock to many. Never compromise your physical and mental well-being," she wrote in the caption. Ms Voigt was crowned the 72nd Miss USA winner in Nevada in 2023. She was the first Venezuelan-American woman to win Miss USA, as per her statement.</p>

<p>Notably, according to AFP, the Miss USA contest has seen several controversies and scandals in recent years, with multiple allegations of preferential treatment given to certain contestants.</p>

<p>Although the organisation eventually determined that the allegations were unsubstantiated, Crystle Stewart, a previous Miss USA winner, resigned as president. After serving as the vice president of the organisation, her husband Max Sebrechts departed under a flurry of accusations of sexual harassment from previous participants. Cheslie Kryst, who was crowned Miss USA in 2019, died by suicide in early 2022.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4so15c8_miss-usa_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Cooper is a military intelligence officer who serves as a second lieutenant.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-calls-for-un-probe-into-bangladesh-turmoil-no-mention-of-sheikh-hasina-asylum-6273246]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Wants UN Probe Into Bangladesh Turmoil, Skirts Sheikh Hasina Asylum]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-calls-for-un-probe-into-bangladesh-turmoil-no-mention-of-sheikh-hasina-asylum-6273246]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 09:24:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The British government has called for a United Nations-led probe into the turmoil that saw Sheikh Hasina resign as the Bangladesh prime minister and flee the country yesterday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British government has called for a United Nations-led probe into the turmoil that saw Sheikh Hasina resign as the Bangladesh prime minister and flee the country yesterday. Foreign Secretary David Lammy also said that the UK wants to see a "peaceful and democratic future" of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>There was, however, no mention of any asylum being provided to Ms Hasina.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The last two weeks in Bangladesh have seen unprecedented levels of violence and tragic loss of life. All sides must work together to restore calm under a transitional government.<br />
<br />
My statement on the ongoing situation ⬇️<a href="https://t.co/g0n4dfwHE9">https://t.co/g0n4dfwHE9</a></p>
— David Lammy (@DavidLammy) <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidLammy/status/1820508707022598429?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"The people of Bangladesh deserve a full and independent UN-led investigation into the events of the past few weeks. The UK wants to see action taken to ensure Bangladesh a peaceful and democratic future. The UK and Bangladesh have deep people-to-people links and shared Commonwealth values," the Foreign Secretary said in a statement.</p>

<p>The top UK official said the last two weeks in Bangladesh saw "unprecedented levels of violence and tragic loss of life". A transitional period has been announced by the Chief of the Army Staff, he said.</p>

<p>"All sides now need to work together to end the violence, restore calm, deescalate the situation and prevent any further loss of life," said Lammy.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, who has been in power in Bangladesh for the past 15 years, resigned as the prime minister yesterday as deadly protests led by students threatened to snowball further. Soon after, she fled to India as an uncertainty loomed over her political future.</p>

<p>She is expected to leave for London later, where she may seek political asylum, sources told NDTV. Her plane is being refuelled for her London journey, they added.</p>

<p>No such references, however, were made in the UK official's statement.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/64dpq37g_bangladesh-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, who has been in power in Bangladesh for the past 15 years, resigned yesterday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-mujibur-rahmans-rise-to-sheikh-hasinas-fall-a-bangladesh-timeline-6272813]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mujibur Rahman's Rise To Sheikh Hasina's Fall: A Bangladesh Timeline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-mujibur-rahmans-rise-to-sheikh-hasinas-fall-a-bangladesh-timeline-6272813]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 07:25:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ex-prime minister Sheikh Hasina's dramatic flight from Bangladesh in a helicopter on Monday under pressure from protesters and the army is far from a first in the South Asian nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ex-prime minister Sheikh Hasina's dramatic flight from Bangladesh in a helicopter on Monday under pressure from protesters and the army is far from a first in the South Asian nation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since independence half a century ago, many of the country's leaders have been forced to flee or had their time in office cut short by violent deaths.</p>

<p>AFP looks back at five key points in Bangladesh's turbulent history.</p>

<p><strong>1975: assassinations and coups galore</strong></p>

<p>Formerly East Pakistan, Bangladesh emerged as a new nation in 1971 after a brutal war involving India.</p>

<p>Independence hero Sheikh Mujibur Rahman became the country's first prime minister, before introducing a one-party system and taking office as president in January 1975.</p>

<p>Within a year he was assassinated by a group of soldiers on August 15, along with his wife and three sons. Khondaker Mostaq Ahmad, with the support of part of the army, then took power.</p>

<p>Ahmad's tenure was short-lived. He was overthrown in a coup instigated by the army's chief of staff Khaled Mosharraf on November 3, who was assassinated in turn by rival mutineers.</p>

<p>After a series of further coups and counter-coups, General Ziaur Rahman took power on November 7.</p>

<p><strong>1981-83 : Bloody rebellion, bloodless coup</strong></p>

<p>After less than six years in power, Rahman was assassinated during an attempted revolt on May 30, 1981.</p>

<p>His vice-president Abdus Sattar took over as interim president with the backing of General Hussain Muhammad Ershad.</p>

<p>But Ershad turned on Sattar within a year, ousting him in a bloodless coup on March 24, 1982.</p>

<p>Immediately after the takeover, he imposed martial law and installed Ahsanuddin Chowdhury as president.</p>

<p>Then, on December 11, 1983, Ershad proclaimed himself head of state. Chowdhury, whose position was honorary, went on to lead a political party loyal to the general.</p>

<p><strong>1990: Ershad resigns after protests</strong></p>

<p>After a wave of protests calling for democracy in Bangladesh, Ershad resigned as president on December 6, 1990.</p>

<p>He was then arrested on December 12 and jailed after being convicted for corruption.</p>

<p>Justice Minister Shahabuddin Ahmed took over as interim leader until elections could be held the year after.</p>

<p>Ershad would eventually be released in January 1997.</p>

<p><strong>1991: First free elections</strong></p>

<p>The country's first free elections were held in early 1991, with the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) running out as clear winners.</p>

<p>Khaleda Zia, General Ziaur Rahman's widow, became Bangladesh's first woman prime minister.</p>

<p>She was succeeded by her arch-rival Sheikh Hasina, daughter of the country's founding father Mujibur Rahman, after Hasina's Awami League beat the BNP at the ballot box in 1996.</p>

<p>The BNP returned to power in 2001, with Zia once again becoming prime minister and completing her term of office in October 2006.</p>

<p><strong>2007: Anti-corruption purge</strong></p>

<p>In 2007, with the army's support, President Iajuddin Ahmed declared a state of emergency after anti-government demonstrations.</p>

<p>A military-led transitional government then launched an anti-corruption purge, imprisoning both Hasina and Zia on graft allegations before their release in 2008.</p>

<p>After her party's win in the polls in December 2008, Hasina once again became prime minister.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/32iukmo_bangladesh-unrest-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Mujibur Rahman was assassinated during an attempted revolt on May 30, 1981.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taslima-nasreen-in-exile-finds-an-irony-in-sheikh-hasinas-escape-6272732]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Exiled Author Taslima Nasreen Said After Sheikh Hasina Fled Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taslima-nasreen-in-exile-finds-an-irony-in-sheikh-hasinas-escape-6272732]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 07:01:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Exiled Bangladeshi author Taslima Nasreen, a staunch critic of communalism, has highlighted an irony in the resignation of Sheikh Hasina as the Bangladesh Prime Minister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exiled Bangladeshi author Taslima Nasreen, a staunch critic of communalism, has found an irony in ousted Bangladesh premier Sheikh Hasina's escape in the face of deadly student-led protests.</p>

<p>Ms Nasreen said Hasina had thrown her out of Bangladesh to "please Islamists", and the "same Islamists" were part of the student movement that forced her to leave the country.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p0r3m19_taslima-tweet_625x300_06_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"Hasina in order to please Islamists threw me out of my country in 1999 after I entered Bangladesh to see my mother in her deathbed and never allowed me to enter the country again. The same Islamists have been in the student movement who forced Hasina to leave the country today," said Ms Nasreen in an online post.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina fled to India in a military plane yesterday and is likely to fly to London to seek asylum in the UK.</p>

<p>The author blamed her for allowing "Islamists to grow" and letting those involved in corruption to thrive. She also spoke against Army rule in her country and batted for democracy.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/she-didnt-want-to-leave-we-insisted-sheikh-hasinas-son-to-ndtv-6271386">"She Didn't Want To Leave, We Insisted": Sheikh Hasina's Son To NDTV</a></p>

<p>"Hasina had to resign and leave the country. She was responsible for her situation. She made Islamists to grow. She allowed her people to involve in corruption. Now Bangladesh must not become like Pakistan. Army must not rule. Political parties should bring democracy &amp; secularism," she said in an earlier post.</p>

<p>Ms Nasreen had to leave Bangladesh in 1994 in the wake of death threats by fundamentalist outfits over her book "Lajja". The 1993 book was banned in Bangladesh, but became a bestseller elsewhere.</p>

<p>Khaleda Zia, the jailed arch-rival of Ms Hasina, was the prime minister at that time.</p>

<p>The author has been living in exile since.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-president-orders-release-of-jailed-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-6270786">Sheikh Hasina Flees, Bangladesh President Orders Ex PM Khaleda Zia's Release</a></p>

<p>Bangladesh saw one of its deadliest demonstrations on Sunday with nearly 100 protesters dying in clashes with cops. In the fallout, the protesters breached the Prime Minister's residence on Monday. Ms Hasina avoided a direct confrontation, having already resigned and left the country in a military plane.</p>

<p>The country's army chief called a press conference hours later and declared an interim government would be formed to run the country.</p>

<p>Later in the day, Ms Hasina landed at the Hindon Air Force base in India - about 30 km from capital Delhi. She is likely to leave for London where she may seek asylum, sources told NDTV. They said her plane was being refuelled for the flight to London.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/10qol94_taslima-nasreen-sheikh-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-holds-around-the-clock-crisis-talks-to-avoid-israel-iran-war-6272621]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Holds 'Around-The-Clock' Crisis Talks To Avoid Israel-Iran War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-holds-around-the-clock-crisis-talks-to-avoid-israel-iran-war-6272621]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 06:23:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden held crisis talks on Monday on a potential Iranian counterattack on Israel as his administration said it was working around the clock to avoid all-out war in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden held crisis talks on Monday on a potential Iranian counterattack on Israel as his administration said it was working around the clock to avoid all-out war in the Middle East.<br />
Biden and Secretary of State Antony Blinken engaged in frantic diplomacy to try to ease tensions sparked by a suspected Israeli attack that killed Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran.</p>

<p>The president called King Abdullah II of Jordan, which helped down Iranian drones and missiles in an earlier showdown in April, while Blinken called top officials in Qatar and Egypt, the key intermediaries seeking a ceasefire in the 10-month Israel-Hamas war.</p>

<p>"We are engaged in intense diplomacy, pretty much around the clock, with a very simple message -- all parties must refrain from escalation," Blinken said after joining other top officials in a White House meeting.</p>

<p>"It's also critical that we break this cycle by reaching a ceasefire in Gaza," said Blinken, who has also spoken since Sunday with G7 counterparts and Iraq's prime minister.</p>

<p>On Monday, multiple US personnel were injured in a rocket attack on a base in Iraq, adding to the already heightened regional tensions.</p>

<p>Biden had been hoping in his final months in office to end the Gaza war and work on clinching a landmark deal between Israel and Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>Instead, he has boosted the US military presence in the Middle East in a show of strength to Iran.</p>

<p>After staunchly backing Israel's war against Hamas, Biden has made clear his frustration with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu over the killing of Haniyeh, who was involved in the ceasefire negotiations.</p>

<p>Blinken, who has warned that Iran could strike soon, made a new pitch for Biden's ceasefire plan that would freeze fighting in Gaza and return hostages seized in the October 7 mega-attack on Israel by Hamas.</p>

<p>A ceasefire "will unlock possibilities for more enduring calm, not only in Gaza itself, but in other areas where the conflict could spread," Blinken said as he met Australian Foreign Minister Penny Wong.</p>

<p>In a veiled allusion to US frustrations, Blinken said, "What it really comes down to, really, is all parties finding ways to come to an agreement, not look for reasons to delay or to say no."</p>

<p>"It is urgent that all parties make the right choices in the hours and days ahead," he said.</p>

<p><strong>Fears of spiraling conflict</strong></p>

<p>Biden met in the White House's heavily secured Situation Room with his national security team including Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>He flew to the White House after a weekend home in Delaware, and after a kiss for First Lady Jill Biden, he headed straight into the Oval Office without commenting to reporters.</p>

<p>The White House said that Biden and the Jordanian king in their call "discussed their efforts to de-escalate regional tensions, including through an immediate ceasefire and hostage release deal."</p>

<p>King Abdullah called for "an immediate and permanent ceasefire to end the catastrophe in Gaza" and for "ceasing all escalatory measures," according to a readout by the Jordanian royal court.</p>

<p>Iran fired directly at Israel in April, taking their long shadow war into the open following a strike on an Iranian diplomatic building in Syria.</p>

<p>The United States helped intercept the drones and missiles, and damage was minimal.</p>

<p>But Jordan -- in a delicate position with its large Palestinian population and a peace deal with Israel -- has insisted it does not want to be a battleground.</p>

<p>State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said that in April, "we were able to chart a path that ultimately got us through that time without tipping into a wider war."</p>

<p>"But every time you have one of these cycles of escalation, you have a risk of parties miscalculating, you have the risk of them taking actions that get out of hand," Miller told reporters.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/uj0lr04_joe-biden_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden met in the White House's heavily secured Situation Room with his national security team]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-us-says-interim-government-should-be-made-with-6272512]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Unrest: US Says Interim Government Should Be Made With...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-us-says-interim-government-should-be-made-with-6272512]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:49:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden Administration has said an interim government in Bangladesh, which has descended into chaos after the sudden resignation of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina amid violent anti-quota protests, should be formed according to democratic principles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden Administration has said an interim government in Bangladesh, which has descended into chaos after the sudden resignation of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina amid violent anti-quota protests, should be formed according to democratic principles, rule of law and the will of the Bangladeshi people.</p>

<p>"We want to see the Bangladeshi people decide the future of the Bangladeshi government," State Department Spokesperson Matthew Miller told reporters at his daily news conference.</p>

<p>Bangladesh descended into chaos as Prime Minister Hasina surreptitiously resigned and fled the country in a military aircraft while the army stepped in to fill the power vacuum by announcing an interim government.</p>

<p>As the news of Hasina's departure spread, hundreds broke into her residence, vandalising and looting the interiors, providing dramatic expression to the anti-government protests that have killed more than 300 people in a fortnight.</p>

<p>The embattled Bangladeshi leader later landed at the Hindon airbase in Ghaziabad as part of her plan to go to London.</p>

<p>Miller told the press conference here the United States is monitoring the situation carefully and calls for an end to violence and fixing accountability for the deaths that have occurred over the past few weeks.</p>

<p>"All decisions regarding the interim government should be made with respect to democratic principles, rule of law and the will of the Bangladeshi people," he said.</p>

<p>"Now, as to what accountability looks like, that's something that should take place under Bangladeshi law. Obviously, anyone responsible for acts of violence, acts that break the law should be held accountable for them," he said.</p>

<p>In response to a question, Miller said he is not aware if the former prime minister Hasina has sought an asylum in the United States.</p>

<p>"With respect to the violence over the past few weeks and the deaths that have occurred, it is vital that we have full and transparent investigations to ensure accountability for these deaths. As relates to the interim government, we think that it's important that we focus on the Bangladeshi people's democratic aspirations and see a path to democratic governance," Miller said.</p>

<p>Noting that the US greatly values its relationship with the people of Bangladesh, he said, "We want to see that continued. I would just urge everyone with requests or questions about what the future may entail, we are not even 12 hours out from the reported resignation of the prime minister." Miller said the United States is monitoring the situation in Bangladesh carefully. "The United States stands with the people of Bangladesh. We urge all parties to refrain from further violence. Too many lives have been lost over the course of the past several weeks and we urge calm and restraint in the days ahead," he said.</p>

<p>"We welcome the announcement of an interim government and urge any transition be conducted in accordance with Bangladesh's laws. Finally, we are deeply saddened about the reports of human rights abuses, casualties and injuries over the weekend and past weeks. We share our deepest condolences with those who have lost loved ones and those who are suffering," Miller said.</p>

<p>Earlier, a White House National Security Council spokesperson said, "We are monitoring the situation in Bangladesh closely." "The United States has long called for respecting democratic rights in Bangladesh, and we urge that the interim government formation be democratic and inclusive," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The NSC spokesperson said the US "commend the Army for the restraint they have shown today. We encourage all parties to refrain from further violence and restore peace as quickly as possible".</p>

<p>"We express our deep concern and sadness about the reports of casualties and injuries over the weekend and past weeks, and we share our deepest condolences with those who lost loved ones and those who are suffering.</p>

<p>"It will be vital for the new government to carefully and credibly investigate all attacks, and provide accountability and justice for the victims," the spokesperson said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9f6ihepg_bangladesh-unrest_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US official said that it is monitoring the situation carefully and calls for an end to violence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-vows-crushing-response-against-israel-after-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-killing-6272459]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Vows "Crushing Response" Against Israel After Hamas Chief's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-vows-crushing-response-against-israel-after-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-killing-6272459]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:24:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran has vowed to take "decisive" action against the "aggressor" behind the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, accusing Israel of carrying out a "cowardly" attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Iran has vowed to take "decisive" action against the "aggressor" behind the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, accusing Israel of carrying out a "cowardly" attack.</p>

<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Nasser Kanaani said on Monday that the killing of Haniyeh, who was in Iran for the swearing-in of President Masoud Pezeshkian, was a "flagrant violation" of international law, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Iran will take its serious and deterrent action with "strength and decisiveness" to punish the "aggressor" based on its inherent right and the international law principles, Kanaani said at a weekly press conference.</p>

<p>He added that Tehran would pursue the matter through the United Nations and the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation, which will hold an emergency meeting of Foreign Ministers on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Iran's Islamic Revolution Guards Corps (IRGC) has blamed Israel for the attack, vowing a "harsh and painful response".</p>

<p>IRGC Chief Hossein Salami said on Monday that Israel would "understand its miscalculation" after Tehran retaliates.</p>

<p>The assassination has significantly heightened tensions in the region.</p>

<p>While Iran has insisted it does not seek escalation, it has made clear it will not tolerate attacks on its territory or its citizens.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/cvee6ek_iran-flag-generic-_625x300_18_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The assassination of Ismail Haniyeh has significantly heightened tensions in the region.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/several-us-personnel-injured-in-rocket-attack-on-iraq-base-6272401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Multiple US Soldiers Injured In Rocket Attack On Iraq Base]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/several-us-personnel-injured-in-rocket-attack-on-iraq-base-6272401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:08:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rocket attack on a base in Iraq wounded multiple US personnel on Monday, officials said, adding to already heightened regional tensions over an expected Iranian counterattack on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rocket attack on a base in Iraq wounded multiple US personnel on Monday, officials said, adding to already heightened regional tensions over an expected Iranian counterattack on Israel.</p>

<p>The rocket fire is the latest in a series of attacks targeting Ain al-Assad base in western Iraq, which hosts American troops as well as personnel from the US-led coalition against the Islamic State jihadist group.</p>

<p>"There was a suspected rocket attack today against US and coalition forces" at the base, a US defense spokesperson said. "Initial indications are that several US personnel were injured."</p>

<p>"Base personnel are conducting a post-attack damage assessment" and updates will be provided as more information becomes available, the spokesperson added.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris were briefed on the attack, the White House said.</p>

<p>"They discussed the steps we are taking to defend our forces and respond to any attack against our personnel in a manner and place of our choosing," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>An Iraqi military source had earlier said that multiple rockets were fired at the base, with some landing inside it and another hitting a nearby village but not causing damage.</p>

<p>A commander in a pro-Iran armed group told AFP that at least two rockets targeted the base, without saying who had carried out the attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another source in the group and a security source confirmed an attack occurred.</p>

<p>Such attacks were frequent early in the war between Israel and Hamas Palestinian militants in Gaza but since then have largely halted.</p>

<p>The latest rocket fire comes as fears grow of an attack by Iran and its allies on Israel in retaliation for the killing of top Hamas and Hezbollah figures in strikes last week either blamed on or claimed by Israel.</p>

<p><br />
- Series of attacks -<br />
The killings, with both Iran and Hezbollah vowing retaliation, are among the most serious series of tit-for-tat attacks that have heightened fears of a regional conflagration stemming from the Gaza war.</p>

<p>The Iran-aligned "Axis of Resistance" against Israel, which also includes Iraqi groups and Yemen's Huthis, have already been drawn into the nearly 10-month war.</p>

<p>Monday's rocket attack occurred after US forces carried out a strike last week on combatants who were attempting to launch drones that were deemed a threat to American and allied troops, a US official said.</p>

<p>The strike, which Iraqi sources said left four killed, was the first by American forces in Iraq since February.</p>

<p>There have been two recent attacks targeting bases hosting US and allied forces in Iraq -- on July 16 and 25.</p>

<p>Prior to that, US troops in Iraq and Syria had not been targeted since April. But attacks against them were much more common in the first few months of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza, when they were targeted more than 175 times.</p>

<p>The Islamic Resistance in Iraq, a loose alliance of pro-Iran groups, claimed the majority of the attacks, saying they were in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza.</p>

<p>In January, a drone strike blamed on those groups killed three US soldiers at a base in Jordan. In retaliation, US forces launched dozens of strikes against Tehran-backed fighters in Iraq and Syria.</p>

<p>Baghdad has sought to defuse tensions, engaging in talks with Washington on the future of the US-led coalition's mission in Iraq, with Iran-backed groups demanding a withdrawal.</p>

<p>The US military has around 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in Syria.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/uscrsqr8_us-troops-in-iraqafp650_625x300_11_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris were briefed on the attack, the White House said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-injured-after-shooting-in-us-seattle-cops-6272375]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Injured After Shooting In US' Seattle: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-injured-after-shooting-in-us-seattle-cops-6272375]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 05:00:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least four people were injured following a shooting in Seattle, US state of Washington, police said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least four people were injured following a shooting in Seattle, US state of Washington, police said.</p>

<p>Police added early Monday that they found a woman in her 20s with a gunshot graze wound to her head at the scene, and a man in his 20s who appeared to have been shot in his finger, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>While police were investigating, another man in his 20s with two gunshot wounds to his lower back and ankle crashed a vehicle into the entrance of Swedish First Hill hospital, police said, adding that the crashed vehicle appeared to have been shot at multiple times.</p>

<p>Additionally, a third man in his 20s walked into a nearby Kaiser Permanente medical facility with a gunshot wound to his right leg, according to police.</p>

<p>Police said any suspect or suspects responsible for the gunfire fled the crime area. No arrests have been made.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least four people were injured following a shooting in Seattle, police said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>