<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 13:24:08 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mystery-controversy-volatility-and-donald-trump-the-bitcoin-phenomenon-7177265]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mystery, Controversy, Volatility, And Donald Trump: The Bitcoin Phenomenon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mystery-controversy-volatility-and-donald-trump-the-bitcoin-phenomenon-7177265]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 13:24:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Here are some things to know about Bitcoin, the volatile digital unit that has soared since Donald Trump won the US election promising to make the country the "bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world":]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite being the world's most famous cryptocurrency, Bitcoin -- whose value on Thursday passed $100,000 for the first time -- has always been surrounded by mystery and controversy.</p>

<p>Here are some things to know about the volatile digital unit, which has soared since Donald Trump won the US election promising to make the country the "bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world":</p>

<p><strong>Secret creator</strong></p>

<p>In the 16 years since Bitcoin was invented, no one has been able to name its founder.</p>

<p>It all started in October 2008, when a nine-page "white paper" attributed to Satoshi Nakamoto theorised "a purely peer-to-peer version of electronic cash (that) would allow online payments to be sent directly from one party to another".</p>

<p>The idea was to break free from the control of central banks, traditionally the only institutions who can create money.</p>

<p>But is Satoshi Nakamoto a real name, a pseudonym, or a team of people? Despite various theories, the mystery endures.</p>

<p>An Australian computer scientist called Craig Wright claimed to have written the white paper, but the High Court in London ruled this year that he was not the mythical Nakamoto.</p>

<p>Since its creation, bitcoin has been accused of being the currency of choice on the dark web for illegal payments that leave no trace. It is also the currency that hackers usually demand to be paid in during ransomware attacks.</p>

<p><strong>Fallen stars</strong></p>

<p>The crypto world has been shaken by high-profile bankruptcies and the fall of several star entrepreneurs.</p>

<p>Changpeng Zhao, formerly head of the world's largest cryptocurrency platform Binance, was sentenced to four months in jail for violating US anti-money laundering laws.</p>

<p>"No wish to be CEO again. But definitely wouldn't mind a pardon," Zhao said on X this week, alluding to Trump's presidential authority to grant clemency.</p>

<p>Binance's main rival, FTX, filed for bankruptcy in late 2022, and its founder Sam Bankman-Fried was sentenced in March to 25 years in prison for fraud and conspiracy.</p>

<p>His downfall has smeared the sector's reputation, but the crypto industry has continued to call for more regulatory clarity, a cause championed by Bankman-Fried.</p>

<p><strong>Towards respectability</strong></p>

<p>Bitcoin investors on Thursday cheered Trump's decision to pick a crypto fan to head the US securities regulator, reinforcing hopes that the leader will push through looser measures.</p>

<p>Even though much of the hype around bitcoin is speculative, the currency has gained some respectability in recent years.</p>

<p>US financial regulators in January approved bitcoin ETFs, or exchange traded funds, which allow a wider public to invest without having to hold the cryptocurrency directly.</p>

<p>El Salvador in September 2021 became the first country to accept bitcoin as legal tender.</p>

<p>But the crypto money hasn't won over the country's population. According to a study by Central America University (UCA), 88 percent of Salvadorians never used it in 2023.</p>

<p><strong>Based on blockchain</strong></p>

<p>Bitcoin is based on blockchain technology, a virtual ledger that allows information to be stored and exchanged in a secure, secret and unmodifiable manner. Each transaction is recorded in real time, in a tamper-proof register.</p>

<p>Bitcoins are created -– or "extracted" -- as a "reward" when powerful energy-sucking computers solve complex problems. So-called "miners" validate the transactions to create bitcoins.</p>

<p>To prevent uncontrollable growth, Satoshi Nakamoto limited the global number of coin units to 21 million, a level that should be reached around 2140.</p>

<p>Every four years, the reward for "miners" is cut in two -- slowing down the rate that new bitcoins enter the market, further boosting their scarcity and their value.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/sadqe0ag_bitcoin-reuters_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Thursday, for the first time, Bitcoin's value passed $100,000.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-plunges-deeper-into-crisis-after-emmanuel-macrons-premier-ousted-7177192]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Plunges Deeper Into Crisis After Emmanuel Macron's Premier Ousted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-plunges-deeper-into-crisis-after-emmanuel-macrons-premier-ousted-7177192]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 13:14:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron is looking for a new prime minister after the far right joined forces with the left to push through a no-confidence motion against his government over a budget dispute.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Emmanuel Macron is looking for a new prime minister on Thursday after the far right joined forces with the left to push through a no-confidence motion against his government over a budget dispute.</p>

<p>The French president needs to find a premier who can pass a 2025 budget through a deeply divided parliament.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But any new leader will face the same financial squeeze that brought down Prime Minister Michel Barnier's administration.</p>

<p>The budget bill presented by Barnier — that sank with his government — contained €60 billion ($63 billion) in tax increases and spending cuts that aimed for a reduction in the deficit to 5% of economic output in 2025, from an estimated 6.1% this year.</p>

<p>The French president is due to make a statement at 8 p.m. on Thursday.</p>

<p>Far-right leader Marine Le Pen teamed up with a left-wing coalition to topple Barnier late Wednesday, pitching the country into a prolonged period of turbulence that's likely to further unsettle investors.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With the result of the vote widely anticipated, the euro was little changed around $1.0514 after the result and French bond futures gave up some of their earlier gains.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Barnier's tenure was the shortest for a premier since France's Fifth Republic was founded in 1958. Barnier, a seasoned conservative and the EU's chief Brexit negotiator, was appointed in September.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rn7mdkm8_marine-le-pen-_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>There is little to suggest that the current stalemate will end so easily for Macron as the next premier will be subject to the same parliamentary calculus and risk of censure.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Macron has the authority to appoint a new prime minister, but he had a lengthy struggle before he managed to win limited support for Barnier from a fragmented parliament.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The roots of the current turmoil date back to June, when Macron dissolved parliament and called a snap vote as he sought to rebound from a crushing defeat for his party in the European elections — where Le Pen's party won more than double the president's party.</p>

<p>Instead, he made Le Pen's National Rally the largest party in parliament and its leader became the country's most influential power broker as his centrist coalition crumbled.</p>

<p>Following the June ballot, the lower house was split into three fiercely opposed blocs: a diminished center supporting the president, a leftist alliance and the far right led by Le Pen. That makeup won't change as a new parliamentary election can't be held until July at the earliest.</p>

<p>The divisions between those groups have been exacerbated by the economic problems facing France, with the budget deficit set to exceed 6% of GDP this year and voters reluctant to accept spending cuts or higher taxes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“To those who think I'm intent on choosing a policy of disaster through a vote of no confidence, I want to tell them that the disastrous policy would be not to censure such a budget,” she told lawmakers on Wednesday. “It's the end of this ephemeral government.”&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>What Happens Next:</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p>The outgoing cabinet remains in place with limited powers and will likely rely on untested emergency legislation to collect taxes and enact crucial spending</p>
	</li>
	<li>The French president is solely responsible for appointing a new premier, but there is no constitutional time limit for a decision and no obvious candidate — it took Macron nearly two months to settle on Barnier</li>
	<li>Once named, a new premier proposes a cabinet, appointed by the president, and then has to send a new 2025 budget bill to parliament</li>
	<li>A new legislative election can't be held before July</li>
</ul>

<p>The chaos in the European Union's second-biggest economy has prompted bond investors to punish France's sovereign debt relative to its peers. Barnier warned of a “storm” in financial markets if he was ousted.</p>

<p>The outgoing administration will continue in a caretaker capacity for the time being, allowing the government to avoid a US-style shutdown. Barnier can use emergency laws to collect taxes and guarantee a minimal level of spending, but the broader impact is hard to predict.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/q0aneqc8_michel-barnier-_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Finance Minister Antoine Armand warned Tuesday that stopgap legislation would raise taxes for millions of households and block planned spending increases for some priorities, including security and farming.</p>

<p>Following the vote, Le Pen said that she is willing to work with another government, so long as they work with her party to draw up the budget. “This budget was toxic for the French,” she said in an interview on French television. Instead, she said, the country needs “a budget that's acceptable to all.”</p>

<p>Barnier became the first French prime minister to lose a no-confidence vote in more than 60 years. The only other premier to be ousted under the Fifth Republic was Georges Pompidou in 1962 and, with the backing of the powerful president, Charles de Gaulle, he was eventually reappointed.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kgttt0n8_french-parliament_625x300_05_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Le Pen has been ramping up the pressure on Macron to resign as a way to break the impasse and allow France to move forward.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“It's up to his conscience to decide whether he can sacrifice public action and the fate of France to his own pride,” she said during the debate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Macron has said he won't step down until his term ends in 2027 and he can't be forced out of his job. Le Pen is the frontrunner for the next presidential election, according to opinion polls.</p>

<h3><strong>Possible Barnier Successors:</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Bernard Cazeneuve, 61: A former prime minister and interior minister under Socialist President Francois Hollande. He was already considered as a possible premier this summer before Macron picked Barnier. Tapping Cazeneuve could potentially help Macron fracture the left-wing bloc.</li>
	<li>Sébastien Lecornu, 38: In 2022, he became the youngest defense minister since the French Revolution. He's a Macron loyalist who originally came from the center-right Republicans party. The skilled politician has been a minister since Macron became president and has overseen a jump in military spending.</li>
	<li>François Bayrou, 73: The veteran centrist is the leader of the MoDem party, a key Macron ally in parliament. Currently the high commissioner for government planning, Bayrou supports proportional representation in parliamentary elections, which has also been backed by the National Rally.</li>
	<li>Jean Castex, 59: A former prime minister under Macron known for his southern French accent and his management skills. Currently the head of the RATP, the state-owned company that operates the Paris metro.</li>
</ul>

<p>And finally...</p>

<ul>
	<li>Barnier, 73: Macron could re-name the outgoing prime minister. Barnier did, however, appear to rule himself out on Tuesday. “I want to serve,” he said “But what does it mean if I fall tomorrow, and the day after you find me back here, as if nothing had happened?”</li>
</ul><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/tvo5kai8_emmanuel-macron_625x300_05_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French president needs to find a premier who can pass a 2025 budget through a deeply divided parliament.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-police-investigate-president-yoon-amid-impeachment-call-over-martial-law-top-points-7177118]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Police Investigate President Amid Impeachment Call: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-police-investigate-president-yoon-amid-impeachment-call-over-martial-law-top-points-7177118]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 13:03:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trouble seems to be mounting for South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol, as lawmakers began the impeachment proceedings against him following a bungled imposition of martial law that brought thousands of protesters to the streets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>Impeachment Vote Scheduled: </strong>President Yoon was still clinging to power on Thursday as he faces impeachment after imposing martial law and sending troops and helicopters to parliament. The opposition has filed a motion to impeach Yoon, 63, who has since gone to ground. A vote in the South Korean parliament on the President's proposed impeachment is scheduled for Saturday at around 7:00 pm (1000 GMT), opposition lawmaker Jo Seoung-lae was quoted as saying by news agency Yonhap.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>No Presidential Address:</strong> Embattled Mr Yoon will not make any public statements on Thursday, his office said, after the short-lived declaration of martial law imploded his political fortunes and his grip on the country spectacularly. Mr Yoon has not been seen in public since his televised address in the early hours of Wednesday after the law was lifted.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>Police Investigating President: </strong>South Korean police said it has begun investigating President Yoon, who has lurched from crisis to crisis since taking office in 2022, for alleged "insurrection" over his declaration of martial law. Woo Jong-soo, head of the National Investigation Headquarters of the National Police Agency, told lawmakers that "the case has been assigned," footage showed.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>South Korean Defence Minister Resigns: </strong>South Korean Defence Minister Kim Yong-hyun resigned on Thursday, the president's office said. The resignation came after it came to light that it was Mr Kim, a longtime confidant of Mr Yoon, who recommended imposing martial law, according to a senior military official and impeachment filings by opposition figures on Wednesday. "Today, the President accepted the resignation of Minister of National Defence Kim Yong-hyun and approved his dismissal, and nominated Ambassador to Saudi Arabia Choi Byung-hyuk as the new ministerial candidate," Mr Yoon's office said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>Travel Ban On Ex-Defence Minister: </strong>Prosecutors in the Asian country banned ex-defence minister Kim from leaving the country over his role in a martial law declaration. "The Seoul Central District Prosecutors' Office has imposed a travel ban on the former minister," according to a report by news agency Yonhap.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>Ruling PPP Lawmakers To Reject Impeachment Bill: </strong>The floor leader of South Korea's ruling People Power Party (PPP) vowed that all their lawmakers would "unite" to defeat an opposition-led motion to impeach President Yoon. "All 108 lawmakers of the People Power Party will stay united to reject the president's impeachment," Choo Kyung-ho said at a live-streamed party meeting. The opposition-dominated parliament needs eight ruling party lawmakers to vote with them for the impeachment bill to pass.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>Ruling PPP Asks President To Leave Party:</strong> Despite the call to oppose the impeachment bill, the PPP has asked President Yoon to leave the party. The leader of PPP, Han Dong-hoon told reporters he had "demanded the president's resignation from the party," adding that his party was "not trying to defend the president's unconstitutional martial law".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>US Praises South Korea Amid Crisis: </strong>The White House on Wednesday praised South Korea's "democratic resilience" as lawmakers in Seoul moved to impeach the President. South Korea "is demonstrating democratic resilience. We are confident the people of Korea will resolve this episode peacefully, democratically, and constitutionally," US National Security Council spokesman Sean Savett said on X.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>South Korea Crisis: </strong>Long-simmering disputes between the conservative government and its opponents over budgets, investigations and scandals spiralled into the imposition of martial law by the President. The sudden declaration of decree also reportedly blindsided the ruling party, whose leader Han Dong-hoon told reporters the presidential office had not consulted with him about the move. He, along with Prime Minister Han Duck-soo joined calls for Mr Yoon to rescind the order. Mr Han, a Yoon appointee would become acting president if Yoon is removed from office, according to a report by Reuters.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>Martial Law In Korea: </strong>The imposition was the first such declaration in over four decades in South Korea and brought back painful memories of its autocratic past. The move was to "safeguard a liberal South Korea from the threats posed by North Korea's communist forces and to eliminate anti-state elements plundering people's freedom and happiness," Mr Yoon had said.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pno35hfg_south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-reuters_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Yoon Suk Yeol declared martial law in a live TV address on Tuesday night.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/the-story-of-south-koreas-six-hours-of-turmoil-7177068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: The Six Hours of Turmoil That Shook South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/the-story-of-south-koreas-six-hours-of-turmoil-7177068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:59:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From the chaos that lasted only six hours, one thing is clear: this political drama has showcased South Koreas remarkable democratic resilience.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nc490tig_so_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On December 3 at 10:25 pm Korean Standard Time (KST), surprising news shocked the world as reports spread across social media announcing the imposition of Martial Law by the President of South Korea, Yoon Suk Yeol. The announcement was a shock for most South Koreans, who had long enjoyed the benefits of democracy and had only studied the imposition of martial law in history lessons.</p>

<p>The news prompted lawmakers and citizens to gather at the National Assembly, where the opposition, led by Lee Jae-myung, head of the Democratic Party, entered the assembly to vote on the president's decision. Armed troops attempted to enter the building, jostling with lawmakers and staff, but were unsuccessful in halting proceedings, which led to a vote rejecting the martial law. Following the National Assembly's decision, the President was forced to lift martial law at 4:40 am KST on December 4, after an ordeal lasting six hours.</p>

<p>While the declaration of emergency martial law was a surprise, it was not entirely unexpected. Many experts had already discussed the possibility of martial law being implemented, particularly after the recent appointment of close allies to Yoon's cabinet. This raised suspicions about the likelihood of a ‘palace coup'. But what led to this extreme measure?</p>

<h2><strong>Reaction To Intensifying Pressure</strong></h2>

<p>President Yoon's administration has been mired in allegations of corruption and misgovernance since 2022. For example, his handling of the doctors' protest and the Itaewon crowd disaster has faced widespread condemnation from both the opposition and the public. In addition to governance issues, the First Lady has become a focal point, having been accused of corruption, scandals, and exerting undue influence within the presidential office. However, the situation grew more serious after the April National Assembly elections, when the opposition secured a majority, making it difficult for the president's party to pass legislation and conduct normal proceedings.</p>

<p>The likely reason behind Yoon's extreme step was the growing pressure from all sides, including the Democratic Party (DP), the public, and his own party. This pressure intensified in September when the 22nd Assembly's first regular session began. Following that, Yoon faced increasing partisan strife as the assembly turned hostile, repeatedly demanding accountability from the president over actions taken against the First Lady. Just last week, the president vetoed a bill passed by the opposition for the third time, calling for a special counsel investigation into corruption charges against the First Lady. The tension between the president and the legislature also coincided with his declining popularity.</p>

<p>In his public address declaring martial law, he stated, “I declare martial law to protect the Republic of Korea from the threats of North Korean communist forces, to immediately eradicate the unscrupulous pro-Pyongyang antistate forces that pillage the freedom and happiness of our people, and to protect free constitutional order.” He described the opposition's decision to block the National Assembly from functioning as a “legislature dictatorship”, which had paralysed the administration and sabotaged state functions. The speech highlighted his frustration with the opposition in the country.</p>

<p>With rising allegations against his wife and his falling popularity, the president also faced increasing pressure from within his party, particularly from Han Dong-hoon, the People Power Party (PPP) leader who publicly urged the president to take action. Sensing that he was losing support from the public and the party, and that the opposition's tactics were succeeding, he may have felt compelled to take this drastic step, which was supported only by a select few in the cabinet. As reported by the media, the Chungam Faction—a small group of close aides, including the president and the Defence Minister—took the decision without consulting the Prime Minister or the party. This indicates that the president felt he had no choice but to declare martial law to save his presidency.</p>

<h2><strong>What Lies Ahead for Yoon and His Party?</strong></h2>

<p>After the martial law was lifted, the entire cabinet offered to resign en masse. Several senior officials in the presidential offices, including the Presidential Chief of Staff, National Security Adviser, Chief of Staff for Policy, and seven others, have already submitted their resignations. The ruling party, PPP, has apologised for the president's decision, stating, “As the ruling party, we deeply apologise to the public for this distressing situation”, while its leader, Han Dong-hoon, has called for immediate action against Defence Minister Kim Yong-hyun, who was instrumental in making the decision alongside the president.</p>

<p>In contrast, the DP, the opposition, has not relented. It has doubled down after this incident and resolved to initiate impeachment proceedings against President Yoon if he refuses to resign immediately, calling his decision a “clear violation of the constitution” and further stating that it constitutes “a serious act of rebellion and a perfect reason for impeachment”.</p>

<p>While the impeachment process may take some time, beginning in the National Assembly and then moving through the Constitutional Court, the first leg of the process is expected to proceed swiftly. Six parties, led by the opposition DP, have already submitted the impeachment bill yesterday, which will be listed today. The impeachment procedure requires a majority to propose a motion and support from two-thirds of the National Assembly for it to pass. Although the DP holds 170 seats in the assembly, it still requires 200 votes to secure the motion. Even with the support of smaller parties, such as the New Reform Party, the number reaches only 192—eight short of the expected total. Even if the motion passes through the National Assembly, the judicial process is likely to take much longer due to the procedural requirements for the Constitutional Court.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the opposition is expected to push for a serious investigation into the procedures surrounding the declaration of martial law, including examining the process behind the summoning of state council meetings for approval, with a view to supporting insurrection charges against the president. Nonetheless, what is certain is that the president's political career is likely over as a result of this decision. It will also have a significant impact on the prospects of his party, which was already plagued by serious allegations and internal conflict before this incident.</p>

<p>However, it remains to be seen whether the PPP, the ruling party, will oppose the president's impeachment, which, if it does, will further damage the party's reputation. On the other hand, adopting a ‘keep-at-arm's-length' approach by distancing itself from the president may help it save face. From this incident, which lasted only six hours, one thing is clear: this political drama has showcased South Korea's remarkable democratic resilience.</p>

<p><em>(Abhishek Sharma is a Research Assistant with ORF and a PhD Candidate&nbsp;in Korean Studies at Delhi University.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nc490tig_so_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-sued-over-slow-deliveries-to-low-income-areas-in-us-7175565]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Sued Over Slow Deliveries To Low-Income Areas In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-sued-over-slow-deliveries-to-low-income-areas-in-us-7175565]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:50:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The attorney general of the US District of Columbia sued Amazon, accusing it of violating consumer protection laws by making slower deliveries to Prime members in historically lower-income neighbourhoods.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The attorney general of the US District of Columbia sued Amazon, accusing it of violating consumer protection laws by making slower deliveries to Prime members in historically lower-income neighbourhoods.</p>

<p>In one of the first complaints of its kind, which was filed with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, Attorney General Brian L. Schwalb on Wednesday said Amazon had deliberately and secretly stopped its fastest delivery service to the nearly 50,000 Prime subscribers in certain ZIP codes that were lower-income neighbourhoods, reports Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>According to the lawsuit, Amazon has used third parties like United Parcel Service and the Postal Service to make Prime deliveries in those areas for the past two years. That resulted in slower deliveries than those made by Amazon's own delivery drivers, who serve other Washington residents.</p>

<p>Amazon "cannot covertly decide that a dollar in one ZIP code is worth less than a dollar in another," Schwalb said in a statement. "We're suing to stop this deceptive conduct and make sure District residents get what they're paying for."</p>

<p>"The suit adds to growing regulatory scrutiny of Amazon's treatment of customers," said The New York Times in its report about the situation. The District of Columbia sued the company in 2021 over price-fixing allegations, a case that an appeals court revived in August. In a suit filed last year, the Federal Trade Commission accused Amazon of illegally protecting a monopoly over swaths of online retail by squeezing merchants and favouring its own services.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/iea3toug_amazon-generic_625x300_17_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Amazon is accused of violating consumer protection laws by making slower deliveries]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-top-100-cities-for-2024-revealed-check-delhis-rank-7176849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Top 100 Cities For 2024 Revealed. Check Delhi's Rank]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-top-100-cities-for-2024-revealed-check-delhis-rank-7176849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:30:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Delhi secured the 74th spot on the list, standing out as one of the highest-ranked Indian cities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paris has been crowned the world's most attractive city for the fourth consecutive year, according to the latest report by data analytics company <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.euromonitor.com/press/press-releases/december-2024/euromonitor-international-reveals-worlds-top-100-city-destinations-for-2024" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Euromonitor International</em></a>. The ranking evaluates cities based on 55 metrics across six key pillars: economic and business performance, tourism performance, tourism infrastructure, policy and attractiveness, health and safety, and sustainability.</p>

<p>Delhi secured the 74th spot on the list, standing out as one of the highest-ranked Indian cities.</p>

<p>The 2024 report highlights Madrid in second place, Tokyo third, Rome fourth, and Milan rounding out the top five. The rest of the top 10 include New York (sixth), Amsterdam (seventh), Sydney (eighth), Singapore (ninth), and Barcelona (10th).</p>

<p>In terms of international arrivals, Bangkok emerged as the most visited city with 32 million arrivals in 2024, followed by Istanbul (23 million), London (21.7 million), Hong Kong (20.5 million), and Mecca (19.3 million).</p>

<p>Euromonitor International attributes Paris's dominance to its robust tourism offerings, further boosted by hosting major events like the Summer Olympic Games in 2024. Meanwhile, Europe remained the most popular region, attracting 793 million international trips this year.</p>

<p>At the other end of the rankings, Cairo was placed 100th, with Zhuhai at 99th and Jerusalem at 98th.</p>

<p>The report also highlighted a global surge in international arrivals, which grew by 19% in 2024, driven by strong tourism demand post-pandemic.&nbsp; The most visited city in terms of international arrivals is Bangkok, with 32 million in 2024.</p>

<p>Euromonitor International said, "The city surpassed the pre-pandemic level of international tourism flows in 2023 and continued dynamic growth of over 30 per cent in 2024."</p>

<p>The rest of the top five for international arrivals include Istanbul (second, 23million/up 14 per cent); London (third, 21.7million/up seven per cent); Hong Kong (fourth, 20.5million/up 19 per cent) and Mecca (fifth, 19.3million/up 20 per cent).</p>

<p>Rounding out the top 10 are Antalya (sixth), Dubai (seventh), Macau (eighth), Paris (ninth) and Kuala Lumpur (10th).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fnh23vlo_paris_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The report also highlighted a global surge in international arrivals]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/raw-milk-recall-in-california-expands-after-bird-flu-virus-detection-7175947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Raw Milk Recall In California Expands After Bird Flu Virus Detection]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/raw-milk-recall-in-california-expands-after-bird-flu-virus-detection-7175947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:26:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Public health officials in the western US state of California said they have secured a broad, voluntary recall of all raw milk and cream products from a local dairy farm due to possible bird flu contamination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Public health officials in the western US state of California said they have secured a broad, voluntary recall of all raw milk and cream products from a local dairy farm due to possible bird flu contamination.</p>

<p>The California Department of Public Health said in a news release on Tuesday night that the statewide recall includes all Raw Farm, LLC raw milk and cream remaining on retail shelves.</p>

<p>The department warned consumers against consuming any raw milk products from the quarantined farm, reports Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>The move followed two limited recalls of Raw Farm products after bird flu was first detected in samples of raw milk produced by Fresno-based Raw Farm on November 21.</p>

<p>Officials said that Raw Farm milk products have tested positive for bird flu at both retail and dairy storage and bottling sites in recent days.</p>

<p>The California Department of Public Health said that customers "should immediately return any remaining product to the retail point of purchase."</p>

<p>In addition, public health officials urged consumers "to avoid consuming any Raw Farm products for human consumption including raw milk, cream, cheese, and kefir, as well as raw milk pet food topper and pet food kefir marketed to pet owners."</p>

<p>The California Department of Food and Agriculture has placed the farm under quarantine, suspending any new distribution of its raw milk, cream, kefir, butter and cheese products produced on or after November 27.</p>

<p>Public health experts have long warned consumers against consuming raw milk or raw milk products due to elevated risks of foodborne illness. The California Department of Public Health noted in its news release that no human bird flu cases associated with the product have been confirmed to date, and the state is working closely with federal and local partners to investigate the situation and better understand how it might impact consumers.</p>

<p>"California continues to monitor and respond to bird flu outbreaks in dairy cows and poultry," said the department, adding that "bird flu virus levels have been demonstrated to be high in raw milk from infected cows, and sporadic human cases identified in workers in close contact with infected dairy cows and their milk indicate that raw milk is infectious to humans."</p>

<p>So far, 58 human cases of H5 bird flu have been reported in the United States during 2024, with 32 in California, according to the latest data released by the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/p29t6jh8_milk-generic_625x300_21_November_22.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Officials said that Raw Farm milk products have tested positive for bird flu.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-video-of-attack-on-sufi-shrine-shared-as-temple-vandalised-in-bangladesh-7176582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Of Attack On Sufi Shrine Shared As Temple Vandalised In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-video-of-attack-on-sufi-shrine-shared-as-temple-vandalised-in-bangladesh-7176582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:49:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[BOOM found that the incident in the viral video is from an attack on a Sufi shrine in Kazipur, Sirajganj, Bangladesh in August 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Claim:&nbsp;</strong>Video shows a Hindu temple being attacked in Bangladesh</p>

<p><strong>Fact Check:&nbsp;</strong>BOOM found that the incident in the viral video is from an attack on a Sufi shrine in Kazipur, Sirajganj, Bangladesh in August 2024. BOOM Bangladesh reached out to a local reporters who confirmed the location and stated that it is a Sufi shrine and not a Hindu temple.</p>

<p>A video of a mob vandalising a Sufi shrine in Bangladesh in August this year is being shared as an attack on a Hindu temple in the country.</p>

<p>The incident in the video is from August 2024 when the Sufi shrine of Ali Pagla in Kazipur, Sirajganj in Bangladesh was vandalised.</p>

<p>BOOM Bangladesh reached out to a local reporters who confirmed the location and stated that it is a Sufi shrine and not a Hindu temple. Bangladesh has been in a state of flux since former prime minister Sheikh Hasina was forced to flee the country in early August following widespread protests.</p>

<p><strong>Viral video from Bangladesh shared with false claim</strong></p>

<p>The two minutes-long video is being shared on X with the caption, "Hindu temple status in Bangladesh yesterday."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Click here to view, and here for an archive." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/i0hoh68o_fact-check-hindu-temple-in-bangladesh-_625x300_05_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Click here to view, and here for an archive." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Click <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/Mahaveer_VJ/status/1863533045376074116">here </a>to view, and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://perma.cc/2UT6-W9P8?type=standard">here </a>for an archive.</p>
</div>

<p><strong>FACT-CHECK: Structure in viral video attacked is a Sufi shrine</strong></p>

<p>BOOM found that the viral video is from August 2024 when Sufi shrine of Ali Pagla in Kazipur, Sirajganj in Bangladesh, was attacked and vandalised.</p>

<p>Taking a hint from <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/Mrityun91255972/status/1863501729641460172">replies </a>stating that the location in the viral video is not a temple but a Sufi shrine named Ali Pagla in Sirajganj, Bangladesh, we found several Bangladeshi news reports on the incident. The reports stated that Ali Pagla mazhar was vandalised on August 29, 2024.</p>

<p>We found a news report by Kalbela which had reported that the incident in the viral video is from August 31, 2024. The report also has a screengrab that matches the visuals in the video.</p>

<p>The report mentioned that in Kazipur, Sirajganj, Bangladesh, villagers had sacked the imam of a mosque in the area after the shrine was attacked allegedly by his men. The report states that several people in the area had claimed that Imam Golam Rabbani and his men had vandalised the shrine of Ali Pagla on August 29.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Click here to view" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pqddv988_fact-check-_625x300_05_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Click here to view" />&nbsp;</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Click <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.kalbela.com/country-news/116989">here </a>to view</p>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;<strong>Local journalists confirm to BOOM Bangladesh the location of the video</strong></p>

<p>BOOM Bangladesh reached out to Abdul Jaleel, a local journalist from Sirajganj, Kazipur, who confirmed that the viral video is from Ali Paglar Mazhar, Sirajganj. Daily Star correspondent Shahidul Islam Nirob, also confirmed to BOOM Bangladesh that the video is from Ali Paglar Mazhar and stated that it is not a Hindu temple as being falsely claimed. The visuals in the below news report on the shrine being vandalised also match the visuals viral video. From the 2.50 minutes timestamp we can see the shrine being attacked with the steel rods.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XJDiNJM4UpI?si=AAR1bnx8oXSZ-7uy" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p><em>(This story was originally published by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.boomlive.in/fact-check/hindu-temple-attacked-bangladesh-video-old-sufi-shrine-vandalised-fake-news-27167" target="_blank">Boom</a>, and republished by NDTV as part of the Shakti Collective)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/n17blp7o_fact-check-hindu-temple-in-bangladesh-_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-game-woman-jailed-for-after-boyfriend-dies-during-hide-and-seek-7176546]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deadly Game: US Woman Jailed After Boyfriend Dies In Hide-And-Seek Game]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-game-woman-jailed-for-after-boyfriend-dies-during-hide-and-seek-7176546]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:41:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida woman received a life sentence after being found guilty of killing her boyfriend by locking him in a suitcase and leaving him to suffocate, amid a background of domestic and alcohol-related issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An American woman from Florida has been sentenced to life in prison for the 2020 death of her boyfriend, whom she trapped in a suitcase and left to suffocate. The sentence was given on Monday by Circuit Judge Michael Kraynick in Orlando. Sarah Boone, 47, was convicted of killing 42-year-old Jorge Torres.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/CollinRugg/status/1863710143722164260">tragic incident occurred on 24 February 2020</a> at Winter Park, when Boone and Torres, both intoxicated, engaged in a game of hide-and-seek. Boone reportedly zipped in Torres into a suitcase leaving him there, which led to his death by asphyxiation. The case had a history of marital strife and alcohol abuse between the couple.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/miami/news/florida-woman-sentenced-to-life-for-zipping-boyfriend-into-suitcase-suffocating-him/"><em>CBS News,</em></a> a jury deliberated only 90 minutes on October 25 before convicting Boone of the second-degree murder of Jorge Torres after a 10-day trial. Boone had insisted she was herself a victim of domestic violence at the hands of Torres and had rejected a plea deal offer of a 15-year sentence. Torres' family members testified at the hearing that his death had torn them apart.</p>

<p>"Sarah deserves to rot in jail," said a sister, Victoria Torres. "Sarah has caused a lifetime of pain."</p>

<p>In her own statement, Boone went through a litany of abuse by Torres she said occurred over many years, decried the way her trial was handled and covered by the media, yet asked forgiveness for her actions.</p>

<p>"I forgive myself for falling in love with a monster. I tried breaking the spell ... I never stopped loving him," said Boone, who has been in jail for 58 months. "I didn't mean for this to happen. Forgive me Jorge. Forgive me Torres family."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tmsuh7c8_boone-and-torres_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sarah Boone (left) suffocated boyfriend Jorge Torres while he was trapped in suitcase.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-stands-by-forecast-after-ceo-exit-vows-to-be-thriftier-7176428]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Intel Stands By Forecast After CEO Exit, Vows To Be Thriftier]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-stands-by-forecast-after-ceo-exit-vows-to-be-thriftier-7176428]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:21:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Intel Corp, fresh off the abrupt departure of Chief Executive Officer Pat Gelsinger, stuck with its current financial forecast during a presentation Wednesday while also saying it would keep a tight rein on capital spending.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Intel Corp., fresh off the abrupt departure of Chief Executive Officer Pat Gelsinger, stuck with its current financial forecast during a presentation Wednesday while also saying it would keep a tight rein on capital spending.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We stand by the guidance that we gave at earnings," Chief Financial Officer and interim Co-CEO Dave Zinsner said during the UBS Global Technology and AI Conference on Wednesday. He also said that Intel's "core strategy" remains intact.</p>

<p>Still, he and Intel executive Naga Chandrasekaran offered a vision for the company that included a more conservative approach to capital spending - something that had been a concern for investors during Gelsinger's tenure.</p>

<p>"There's a significant cultural change that has to happen," said Chandrasekaran, a Micron Technology Inc. veteran who oversees Intel's manufacturing operations and supply chain. The company previously made as many chips as were needed to satisfy demand, an approach Chandrasekaran called "no wafer left behind." Intel now needs to embrace the attitude of "no capital left behind," he said.</p>

<p>Intel announced Gelsinger's retirement on Monday, less than four years after he took the job. His departure came after the board gave him the option to retire or be removed, Bloomberg reported earlier, citing people familiar with the matter. Last month, the company said that sales would be $13.3 billion to $14.3 billion in the current quarter, compared with an average analyst estimate at the time of $13.6 billion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the UBS event, the executives said that Intel would continue Gelsinger's strategy of turning the company into a "world-class" foundry - a maker of chips for outside clients. Intel also has no concerns about its Chips Act grant, Zinsner said. The Santa Clara, California-based company is set to get about $7.9 billion in awards as part of a federal program meant to revitalize the domestic semiconductor industry.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's an ironclad agreement," Zinsner said. He also noted that much of the Chips Act incentives will come in the form of tax credits, rather than grants, and the incoming Trump administration "values manufacturing."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ucgoc31_intel-reuters_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Intel announced Pat Gelsinger's retirement, less than four years after he took the job.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-keir-starmer-offers-plan-for-change-to-deliver-on-poll-pledges-7176396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Keir Starmer Offers 'Plan For Change' To Deliver On Poll Pledges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-keir-starmer-offers-plan-for-change-to-deliver-on-poll-pledges-7176396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:17:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Keir Starmer will unveil a "plan for change" for Britain on Thursday as he attempts a de-facto relaunch of his government following a bumpy first five months in power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer will unveil a "plan for change" for Britain on Thursday as he attempts a de-facto relaunch of his government following a bumpy first five months in power.</p>

<p>The Labour leader is to lay out "ambitious milestones" on which voters can judge his administration, seeking to move on from several unpopular decisions that have overshadowed his young premiership.</p>

<p>"Mission-led government does not mean picking milestones because they are easy or will happen anyway," Mr Starmer, who entered office in July, is set to say in a speech near London.</p>

<p>"It means relentlessly driving real improvements in the lives of working people."</p>

<p>Mr Starmer's first weeks were dominated by controversies over scrapping winter fuel payments for millions of pensioners, keeping a child benefit restriction, and for accepting gifts from a wealthy donor.</p>

<p>They were also overshadowed by the departure of his chief of staff Sue Gray following intense media scrutiny over her role and reports of factional in-fighting inside Number 10.</p>

<p>His finance minister's debut budget on October 30 failed to provide a more positive narrative after coverage focused on farmers and business owners angry at increases in inheritance tax and employer payroll contributions.</p>

<p>Critics say the business tax rise, an increase in the national minimum wage, and plans for higher state borrowing will undermine the Labour government's overriding mission to fire up an anaemic economy.</p>

<p>"Some may oppose what we are doing and no doubt there will be obstacles along the way," the premier was due to say in his speech, according to excerpts released by Downing Street.</p>

<p>"But this government was elected on a mandate of change and our plan reflects the priorities of working people."</p>

<p>The speech comes amid plunging approval ratings for the government and a week after Mr Starmer suffered his first ministerial resignation when Louise Haigh quit the transport brief after it emerged she had pleaded guilty to a criminal offence before she became a lawmaker.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer's spokespeople insist his speech forms the next phase of his plan for "a decade of national renewal", after the first stage focused on "fixing the foundations" of the country.</p>

<p>The premier has repeatedly claimed that he is taking "tough decisions" because the former Conservative administration bequeathed Labour a dire inheritance across several sectors after 14 consecutive years in power.</p>

<p>Labour accuses the Tories of leaving behind a &amp;#163;22-billion "black hole" in the public finances ($28-billion), a prison system bursting at the seams and a National Health Service (NHS) on its knees.</p>

<h2><strong>'Honest'</strong></h2>

<p>Mr Starmer's government highlights several policies already announced, including the launching of a publicly owned clean energy company and the lifting of a ban on new onshore wind farms.</p>

<p>It has also strengthened workers' rights and moved to cut planning regulations to help build 1.5 million new homes, while Mr Starmer has visited more than a dozen countries to repair relations damaged by Brexit.</p>

<p>Westminster is very much viewing his speech as a "reset", however, with UK newspapers reporting that he is likely to revise some pledges made during his successful general election campaign.</p>

<p>The prime minister is expected to drop a promise to make Britain the fastest-growing economy in the G7 and replace it with targets to improve living standards.</p>

<p>He is also expected to set a target for NHS waiting lists and will announce his intention to put an extra 13,000 police on Britain's streets to crack down on anti-social behaviour.</p>

<p>"It's about trying to use language that is going to connect with voters," Patrick Diamond, a policy adviser when Labour was last in Number 10, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's going to be a set of commitments that voters can tangibly judge whether or not the government's really making an impact," added Mr Diamond, now a professor at Queen Mary University of London.</p>

<p>Milestones risk becoming millstones, however. Mr Starmer's predecessor Rishi Sunak was hampered by his failure to meet key pledges.</p>

<p>"This plan for change is the most ambitious yet honest programme for government in a generation," Mr Starmer was to say.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fgtlk7t8_uk-keir-starmer-afp_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer's first weeks were dominated by controversies over scrapping winter fuel payments]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/britney-spears-reveals-she-moved-to-mexico-to-get-away-from-cruel-paparazzi-7176339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Britney Spears Reveals She Moved To Mexico To Escape "Cruel" Paparazzi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/britney-spears-reveals-she-moved-to-mexico-to-get-away-from-cruel-paparazzi-7176339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:10:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 'Oops!... I Did It Again' singer in her clip said that the media have always been cruel to her]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singer Britney Spears recently revealed in an Instagram video that she relocated to Mexico to escape "cruel" paparazzi attention. "It really kind of hurts my feelings that the paparazzi make my face look like I'm wearing like a white Jason mask, and it doesn't even look like me," Spears said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 'Oops!... I Did It Again' singer in her clip said that the media have always been cruel to her. "They've always been incredibly cruel to me, the paparazzi and pictures and the way they've illustrated me to be in some of it. I know I'm not perfect at all, by any means, but some of it is extremely mean and cruel, and that's why I've moved to Mexico," she said in the video.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 'Toxic' singer shared a separate clip on the same day acknowledging her birthday on December 2, "I'm turning five this year. I'm turning five years old, and I have to go to kindergarten tomorrow," she said.</p>

<p><strong>See the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by XILA MARIA RIVER RED (@britneyspears)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, Spears is not the only person who has moved out of the US. In November, actress and film producer Eva Longoria revealed that she, her husband Jose Baston, and their six-year-old son Santiago are splitting their time between living in Spain and Mexico City, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/britney-spears-moved-mexico-paparazzi-b2658782.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Independent </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an interview with <em>Marie Claire</em>, the actress said that she noticed Los Angeles was changing to the point where she no longer wanted to live there.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I had my whole adult life here," she said about California. "But even before [the pandemic], it was changing. The vibe was different. And then Covid happened, and it pushed it over the edge. Whether it's the homelessness or the taxes, not that I want to s*** on California - it just feels like this chapter in my life is done now."</p>

<p>The actress acknowledged that she is "privileged" to be able to move countries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I get to escape and go somewhere. Most Americans aren't so lucky. They're going to be stuck in this dystopian country, and my anxiety and sadness is for them."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/7vv803r_britney-spears-afp_625x300_25_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Spears is not the only person who has moved out of the US]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bryan-thompson-unitedhealthcare-quiet-walk-silencer-on-gun-how-unitedhealthcare-ceo-was-murdered-7176331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Quiet Walk, Silencer on Gun: How UnitedHealthcare CEO Was Murdered]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bryan-thompson-unitedhealthcare-quiet-walk-silencer-on-gun-how-unitedhealthcare-ceo-was-murdered-7176331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:08:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The CEO of US-based UnitedHealthcare, Brian Thompson, was gunned down outside a New York hotel on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The CEO of US-based UnitedHealthcare, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-received-death-threats-before-being-killed-reveals-wife-7174451#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Brian Thompson</a>, was gunned down outside a New York hotel on Wednesday. Mr Thompson, 50, was walking toward the New York Hilton Midtown, where he was set to deliver a keynote address at an investor conference when he was ambushed. Surveillance footage captured the suspect - a white man wearing a hooded jacket, a black face mask, and sneakers -approaching Thompson from behind.</p>

<p>According to the NYPD, the gunman fired multiple shots using a semi-automatic handgun equipped with a silencer in the bustling Midtown Manhattan area.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NYC has some of the strictest gun laws. That doesn't prevent the execution of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson by a gunman using a gun with a silencer attached.<br />
It appears overreaching gun laws don't work.<br />
Murderers don't care about laws.<br />
Go figure. <a href="https://t.co/qhcP7Ty6lP">pic.twitter.com/qhcP7Ty6lP</a></p>
— Chris Randolph (@TrumpAF2024) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpAF2024/status/1864391488198619202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Initial shots struck Mr Thompson in the back and leg, causing him to stagger and collapse against a wall. Despite the firearm jamming three times, the shooter cleared the weapon and continued firing. After ensuring Mr Thompson was incapacitated, the attacker calmly walked away, later fleeing the scene on an electric bike toward Central Park.</p>

<p>Officers responded to a 911 call, arriving to find Mr Thompson on the sidewalk with critical gunshot wounds. He was rushed to a nearby hospital, where he was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>Surveillance footage revealed the suspect had been near the scene for several minutes before the attack, blending in with morning commuters. Earlier, at 6:17 am, cameras captured the gunman at a nearby Starbucks, purchasing water and power bars while wearing a surgical mask.</p>

<p>According to the CNN, police recovered a water bottle and a phone from an alley near the shooting site, believed to have been discarded by the suspect. Investigators are analysing the phone for potential fingerprints, DNA, or communication records that might reveal the killer's identity.</p>

<p>UnitedHealth Group, the parent company of UnitedHealthcare, issued a heartfelt statement mourning Mr Thompson's loss:</p>

<p>"We are deeply saddened and shocked at the passing of our dear friend and colleague Brian Thompson, the CEO of UnitedHealthcare," UnitedHealth Group said in a statement.</p>

<p>Mr Thompson's wife, Paulette, described the attack as "senseless" and mentioned her husband had received threats in the past, CNN reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The NYPD has released images of the suspect and is offering a $10,000 reward for information leading to his capture. The attacker is described as a white male in his 30s or 40s, wearing a gray backpack, black-and-white sneakers, and a hooded jacket.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8t1vf4t_unitedhealthcare-ceo_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the NYPD, the gunman fired multiple shots using a semi-automatic handgun.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/marcela-alcazar-rodriguez-actress-dies-at-mexican-spiritual-retreat-after-consuming-deadly-monkey-frog-venom-7176328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Actress Dies At Spiritual Retreat After Consuming Deadly Monkey Frog Venom]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/marcela-alcazar-rodriguez-actress-dies-at-mexican-spiritual-retreat-after-consuming-deadly-monkey-frog-venom-7176328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:04:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mexican short film actress Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez tragically passed away after participating in a Kambo cleansing ritual at a spiritual retreat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Faith holds great significance, but when it lacks rational thinking, it can lead to tragic consequences. This was the case for Mexican short film actress Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez, who sadly lost her life after vomiting and suffering from diarrhoea on December 1 after participating in a cleansing ritual at a retreat. The ritual involved ingesting the venom of the Amazonian giant monkey frog, known as Kambo.</p>

<p>The young actress was attending a spiritual retreat ceremony in Mexico as part of a Healer Training Diploma program when she consumed a drink called Kombo. This drink, which contains frog poison from South America, is traditionally used by indigenous communities for toxin cleansing but is banned in some countries.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/12/05/actress-vomits-amazon-frog-venom-spiritual-cleansing-dies-22124674/"><em>The Metro,</em></a> Rodriguez started throwing up and had severe diarrhoea, which are part of the body's reactions while going through the healing.' She first refused help while feeling ill but eventually gave in when her friend came to see her, witnesses said.Rodriguez was rushed to a Red Cross hospital, where she died.</p>

<p>It was not immediately known how long it took for her to arrive at the hospital. She was identified by the Mexican production company Mapache Films, which posted a tribute to her on Instagram.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Mapache Films (@mapache_films)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>"With deep regret, we mourn the death of our beloved colleague and friend, Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez,' stated the production company in Spanish. Her passing left an immense vacuum in our hearts and in our professional community. Her dedication, joy, and commitment left a profound mark on all of us who had the privilege of working beside her."</p>

<p>This unfortunate incident has ignited discussions about the dangers of such traditional practices and their increasing popularity among wellness seekers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fc4389n_marcela-alcazar-rodriguez_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez was rushed to a hospital but could not be saved.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-billionaire-yi-zhengs-royalflush-trading-app-is-big-winner-of-stimulus-7176207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Billionaire's RoyalFlush Trading App Is Big Winner Of Stimulus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-billionaire-yi-zhengs-royalflush-trading-app-is-big-winner-of-stimulus-7176207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:48:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The tycoon behind China's RoyalFlush trading app has added $6 billion to his wealth since the nation's stimulus blitz in September, underscoring how the volatility has been a boon for an elite few.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The tycoon behind China's RoyalFlush trading app has added $6 billion to his wealth since the nation's stimulus blitz in September, underscoring how the volatility has been a boon for an elite few.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yi Zheng, an engineering graduate who founded the entity behind Hithink RoyalFlush Information Network Co. in 1994, four years after China's stock exchanges opened, is overseeing his company's best share performance in half a decade after trading of mainland stocks surged.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While Yi's fortune is up 190% since the announcements, it's not yet clear if the sweeping measures will meaningfully lift the nation's $10 trillion stock market after a turbulent couple of months.</p>

<p>The 54-year-old is now worth $9.2 billion, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index. That's largely based on his 36% stake in the company, which also sells financial data. Its shares have more than doubled this year and are on track for the best year since 2019. Volatility on China's benchmark CSI 300 Index had spiked in the past two months, with a 30-day gauge jumping to the highest since 2015, when Asia's largest economy experienced an epic boom and bust in stocks.</p>

<p>Home to the world's second largest stock market, China has allowed trading and software entrepreneurs to accumulate vast fortunes. East Money Information Co., Hithink's biggest domestic competitor, grew more valuable than Credit Suisse in 2020 after frenzied trading in China, making founder Qi Shi a billionaire several times over. The Swiss bank was eventually taken over by rival UBS Group AG. Online broker Futu Holdings Ltd, which has customers in the US, China and Hong Kong, has created vast wealth for founder Li Hua.</p>

<p>That growth has also been marked by stumbles. In 2021, the legitimacy of online brokerages, which had allowed millions of Chinese investors to evade capital controls to trade shares in markets such as Hong Kong and New York, was abruptly questioned. Financial data providers like Hithink have also drawn scrutiny.</p>

<p><strong>Explosive Growth</strong></p>

<p>In October, 6.85 million accounts were opened in China's mainland A-share market - versus the monthly average of 1.5 million in the first nine months of 2024, according to data from HSBC Qianhai Securities.</p>

<p>Hithink has more than 19 million active users per week on its free trading platform, according to the company's website. The Hangzhou, Zhejiang-based company reported revenue of 3.6 billion yuan ($495 million) in 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The recent stimulus has resulted in higher stock trading volume, which could boost demand for better financial information from retail investors," said Yiran Liu, an analyst at HSBC Qianhai Securities.</p>

<p>China's stimulus, which included interest rate cuts, more cash for banks, bigger incentives to buy homes and plans to consider a stock stabilization fund, led to the nation's benchmark index gaining about a third to peak on Oct. 8. It has since given up some of those gains amid concerns about the economy and US President-elect Donald Trump's tariff threats.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hithink also generates revenue through selling funds and software. For a fee, retail investors on the RoyalFlush app can use AI to find the right price to enter and sell stock positions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yi and Hithink didn't respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yi was born in 1970 in Beijing, and his own success is largely tied to the development of the nation's stock markets. He graduated from Zhejiang University with a bachelor's degree in electrical engineering in 1993. While still a student, he developed a securities software for Industrial &amp; Commercial Bank of China Ltd, according to local media reports.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China's two stock exchanges were founded in 1990. In 1994, Yi co-founded Hangzhou Hexin Software Technology Ltd., now a key unit of his Hithink, and made an early win with the Longhubang, or Dragon and Tiger Ranking, which tracked futures contracts to give traders an indication of market sentiment.</p>

<p>In 1997, Yi ventured into developing a securities trading platform, which later morphed into Hithink's signature product. Hithink still uses Longhubang for its listings of the most active traders and stocks.</p>

<p><strong>Royal Flush</strong></p>

<p>The firm's Chinese name Tonghuashun translates to Royal Flush, the best hand in poker. It first debuted in late 2009 on China's Shenzhen Stock Exchange. Its shares have soared more than 4900% since the listing.</p>

<p>The listed entity has since evolved to become a top financial data provider in China, with over 5,000 employees.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But there were bumps along the way. Hithink was caught last month in China's crackdown on influencers and livestreaming platforms that offer investment advice. It was ordered to suspend its investment advisory service unit from adding new clients for three months.</p>

<p>The firm was also investigated by the market regulator in 2015 and fined 6.53 million yuan for selling securities trading systems to unqualified investors.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7t4k19ig_royalflush-bloomberg_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yi Zheng is now worth $9.2 billion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-prince-harry-said-on-separation-rumours-with-meghan-markle-7176109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Prince Harry Said On Separation Rumours With Meghan Markle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-prince-harry-said-on-separation-rumours-with-meghan-markle-7176109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:43:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over the last few months, whenever Prince Harry and Meghan Markle made solo public appearances, the media and royal family observers wondered if there was trouble in their marriage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few months, whenever Prince Harry and Meghan Markle made solo public appearances, the media and royal family observers wondered if there was trouble in their marriage.</p>

<p>And now, Prince Harry has finally addressed all the rumours, saying, “Apparently we've bought or moved houses 10, 12 times. We've apparently divorced maybe 10, 12 times as well. So it's just like, what?”<br />
<br />
At The New York Times' 2024 DealBook Summit in New York City on Wednesday, Harry, 40, discussed his life and speculations surrounding his marriage with Meghan, 43.<br />
<br />
At the Summit, DealBook founder Andrew Ross Sorkin asked Harry about the interest many have in the couple's personal life. He shared that when he searched his name on Google News, "there were people fascinated by everything you're doing, all the time. They're fascinated by Meghan being in California right now, and you're here,” Sorkin said.<br />
<br />
Asked why the couple was doing independent events and not together, Harry said, "Because you invited me, you should have known!”&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Sorkin then continued, "True... Is that normal for you? The second there's an article — she's in California, you're in New York — they say, ‘Well, what is happening with these two, right?' Is that a good thing for you, in a way, that there's so much interest in you?”<br />
<br />
To this, Harry replied, "No, that's definitely not a good thing."<br />
<br />
Although Harry admitted that it was hard to keep up with, he tries to ignore it.<br />
<br />
“It's hard to keep up with, but that's why you just sort of ignore it. The people I feel most sorry about are the trolls...Their hopes are just built and built, and it's like, ‘Yes, yes, yes,' and then it doesn't happen. So I feel sorry for them. Genuinely, I do.”<br />
<br />
He further said he had “no doubt” that his interview with Sorkin “will be spun or twisted somehow against me," adding that maybe "the host will also be trolled relentlessly.”<br />
<br />
“For that, I can only apologise, but you did invite me, so it's not my fault,” he quipped.<br />
<br />
The divorce rumours started when the Duke and Duchess of Sussex were seen appearing separately at various professional engagements. While many called it a “professional separation,” the move was said to be a new “twin-track” approach that could overhaul their image, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/04/entertainment/prince-harry-breaks-silence-on-meghan-markle-divorce-rumors/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Post</a> reported.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/7ij5uja8_prince-harry-meghan-markle_625x300_11_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prince Harry discussed his life and speculations surrounding his marriage with Meghan Markle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/he-has-spent-months-in-capsule-under-the-sea-for-a-world-record-7176160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Home Under The Sea With A Bed, Toilet, TV: All That Is Missing Is...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/he-has-spent-months-in-capsule-under-the-sea-for-a-world-record-7176160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:41:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rudiger Koch has been living in a submerged capsule off the coast of Panama for two months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are probably easier ways to set a world record, but Rudiger Koch has found his method 11 meters (36 feet) under the sea.</p>

<p>He's been living in a submerged capsule off the coast of Panama for two months -- which means, he told a visiting AFP journalist, he has about two more to go.</p>

<p>"The last time I checked, I was still married," he joked, as fish swim through bright blue Caribbean waters outside the portholes.</p>

<p>But Koch, a 59-year-old aerospace engineer from Germany, has grander plans than simply notching a record. His stunt, he says, could change the way we think about human life -- and where we can settle, even permanently.</p>

<p>"Moving out to the ocean is something we should do as a species," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"What we are trying to do here is prove that the seas are actually a viable environment for human expansion."</p>

<p>Koch's 30-square-meter (320-square-foot) capsule has most of the trappings of modern life: a bed, toilet, TV, computer and internet -- even an exercise bike.</p>

<p>The only thing missing? A shower.</p>

<p>His home under the sea is attached through a vertical tube to another chamber perched above the waves, housing other members of his team -- and providing a way for food and curious journalists to be sent down.</p>

<p>The underwater chamber, meanwhile, provides a shelter for fish and acts as an artificial reef -- providing an environmental benefit.</p>

<p>"In the night, you can hear all the crustaceans," he said. "There's the fish out there, and there's all that stuff, and that wasn't here before we came."</p>

<p><strong>A window into the sea</strong></p>

<p>On a small bedside table lies Jules Verne's "Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea," a 19th century sci-fi classic.</p>

<p>An admirer of the novel's Captain Nemo, Koch, who went down on September 26, is hoping to come up for air on January 24, surpassing by 20 days the record held by American Joseph Dituri, who spent 100 days submerged in a Florida lake.</p>

<p>Two clocks show how much time has passed -- and how much remains.</p>

<p>A narrow spiral staircase leads to the chamber above, the entire contraption located some 15 minutes by boat from the Puerto Lindo coast, off northern Panama.</p>

<p>Four cameras film his moves in the capsule -- capturing his daily life, monitoring his mental health and to provide proof that he's never come up to the surface.</p>

<p>Eial Berja, an Israeli, operates them from the section above, while minding the electricity and back-up generator.</p>

<p>It's not all easy going, he told AFP, noting that a heavy storm almost put an end to the project.</p>

<p>Outside of the media, Koch's only visitors have been his doctor, his children and his wife.</p>

<p>Supporting the project is Grant Romundt, from Canada. Both he and Koch have grander visions linked to the libertarian -- and at-times controversial -- "seasteading" movement that envisions ocean-based communities outside government control.</p>

<p>Though he still has a long way to go to resurface, Koch knows exactly what he'll do first once he's back on land: "a shower, a real shower."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tp1qiimo_german-aerospace-engineer-rudiger-koch_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[German aerospace engineer Rudiger Koch, 59, inside an underwater room off the coast of Puerto Lindo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-ceo-thinks-elon-musk-wont-use-political-power-against-rivals-7176107]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI CEO Thinks Elon Musk Won't Use Political Power Against Rivals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-ceo-thinks-elon-musk-wont-use-political-power-against-rivals-7176107]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:33:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman dismissed concerns that rival Elon Musk might use his newfound political influence to undercut competitors and benefit his own artificial intelligence efforts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman dismissed concerns that rival Elon Musk might use his newfound political influence to undercut competitors and benefit his own artificial intelligence efforts.</p>

<p>“It would be profoundly un-American to use political power to hurt your competitors and advantage your own businesses,” Altman said in an interview at the New York Times DealBook Summit on Wednesday. “I don't think people would tolerate that. I don't think Elon would do it.”</p>

<p>Musk has emerged as a top ally to President-elect Donald Trump and was recently <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-us-government-efficiency-department-donald-trump-7006239" target="_blank">appointed to lead the new Department of Government Efficiency</a> alongside ex-presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Musk and Altman have a tense relationship. Musk, who helped launch OpenAI as a nonprofit, has spent months&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-15/musk-escalates-altman-legal-feud-casting-openai-as-monopolist" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">pursuing litigation</a>&nbsp;against Altman and the ChatGPT maker for allegedly betraying its founding mission. While OpenAI remains the market leader for generative AI products, Musk's company, xAI, has rapidly gained momentum by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-29/musk-s-xai-in-talks-for-40-billion-valuation-wsj-says" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">raising billions</a>&nbsp;from investors.</p>

<p>In the interview Wednesday, Altman called Musk's startup “a serious competitor” to OpenAI and said he had “tremendous respect” for Musk's plans to build an xAI data center in Tennessee. Altman also expressed disappointment at the state of their relationship.</p>

<p>It's “tremendously sad,” he said, when asked about Musk's lawsuit. “I grew up with Elon as a mega hero.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1mq2a6g_openai_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sam Altman called Elon Musks startup "a serious competitor" to OpenAI.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-blank-pure-white-canvas-expected-to-sell-for-over-1-5-million-7176018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Blank 'Pure White' Canvas Expected To Sell For Over $1.5 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-blank-pure-white-canvas-expected-to-sell-for-over-1-5-million-7176018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:19:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 1970 artwork, titled General 52" x 52"- a reference to its dimensions-will be available for bidding at the Ketterer Kunst auction house in Berlin on December 6 and 7.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A blank "pure white" canvas by minimalist American painter Robert Ryman, valued at over $1.5 million, is heading to auction in Germany. The 1970 artwork, titled General 52" x 52"- a reference to its dimensions-will be available for bidding at the Ketterer Kunst auction house in Berlin on December 6 and 7, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/03/lifestyle/blank-pure-white-art-canvas-expected-to-sell-for-over-1-5m/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the canvas appears blank, it is actually painted with white enamel and enamelac, materials typically used for metal surfaces. This choice of medium creates a delicate finish, so sensitive that the piece cannot be transported for viewing prior to the auction, according to the auction house.</p>

<p>"The material is very sensitive and the smallest traces in the flawless surface would immediately reduce the value of the work significantly," said the auction house in a statement. "That's why we are not sending it on a journey."</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KfKvSKxOeo8?si=K8hLZi4t2LNKu7Sf" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Although the piece may appear blank, it invites viewers to uncover deeper meaning. "White is not always white. The white colour reveals the light, movement, and structure of the material," explained Simone Wichmann, an expert at Ketterer Kunst. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Wichmann further noted that Ryman's work transforms the viewer into an active participant. "The viewer is challenged and becomes the creator of the art," she said. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Ryman's minimalist works, while often divisive, have achieved significant acclaim and commanded high prices, with some selling for millions. Remarkably, Ryman was a self-taught artist who worked as a security guard at the Museum of Modern Art in New York before earning recognition for his innovative and thought-provoking pieces. &nbsp;</p>

<p>This auction follows a series of provocative art sales that have fueled public debate. Just last month, Maurizio Cattelan's Comedian- a banana duct-taped to a wall- sold for $6.2 million, only to be eaten by the buyer, a cryptocurrency entrepreneur.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qb21g9lo_blank-canvas_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wichmann further noted that Ryman's work transforms the viewer into an active participant.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-frances-government-felled-in-no-confidence-vote-what-happens-next-7176003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France's Government Ousted In No-Confidence Vote. What Happens Next?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-frances-government-felled-in-no-confidence-vote-what-happens-next-7176003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:15:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The government in France collapsed on Wednesday after lawmakers of both left and right wings joined forces to push a no-confidence against the country's Prime Minister Michel Barnier]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The government in France collapsed on Wednesday after lawmakers of both left and right wings joined forces to push a no-confidence against the country's Prime Minister Michel Barnier, throwing the European Union's second-biggest economic power deeper into chaos that threatens to exacerbate its budgetary and looming economic crises.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister addressed the nation just before the vote, calling it an honour to have served France and its people with dignity. He'd been on the job for just two months and 29 days. With the vote of confidence against him, Mr Barnie will now have to tender his resignation and that of his government to President Emmanuel Macron, making his minority government's tenure the shortest lived in France's Fifth Republic beginning in 1958.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per French media reports, he is expected to do so on Thursday morning. The president will then address the nation at 1900 GMT, the Elysee Palace said.</p>

<h2><strong>Rise and Fall Of Michel Barnier</strong></h2>

<p>Michel Barnier's government fell after 331 deputies voted against him, making him the shortest-serving Prime Minister in modern French political history. Only 288 votes were needed to pass the no-confidence motion in the 577-member chamber. It was the first successful no-confidence vote since a defeat for Georges Pompidou's government in 1962, when Charles de Gaulle was president.</p>

<p>In France, the President nominates prime ministers. However, lawmakers can reject his picks at any time by passing a no-confidence vote, like in the case of Barnier. National Assembly, the French parliament's lower house, is almost equally divided between the far right, a loosely united left-wing, centrists including Macron's allies, and a few candidates who please all three factions, according to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/389827/france-government-collapse-budget-economic-crisis-bernier-macron-le-pen" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Vox</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though not a popular leader, Mr Barnier was seen as a capable choice after the Prime Minister's post following surprise elections this past summer. However, he was met with challenges while trying to lead a government without a majority. He angered lawmakers on both the right and left after he attempted to push through a 2025 national budget without a vote in the lower house of parliament. Amid a standoff over the social security financing bill, France's far-right party and its left-wing alliance each put forward no-confidence motions against him.</p>

<h2><strong>Passage of No Confidence Vote</strong></h2>

<p>The successful vote means President Macron will have to find a new Prime Minister to replace Mr Barnier, which doesn't seem to be an easy affair. A similar situation happened once before in 1962, but the particular situation was dealt with by calling early legislative elections.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, President Macron doesn't have that choice as he has already called called early poll last June. This means he can't call new ones until next July, because under the French Constitution, the National Assembly must remain in place for a minimum of one year.</p>

<p>So for the moment, France has no government. However, it will have caretaker ministers in place, appointed by the President. Amid limited options given the dysfunction in the National Assembly, Emmanuel Macron needs to appoint a new prime minister quickly to pass the government's budget and, hopefully, prevent an economic crisis from engulfing France.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A source close to Macron told news agency AFP that the president, who has taken time with appointments in the past, has "no choice" but to name the new premier within 24 hours.</p>

<h2><strong>Call For Emmanuel Macron's Resignation</strong></h2>

<p>France's hard left on Wednesday urged President Emmanuel Macron to resign and hold early presidential elections after lawmakers voted to oust the government of Prime Minister Michel Barnier.</p>

<p>"We are now calling on Macron to go," Mathilde Panot, the head of the parliamentary faction of the hard-left France Unbowed (LFI) party told reporters, urging "early presidential elections" to solve a deepening political crisis.</p>

<p>But taking care not to crow over the government's fall, Le Pen said in a television interview that her party -- once a new premier is appointed -- "would let them work" and help create a "budget that is acceptable for everyone".</p>

<p>Laurent Wauquiez, the head of right-wing deputies in parliament, said the far right and hard left bore the responsibility for a no-confidence vote that would "plunge the country into instability".</p>

<p>Macron, however, has rejected calls to resign.</p>

<h2><strong>Growing Crisis In France</strong></h2>

<p>With markets nervous and France bracing for public-sector strikes against the threat of cutbacks, action that will shut schools and hit air and rail traffic, there is a growing sense of crisis. The unions have called for civil servants, including teachers and air-traffic controllers, to strike on Thursday over separate cost-cutting measures.</p>

<p>Moreover, Macron is due to host a major international event on Saturday, with the reopening of the Notre-Dame Cathedral after the 2019 fire, with guests including Donald Trump on his first foreign trip since he was elected to be the next US president.</p>

<p>France also risks ending the year without a stable government or a 2025 budget, although the constitution allows special measures that would avert a US-style government shutdown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Any new prime minister appointed by the President would face the same challenges as Barnier in getting bills, including the 2025 budget, adopted by a divided parliament. Macron could alternatively ask Barnier and his ministers to stay on in a caretaker capacity while he takes time to identify a prime minister able to attract sufficient cross-party support to pass legislation.</p>

<p>A caretaker government could either propose emergency legislation to roll the tax-and-spend provisions in the 2024 budget into next year or invoke special powers to pass the draft 2025 budget by decree - though jurists say this is a legal grey area and the political cost would be huge.</p>

<p>This could potentially cause further concerns in markets, which are already unnerving investors in French sovereign bonds and stocks. Earlier this week, France's borrowing costs briefly exceeded those of Greece, generally considered far more risky.&nbsp;</p>

<p>France's political turmoil also threatens to weaken a European Union already reeling from the implosion of Germany's coalition government, weeks before US President-elect Donald Trump returns to the White House.</p>

<p>The country's outgoing defence minister Sebastien Lecornu warned the turmoil could impact French support for Ukraine.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fp3rvmng_french-prime-minister-michel-barnier-reuters_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Michel Barnier now has to tender his resignation to President Macron]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>