<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 15:48:28 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/couple-found-dead-in-lifeboat-off-canadian-coast-6160734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Couple Who Set Sail In Self-Built Eco-Friendly Yacht Found Dead In Lifeboat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/couple-found-dead-in-lifeboat-off-canadian-coast-6160734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 14:58:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brett Clibbery and Sarah Packwood embarked across the Atlantic Ocean, sailing from Halifax to the Azores in their self-built, eco-friendly yacht, Theros.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British-Canadian couple, who set sail across the Atlantic Ocean roughly six weeks ago, were found dead in a lifeboat off the coast of Canada. The bodies of Brett Clibbery and Sarah Packwood were discovered after their raft washed ashore on Sable Island, off the coast of Nova Scotia, reported the&nbsp;<a href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/21/world-news/theories-emerge-on-brett-clibbery-and-sarah-packwood-deaths/ ">NY Post</a>.</p>

<p>The pair had embarked on an ambitious journey across the Atlantic Ocean, sailing from Halifax to the Azores in their self-built, eco-friendly yacht, Theros. The 42-foot vessel, powered solely by electric, wind, and solar energy, was intended to demonstrate the feasibility of sustainable travel. The couple had been posting about the construction of Theros on their YouTube channel, "Theros Adventures," and this voyage was to be their inaugural fully "green" journey.</p>

<p>They left Halifax Harbour on June 11 aboard their yacht bound for the Azores region of Portugal. They were reported missing on June 18 and found three weeks later on July 10.</p>

<p>While initially reported to be from British Columbia, it is believed that Ms Packwood was from the UK and Mr Clibbery was from Canada. Formal identification is still pending.</p>

<p>The cause of death is not yet known. The Royal Canadian Mounted Police are investigating the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Their sailboat, Theros, was severely damaged, and investigators suspected that it was struck by a larger vessel.</p>

<p>The area they were sailing in is notoriously known as the "Graveyard of the Atlantic" due to the large number of shipwrecks that occurred there. The exact circumstances of the incident are still unknown, but investigators are exploring several theories.</p>

<p>One leading theory is that Theros was hit by a bulk carrier, which may have caused significant damage to the sailboat. Investigators have inspected a carrier ship, which was in the same area as Theros at the time of the incident, but they have not released their findings, as per the <a href="https://www.saltwire.com/atlantic-canada/news/ship-may-have-collided-with-couples-sailboat-off-nova-scotia-says-source-they-cant-be-positive-100979604/ ">Saltwire</a>.</p>

<p>The crew of the carrier ship reported that they did not notice any damage or collision, the <a href="https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/world-news/expert-theory-what-caused-deaths-33289850 ">Mirror</a>&nbsp;reported. Some veteran sailors have suggested the homemade additions to Theros may have contributed to the tragedy, particularly the excessive weight of batteries and solar panels, which may have destabilised the boat.</p>

<p>Brett Clibbery and Sarah Packwood met by chance in 2015 at a bus stop in London. At the time, Ms Packwood was preparing to donate a kidney to her sister, while Mr Clibbery was visiting from Canada. This chance encounter led to them eventually falling in love and getting married on their yacht, Theros, in 2016.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/m3jsbq98_theros_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple had left Halifax Harbour on June 11 aboard their yacht. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-democratic-party-chairs-endorse-kamala-harris-as-biden-exits-poll-race-6160804]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All Democratic Party Chairs Endorse Kamala Harris As Biden Exits Poll Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-democratic-party-chairs-endorse-kamala-harris-as-biden-exits-poll-race-6160804]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 14:44:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[State Democratic party chairs on Sunday threw their weight behind Vice President Kamala Harris to be the party's new presidential nominee to run against Republican nominee and former president, Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>State Democratic party chairs on Sunday threw their weight behind Vice President Kamala Harris to be the party's new presidential nominee to run against Republican nominee and former president, Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The chairs held a conference call after President Joe Biden announced he was stepping aside as the party's candidate.</p>

<p>“Following President Biden's announcement, our members immediately assembled to unite behind the candidate who has a track record of winning tough elections, and who is a proven leader on the issues that matter to Americans: reproductive freedom, gun violence prevention, climate protection, justice reform, and rebuilding the economy," said Ken Martin, president of the Association of State Democratic Committees, in a statement.</p>

<p>"That person is our sitting Vice President Kamala Harris."</p>

<p>Reuters reported earlier that the group had backed the vice president, with one source saying there was "full support" for her being at the top of the ticket.</p>

<p>Many Democrats quickly backed Harris to run as the party's presidential nominee against Trump in the November election, but some powerful party members, including former House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi, stayed quiet.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h0ho4s7g_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-and-israel-stand-together-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-before-leaving-for-us-6160574]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Israel's Enemies Know...": Netanyahu On US Ties After Biden's Poll Exit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-and-israel-stand-together-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-before-leaving-for-us-6160574]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 14:14:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel will be the United States' strongest ally in the Middle East regardless of who is elected president in November, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Monday before flying to Washington, where he was due to address the U.S. Congress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel will be the United States' strongest ally in the Middle East regardless of who is elected president in November, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Monday before flying to Washington, where he was due to address the U.S. Congress.</p>

<p>The visit, Netanyahu's first to his most important international ally since returning for a record sixth term as prime minister at the end of 2022, has been overshadowed by President Joe Biden's decision not to seek reelection.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said he would thank Biden for all he has done for Israel throughout his career and discuss with him issues such as securing the release of Israeli hostages in Gaza, defeating the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, and confronting Iran and its proxies in the region.</p>

<p>A meeting with Biden is tentatively planned for Tuesday if the 81-year-old president has recovered from Covid-19. Netanyahu is scheduled to address Congress on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"I will tell my friends on both sides of the aisle that regardless of who the American people choose as their next president, Israel remains America's indispensable and strong ally in the Middle East," he told reporters before taking off.</p>

<p>"In this time of war and uncertainty, it's important that Israel's enemies know that America and Israel stand together today, tomorrow and always," Netanyahu said, adding he wanted to "anchor the bipartisan support that is so important for Israel".</p>

<p>After months of frosty relations with Washington over how Israel has conducted its offensive launched in Gaza after the Hamas-led attack on Oct. 7, the visit offers Netanyahu a platform to try to reset relations with Washington.</p>

<p>His speech to Congress is expected to focus on coordinating the Israeli and U.S. response to the volatile situation in the Middle East, where there is a growing danger of the Gaza war spilling over into a wider regional conflict.</p>

<p>The speech is likely to be less confrontational than an address Netanyahu gave to Congress in 2015, when he criticised Barack Obama's drive as president for a nuclear deal with Iran.</p>

<h3><strong>PRESSURE</strong></h3>

<p>U.S. pressure on Israel for a resumption of talks on reaching a political agreement with the Palestinians, and a U.S. threat to withhold arms, have underlined perceptions in Israel that ties with Washington have weakened under Netanyahu. He has also faced protests in Israel demanding a ceasefire in Gaza.</p>

<p>"Part of the goal is to try to show that with all that's been said, with all the protests, Netanyahu is still the leader, still has support, he still has strong relations with America," said Yonatan Freeman, an international relations specialist at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem.</p>

<p>The invitation for Netanyahu to address a joint meeting of Congress - a rare honour generally reserved for the closest U.S. allies - was orchestrated by the House of Representatives' Republican leadership, which has accused Biden of not showing sufficient support for Israel.</p>

<p>There was no immediate sign that Netanyahu will see Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump. The two forged a close relationship during Trump's presidency but Trump has since criticised Netanyahu and said the Gaza war must end quickly.</p>

<p>Although his welcome in Congress should be generally warm, protests roiling U.S. campuses suggest Netanyahu's reception outside official Washington may be hostile.</p>

<p>Activists opposing Israel's offensive in Gaza and Washington's support for Israel plan protests at the U.S. Capitol on Wednesday. Police expect a "large number of demonstrators" and are making additional security arrangements but said there were no known threats.</p>

<p>Israel has been isolated internationally over its campaign in Gaza, which Gaza health authorities say has killed almost 39,000 Palestinians, the expansion of settlement-building in the occupied West Bank and Jewish settlers' attacks on Palestinians.</p>

<p>An opinion issued on Friday by the International Court of Justice that Israel's occupation of Palestinian territories is illegal was criticised by Washington. But it followed similar developments including a decision by the International Criminal Court's prosecutor to seek an arrest warrant against Netanyahu.</p>

<p>In Israel, Netanyahu faces growing calls for a deal that would halt the fighting in Gaza and allow the return of 120 hostages - alive or dead - still held in the enclave run by the Palestinian operative group Hamas.</p>

<p>Netanyahu has resisted pressure for an inquiry into the security failures before the Oct. 7 attack on Israel in which 1,200 people were killed and over 250 abducted into Gaza.</p>

<p>Opinion polls show most Israelis hold him responsible and would vote him out if elections were held.</p>

<p>Netanyahu will be accompanied by Noa Argamani, a hostage rescued by Israeli commandos last month. Her presence has been criticised by other hostage families who say Netanyahu has not been doing enough to secure the release of their loved ones.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/42v9reng_joe-biden-netanyahu-reuters_650x400_18_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu said he would thank Joe Biden for all he has done for Israel (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starlink-satellites-could-be-destroyed-if-what-china-study-says-6160562]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Starlink Satellites Could Be Destroyed If...": What China Study Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starlink-satellites-could-be-destroyed-if-what-china-study-says-6160562]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 14:12:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The research by Wang Dan, a professor with the Naval Submarine Academy, was published last month in the Chinese-language journal, Command Control & Simulation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's Starlink has been covering the empty space above the Earth with its satellites with a plan to provide internet to the remotest corner of the planet. But a study in China has claimed that People Liberation Army's (PLA's) submarines equipped with laser would be able to destroy these satellites if the country's security was at risk. According to <em>South China Morning Post (SCMP)</em>, the study has been conducted by the scientists of PLA. It further said that such submarines will be produced in large numbers and deployed in various oceans to counter military threats to China.</p>

<p>The undersea vehicles will have the capability to remain submerged in water with a retractable "optoelectronic mast" coming out and firing at the target, the study further said.</p>

<p>The research by Wang Dan, a professor with the Naval Submarine Academy, was published last month in the Chinese-language journal, Command Control &amp; Simulation, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3270890/china-could-attack-starlink-satellites-submarine-laser-weapon-naval-study">the <em>SCMP</em> report</a>.</p>

<p>The entire project has been planned to hide the location of the attack vehicles (or submarines). Currently, missile launches are often accompanied by long trails of smoke, which can reveal the position of the attack vehicle. The team said this is too risky.</p>

<p>"Currently, the primary means of anti-satellite operations relies on ground-to-air missiles, but this approach has certain issues, mainly in terms of concealment," <em>SCMP</em> quoted Ms Ms Wang and her colleagues as saying in the study.</p>

<p>"Taking the satellites launched by the Starlink programme as an example, they are numerous, densely packed and small in size, making the satellite network extremely resilient. Even if a significant number of satellites are destroyed, there are redundancies to replace them. Therefore, using missiles to attack such satellites is highly inefficient," said the team.</p>

<p>"Submarine-based laser weapons can solve these issues," the study document further mentioned.</p>

<p>It then detailed a step-by-step guide to attacking Starlink-like satellites.</p>

<p>"First, one or several submarines equipped with laser weapons are deployed to the sea area where the operation is to be conducted. They enter the target sea area according to the command instructions and wait for the satellites to come within their attack range. The time to raise the laser weapon is determined based on the previously acquired satellite overhead time," said the study.</p>

<p>"When the satellite enters the attackable range, the laser weapon is raised. Due to the limitations of the submarine's detection equipment, other forces are required to provide satellite position guidance for the submarine to attack the satellite. After the attack is completed, the submarine can submerge and wait for the next mission or return to the home port," the researchers further said.</p>

<p>As of June 2024, there are 6,219 Starlink satellites in orbit, of which 6,146 are working, according to Astronomer Jonathan McDowell who tracks the constellation on his website.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/u06bai88_china-nuclear-arsenal-china-submarine-reuters_625x300_29_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study has been conducted by China's PLA. (Representational Pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-operation-is-priority-says-russia-as-biden-quits-us-election-race-6160173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Operation Is "Priority", Says Russia As Biden Quits Election Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-operation-is-priority-says-russia-as-biden-quits-us-election-race-6160173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 13:19:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After US President Joe Biden abandoned his reelection bid, the Kremlin said that for Russia the most important thing was achieving its goals in the Ukraine war not US politics where Moscow said much could change over coming months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After US President Joe Biden abandoned his reelection bid, the Kremlin said that for Russia the most important thing was achieving its goals in the Ukraine war not US politics where Moscow said much could change over coming months.</p>

<p>Biden abandoned his reelection bid on Sunday under growing pressure from his fellow Democrats and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the party's candidate to face Republican Donald Trump in the November election.</p>

<p>"The elections are still four months away, and that is a long period of time in which a lot can change," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told the SHOT news outlet.</p>

<p>"We need to be patient and carefully monitor what happens. The priority for us is the special military operation," Peskov said, using the euphemism for the Ukraine war that President Vladimir Putin prefers.</p>

<p>Putin had said several times said that he felt Biden was preferable as the future US president to Trump for Russia, even after Biden cast the Kremlin chief as a "crazy SOB" though some of his remarks have been ambiguous.</p>

<p>Russian state television led news bulletins with the news of Biden leaving the election race and Biden's support for Harris, though it said it was unclear if Harris would earn the Democratic nomination.</p>

<p>Former Russian President Dmitry Medvedev said on the Telegram messaging app that he wished Biden good health and added that the goals of the special military operation would be achieved.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/ef7e3qq_vladimir-putin-afp-_625x300_08_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We need to be patient and carefully monitor what happens," the Kremlin spokesman said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cardi-b-ellen-degeneres-other-hollywood-celebs-react-to-joe-bidens-dropout-from-us-presidential-race-6160145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cardi B, Ellen DeGeneres, Others React To Biden Quitting Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cardi-b-ellen-degeneres-other-hollywood-celebs-react-to-joe-bidens-dropout-from-us-presidential-race-6160145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 13:14:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden's decision to step down from the 2024 presidential campaign has evoked reactions from the members of the Hollywood fraternity as well.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden's decision to step down from the 2024 presidential campaign has evoked reactions from the members of the Hollywood fraternity as well.</p>

<p>Taking to X, actor, singer and director Barbra Streisand penned a post in support of Biden.</p>

<p>She called Biden "a man who accomplished significant achievements".</p>

<p>"Joe Biden will go down in history as a man who accomplished significant achievements in his 4 year term. We should be grateful for his upholding of our democracy," Barbra posted on X.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Biden announced he is not seeking re-election in the "best interest" of the Democratic Party and the country. He has endorsed US Vice President Kamala Harris as the presidential nominee for the Democratic Party and called on Democrats to "come together and beat" Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Comedian and TV host, Ellen DeGeneres also reacted to the news and took to her official Instagram account to share, "I'm grateful to President Biden for everything he's done."</p>

<p>As per Variety, Oscar-winner and Billie Eilish's brother and song-writing collaborator Finneas posted a photo of his family standing with the President and wrote, "I see a person putting the people before themselves and their pride today, and for that, I have an enormous amount of respect."</p>

<p>Singer Lizzo posted a screenshot of the news with the comment, "We are truly living in unprecedented times."</p>

<p>Jimmy Kimmel on social media wrote, "Thank you President Joe Biden and First Lady Dr. Jill Biden for your leadership, integrity, empathy and service to our country."</p>

<p>The comedian also shared a picture of Biden with First Lady Jill Biden on his Instagram.</p>

<p>On Instagram, singer Ariana Grande re-posted Biden's own post endorsing Harris as his replacement in the coming presidential election.</p>

<p>Cardi B also threw her support immediately behind Harris.</p>

<p>"AHAHAHAHA LETS GOOOOO I TOLD YALLL KAMALA WAS SUPPOSED TO BE THE 2024 candidate," she wrote on X.</p>

<p>"The Bear" and "Borderlands" star Jamie Lee Curtis gives Harris a big thumbs up online writing, "She is trusted and tested and she is a fierce advocate for women's rights and people of color and her message is one of hope and unity for America at her time of great national divide."</p>

<p>Avenger, actor and activist Mark Ruffalo talks next steps and giving his followers the "marching orders." "No to Trump/Vance. No to the right-wing Christian religious takeover for our nation. Nothing wrong with Christianity, just shouldn't be running a nation birthed from freedom of religion."</p>

<p>"Veep" star and Emmy-winner Julia Louis-Dreyfus (who played the Vice President turned President Selina Meyer) showed her support for Biden, thanking him for his service.</p>

<p>Notably, Biden has been isolating at his home in Delaware after testing positive for COVID-19 on Wednesday while he was campaigning in Las Vegas.</p>

<p>His announcement to withdraw from the race to be the next president comes following mounting pressure from Democrats after his incoherent performance in the nationally televised debate with former US President Donald Trump on June 27.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-04/cardi-b_650x400_61523950325.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cardi B also threw her support immediately behind Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-500-people-arrested-amid-violence-in-bangladesh-says-police-6159987]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 500 People, Including Opposition Leaders, Arrested In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-500-people-arrested-amid-violence-in-bangladesh-says-police-6159987]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 12:55:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 500 people, including some opposition leaders, have been arrested so far over days of clashes in the Bangladeshi capital Dhaka sparked by protests against job quotas, police said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 500 people, including some opposition leaders, have been arrested over days of clashes in the Bangladesh capital Dhaka sparked by protests against job quotas, police said Monday.<br />
"At least 532 people have been arrested over the violence," Dhaka Metropolitan Police spokesman Faruk Hossain told AFP.</p>

<p>"They include some BNP leaders," he added, referring to the opposition Bangladesh National Party.</p>

<p>The detainees included the BNP's third-most senior leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury and its spokesman Ruhul Kabir Rizvi Ahmed, he said.</p>

<p>A former national football captain turned senior BNP figure, Aminul Huq, was also held, he added.</p>

<p>Mia Golam Parwar, the general secretary of the country's largest Islamist party, Jamaat-e-Islami, was also arrested, Hossain said.</p>

<p>He said at least three policemen had been killed during the unrest in the capital and about 1,000 injured, at least 60 of them critically.</p>

<p>BNP spokesman A.K.M Wahiduzzaman told AFP that nationwide, "several hundred BNP leaders and activists were arrested in the past few days".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7ioml3tg_bangladesh-clashes-afp-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 500 people, including some opposition leaders, have been arrested so far in Dhaka over protests]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-sudan-women-forced-to-line-up-for-sex-with-soldiers-for-food-report-6159929]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Sudan, Women Forced To Line Up For Sex With Soldiers For Food: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-sudan-women-forced-to-line-up-for-sex-with-soldiers-for-food-report-6159929]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 12:50:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In war-torn Sudan, women are being forced to have sex with soldiers to get food to feed their families, a report by The Guardian said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In war-torn Sudan, women are being forced to have sex with soldiers to get food to feed their families, a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/article/2024/jul/22/women-forced-to-have-sex-with-soldiers-for-food-in-sudanese-city">The Guardian</a> said. Over two dozen women who fled the Sudanese city of Omdurman said that having sex with soldiers was the only way they could access food or goods that they could sell to raise money to feed their families.</p>

<p>One woman who spoke to the Guardian said the assaults took place in factories across the the city where the food is stockpiled. “Both of my parents are too old and sick and I never let my daughter go out to look for food. I went to the soldiers and that was the only way to get food – they were everywhere in the factories area," said a woman, who was forced to have sex with soldiers at a meat-processing factory in May last year.</p>

<p>The assaults reportedly began soon after a civil war broke out in the country which has seen the country's army face off against paramilitary Rapid Support Forces. Reports of rape by armed men emerged within days of the conflict starting on 15 April last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The war in Sudan has killed tens of thousands of people, with some estimates placing the death count as high as 150,000. The war has created the world's worst displacement crisis -- with more than 11 million uprooted and brought the country to the brink of famine.</p>

<p>Several women have come forward sharing harrowing tales of RSF fighters sexually abusing them in a systematic manner in areas under their control. The soldiers have also demanded sex in exchange for access to abandoned houses where it is still possible to loot items to sell in local markets, the women told the Guardian.</p>

<p>One woman said that she was allowed to take food, kitchen equipment and perfumes from empty houses after she had sex with soldiers. “What I went through is indescribable, I would not wish it on an enemy … I only did it because I wanted to feed my children," she said.</p>

<p>Residents of the city claimed they see soldiers bringing women to abandoned houses where they were made to queue up as soldier picked the ones "they liked the look of". "A lot of women come and queue outside our neighbourhood. I sometimes hear screaming but what can you do? Nothing," one resident said.</p>

<p>Another woman told the Guardian that once she refused to have sex with the solider they tortured her and burned her legs. The 21-year-old said she had had sex with soldiers in exchange for being allowed to loot houses for food and goods, but went she refused to do so again the soldiers held her down and burned her legs.</p>

<p>A soldier, who denied ever assaulting a woman himself, said he had witnessed his colleagues. “It's awful. The amount of the sins in this city can never been be forgiven," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hfq0pau8_sudan-women_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several women have come forward sharing harrowing tales of RSF fighters sexually abusing them]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-joever-social-media-flooded-with-memes-as-joe-biden-withdraws-from-us-presidential-race-6159811]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["It's Joever": Meme Fest On Social Media As Biden Exits Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-joever-social-media-flooded-with-memes-as-joe-biden-withdraws-from-us-presidential-race-6159811]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 12:36:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Announcing his exit, Joe Biden endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the Democratic nominee for the 2024 presidential race against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden dropped out of the forthcoming presidential election on Sunday and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the Democratic Party's new nominee. The announcement wasn't completely unexpected, especially after pressure mounted on Biden following his poor performance in the first presidential debate last month.</p>

<p>Soon after Biden's decision, people on social media wasted no time weighing in on his decision and shared some hilarious memes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Live shot at the Democratic party," wrote an X user, sharing a video featuring morphed faces of President Biden and former President Barack Obama.</p>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Live shot at the Democratic party <a href="https://t.co/zQQQinU7Xb">pic.twitter.com/zQQQinU7Xb</a></p>
— Not Jerome Powell (@alifarhat79) <a href="https://twitter.com/alifarhat79/status/1815123085898457497?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<blockquote data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">So long. <a href="https://t.co/FGRiZwkR1o">pic.twitter.com/FGRiZwkR1o</a></p>
— Liberty Pill Memes (@LibertyPillMeme) <a href="https://twitter.com/LibertyPillMeme/status/1815131332722163846?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>Another viral image shows Kamala Harris all dressed up as she makes her way towards the White House.</p>

<p>"Came to me in a sudden vision," the user wrote.</p>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">came to me in a sudden vision <a href="https://t.co/nG0amkmWm6">pic.twitter.com/nG0amkmWm6</a></p>
— ali golub really needs a job ???? (@alibrooke4ever) <a href="https://twitter.com/alibrooke4ever/status/1815096243250692345?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>"You say it's Joever; I say it's just Kamencing," another user added.</p>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">You say it's Joever; I say it's just Kamencing. <a href="https://t.co/xuGv8KM949">pic.twitter.com/xuGv8KM949</a></p>
— Dan Cluchey (@dancluchey) <a href="https://twitter.com/dancluchey/status/1815081819684904997?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>A third person wrote, "If Joe Biden dropping out on National Ice Cream Day doesn't prove we live in a simulation idk what will."</p>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">What? <a href="https://t.co/ftJnVLjW3Q">pic.twitter.com/ftJnVLjW3Q</a></p>
— Fight With Memes (@fightwithmemes) <a href="https://twitter.com/fightwithmemes/status/1814667076675440787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>Announcing his decision, Biden said, "It has been the greatest honor of my life to serve as your President. And while it has been my intention to seek re-election, I believe it is in the best interest of my party and the country for me to stand down and to focus on fulfilling my duties as President for the remainder of my term".</p>

<p>He further said that he would speak about his decision in detail later this week.</p>

<p>"For now, let me express my deepest gratitude to all those who have worked so hard to see me re-elected. I want to thank Vice President Kamala Harris for being an extraordinary partner in all this work," he added.</p>

<p>This comes days after Biden announced that he was diagnosed with COVID-19 and was in isolation.</p>

<p>The presidential elections in the US are slated for November 5 this year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nr2urfi_biden-meme_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-dead-16-others-shot-outside-a-nightclub-in-us-mississippi-6159773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Dead, 16 Others Shot Outside A Nightclub In US' Mississippi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-dead-16-others-shot-outside-a-nightclub-in-us-mississippi-6159773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 12:31:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least three people were killed and 16 others were injured after a gunman opened fire near a nightclub in the US state of Mississippi, local media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least three people were killed and 16 others were injured after a gunman opened fire near a nightclub in the US state of Mississippi, local media reported.</p>

<p>The mass shooting was reported from Church Street in Indianola, Mississippi.</p>

<p>Witnesses heard dozens of gunshots during the shooting which occurred in the vicinity of the nightclub, reported BNO News.</p>

<p>"Several people said that they were standing outside the nightclub, and they started to hear gunshots," Indianola Police Chief Ronald Sampson told the media.</p>

<p>Mayor Ken Featherstone of Indianola confirmed that three 19-year-old men were killed in the shooting.</p>

<p>Officials said no arrests have been made yet and investigation is on.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mass shooting was reported from Church Street in Indianola, Mississippi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-if-she-wins-kamala-harris-will-be-the-first-woman-to-become-us-president-6159719]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[If She Wins, Kamala Harris Will Be The First Woman To Become US President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-if-she-wins-kamala-harris-will-be-the-first-woman-to-become-us-president-6159719]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 12:23:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris wasted no time launching her 2024 presidential campaign, seeking the support of fellow Democrats with the backing of President Joe Biden after he pulled out of the race amid concerns about his age and health.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris wasted no time launching her 2024 presidential campaign, seeking the support of fellow Democrats with the backing of President Joe Biden after he pulled out of the race amid concerns about his age and health.</p>

<p>Her campaign officials and allies made hundreds of calls on behalf of Harris on Sunday, urging delegates to the Democratic Party convention next month to join in nominating her for president in the Nov. 5 election against Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Multiple sources said the calls, aimed at blocking would-be Democratic challengers, began almost immediately after the 81-year-old Biden abandoned the race.</p>

<p>At the same time, Democratic state party chairs backed Harris in a phone call, several participants said.</p>

<p>Harris spoke with Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, a potential vice presidential running mate, House Democratic leader Hakeem Jeffries, and Congressional Black Caucus chair Representative Steven Horsford, said a source familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>Harris, a 59-year-old woman who is Black and Asian-American, would fashion an entirely new dynamic with Trump, 78, offering a vivid generational and cultural split-screen.</p>

<p>The United States has yet to elect a woman president in its 248-year history.</p>

<p>"Harris will be easier to beat than Joe Biden would have been," Trump asserted on CNN shortly after Biden's announcement.</p>

<p>Biden, the oldest person ever to have occupied the Oval Office, said he would remain in the presidency until his term ends on Jan. 20, 2025, while endorsing Harris to run for president in his place.</p>

<p>The White House said Harris would deliver remarks on the South Lawn at 11:30 a.m. ET (1530 GMT) on Monday at an event celebrating the NCAA 2023-24 college championship teams.</p>

<p>Facing mounting questions about his mental acuity, Biden is the first sitting president to give up his party's nomination for reelection since President Lyndon B. Johnson during the Vietnam War in March 1968.</p>

<p>Biden's withdrawal leaves his replacement with less than four months to wage a campaign. Prominent Democrats, including potential Harris challengers such as California Governor Gavin Newsom, immediately backed the vice president.</p>

<p>"My intention is to earn and win this nomination," Harris said in a statement. "I will do everything in my power to unite the Democratic Party — and unite our nation — to defeat Donald Trump."</p>

<p>Despite the early show of support for Harris, talk of an open convention when Democrats gather in Chicago Aug. 19-22 was not totally silenced.</p>

<p>Former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi and former President Barack Obama did not announce endorsements, although both praised Biden.</p>

<p>Two other potential challengers - Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer and Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear - made no mention of the vice president in their statements.</p>

<p>With Democrats wading into uncharted territory, Democratic National Committee Chair Jaime Harrison said the party would soon announce the next steps in its nomination process.</p>

<p>What is certain is that Biden's withdrawal has again reshaped a White House contest shaken repeatedly during the last month.</p>

<p>On June 27, Biden's poor performance in a debate with Trump led many Democrats to urge him to drop out. Then on July 13, a gunman attempted to assassinate former President Trump.</p>

<p>And last week Trump named hardline Republican U.S. Senator J.D. Vance, 39, to serve as his vice presidential running mate.</p>

<h3><strong>ABORTION RIGHTS LEADER</strong></h3>

<p>A former attorney general of California and former U.S. senator, Harris ran unsuccessfully for the Democratic Party's presidential nomination in 2020.</p>

<p>Biden won the nomination, picked Harris to be his vice president, and went on to beat Trump.</p>

<p>Harris has been outspoken on abortion rights, an issue that resonates with younger voters and progressives.</p>

<p>She is expected to stick largely to Biden's foreign policy playbook on such issues as China, Iran and Ukraine, but could strike a tougher tone with Israel over the Gaza war if she tops the Democratic ticket and wins the November election.</p>

<p>Proponents argue she would energize those voters, consolidate Black support and bring sharp debating skills to prosecute the political case against the former president.</p>

<p>But some Democrats were concerned about a Harris candidacy, in part because of the weight of a long history of racial and gender discrimination in the United States.</p>

<p>Polling shows that Harris performs no better statistically than Biden had done against Trump.</p>

<p>In a head-to-head match-up, Harris and Trump were tied with 44% support each in a July 15-16 Reuters/Ipsos poll conducted immediately after the July 13 assassination attempt on Trump.</p>

<p>Trump led Biden 43% to 41% in that same poll, though the 2 percentage point difference was not meaningful considering the poll's 3-point margin of error.</p>

<p>Biden's campaign had $95 million on hand at the end of June, according to a filing with the Federal Election Commission. Campaign finance law experts disagree on how easily that money could be shifted to a Harris-led campaign.</p>

<p>Small-dollar donors raised more than $46.7 million on ActBlue in the first five hours of Harris' presidential campaign, the fundraising platform said on X on Sunday.</p>

<h3><strong>LAST-MINUTE SHIFT</strong></h3>

<p>Biden, who said he would address the nation this week, has not been seen in public since testing positive for COVID-19 last week. He was isolating at his home in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware.</p>

<p>"While it has been my intention to seek reelection, I believe it is in the best interest of my party and the country for me to stand down and to focus solely on fulfilling my duties as President for the remainder of my term," Biden wrote on X.</p>

<p>Congressional Republicans argued on Sunday that Biden should resign as president immediately, which would turn the White House over to Harris and put House of Representatives Speaker Mike Johnson, a Republican, next in line in succession.</p>

<p>"If he's incapable of running for president, how is he capable of governing right now? I mean, there is five months left in this administration. It's a real concern, and it's a danger to the country," Johnson told CNN on Sunday before Biden's announcement.</p>

<p>During the 2020 campaign, Biden described himself as a bridge to the next generation. Some interpreted that to mean he would serve one term, a transitional figure who beat Trump and brought his party back to power.</p>

<p>But Biden decided to seek reelection, believing he could beat Trump again. His campaign was already struggling and ran into deep trouble after his debate performance raised serious concerns about his ability to win the election or stay on as president for another four years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dr036ijg_kamala-harris_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's withdrawal leaves Kamala Harris with less than four months to wage a campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-microsoft-meta-google-gemini-all-eyes-on-ai-to-drive-big-tech-earnings-6159478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All Eyes On AI To Drive Big Tech Earnings]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-microsoft-meta-google-gemini-all-eyes-on-ai-to-drive-big-tech-earnings-6159478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 11:45:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Analysts at Wedbush Securities, one of Wall Street's biggest believers in AI's potential, expect "growth and earnings to accelerate with the AI revolution and the wave of transformation" it is causing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the next two weeks, the quarterly results of Big Tech giants will offer a glimpse on the bankability of artificial intelligence and whether the major investments AI requires are sustainable for the long haul.</p>

<p>Analysts at Wedbush Securities, one of Wall Street's biggest believers in AI's potential, expect "growth and earnings to accelerate with the AI revolution and the wave of transformation" it is causing.</p>

<p>The market generally agrees with this rosy AI narrative. Analysts forecast double-digit growth for heavyweights Microsoft and Google, in contrast to Apple, a latecomer to the AI party, with only three percent growth expected.</p>

<p>The iPhone maker, which releases its results on August 1, unveiled its new Apple Intelligence system only last month and plans to roll it out gradually over the next months, and only on the latest models.</p>

<p>CFRA analyst Angelo Zino believes that the impact of these new features will not be felt until the iPhone 16 launches in September, the first to feature the new AI powers built-in across all options.</p>

<p>But he expects Apple's upcoming earnings to show improvement in China sales, a black spot since last year.</p>

<p>"Apple's forecasts for the current quarter will be important" in assessing the company's momentum, said Zino.</p>

<p>But "if there's one that we were maybe a little bit more concerned about, versus the others, it would be Meta," he said.</p>

<p>He pointed out that Mark Zuckerberg's company raised its investment projections last April as it devoted a few billion dollars more on the chips, servers and data centers needed to develop generative AI.</p>

<p>CFRA expects Meta's growth to decelerate through the end of the year. Combined with the expected increase in spending on AI, that should put earnings under pressure.</p>

<p>As for the earnings of cloud giants Microsoft (July 30) and Amazon (August 1), "we expect them to continue to report very good results, in line with or better than market expectations," said Zino.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Crucial' bet&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Microsoft is among the best positioned to monetize generative AI, having moved the fastest to implement it across all its products, and pouring $13 billion into OpenAI, the startup stalwart behind ChatGPT.</p>

<p>Winning the big bet on AI is "crucial" for the group, said Jeremy Goldman of Emarketer, "but the market is willing to give them a level of patience."</p>

<p>The AI frenzy has helped Microsoft's cloud computing business grow in the double digits, something that analysts said could be hard to sustain.</p>

<p>"This type of growth cannot hold forever, but the synergies between cloud and AI make it more likely that Microsoft holds onto reliable cloud growth for some time to come," Goldman said.</p>

<p>As for Amazon, "investors will want to see that the reacceleration of growth over the first quarter wasn't a one-off" at AWS, the company's world-leading cloud business, said Matt Britzman of Hargreaves Lansdown.</p>

<p>Since AWS leads "in everything data-related, it should be well placed to capture a huge chunk of the demand coming from the AI wave," he added.</p>

<p>The picture "might be a little less clear" for Google parent Alphabet, which will be the first to publish results on Tuesday, "because of their search business" online, warned Zino.</p>

<p>"Skepticism around AI Overviews," introduced by Google in mid-May, "is certainly justified," said Emarketer analyst Evelyn Mitchell-Wolf.</p>

<p>This new feature, which offers a written text at the top of results in a Google search, ahead of the traditional links to sites, got off to a rocky start.</p>

<p>Internet users were quick to report strange, or potentially dangerous, answers proposed by the feature that had been touted by Google executives as the future direction of search.</p>

<p>According to data from BrightEdge, relayed by Search Engine Land, the number of searches presenting a result generated by AI Overviews has plummeted in recent weeks as Google shies away from the feature.</p>

<p>Still, many are concerned about the evolution of advertising across the internet if Google pushes on with the Overviews model, which reduces the necessity of clicking into links. Content creators, primarily the media, fear a collapse in revenues.</p>

<p>But for Emarketer's Mitchell-Wolf, "as long as Google maintains its status as the default search engine across most smartphones and major browsers, it will continue to be the top destination for search, and the top destination for search ad spending."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pfmva8q_ai-economic-growth_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[AI is expected to drive Big Tech earnings (Disclaimer: AI Generated Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-how-kamala-harris-nomination-could-reshape-donald-trump-campaign-6159309]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Analysis: How Kamala Harris' Nomination Could Reshape Trump Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-how-kamala-harris-nomination-could-reshape-donald-trump-campaign-6159309]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 11:18:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump will try to show swing voters that his likely new rival, Vice President Kamala Harris, has her fingerprints all over two issues he is counting on for victory in November: immigration and the cost of living.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump will try to show swing voters that his likely new rival, Vice President Kamala Harris, has her fingerprints all over two issues he is counting on for victory in November: immigration and the cost of living.</p>

<p>Sources within the Trump campaign said it will cast Harris, the likely Democratic candidate after President Joe Biden quit the race on Sunday, as the "co-pilot" of administration polices it says are behind both sources of voter discontent.</p>

<p>Biden's sudden exit and endorsement of Harris has upended the race, just eight days after Trump survived an assassination attempt at a campaign rally.</p>

<p>Sources told Reuters that Trump's campaign had for weeks been preparing for Harris should Biden drop out and she win her party's nomination.</p>

<p>"Harris will be easier to beat than Joe Biden would have been," Trump told CNN shortly after Biden's announcement on Sunday.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign has signaled it will tie her as tightly as possible to Biden's immigration policy, which Republicans say is to blame for a sharp increase in the numbers of people crossing the southern border with Mexico illegally.</p>

<p>The second line of attack will revolve around the economy. Public opinion polls consistently show Americans are unhappy with high food and fuel costs as well as interest rates that have made buying a home less affordable.</p>

<p>"She's the co-pilot of the Biden vision," said one Trump adviser, speaking on condition of anonymity during last week's Republican National Convention, where a unified party anointed Trump as its nominee in the White House race.</p>

<p>"If they want to switch to Biden 2.0 and have 'Cackling' Kamala at the top of the ticket, we're good either way," the adviser said, repeating an insult the campaign has been trying out for weeks focused on how the vice president laughs.</p>

<p>Make America Great Again Inc, a super PAC backing Trump, said on Sunday it was pulling anti-Biden television ads that had been set to run in the battleground states of Arizona, Georgia, Nevada and Pennsylvania and replacing them with an ad attacking Harris.</p>

<p>The 30-second ad accuses Harris of hiding Biden's infirmity from the public, and it seeks to pin the administration's record solely on her. "Kamala knew Joe couldn't do the job, so she did it. Look what she got done: a border invasion, runaway inflation, the American Dream dead," the narrator says.</p>

<p>Trump, known for using insulting and sometimes offensive language to attack his opponents, gave supporters at a rally in Michigan on Saturday a taste of the insults he is likely to fling at Harris in the coming days.</p>

<p>"I call her laughing Kamala. You ever watch a laugh? She's crazy. You can tell a lot by a laugh. She's crazy. She's nuts," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>ALTERED RACE</strong></h3>

<p>The Democratic Party has yet to determine how to move forward, and there is as yet no guarantee that Harris will emerge as the party's nominee despite Biden's endorsement.</p>

<p>Harris as the Democratic nominee would alter the race in perhaps unforeseen ways, political strategists said.</p>

<p>A 59-year-old woman who is Black and Asian-American would fashion an entirely new dynamic with Trump, 78, offering a vivid generational and cultural split-screen. The United States has yet to elect a woman president in its 248-year history.</p>

<p>Rodell Mollineau, a Democratic strategist and longtime congressional aide, said Harris would be able to mount "a more energetic campaign with excitement from younger voters and people of color" after Biden struggled to energize these important Democratic Party voting blocs.</p>

<p>A former prosecutor and California attorney general as well as a former U.S. senator, Harris would be able to use "her years of litigation experience to effectively prosecute Trump in the court of public opinion," Mollineau said.</p>

<p>Chip Felkel, a Republican strategist, cautioned that it would be a mistake for the Trump campaign to assume Harris could serve as a simple stand-in for Biden, because of her potential appeal to different parts of the electorate.</p>

<p>Recent polls have shown Harris to be competitive with Trump. In a hypothetical head-to-head matchup, Harris and Trump were tied with 44% support each in a July 15-16 Reuters/Ipsos poll.</p>

<p>Before Sunday, the Trump campaign had already begun discussions about how they would redeploy campaign resources should Biden drop out of the race, according to a source with direct knowledge of the matter.</p>

<p>Jeanette Hoffman, a Republican political consultant, said despite the contrasts Harris would bring to the ticket, her close ties to Biden would be a drag on her candidacy.</p>

<p>Harris "doesn't represent the change America is looking for," Hoffman said.</p>

<p>MAGA Inc CEO Taylor Budowich said his group has commissioned opposition research on several possible Democratic candidates. "MAGA Inc is prepared for all outcomes of a Democrat Party who has only brought chaos and failure," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is known for using insulting and sometimes offensive language to attack his opponents.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamys-prediction-on-joe-bidens-re-election-bid-comes-true-6159220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Reacts After Vivek Ramaswamy's Biden Prediction Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamys-prediction-on-joe-bidens-re-election-bid-comes-true-6159220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 11:02:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden announced on Sunday that he decided to give up running for re-election as president of the US and endorsed his deputy Kamala Harris to be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-American businessman-turned-politician Vivek Ramaswamy had predicted some eight months ago that incumbent President Joe Biden would not be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-drops-out-of-us-presidential-election-race-says-it-is-in-best-interest-of-country-for-me-to-stand-down-6156671#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Joe Biden</a> announced on Sunday that he decided to give up running for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/live-updates-joe-biden-withdraws-from-us-presidential-race-6156785">re-election as president of the United States</a> and endorsed his deputy <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-kamala-harris-joins-presidential-race-who-will-be-her-running-mate-6158830#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Kamala Harris</a> to be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>“Best way to predict the future: just follow the incentives. It's shocking how precisely right you can be, right down to the exact timing,” Ramaswamy, a 38-year-old Republican, said in a social media post along with the video interview with Fox News last November, soon after Biden announced his decision.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Best way to predict the future: just follow the incentives. It's shocking how precisely right you can be, right down to the exact timing. <a href="https://t.co/Xz5CBC8XxW">pic.twitter.com/Xz5CBC8XxW</a></p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1815093862748303795?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“Yeah, all his predictions have come true,” Tesla CEO and X owner Elon Musk said in response. “Wish it weren't so,” Ramaswamy responded.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yeah, all his predictions have come true</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1815093642366980353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Wish it weren't so. <a href="https://t.co/upKkCY2iY2">https://t.co/upKkCY2iY2</a></p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1815094952050737167?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In his interview with Fox News, Ramaswamy had said: “I think that the reality is the managerial class around Biden has lost their use for him. This has been obvious to me since last year to play out the incentives. He is not the strongest candidate they can put up. And these people, they have stopped at nothing to keep Donald J Trump out of office,” he said.</p>

<p>The Indian-American, who then was the Republican presidential candidate in the primaries along with former president Donald Trump, said that two candidates – Kamala Harris and Michelle Obama – were possibly to be picked by the Democrats.</p>

<p>“Let's give credit where credit is due. For almost a year one man has been saying “Biden won't be the Democratic nominee” and predicting a last-minute blindside. People called him crazy,” Tristane Tate, a social media influencer, said, applauding Ramaswamy for his prediction coming true. Ramaswamy had made a similar prediction during one of the Republican presidential debates.</p>

<p>He also posted a compilation of videos of his predictions and said, "The anatomy of how a “conspiracy theory” became reality, in just 18 months."&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The anatomy of how a “conspiracy theory” became reality, in just 18 months. <a href="https://t.co/yU4wlnJ6oK">pic.twitter.com/yU4wlnJ6oK</a></p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1815089834278690991?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“‘I remember corporate media reporters sneering and laughing when Vivek Ramaswamy made this point in the debate. They're not laughing now!” Raheem Kassam, a journalist, said on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tf9f5pcg_vivek-ramaswamy-joe-biden_625x300_28_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy had predicted eight months ago that Joe Biden would not be the presidential nominee]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-simpsons-prediction-comes-true-joe-biden-out-kamala-harris-in-6159125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['The Simpsons' Predicted It? On Kamala Harris, X User Cites 2000 Episode]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-simpsons-prediction-comes-true-joe-biden-out-kamala-harris-in-6159125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:44:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has ended his reelection bid and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the new Democratic nominee.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden has ended his reelection bid and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the new Democratic nominee. The sudden change is similar to a development predicted years ago in the popular animated series <em>The Simpsons.</em></p>

<p>In the 17th episode of the 11th season, which aired in 2000, Lisa Simpson became the first female president of the US. She is seen in an outfit similar to what Kamala Harris wore at Joe Biden's inauguration, hinting at her rise to the presidency in future.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The episode also points to a predecessor who left behind a budget crisis for President Lisa to manage, strongly suggesting a real estate mogul (Donald Trump) had previously held the office.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The 17th episode of the 11th season of The Simpsons shows Lisa Simpson as the first female president of the United States, dressed similarly to Kamala Harris at Joe Biden's inauguration.<br />
<br />
This episode, which aired in 2000, strongly suggests that real estate mogul Donald Trump… <a href="https://t.co/zvFZ5RVLl8">pic.twitter.com/zvFZ5RVLl8</a></p>
— Shadow of Ezra (@ShadowofEzra) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShadowofEzra/status/1815106589239726422?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Simpsons has a history of making eerily accurate and satirical references to global events. Some of their previous predictions include the rise of smartwatches, Donald Trump's presidency, Disney's acquisition of 20th Century Fox and Finnish economist Bengt R Holmstrom winning the Nobel Prize for his work.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most recently, a cartoon showing the former president lying in a coffin went viral. This comes after the recent <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-did-the-simpsons-predict-trump-assassination-attempt-6115400 ">attempted assassination</a> of Trump.</p>

<p>Joe Biden <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-drops-out-of-us-presidential-election-race-says-it-is-in-best-interest-of-country-for-me-to-stand-down-6156671">dropped out of the US presidential race</a> on Sunday, saying it was in the "best interest of my party and the country" to step aside. His withdrawal was widely anticipated following his abysmal performance in the June debate against Trump. The announcement came unexpectedly while he was recovering from COVID-19 at his Delaware beach house.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Kamala Harris received significant backing from key Democratic figures, including Hillary Clinton and California Governor Gavin Newsom, who is also a potential rival for the nomination.</p>

<p>The Democratic fundraising group ActBlue reported Harris received $27.5 million in small-donour contributions within just five hours.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/8o3p0a6g_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_22_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden dropped out of the US presidential race on Sunday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/nvidia-ai-ai-chip-china-ai-nvidia-preparing-version-of-new-flagship-ai-chip-for-chinese-market-sources-say-6159124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Preparing New Flagship AI Chip For Chinese Market, Sources Say]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/nvidia-ai-ai-chip-china-ai-nvidia-preparing-version-of-new-flagship-ai-chip-for-chinese-market-sources-say-6159124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:44:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nvidia will work with Inspur, one of its major distributor partners in China, on the chip which is tentatively named the "B20"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia is working on a version of its new flagship AI chips for the China market that would be compatible with current U.S. export controls, three sources familiar with the matter said.<br />
<br />
The AI chip giant in March unveiled its "Blackwell" chip series, which is due to be mass produced later in the year. Within that series, the B200 is 30 times speedier than its predecessor at some tasks like serving up answers from chatbots.</p>

<p>Nvidia will work with Inspur, one of its major distributor partners in China, on the launch and distribution of the chip which is tentatively named the "B20", two of the sources said.</p>

<p>The sources declined to be identified as Nvidia has yet to make a public announcement.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Nvidia declined to comment. Inspur did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Washington tightened its controls on exports of cutting-edge semiconductors to China in 2023, seeking to prevent breakthroughs in supercomputing that would aid China's military.</p>

<p>Since then, Nvidia has developed three chips tailored specifically for the Chinese market.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aqaknihg_nvidia_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The sources declined to be identified as Nvidia has yet to make a public announcement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-tycoon-on-trial-for-146-million-fraud-in-corruption-crackdown-6159062]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vietnamese Tycoon On Trial For $146 Million Fraud In Corruption Crackdown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-tycoon-on-trial-for-146-million-fraud-in-corruption-crackdown-6159062]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:36:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former Vietnamese property and aviation tycoon charged with $146 million in fraud and stock market manipulation went on trial in Hanoi Monday, the latest corruption case targeting the communist country's business elite.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former Vietnamese property and aviation tycoon charged with $146 million in fraud and stock market manipulation went on trial in Hanoi Monday, the latest corruption case targeting the communist country's business elite.</p>

<p>Trinh Van Quyet, who owned the FLC empire of luxury resorts, golf courses, and the budget Bamboo Airways, had nearly $2 billion in stock market wealth before his arrest, according to state media estimates.</p>

<p>But on Monday the 48-year-old -- handcuffed and dressed in a white shirt -- was led into court by police officers.</p>

<p>The trial comes just days after the death of former Communist Party of Vietnam leader Nguyen Phu Trong, who is credited with spearheading a crackdown on graft at the highest levels.</p>

<p>Trong, 80, died on Friday at a military hospital in Hanoi "due to old age and serious illness", the party said, a day after announcing he was standing down to seek medical care.</p>

<p>Tycoon Quyet is accused of illegally pocketing more than $146 million between 2017 and 2022.</p>

<p>Following his arrest in March 2022, 49 other alleged accomplices were picked up -- including his two sisters and the former chairman of the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange and its chief executive officer.</p>

<p>According to the prosecution indictment, Quyet set up several stock market brokerages and registered dozens of family members to, ostensibly, trade shares.</p>

<p>But police said while orders to buy shares were placed in hundreds of trading sessions -- pushing up the value of the stock -- they were cancelled before being matched.</p>

<p>The case is part of a national corruption crackdown that has swept up numerous officials and members of Vietnam's business elite in recent years.</p>

<p>In April, a top Vietnamese property tycoon sentenced to death in a $27 billion fraud case, launched an appeal against her conviction.</p>

<p>The head of one of Vietnam's top soft drinks companies, meanwhile, was jailed for eight years in April in a $40 million fraud case.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6jf8nq6g_court-room_625x300_22_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tycoon is accused of illegally pocketing more than $146 million between 2017 and 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-zealand-deaths-linked-to-online-suicide-kits-sold-by-canadian-chef-6158980]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 New Zealand Deaths Linked To Online "Suicide Kits" Sold By Canadian Chef]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-zealand-deaths-linked-to-online-suicide-kits-sold-by-canadian-chef-6158980]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:21:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New Zealand coroner has formally linked four deaths to the sale of "suicide kits" bought online from a former Canadian chef, according to findings published Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New Zealand coroner has formally linked four deaths to the sale of "suicide kits" bought online from a former Canadian chef, according to findings published Monday.</p>

<p>Coroner Alexandra Cunninghame found that three students, aged 18 to 21, and one 40-year-old personal trainer killed themselves after buying kits from businesses linked to Canadian <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-man-charged-with-murder-for-assisting-100-suicides-across-40-nations-4659337">Kenneth Law</a>.</p>

<p>Canadian police believe Law sent as many as 1,200 "suicide kits" to people in more than 40 countries between 2020 and his arrest last year -- specifically targeting vulnerable people online.</p>

<p>Canadian prosecutors allege the kits contained a food additive that can kill if misused.</p>

<p>Law was arrested in May 2023 and charged in Canada with 14 counts of murder and a further 14 counts of aiding and counselling suicide.</p>

<p>He has denied the charges.</p>

<p>Alerted by Interpol, several other countries have launched investigations.</p>

<p>In Britain, at least 272 people purchased products from Law's websites and 88 of them died, police there have said.</p>

<p>In Italy, nine buyers have been identified and at least one victim has died.</p>

<p>The Canadian victims were both male and female between the ages of 16 and 36, according to police.</p>

<p>New Zealand's Suicide Prevention Office has asked internet service providers to block Law's website in New Zealand, the coroner added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/srfkddmo_kenneth-law-suicide-kits-x-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canadian police believe Kenneth Law sent 1,200 "suicide kits" to people in more than 40 countries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-nancy-pelosi-yet-to-endorse-kamala-harris-for-presidential-job-6158594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Barack Obama, Nancy Pelosi Yet To Endorse Kamala Harris For Presidential Job]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-nancy-pelosi-yet-to-endorse-kamala-harris-for-presidential-job-6158594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 09:58:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former President Barack Obama, former Speaker Nancy Pelosi and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer have yet to make their stand clear on endorsing Kamala Harris for the Presidential nomination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former President Barack Obama, former Speaker Nancy Pelosi and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer have yet to make their stand clear on endorsing Kamala Harris for the Presidential nomination. This even as a slew of Democrat Party leaders on Sunday displayed a show of support for Vice President Kamala Harris as their new presidential candidate, Politico reported.</p>

<p>Former President Barack Obama in a post on the platform Medium said "We will be navigating uncharted waters in the days ahead. But I have extraordinary confidence that the leaders of our party will be able to create a process from which an outstanding nominee emerges."</p>

<p>The statement, however, stops just short of officially backing Harris for the top job. Obama's endorsement of Harris will be critical given that the Democratic National Convention is being held between August 19 to 22 on Obama's home turf of Chicago.</p>

<p>Former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi's reaction to the withdrawal of Joe Biden from the presidential race was one of effusive praise for Biden but had nothing to suggest that she had endorsed Harris.</p>

<p>"President Joe Biden is a patriotic American who has always put our country first. His legacy of vision, values and leadership make him one of the most consequential Presidents in American history. With love and gratitude to President Biden for always believing in the promise of America and giving people the opportunity to reach their fulfilment," she said on X.</p>

<p>After President Joe Biden endorsed her to be the new Presidential nominee, Harris got support from several Democrats like former President Bill Clinton, and former Democratic Presidential nominee Hillary Clinton. In a statement, the Clintons said "We are honoured to join the President in endorsing Vice President Harris and will do whatever to support her."</p>

<p>Congressman Ro Khanna also endorsed Kamla Harris saying "I am proud to endorse Kamala Harris as our nominee. Her trailblazing candidacy as the first African American woman and first Asian American will be a jolt of energy in our party. Our party can now run on a message of hope and a vision for the future."</p>

<p>Congressman Jim Clyburn representing South Carolina's 6th Congressional district said he echoed President Biden's endorsement of Harris.</p>

<p>"I echo the good judgement he demonstrated in selecting Vice President Harris to lead this nation alongside him, and I am proud today to follow his lead in support of her candidacy to succeed him as the Democratic Party's 2024 nominee for President," he said.</p>

<p>The goal now for the supporters of Harris is to get enough backers on board to help her win the nomination when the Democratic National Convention gets underway.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, who has been spoken of as a potential Vice Presidential running mate to Harris called for the party to unite behind her and focus on winning the election.</p>

<p>"The best path forward for the Democratic Party is to quickly unite behind Vice President Harris and refocus on winning the presidency. the contrast in this race could not be clearer and the road to victory in November runs right through Pennsylvania this collective work began. I will do everything I can to help elect Kamala Harris as the 47th President of the United States," Shapiro said in a statement on X.</p>

<p>With barely a month to go before the Democratic party convenes in Chicago the task before them is tough, Donald Trump already has a head start and only a united front can hope to wrest the initiative from him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/qmmgrfao_barack-obama-kamala-harris-facebook-ndtv-file-photo_625x300_12_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama is yet to make his stand clear on endorsing Kamala Harris for the Presidential nomination.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-americans-on-joe-biden-dropping-out-of-2024-presidential-race-right-thing-to-do-6158649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Right Thing To Do": Indian-Americans On Biden Quitting Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-americans-on-joe-biden-dropping-out-of-2024-presidential-race-right-thing-to-do-6158649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 09:57:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden did the "right thing" by dropping out of the 2024 presidential race, prominent members of the Indian-American community have said, noting that this must have been a hard decision for him to make but one he took to put "America]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden did the “right thing” by dropping out of the 2024 presidential race, prominent members of the Indian-American community have said, noting that this must have been a hard decision for him to make but one he took to put “America first.”</p>

<p>Biden, 81, announced on Sunday that he decided to give up running for re-election as president of the United States and endorsed his deputy Harris to be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>“While I acknowledge President Biden's decision to drop out of this race, I accept that decision as his last act to preserve American exceptionalism and as an ‘America First' decision,” New York-based eminent Indian-American attorney Ravi Batra told PTI.</p>

<p>"Thank you, Joe Biden, for doing what must have been the hardest decision for you, and yet what every soldier on the battlefield does - give our last best measure to America,” he said.</p>

<p>Al Mason, prominent New York-based global real estate advisor and entrepreneur who also advises international education institutions, said that it was expected that Biden would drop out of the 2024 presidential race.</p>

<p>“He did the right thing. He is a good man, but he could never win against Trump. In fact Biden's endorsed candidate Kamala Harris too cannot beat Trump. She has no appeal in the battleground states,” Mason said.</p>

<p>Batra said Biden has served the United States with distinction and his 50-year career, especially as Senate Foreign Relations chair and then as President Barack Obama's vice president are “remarkable”. He added that the citizens of the country are at their core not Democrats or Republicans or Independents but are Americans first.</p>

<p>Biden has done his “finest duty by dropping out, knowing that he cannot be a standard bearer for the Democratic Party and win against” Republican presidential nominee former US President Donald Trump who after being shot at during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, “in a moment of extreme personal crisis had the strength of heart and mind on the stage with a face bloodied to put up his fist and say ‘Fight'.” “After all, that's what all we Americans do. We fight for democracy. We fight for meritocracy, because if we don't fight it's all over. It's game over,” Batra said.</p>

<p>Mason said Trump is “impossible” to beat, even more so now with his 39-year-old Vice Presidential candidate Senator J D Vance, who has great appeal in states like Arizona, North Carolina, Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/368soaeo_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden decided to give up running for re-election as president of the United States.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>