<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:59:36 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-expected-to-drop-out-of-us-presidential-race-report-6390860]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Robert Kennedy Jr To Quit US Presidential Race, Will Support Trump: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-expected-to-drop-out-of-us-presidential-race-report-6390860]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:29:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. is expected to drop out of the race for the White House, US media reported on Wednesday, with the independent candidate due to make a major address later in the week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. is expected to drop out of the race for the White House, US media reported on Wednesday, with the independent candidate due to make a major address later in the week.</p>

<p>The New York Times and CNN reported that Kennedy, whose support was at 8.7 percent in a nationwide poll by The Hill this week, would back Republican nominee Donald Trump upon dropping out.</p>

<p>Analysts say that in the tight race between the Democratic Party's Kamala Harris and Trump for the presidency, the votes of Kennedy's supporters could determine the outcome in some battleground states.</p>

<p>Kennedy, the scion of America's most famous political clan, is an environmental lawyer and long-time vaccine skeptic whose campaign struggled to gain traction with mainstream voters.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, his campaign said he would make an address to the nation on Friday from the swing state of Arizona, where Trump is also due to hold a campaign event that day.</p>

<p>"Independent Presidential Candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. will address the nation live on Friday about the present historical moment and his path forward," read a brief statement from RFK Jr.'s campaign.</p>

<p>The New York Times on Wednesday cited three anonymous sources as saying Kennedy would end his campaign and potentially endorse Trump.</p>

<p>CNN cited two anonymous sources who reported Kennedy was expected to suspend his campaign on Friday.</p>

<p>AFP has reached out to Kennedy's campaign for comment on the reports.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a podcast interview this week, Kennedy's running mate Nicole Shanahan hinted that he could withdraw in favor of Trump.</p>

<p>The Republican nominee told CNN on Tuesday that he would "certainly" be open to Kennedy playing a role in his administration if he was elected.</p>

<p>"He's a brilliant guy. He's a very smart guy," Trump told CNN. "I've known him for a very long time.</p>

<p>"I didn't know he was thinking about getting out, but if he is thinking about getting out, certainly I'd be open to it."</p>

<p>Known for sometimes bizarre pronouncements and for spreading often dangerous health-related conspiracy theories, Kennedy has faced a number of setbacks in his electoral campaign.</p>

<p>This month, a judge in New York claimed that Kennedy had falsely claimed residency in the state and barred him from ballots there.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/h3r1nft8_robert-kennedy-jr_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-party-acts-like-a-cult-anti-trump-republicans-at-democrat-event-6390844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Our Party Acts Like A Cult": Anti-Trump Republicans At Democrat Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-party-acts-like-a-cult-anti-trump-republicans-at-democrat-event-6390844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:26:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While Democratic luminaries including the Obamas enthusiastically support Kamala Harris for US president at their party's convention, an unlikely band of rebels is joining the effort: Republicans urging fellow conservatives to ditch Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While Democratic luminaries including the Obamas enthusiastically support Kamala Harris for US president at their party's convention, an unlikely band of rebels is joining the effort: Republicans urging fellow conservatives to ditch Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The message is nothing new -- several Republicans have spoken out against Trump over the years. But their presence at this week's carefully orchestrated Democratic confab has amplified the call for conservatives and independents to reconsider their election choice in November.</p>

<p>"Let me be clear to my Republican friends at home watching," Geoff Duncan, the former lieutenant governor of Georgia where Trump sought to overturn the results of the 2020 election, said Wednesday from the convention stage.</p>

<p>"If you vote for Kamala Harris in 2024 you're not a Democrat, you're a patriot," he boomed.</p>

<p>Slamming the recently convicted -- and twice-impeached -- former president as "a direct threat to democracy," Duncan said he was aiming his remarks at the millions of Republicans and independents he knows are "sick and tired of making excuses" for Trump.</p>

<p>"These days our party acts more like a cult, a cult worshipping a felonous thug," said Duncan.</p>

<p>Multiple Republicans have offered similar messages in Chicago, as the Harris campaign seeks to peel off as many Republicans and independent voters as possible in an election that is going down to the wire.</p>

<p>Former White House communications director Stephanie Grisham, who had close access to Trump, took the stage Tuesday slamming her ex-boss as a liar with "no empathy, no morals and no fidelity to the truth."</p>

<p>"I saw him when the cameras were off. Behind closed doors, Trump mocks his supporters, he calls them basement dwellers," she said.</p>

<p>Grisham, who was also first lady Melania Trump's chief of staff, mentioned how she had gone from "a true believer" to a disaffected close advisor who wanted out, and recalled a turning point during the 2021 US Capitol riot by Trump supporters.</p>

<p>"On January 6 I asked Melania if we could at least tweet that while peaceful protest is the right of every American, there's no place for lawlessness or violence," Grisham said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She replied with one word: 'No.'"</p>

<p>Grisham resigned that day, "because I love my country more than my party," she said, to loud applause, adding that Harris "has my vote."</p>

<p>- 'Kidnapped by extremists' -</p>

<p>John Giles, mayor of Mesa, Arizona, and a self-described "lifelong Republican" who claims late senator John McCain as his hero, was equally blunt.</p>

<p>He told the convention his Republican Party "has been kidnapped by extremists and devolved into a cult: the cult of Donald Trump."</p>

<p>Giles's message to Americans like him who are in the political middle: "John McCain's Republican Party is gone, and we don't owe a damn thing to what's been left behind."</p>

<p>Organizers aired a video Wednesday showing former Trump voters explaining why they were flipping to Harris.</p>

<p>"I made a grave mistake," Florida voter Rich Logis said via video about how he had jumped headlong into Trump's MAGA movement. "But it's never too late to change your mind," Logis said.</p>

<p>Olivia Troye, a former counter-terrorism advisor for Trump's vice president Mike Pence, addressed the convention, while high-profile Republican never-Trumper Adam Kinzinger, an ex-congressman, takes the stage Thursday, the closing night.</p>

<p>Trump frequently assails such critics as traitors to the cause, and it remains unclear how persuasive they will be.</p>

<p>David Urban, a Republican advisor to Trump's 2016 campaign, dismissed any substantial impact.</p>

<p>But he told CNN the appearance by Georgia's Duncan "may give people permission to vote for Kamala Harris" in the state.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jkb4o3qo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-awaiting-sex-change-surgery-sues-hospital-says-he-was-given-electric-shocks-6390832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Man Awaiting Sex Surgery Sues Hospital Over Electric Shock Therapy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-awaiting-sex-change-surgery-sues-hospital-says-he-was-given-electric-shocks-6390832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:22:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In China, having a sex change procedure is viewed as disrespectful to parents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man in China who was waiting for sex reassignment surgery has filed an 80,000 yuan (Rs 9.4 lakh approximately) lawsuit against a hospital, claiming he was coerced into receiving electroshock treatment, as per a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3275106/china-man-awaiting-sex-reassignment-surgery-sues-hospital-over-forced-electroshock-therapy"><em>South China Morning Post. </em></a>The 27-year-old is a live-streamer from the northern Chinese province of Hebei and posts videos of himself donning women's clothes and makeup. The man said that he received electric shocks for several days while being forced into a hospital for 97 days.</p>

<p>Despite being born a male, he informed <em>Hongxing News</em> that he identifies as a woman. The social media star started taking oestrogen, one of the main female sex hormones. As a result, he developed long hair, lost facial hair, and softened his voice. He claims that he has been putting aside the money he earned from live-streaming in the hopes of undergoing surgery to change his gender.</p>

<p>However, Linger's parents disapproved of his choice. Since the Chinese traditionally believe that a person's body is a gift from their parents and that a person's gender should not be changed, they were unable to accept their son's gender transition, which caused several disputes within the family. Notably, in China, having a sex change procedure is viewed as disrespectful to parents.</p>

<p>Linger told <em>Hongxing News</em> that he agreed to visit a hospital in 2022 to avoid any other conflicts. Although he was aware that the facility was for psychiatric patients, he did not believe he was mentally ill. A doctor there diagnosed him with "anxiety disorder" and "ego-dystonic sexual orientation," a mental illness characterising a conflict between a person's intended and real sexual orientation. Soon after, the medical personnel took away his phone and forced him to stay in the hospital for 97 days. "After being admitted to the hospital, I was tied to the bed with ropes, and many doctors controlled my body and administered electroshock therapy for days," Linger said.</p>

<p>He sued the hospital for violating his human rights, requesting 80,000 yuan in damages. However, on August 13, Jiulongshan Hospital said during the hearing that they had "done nothing wrong" and the shocks were given to control the emotions to enhance the self-awareness of psychiatric patients.</p>

<p>According to the hospital, Linger's mother signed a consent form. The legal case is still being heard in court.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dlc8vceg_hospital_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[iulongshan Hospital said during the hearing that they had "done nothing wrong."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-penguin-dies-ending-famous-same-sex-power-couple-6390785]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian Penguin Dies, Ending Famous "Same-Sex Power Couple"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-penguin-dies-ending-famous-same-sex-power-couple-6390785]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:14:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A celebrated Australian penguin famous for raising chicks as part of an unlikely same-sex couple has died, a Sydney aquarium said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A celebrated Australian penguin famous for raising chicks as part of an unlikely same-sex couple has died, a Sydney aquarium said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Male gentoo penguins Sphen and Magic caught the attention of zookeepers, and then the world, when they built a nest of pebbles together in 2018.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They were eventually given live eggs to incubate from other penguin couples, hatching chick Sphengic in 2018 and Clancy two years later.</p>

<p>Sealife Aquarium said Sphen -- the older partner in the "same-sex" penguin "power couple" -- had died just shy of turning 12, considered a long life in captivity.</p>

<p>Sphen and Magic were adopted as gay icons in Australia and further abroad, inspiring a float at the Sydney Mardi Gras parade and featuring in the Netflix sitcom Atypical.</p>

<p>But they also had their critics, with some in conservative circles saying the penguins were unwittingly being used to push a political agenda.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unlike many mammal species, male and female penguins take on the same parenting roles, and share parental duties 50-50.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Same-sex couples between both males and females are not unheard of, although they are often short-lived in the wild.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was not the first time same-sex penguin couples had adopted eggs in captivity, with a handful of zoos worldwide reporting similar cases.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2009, two male penguins -- Z and Vielpunkt -- successfully hatched and reared a chick that was rejected by its heterosexual parents at a zoo in Berlin.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Before them came Roy and Silo, two male chinstrap penguins at a zoo in New York who were spotted frequently trying to mate with each other.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ttogh5uo_sphen-magic_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sphen and Magic were adopted as gay icons in Australia and further abroad.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-kamala-harris-dials-running-mate-tim-walz-before-his-special-night-6390769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Kamala Harris Dials Running Mate Tim Walz Before His "Special Night"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-kamala-harris-dials-running-mate-tim-walz-before-his-special-night-6390769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 10:10:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ahead of his big night on the third day of the Democratic National Convention, US presidential candidate Kamala Harris gave a pep talk to his running mate Tim Walz.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of his big night on the third day of the Democratic National Convention, US presidential candidate Kamala Harris gave a pep talk to his running mate Tim Walz.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The stage is yours, Tim Walz. Enjoy the moment," Kamala Harris said on X, sharing a video of her call to the Democratic vice presidential candidate.</p>

<p>"Hi, Tim. It's Kamala. How are you feeling?," the current US Vice President says on her call to Tim Walz.</p>

<p>Harris, dressed in a navy pantsuit, says "You're going to be fantastic tonight. So good."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The stage is yours, <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Tim_Walz</a>. Enjoy the moment. <a href="https://t.co/7TgxBcm0Ji">pic.twitter.com/7TgxBcm0Ji</a></p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1826461408705319284?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"I am excited. Thanks for the opportunity. It's going to be electric in there and the messages this week are so great. So, I'll go down there and deliver a freedom speech," Mr Walz replied.</p>

<p>Ms Harris advises her running mate to "just feel the love in the room" as he addressed the crowd gathered at the Democratic National Convention.</p>

<p>"We've been seeing it everywhere we go. Enjoy the moment, its a special night for you," she says.</p>

<p>The two share a hearty laugh as he quips that the "Minnesotans will be pretty jazzed up".</p>

<p>The governor formally accepted his nomination to be the Democratic Party's vice presidential candidate as he began his keynote address, professing his love for his country.</p>

<p>"It's the honour of my life to accept your nomination for vice president of the United States. What all we're all here tonight for one beautiful, simple reason. We love this country," Walz told the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</p>

<p>Taking the stage ahead of Harris's big night on Thursday, the former teacher and National Guard soldier Walz outlined his life story in a speech.</p>

<p>Ahead of his speech, former US president Bill Clinton and talk show legend Oprah Winfrey took the stage to rally support for Harris and Walz.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lo3nk2mo_kamala-harris-tim-walz-call_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democratic-convention-hindu-priest-rakesh-bhatt-om-shanti-ahead-of-kamala-harris-big-night-a-vedic-prayer-at-democrat-event-6390153]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Om Shanti Chants At Democratic Convention As Hindu Priest Opens Day 3]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democratic-convention-hindu-priest-rakesh-bhatt-om-shanti-ahead-of-kamala-harris-big-night-a-vedic-prayer-at-democrat-event-6390153]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 07:46:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chants of "Om Shanti Shanti" reverberated across the hall as a Hindu priest began proceedings on day 3 of the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chants of "Om Shanti Shanti" reverberated across the hall as a Hindu priest began proceedings on day 3 of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-3-live-kamala-harris-running-mate-tim-walz-bill-clinton-nancy-pelosi-to-speak-at-dnc-tod-6389363">Democratic National Convention</a> in Chicago. Rakesh Bhatt, a priest at the Sri Siva Vishnu Temple in Maryland, chanted a Vedic prayer seeking blessings for a united country.</p>

<p>"Even if we have differences, when it comes to the nation, we have to be united," Mr Bhatt said.</p>

<p>"We should be in unison. Let our minds think together. Let our hearts beat as one. All for the betterment of society. May this make us powerful so we can unite and make our nation proud," the senior Hindu priest added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sri Rakesh Bhatt, a Hindu priest with Sri Shiva Vishnu Temple in MD, delivers invocation in Sanskrit &amp; English at start of 3rd night of DNC convention in Chicago: “Even if we have differences…we have to be united &amp; it moves us towards justice for all. We are 1 universal family.” <a href="https://t.co/i2rsqSWhq0">pic.twitter.com/i2rsqSWhq0</a></p>
— Niraj Warikoo (@nwarikoo) <a href="https://twitter.com/nwarikoo/status/1826410371919609876?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 22, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Taking the stage ahead of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vice-president-tim-walz-pick-set-to-star-on-day-3-of-democratic-convention-6388689">Kamala Harris' big night</a> on Thursday, Mr Bhatt urged America to choose a leader who believes in the Vedic concept of 'Vasudhaiva Kutumbakam' (the whole world is one family).</p>

<p>"We are one universal family. Truth is our foundation and always prevails. Lead us from unreal to real, from darkness to the light, and from death to immortality. Om Shanti Shanti Shanti," Mr Bhatt said.</p>

<p>Rakesh Bhatt is a Madhwa priest who moved to the US from Bengaluru. He trained in Rig Veda and Tantrasaara (Maadhva) Agama, under his guru, Pejavar Swamiji of Udupi Ashta Matha.</p>

<p>Mr Bhatt, who speaks Hindi, English, Sanskrit, Tamil, Telugu, Kannada, and Tulu fluently, holds a Bachelor's and Master's degree in three languages: Sanskrit, English, and Kannada. He earned his English and Kannada degrees from Osteen College, Bengaluru, and his Sanskrit degree from Jayachamarajendra College. Following a brief stint at Udupi Ashta Matha, he worked briefly at Badrinath and Raghavendra Swami Koil, Salem, before joining Sri Sri Vishnu Temple in July 2013.</p>

<p>Ajay Bhutoria, Deputy National Finance Chair of the Democratic Party, remarked, "Rakesh Bhatt's Hindu prayer at the DNC today is a significant moment, showcasing the Democratic Party's commitment to inclusivity and diversity."</p>

<p>"It is heartening to see the rich cultural and spiritual traditions of the Indian American community being honoured on such a prominent stage. This moment reflects the growing influence and recognition of our community within the fabric of American society," Mr Bhutoria said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hindu prayer at the DNC Convention today is a significant moment, showcasing the Democratic Party's commitment to inclusivity and diversity. It is heartening to see the rich cultural and spiritual traditions of the Indian American community being honored on such a prominent stage <a href="https://t.co/6wNsnthmbd">pic.twitter.com/6wNsnthmbd</a></p>
— Ajay Jain Bhutoria (@ajainb) <a href="https://twitter.com/ajainb/status/1826426420714672263?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 22, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The Democrats will officially hand the baton to 59-year-old Kamala Harris with hopes of defeating Donald Trump in the US presidential elections later this year.</p>

<p>Polls show the race remains close, but Harris is moving slightly ahead - a remarkable turn of events, given that only a month ago Trump seemed to be gaining a steadily tightening grip over Joe Biden.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fqbd8gjg_rakesh-bhatt_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rakesh Bhatt is a priest at the Sri Siva Vishnu Temple in Maryland.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-filled-with-fear-guilt-after-vienna-concert-terror-threat-6390121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taylor Swift Filled With "Fear, Guilt" After Vienna Concert Terror Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-filled-with-fear-guilt-after-vienna-concert-terror-threat-6390121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 07:37:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pop megastar Taylor Swift on Wednesday broke her silence about the cancellation of three Vienna concerts over an alleged suicide attack plot, saying the incident filled her with "fear" and "guilt."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pop megastar Taylor Swift on Wednesday broke her silence about the cancellation of three Vienna concerts over an alleged suicide attack plot, saying the incident filled her with "fear" and "guilt."<br />
"Having our Vienna shows cancelled was devastating. The reason for the cancellations filled me with a new sense of fear, and a tremendous amount of guilt because so many had planned on coming to those shows," the American said in a post on social media platform Instagram.</p>

<p>The Vienna shows, part of the European leg of Swift's record-breaking "Eras" tour, were cancelled after authorities warned of a terror plot by sympathizers of the Islamic State armed group.</p>

<p>Police have detained three suspects over the alleged attack threat, with the United States saying it shared intelligence to assist in the investigation.</p>

<p>The main suspect, a 19-year-old Austrian with North Macedonian roots, had allegedly confessed, saying he "intended to carry out an attack using explosives and knives," according to Austrian domestic intelligence agency (DSN) head Omar Haijawi-Pirchner.</p>

<p>In the social media post Wednesday, Swift thanked the authorities.</p>

<p>"I was also so grateful to the authorities because thanks to them, we were grieving concerts and not lives. I was heartened by the love and unity I saw in the fans who banded together," she said.</p>

<p>The European leg of Swift's sold-out tour began in Paris in May and has taken in Sweden, Portugal, Spain, Britain, Ireland, the Netherlands, Switzerland, Italy, Germany and Poland.</p>

<p>It concluded on Tuesday with five shows at London's Wembley stadium.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/hbet97sg_taylor-swift_625x300_15_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-jailed-for-11-years-for-killing-man-who-allegedly-sexually-trafficked-her-6390118]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Jailed For 11 Years For Killing Man Who Allegedly Abused Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-jailed-for-11-years-for-killing-man-who-allegedly-sexually-trafficked-her-6390118]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 07:33:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 24-year-old woman in the United States has been sentenced to 11 years in prison after pleading guilty to second-degree reckless homicide in the killing of a man who she said trafficked her as a teenager.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 24-year-old woman in the United States has been sentenced to 11 years in prison after pleading guilty to second-degree reckless homicide in the killing of a man who she said trafficked her as a teenager. According to <em>CNN</em>, Chrystul Kizer was sentenced on Monday. She will also serve five years of parole. She must submit a DNA sample to authorities and attend a restitution hearing later. "The 11 years is minus ... 570 days because she has served those awaiting trial," Kenosha County District Attorney Michael Graveley told the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Kizer shot 34-year-old Randall Volar at his Kenosha, Wisconsin, home in 2018 when she was 17 years old. She shot him in the head, burned his house down and stole his BMW. She was initially charged with multiple counts, including first-degree intentional homicide, arson, car theft and being a felon in possession of a firearm, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://amp-cnn-com.cdn.ampproject.org/v/s/amp.cnn.com/cnn/2024/08/19/us/chrystul-kizer-sentencing-sex-trafficking-death?amp_js_v=0.1&amp;amp_gsa=1#webview=1&amp;cap=swipe">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Kizer was 16 when she met Volar. She alleged that he had sexually abused her multiple times. The prosecutor's office also confirmed that it was working on a case against Volar at the time of his death. But prosecutors also said that Ms Kizer didn't give any indication at the time of the killing that she was trafficked by Volar.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a 2019 interview with<em> The Washington Post</em>, Ms Kizer said that in 2018 she went to Volar's house with a gun in her purse that she said her boyfriend gave her for protection. She alleged that while she was there, Volar gave her a drug and the two decided to watch a movie. They then began to fight after Volar began touching her and she refused to have sex with her, she alleged.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-hospital-for-allegedly-losing-part-of-his-skull-following-brain-surgery-6383052">&nbsp;US Man Sues Hospital For Allegedly Losing Part Of His Skull Following Brain Surgery</a></strong></p>

<p>Ms Kizer also said that Volar pinned her before she shot him twice. She then set Volar's body on fire and fled in his car. "I just thought that I didn't want to do that stuff anymore because I was trying to change," she said.</p>

<p>Kenosha District Attorney Michael D. Graveley accused Ms Kizer of premeditated murder, alleging she planned to steal Volar's BMW. In 2022, she had a legal victory when the state Supreme Court upheld a ruling that she could argue she acted in self-defence under a state law that allows victims of trafficking to present "an affirmative defence for any offence committed as a direct result" of being trafficked. She was released from prison earlier this year on a $400,000 bond when she fled the state, violating the conditions of her bail. She was caught two weeks later in Louisiana and was returned to Wisconsin.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fcmtir5_chrystul-kizer-_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman will also serve five years of parole. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senior-us-officials-meet-with-dalai-lama-in-new-york-6389844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Senior US Officials Meet With Dalai Lama In New York]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senior-us-officials-meet-with-dalai-lama-in-new-york-6389844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 06:04:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Senior officials from the U.S. State Department and the White House met with the Dalai Lama in New York on Wednesday and "reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to advancing the human rights of Tibetans," the State Department said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Senior officials from the U.S. State Department and the White House met with the Dalai Lama in New York on Wednesday and "reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to advancing the human rights of Tibetans," the State Department said.</p>

<p>The meeting with the 89-year-old exiled spiritual leader of Tibetan Buddhism will likely irritate China, which considers him a dangerous separatist and opposes contact by officials of any country with him.</p>

<p>The Dalai Lama, who fled to India in 1959 after a failed uprising against Chinese rule in Tibet, traveled to New York in June for medical treatment on his knees, his first visit to the United States since 2017.</p>

<p>A State Department statement said Uzra Zeya, the U.S. undersecretary of state for human rights and special coordinator for Tibetan issues, traveled to New York for an audience with the Dalai Lama, joined by the White House director for human rights, Kelly Razzouk.</p>

<p>It said Zeya "conveyed, on behalf of President Biden, best wishes for His Holiness's good health and reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to advancing the human rights of Tibetans and supporting efforts to preserve their distinct historical, linguistic, cultural, and religious heritage."</p>

<p>Zeya discussed U.S. efforts to address human rights abuses in Tibet and support for a resumption of dialogue between China and the Dalai Lama, the statement said.</p>

<p>A group of U.S. lawmakers met the Dalai Lama in India before his U.S. trip and said they would not allow China to influence the choice of his successor.</p>

<p>Last month, China expressed strong opposition to a U.S. law signed by President Joe Biden that presses Beijing to resolve a dispute over Tibet's demands for greater autonomy and vowed to "firmly defend" its interests.</p>

<p>The Dalai Lama has met U.S. officials, including U.S. presidents, during previous visits to the U.S., but Biden has not met him since taking office in 2021.</p>

<p>In 2020, Biden criticized then President Donald Trump for being the only president in three decades who had not met or spoken with the Tibetan spiritual leader, calling it "disgraceful."</p>

<p>Wednesday's meeting comes at a time when Biden has sought to stabilize rocky ties with China ahead of a presidential election on Nov. 5, in which Vice President Kamala Harris is pitted against Trump.</p>

<p>China's embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the meeting.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kksv507_dalai-lama_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Dalai Lama traveled to New York in June for medical treatment on his knees.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-neuralink-reports-successful-2nd-implant-trial-no-thread-issues-6389755]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk's Neuralink Reports Successful 2nd Implant Trial, No Thread Issues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-neuralink-reports-successful-2nd-implant-trial-no-thread-issues-6389755]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 05:31:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's brain technology startup Neuralink said its implant, designed to allow paralyzed patients to use digital devices by thinking alone, is working well in a second trial patient.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's brain technology startup Neuralink said its implant, designed to allow paralyzed patients to use digital devices by thinking alone, is working well in a second trial patient.</p>

<p>The company said the patient, identified as Alex, did not face issues of "thread retraction", unlike Noland Arbaugh, Neuralink's first patient who received the implant in January.</p>

<p>The tiny wires of the implant retracted post surgery for Arbaugh, resulting in a sharp reduction in the electrodes that could measure brain signals. The threads have stabilized for Arbaugh, Neuralink said.</p>

<p>Reuters had reported Neuralink was aware of this issue from its animal trials.</p>

<p>The company said on Wednesday it implemented measures such as reduction in the motion of the brain during surgery as well as limiting the gap between the implant and the surface of the brain to prevent similar issues in its second patient.</p>

<p>Neuralink is in the process of testing its device, which is intended to help people with spinal cord injuries. The device has allowed the first patient to play video games, browse the internet, post on social media and move a cursor on his laptop.</p>

<p>Last month, the company successfully implanted the device in the second patient, who has been using the device to play video games and learn how to design 3D objects.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pnvon14o_elon-musk-neuralink_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's brain technology startup Neuralink said its implant is working well in a 2nd trial patient.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-rising-tensions-us-aircraft-carrier-arrives-in-middle-east-6389503]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Rising Tensions, US Aircraft Carrier Arrives In Middle East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-rising-tensions-us-aircraft-carrier-arrives-in-middle-east-6389503]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 04:01:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The USS Abraham Lincoln aircraft carrier and accompanying destroyers have arrived in the Middle East, the US military said Wednesday, after the country's defense secretary ordered the strike group to accelerate its speed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The USS Abraham Lincoln aircraft carrier and accompanying destroyers have arrived in the Middle East, the US military said Wednesday, after the country's defense secretary ordered the strike group to accelerate its speed.</p>

<p>The carrier's arrival brings the number in the region to two -- at least temporarily, as the Lincoln is to replace the USS Theodore Roosevelt -- at a time of heightened fears of regional conflict following high-profile assassinations claimed by, or blamed on, Israel.</p>

<p>"USS Abraham Lincoln (CVN 72), equipped with F-35C and F/A-18 Block III fighters, entered the US Central Command (USCENTCOM) area of responsibility," the military command responsible for the Middle East said on social media.</p>

<p>"The USS Abraham Lincoln (CVN 72), the flagship of Carrier Strike Group 3, is accompanied by Destroyer Squadron (DESRON) 21 and Carrier Air Wing (CVW) 9," it added.</p>

<p>The Pentagon said on August 11 that US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin had ordered the Lincoln to "accelerate its transit" to the Middle East, after directing its deployment to the region at the beginning of the month.</p>

<p>Fears of a major escalation have mounted since Hezbollah and Iran vowed to respond to twin killings blamed on Israel late last month.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike on Beirut's southern suburbs killed a top Hezbollah commander, Fuad Shukr, shortly before an attack in Tehran blamed on Israel killed Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7di006e_uss-lincoln_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The USS Abraham Lincoln aircraft carrier and accompanying destroyers have arrived in the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-stands-behind-bulletproof-glass-in-1st-outdoor-rally-since-shooting-6389421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Stands Behind Bulletproof Glass In 1st Outdoor Rally Since Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-stands-behind-bulletproof-glass-in-1st-outdoor-rally-since-shooting-6389421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 03:35:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump held his first outdoor campaign event on Wednesday since an assassination attempt, lobbing insults at his surging Democratic opponent Kamala Harris from behind bulletproof glass at a rally in the battleground state of North Carolina.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump held his first outdoor campaign event on Wednesday since an assassination attempt, lobbing insults at his surging Democratic opponent Kamala Harris from behind bulletproof glass at a rally in the battleground state of North Carolina.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, speaking against a backdrop of vintage warplanes at an aviation museum, called Harris the "most radical left person" ever to run for the White House and claimed that millions of jobs will "vanish overnight" if she wins in November.</p>

<p>"Your life savings will be totally wiped out," the Republican candidate told the crowd, one of a number of apocalyptic scenarios he painted during his speech.</p>

<p>"All over the world, our adversaries knew that America was not to be trifled with when I was your commander in chief," Trump said. "If comrade Kamala wins this November, World War III is virtually guaranteed to happen."</p>

<p>With Harris drawing enthusiastic crowds since replacing Joe Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket, the event in Asheboro was a chance for Trump to reclaim his longtime dominance in staging spectacular rallies.</p>

<p>It was his first big outdoor event since being lightly wounded in an attempted assassination at a similarly open site in Butler, Pennsylvania, a month ago.</p>

<p>That attack left one rally participant dead before the 20-year-old gunman was killed by a Secret Service sniper.</p>

<p>The Secret Service recommended that Trump stick to more easily controllable indoor venues such as sports arenas. He has since held about a dozen indoor events.</p>

<p>The Secret Service does not comment publicly on security operations and did not respond to requests for comment on Wednesday's preparations.</p>

<p>A bulletproof screen could be seen around the podium where Trump and his vice presidential pick, J.D. Vance, addressed the crowd in Asheboro.</p>

<p>At one point during his speech, Trump left the stage and entered the crowd to check on an attendee who was suffering a medical issue.</p>

<p>Crowds are an integral part of Trump's political brand, with the right-wing billionaire seeking to portray himself as an outsider and man of the people.</p>

<p>Even as president, he kept up a steady schedule of election-style rallies, often filling sports arenas with at least 10,000 people.</p>

<p>He had counted on these demonstrations of strength as a key weapon in his plan to make the 81-year-old Biden, whose own public events were generally low-key and relatively small-scale affairs, look ineffectual.</p>

<p>- Trump's strategy upended -</p>

<p>Trump's strategy was upended on July 21, however, when Biden abruptly dropped his reelection bid and endorsed his 59-year-old vice president as the future of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>The immediate explosion of Democratic support for Harris appears to have stunned the Trump campaign.</p>

<p>Nowhere is the shift in momentum more visible than in Harris's ability to pack arenas.</p>

<p>She is consistently filling venues with well over 10,000 people. On Tuesday night, supporters packed the Democratic National Convention in Chicago while she hosted a mass rally of her own in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>In a clear dig at Trump, her Milwaukee event took place in the same arena that the Republicans had used for their convention back in July.</p>

<p>North Carolina is one of a handful of swing states that are expected to determine the outcome of the November 5 election.</p>

<p>US presidential elections are not decided by an overall national vote but state-by-state, with each state worth varying amounts of Electoral College votes. The winning candidate needs to win a majority of the Electoral College.</p>

<p>Most states trend solidly Republican or firmly Democrat, and only around seven are considered true toss-ups where the race is really fought -- and where the candidates spend most of their campaigning time and money.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1ger1kto_donald-trump_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was Trump first outdoor event since being lightly wounded in an attempted assassination last month.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-3-live-kamala-harris-running-mate-tim-walz-bill-clinton-nancy-pelosi-to-speak-at-dnc-tod-6389363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Highlights: Democratic Vice Presidential Candidate Tim Walz Accepts Nomination]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-3-live-kamala-harris-running-mate-tim-walz-bill-clinton-nancy-pelosi-to-speak-at-dnc-tod-6389363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 03:19:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 2024 Democratic National Convention continues today with Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, the running mate of Vice President and Democratic nominee Kamala Harris, set to deliver the keynote address.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 2024 Democratic National Convention continues today with Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, the running mate of Vice President and Democratic nominee Kamala Harris delivering the keynote address. As the convention enters its third day, anticipation is high for Walz's speech.</p>

<p>In addition to Walz, prominent figures such as former President Bill Clinton, former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, and House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries also spoke at the convention. Wednesday's theme is "A Fight for Our Freedoms," where Democrats will emphasise the importance of Harris as a defender of American freedoms and argue that former President Donald Trump poses a significant threat to the nation.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, former President Barack Obama and former First Lady Michelle Obama captivated the audience with their powerful speeches, receiving standing ovations. In his remarks, Obama criticised Trump, stating that the US cannot afford another four years of chaos.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the Live updates of the US Democratic Convention day 3:</strong></h2><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nnmsaa8_tim-walz-afp_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Live: On the third day of the event, the theme will be "A Fight for Our Freedoms".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vice-president-tim-walz-pick-set-to-star-on-day-3-of-democratic-convention-6388689]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Honour Of My Life": Democrats' Vice President Pick Accepts Nomination]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vice-president-tim-walz-pick-set-to-star-on-day-3-of-democratic-convention-6388689]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 03:07:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tim Walz, Governor from Minnesota, has accepted his nomination to be Kamala Harris' White House running mate in a keynote address at the Democratic Convention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>"It's the honor of my life to accept your nomination for vice president of the United States. We're all here tonight for one beautiful, simple reason -- we love this country," Walz said at the Convention in Chicago. The Republican running mate of Donald Trump is JD Vance.</li>
	<li>The former National Guard officer has been making a name for himself as one of the Democrats' most effective communicators, with his criticism of Trump and running mate J.D. Vance as "weird" going viral shortly before Harris entered the race.</li>
	<li>The chemistry between Harris and Walz and the noise energy generated at their rallies is helping to fuel Democratic hopes that they can defeat Trump in November.</li>
	<li>Earlier in the day, former president Bill Clinton delighted the crowd with his 12th appearance at the Democratic convention. Harris had "knocked it out of the park" by picking Walz as her running mate, he said.</li>
	<li>On Day 2, Michelle Obama spoke about Kamala Harris' background, highlighting her multi-racial origin as "the embodiment of stories we speak about (in) this country. "Her story is your story. It is my story," she said, in response to jibes by Donald Trump. Her counterattacks were brief but packed a punch, and included a sarcastic dig at the twice-impeached former President for running for "one of those Black jobs".</li>
	<li>Her husband and former US President Barack Obama came with the second punch against Trump and said, "Here is a 78-year-old billionaire who has not stopped whining about his problems since he rode down his golden elevator nine years ago," Mr Obama said. "It has been a constant gripe, conspiracy theories and grievance that has been getting worse since he is afraid of losing to Kamala."</li>
	<li>Kamala Harris will make a big speech on August 22, the last day of the event, but one of the notable speakers yesterday will be her husband, Doug Emhoff, a successful lawyer. If Harris wins, then Emhoff will be the first "first gentleman" of the United States.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Mr Emhoof cheered for his wife and said "She brings both joy and toughness to this task. At this moment in our nation's history, she is exactly the right president."</li>
	<li>The convention served as a farewell for Joe Biden, who withdrew his nomination in an unprecedented move witnessed in modern US electoral history. In 1968, President Lyndon B Johnson declared in the middle of the Vietnam War that he would not run for re-election.</li>
	<li>On day one, President Biden criticised Mr Trump's "America First" doctrine, which he said had damaged the nation's global image, contrasting his own administration's efforts to unite Europe and counter Russian aggression.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/37jvoulg_tim-walz-afp_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tim Walz is the the current Governor of Minnesota.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-spoke-to-netanyahu-on-gaza-truce-white-house-6388929]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Spoke To Netanyahu On Gaza Truce: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-spoke-to-netanyahu-on-gaza-truce-white-house-6388929]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:54:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden called Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Wednesday as Gaza ceasefire talks between Israel and Hamas stumble, the White House said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden called Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Wednesday as Gaza ceasefire talks between Israel and Hamas stumble, the White House said.</p>

<p>The pair, joined by Vice President and White House hopeful Kamala Harris, discussed "the ceasefire and hostage release deal and diplomatic efforts to de-escalate regional tensions," the White House said in a brief statement.</p>

<p>A readout of the call would be forthcoming, the White House added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/r1f2pcco_biden-netanyahu-_625x300_05_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tim-walz-to-accept-vice-president-nomination-at-democratic-convention-6388703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tim Walz To Accept Vice President Nomination At Democratic Convention]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tim-walz-to-accept-vice-president-nomination-at-democratic-convention-6388703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 23:57:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tim Walz will officially accept the nomination to be Kamala Harris's White House running mate Wednesday as he presses a charm offensive that has made him a darling of the Democratic National Convention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tim Walz will officially accept the nomination to be Kamala Harris's White House running mate Wednesday as he presses a charm offensive that has made him a darling of the Democratic National Convention.</p>

<p>The relatively unknown Minnesota governor brings an earthy, Midwestern vibe to Harris's surging campaign against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Taking the stage ahead of Harris's big night on Thursday, former school teacher and National Guard soldier Walz will emphasize his "small town values" and "lifetime of service," said Alex Hornbrook, a convention organizer.</p>

<p>"The coach is going to coach tonight," said Democratic National Committee chairman Jaime Harrison on CNN, referring to Walz's days coaching a high-school football team.</p>

<p>With former president Bill Clinton as an opener, Walz will tee up Harris's Thursday speech and the climax of a convention that has defied predictions of disunity or even chaos in the wake of President Joe Biden's decision to drop his reelection bid on July 21.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, it was Democratic superstars Michelle and former president Barack Obama who spoke, following up on Biden's emotional speech Monday, where he passed the torch to his vice president, then both figuratively and literally left the stage.</p>

<p>The convention has seen intense enthusiasm, reflecting Democrats' relief after an extraordinary month in which the party went from despair over 81-year-old Biden's stumbling campaign to giddy excitement at Harris's rebranding.</p>

<p>A big part of that change in atmosphere has been due to Walz, who is getting chants of "Tim! Tim! Tim!" and requests for selfies at the convention.</p>

<p>He has made a name for himself as an able communicator and is credited with coming up with one of the sharpest attack lines on Trump and his running mate J.D. Vance, whom he labeled "weird."</p>

<p>As a folksy, white Midwesterner, Walz balances Harris's California background and barrier-breaking status as the first Black woman nominee.</p>

<p>Walz, 60, will likely speak of his upbringing in small-town Nebraska, where he worked on the family farm, and describe his military service, his experiences as a teacher and his record in politics.</p>

<p>"He's that uncle that you just want to hang out with," Harrison said.</p>

<h3><strong>Battle of the rallies</strong></h3>

<p>The chemistry between 59-year-old Harris and Walz and the noisy energy generated at their rallies is helping to fuel Democratic hopes that they can defeat Trump, 78, in November.</p>

<p>Polls show the race remains close, but Harris is moving slightly ahead -- a remarkable turn of events, given that only a month ago Trump seemed to be gaining a steadily tightening grip over Biden.</p>

<p>Exhibit number one in that shift has been Harris's ability to pack arenas in a way that for years Trump had touted as evidence of his seemingly unique political strength.</p>

<p>In a dramatic gesture, Harris and Walz held a mass rally on Tuesday in Milwaukee at the same time as the convention crowd jammed into the Chicago venue.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Trump was due to gather supporters in North Carolina for his first outdoor rally since an attempt on his life last month that saw him lightly injured and a bystander killed. Security will be especially tight, with a bulletproof glass screen erected around the podium.</p>

<p>Republicans have ramped up attacks on Walz in an attempt to paint him as an extreme leftist, much as Trump routinely brands Harris a "communist" and "marxist."</p>

<p>But Sabrina Karim, associate professor in the department of government at Cornell University, said Walz was successfully balancing the Harris ticket.</p>

<p>"His form of masculinity stands in contrast to Donald Trump, and provides some voters, particularly white male voters, an alternative way to be masculine that could be appealing."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/oue2hme8_tim-walz-afp_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tim Walz has served as the governor of Minnesota since 2019. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-is-big-tech-opposing-california-bill-on-artificial-intelligence-6388642]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Is Big Tech Opposing California Bill On Artificial Intelligence?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-is-big-tech-opposing-california-bill-on-artificial-intelligence-6388642]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 23:47:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[California legislators are set to vote on a bill as soon as this week that would broadly regulate how artificial intelligence is developed and deployed in California even as a number of tech giants have voiced broad opposition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>California legislators are set to vote on a bill as soon as this week that would broadly regulate how artificial intelligence is developed and deployed in California even as a number of tech giants have voiced broad opposition.</p>

<p>Here is background on the bill, known as SB 1047, and why it has faced backlash from Silicon Valley technologists and some lawmakers:</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT DOES THE BILL DO?</strong></h3>

<p>Advanced by State Senator Scott Wiener, a Democrat, the proposal would mandate safety testing for many of the most advanced AI models that cost more than $100 million to develop or those that require a defined amount of computing power. Developers of AI software operating in the state would also need to outline methods for turning off the AI models if they go awry, effectively a kill switch.</p>

<p>The bill would also give the state attorney general the power to sue if developers are not compliant, particularly in the event of an ongoing threat, such as the AI taking over government systems like the power grid.</p>

<p>As well, the bill would require developers to hire third-party auditors to assess their safety practices and provide additional protections to whistleblowers speaking out against AI abuses.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT HAVE LAWMAKERS SAID?</strong></h3>

<p>SB 1047 has already passed the state Senate by a 32-1 vote. Last week it passed the state Assembly appropriations committee, setting up a vote by the full Assembly. If it passes by the end of the legislative session on Aug. 31, it would advance to Governor Gavin Newsom to sign or veto by Sept. 30.</p>

<p>Wiener, who represents San Francisco, home to OpenAI and many of the startups developing the powerful software, has said legislation is necessary to protect the public before advances in AI become either unwieldy or uncontrollable.</p>

<p>However, a group of California Congressional Democrats oppose the bill, including San Francisco's Nancy Pelosi; Ro Khanna, whose congressional district encompasses much of Silicon Valley; and Zoe Lofgren, from San Jose.</p>

<p>Pelosi this week called SB 1047 ill-informed and said it may cause more harm than good. In an open letter last week, the Democrats said the bill could drive developers from the state and threaten so-called open-source AI models, which rely on code that is freely available for anyone to use or modify.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT DO TECH LEADERS SAY?</strong></h3>

<p>Tech companies developing AI - which can respond to prompts with fully formed text, images or audio as well as run repetitive tasks with minimal intervention - have called for stronger guardrails for AI's deployment. They have cited risks that the software could one day evade human intervention and cause cyberattacks, among other concerns. But they also largely balked at SB 1047.</p>

<p>Wiener revised the bill to appease tech companies, relying in part on input from AI startup Anthropic - backed by Amazon and Alphabet. Among other changes, he eliminated the creation of a government AI oversight committee.</p>

<p>Wiener also took out criminal penalties for perjury, though civil suits may still be brought.</p>

<p>Alphabet's Google and Meta have expressed concerns in letters to Wiener. Meta said the bill threatens to make the state unfavorable to AI development and deployment. The Facebook parent's chief scientist, Yann LeCun, in a July X post called the bill potentially harmful to research efforts.</p>

<p>OpenAI, whose ChatGPT is credited with accelerating the frenzy over AI since its broad release in late 2022, has said AI should be regulated by the federal government and that SB 1047 creates an uncertain legal environment.</p>

<p>Of particular concern is the potential for the bill to apply to open-source AI models. Many technologists believe open-source models are important for creating less risky AI applications more quickly, but Meta and others have fretted that they could be held responsible for policing open-source models if the bill passes. Wiener has said he supports open-source models and one of the recent amendments to the bill raised the standard for which open-sourced models are covered under its provisions.</p>

<p>The bill also has its backers in the technology sector. Geoffrey Hinton, widely credited as a "godfather of AI," former OpenAI employee Daniel Kokotajlo and researcher Yoshua Bengio have said they support the bill.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d6h7nnlg_ai-reuters_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bill would require developers to hire third-party auditors to assess their safety practice]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/displaced-gaza-student-tries-to-study-despite-destruction-of-universities-6388535]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Displaced Gaza Student Tries To Study Despite Destruction Of Universities]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/displaced-gaza-student-tries-to-study-despite-destruction-of-universities-6388535]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 23:29:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shahed Abu Omar, 20, was in her third year studying computer science at Gaza's Al Azhar University when it was reduced to rubble by Israel's military campaign in the Palestinian territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shahed Abu Omar, 20, was in her third year studying computer science at Gaza's Al Azhar University when it was reduced to rubble by Israel's military campaign in the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>She is now one of 90,000 university students left stranded in a war with no end in sight that has damaged or destroyed all 12 of the higher education institutions in the Gaza Strip, according to Palestinian official data.</p>

<p>However, Abu Omar is determined to keep studying, braving a perilous daily journey to reach a stable internet connection that allows her to learn online.</p>

<p>"We cannot go to our university or study away from it," she said, alluding to the difficulty of remote learning with such poor internet connection.</p>

<p>Perched in the rubble of a destroyed house, Abu Omar studies from her mobile phone. Her mother, Hanin Sarour, said they had come to the area to reach an internet connection. The connection, vital to downloading pre-recorded lectures and communicating with professors, was still weak, she said. "Every step is dangerous and difficult," Sarour added.</p>

<p>Most of Abu Omar's professors are in the Gaza Strip as well, she said, facing the same difficulties their students do.</p>

<p>Abu Omar's final exams are in just two weeks. She fears she will only fall further behind. "I am sure we will lose more than the year that we've lost already," she said.</p>

<p>She dreams of returning to university, sitting in a classroom, and meeting with professors and friends.</p>

<p>The war, now in its 11th month, has also interrupted education for Gaza's estimated 625,000 school-aged children, leaving them unable to attend classes.</p>

<p>The uncertainty for Abu Omar and students across the small coastal enclave is likely to persist. Even after the war ends, students do not know when universities will reopen, she said.</p>

<p>Despite all the difficulties, Abu Omar will continue to study in the hopes of not losing a whole year. "We are trying to achieve something," she said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3e2gapa_gaza-student-reuters_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shahed Abu Omar is now one of 90,000 university students left stranded in a war]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-donald-trump-to-hold-1st-outdoor-rally-since-assassination-attempt-6388517]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump To Hold 1st Outdoor Rally Since Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-donald-trump-to-hold-1st-outdoor-rally-since-assassination-attempt-6388517]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 23:21:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump will be behind bulletproof glass Wednesday for his first outdoor rally since surviving an assassination attempt, but the Republican faces a bigger challenge in matching the white-hot enthusiasm of crowds flocking to Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump will be behind bulletproof glass Wednesday for his first outdoor rally since surviving an assassination attempt, but the Republican faces a bigger challenge in matching the white-hot enthusiasm of crowds flocking to Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>The event in Asheboro, North Carolina, a battleground state in the tight November 5 election, is a chance for Trump to reclaim his longtime dominance in staging spectacular rallies.</p>

<p>Accompanied by vice presidential pick J.D. Vance, he will take to the stage at an aviation museum, speaking against a backdrop of vintage war planes about his national security policies.</p>

<p>It is the first time he will hold a big event outdoors since being lightly injured in an attempted assassination at a similarly open site in Butler, Pennsylvania, a month ago. That attack left one bystander dead before the shooter was killed in return fire by a Secret Service sniper.</p>

<p>The Secret Service recommended that Trump, 78, stick to more easily controllable indoor venues, such as sports arenas. He has since attended about a dozen indoor events.</p>

<p>The Secret Service does not comment publicly on security operations and did not respond to requests for comment on Wednesday's preparations. However, a screen could clearly be seen being erected around the stage Trump and Vance will speak from later.</p>

<p>Crowds are an integral part of Trump's political brand in which the right-wing billionaire seeks to portray himself as an outsider and man of the people. Even as president he kept up a steady schedule of election-style rallies, often filling sports arenas with at least 10,000 people.</p>

<p>He'd counted on these demonstrations of strength as a key weapon in his plan to make President Joe Biden, whose own public events are generally low-key and relatively small affairs, look ineffectual.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump's rally dominance upended</strong></h3>

<p>Trump's strategy was upended on July 21, however, when Biden, 81, abruptly dropped his reelection bid and endorsed his younger vice president as the future of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>The immediate explosion of Democratic support for Harris has stunned the Trump campaign.</p>

<p>And nowhere is the shift in momentum more visible than in the 59-year-old Harris's ability to pack arenas.</p>

<p>She is consistently filling venues with well over 10,000. On Tuesday night supporters packed the Democratic National Convention in Chicago while she hosted a mass rally of her own in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>In a clear dig at Trump, her Milwaukee event took place in exactly the same arena that the Republicans had used for their convention back in July.</p>

<p>North Carolina is one of a handful of swing states that are expected to determine the outcome of the November 5 election.</p>

<p>US presidential elections are not decided by an overall national vote but state-by-state, with each state worth varying amounts of Electoral College votes, and the winning candidate needing to score the majority.</p>

<p>Most states trend solidly Republican or firmly Democrat, and only around seven are considered true toss-ups where the race is really fought -- and where the candidates spend most of their campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8od8vok_donald-trump_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was injured in an assassination bid during a rally in Pennsylvania a month ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dosa-butter-chicken-lassi-attract-polish-diners-at-indian-restaurants-in-poland-6388269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dosa, Lassi Attract Polish Diners At Indian Restaurants In Poland]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dosa-butter-chicken-lassi-attract-polish-diners-at-indian-restaurants-in-poland-6388269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:39:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dosa, butter chicken and mango lassi, an unlikely combo for some perhaps but topping the list of favourites for Polish diners who say the dishes remind them of their travels to the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dosa, butter chicken and mango lassi, an unlikely combo for some perhaps but topping the list of favourites for Polish diners who say the dishes remind them of their travels to the country.</p>

<p>More than 45 Indian restaurants are offering a variety of traditional Indian food across Poland, with the capital Warsaw City having at least a dozen of them, as per the listing of the Embassy of India in Poland here.</p>

<p>And not just dining out, Indian food is popular as a takeaway option too across Poland.</p>

<p>India and Indian food are the talk of the town yet again as Warsaw is excited to receive Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who will arrive here for his two-day visit on Wednesday. This will be the first official visit of an Indian prime minister to this country in 45 years.</p>

<p>In Warsaw, Chetan Nandani, a Gujarati businessman, recently opened a restaurant called 'Chaiwala', possibly alluding to the moniker that has stuck with PM Modi since 2014.</p>

<p>Nandani, who already ran a restaurant called 'Curry House,' opened the 'Chaiwala' owing to the popular demand for Indian food. He claimed to have introduced Indian street food to Warsaw.</p>

<p>Polish people who visit India, who visit metros such as Delhi, Mumbai and Kolkata, they get many other things here but not the Indian street food, Nandani said, adding, "I have named it after our beloved Prime Minister Narendra Modi." "Our 'Curry House' chain is already very big here in Poland. We own nine of them. People were suggesting that because we are from India, we should introduce some Indian street food that Polish people can relish. That was the aim behind opening 'Chaiwala'," he told PTI Videos.</p>

<p>According to Indian restaurant owners, Polish people have developed a liking not just for Indian cuisine but also for its rich culture.</p>

<p>"I really like dosa. The best dosa in Warsaw is in India Gate (restaurant), and it really feels like (those) in South India. I have travelled many times to Chennai and Kerala and actually, the food here definitely tastes like that," Anna Maria Rozek, a Polish national, told PTI Videos here.</p>

<p>Chandu, the owner of India Gate food chain, said, "The food is really tasty here ... Indian food with a lot of spices. Every item has a different taste. They (the Polish people) love butter chicken, mango lassi. They love Indian food and Indian people also." The Polish people also love Indian culture and Indian movies are also doing well in Poland nowadays, Chandu said.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Nandani is also confident the demand for Indian street food will grow more and more in times to come in Poland.</p>

<p>Not just in the capital Warsaw, but Indian restaurants are popular in cities such as Krakow and Wroclaw, offering a variety of options to satisfy the curiosity and cravings of foodies in this eastern European country.</p>

<p>For instance, The Castle, a homestay in Krakow, advertises on its website, "Krakow may be deeply rooted in Polish tradition, but its culinary scene offers a wide range of international flavours, with Indian cuisine taking a prominent spot. If you're craving the spicy and aromatic dishes of India, Krakow has a wide range of restaurants that bring authentic tastes right to your plate." It then lists about half a dozen places in the city.</p>

<p>Krakow Buzz, a site that is all about the buzz about the city, and has guides to everything that's hot in the Polish city of the kings, says: "When those endless plates of Polish dumplings and sour Slavic soups get just a little too much, there's a whole stack of Indian restaurants in Krakow that can come to the rescue." "They'll let you swap the potatoes and carbs of Central Europe for a tongue-sizzling sampling of the East. They tout spice-packed curries and pakoras, and can be found in some seriously stunning corners of the city," it describes the mouth-watering Indian dishes and goes on to detail at least half a dozen Indian restaurants in the city.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mghocdi8_dosa_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Not just dining out, Indian food is popular as a takeaway option too across Poland. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>