<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 04:10:08 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[26-Year-Old Man Arrested Over UnitedHealthcare CEO's Murder: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 02:14:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 26-year-old man was arrested Monday after the targeted killing of a top health insurance executive on the streets of New York, police said, crediting a McDonald's employee in Pennsylvania who spotted a suspicious-looking customer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>A 26-year-old man was arrested Monday after the targeted killing of a top health insurance executive on the streets of New York, police said, crediting a McDonald's employee in Pennsylvania who spotted a suspicious-looking customer.</p>

<p>Investigators were interrogating the man, Luigi Mangione, in connection with last week's killing of a senior figure at UnitedHealthcare, New York Police Commissioner Jessica Tisch said.</p>

<p>He is being held by officers in Altoona, Pennsylvania, after being found with a weapon that New York Chief of Detectives Joseph Kenny described as a "ghost gun" capable of firing 9MM rounds and equipped with a suppressor.</p>

<p>The man was spotted in a McDonald's in the town some 300 miles (500 kilometers) west of New York, by someone who tipped off the authorities, Jessica Tisch added.</p>

<p>He also had fake IDs similar to those used by the killer ahead of the slaying as well as a handwritten manifesto about the ills of the insurance industry, The New York Times said, citing a law enforcement source.</p>

<p>New York detectives were headed to Altoona, Tisch said, while Chief of Detectives Kenny said that Mangione possessed material that suggested he had "ill-will towards corporate America."</p>

<p>Police had been looking into the possibility that the shooter used a long-barrel veterinary gun -- normally used to euthanize animals -- to commit the murder.</p>

<p>The gunman walked up behind Brian Thompson, the senior executive at UnitedHealthcare -- one of the country's largest medical insurers -- and shot him dead last Wednesday in front of bystanders, in an attack captured by a surveillance camera and since seen by millions.</p>

<p>Brian Thompson was attending an investor conference in the Midtown business district.</p>

<p><strong>Ample video footage</strong></p>

<p>Detectives said the suspect fled the crime scene on foot, before riding a bike to Central Park, and later boarding a bus from a terminal in the north of the city connecting New York to surrounding states and beyond.</p>

<p>Police would not confirm media reports that the words "delay" and "deny" -- language often used by insurance companies to reject claims -- were written on shell casings found at the scene.</p>

<p>Video footage shows Thompson on the sidewalk outside the New York Hilton Midtown when a man in a hooded top, his lower face covered, approaches from behind, then fires several shots at his 50-year-old victim, who crumples to the ground.</p>

<p>An image released of the smiling suspect was obtained from a youth hostel where the gunman apparently stayed before the hit, with media reporting he had lowered his mask to flirt with a receptionist.</p>

<p>Authorities subsequently located a gray backpack in Central Park thought to belong to the killer containing a jacket and Monopoly money, US media reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/af1b0ago_new-york-police-generic_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Accused also had fake IDs similar to those used by the killer, say police (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-will-attack-us-again-if-we-end-war-now-says-israeli-pm-netanyahu-7211534]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Will Attack Us Again If We End War Now, Says Israeli PM Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-will-attack-us-again-if-we-end-war-now-says-israeli-pm-netanyahu-7211534]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 02:05:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday he would not stop the war in Gaza "now", with renewed efforts towards a ceasefire underway.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday he would not stop the war in Gaza "now", with renewed efforts towards a ceasefire underway.</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference in Jerusalem 14 months into the war against Hamas Palestinian operatives, he said "if we end the war now, Hamas will return, recover, rebuild and attack us again -- and that is what we do not want to go back to".</p>

<p>Netanyahu reiterated that he had set the goal of "the annihilation of Hamas, the elimination of its military and administrative capabilities" to prevent future attacks but said that the objective was not yet complete.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on October 23 that Israel had "managed to dismantle Hamas's military capacity" and eliminated its senior leadership. With those successes, he said, it was time to "get the hostages home and bring the war to an end with an understanding of what will follow."</p>

<p>In recent days, there had been signs that months of failed ceasefire and hostage release negotiations might be revived and achieve a breakthrough.</p>

<p>Qatar, a main mediator, said on Saturday there was new "momentum" for negotiations created by the election of Donald Trump in the United States.</p>

<p>A source close to the Hamas delegation said at the same time that Turkey as well as Egypt and Qatar had been "making commendable efforts to stop the war," and a new round of talks could begin soon.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the prime minister met with the families of hostages held in Gaza and said that Israel's wars on Hezbollah and Hamas would facilitate negotiations for their release.</p>

<p>Protesters, including relatives of the hostages, have repeatedly called for a deal to free the captives and accused him of prolonging the war.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza was sparked by Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack which resulted in the deaths of 1,208 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official data.</p>

<p>During the attack, operatives also kidnapped 251 hostages, 96 of whom remain in Gaza, including 34 who the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 44,758 people, mostly civilians, according to data from the Hamas-run health ministry that is considered reliable by the UN.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c803ouj8_netanyahu-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 44,758 people, says Hamas (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-says-occupied-golan-heights-will-remain-israeli-for-eternity-7211486]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli PM Says Occupied Golan Heights Will Remain Israeli "For Eternity"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-says-occupied-golan-heights-will-remain-israeli-for-eternity-7211486]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 01:58:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that the Golan Heights, occupied by Israel for almost 60 years, would remain Israeli "for eternity".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that the Golan Heights, occupied by Israel for almost 60 years, would remain Israeli "for eternity".</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference in Jerusalem,Benjamin Netanyahu thanked US President-elect Donald Trump for recognising Israel's 1981 annexation of the territory during his first term and said "the Golan will be part of the State of Israel for eternity"</p>

<p>.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdpp60fk_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Golan Heights has been occupied by Israel for almost 60 years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/penguins-of-antarctica-will-sail-to-india-on-special-postcards-7211370]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Post Unveils Postcards Featuring Penguins From Antarctica]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/penguins-of-antarctica-will-sail-to-india-on-special-postcards-7211370]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 01:17:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a unique initiative, the India Post, Maharashtra & Goa Circle, have arranged for a huddle of Penguins - the most recognisable original inhabitants of the Antarctic continent - to sail to India on a set of special postcards, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a unique initiative, the India Post, Maharashtra &amp; Goa Circle, have arranged for a huddle of Penguins - the most recognisable original inhabitants of the Antarctic continent - to sail to India on a set of special postcards, officials said here on Monday.</p>

<p>The flightless birds with flippers - the only aquatic variety that live and breed on ice - are considered the symbol of the frozen, 14.2 million sq. km of landmass surrounding the South Pole.</p>

<p>The India Post colour picture cards depict at least three of the 18 breeds that roam Antarctica - the majestic 'Emperor Penguin', the regal 'King Penguin' and the cut but much smaller 'Adelie'.</p>

<p>Union Ministry of Communications Secretary (Posts), Vandita Kaul, released the Penguin postcards in the presence of Chief Postmaster General Amitabh Singh, PMGs Suchita Joshi (Mumbai) and R. K. Jayabhaye (Pune), top officers, staffers and philatelists at the General Post Office Mumbai, today.</p>

<p>"These postcards, 250 of each picture, or totalling 1,500, shall be taken by the 44th Antarctica Expedition, organized by the National Centre for Polar and Ocean Research (NCPOR), scheduled to sail from Goa around Dec. 13," Assistant Post Master General Sudhir Jakhere told IANS.</p>

<p>NCPOR Scientist Ravi Mishra, leading the 44th Antarctica Expedition, will also be the designated special Postman this year and will bring back the coveted post-cards consignment on the return journey sometime late next year.</p>

<p>Depending on the voyage and weather en route, it is expected to reach Antarctica the Indian stations there, Dakshin Gangotri (the first one established in 1983, defunct since1990), followed by Maitri (instituted in 1990), and Bharati (set up in 2015).</p>

<p>The same expedition will bring them back after getting stamped there, with a legend: 'Bharati Branch Office' and 'Maitri Branch Office', both under NIO, Dona Paula, Goa, with a common PIN Code - 403004, said Jakhere.</p>

<p>The postal stamp symbolises India's sovereign dominance in those regions, the articles get a special postmark stamped there and these would be brought back to India, he explained.</p>

<p>Bharati Branch and Maitri Branch sharing the same PIN Code are the only two overseas post offices of India, and also have strategic importance, Jakhere added.</p>

<p>Besides India, more than 30 countries like China, the U.S., Russia, France, the U.K., Argentina, Brazil, Japan, Australia and others have permanent/temporary research bases there.</p>

<p>This is 125 years after the first base came up there during the Southern Cross Expedition (1899) - 12 years before the South Pole was conquered by a Norwegian explorer, Ronald Amundsen on December 14, 1911.</p>

<p>Incidentally, just three weeks later, Britisher Robert F. Scott also reached the South Pole but died during a severe blizzard that lashed the region on his return journey.</p>

<p>Jakhere said that the IndiaPosts started the tradition of special postcards in 2020, with the earlier annual themes being: Antarctica flora-fauna, Icebergs, Aura of Aurora, the Bharati Station, and now the Penguins.</p>

<p>Kaul released a permanent pictorial cancellation of 'Strawberry at Mahabaleshwar Post Office, Pune', commemoration the Geographical Indication (GI) tag for the state's favourite winter fruit, a slogan cancellation with a mascot and tagline of "Collect, Connect, Celebrate', the Festival of Stamps" for Mahapex-2025, on Jan. 22-25 next year, and reviewed the progress on the facelift going on for the GPO Heritage Building.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tqasl3ug_penguin-ians_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The colour picture cards depict at least 3 of 18 breeds that roam Antarctica (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-detain-man-in-connection-with-unitedhealth-ceos-murder-reports-7211128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Police Detain Man In Connection With UnitedHealth CEO's Murder: Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-detain-man-in-connection-with-unitedhealth-ceos-murder-reports-7211128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities on Monday detained a man in central Pennsylvania in connection with last week's murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson after finding him in possession of a gun, a silencer and false identification cards similar the killer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities on Monday detained a man in central Pennsylvania in connection with last week's murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson after finding him in possession of a gun, a silencer and false identification cards similar to those used by the killer, several media outlets reported.</p>

<p>Investigators received a tip about the man after he was spotted at a McDonald's in Altoona by someone who thought he looked like the suspected killer, CNN reported, citing unnamed officials.</p>

<p>The man being questioned had a handwritten "manifesto" criticizing healthcare companies for prioritizing profits over care, the New York Times reported, citing a law enforcement official.</p>

<p>One of the false cards found on the man also matched the ID used by the suspect to check into a hostel in Manhattan before the shooting, the Times reported.</p>

<p>The man has been arrested on local charges, possibly in connection with presenting a false ID to police, and New York detectives are headed to Altoona, according to the Times.</p>

<p>Neither the New York City Police Department nor the Altoona Police Department responded to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Thompson, 50, was gunned down outside a Manhattan hotel early on Wednesday morning by a masked man who appeared to wait for his arrival before shooting the executive from behind.</p>

<p>Police have not publicly identified a motive but have said Thompson appeared to be deliberately targeted.</p>

<p>The words "deny," "defend" and "depose" were carved into shell casings found at the scene, several news outlets have reported. The words evoke the title of a book critical of the insurance industry published in 2010 titled "Delay, Deny, Defend: Why Insurance Companies Don't Pay Claims and What You Can Do About It."</p>

<p>The suspect, who has not been identified by police, ran from the scene and then rode a bike into Central Park. Surveillance video captured him exiting the park and taking a taxi to a bus station in northern Manhattan, where police believe he used a bus to flee the city.</p>

<p>Thompson, a father of two, had been CEO of UnitedHealth Group's insurance unit since April 2021, part of a 20-year career with the company. He had been in New York to attend the company's annual investor conference.</p>

<p>A UnitedHealth spokesperson declined to comment on the latest reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/scn21b3o_unitedhealthcare-ceo-killer_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One of the false cards found on the man also matched the ID used by the suspect. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-syrian-leader-bashar-al-assads-father-in-law-7211085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sanctions Syrian Leader Bashar Al Assad's Father-In-Law]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-syrian-leader-bashar-al-assads-father-in-law-7211085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:56:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US unveiled sanctions Monday against Bashar al-Assad's father-in-law, a day after the former Syrian president reportedly fled to Russia as rebels took over the capital Damascus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US unveiled sanctions Monday against Bashar al-Assad's father-in-law, a day after the former Syrian president reportedly fled to Russia as rebels took over the capital Damascus.</p>

<p>Assad's abrupt departure brought to a spectacular end five decades of brutal rule by his clan over a country ravaged by one of the deadliest wars of the century.</p>

<p>He oversaw a crackdown on a pro-democracy movement that erupted in 2011, sparking a civil war that killed 500,000 people and forced half the country to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The Treasury Department announced in a statement that Fawaz al-Akhras was being designated for providing "support and facilitation to Bashar al-Assad related to financial matters, sanctions evasion and attempts by Bashar al-Assad to achieve international political engagement."</p>

<p>Akhras was born in the Syrian city of Homs in September 1946, and is a dual Syrian and UK national, according to the Treasury's list of sanctioned individuals.</p>

<p>He trained as a cardiologist, and practised medicine in London, where his daughter Asma -- who is married to the toppled former president -- was born.</p>

<p>Akhras, whose registered address is an unassuming house in west London, was previously sanctioned by the US in 2020 along with Asma, his wife Sahar, and several other family members.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/osuo314g_fawaz-alakhras_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fawaz al-Akhras was being designated for providing "support and facilitation to Bashar al-Assad. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-study-suggest-extreme-heat-greater-risk-for-young-people-7211014]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexico Study Suggest Extreme Heat Greater Risk For Young People]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-study-suggest-extreme-heat-greater-risk-for-young-people-7211014]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:46:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Extreme heat poses a greater risk to younger populations than the elderly, according to a new analysis which revealed that 75 per cent of heat-related deaths in Mexico from 1998-2019 occurred among those aged under 35 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Extreme heat poses a greater risk to younger populations than the elderly, according to a new analysis which revealed that 75 per cent of heat-related deaths in Mexico from 1998-2019 occurred among those aged under 35 years.</p>

<p>Researchers, including those from Columbia University, US, said the findings challenge the conventional belief that the elderly population are especially vulnerable to extreme heat on its head.</p>

<p>"It's a surprise. The young are physiologically the most robust people in the population. I would love to know why this is so," co-author Jeffrey Shrader of the Center for Environmental Economics and Policy, Columbia University's Climate School, said.</p>

<p>Published in the journal Science Advances, the team analysed excess deaths -- the number of deaths more or less than the average -- with 'wet-bulb' temperatures, a metric that combines heat and humidity or humid-heat to measure their intensified effects.</p>

<p>They found that over the two decades, the country suffered about 3,300 deaths a year related to heat, with nearly a third occurring in people aged 18-35 years. Children aged under five years, especially infants, too were found to be highly vulnerable.</p>

<p>However, people aged 50 years and above, usually considered at high risk in a warmer future, suffered the least levels of heat-related death. Instead, people in the age group died predominantly from modest cold, the team found.</p>

<p>They explained that while Mexico is mainly tropical and subtropical, there are many climate zones, including high-elevation areas, that can get relatively chilly.</p>

<p>The authors said, younger people are predominantly vulnerable to heat, with 35 years old accounting for 75 per cent of recent heat-related deaths and 87 per cent of heat-related lost life years.</p>

<p>Those 50 and older account for 96 per cent of cold-related deaths and 80 per cent of cold-related lost life years, the authors wrote.</p>

<p>According to researchers several factors are at work, for instance young adults are more likely to be engaged in outdoor labour, such as farming and construction activities, and thus could be more exposed to dehydration and heat stroke.</p>

<p>The same could go for indoor manufacturing in spaces lacking air conditioning, they said.</p>

<p>"These are the more junior people, low on the totem pole, who probably do the lion's share of hard work, with inflexible work arrangements," Shrader said.</p>

<p>Young adults are also more likely to participate in strenuous outdoor sports, the researchers said.</p>

<p>They cited a previous study by Mexican researchers which has shown that death certificates of working-age men were more likely to list extreme weather as a cause than those of other groups.</p>

<p>"We project, as the climate warms, heat-related deaths are going to go up, and the young will suffer the most," co-lead author, R. Daniel Bressler, a PhD candidate at Columbia University's Sustainable Development program, said.</p>

<p>Mexico was chosen for the analysis as the country collects highly granular geographical data on both mortality and daily temperatures, the team said.</p>

<p>They added that despite attention given to global warming and its dangers, extensive research has revealed that cold, not heat, is currently the world's number one cause of temperature-related mortality, including in Mexico.</p>

<p>However, heat-related deaths have been climbing in proportion since at least 2000, a trend that is expected to continue, the authors said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/q6mas5ug_heat-generic_625x300_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The authors said, younger people are predominantly vulnerable to heat. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-fall-an-opportunity-to-rid-syria-of-chemical-weapons-7210946]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Assad's Fall An Opportunity To Rid Syria Of Chemical Weapons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-fall-an-opportunity-to-rid-syria-of-chemical-weapons-7210946]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:32:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The downfall of Syria's Bashar al-Assad, found to have used chemical weapons against his own people on multiple occasions during the civil war, creates an opportunity to rid the country of banned munitions, diplomatic sources said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The downfall of Syria's Bashar al-Assad, found to have used chemical weapons against his own people on multiple occasions during the civil war, creates an opportunity to rid the country of banned munitions, diplomatic sources said on Monday.</p>

<p>The Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW) said it was following the situation in Syria with "special attention" to chemical weapons-related sites and had reminded Syria, through its embassy, of its continued obligation to declare and destroy all banned chemical weapons.</p>

<p>A team at OPCW has spent more than a decade trying to clarify what types of chemical weapons Syria still possesses, but has made little progress due to obstruction by Assad's government, it said.</p>

<p>"To date, this work has continued, and the Syrian declaration of its chemical weapons programme still cannot be considered as accurate and complete," the OPCW statement said.</p>

<p>A diplomatic source said Assad's government had been "playing cat and mouse with us for years" and that "we are convinced that they still had an ongoing programme."</p>

<p>"It costs millions and millions of dollars without making any progress," said the source, speaking on condition of anonymity. "So it really is a great opportunity now to get rid of (chemical weapons) for good. This is the moment."</p>

<p>Security guarantees will need to be arranged before any deployment by OPCW inspectors. That would require contacting new power brokers in Syria, possibly rebel forces in the alliance that toppled Assad, such as Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, a former al Qaeda affiliate labelled a terrorist group by some governments.</p>

<p>Past missions have not been free of risk. Members of a United Nations-OPCW mission to Syria were hit by explosives and AK-47 fire while trying to reach the site of a chemical attack in the northern town of Kafr Zita in May 2014.</p>

<p>Assad's government and its Russian allies always denied using chemical weapons against opponents in the civil war, which erupted in March 2011.</p>

<p>Three different investigations - a joint UN-OPCW mechanism, the OPCW's Investigation and Identification team, and a UN war crimes investigation - concluded that Syrian government forces used the nerve agent sarin and chlorine barrel bombs in attacks during the civil war that killed or injured thousands.</p>

<p>A French court issued an arrest warrant for Assad which was upheld on appeal over the use of banned chemical weapons against civilians.</p>

<p><strong>EVIDENCE</strong></p>

<p>Syria declared 1,300 tons of banned chemical weapons after joining the OPCW in 2013. The weapons were destroyed by the international community, but weapons inspectors have since found evidence of an ongoing programme that violated the 1997 Chemical Weapons Convention overseen by the OPCW.</p>

<p>The OPCW has conducted 28 rounds of consultations with Assad's government since 2013, but a list of unexplained inconsistencies has only grown.</p>

<p>A recent assessment said 19 outstanding issues included "potentially undeclared full-scale development and production of chemical weapons at two declared chemical weapons-related facilities," OPCW chief Fernando Arias said in November.</p>

<p>"The facilities were previously declared as having never been in operation," he said. But inspectors found evidence contradicting that claim, sources said.</p>

<p>Among thousands of victims of suspected chemical weapons attack were more than 1,000 killed in a sarin gas attack on Aug. 21, 2013 in the Damascus suburb Ghouta, and around 100 killed in an April 4, 2017 gas attack on the Khan Sheikhoun in northern Syria. The systematic use of chlorine barrel bombs has killed and injured hundreds more, the OPCW has found.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/jr7baoio_organisation-for-the-prohibition-of-chemical-weapons_625x300_08_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The OPCW has conducted 28 rounds of consultations with Assad's government since 2013. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ins-tushil-russia-ukraine-come-together-despite-war-to-deliver-navy-ship-to-india-7210940]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's Russia-Made Warship Comes With Ukrainian Engines. How It Happened]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ins-tushil-russia-ukraine-come-together-despite-war-to-deliver-navy-ship-to-india-7210940]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:31:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite the years-long war between Russia and Ukraine, Moscow and Kiev worked separately for a common cause - to manufacture an Indian Navy warship, which was handed over to New Delhi on Monday when Defence Minister Rajnath Singh arrived in Moscow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite the years-long war between Russia and Ukraine, Moscow and Kiev worked separately for a common cause - to manufacture an Indian Navy warship, which was handed over to New Delhi on Monday when Defence Minister Rajnath Singh arrived in Moscow for a top-level visit.</p>

<p>The frigate - INS Tushil - is one of two naval ships for which India placed an order with Russia in 2016. It is a Krivak III-class warship, which is an advanced stealth missile frigate. India currently operates six such warships - all manufactured in Russia.</p>

<p>Besides the two that is being made in Russia, two more similar ships have been ordered to be manufactured in India and will likely be manufactured at the Goa Shipyard.</p>

<p>What is interesting is that the primary engines - the gas turbines of these frigates - is manufactured in Ukraine. A Russian warship with a Ukrainian engine, made for India - which shares close ties with both countries.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/u4eqkrd8_ins-tushil-ceremony_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A majority of the ships in the Indian navy fleet use gas turbines made by the Ukrainian company Zorya-Mashproekt - which is a recognised globally as a leader in marine gas turbine production.</p>

<p>What is unique however, is that this order has been delivered while the war is on between Russia and Ukraine, and it is significant to note that both countries have delivered the order in spite of the conflict. However, there was a bit of a challenge involved - India had to physically procure these engines from Ukraine and have them delivered to Russia before they could be installed on this warship, so it has been somewhat delayed.</p>

<h2><strong>ALL ABOUT THE INS TUSHIL</strong></h2>

<p>INS Tushil is the Indian Navy's latest multi-role, stealth-guided missile frigate. The name 'Tushil' means a 'protector shield' and its crest represents the 'Abhedya Kavacham' (Impenetrable Shield). It has a motto - 'Nirbhay, Abhedya aur Balsheel' (Fearless, Indomitable, and Resolute). The ship stands as a symbol of the Indian Navy's undying commitment to safeguarding the nation's maritime frontiers.</p>

<p>The INS Tushil is an advanced Russian Krivak III-class warship under 'Project 11356'.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/bpnt3vr8_ins-tushil_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Project 11356 is the code name for the Talwar-class frigates, which are a class of stealth, guided-missile frigates designed and built by Russia for the Indian Navy. The design for the Talwar Class frigates have been developed as an advanced version of the Admiral Grigorovich-class frigates that Russia uses. So far, six such ships have been built and delivered by Russia to India between 1999 and 2013.</p>

<p>The six Krivak class warships that are already in service are 3 Talwar Class ships built at Baltiysky shipyard in St. Petersburg, and three Teg Class ships constructed at the Yantar shipyard in Kaliningrad.</p>

<p>'INS Tushil' will be the seventh in the series, and the first of the two upgraded, advanced warships for which the Indian government and the Indian Navy had signed a contract with Russia's JSC Rosoboronexport, in October 2016.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hp6vc2b_ins-tushil_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The construction of the 125-metre-long warship, weighing 3,900 tonnes, was under constant monitoring by experts of India's Warship Overseeing Team stationed permanently in Russia's Kaliningrad throughout its construction. The warship is fitted with advanced Indian missiles, details of which are not revealed by the Indian Navy.</p>

<p>The warship has undergone a series of sea trials, factory sea trials, and state committee trials starting January 2024, during which it clocked an impressive speed of more than 30 knots (55 kmph). It is now being delivered to India in a combat-ready condition.</p>

<p>Russia is delivering the warship to India at Kaliningrad on Monday, and Defence Minister Rajnath Singh along with Indian Navy Chief Admiral Dinesh K Tripathi will be commissioning it.</p>

<p>Upon commissioning, INS Tushil will join the 'Sword Arm' of the Indian Navy, the Western Fleet, under the Western Naval Command.</p>

<h2><strong>THE CHINA CHALLENGE</strong></h2>

<p>While the first of the two warships have been delivered on Monday, the delivery date for the second ship might take a while. The warship is an important addition to the Indian Navy which is faced with the challenge of the fast-growing Chinese Navy in the Indian Ocean.</p>

<p>The Chinese Navy is the fastest-growing navy in the world, and according to some reports the Chinese Navy might have already outnumbered the US Navy to become the largest naval fleet globally. Nowhere is this felt more significantly that the Indian Ocean.</p>

<p>While India has the geographical advantage over China in the Indian Ocean and its strategic location close to key choke points leading to it, China has the advantage in terms of number of vessels in the naval fleet.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/bpnt3vr8_ins-tushil_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[INS Tushil will join 'Sword Arm' of Indian Navy, the Western Fleet, under Western Naval Command.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-indian-student-anoushka-kale-elected-president-of-historic-cambridge-union-7210898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[British Indian Student Elected President Of Historic Cambridge Union]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-indian-student-anoushka-kale-elected-president-of-historic-cambridge-union-7210898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:27:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A British Indian student, Anoushka Kale, has been elected president of the University of Cambridge's historic Cambridge Union Society, among the world's oldest debating societies which prides itself as a defender of free speech since 1815.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British Indian student has been elected president of the University of Cambridge's historic Cambridge Union Society, among the world's oldest debating societies which prides itself as a defender of free speech since 1815.</p>

<p>Anoushka Kale won 126 votes to be elected uncontested for the next Easter 2025 term in an election held recently. As the serving debate officer of the society, Ms Kale ran on a platform of strengthening ties with cultural societies of the university such as the India Society.</p>

<p>"I am absolutely delighted and honoured to have been elected as President of the Cambridge Union Society for Easter 2025 and grateful for the membership's support," said Ms Kale.</p>

<p>"For my term, I will seek to expand diversity and access at the Union through greater collaboration with cultural groups, like the university's India Society. I am also especially passionate about continuing to host international speakers and global debate motions, as I did as Debates Officer of the society," she said.</p>

<p>Former presidents and officers of the Cambridge Union Society have included celebrated English economist and philosopher John Maynard Keynes, novelist Robert Harris and, in recent years, British Indian peer and founder of Cobra Beer Karan Bilimoria.</p>

<p>Like the Oxford University's Oxford Union Society, the Cambridge Union has a long tradition of hosting prominent figures from all areas of public life in its chamber, from US presidents Theodore Roosevelt and Ronald Reagan and UK Prime Ministers Winston Churchill, Margaret Thatcher and John Major, to Stephen Hawking, Bill Gates and the Dalai Lama.</p>

<p>Anoushka Kale, a 20-year-old student who is reading English Literature at Sidney Sussex College at Cambridge University, is among the few South Asian heritage female members to take on the prestigious role.</p>

<p>"I'm looking forward to delivering on my manifesto promises, particularly on expanding diversity through society collaborations and reduced access tickets for the summer garden party," she added.</p>

<p>It follows the Cambridge Union's decision to increase prices amid financial pressures and increasing "upkeep costs" of its Grade-II listed heritage building.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r93okv78_anoushka-kale_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cambridge Union has a tradition of hosting prominent figures from all areas of public life.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-president-banned-from-leaving-country-7210873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korean President Banned From Leaving Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-president-banned-from-leaving-country-7210873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:22:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol was banned Monday from travelling abroad, the justice ministry said, less than a week after he plunged the country into chaos by briefly imposing martial law.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol was banned Monday from travelling abroad, the justice ministry said, less than a week after he plunged the country into chaos by briefly imposing martial law.</p>

<p>Yoon sent special forces and helicopters to parliament on the night of December 3 before lawmakers forced him to rescind the order by rejecting his decree.</p>

<p>The unpopular leader narrowly survived an impeachment motion in parliament on Saturday even as huge crowds braved freezing temperatures to call for his ouster.</p>

<p>Despite remaining in office, a clutch of investigations has been closing in on Yoon and his close allies, including a probe for alleged insurrection.</p>

<p>The ministry of justice confirmed on Monday that Yoon had become the first sitting South Korean president to be banned from leaving the country.</p>

<p>A lawmaker was asked at a parliamentary hearing on Monday whether Yoon had been banned from leaving the country. "Yes, that's right," Bae Sang-up, an immigration services commissioner at the ministry, replied.</p>

<p>Also under travel bans for their roles in last week's events are former defence minister Kim Yong-hyun -- currently in detention -- and ex-interior minister Lee Sang-min.</p>

<p>General Park An-su, the officer in charge of the martial law operation, and defence counterintelligence commander Yeo In-hyung are also barred from leaving the country.</p>

<p>Investigators hauled Park in for further questioning on Monday, and Yonhap news agency reported late Monday that prosecutors had asked for a warrant for Kim's formal arrest.</p>

<p><strong>'Second coup'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The impeachment push failed to pass after members of Yoon's own People Power Party (PPP) walked out of parliament, depriving it of the necessary two-thirds majority.</p>

<p>The PPP says that in exchange, the 63-year-old Yoon has agreed to hand power to the prime minister and party chief, prompting howls of protest from the opposition.</p>

<p>"This is an unlawful, unconstitutional act of a second insurrection and a second coup," Democratic Party floor leader Park Chan-dae said on Monday.</p>

<p>Under South Korea's constitution, the president remains head of government and commander in chief of the army unless he or she is incapacitated, resigns or steps down.</p>

<p>In such a case, power would then be handed to the prime minister on an interim basis until elections could be held.</p>

<p>Claiming that Yoon can remain in office but has delegated his powers to the prime minister and leader of his ruling PPP -- who is not an elected official -- is "a blatant constitutional violation with no legal basis", Park said.</p>

<p>"Their attitude of placing themselves above the constitution mirrors that of insurrectionist Yoon Suk Yeol," he said.</p>

<p><strong>Power vacuum?</strong></p>

<p>The defence ministry confirmed on Monday that the embattled Yoon remained at the head of the country's security apparatus, despite the apparent power vacuum in a country that remains technically at war with nuclear-armed North Korea.</p>

<p>"Legally, (control of military forces) currently lies with the commander in chief," defence ministry spokesperson Jeon Ha-kyou said.</p>

<p>Yoon has apologised for "anxiety and inconvenience" caused by his declaration of martial law but has not stepped down, saying instead he would entrust decisions about his fate to his party.</p>

<p>He also said he would accept all political and legal responsibility for the martial law fiasco.</p>

<p>There is no constitutional basis supporting the ruling party's claim that Yoon can stay in office but hand over his power to unelected party officials, said Kim Hae-won, a constitutional law professor at Pusan National University Law School.</p>

<p>"It seems to resemble an unconstitutional soft coup," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"If there are issues with the president, there are ways laid out in the constitution such as suspending the president from his duties, and then move on to proceedings set out in the constitution, such as impeachment," he said.</p>

<p>The opposition has already said they would try again to impeach Yoon, with leader Lee Jae-myung saying another vote would be held on Saturday.</p>

<p>Huge crowds are expected to gather again outside the National Assembly building.</p>

<p>Yoon's approval rating hit 11 percent, a historic low for the unpopular president, according to a new Gallup poll commissioned by local media.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rs525hi8_yoon-suk-yeol_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The unpopular leader narrowly survived an impeachment motion in parliament on Saturday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop16-report-warns-over-75-of-global-land-permanently-drier-7210830]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[COP16 Report Warns Over 75% Of Global Land "Permanently Drier"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop16-report-warns-over-75-of-global-land-permanently-drier-7210830]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:16:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Just over 75 percent of the world's land has been left "permanently drier" over the previous three decades, a UN-backed report coinciding with COP16 talks on desertification in Saudi Arabia said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just over 75 percent of the world's land has been left "permanently drier" over the previous three decades, a UN-backed report coinciding with COP16 talks on desertification in Saudi Arabia said on Monday.</p>

<p>Dry land now covers around 40 percent of the Earth's land mass, excluding Antarctica, the United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification (UNCCD) study found, cautioning the shift could affect up to five billion people by 2100.</p>

<p>"Some 77.6 percent of Earth's land experienced drier conditions during the three decades leading up to 2020 compared to the previous 30-year period," the report said.</p>

<p>It indicates an "existential threat" posed by the seemingly irreversible trends and showed that dry land -- regions where agriculture is difficult -- increased by 4.3 million square kilometres (1.7 million square miles) between 1990 and 2020, an area a third the size of India.</p>

<p>The warning comes during a 12-day meeting in Riyadh, which began last week, for the 16th session of the Conference of the Parties (COP16) under the UNCCD and seeks to protect and restore land and respond to drought amid ongoing climate change.</p>

<p>Aridity, a chronic shortage of water, now extends over 40.6 percent of the Earth's land mass, again excluding Antarctica, compared with 37.5 percent 30 years ago, the report warns.</p>

<p>It also cautions the areas most affected include the nations bordering the Mediterranean, southern Africa, southern Australia and certain regions of Asia and Latin America.</p>

<p>"Unlike droughts -- temporary periods of low rainfall -- aridity represents a permanent, unrelenting transformation," said Ibrahim Thiaw, UNCCD Executive Secretary.</p>

<p>"The drier climates now affecting vast lands across the globe will not return to how they were and this change is redefining life on Earth," he added.</p>

<p>The changes are largely attributed to global warming caused by greenhouse gas emissions, which alter rainfall and increase evaporation, the report said.</p>

<p>"For the first time, a UN scientific body is warning that burning fossil fuels is causing permanent drying across much of the world," lead UNCCD Chief Scientist Barron Orr said.</p>

<p>He added this could have "potentially catastrophic impacts affecting access to water that could push people and nature even closer to disastrous tipping points".</p>

<p>The effects of the chronic water shortages include soil degradation, ecosystem collapse, food insecurity and forced migration, according to the scientists.</p>

<p>Already, 2.3 billion people live in expanding dry areas, according to the report, with projections showing a "worst-case scenario" of five billion people living in the conditions as the planet continues to warm.</p>

<p>To counter this trend, the scientists urged members to "integrate aridity metrics into existing drought monitoring systems", improve soil and water management, and "build resilience in vulnerable communities".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pk9n5i9g_cop16_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The warning comes during a 12-day meeting in Riyadh. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-exit-shatters-irans-influence-but-risks-islamists-rise-in-syria-7210282]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Assad's Exit Shatters Iran's Influence But Risks Islamists' Rise In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-exit-shatters-irans-influence-but-risks-islamists-rise-in-syria-7210282]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 21:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ouster of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, after rebel forces swept into Damascus this weekend, shattered Iran's network of influence in the Middle East but Israel, the United States and Arab powers must now deal with the risk of instability.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ouster of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, after rebel forces swept into Damascus this weekend, shattered Iran's network of influence in the Middle East but Israel, the United States and Arab powers must now deal with the risk of instability and extremism from the mosaic of forces that replaces him.</p>

<p>Chief among the rebel forces that ended 50 years of brutal dynastic rule by Assad and his father was Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), a Sunni Muslim group previously affiliated with Al Qaeda that is designated as a terrorist organization by the US and the UN.</p>

<p>Western and Arab nations fear that the HTS-led rebel coalition may seek to replace Assad's regime with a hardline Islamist government, or one less able or inclined to prevent the resurgence of radical forces, three diplomats and three analysts told Reuters.</p>

<p>"There is strong fear inside and outside the region of the power vacuum that Assad's sudden collapse may cause," said Abdelaziz al-Sager, director of the Gulf Research Center, a think tank focused on the Middle East. He cited the civil wars that followed the toppling of Iraqi president Saddam Hussein in 2003 and Libyan dictator Muammar Gaddafi in 2011.</p>

<p>One senior Western diplomat in the region, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told Reuters that - with the rebel forces fragmented - there was no plan for how to rule Syria, a complex nation divided into various sects and ethnic groups, each with its own regional power base.</p>

<p>The senior diplomat expressed fears that lawlessness in Syria could allow the flourishing of extremist groups like Islamic State (IS), which in 2014 swept through large swathes of Syria and Iraq and established an Islamic Caliphate before it was driven out by a US-led coalition by 2019.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden on Sunday welcomed Assad's toppling and said he should be "held accountable" for his despotic rule but he warned that his departure was a moment of "risk and uncertainty". US forces on Sunday conducted dozens of strikes within Syria against IS to prevent it reasserting itself.</p>

<p>The speed of Assad's ouster, just two weeks since the rebel offensive began, took many in the White House by surprise. A senior US official said Washington was now seeking ways to communicate with all the rebel groups, not just HTS.</p>

<p>So far, Washington had mostly thrown its support behind Syrian Kurdish groups, such as the Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), whose areas of control are in northeast Syria. These groups, however, are in conflict with one of the main victorious rebels factions, the Syrian National Army (SNA), backed by regional power broker, Turkey, which opposes Kurdish influence.</p>

<p>Assad's allies, Tehran and Moscow, who propped up his rule for 13 years with military support, men and airpower, also face far-reaching implications from his precipitous downfall.</p>

<p>Moscow - which has given Assad and his family asylum - has two major military bases in Syria, its main footprint in the Middle East. Its naval base in Tartous on the Mediterranean has been a staging post to fly military contractors in and out of Africa.</p>

<p>For Tehran, its alliance with Assad - a member of the minority Alawite sect, an offshoot of Shi'ite Islam - was a cornerstone of its powerbase in a predominantly Sunni region wary of Shi'ite Iran.</p>

<p>Assad's departure shattered a pivotal axis of influence, eroding Tehran's ability to project power and sustain its network of militia groups across the Middle East, particularly to its ally Hezbollah in Lebanon. A senior Iranian official told Reuters on Monday it had opened a direct line of communication with the rebels in an attempt to "prevent a hostile trajectory".</p>

<p>Israel's year-long military campaign has already severely weakened the military power of Hezbollah and Palestinian group Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>Assad offered Iran a vital conduit for arms shipments to rebuild Hezbollah. Jonathan Panikoff, a former US deputy national intelligence officer for the Middle East, said his ouster could make it more difficult for Hezbollah to rearm, increasing the prospects that a ceasefire with Israel agreed last month would hold.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu hailed the ousting of Assad as an "historic day" that followed the blows delivered by Israel against Iran and Hezbollah. He said he had ordered Israeli forces to seize areas along the bordering buffer zone to ensure Israel's security.</p>

<p>Israeli forces carried out air strikes against suspected chemical weapons and missile sites on Monday to prevent them from falling into the hands of hostile actors, the foreign minister said.</p>

<p>Carmit Valensi, a senior researcher at the Institute for National Security Studies (INSS), a think tank for Israeli security policy based in Tel Aviv, said that - despite the risk of a prolonged period of chaos and violence in Syria - Assad's fall could benefit Israel.</p>

<p>"Despite concerns over the rise of extremist elements near the border and the lack of a clear authority in charge, the military capabilities of the rebels, in their various forms, aren't comparable to those of Iran and its proxies," she said.</p>

<p>CALLS FOR NEW CONSTITUTION, ELECTIONS</p>

<p>Marwan al-Muasher, vice president for studies at the US-based Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, said Assad's exit could provide an opportunity for Syrians to establish an inclusive political governance through an orderly transition that avoided a power vacuum that would allow extremist groups to gain ascendancy.</p>

<p>Hadi Al-Bahra, the head of Syria's main opposition abroad, told Reuters on the sidelines of the Doha Forum on Sunday that Syria should have an 18-month transition period to establish "a safe, neutral, and quiet environment" for free elections.</p>

<p>Al-Bahra, President of the Syrian National Coalition, said Syria should draft a constitution within six months, on which the first election would be a referendum. He said the opposition had asked state employees to report to work until the power transition, and assured them that they would not be harmed.</p>

<p>But Syria's political opposition has little influence on the ground in Damascus, where armed groups hold sway, and many Syria watchers remain skeptic.</p>

<p>HTS' leader, Abu Mohammed al-Golani, addressed huge crowds at the medieval Umayyad Mosque in central Damascus on Sunday, promising a new chapter for the region and that Syria would become "a beacon for the Islamic nation".</p>

<p>There are, however, questions about whether Golani's form of strict Islamist ideology would be accepted throughout Syria, a country where a moderate and liberal form of Islam prevails and with a mixed Christian, Alawite, Druze and Kurdish population.</p>

<p>Both Western and Middle Eastern officials expressed concern about the unity of Syria, with key territories, including those along borders with Iraq and Turkey, under the control of different sects and ethnic groups: these divisions, which were entrenched by a bloody 2011 uprising, present a growing threat to national stability.</p>

<p>The analysts and diplomats who spoke to Reuters warned of the risk of a free-for-all conflict - akin to the wake of the toppling of Gaddafi in Libya or Saddam in Iraq - in which armed groups from different Islamist, ethnic and ideological shades fight for supremacy over territory. Such a failed state in Syria would have a major impact on neighbors Lebanon, Turkey, Iraq and Jordan, they said.</p>

<p>RIVALRY AMONG REBELS</p>

<p>Syria's opposition comprises a broad spectrum from moderate groups such as the SNA to jihadi elements within the HTS, each with its own vision for Syria's future, ranging from secular democracy to Islamic governance.</p>

<p>"Each one of these rebel group is vying for supremacy; each one wants to be in charge. Each one thinks they can be Bashar al-Assad, and each one has allegiance to a foreign party funding his group," said al-Sager. "They will clash unless there is an effort by the UN and some regional countries with influence to unify them."</p>

<p>Turkish-backed forces dominate in the north, while US-aligned Kurdish groups, such as the Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), hold sway in northeastern Syria.</p>

<p>In a sign of the tensions between the groups, the Turkey-backed SNA seized swathes of territory, including the city of Tel Refaat, from US-backed Kurdish forces at the start of the recent offensive. On Sunday, a Turkish security source said the rebels entered the northern city of Manbij after pushing the Kurds back again.</p>

<p>Still, some analysts say that an orderly transition is possible, arguing that well-established government institutions in Damascus remain capable of carrying out duties.</p>

<p>They also point to the rebels' experience of governing in enclaves across Syria that they have managed in some cases for more than a decade. The rebel alliance, led by HTS, made a point of offering clemency for members of the security forces when it seized Aleppo, Syria's second-largest city, late last month and promised the sizeable minority populations that it would preserve their way of life.</p>

<p>But Hassan Hassan, an expert on Islamist groups in the Middle East based in Washington, said that concerns persisted among these minority groups now that the rebels had captured Damascus.</p>

<p>"There is uncertainty about what will happen next, particularly about religious influence and how (Islamic) laws may evolve," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hnlpk09g_bashar-al-assad_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Western and Arab nations fear that the HTS-led rebel coalition may seek to replace Assad's regime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fall-of-assad-breaks-key-link-in-irans-axis-of-resistance-7209638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fall Of Assad Breaks Key Link In Iran's "Axis Of Resistance"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fall-of-assad-breaks-key-link-in-irans-axis-of-resistance-7209638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 20:23:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fall of Syrian leader Bashar al-Assad shattered the key link in Iran's "axis of resistance", but Tehran will look for ways to adapt to the new reality, analysts say.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fall of Syrian leader Bashar al-Assad shattered the key link in Iran's "axis of resistance", but Tehran will look for ways to adapt to the new reality, analysts say.</p>

<p>After nearly 14 years of war in Syria, a lightning offensive launched by an Islamist-led rebel alliance brought Assad down.</p>

<p>The offensive began on November 27, just as a ceasefire took effect in the war between Iran's powerful proxy Hezbollah and Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had long used Syria as its key conduit for weapons and supplies from Iran.</p>

<p>With Assad gone, it is to be seen how Hezbollah will adapt, particularly after the staggering losses it suffered in its own recent war.</p>

<p><strong>'Frontline of resistance'</strong></p>

<p>In the past, Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who has the final say in his country's affairs, has said that "Syria is on the frontline of the resistance against Israel".</p>

<p>The axis of resistance, to use Tehran's term, comprises Iran itself and a smattering of proxy forces united by their opposition to Israel, including Lebanon's Hezbollah, Palestinian operator group Hamas and Yemen's Huthi rebels, as well as smaller groups in Iraq.</p>

<p>Until Sunday, Assad's government was a key component of the axis, and he would likely not have survived for as long as he did had it not been for Hezbollah and Iran's military backing.</p>

<p>But the fall of Assad on Sunday was a major blow to the loose alliance, and the latest in a string of setbacks for Iran in its fight against Israel.</p>

<p>In recent months Israel has killed Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar in Gaza and Hezbollah's secretary general Hassan Nasrallah in Lebanon, and decimated both groups' mid-level leadership.</p>

<p>Iran also blames Israel for the killing of former Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh in an attack in Tehran in July.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Islamic republic has lost hundreds of its Revolutionary Guards in Syria over more than a decade of the country's civil war, including in Israeli air strikes.</p>

<p><strong>'Destabilise'</strong></p>

<p>Within Iran, some believe the Syrian rebels' goal was to sever the link between Tehran and its allies.</p>

<p>With its influence now threatened in Syria, Iran "will no longer be able to support Hezbollah as it did before", Mehdi Zakerian, an expert on international relations in Tehran, told AFP.</p>

<p>In Tehran's official narrative, the revolt against Assad's rule was an American-Israeli plot to "destabilise" the Middle East and redraw its political map.</p>

<p>Syria's civil war was sparked by a crackdown on democracy protests inspired by the Arab Spring.</p>

<p>Iran sent to Syria what it presented as "military advisers" to support Assad's army, at his request.</p>

<p>Shiite Muslim militias close to Iran also deployed, allowing Tehran to gain influence in Syria, which borders not only Lebanon but also Israel.</p>

<p>After the fall of Damascus on Sunday, the Iranian embassy was ransacked, an act that would have been previously unimaginable.</p>

<p><strong>'He did not pay attention'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>And while Iran was a key backer of Assad, some official critiques of the former leader were emerging after his downfall.</p>

<p>"Bashar was an opportunity for Iran, but he did not pay enough attention to the recommendations of the Islamic Republic," Iranian news agency Fars said.</p>

<p>Following the rebels' declaration of victory, Iran's foreign ministry said its policy towards any new Syrian government would depend on "developments in Syria and the region, as well as the behaviour of the actors".</p>

<p>But the statement also said Iran expected to continue "friendly" relations with the country.</p>

<p>On Saturday, as rebels were swiftly advancing towards Damascus, Tehran had called on all sides in the conflict to engage in negotiations.</p>

<p>That statement by Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi was significant, not least because of its timing, and appeared to mark a change in tone.</p>

<p>Iran had long branded any form of opposition in Syria as "terrorism".</p>

<p>On Sunday, with that opposition now seemingly in charge, Araghchi said: "Syria played an important role in supporting the resistance, but it is not the case that the resistance will stop without Syria."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/o44h6kc8_bashar-al-assad_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran had long branded any form of opposition in Syria as "terrorism". (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-woman-stays-calm-without-phone-for-8-hours-in-unique-contest-wins-1-400-7209320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Unique Contest, China Woman Wins $1,400 For Ditching Phone For 8 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-woman-stays-calm-without-phone-for-8-hours-in-unique-contest-wins-1-400-7209320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:41:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The challenge was designed to highlight the growing dependence on technology and encourage people to embrace mindfulness and digital detox practices.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese woman,&nbsp;surnamed Dong, has made headlines for winning a unique competition where she abstained from using her mobile phone for eight hours without showing signs of anxiety.&nbsp;Dong, a sales manager at a finance firm, emerged victorious among ten contestants, taking home a prize of 10,000 yuan (approximately Rs 1,16,820),<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3289134/chinese-woman-wins-us1400-not-feeling-anxious-without-mobile-8-hours"> South China Morning Post </a></em>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The competition, sponsored by an undisclosed organization in Chongqing, southwestern China, required participants to surrender their electronic devices and adhere to strict rules while spending eight hours on a designated bed. The challenge was designed to highlight the growing dependence on technology and encourage people to embrace mindfulness and digital detox practices.</p>

<p>Contestants were allowed to leave their beds only for brief toilet breaks, limited to five minutes each. A quota was set for the total time spent away from their beds during the eight hours.&nbsp;Meals and drinks were provided, but participants had to consume them in bed. The rules also prohibited contestants from using their mobile phones, falling into a deep sleep, or exhibiting anxiety. To monitor their sleep quality and anxiety levels, contestants wore wrist straps throughout the competition. To pass the time, contestants were allowed to read books or rest with their eyes closed.</p>

<p>Dong reportedly managed this feat with ease, stating that she is accustomed to minimal phone usage in her daily life. She scored an impressive 88.99 out of 100, earning her a 10,000-yuan prize.&nbsp;Dong's strategy of wearing pyjamas and focusing on relaxation paid off, earning her the nickname "pyjama sister" on social media. Her everyday habits, which include tutoring her child instead of mindlessly browsing her phone, also contributed to her success.</p>

<p>The competition sparked widespread interest on Chinese social media, with many users expressing curiosity and amusement. One user wrote, "I want to join the competition. It seems so interesting and not challenging at all."</p>

<p>Another commented, "My grandma could win the top prize."</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/t0svc2m_china-woman_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[She scored an impressive 88.99 out of 100, earning her a 10,000-yuan prize]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-looking-back-at-2024-remembering-those-who-left-us-7209211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Pics: Looking Back At 2024 - Remembering Those Who Left Us]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-looking-back-at-2024-remembering-those-who-left-us-7209211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:29:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As we bid farewell to 2024 and recount the glories of the season, we remember there were tears too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we bid farewell to 2024 and recount the glories of the season, we remember there were tears too. The year was filled with wars and revolutions, trends and tragedies, with the world saying goodbye to some notable figures, including Russian President Vladimir Putin's staunchest critic Alexei Navalny, former One Direction member Liam Payne, famed producer Quincy Jones and industrialist Ratan Tata.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are some of the most famous people who have died in 2024.</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Glynis Johns | 5 October 1923 - 4 January 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: IMDB)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p45ear3o_glynis-johns-imdb_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: IMDB)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: IMDB)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A Tony Award-winning stage and screen star, Johns passed away at the age of 100. She is best remembered for playing the mother opposite Julie Andrews in the classic movie "Mary Poppins". She also introduced the world to the bittersweet standard-to-be "Send in the Clowns" by Stephen Sondheim.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Alexei Navalny | 4 June 1976 - 6 February 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@navalny)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/iuic3hp8_alexei-navalny-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: X/@navalny)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@navalny)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>One of the fiercest critics of Russian President Vladimir Putin, Navalny passed away in the Arctic penal colony where he was serving a 19-year sentence, Russia's prison agency said. He was 47. Before his arrest, Navalny campaigned against official corruption, organized major anti-Kremlin protests and ran for public office.</p>

<h3><strong>Jacob Rothschild | 29 April 1936 - 26 February 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Partners Capital website)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/a1a1a4p_jacob-rothschild-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: Partners Capital website)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Partners Capital website)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A financier and philanthropist, Rothschild passed away at the age of 87. He was part of the renowned Rothschild banking dynasty and began his career in the family bank, NM Rothschild &amp; Sons, in 1963. He later broke away to start businesses and charitable organizations.&nbsp;Rothschild was Chairman of RIT Capital Partners plc, one of the largest investment trusts quoted on the London Stock Exchange with a net asset value of about 2 billion. He played a prominent part in Arts philanthropy in Britain and was Chairman of Trustees of the National Gallery from 1985 to 1991, and from 1992 to 1998, chairman of the National Heritage Memorial Fund.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Peter Higgs | 29 May 1929 - 8 April 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@NobelPrize)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vf2geo8o_peter-higgs-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: X/@NobelPrize)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@NobelPrize)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>Nobel prize-winning physicist Peter Higgs died at age 94. Higgs is credited for proposing the existence of the so-called God particle that helped explain how matter formed after the Big Bang.&nbsp;Higgs predicted the existence of a new particle in 1964, which later came to be known as the Higgs boson. The physicist's work helped scientists in getting a better understanding of one of the most fundamental riddles of the universe: how the Big Bang created something out of nothing 13.8 billion years ago.</p>

<h3><strong>OJ Simpson | 9 July 1947 - 10 April 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/e9q1n84_oj-simpsons-afp_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: AFP)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A decorated football superstar and Hollywood actor, Simpson died aged 76. &nbsp;Simpson found fame and fortune through football and show business, but his legacy was forever changed by the June 1994 knife slayings of his ex-wife, Nicole Brown Simpson, and her friend Ronald Goldman in Los Angeles. His public trial captured America's attention and sparked debates on race, gender, domestic abuse, celebrity justice and police misconduct. &nbsp;He was acquitted in the murder case in 1995, but a separate civil trial jury found him liable in 1997 for the deaths and ordered him to pay $33.5 million to relatives of Brown and Goldman.</p>

<h3><strong>Ebrahim Raisi | 14 December 1960 - 19 May 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@raisi_com)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/08ritu8_ebrahim-raisi-_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: X/@raisi_com)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@raisi_com)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The Iranian president Raisi, a hard-line protege of the country's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Raisi died in a Helicopter crash aged 63. Raisi helped oversee the mass executions of thousands in Iran in 1988 and later led the country as it enriched uranium near weapons-grade levels, launched a major attack on Israel and experienced mass protests.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Maggie Smith | 28 December 1934 - 27 September 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Reuters)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ljvacj8g_maggie-smith-reuters_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: Reuters)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Reuters)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The masterful, scene-stealing actor, Smith won an Oscar for the 1969 film The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie. She gained new fans in the 21st century with her roles of dowager Countess of Grantham in "Downton Abbey" and Professor Minerva McGonagall in the Harry Potter films. Smith was often rated the preeminent British female performer of a generation along with Vanessa Redgrave and Judi Dench. The two-time Oscar winner died aged 89.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Quincy Jones | 14 March 1933 - &nbsp;3 November 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@DiscussingFilm)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ja7ck3a8_james-earl-jones-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: X/@DiscussingFilm)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@QuincyDJones)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A multi-talented music titan, Jones' vast legacy ranged from producing Michael Jackson's historic "Thriller" album to writing prize-winning film and television scores. He collaborated with icons Frank Sinatra, and Ray Charles among hundreds of other recording artists to make chart-breaking music and earn honours and awards that fill 18 pages in his 2001 autobiography Q". The 28-time Grammy winner and twice Academy Award awardee passed away aged 91.</p>

<h3><strong>Ratan Tata | 28 December 1937 - 9 October 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Tata.com)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/496pl1c_ratan-tata-tatacom_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: Tata.com)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Tata.com)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>One of India's most influential business leaders, Ratan Tata passed away aged 86. He joined the Tata Group in 1961 and succeeded his uncle J.R.D. Tata as chairman after the latter's retirement in 1991. Under his leadership, the company grew significantly to a sprawling collection of nearly 100 companies and expanded globally with revenue exceeding $100 billion on his retirement.</p>

<h3><strong>Liam Payne | 29 August 1993 - 16 October 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@LiamPayne)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6kse7kd8_liam-payne-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: X/@LiamPayne)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@LiamPayne)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The former One Direction singer whose chart-topping British boy band generated a global following of swooning fans, died aged 31 after falling from a hotel balcony in Argentina.</p>

<h3><strong>Rohit Bal | 8 May 1961 - 1 November 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Rohit Bal  Facebook)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/v2fom42g_rohit-bal-facebook_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: Rohit Bal  Facebook)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Rohit Bal Facebook)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>One of India's most celebrated fashion designers, Bal died aged 63 after a long period of illness. He popularised fashion designing as a viable, glamorous profession in the 1990s and many who came after him credit him for their success.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/lj2eud8g_year-ender-2024_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Peter Higgs , Liam Payne and Ebrahim Raisi died in 2024]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-voted-for-people-south-korean-mp-defies-party-to-impeach-president-7209125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Voted For People": South Korean MP Defies Party To Impeach President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-voted-for-people-south-korean-mp-defies-party-to-impeach-president-7209125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:14:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As South Korean lawmakers tried to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol for declaring martial law, ruling party MPs marched out of the chamber to thwart the effort -- except for Ahn Cheol-soo.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As South Korean lawmakers tried to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol for declaring martial law, ruling party MPs marched out of the chamber to thwart the effort -- except for Ahn Cheol-soo.</p>

<p>Ahn -- a self-made multi-millionaire, trained doctor and software designer -- sat alone in his party's bank of chairs in the National Assembly debating hall, one of just two members of the ruling People Power Party to vote to remove Yoon from office.</p>

<p>Despite tens of thousands of protesters outside, demanding the leader be removed after he sent soldiers in helicopters to parliament in a bid to overturn civilian rule, the impeachment motion failed by not meeting the quorum.</p>

<p>Days earlier, lawmakers from both parties had come together, jumping fences, barricading doors with office furniture, and battling special forces troops as they raced to vote down the martial law declaration.</p>

<p>But then the ruling party closed ranks -- saying Yoon had promised to resign and hand power to the prime minister and party chief, in what the opposition has called an unconstitutional power grab and "second coup".</p>

<p>Ahn said he was booed and heckled at a party meeting, when he tried to argue with other lawmakers that the president needed to be held to account.</p>

<p>"The idea that a president responsible for upholding the constitution of the world's 10th largest economy would stage an unconstitutional coup is beyond imagination," Ahn told AFP on Monday in his parliamentary office overlooking the National Assembly.</p>

<p>"Who could have foreseen he would commit such an unconstitutional act as president?"</p>

<p>Always unpopular, Yoon's approval rating has hit a record low of just 11 percent, a Gallup poll showed Monday, and further mass protests are expected this coming weekend, when the opposition will try again to impeach.</p>

<p>A "sense of duty" to uphold the constitutional order weighed heavily on him as he thought about how he should vote, Ahn told AFP.</p>

<p>"I have always believed that my role in politics is to represent the people's will, not my own personal interests. That is why I stayed to cast my vote."</p>

<p>"I didn't vote for the opposition party. I voted for the people"</p>

<p><strong>Presidential candidate&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Ahn himself had ambitions to be president: he ran in 2022, but dropped out and supported Yoon just a week before the election, with his support proving crucial in the neck-and-neck poll, which Yoon won by the narrowest margin in South Korean history.</p>

<p>His party merged with the PPP, but Ahn now finds himself at odds with his parliamentary colleagues, who are officially calling for an "orderly exit" for Yoon -- but in reality, experts say, trying to buy time ahead of an election they're likely to lose.</p>

<p>The PPP blocked impeachment, saying that Yoon had agreed to step down at some unspecified point in the future, with the country to be run by the prime minister and party chief in the interim.</p>

<p>But Ahn insists this is insufficient.</p>

<p>"I had expected Yoon to announce when and how he would resign and to detail plans for the formation of a joint governing body with ruling and opposition parties," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"Instead, he handed everything over to the ruling party," he said.</p>

<p>Without a clear roadmap from either the president or his party, "I concluded I had no choice but to support impeachment."</p>

<p>Ahn said he would vote for impeachment again.</p>

<p>"According to the constitution, each MP is a constitutional agent. Voting according to one's conscience, even if it goes against the party's official stance, takes precedence."</p>

<p>Yoon has lost the confidence of not only the South Korean public but also international allies, leaving him "incapable of continuing his duties as president," Ahn said.</p>

<p>"He must personally explain when and how he intends to resign."</p>

<p><strong>Household name&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Ahn is a household name in South Korea and was widely known even before entering politics in 2012 with his first presidential bid.</p>

<p>As a medical student in the 1980s, he wrote a programme to remove a virus from his computer and went on to pursue parallel careers as a software developer, doctor, and professor.</p>

<p>In 1995, he founded AhnLab, now the largest antivirus software company in South Korea, with a market capitalisation of nearly $635 million.</p>

<p>He has run as a presidential candidate multiple times, but it was his bid in 2022 that has proved most impactful.</p>

<p>Six days before the election, he endorsed Yoon -- a move analysts described as crucial to Yoon's razor-thin victory margin of less than one percentage point.</p>

<p>If he had known then what he knows now, Ahn said, he would not have done it.</p>

<p>"Not just me -- others would also have been unable to vote for him if we had known this information."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rgk9ntn_south-korea-mp_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A "sense of duty" to uphold the constitutional order weighed heavily, Ahn told AFP. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-the-mastermind-behind-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasina-7209051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus The "Mastermind" Behind Bangladesh Turmoil: Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-the-mastermind-behind-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasina-7209051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:04:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's former PM Sheikh Hasina has launched a fierce attack on the interim administration, accusing its Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus of running a "fascist regime" that allows terrorists and fundamentalists to act without restraint.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's former PM Sheikh Hasina has launched a fierce attack on the interim administration, accusing its Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus of running a "fascist regime" that allows terrorists and fundamentalists to act without restraint.</p>

<p>In a virtual address to a gathering of overseas Awami League supporters in London on Sunday, Ms Hasina accused Mr Yunus of being the "mastermind" behind the July-August turmoil that ousted her government and vowed to bring him and his allies to justice under Bangladeshi law.</p>

<p>She criticised Mr Yunus and his interim government for their alleged persecution of religious minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Since August 5, the attacks on minorities, places of worship of Hindus, Christians and Buddhists have been rampant. We condemn it. The Jamaat and terrorists are having a free run under the new regime," she said.</p>

<p>The audio recording of Hasina's address was shared on the Facebook page of the Bangladesh Students' League and Bangladesh Awami League.</p>

<p>Her remarks came as Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri is visiting to Dhaka today where he raised India's concerns over the safety of minorities, flagging "regrettable incidents of attacks on cultural, religious and diplomatic properties" in the country.</p>

<p>There have been a spate of incidents of violence against Hindus and other minorities, as well as attacks on temples in Bangladesh in the last few weeks that triggered strong concerns in New Delhi.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh is now under the grip of a fascist regime where people's democratic rights have been obliterated. Our government's achievements in poverty alleviation and infrastructure development, strengthening of democracy were being undone under Yunus's leadership," Ms Hasina said during her 37-minute virtual address over the phone.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina accused the Yunus government of providing clemency to terrorists and criminals, including those involved in arson and murders.</p>

<p>"The release of convicted criminals and terrorists, including those responsible for attacks on the Bangladesh Parliament and other atrocities, proves the complicity of this government," she alleged.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina vowed that those responsible for the alleged atrocities under the Yunus administration would be brought to justice.</p>

<p>"Md Yunus and his allies are the masterminds of the July-August unrest in the country. They are behind the killing of students and policemen, arson and atrocities. The murderers and conspirators who have harmed our nation will be held accountable under Bangladeshi law. Just as we took action against war criminals, justice will prevail for today's wrongdoers. No one will escape the law," she said.</p>

<p>On August 5, the student-led Monsoon Revolution under the banner of "Students Against Discrimination" succeeded in toppling Sheikh Hasina's 16-year regime, propelled by fervent demands for change and accountability.</p>

<p>After unprecedented anti-government protests, Ms Hasina resigned as Prime Minister and fled the country. She landed in India on August 5 and is currently staying here.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina criticised Mr Yunus and his government for their alleged persecution of religious minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Since August 5, the attacks on minorities, places of worship of Hindus, Christians and Buddhists have been rampant. We condemn it. The Jamaat and terrorists are having a free run under the new regime," she said.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina expressed outrage over the judicial and administrative repression under the current government, citing the case of Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das as an example.</p>

<p>"Chinmoy Krishna Das' lawyer was barred from contesting his case, a blatant violation of legal rights. This government is using every tool to suppress dissent and deny justice," she said.</p>

<p>Chinmay Krishna Das, a prominent spokesperson for Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote, was arrested at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday while en route to Chattogram for a rally. He was denied bail and remanded to jail on Tuesday. His arrest has further fueled concerns over the treatment of Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Condemning the ongoing oppression, Hasina declared, "This dark chapter of our nation's history will not last forever. Mohammed Yunus will be held accountable for his actions, and justice will prevail." Hasina further alleged that people are being subjected to brutal violence.</p>

<p>"Innocent people have been beaten to death under this fascist regime. The rule of law has been completely eroded," she said, calling for accountability and justice.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina claimed that the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has ignored allegations of financial irregularities involving Mr Yunus and his organization, Grameen Bank.</p>

<p>"They accuse my government of corruption but fail to provide evidence. Meanwhile, Yunus's activities remain unchecked by the ACC," she said, reiterating her challenge for the interim government to substantiate its allegations against her.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina claimed that since August, more than a thousand leaders and workers of the Awami League have been killed, their homes looted, and their businesses destroyed.</p>

<p>She claimed that members of her party were being systematically targeted and that these incidents were part of a broader conspiracy to eliminate the Awami League's influence.</p>

<p>"All units of the Awami League have been subjected to attacks. The homes and businesses of our leaders have been looted. Those who are reporting these atrocities face severe consequences under the current regime," she stated.</p>

<p>While concluding her virtual address, Ms Hasina expressed hope for a brighter future, assuring the people that "a new dawn will soon break, dispelling the darkness that has engulfed our country."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r5j153uk_sheikh-hasina-ians_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina slammed Muhammad Yunus's regime as "fascist", vows justice for atrocities]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-struck-chemical-weapons-in-syria-says-foreign-minister-7209002]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Struck "Chemical Weapons" In Syria, Says Foreign Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-struck-chemical-weapons-in-syria-says-foreign-minister-7209002]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:00:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar said Monday that his country had struck "chemical weapons" in neighbouring Syria, where rebel forces ousted president Bashar al-Assad over the weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar said Monday that his country had struck "chemical weapons" in neighbouring Syria, where rebel forces ousted president Bashar al-Assad over the weekend.</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference, Saar said "we attacked strategic weapon systems like, for example, remaining chemical weapons or long-range missiles and rockets in order that they will not fall in the hands of extremists".</p>

<p>Saar said Israel was monitoring the actions of the rebels, adding: "The steps we took, the only interest we have is the security of Israel and its citizens."</p>

<p>Israeli media reported on Friday that the military had struck a chemical weapons cache in Syria.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a Britain-based monitor, said on Monday the Israeli military conducted overnight strikes on multiple locations spanning coastal and southern Syria.</p>

<p>"Since the initial hours after the announcement of the fall of the former regime, Israel began launching intensive air strikes, deliberately destroying weapons and ammunitions depots," it said.</p>

<p>AFP photos on Monday showed damage at Mazzeh military airport on the outskirts of Damascus, including destroyed helicopters and jets, where the Israeli military struck nearby weapons depots.</p>

<p>Since Syria's civil war erupted in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes in the country, mainly targeting the army and Iran-backed groups.</p>

<p>Israel rarely comments on individual strikes in Syria but has repeatedly said it will not allow Iran to expand its presence in the country.</p>

<p>The country also moved troops into a demilitarised buffer zone in the Golan Heights region bordering Syria on Saturday.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel would "not allow any hostile force to establish itself on our border".</p>

<p>Saar said Monday that the takeover of the buffer was "a limited and temporary step we took for security reasons".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rooujejg_israel-strike-golan-heights-afp-_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since Syria's civil war erupted in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes in the country.(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/france-to-germany-to-belgium-the-eu-is-withering-away-7208998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: France To Germany To Belgium, EU Is Imploding]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/france-to-germany-to-belgium-the-eu-is-withering-away-7208998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:59:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The greatest threat to the EU doesn't come from Moscow or Beijing, but from within. Populist and nationalist movements are on the rise, fuelled by a toxic blend of economic anxiety, cultural insecurity, and distrust of Brussels.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-06/british-with-eu-flag-reuters_650x400_51466763676.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>France is without a government or an annual budget. Germany, the supposed anchor of European stability, is being run by a caretaker administration. Poland, meanwhile, has temporarily suspended the right to asylum, a cornerstone of European values, in a "bold new migration strategy" that looks more like a move that undermines the European Union ideals. Russia is firmly in the driver's seat in the Ukraine war. And as if that wasn't enough, the EU is staring down the barrel of a new American presidencyone that promises to hike import tariffs and bully Europe's NATO allies into coughing up more cash.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These aren't just random hiccups. France, Germany and Polandthe EU's big boysare all in turmoil. Indeed when the pillars of a structure start to crack, how long can the roof hold up?&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Union In Crisis</strong></h2>

<p>The European Union, built on the lofty ideals of democracy, human rights and freedom of speech, now finds itself teetering on the edge of an existential crisis. The irony is as rich as it is tragic: a union founded on unity is fracturing under the weight of its contradictions.</p>

<p>Let's start with the obvious. Britain exited the Union, but it's not alone. In France, Marine Le Pen lurks menacingly in the political shadows, her far-right populism offering voters a seductive, anti-EU narrative. In Italy, Matteo Salvini champions a similar brand of nationalist fervour, while in Germany, the far-right AfD party is no longer a fringe player but a rising force to be reckoned with. The EU isn't just rotting from outsideit is under siege from within.</p>

<h2><strong>When Europhiles Play The Populist Card</strong></h2>

<p>Poland's Prime Minister, Donald Tusk, is a known Europhile. But it was shocking for many in the EU that he suspended the right to asylum in his country, putting aside the bloc's own principles. Tusk was a man who spent years championing European values, and now he undermines one of their cornerstones, all to save his own skin. Cynically, he justified his decision by saying that Russia and Belarus were diverting asylum seekers to his country and other EU member countries, a charge still unproven. But his critics point out that his real worries are a lot closer to home. His pro-EU Civic Platform coalition may have scraped through Poland's parliamentary elections last year, but it's been floundering ever since. Polls now show Tusk's party neck and neck with the Eurosceptic Law and Justice Party (PiS).</p>

<p>Tusk is not alone. Struggling Europhile leaders across the continent are suddenly discovering the political utility of "securing national borders". Take, for example, Olaf Scholz, Germany's embattled chancellor. His popularity is sinking fast. Recently, Scholz imposed border controls across all of Germany's land borders, citing an Islamist terror attack in Solingen as the trigger. But let's call it what it is: a calculated move for the February election to placate voters fed up with migration and to fend off rising populist parties like the AfD.</p>

<h2><strong>Double Standards</strong></h2>

<p>Then there is Brussels itselfthe hallowed guardian of European unity, democracy and human rights. It has made a remarkable U-turn on migration. Recently, after one of its signature closed-door meetings, the European Commission threw its weight behind Tusk. In a statement backed by all 27 member states, Brussels claimed that Russia and Belarus are abusing our values and undermining our democracies. It justified its stance by saying that exceptional situations require appropriate measures.</p>

<p>Apparently, the EU has decided that border controls are acceptable so long as the justification is wrapped in anti-Russian rhetoric and presented by the right kind of leader. To understand the EU's hypocrisy, let's remind ourselves what it did to Viktor Orbn's HungaryOrbn being a bad boy' of Europe for supporting Russia. Recently, the EU's top court fined Hungary 200m for failing to follow the union's asylum policies. The court will also issue a penalty of 1m a day until it changes its policy. The European Court of Justice said Budapest was in breach of a 2020 judgement and had violated EU laws by forcing asylum seekers to travel to Belgrade or Kyiv to apply for a travel permit for entering Hungary.</p>

<p>These double standards are impossible to ignore. When Poland's PiS government previously clamped down on migration, Brussels was quick to condemn it as a betrayal of European values. But now that Tusk is doing the same, suddenly, the EU is all right with it.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>France Faces People's Mistrust</strong></h2>

<p>President Macron and France's so-called political class are facing a sea of public mistrust. A recent Le Monde survey paints a grim picture: only 22% of French people trust their MPsa seven-point drop in just a year. Voters are sick of the endless political bickering. And who can blame them? With faith in the system evaporating, the odds that fresh parliamentary elections next summer will magically deliver a stable majority seem very slim.</p>

<p>The timing couldn't be worse. The war in Ukraine is at a potential turning point, and across the Atlantic, a new Trump administration looms, itching to kickstart a trade war that could send shockwaves through Europe's fragile economy. For now, Macron still holds the reinsat least on paper. But he has to convince France's allies that the nation isn't about to unravel completely. With domestic gridlock and global crises closing in, it's up to him to prove that France can still play ball on the world stage. The question is: does anyone still believe he can pull it off?</p>

<h2><strong>Ukraine Obsession: A Crisis Of Priorities</strong></h2>

<p>The European Union is pouring billions into Ukrainedefence aid, financial packages, reconstruction pledgesall in the name of standing up to Russian aggression. But its own citizens are buckling under the weight of spiralling costs. Energy bills are sky-high, inflation continues to bite and wages remain stagnant. Let's be blunt, I live and travel in the heart of Europe and I feel it: the EU's relentless commitment to Ukraine isn't just draining its coffers, it's bleeding its people dry.</p>

<p>The Biden administration, ever the puppet master, has pulled the EU deep into the Ukrainian quagmire. Washington's playbook is clear: keep Europe committed to Ukraine as a frontline bulwark against Russia. But what has Europe gained? Endless sanctions that hurt its own economies more than Moscow's, and a cold winter of discontent driven by an overreliance on expensive LNG imports from across the Atlantic. Meanwhile, Russia, as I have said in my previous columns, though battered, is far from broken. Its economy is adapting and its territorial grip in eastern Ukraine remains firm.</p>

<h2><strong>An Awkward Dance With Trump And Musk</strong></h2>

<p>Europe's love affair with the American tech and political elite has soured spectacularly. Donald Trump's triumphant return and his bromance with Elon Musk may spell trouble for the EU's ambitious tech crackdown.</p>

<p>Let's talk about X, Musk's digital playground, and its showdown with the EU's Digital Services Act (DSA). This isn't just another slap-on-the-wrist regulation. Passed in 2022, the DSA packs a punch, demanding platforms remove illegal content or face fines of up to 6% of their annual revenue. Musk's X is on the radar of the EU regulators, who have alleged multiple violations of the DSA rules. Now, they're mulling their next movefine X, slap Musk with penalties, or go after both. But that was before Trump was in play. Now that he is, the EU's tech crusade is about to get a lot messier.</p>

<h2><strong>Digital Dinosaur In A World Of Tech Titans</strong></h2>

<p>One of the EU's biggest problems is that it's not disintegratingit's badly stagnating. Former Italian Prime Minister Mario Draghi sounded the alarm in September. In his much-anticipated 328-page report, Draghi pulled no punches: "This is an existential challenge, he said. Europe needs to raise its annual investment by a staggering 800 billion to keep pace with the US and China, with much of that going to tech. Without it, the continent risks being left in the dust.</p>

<p>Seattle-based, Indian-origin tech expert S. Aamir Aarfi says that Europe needs to act fast, as it currently lags behind all the top players. Says he, "Silicon Valley churns out innovation at warp speed, China dominates AI and 5G, and even India is emerging as a tech powerhouse. Unfortunately, Europe clings to regulations and bureaucracy, dangerously close to stagnation and irrelevance."</p>

<p>Consider the cold, hard facts, says Aarfi, the US dominates Big Tech and is home to giants like Apple, Google and Microsoft. China has its state-backed juggernautsTencent, Alibaba, and Huawei. But Europe? It boasts only the SAP". Draghi notes that a mere four of the world's top 50 tech companies are European. He doesn't mince words: "Europe largely missed out on the digital revolution led by the internet and the productivity gains it brought.</p>

<p>The EU appears to be spending more time regulating than innovating. Its flagship Digital Services and Markets Acts are more about policing foreign tech than fostering local growth. Meanwhile, European startups struggle to scale, stifled by red tape and a lack of venture capital. Europe dithers over ethics, while its brightest minds head to Silicon Valley or Shenzhen.</p>

<p>Draghi's diagnosis is clear: Europe isn't just falling behindit's failing to show up. If it doesn't act boldly and invest massively, it risks becoming a digital backwater, sidelined in the industries defining the future. As Aarfi says, "Europe needs a tech revolution and it needs it now.</p>

<p>The greatest threat to the EU doesn't come from Moscow or Beijing but from within. Populist and nationalist movements are on the rise, fuelled by a toxic blend of economic anxiety, cultural insecurity, and distrust of Brussels. Stuck in a web of noble intentions but shoddy execution, the EU risks becoming irrelevantnot through dramatic collapse, but through a slow, self-inflicted decline.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-06/british-with-eu-flag-reuters_650x400_51466763676.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>