<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:09:22 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-invited-to-india-by-pm-modi-visit-dates-to-be-set-in-2025-kremlin-7153714]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Invited To India By PM Modi, Visit Dates To Be Set In 2025: Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-invited-to-india-by-pm-modi-visit-dates-to-be-set-in-2025-kremlin-7153714]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:20:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin has received an invitation to visit India from Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the dates for his visit will be set in early 2025, Kremlin aide Yury Ushakov said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has received an invitation to visit India from Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the dates for his visit will be set in early 2025, Kremlin aide Yury Ushakov said.</p>

<p>While addressing a briefing, Ushakov stated that Putin and PM Modi have an agreement to hold meetings once a year and it is Russia's turn this time, according to Russian Embassy in India.</p>

<p>The diplomat stated, "Our leaders have an agreement to hold meetings once a year. This time, it's our turn." He further said, "We received Mr. Modi's invitation and we will certainly consider it positively."</p>

<p>Yury Ushakov noted, "We will figure out the tentative dates early next year."</p>

<p>This will be Putin's first visit to India since the beginning of the conflict between Ukraine and Russia in 2022. India has always advocated "peace and diplomacy" for resolving conflict between Ukraine and Russia.</p>

<p>Putin and PM Modi remain in regular contact, holding talks over phone-call once every couple of months, according to Russian Embassy in India. The two leaders also hold in-person meetings. This year, the two leaders met twice as PM Modi in July travelled to Moscow to participate in the 22nd Russia-India summit.</p>

<p>PM Modi's official visit to Russia in July marked his first bilateral visit after resuming office for the third time. PM Modi was also conferred with Russia's highest national award "The Order of St. Andrew the Apostle" for his contribution to fostering India-Russia ties.</p>

<p>From a warm hug to driving an electric car for 'dost' PM Modi, the chemistry between the leaders hogged the limelight. During his visit to Russia, PM Modi held a bilateral meeting and an informal meeting with Putin. The two leaders also visited the Rosatom Pavilion at the VDNKh Exhibition Centre in Moscow.</p>

<p>In October, PM Modi visited Russia's Kazan for a two-day visit to attend the BRICS Summit. He thanked Russian President Vladimir Putin, the people of Russia and their government for their hospitality. PM Modi took to X to share glimpses of his visit to Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0tksfg5k_narendra-modi-vladimir-putin-modi-putin-pti_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin and PM Modi remain in regular contact, according to Russian Embassy in India. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xrp-becomes-third-largest-cryptocurrency-beats-usdt-and-solana-7153546]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[XRP Becomes Third Largest Cryptocurrency, Beats USDT And Solana]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xrp-becomes-third-largest-cryptocurrency-beats-usdt-and-solana-7153546]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 13:52:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With a market cap exceeding $135.37 billion, XRP has overtaken the USDT stablecoin ($134.17 billion) and Solana ($108.01 billion).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The crypto market is abuzz following a seismic shift as XRP, the token powering Ripple's ecosystem, surged beyond $2, solidifying its position as the third-largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://beincrypto.com/ripple-xrp-flips-usdt-solana/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Beincrypto </em></a>reported.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>With a market cap exceeding $135.37 billion, XRP has overtaken the USDT stablecoin ($134.17 billion) and Solana ($108.01 billion), reigniting discussions about its potential to challenge Ethereum's dominance. At the time of writing, XRP is trading at $2.37, marking a remarkable 25.57% increase since Monday's session began. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Speculation is rife about XRP's trajectory, with enthusiasts suggesting it could rival Ethereum (ETH), whose market cap currently stands at $441.46 billion. Adding to the buzz, a recent meeting between Cardano founder Charles Hoskinson and Ripple CEO Brad Garlinghouse has captured attention, along with rumours of Garlinghouse being considered for a role as Donald Trump's potential crypto czar. Such a development could further bolster XRP's standing, especially given Trump's reported pro-crypto stance, Beincryto reported.</p>

<p>XRP's resurgence aligns with renewed scrutiny of Ripple's ongoing legal battle with the U.S. SEC. The lawsuit, which began in December 2020, has subjected XRP to intense market and regulatory pressures. Despite these challenges, XRP has regained its pre-lawsuit valuation, evoking memories of its dominance before the SEC's 2018 classification of Bitcoin and Ethereum as non-securities following the pivotal Hinman speech. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The Ripple case has unveiled internal SEC debates through the so-called "Hinman emails," revealing disagreements over the speech's implications for other cryptocurrencies. While these revelations have fueled market optimism, XRP's regulatory status remains unresolved, with legal analysts predicting the case could stretch into July 2025. &nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sneaky Moves From Whales on XRP<br />
<br />
Historically, significant spikes in whale-to-exchange transactions (marked by red circles) align closely with XRP price peaks, this suggests that whales tend to move large amounts of XRP to exchanges to sell near local or cycle tops.<br />
<br />
The latest… <a href="https://t.co/i0qKDs19XM">pic.twitter.com/i0qKDs19XM</a></p>
— 우민규 (Woominkyu) (@Woo_Minkyu) <a href="https://twitter.com/Woo_Minkyu/status/1863439161979703344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"Historically, significant spikes in whale-to-exchange transactions (marked by red circles) align closely with XRP price peaks. This suggests that whales tend to move large amounts of XRP to exchanges to sell near local or cycle tops. The latest spike in whale-to-exchange activity coincides with XRP reaching a local price of around $2.3. This could indicate whales preparing for potential profit-taking or increased market activity," a CryptoQuant analyst wrote on X.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mkdi1tt8_xrp_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Speculation is rife about XRP's trajectory]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-satellites-space-junk-crowd-earth-orbit-global-push-for-cooperation-7153429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[More Than 14,000 Satellites, 120 Million Pieces Of Debris Jamming Earth Orbit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-satellites-space-junk-crowd-earth-orbit-global-push-for-cooperation-7153429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 13:31:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The rapid increase in satellites and space junk will make low Earth orbit unusable unless companies and countries cooperate and share the data needed to manage that most accessible region of space, experts and industry insiders said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The rapid increase in satellites and space junk will make low Earth orbit unusable unless companies and countries cooperate and share the data needed to manage that most accessible region of space, experts and industry insiders said.</p>

<p>A United Nations panel on space traffic coordination in late October determined that urgent action was necessary and called for a comprehensive shared database of orbital objects as well as an international framework to track and manage them.</p>

<p>More than 14,000 satellites including some 3,500 inactive surround the globe in low Earth orbit, showed data from US-based Slingshot Aerospace. Alongside those are about 120 million pieces of debris from launches, collisions and wear-and-tear of which only a few thousand are large enough to track.</p>

<p>"There's no time to lose on space traffic coordination. With so many objects being launched into space, we have to do everything we can to ensure space safety, and that means facilitating the sharing of information between operators, be they public or private, in order to avoid collisions," said panel co-chair Aarti Holla-Maini, director of the United Nations Office for Outer Space Affairs.</p>

<p>Low Earth orbit must remain safe to prevent costly disruption to the technology behind global communication, navigation and scientific exploration, she said.</p>

<p>Yet there is no centralised system that all space-faring nations can leverage and even persuading them to use such a system has many obstacles. Whereas some countries are willing to share data, others fear compromising security, particularly as satellites are often dual-use and include defence purposes. Moreover, enterprises are keen to guard commercial secrets.</p>

<p>In the meantime, the mess multiplies.</p>

<p>A Chinese rocket stage exploded in August, adding thousands of fragments of debris to low Earth orbit. In June, a defunct Russian satellite exploded, scattering thousands of shards which forced astronauts on the International Space Station to take shelter for an hour.</p>

<p>Low Earth orbit is the region most congested with human-made objects as it offers a balance between cost and proximity, making it a prime target for the rapidly growing commercial space sector. It has also seen a 17% rise in close approaches per satellite over the past year, Slingshot data showed.</p>

<p>Projections point to tens of thousands more satellites entering orbit in the coming years. The potential financial risk of collisions is likely to be $556 million over five years, based on a modelled scenario with a 3.13% annual collision probability and $111 million in yearly damages, said Montreal-based NorthStar Earth &amp; Space.</p>

<p>"We are at a critical point with respect to putting regulations and structure in space to monitor and manage the growing congestion. With Starlink launching thousands of satellites per year, China and others preparing to follow, we will soon push the bearing capacity of prime orbits," said NorthStar CEO Stewart Bain.</p>

<h3><strong>Risky business</strong></h3>

<p>Low Earth orbit is densely packed, with bands such as the one for satellite internet service Starlink from commercial space company SpaceX - at an altitude of 540-570 km (336-354 miles). As of Nov. 27, Starlink had 6,764 satellites in orbit, Jonathan's Space Report showed.</p>

<p>SpaceX data showed Starlink satellites performed nearly 50,000 collision-avoidance manoeuvres in the first half of 2024, about double the previous six months.</p>

<p>SpaceX did not respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>The European Space Agency, which has fewer spacecraft than SpaceX, said in 2021 its manoeuvres have increased to three or four times per craft versus a historical average of one.</p>

<p>The 800-900 km band contains fewer satellites but has 3,114 objects - including operational and non-operational payloads, rocket bodies and fragments - which make up 20% of the total mass of objects in low Earth orbit, posing significant collision risk, LeoLabs data showed.</p>

<p>Expired satellites add to the clutter as they stay in orbit until they fall into - and burn up in - Earth's atmosphere years later or are flown to a "graveyard orbit" some 36,000 km away.</p>

<p>Russia drew global criticism in November 2021 when it test fired a missile at a defunct satellite in orbit, creating thousands of fragments of debris. Russia invaded Ukraine three months after the test.</p>

<p>"The potential for conflicts between states has been on a steep rise in the recent past. If these extend to space it could complicate the outer space environment. We urgently need common global rules for coordination," said Anirudh Sharma, CEO of Bengaluru-based Digantara, which specialises in space situational awareness.</p>

<h3><strong>Final frontliner</strong></h3>

<p>The UN's Holla-Maini, whose office serves as secretariat for the Committee on the Peaceful Uses of Outer Space, said the October panel aimed to bring together public- and private-sector experts to outline steps needed to start work on coordination. It will present its findings at a committee meeting next year.</p>

<p>Global cooperation is essential to developing enforceable rules akin to those used by the International Civil Aviation Organization for air traffic, industry experts told Reuters.</p>

<p>Such effort would involve the use of existing tools, such as databases, telescopes, radars and other sensors to track objects while improving coverage, early detection and data precision.</p>

<p>Yet geopolitical tension and reluctance to share data with nations deemed unfriendly as well as commercial concerns over protecting proprietary information and competitive advantages remain significant barriers.</p>

<p>That leaves operators of orbital equipment relying on informal or semi-formal methods of avoiding collisions, such as drawing on data from the U.S. Space Force or groups like the Space Data Association. However, this can involve issues such as accountability and inconsistent data standards.</p>

<p>"The top challenges are speed - as consensus-building takes time - and trust," Holla-Maini said. "Some countries simply can't communicate with others, but the U.N. can facilitate this process. Speed is our biggest enemy, but there's no alternative. It must be done."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p1u6k208_space-junk-generic-space-debris-generic-pixabay_625x300_09_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Low Earth orbit is densely packed, with bands such as the one for satellite internet service Starlink.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-massad-boulos-donald-trumps-new-middle-east-adviser-7152005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Massad Boulos, Donald Trump's New Middle East Adviser]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-massad-boulos-donald-trumps-new-middle-east-adviser-7152005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 13:17:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has appointed Massad Boulos, a Lebanese-born billionaire, as his senior adviser for Arab and Middle Eastern Affairs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has appointed Massad Boulos, a Lebanese-born billionaire, as his senior adviser for Arab and Middle Eastern Affairs. Boulos is also the father-in-law of Trump's daughter Tiffany Trump. The President-elect made the announcement on Truth Social, highlighting Boulos's legal and business expertise.</p>

<p>"I am proud to announce that Massad Boulos will serve as Senior Advisor to the President on Arab and Middle Eastern affairs. Massad is an accomplished lawyer and a highly respected leader in the business world, with extensive experience on the International scene," Trump wrote on Truth Social.</p>

<p>"He has been a longtime proponent of Republican and Conservative values, an asset to my Campaign, and was instrumental in building tremendous new coalitions with the Arab American Community. Massad is a dealmaker, and an unwavering supporter of PEACE in the Middle East. He will be a strong advocate for the United States, and its interests, and I am pleased to have him on our team,” Trump concluded.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/GKe6TuIWEJ">pic.twitter.com/GKe6TuIWEJ</a></p>
— Donald J. Trump Posts From His Truth Social (@TrumpDailyPosts) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpDailyPosts/status/1863274449014870422?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Earlier, Trump extended a diplomatic role to Charles Kushner, the father-in-law of his daughter Ivanka Trump, as ambassador to France.</p>

<h2><strong>Who is Massad Boulos?</strong></h2>

<p>Massad Boulos, born in Lebanon, moved to Texas as a teenager to pursue higher education at the University of Houston. His professional journey began in Nigeria, where he joined his family's automotive business, eventually rising to leadership positions at SCOA Motors and Boulos Enterprises.</p>

<p>Some reports suggest Mr Boulos unsuccessfully contested a parliamentary seat in Lebanon in 2009 and maintained ties with the country's Christian political elite - partly due to his father-in-law's financial support of the Free Patriotic Movement, a Christian party aligned with Hezbollah. Mr Boulos has denied these claims.</p>

<p>In an October 2024 interview with Newsweek, he said he was not affiliated with any party in Lebanon, though he acknowledged being “acquainted with most Lebanese Christian leaders,” including a Hezbollah-endorsed presidential candidate. He also refuted earlier reports by Arab News and AP about his alleged parliamentary candidacy.</p>

<p>In a June interview with AP, Mr Boulos described himself as a “friend” of Suleiman Frangieh, the leader of Lebanon's Marada Movement, whose presidential bid is backed by Hezbollah. Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah, who endorsed Frangieh in 2023, was later killed in an Israeli airstrike on Beirut in September.</p>

<p>Mr Boulos's father and grandfather were influential figures in Lebanese politics, and his father-in-law was a significant financial supporter of the Free Patriotic Movement, a Christian party allied with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Recently, Mr Boulos played a major role in Donald Trump's campaign, focusing on gaining support from Arab American voters in key states like Michigan. As reported by Axios, he has also acted as a crucial intermediary between Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas and Trump, facilitating communication in the months leading up to the election.</p>

<p>Michael Boulos, the son of Massad Boulos, and Tiffany Trump were married in an elaborate ceremony at Donald Trump's Mar-a-Lago Club in Florida in November 2022, following their engagement in the White House Rose Garden during Trump's first term.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fsngp5f_massad-boulos_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-hunter-bidens-case-history-reactions-to-joe-bidens-presidential-pardon-7153318]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Hunter Biden's Case History, Reactions To Presidential Pardon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-hunter-bidens-case-history-reactions-to-joe-bidens-presidential-pardon-7153318]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 13:16:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Reversing his past promises to not use the powers of the presidency for the benefit of his family, US President Joe Biden on Sunday issued an official pardon for his son, Hunter Biden, sparing him a possible prison sentence for two criminal cases.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reversing his past promises to not use the powers of the presidency for the benefit of his family, US President Joe Biden on Sunday issued an official pardon for his son, Hunter Biden, sparing him a possible prison sentence for two criminal cases related to federal felony gun and tax convictions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Joe Biden had time and again said that he would not pardon his son or commute his sentence after convictions in the two cases in Delaware and California. Mr Biden's decision to use his position to help his son marks a significant shift in the Democratic President's political position, who promised Americans to restore norms and respect for the rule of law, after Donald Trump's first term in office.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Biden's Statement</strong></h2>

<p>"Today, I signed a pardon for my son Hunter. From the day I took office, I said I would not interfere with the Justice Department's decision-making, and I kept my word even as I have watched my son being selectively, and unfairly, prosecuted," the US President said in a statement.</p>

<p>Mr Biden,&nbsp;who is in the final weeks of his presidency before Trump takes office on January 20,&nbsp;said that his opponents had sought to break his son with selective prosecution.</p>

<p>"No reasonable person who looks at the facts of Hunter's cases can reach any other conclusion than Hunter was singled out only because he is my son -- and that is wrong," said the President.</p>

<p>He stressed that people were rarely brought to trial for felony charges for how they filled out a gun form, and said others who were late in paying taxes because of addiction but paid them back with interest and penalties, as his son had, typically received non-criminal resolutions to their cases.</p>

<p>"It is clear that Hunter was treated differently. The charges in his cases came about only after several of my political opponents in Congress instigated them to attack me and oppose my election," Mr Biden said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In trying to break Hunter, they've tried to break me - and there's no reason to believe it will stop here. Enough is enough," he added.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden, a recovering drug addict who became a target of Republicans, has been granted "a full and unconditional" pardon for any offences in a window from January 1, 2014, to December 1, 2024.</p>

<p>Mr Biden said he had made his decision to pardon over the weekend.</p>

<p>The president, his wife, Jill Biden, and their family including Hunter, spent the Thanksgiving holiday in Nantucket, Massachusetts, and returned to Washington on Saturday night.</p>

<p>"Here's the truth: I believe in the justice system, but as I have wrestled with this, I also believe raw politics has infected this process and it led to a miscarriage of justice - and once I made this decision this weekend, there was no sense in delaying it further," he said.</p>

<p>"I hope Americans will understand why a father and a President would come to this decision," the President added.</p>

<h2><strong>What Is Presidential Pardon?</strong></h2>

<p>The US Constitution gives power to presidents to grant clemency, which can include commutations and pardons. Granting commutation reduces penalties against the convicted felon without erasing the conviction. Meanwhile, a pardon forgives a person's federal crimes entirely.</p>

<h2><strong>Republicans Criticized Joe Biden's Move</strong></h2>

<p>"Does the Pardon given by Joe to Hunter include the J-6 Hostages, who have now been imprisoned for years? Such an abuse and miscarriage of Justice!" President-elect Donald Trump said in a post on his Truth Social site, referring to those convicted for storming the US Capitol on January 6, 2021, after Trump claimed falsely that he had won the 2020 election.</p>

<p>"Joe Biden has lied from start to finish about his family's corrupt influence-peddling activities," said Representative James Comer, chair of the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</p>

<h2><strong>Cases Against Hunter Biden</strong></h2>

<p>The younger Biden faced sentencing for the false statements and gun convictions this month. He was convicted earlier this year of lying about his drug use when he bought a gun -- a felony.</p>

<p>In September he also pleaded guilty to federal charges of failing to pay $1.4 million in taxes while spending lavishly on drugs, sex workers and luxury items. He was scheduled for sentencing in that case on December 16.</p>

<p>Earlier, Hunter Biden has paid the back taxes, as well as penalties levied by authorities. In August 2023, his lawyers said prosecutors had reneged on a plea deal that would have resolved the tax and firearms charges -- but that agreement fell apart at the last minute.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For tax evasion, Hunter Biden was facing up to 17 years in prison. For the separate gun charge, he was facing 25 years in prison.</p>

<p>"I have admitted and taken responsibility for my mistakes during the darkest days of my addiction - mistakes that have been exploited to publicly humiliate and shame me and my family for political sport," Hunter Biden said in a statement on Sunday.</p>

<p>"In the throes of addiction, I squandered many opportunities and advantages ... I will never take the clemency I have been given today for granted and will devote the life I have rebuilt to helping those who are still sick and suffering," He said further, adding he had remained sober for more than five years.</p>

<p>His case has long been a thorn in the Biden family's side, particularly during this election year when Republicans have charged that Hunter was being treated too leniently.</p>

<p>However, President Biden's withdrawal from the presidential race in favour of Vice President Kamala Harris had taken much of the zeal out of the Republican drive to make an example out of his son. Still, prosecutors appeared unwilling to cut him any slack, rejecting a so-called "Alford plea," whereby Hunter Biden would admit guilt because of the high probability of conviction, but would maintain his innocence.</p>

<h2><strong>Power And Pardon</strong></h2>

<p>The move brings fresh scrutiny over the independence of the US judicial system -- especially at a time when incoming president Donald Trump has moved to appoint loyalists to the FBI and Justice Department himself.</p>

<p>But, this is not the first time when a US President used pardon to help family members and other political allies.</p>

<p>Bill Clinton pardoned his half-brother for old cocaine charges and Mr Trump pardoned the father of his son-in-law for tax evasion, though in both cases those men had already served their prison terms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Trump has also vowed to pardon supporters who stormed the US Capitol in a deadly riot on January 6, 2021, in a bid to reverse his 2020 election loss.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7icvjqng_joe-hunter-biden-afp_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden said he made the decision to pardon son Hunter over the weekend.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/time-moves-faster-on-moon-than-on-earth-scientists-reveal-7153093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Time Moves Faster On Moon Than On Earth? Scientists Reveal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/time-moves-faster-on-moon-than-on-earth-scientists-reveal-7153093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:46:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[To explore the Earth's natural satellite, the communication and navigation infrastructure between both worlds must be synced immaculately.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time moves faster on the Moon than on Earth, a new study based on Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity, published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/1538-3881/ad643a" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Astronomical Journal</em></a> has shown. Since the moon's gravitational pull is weaker than Earth's, the clocks on the Moon tick faster with the difference being about 56 microseconds per Earth day, or 0.000056 seconds. "If we are on the Moon, clocks are going to tick differently [than on Earth]," said theoretical physicist Bijunath Patla of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) associated with the study.</p>

<p>Mr Patla and his colleague Neil Ashby, improved on previous analyses by using Einstein's work to calculate the number. The theory of general relativity posits that the rate of a standard clock is influenced by the gravitational potential at its location and its relative motion.</p>

<p>"For example, clocks farther away from Earth tick faster, and clocks in uniform motion tick slower with respect to "ideal" clocks, and vice versa. Therefore, choosing an appropriate reference frame becomes essential for obtaining self-consistent results when comparing clocks on two celestial bodies," the study stated.</p>

<p>To tackle such a problem, Mr Patla and Mr Ashby acknowledged that the Earth-Moon system is in free fall, moving only under the influence of the Sun's gravity. This enabled them to formulate the contributions from each complication: the rotation of each body, tidal forces, deviations in shape from perfect spheres, and so forth.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/massive-moon-replica-at-iit-festival-brings-lunar-terrain-to-life-7152334" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Massive Moon Replica At IIT's Science Festival Brings Lunar Terrain To Life</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Why is it important?</strong></h3>

<p>Over 50 years after the first lunar landing, NASA is now preparing to send humans back to the Moon as part of the Artemis mission. To explore the Earth's natural satellite, the communication and navigation infrastructure between both worlds must be synced immaculately.</p>

<p>When it comes to navigation, a drift of 56 microseconds over a day between a clock on the Moon and a clock on Earth can be a big difference. The relativistic framework enables us to compare clock rates on both bodies and might help establish Coordinated Lunar Time (LTC). The White House Office of Science and Technology Policy has instructed NASA to work with the US government to devise a plan by the end of 2026.</p>

<p>As part of the Artemis Mission, NASA is planning to study places on the lunar surface where bases can be set up that can later be used to venture deeper into the vast emptiness of the cosmos. Scientists are also planning to set up rail tracks on the moon along with a transit system to transfer humans and cargo to the lunar body.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ap4i0m9g_moon-unsplash_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Time moves faster on Moon than on Earth, the study revealed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-adults-are-hiring-partners-on-rent-to-please-parents-applicants-must-be-fit-good-cook-7153077]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vietnam Adults Are Hiring Partners On Rent To Please Parents]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-adults-are-hiring-partners-on-rent-to-please-parents-applicants-must-be-fit-good-cook-7153077]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:44:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While this trend offers a temporary solution to societal expectations, experts warn of the potential risks and emotional complexities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As societal pressures and career aspirations delay marriage for many young Vietnamese, a unique trend has emerged: renting boyfriends. Social media groups have seen a surge in women seeking temporary partners to appease their families and avoid the stigma of being single, according to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3288539/vietnam-youth-rent-partners-meet-parental-expectations-applicants-must-be-fit-good-cooks" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>South China Morning Post</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Minh Thu, a 30-year-old professional, faced immense pressure from her parents to bring a boyfriend home for the Lunar New Year. Unable to find a suitable partner, she resorted to hiring a man to pose as her boyfriend. The man, skilled in domestic chores and social graces, successfully impressed her family.</p>

<p>Khanh Ngoc, another young woman, had a similar experience. She rented a handsome, younger man who charmed her parents during a visit. This experience improved her relationship with her family.</p>

<p>Huy Tuan, a 25-year-old man, has made a business out of being a "fake boyfriend." He undergoes rigorous training to meet the diverse needs of his clients, from casual dates to family gatherings.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While this trend offers a temporary solution to societal expectations, experts warn of the potential risks and emotional complexities associated with such arrangements.</p>

<p>Nguyen Thanh Nga, a researcher at the Academy of Journalism and Communication in Vietnam, stated: "If exposed, families could experience significant emotional damage and lose trust. Additionally, renting a partner is not legally protected in Vietnam, so women should be especially cautious."</p>

<p>The trend of renting partners has garnered widespread attention on social media.</p>

<p>One online observer remarked, "Marrying without a successful career just leads to a lot of problems. Renting a partner is a win-win - it makes your parents happy and alleviates pressure on you."</p>

<p>Conversely, another commenter expressed concern: "I can't imagine how heartbreaking it would be for parents to find out it was a lie."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kbkktro8_asian-couple-generic_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The trend of renting partners has garnered widespread attention on social media.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-estimates-16-billion-siphoned-yearly-in-sheikh-hasina-rule-7153013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[$16 Billion Siphoned Yearly During Sheikh Hasina Rule: Bangladesh Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-estimates-16-billion-siphoned-yearly-in-sheikh-hasina-rule-7153013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:39:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An average $16 billion may have been illicitly siphoned out of Bangladesh annually during former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's 15-year rule.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An average $16 billion may have been illicitly siphoned out of Bangladesh annually during former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's 15-year rule, according to the findings of a committee formed by interim leader Muhammad Yunus.</p>

<p>The panel led by economist Debapriya Bhattacharya submitted a white paper on the state of Bangladesh's economy to Yunus in Dhaka on Sunday, according to a government statement.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina was ousted by student protesters in August after 15 years of increasingly authoritarian rule. The army and protest leaders tapped Nobel laureate Yunus, who pioneered microcredit to the poor, to lead an interim government.</p>

<p>"Our blood curdles to know how they plundered the economy," Yunus said in the statement. "The sad part is they looted the economy openly. And most of us could not summon courage to confront it."</p>

<p>The document shows "the economy we inherited after the July-August mass uprising," he said.</p>

<p>Leaders in Sheikh Hasina's party are in jail or hiding in Bangladesh, or have left the country. The party doesn't have a spokesperson who can be contacted to comment on allegations in the white paper.</p>

<p>As part of its investigations, the committee looked into seven large projects out of 29 which had more than 100 billion taka ($836 million) expenditure outlay each.</p>

<p>The initial cost of the seven projects examined was estimated at 1.14 trillion taka. Hasina's government later revised project costs to 1.95 trillion taka through the addition of more components and inflated land prices among others, according to the statement.</p>

<p>"The problem is deeper than what we have thought," Bhattacharya said, adding that the 400-page white paper will show "how crony capitalism gave birth to the oligarchs, who controlled the policy framing."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pp02ivl_sheikh-hasina-ians_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Leaders in Sheikh Hasina's party are in jail or hiding in Bangladesh, or have left the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/leaked-audio-clip-indicates-widening-rifts-within-imran-khans-party-in-pakistan-7152903]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Leaked Audio Clip Indicates Widening Rifts Within Imran Khan's Party]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/leaked-audio-clip-indicates-widening-rifts-within-imran-khans-party-in-pakistan-7152903]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:25:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new audio clip featuring Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) leader Ali Muhammad Khan has surfaced, indicating widening rifts within the leadership of the Imran Khan-founded party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new audio clip featuring Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) leader Ali Muhammad Khan has surfaced, indicating widening rifts within the leadership of the Imran Khan-founded party after its "do-or-die" protest fiasco in Islamabad, Geo News reported.</p>

<p>The audio clip was leaked days after PTI suddenly delayed its march after a government crackdown on protesters trying to reach D-Chowk, drawing widespread condemnation within the party. Questions were raised within the PTI parliamentary leadership about why supporters were told to go to D-Chowk instead of holding a sit-in in Sangjani, as Imran Khan had ordered.</p>

<p>In the audio, which Ali Muhammad Khan confirmed was his during a talk with Geo News, the PTI leader said that Imran Khan had ordered the leaders to set up a protest camp in Islamabad's Sangjani area, not at D-Chowk in the Red Zone, according to Geo News report.</p>

<p>In the audio leak, Ali Muhammad Khan said, "The PTI founder had not asked to come to D-Chowk, but to Islamabad. Khan Sahib had said that the final sit-in location would be confirmed after the party members reached Islamabad." He said that Imran Khan had given instructions in the presence of Barrister Gohar Faisal.</p>

<p>Questioning the role of Imran Khan's sister, Aleema Khan, the PTI leader asked why did she made the call instead of the party chairman Gohar Ali Khan.</p>

<p>He asked, "The PTI founder had said that there was no place for hereditary politics in our party, so why did Aleema Khan call the protest herself?" He further said that Khan had said party leadership would give the call, according to Geo News report.</p>

<p>In the audio clip, Ali Muhammad Khan said that PTI's aim was to hold talks through the protests at the orders given by Imran Khan. He further said that Imran Khan was not aware of his wife, Bushra Bibi's presence in the protest and was informed regarding this by Barrister Gohar Ali Khan.</p>

<p>Khan said, "The PTI chairman and secretary general should have announced that the sit-in would be held in Sangjani," adding that Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Chief Minister Ali Amin Gandapur was also in agreement with this. He said that no one had the right to override the decision of PTI founder, Geo News reported.</p>

<p>Stressing that PTI should have followed Imran Khan's instructions, Ali Muhammad Khan said, "We should have followed our leader's orders and stopped in Sangjani. No one, including Bushra Bibi, has the right to override the founder-chairman's decision." He said, "When Barrister Saif had conveyed the message of the founding chairman, we should have acted on it."</p>

<p>The PTI protests, demanding the release of former Pakistan Prime Minister Imran Khan, took a violent turn on Tuesday, resulting in the deaths of four security personnel and two PTI supporters, Dawn reported. The PTI protesters were met with intense tear gas upon reaching Islamabad's D-Chowk following which the clash between protesters and security forces broke out.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vdm52ngg_pakistan-protest-bloomberg_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PTI protests, demanding the release of former Pakistan Prime Minister Imran Khan, took a violent turn.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-scientists-dissect-worlds-rarest-spade-toothed-whale-7152703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Zealand Scientists Dissect World's Rarest Spade-Toothed Whale]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-scientists-dissect-worlds-rarest-spade-toothed-whale-7152703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:59:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New Zealand scientists on Monday began dissecting a whale considered the rarest in the world, a species so elusive that only seven specimens have ever been documented.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand scientists on Monday began dissecting a whale considered the rarest in the world, a species so elusive that only seven specimens have ever been documented.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The dead spade-toothed whale washed ashore on New Zealand's South Island earlier this year, offering a chance to study a deep-sea mammal that has never been seen alive.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Measuring five metres (16.4 feet) long, the whale was winched off the beach in July and has sat in a special freezer since.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Whale expert Anton van Helden said it was the first time scientists had been able to dissect a complete spade-toothed specimen, which belongs to the family of beaked whales.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is a remarkable and globally significant opportunity," he said.</p>

<p>The week-long dissection will help to fill in gaps about the whale's behaviour, its diet, and even its basic anatomy.</p>

<p>"Beaked whales are the most enigmatic group of large mammals on the planet," said Van Helden.</p>

<p>"They are deep divers that are rarely seen at sea, which presents real challenges for researching these marine animals.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This one is the rarest of the rare -- only the seventh specimen known from anywhere in the world, and the first opportunity we have had to undertake a dissection like this."&nbsp;</p>

<p>New Zealand's conservation department said the spade-toothed whale was the "rarest whale in the world".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The species was first described in 1874 from just a lower jaw and two teeth collected from the Chatham Islands off the east coast of New Zealand.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That sample, along with skeletal remains of two other specimens found in New Zealand and Chile, enabled scientists to confirm a new species.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Because so few specimens have been found and there have been no live sightings, the spade-toothed whale is classified as "data deficient" under the New Zealand Threat Classification System.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/lcmliq5g_whale_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The species was first described in 1874.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/charges-against-hunter-biden-and-consequences-avoided-through-presidential-pardon-7152668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Pardons Son Hunter: A Look At Charges And Potential Punishment]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/charges-against-hunter-biden-and-consequences-avoided-through-presidential-pardon-7152668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:50:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hunter Biden had pleaded guilty to failing to pay $1.4 million in taxes during a period when he allegedly spent excessively on drugs, luxury items, and other activities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Outgoing US President <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-pardons-son-hunter-in-2-criminal-cases-hope-americans-will-understand-7151191">Joe Biden</a> on Sunday pardoned his son, Hunter Biden, who was facing legal troubles involving tax violations and firearms-related charges. This decision is a reversal of Biden's earlier stance of not intervening in the Justice Department's handling of his son's cases.<br />
<br />
“Today, I signed a pardon for my son Hunter. From the day I took office, I said I would not interfere with the Justice Department's decision-making, and I kept my word even as I have watched my son being selectively, and unfairly, prosecuted,” Biden said in a statement.</p>

<p>He defended his son, saying the legal actions against him were politically motivated.<br />
<br />
<strong>Charges Against Hunter Biden:</strong></p>

<p>Hunter Biden, 54, was facing legal scrutiny over his business dealings, taxes, and personal struggles. A federal investigation launched in 2018 by US Attorney David Weiss focused on alleged tax and money laundering, including $4.79 million in wire transfers from entities tied to Chinese energy tycoon Ye Jianming and CEFC China Energy. These transactions, linked to his businesses, gained attention after Hunter's laptop was seized ahead of Joe Biden's presidential election.<br />
<br />
<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hunter-biden-found-guilty-of-lying-about-drug-use-to-buy-gun-5868681 ">Hunter Biden had pleaded guilty</a> to failing to pay $1.4 million in taxes during a period when he allegedly spent excessively on drugs, sex workers, luxury items, and other activities.</p>

<p>He was convicted on three felonies for lying about drug use while purchasing a gun in 2018. Prosecutors revealed cocaine residue was found in his gun pouch. He said his guilty plea aimed to protect his family from further embarrassment and his actions, driven by addiction, had been unfairly exploited for political reasons.<br />
<br />
<strong>Punishment Hunter Biden Was Facing:</strong><br />
<br />
Hunter Biden had pleaded guilty to nine federal tax charges for which he could have faced up to 17 years in federal prison while the gun-related charges could lead to up to 25 years.<br />
<br />
However, experts believed he would have likely served no more than 36 months and 16 months behind bars respectively. It was anticipated that the sentences for the tax and gun charges would run concurrently, with Hunter Biden serving the longer term.<br />
<br />
Hunter's sentencing was scheduled for December 16.<br />
<br />
Acknowledging his past, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-pardons-son-hunter-in-2-criminal-cases-hope-americans-will-understand-7151191">Hunter Biden</a> on Sunday said in a statement, “I have admitted and taken responsibility for my mistakes during the darkest days of my addiction – mistakes that have been exploited to publicly humiliate and shame me and my family for political sport.”</p>

<p>“I will never take the clemency I have been given today for granted,” he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tk7bo36o_hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nfl-legend-randy-moss-asks-for-prayers-after-revealing-hes-battling-health-issues-7152570]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NFL Legend Randy Moss Reveals He's Battling Health Issues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nfl-legend-randy-moss-asks-for-prayers-after-revealing-hes-battling-health-issues-7152570]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:37:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Randy Moss has been a six-time Pro Bowler and four-time All-Pro after playing 14 years in the NFL.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NFL legend Rando Moss has revealed that he is "battling" an illness as he appeared on <em>ESPN's Sunday NFL Countdown </em>show, wearing sunglasses. The former Minnesota Vikings and New England Patriots star wide receiver did not specify what he was suffering from but requested the viewers and fans to pray for him to come out on top. "I just wanted to let the viewers know that me and my wife and my family are battling something internally. I have some great doctors around me," Mr Moss said during the show, surrounded by co-hosts Mike Greenberg, Rex Ryan, Alex Smith and Tedy Bruschi.</p>

<p>"I couldn't miss the show. I wanted to be here with you guys. I feel great. But if you see me with these 'Michigan turnover glasses' that I have on, it's not being disrespectful because I'm on television. It's because I'm battling something."</p>

<p>"I need all the prayer warriors. God bless you all. Thanks for the prayers. We'll work through it."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">MORE FROM RANDY MOSS?<br />
<br />
“You were talking about my eyes last week… I just want to let the viewers know that me and my wife, me &amp; my family, we are battling something internally”<br />
<br />
“I'm battling something. I need all the prayer warriors. God bless you all”<br />
<a href="https://t.co/8Yos4743lz">pic.twitter.com/8Yos4743lz</a> <a href="https://t.co/UpTU6HHKvr">https://t.co/UpTU6HHKvr</a></p>
— MLFootball (@_MLFootball) <a href="https://twitter.com/_MLFootball/status/1863279646554431777?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>After Mr Moss's update, all the co-hosts on the panel pulled out their glasses at the same time and wore them to show solidarity with the NFL alum. "All for one and one for all," Mr Greenberg said while sliding the glasses on his face. "If he's wearing glasses, we're all wearing glasses today."</p>

<p>Mr Moss, who turns 48 next year, has been a six-time Pro Bowler and four-time All-Pro after playing 14 years in the NFL. He was inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 2018 in what was his first year of eligibility.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turducken-and-how-nfl-legend-john-madden-made-it-popular-on-thanksgiving-7135171" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | As Thanksgiving Dish Turducken Trends, It's Link To NFL Legend John Madden</strong></a></p>

<p><strong>Internet reacts</strong></p>

<p>As the video clip of Mr Moss's health update went viral, fans from across the board came out in his support, wishing him good luck on his recovery journey.</p>

<p>"The solidarity of these guys to put their glasses on with him made my heart full," said one user, while another added: "I love Randy the GOAT!!! Praying for you."</p>

<p>A third user speculated: "Eye changes are most common in cancer patients who undergo radiation therapy. This is especially true for patients with head and neck cancers since radiation is delivered close to the eyes."</p>

<p>Notably, prior to joining the ESPN crew in 2016 where he is now a regular member of the "Sunday NFL Countdown" crew, Mr Moss worked for Fox Sports as a broadcaster as well.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hpqdo7e8_randy-moss_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Randy Moss revealed he is battling "something internally".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crypto-millionaire-hides-2-million-treasure-across-us-heres-how-to-find-them-7152315]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Millionaire Hides $2 Million Treasure Across US. Here's How To Find Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crypto-millionaire-hides-2-million-treasure-across-us-heres-how-to-find-them-7152315]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:54:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The treasure chests are filled with items, including gold doubloons, rare Pokemon cards, a Bitcoin valued at nearly $100,000, and historical artefacts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you're a treasure-hunting enthusiast, this might pique your interest: a Bitcoin millionaire in the U.S. has hidden over $2 million worth of treasures across the country. Entrepreneur Jon Collins-Black, who built his wealth through cryptocurrency investments, has created this elaborate project to spark curiosity and adventure, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fox10phoenix.com/news/bitcoin-millionaire-2m-treasure-hunt-clues" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Fox 10</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The treasure chests are filled with extraordinary items, including gold doubloons, rare Pokemon cards, a Bitcoin valued at nearly $100,000, and historical artefacts such as a diamond and sapphire brooch once owned by Jacqueline Onassis. Clues to the five hidden chests can be found in Collins-Black's book,<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://treasureinside.com/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em> There's Treasure Inside</em></a>, which features puzzles and maps to guide seekers.</p>

<p>A lifelong fantasy and adventure enthusiast, Collins-Black grew up immersed in games like <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>. Now, he's channelling that passion into a real-world quest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To ensure safety and accessibility, Collins-Black has strategically placed the treasures in non-remote locations within three miles of public roads. None are buried or located on private property. "You don't have to be a genius to solve the clues," he told the *New York Post*. "With curiosity, imagination, and a willingness to try something new, anyone can find the treasures I've hidden."</p>

<h3><strong>The treasure includes a diverse array of unique items to capture different interests, such as: &nbsp;</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>A fourth-century BCE gold Greek laurel &nbsp;</li>
	<li>A coin designed and minted by Pablo Picasso &nbsp;</li>
	<li>A rare lunar rock specimen &nbsp;</li>
	<li>A Michael Jordan 1986 rookie card &nbsp;</li>
	<li>A single Bitcoin, adding a modern twist to the age-old concept of treasure hunting &nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p>Collins-Black began planning the hunt during the COVID-19 lockdowns, inspired to create a legacy of adventure. "I created this treasure hunt because I live for adventure," he said. "I hope to ignite that same sense of wonder and curiosity in everyone who joins this journey."</p>

<p>The project has drawn comparisons to the famous treasure hunt organized by New Mexico art dealer Forrest Fenn, who hid a chest of gold and jewels worth $2 million in the Rocky Mountains in 2010. Fenn's hunt lasted a decade and attracted global attention but also sparked controversy after reportedly leading to the deaths of five searchers. Collins-Black, however, emphasizes that his treasure hunt prioritizes safety and inclusivity.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2r5k3sj_treasure-chest_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hes channeling that passion into a real-world quest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brain-rot-is-oxfords-2024-word-of-the-year-heres-what-it-means-7152144]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brain Rot Is Oxford's 2024 Word Of The Year. Here's What It Means]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brain-rot-is-oxfords-2024-word-of-the-year-heres-what-it-means-7152144]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:22:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Oxford University Press has declared 'brain rot' as the word of the year for 2024, summing up widespread concerns over mindless social media habits and the consumption of low-value content.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oxford University Press has declared 'brain rot' as the word of the year for 2024, summing up widespread concerns over mindless social media habits and the consumption of low-value content. More than 37,000 people participated in the public vote, choosing from a shortlist of six contenders shared by the publisher of the Oxford English Dictionary.<br />
<br />
<strong>What is 'brain rot'?</strong></p>

<p>'Brain rot' is defined as "the supposed deterioration of a person's mental or intellectual state, especially viewed as the result of overconsumption of material (now particularly online content) considered to be trivial or unchallenging."</p>

<p>According to a report in The Guardian, Oxford University Press noted that the term gained traction throughout 2024 and became synonymous with worries about the impact of excessive engagement with low-quality online content, especially on social media platforms.</p>

<p>Though it has gained new relevance in recent years, the phrase can be traced back to Henry David Thoreau's 1854 book, Walden. The expression has now come to represent a cultural critique, highlighting how today's society uses its free time in an age dominated by digital spaces.</p>

<p>"Brain rot speaks to one of the perceived dangers of virtual life, and how we are using our free time. It feels like a rightful next chapter in the cultural conversation about humanity and technology. It's not surprising that so many voters embraced the term, endorsing it as our choice this year," Casper Grathwohl, president of Oxford Languages, was quoted as saying by The Guardian.</p>

<p>Grathwohl also observed an interesting demographic shift. He said, "I also find it fascinating that the word brain rot has been adopted by gen Z and gen Alpha, those communities largely responsible for the use and creation of the digital content the term refers to."</p>

<p>The shortlist included other contenders, such as 'demure,' popularised by a social media movement that celebrated reserved behaviour during the summer, 'dynamic pricing,' which refers to the fluctuation of prices based on demand, 'lore,' signifying background information associated with people or topics, 'romantasy,' a genre that blends romance and fantasy, and 'slop,' a term for low-quality, AI-generated online content.</p>

<p>Oxford University Press factored in public input, social commentary, and analysis before the announcement was made on December 1.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Cambridge Dictionary named 'manifest' as its word of the year for 2024. The term relates to a wellness practice where individuals imagine achieving their goals to make them more attainable. This word has been searched over 130,000 times on the Cambridge Dictionary website.</p>

<p>Social media-driven trends were also reflected in other dictionary awards. Dictionary.com chose 'demure,' tied to a TikTok trend that encouraged people to act with more reservation, while Collins Dictionary selected 'brat' after Charli XCX's album of the same name gained popularity over the summer.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/31vc835o_social-media-_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cambridge Dictionary named 'manifest' as its word of the year for 2024]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-mall-plays-baby-shark-on-loop-to-turn-away-homeless-people-internet-reacts-7152143]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mall Plays 'Baby Shark' On Loop to Turn Away Homeless People. Internet Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-mall-plays-baby-shark-on-loop-to-turn-away-homeless-people-internet-reacts-7152143]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:21:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After the mall started to blast the song on loop, fewer homeless people were seen around the area.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A shopping centre in Canada has divided the internet after it was revealed that it had been playing popular children's song, <em>Baby Shark,</em> on loop, to deter homeless people from loitering on the premises, especially the fire emergency stairwell. Complexe Desjardins, a mall and office complex in downtown Montreal confirmed to Canadian website <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/montreal/montreal-mall-baby-shark-1.7396051" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>CBC </em></a>it had been playing the music for the past year owing to security issues. Mall spokesperson Jean-Benoît Turcotti said the music was installed "because we were having problems in these areas".</p>

<p>As per Mr Turcotti, since the mall started to blast the song on loop, fewer homeless people were seen around the area.</p>

<p>"Since the installation of this sound solution, we have noticed an improvement in the situation," Mr Turcotti told the publication, adding there were no plans to stop playing the song.</p>

<p>Ironically, the mall is situated near the Old Brewery Mission, the city's largest homelessness support organisation.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-searching-for-her-birth-parents-discovers-father-in-facebook-friends-list-7151512" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Woman Searching For Her Birth Parents Discovers Father In Facebook Friends List</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Internet reacts</strong></h3>

<p>As the news of the mall's unconventional action went viral, social media users chimed in with their differing viewpoints, While some sided with the mall, others called out the authorities for being cruel towards the homeless people.</p>

<p>"Actually I'm not even mad. Private property. They can do whatever they want. They can play the song through the entire mall 24/7," said one user, while another added: "It is creative. Better than dousing them with water. What other method would you use? They CAN'T live there."</p>

<p>A third added: "Unconventional but if it works then maybe why not"</p>

<p>"More Canadian citizens are homeless than illegals. So this is a war on Canadian citizens by big business. Let's see the liberal NDP say anything lmao," said one user, who was seemingly against the move.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A Montreal mall is being criticized for playing 'Baby Shark' on loop in the stairwells to discourage homeless people from loitering <a href="https://t.co/fmjtcNzeK4">pic.twitter.com/fmjtcNzeK4</a></p>
— Dexerto (@Dexerto) <a href="https://twitter.com/Dexerto/status/1862515577090081039?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Lionel Carmant, the minister for social services, reacting to the news said the use of the song to scare away the homeless was not alright.</p>

<p>"It's not humane and it's not the right way (to do it). I am here to take care of the homeless," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ledevoir.com/politique/quebec/824672/c-est-pas-humain-dit-ministre-carmant-sujet-utilisation-chanson-baby-shark" rel="noindex, nofollow">said </a>Lionel Carmant, the minister for social services.</p>

<p>Despite the criticism, Mr Carmant did not have a specific plan of action to tackle the issue. "The community needs to come together to take care of people," he said instead.</p>

<p>Notably, Desjardins Group, the company that maintains the mall, pledged £946,000 (Rs 10.1 crore) for homelessness initiatives in Montreal in 2023.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dkdjflog_shopping-mall_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Complexe Desjardins has started playing 'Baby Shark' on loop (Representative picture)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-removes-general-in-charge-of-syrian-ops-amid-violent-clashes-in-aleppo-7152099]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Removes General In-Charge Of Syrian Ops Amid Violent Clashes In Aleppo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-removes-general-in-charge-of-syrian-ops-amid-violent-clashes-in-aleppo-7152099]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:14:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian war bloggers reported on Sunday that Moscow has dismissed Sergei Kisel, the general in charge of its forces in Syria, after insurgents swept into the city of Aleppo in the biggest challenge to President Bashar al-Assad in years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian war bloggers reported on Sunday that Moscow has dismissed Sergei Kisel, the general in charge of its forces in Syria, after insurgents swept into the city of Aleppo in the biggest challenge to President Bashar al-Assad in years.</p>

<p>Russia is a key Assad ally. The removal of Kisel, 53, was reported by the Rybar Telegram channel, which is close to the Russian defence ministry, and by the Voenny Osvedomitel (Military Informant) blog.</p>

<p>Reuters has requested comment from the Russian defence ministry. Since the start of the Ukraine war, Russia has made a number of military reshuffles that were not publicly announced.</p>

<p>Unconfirmed reports said Kisel was being replaced by Colonel General Alexander Chaiko.</p>

<p>The military blogs were scathing about the performance of Kisel, who previously commanded Russia's 1st Guards Tank Army in the Kharkiv region of Ukraine, where Moscow's forces were driven back in a lightning counter-attack by Ukrainian troops in late 2022.</p>

<p>"Apparently he was supposed to reveal his hidden talents in Syria, but something got in the way again," Voenny Osvedomitel wrote.</p>

<p>Rybar commented: "The approach needs to change. The Syrian sandbox has long been a place for laundering the reputations of unsuccessful generals who turned out to be incompetent in the zone of the special military operation" - Russia's term for the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Rybar speculated that Russia might even turn to Sergei Surovikin, a general who earned the nickname "General Armageddon" for his ruthlessness in Syria and was briefly in charge of the Ukrainian war effort. Surovikin was demoted last year, when unconfirmed reports said he had been investigated for possible complicity in a mutiny by Russia's Wagner mercenary group.</p>

<p>The insurgent advance in Syria was the first since March 2020 when Russia and Turkey, which supports the rebels, agreed to a ceasefire that led to the halting of military action in northwest Syria.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the Syrian army said it had recaptured several towns that had been overrun by rebels in recent days. The insurgents are a coalition of Turkish-backed mainstream secular armed groups, along with Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, an Islamist group that is the opposition's most formidable military force.</p>

<p>Aleppo had been held by the government since a 2016 victory there, one of the war's major turning points, when Russian-backed Syrian forces besieged and laid waste to rebel-held eastern areas of what had been the country's largest city.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/h7rkqt0o_russia_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia is a key Assad ally.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-plastic-eating-worm-could-help-reduce-pollution-faster-more-efficiently-7151959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Plastic-Eating Worms Could Be The Solution To Faster Reduction Of Pollution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-plastic-eating-worm-could-help-reduce-pollution-faster-more-efficiently-7151959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:47:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A plastic-eating insect may help solve the trash problem that has choked the Earth for a long time, scientists have concluded in a new study.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A plastic-eating insect may help solve the trash problem that has choked the Earth for a long time, scientists have concluded in a new study. The larvae of the lesser-eating Kenyan mealworm can digest plastic, making it the only insect species native to Africa capable of doing it, The New York Post reported. The study was published in the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-72201-9" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Nature Journal</a>.</p>

<p>"By studying these natural 'plastic-eaters,' we hope to create new tools that help get rid of plastic waste faster and more efficiently," Fathiya Khamis, a senior scientist at the International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology and the person behind the study, said.</p>

<p>Mr Khamis and his team found the worm is the pupae of an Alphitobius darkling beetle. It possesses enzymes which can break down polystyrene, a major ingredient in styrofoam. It runs rampant in aquatic ecosystems and has a long durability.</p>

<p>The mealworm might provide an efficient and eco-friendly alternative to the traditional recycling methods that are usually expensive and can paradoxically increase pollution.</p>

<p>To test the capabilities of the worm, the researchers held a month-long trial and showcased their gut bacteria.</p>

<p>During the study period, the worms were given plastic polystyrene and bran -- a nutrient-dense food.</p>

<p>The results showed the worms consumed polystyrene more efficiently when given with bran, compared with the polystyrene-only diet. They managed to break down 11.7% of the total polymer.</p>

<p>They also survive at a higher rate, indicating the importance of a nutritious diet.</p>

<p>Khamis said the worms that broke down polymer had higher levels of certain bacteria, the enzymes of which they now look forward to isolating to "create microbial solutions that will address plastic waste on a larger scale".</p>

<p>"Instead of releasing a huge number of these insects into trash sites (which is not practical), we can use the microbes and enzymes they produce in factories, landfills, and cleanup sites," Khamis added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nlebjg9g_worms_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During the study period, the worms were given plastic polystyrene and bran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-joe-bidens-pardon-for-son-hunter-miscarriage-of-justice-7151849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Miscarriage Of Justice": Donald Trump Slams Joe Biden For Pardoning Son]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-joe-bidens-pardon-for-son-hunter-miscarriage-of-justice-7151849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:25:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Outgoing US President Joe Biden has pardoned his son Hunter Biden, who had been convicted on charges related to gun crimes and tax violations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has responded to outgoing US President Joe Biden's decision to pardon his son Hunter Biden who had been convicted on charges related to gun crimes and tax violations, calling it a "miscarriage of Justice".</p>

<p>In a post on Truth Social, Trump said, "Does the Pardon given by Joe to Hunter include the J-6 Hostages, who have now been imprisoned for years? Such an abuse and miscarriage of Justice!"</p>

<p>The J6 hostages is a reference to those people imprisoned for their role in the January 6, 2021 riots on Capitol Hill, Trump and his supporters have called the imprisoned people hostages claiming they were acting peacefully and patriotically.</p>

<p>It has been speculated that once Donald Trump takes over as President he will issue a pardon for those who are imprisoned for their role in the siege of Capitol Hill on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-pardons-son-hunter-in-2-criminal-cases-hope-americans-will-understand-7151191#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> on Sunday signed a pardon for his son, Hunter Biden, who had been convicted on charges related to gun crimes and tax violations. The pardon ensures that Hunter Biden will not face sentencing for these offences and removes the possibility of prison time.</p>

<p>In a statement, President Biden addressed the charges against his son, arguing that individuals in similar situations--such as those with tax payment issues due to addiction--typically receive non-criminal resolutions.</p>

<p>He contended that Hunter's case was treated differently, leading to felony charges despite the absence of aggravating factors. Biden also stressed his commitment to not interfere with the Justice Department's decision-making, despite his belief that his son had been "selectively and unfairly prosecuted."</p>

<p>"Today, I signed a pardon for my son Hunter. From the day I took office, I said I would not interfere with the Justice Department's decision-making, and I kept my word even as I have watched my son being selectively and unfairly prosecuted. Without aggravating factors like use in a crime, multiple purchases, or buying a weapon as a straw purchaser, people are almost never brought to trial on felony charges solely for how they filled out a gun form. Those who were late paying their taxes because of serious addictions but paid them back subsequently with interest and penalties are typically given non-criminal resolutions. It is clear that Hunter was treated differently," the statement read.</p>

<p>Biden explained that the charges against his son were initiated after political opponents in Congress pushed for the case to be brought forward. He added that a plea deal, which had been negotiated with the Department of Justice, unravelled in court due to political pressure.</p>

<p>"The charges in his cases came about only after several of my political opponents in Congress instigated them to attack me and oppose my election. Then, a carefully negotiated plea deal, agreed to by the Department of Justice, unravelled in the courtroom--with a number of my political opponents in Congress taking credit for bringing political pressure on the process. Had the plea deal held, it would have been a fair, reasonable resolution of Hunter's cases," the statement added.</p>

<p>The outgoing President maintained that the charges were politically motivated, asserting that Hunter was targeted because of his relationship with him. Biden concluded his statement by expressing his belief that, while he had faith in the justice system, the legal process had been influenced by politics, leading to a "miscarriage of justice."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ra93b5e_donald-trump-joe-biden-hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kash-patel-fbi-chief-in-donald-trump-2-0-joins-x-elon-musk-reacts-7151750]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-American Kash Patel, FBI Chief In Trump 2.0, Joins X, Elon Musk Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kash-patel-fbi-chief-in-donald-trump-2-0-joins-x-elon-musk-reacts-7151750]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:02:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-American Kashyap "Kash" Patel has been nominated as the FBI director by US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-American Kashyap "Kash" Patel, who has been nominated as the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) director by US President-elect Donald Trump, on Sunday joined social media platform X, which was previously known as Twitter.</p>

<p>"Hello X," he said in his first post, which has so far received more than seven million views and 24,000 comments.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hello <a href="https://twitter.com/X?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@X</a></p>
— Kash Patel (@Kash_Patel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Kash_Patel/status/1863285220532695481?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Billionaire and X owner Elon Musk, who has been named Trump's government efficiency chief in the incoming US administration, also congratulated Patel on being nominated to run the FBI.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Congratulations on being nominated to run the <a href="https://twitter.com/FBI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FBI</a>!</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1863298345781133439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-indian-american-kash-patel-donald-trumps-pick-to-head-fbi-7144825" target="_blank">Kash Patel</a>, a former Republican House staffer and a fierce critic of the FBI, was followed by more than three lakh people within hours of joining the social media platform.</p>

<p>He was born in New York in 1980 to parents of Gujarati descent who emigrated from East Africa. Patel completed his undergraduate studies at the University of Richmond before returning to New York to earn his law degree and a certificate in International Law from the University College London Faculty of Laws in the United Kingdom.</p>

<p>After earning his law degree, the 44-year-old worked as a public defender in Florida, representing clients in state and federal courts. He later joined the Department of Justice as a prosecutor, handling high-profile international terrorism cases across East Africa and the United States.</p>

<p>He frequently appeared on the campaign trail to rally support for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kashyap-kash-patel-indian-american-kash-patel-nominated-as-fbi-director-by-donald-trump-7144748" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> in his presidential bid against Democrat Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>During Trump's first term, he advised both the director of national intelligence and the defense secretary.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gtd3c9io_kashyap-patel_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kash Patel has so far been followed by more than three lakh people on X]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ukraine-wars-regional-tensions-boosting-arms-sales-report-7151549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza, Ukraine Wars, Regional Tensions Boosting Arms Sales: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ukraine-wars-regional-tensions-boosting-arms-sales-report-7151549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:13:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sales by major arms makers were boosted last year by wars in Ukraine and Gaza and tensions in Asia, with marked increases for manufacturers based in Russia and the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sales by major arms makers were boosted last year by wars in Ukraine and Gaza and tensions in Asia, with marked increases for manufacturers based in Russia and the Middle East, a report said Monday.</p>

<p>Sales of arms and military services by the world's 100 largest arms companies totalled $632 billion in 2023, up 4.2 percent, according to a report by the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI).</p>

<p>Revenues had dipped in 2022 as global weapons makers struggled to meet the increase in demand, but many of them managed to increase production last year, the authors of the report noted.</p>

<p>In a sign of this surge in demand, all 100 companies tracked achieved sales in excess of $1 billion last year for the first time.</p>

<p>"There was a marked rise in arms revenues in 2023, and this is likely to continue in 2024," Lorenzo Scarazzato, a researcher with the SIPRI Military Expenditure and Arms Production, said in a statement.</p>

<p>Sales from the world's top 100 arms companies "still did not fully reflect the scale of demand, and many companies have launched recruitment drives, suggesting they are optimistic about future sales," Scarazzato added.</p>

<p>Smaller producers have been more effective in meeting the demand linked to the wars in Gaza and Ukraine, growing tensions in East Asia and rearmament programmes in other regions, the institute said.</p>

<p>"A lot of them specialise in either a component of something or build systems that require one set of supply chains," allowing them to react more quickly, Nan Tian, Director of SIPRI's Military Expenditure and Arms Production Programme, told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the leading producers, US companies recorded a 2.5 percent increase in their sales last year and still account for half the world's arms revenues, with 41 US weapons producers in the world's top 100.</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin and RTX (formerly Raytheon Technologies), the world's two largest arms makers, on the other hand, reported a fall in revenue of 1.6 percent and 1.3 percent respectively.</p>

<p>Such behemoths "often depend on complex, multi-tiered supply chains, which made them vulnerable to lingering supply chain challenges in 2023," Tian said.</p>

<h3><strong>Russia's Rostec surges</strong></h3>

<p>In Europe, home to 27 of the top 100, arms makers on average saw an increase of just 0.2 percent.</p>

<p>But European groups manufacturing complex weapons systems were still in the process of honouring old contracts last year, so the revenues do not reflect the influx of orders since then.</p>

<p>"At the same time, a number of other European producers saw their arms revenues grow substantially, driven by demand linked to the war in Ukraine, particularly for ammunition, artillery and air defence and land systems," SIPRI noted.</p>

<p>The figures for Russia, though incomplete, give a clear signal of an economy increasingly geared toward war.</p>

<p>Sales by the two Russian groups in the ranking rose by 40 percent, mainly thanks to a 49 percent increase in sales for state-owned conglomerate Rostec, according to the report.</p>

<p>Manufacturers in the Middle East were buoyed by the war in Ukraine and by the first months of the Israeli offensive in Gaza after Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack -- and saw on average an 18 percent lift in sales.</p>

<p>The three Israeli manufacturers in the ranking posted record sales of $13.6 billion, up 15 percent from the year before, while the three groups based in Turkey, such as drone producer Baykar, saw their sales jump by 24 percent -- boosted by Ukraine and Turkey's investments in its defence.</p>

<p>In Asia, the trend toward rearmament was particularly evident in the growth in sales by the four South Korean manufacturers, with revenues rising 39 percent on average, and five Japanese firms that saw an average increase of 35 percent.</p>

<p>The nine Chinese producers meanwhile saw revenue increase by only 0.7 percent "amid a slowing economy," but their sales still totalled $103 billion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-07/us-arms-sales_650x400_81468433101.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smaller producers have been effective in meeting the demand linked to the wars. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>