<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:06:40 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-indian-origin-ashwin-ramaswami-the-gen-z-democrat-taking-on-georgia-senator-6883618]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Ashwin Ramaswami, Gen Z Democrat Up Against Donald Trump's Ally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-indian-origin-ashwin-ramaswami-the-gen-z-democrat-taking-on-georgia-senator-6883618]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 11:41:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On November 5, Americans will cast their votes not only for the presidency but also for 34 Senate seats, all 435 House seats, 11 governorships and thousands of state legislative positions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On November 5, Americans will cast their votes not only for the presidency but also for 34 Senate seats, all 435 House seats, 11 governorships and thousands of state legislative positions. Among the new contenders is Ashwin Ramaswami, a young Indian American Democrat challenging Republican Senator Shawn Still in Georgia's Senate District 48, a traditionally conservative seat.</p>

<p><strong>Who is Ashwin Ramaswami?</strong></p>

<ol>
	<li aria-level="1">Ashwin Ramaswami was born to Indian immigrant parents from Tamil Nadu and grew up in Johns Creek. He is running for the Georgia State Senate in District 48, and just meets the minimum age requirement of 25, turning that age in May 2024.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Ashwin Ramaswami studied Computer Science at Stanford University and then pursued a law degree at Georgetown University, as per his election <a href="https://ashwinforgeorgia.com/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">campaign website</a>.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">He has a strong background in cybersecurity, having <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashwin-r/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">worked with CISA</a>, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, where he helped secure local election systems from cyberattacks, and Schmidt Futures, where he conducted research on securing open-source software, which contributed to a bill in Congress. He decided to quit his job at CISA after three years to run for office after realising that the greater threat to democracy lies not just in cyberattacks but in political misinformation surrounding election integrity, reported <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/amp/rcna144294 " rel="nofollow,noindex">NBC News</a>.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">During his studies, he taught classes on Hindu philosophy and raised $100,000 for Dharmic programmes at Georgetown, supporting students of various faiths, including Hindu, Sikh, Jain and Buddhist.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Ashwin Ramaswami's campaign promises election security and integrity, positioning him against Shawn Still's alleged 2020 election-related activities. Shawn Still was one of the fake electors who participated in the Donald Trump fake electors plot, which aimed to award Georgia's electoral votes to Donald Trump despite him losing the state to Joe Biden. Mr Ramaswami's campaign has raised more than $700,000 in funding, which is considered a significant amount for a first-time candidate.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/eassa52o_ashwin-ramaswami-facebook-_625x300_19_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ashwin Ramaswami studied Computer Science at Stanford University.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-trami-forces-million-philippines-to-flee-homes-death-count-at-100-6883816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Storm Trami Forces Million Philippines To Flee Homes, Death Count At 100]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-trami-forces-million-philippines-to-flee-homes-death-count-at-100-6883816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 11:29:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rescuers in the Philippines were diving into a lake and scouring isolated villages on Sunday to locate dozens of missing people as the death count from Tropical Storm Trami hit 100.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rescuers in the Philippines were diving into a lake and scouring isolated villages on Sunday to locate dozens of missing people as the death count from Tropical Storm Trami hit 100.</p>

<p>Trami, which rammed into the Philippines on October 24, was among the deadliest storms to hit the Southeast Asian country this year.</p>

<p>According to the national disaster agency, it forced more than half a million people to flee their homes and at least 36 people remain missing.</p>

<p>Police in the hardest-hit Bicol region have recorded 38 deaths, most due to drowning.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are still receiving many calls and we are trying to save as many people as we can," Bicol regional police director Andre Dizon told AFP.</p>

<p>"Hopefully, there will be no more deaths."</p>

<p>Dizon added that "many residents" in the region's Camarines Sur province are still trapped on roofs and the upper floors of their homes. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The death count in Batangas, south of Manila, has risen to 55, provincial police chief Jacinto Malinao told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Two were reported dead in separate incidents of electrocution and drowning in Cavite province, police said.</p>

<p>Five more bodies were recovered in other provinces, bringing the total to 100, according to an AFP tally based on official police and disaster agency sources.</p>

<p>"A higher death toll is possible in the coming days since rescuers can now reach previously isolated places," Edgar Posadas of the Civil Defence Office told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The police, coast guards and a Marines diving team were searching on Sunday for a family of seven at Taal Lake in Batangas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The waters from the mountains hit their home in Balete town, causing it to be swept away with them possibly inside," Malinao, the provincial police chief, said.</p>

<p>Most of the deaths in Batangas have been attributed to rain-induced landslides.&nbsp;</p>

<p>More than 20 bodies were pulled from heaps of mud, boulders and fallen trees, while police said at least another 20 people in the province are still missing.</p>

<p>"We will continue searching until all bodies are retrieved," Malinao said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The national disaster agency said Sunday that about 560,000 people had been displaced by floods, which submerged hundreds of villages in swaths of the northern Philippines.</p>

<p>About 20 big storms and typhoons hit the archipelago nation or its surrounding waters each year, damaging homes and infrastructure and killing dozens of people.</p>

<p>A recent study showed that storms in the Asia-Pacific region are increasingly forming closer to coastlines, intensifying more rapidly and lasting longer over land due to climate change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1iuhpjng_storm-trami_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Storm Trami rammed into the Philippines on October 24.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-year-old-nima-rinji-sherpa-conquered-worlds-14-highest-peaks-this-is-his-next-challenge-6883435]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[18-Year-Old Conquered World's 14 Highest Peaks. This Is His Next challenge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-year-old-nima-rinji-sherpa-conquered-worlds-14-highest-peaks-this-is-his-next-challenge-6883435]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 11:22:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nima Rinji Sherpa became the youngest climber to reach all 14 of the world’s tallest mountains, known as the “eight-thousanders.”]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At just 18 years old, Nepal's Nima Rinji Sherpa has achieved a milestone few have accomplished, becoming the youngest climber to reach all 14 of the world's tallest mountains, known as the "eight-thousanders." Mr Rinji's journey culminated on October 9 with the summit of Shishapangma, Nepal's 8,027-metre peak, alongside climbing partner Pasang Nurbu Sherpa.</p>

<p>Reflecting on his latest feat, Mr Rinji described reaching the summit as "pure joy." His passion, he said, is inspired by his family, a lineage of accomplished mountaineers, including his father, Tashi Lakpa Sherpa, and uncle, Mingma Sherpa, both renowned in Nepal's climbing community.</p>

<p>"My uncles and my father... came from a very small village. To even dream about being this successful, for them it was really hard," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/26/travel/nima-rinji-sherpa-mountaineering-legacy-intl-hnk/index.html">CNN</a>. "I have the privilege that they didn't have."</p>

<p>Mr Rinji's next goal is equally daring: a winter ascent of Manaslu without supplemental oxygen or fixed ropes, in collaboration with Italian climber Simone Moro. "That means we're climbing an 8,000-metre mountain in winter... there is no support for us. So, it's like pure human endurance," he said. "It has never been done in the history of mountaineering."</p>

<p>This recent accomplishment did not attract major sponsors; he relied on his father's 14 Peaks Expedition for funding. Despite the lack of support, he remains hopeful about inspiring young Sherpa climbers. "Hopefully I become the face of a big brand," he said, adding that he hopes to redefine the perception of Sherpa climbers as "support staff" only.</p>

<p>Over the past two years, Mr Rinji has tackled Everest, K2, and five peaks in less than five weeks. Among his climbs, Annapurna remains a personal favourite. "For a teenager of 17 years to do something without using oxygen, you know, normally it's not recommended," he said, recalling the challenges he faced.</p>

<p>Summiting the eight-thousanders requires navigating the perilous "death zone," where oxygen levels are critically low and temperatures are extreme. Nima Rinji noted the harsh reality of life at such altitudes: "Your body starts to shut down... Maybe I like suffering," he joked.</p>

<p>Mr Rinji envisions a sustainable future for Nepal's mountaineering industry and hopes his achievements will inspire a new generation of Nepali climbers. "Hopefully, the younger generation... we will try to mobilise this industry and make it more sustainable for the upcoming generations," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/t2h7h7co_sherpa_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Rinji's next goal is equally daring- winter ascent of Manaslu without supplemental oxygen, fixed ropes]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-iran-hezbollah-operative-behind-1992-1994-bombings-in-argentina-identified-6883615]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Operative Behind 1992, 1994 Bombings In Argentina Identified]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-iran-hezbollah-operative-behind-1992-1994-bombings-in-argentina-identified-6883615]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 10:45:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Long known to law enforcement as a shadowy figure operating under numerous aliases, Hussein Ahmad Karaki has evaded capture for decades, thanks in part to an extensive network and forged documentation allegedly supplied by Venezuela.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 1992, the Israeli embassy in Argentina's capital Buenos Aires was bombed, killing 29 and injuring over 240. Two years later, a Jewish community centre in the capital was bombed, killing 86 and injuring over 300. Now over three decades later, the alleged mastermind behind the attacks has been identified as Hussein Ahmad Karaki, a notorious Hezbollah operative.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Long known to law enforcement as a shadowy figure operating under numerous aliases, Karaki has evaded capture for decades, thanks in part to an extensive network and forged documentation allegedly supplied by Venezuela.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Saturday, Argentina's Defence Minister Patricia Bullrich shared new details about Karaki's alleged role as the head of Hezbollah operations in Latin America. According to Ms Bullrich, Karaki was not only responsible for the planning and execution of the two infamous Argentine bombings but also remains active in the region, with evidence linking him to a series of thwarted terrorist attempts across Peru, Bolivia, and Brazil.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="es">QUEREMOS QUE EL PUEBLO ARGENTINO SEPA QUIÉN ESTUVO DETRÁS DE LOS ATENTADOS A LA EMBAJADA DE ISRAEL Y LA AMIA: NO PERMITIREMOS QUE CON SU RED VUELVA A GOLPEAR<br />
<br />
Hoy le ponemos nombre, apellido y cara al cerebro y jefe de Hezbollah en América Latina: Hussein Ahmad Karaki. Uno de los… <a href="https://t.co/WhPVctgbue">pic.twitter.com/WhPVctgbue</a></p>
— Patricia Bullrich (@PatoBullrich) <a href="https://twitter.com/PatoBullrich/status/1849919369158996055?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 25, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Karaki was responsible for overseeing the logistics behind the 1992 and 1994 attacks in Argentina, Ms Bullrich said, adding that he was operating under the alias "David Assi." "We want the Argentine people to know the identity of the person responsible for these heinous acts," she stated. Bullrich further described Karaki as a "ghost," one who has effectively evaded detection for years, thanks to sophisticated tactics.</p>

<p>Ms Bullrich alleged Hezbollah's growing relationship with Brazilian cartels, notably Primeiro Comando da Capital (PCC) and Comando Vermelho, both known for controlling vast swathes of Brazil's drug trade.</p>

<p>According to Ms Bullrich, Hezbollah has transformed these cartels into hybrid narco-terrorist entities, with PCC's illicit earnings reportedly funnelled to fund Hezbollah's arsenal and attacks against Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The relationship reportedly extends to a vast drug-smuggling operation: PCC drug boats cross the mid-Atlantic, where they rendezvous with vessels linked to the Calabrian or Balkan mafia. South American cocaine is traded for Lebanese hashish, and the boats return to their respective ports to complete the cycle.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The attacks on the Israeli Embassy and the Jewish community centre have long been suspected of having Iranian backing. Recent rulings by Argentina's judiciary further implicate Iran's role in planning, financing, and supporting Hezbollah's operations in Argentina.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f545pvh8_karaki_625x300_27_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Karaki was responsible for overseeing the logistics behind the 1992 and 1994 attacks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/women-running-businesses-to-film-music-new-saudi-is-a-surprise-6883569]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Women-Led Businesses To Social Events, The Surprise That Is New Saudi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/women-running-businesses-to-film-music-new-saudi-is-a-surprise-6883569]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 10:38:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Saudi Arabia with strict gender segregation, tough Islamic laws, and dress codes, no longer exists. The country's women are now truly in the drivers seat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-12/ck3em2f8_saudi-arabia-restaurant-reuters_625x300_09_December_19.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Saudi Arabia is changing. You have to see it to believe it. The Saudi Arabia with strict gender segregation, tough Islamic laws, and dress codes, no longer exists. It's a new country that is open, just, welcoming and rising. With Crown Prince Mohammad Bin Salman's Vision 2023 as its compass, the kingdom is making great strides and is dropping the shackles of the past, very fast. Roam around Riyadh, the capital, and you see it buzzing with young and aspirational Saudis making the most of the newfound freedoms and opportunities. According to the 2022 census, 63% of Saudis are under the age of 30. And the regime's policy changes are guided with this key statistic in mind. The biggest beneficiaries of the new openness are the Saudi women, who never had it so good.</p>

<h2><strong>Women-Led Transformation</strong></h2>

<p>The Kingdom's inclusive Vision 2030 aims to diversify and strengthen the nation's economy. According to a World Bank report, Saudi Arabia is now ranked at the top in terms of economic and social progress for women out of 190 economies. The country's women are now truly in the driver's seat. The lifting of restrictions on their movement and choices has meant that Saudi women are steering the social, cultural and economic transformation of their country. Till a few years ago, they had to look to their fathers, husbands and brothers for even the basics like permission to travel or work.</p>

<p>With Vision 2030, female workforce participation has gone up to nearly 40% now compared to about 15% a few years ago. This progress is evident in the increasing number of women receiving advanced degrees, enrolling in STEM fields, and owning 40% of small and medium-sized startups. Right from the moment you land in Riyadh, you see women taking up key jobs. From immigration counters to shopping malls to government offices, Saudi women are everywhere. I saw women making presentations at key government events, doing camera work, running stalls at local markets. The presence of women in the workforce has also meant increased intermingling of genders and rewriting of many social norms and gender behaviours.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Saudi For All</strong></h2>

<p>A big focus of Vision 2030 is also the cultural and social integration of all those living and working in Saudi Arabia. The Media Ministry's Global Harmony project is aimed at enhancing understanding and collaborations between diverse groups that call Saudi home. According to the Saudi Deputy Minister of Media, Dr Khaled Bin Abdulqader al Ghamdi, the Global Harmony project aims to make expats feel more at home. But more than that, it aspires to make local Saudis understand better the various communities that live among them. So, during the Riyadh Season, which starts in September and continues till February-March, you see a host of public cultural and social events to bring communities together. &nbsp;It's a true celebration and appreciation of diversity.</p>

<h2><strong>Indians Are Special And Loved</strong></h2>

<p>Even among the expats, special attention is on Indians, who are the largest expat group in Saudi Arabia. At present, 2.6 million Indians live in the Kingdom, working in the domestic sector as well as private jobs, and running both start-ups as well as big companies. Recognising the role of India, Dr Khaled calls the community “an integral part of the Saudi story”. This year, the Media Ministry dedicated the Suwaidi Park festival exclusively to India. The 10-day festival saw a celebration of Indian culture, food, music and art. People from all communities streamed into the vast Suwaidi Park to savour a slice of India. The Global Harmony project attempts to present Saudi as an inclusive and harmonious society where people from all backgrounds live and celebrate their own cultures, traditions and festivals. And, it's not some civil society gig. It's a government policy initiative with clear objectives and plans. That makes it an attempt worth emulating for many countries that are facing social fissures due to their diversity.</p>

<h2><strong>Looking Back To The Future</strong></h2>

<p>As Saudi strides into modernity, it is also conscious of its history and heritage. It's encouraging studies and excavations at heritage sites, such as at al Ula, and is promoting its pre-Islamic history too. Nouf Marwaai, a yoga instructor and also a consultant with the Saudi government, gave us a presentation on the historical and social similarities between India and Saudi Arabia. In her talk, she went back to 6000 BCE to trace the Almagar Civilisation.</p>

<p>Clearly, the new Saudi Arabia projects itself as an old civilisation, and not just as a society defined by the advent of Islam 1,400 years ago. That is now portrayed as only an important event, not the sole marker of the civilisational identity. The Kingdom is also promoting its historical sites. The Diriyah town, just outside Riyadh, is one such heritage site that has a UNESCO tag. It was the home of the Saudi royal family and also served as the capital of the Emirate of Diriyah under the first Saudi dynasty from 1744 to 1818. Today, Diriyah is one of the foremost cultural hubs and the centre of many sports and adventure activities in the Kingdom. Even so, its historical character has been maintained all along. On the one hand, you have mega infrastructural projects, new businesses and modern wave sweeping Saudi, and on the other, there is a renewed focus on its over 1,400-year-old history.</p>

<h2><strong>Music Connects</strong></h2>

<p>Coming back to the India connect: wherever there are Indians, there is music. Indian film music has been a great brand ambassador and unifier across the world. Saudi Arabia is no different. My local support, Abdulwahab al Ghamdi, a young, peppy guy in his late 20s, played Hindi songs for me in the car while we drove around Riyadh. He told me that he and his friends dance to Punjabi numbers at their parties. And how he loved Shah Rukh Khan and Indian film music. He also showed me a video of a Saudi artist singing a popular Hindi film song at a Saudi talent show.</p>

<p>The new Saudi Arabia is truly a surprise, and a pleasant one.</p>

<p><em>[Mohd Asim is a Senior Editor with NDTV 24X7. He visited Saudi Arabia from October 15 to October 20 on the invite of the Ministry Of Media]</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-12/ck3em2f8_saudi-arabia-restaurant-reuters_625x300_09_December_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-elections-litmus-test-for-japans-shigeru-ishiba-as-country-votes-in-general-elections-6883371]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Litmus Test For Japan's Ishiba As Country Votes In General Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-elections-litmus-test-for-japans-shigeru-ishiba-as-country-votes-in-general-elections-6883371]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 09:53:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan voted on Sunday in its tightest election in years, with new Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba and his juggernaut Liberal Democratic Party facing potentially their worst result since 2009.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan voted on Sunday in its tightest election in years, with new Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba and his juggernaut Liberal Democratic Party facing potentially their worst result since 2009.</p>

<p>Opinion surveys suggest the conservative LDP and its junior coalition partner risk falling short of a majority, a result that could deal a knockout blow to Ishiba.</p>

<p>The 67-year-old former defence minister took office and called a snap election after being narrowly selected last month to lead the LDP, which has governed Japan for almost all of the past seven decades.</p>

<p>But voters in the world's fourth-largest economy have been rankled by rising prices and the fallout from a party slush fund scandal that helped sink previous premier Fumio Kishida.</p>

<p>"I made my decision first and foremost by looking at their economic policies and measures to ease inflation," Tokyo voter Yoshihiro Uchida, 48, told AFP on Sunday. "I voted for people who are likely to make our lives better."</p>

<p>Ishiba has pledged to revitalise depressed rural regions and to address the "quiet emergency" of Japan's falling population through family-friendly measures such as flexible working hours.</p>

<p>But he has rowed back his position on issues including allowing married couples to take separate surnames. He also named only two women ministers in his cabinet.</p>

<p>The self-confessed security policy "geek" has backed the creation of a regional military alliance along the lines of NATO to counter China, although he has cautioned it would "not happen overnight".</p>

<p>Several polls by Japanese media have found that the LDP and its coalition partner Komeito might struggle to get the 233 lower house seats needed for a majority.</p>

<p>Ishiba has set this threshold as his objective, and missing it would undermine his position in the LDP and mean finding other coalition partners or leading a minority government.</p>

<p>"We want to start afresh as a fair, just and sincere party, and seek your mandate," Ishiba said at a rally on Saturday.</p>

<h3><strong>'Alternative' to LDP</strong></h3>

<p>Local media speculated that Ishiba could potentially even resign immediately to take responsibility, becoming Japan's shortest-serving prime minister in the post-war period.</p>

<p>The current record is held by Naruhiko Higashikuni who served for 54 days -- four days more than British leader Liz Truss in 2022 -- just after Japan's 1945 defeat in World War II.</p>

<p>In many districts, LDP candidates are neck-and-neck with those from the Constitutional Democratic Party (CDP), the second-biggest in parliament, led by popular former prime minister Yoshihiko Noda.</p>

<p>"The LDP's politics is all about quickly implementing policies for those who give them loads of cash," 67-year-old Noda told his supporters on Saturday.</p>

<p>"But those in vulnerable positions... have been ignored," he added, accusing the government of offering insufficient support for survivors of an earthquake in central Japan.</p>

<p>Noda's stance "is sort of similar to the LDP's. He is basically a conservative," Masato Kamikubo, a political scientist at Ritsumeikan University, told AFP.</p>

<p>"The CDP or Noda can be an alternative to the LDP. Many voters think so," Kamikubo said.</p>

<p>Ishiba has promised not to actively support the candidates running in the election despite being caught up in the funding scandal.</p>

<p>"I want to focus on young candidates rather than those who have had a long career, because they may bring something different," said a 63-year-old voter who gave her surname as Taniyama, adding she had "made my decision by elimination".</p>

<p>Mitsuyuki Ikezoe, 86, said he had voted for the LDP because he was "worried North Korea or Russia may invade Hokkaido" in northern Japan.</p>

<p>But "Ishiba may be treated dismissively by the United States because he is new", and if Donald Trump becomes president again, "he will not give Ishiba the time of day," Ikezoe said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/cs56gkpo_shigeru-ishiba_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polls found that LDP and its coalition partner Komeito might struggle to get the 233 lower house seats.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-year-old-plays-dead-to-escape-after-brother-allegedly-kills-5-family-members-6883293]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[11-Year-Old Plays Dead To Escape Brother's Shooting Spree That Killed Five]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-year-old-plays-dead-to-escape-after-brother-allegedly-kills-5-family-members-6883293]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 09:39:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shot in her hand and neck as her brother went on a shooting spree, an 11-year-old girl in Washington escape death by playing dead as he inspected the bodies of their family members.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shot in her hand and neck as her brother went on a shooting spree, an 11-year-old girl in Washington escape death by playing dead as he inspected the bodies of their family members.</p>

<p>The mass shooting left five members of a Washington state family dead early Monday morning.</p>

<p>The 15-year-old brother, charged with multiple counts of murder and attempted murder, allegedly targeted their family in a sequence of violent events. According to the girl's testimony, she woke up to gunshots and discovered a nightmarish scene. She saw her father&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-year-old-charged-with-murder-of-parents-3-siblings-at-2-million-us-home-6868770">Mark Humiston</a>&nbsp;and her nine-year-old brother bloody and lifeless in the hallway. Her seven-year-old sister, who walked out of their shared bedroom, was shot moments later, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/25/us/fall-city-washington-shooting-murders/index.html " rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>Despite her injuries, the girl told investigators she recognised both the shooter – her older brother – and the weapon, a silver Glock handgun that belonged to their father. Court documents said that the girl, wounded in her neck and hand, pretended to be dead as her brother examined the bodies. When he eventually left the room, she escaped through a fire window and ran to a nearby house, where neighbours dialled 911 shortly after 5 am.</p>

<p>Minutes earlier, the 15-year-old had made his own 911 call, claiming he was hiding in a bathroom and alleging his 13-year-old brother had committed the shooting before taking his own life. He suggested that his younger brother's recent trouble over online content might have driven the incident.</p>

<p>Prosecutors are pushing to transfer the case to adult court, where he could face a life sentence if convicted. His attorney, Amy Parker, reminded the public that “these are not proven facts, merely allegations,” noting, “the law presumes our client is innocent of these charges.”</p>

<p>Court documents reveal that investigators believe the accused “systematically” killed his parents, two brothers and sister, then staged the crime scene before first responders arrived. The 11-year-old survivor reportedly indicated that he was the only sibling who knew the lockbox combination for their father's firearm.</p>

<p>Following medical treatment, the girl has been discharged and is now in the care of a family member, while her brother remains in custody under a court order, barring him from contacting his surviving sister.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-03/cjjrs798_us-shooting_625x300_01_March_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-israeli-strikes-hit-irans-missile-fuel-mixing-facilities-shows-satellite-photos-report-6883255]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Airstrikes In Iran Hit Its Missile Fuel-Mixing Facilities: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-israeli-strikes-hit-irans-missile-fuel-mixing-facilities-shows-satellite-photos-report-6883255]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 09:29:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Commercial satellite imagery showed that Israeli airstrikes hit buildings during an attack on Saturday that Iran used for mixing solid fuel for ballistic missiles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Commercial satellite imagery showed that Israeli airstrikes hit buildings during an attack on Saturday that Iran used for mixing solid fuel for ballistic missiles, according to separate assessments by two American researchers.</p>

<p>The judgments were reached by David Albright, a former UN weapons inspector who heads the Institute for Science and International Security research group, and Decker Eveleth, an associate research analyst at CNA, a Washington think tank.</p>

<p>They told Reuters separately that Israel struck Parchin, a massive military complex near Tehran. Israel also hit Khojir, according to Eveleth, a sprawling missile production site near Tehran.</p>

<p>Reuters reported in July that Khojir was undergoing massive expansion.</p>

<p>Eveleth said the Israeli strikes may have "significantly hampered Iran's ability to mass produce missiles."</p>

<p>The Israeli military said three waves of Israeli jets struck missile factories and other sites near Tehran and in western Iran early on Saturday in retaliation for Tehran's October 1 barrage of more than 200 missiles against Israel.</p>

<p>Iran's military said the Israeli warplanes used "very light warheads" to strike border radar systems in the provinces of Ilam, Khuzestan and around Tehran.</p>

<p>Eveleth said that an image from Planet Labs, a commercial satellite firm, showed that an Israeli strike destroyed two buildings in Khojir where solid fuel for ballistic missiles was mixed.</p>

<p>The buildings were enclosed by high dirt berms, according to the image reviewed by Reuters. Such structures are associated with missile production and are designed to stop a blast in one building from detonating combustible materials in nearby structures.</p>

<p>Planet Labs imagery of Parchin showed that Israel destroyed three ballistic missile solid fuel mixing buildings and a warehouse, he said.</p>

<p>Albright said he reviewed low-resolution commercial satellite imagery of Parchin that appeared to show that an Israeli strike damaged three buildings, including two in which solid fuel for ballistic missiles was mixed.</p>

<p>He did not identify the commercial firm from which he obtained the images.</p>

<p>The buildings, he said, are located about 350 yards from a facility once involved in what the UN nuclear watchdog, the International Atomic Energy Agency, and US intelligence say was a comprehensive nuclear weapons development program that Iran shuttered in 2003. Iran denies having such a program.</p>

<p>"Israel says they targeted buildings housing solid-fuel mixers," Eveleth said. "These industrial mixers are hard to make and export-controlled. Iran imported many over the years at great expense, and will likely have a hard time replacing them."</p>

<p>With a limited operation, he said, Israel may have struck a significant blow against Iran's ability to mass-produce missiles and made it more difficult for any future Iranian missile attack to pierce Israel's missile defenses.</p>

<p>"The strikes appear to be highly accurate," he said.</p>

<p>Iran has the Middle East's largest missile arsenal and supplied missiles to Russia for use against Ukraine, and to Yemen's Houthi rebels and the Lebanese militia Hezbollah, according to US officials.</p>

<p>Tehran and Moscow deny that Russia has received Iranian missiles.</p>

<p>Planet Labs imagery reviewed earlier this year by Eveleth and Jeffrey Lewis of the Middlebury Institute of International Studies at Monterey showed major expansions at Khojir and the Modarres military complex near Tehran that the pair assessed were for boosting missile production, Reuters reported.</p>

<p>Three senior Iranian officials confirmed that conclusion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/np9d7e3o_israel-offensive-against-iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran's military said the Israeli warplanes used "very light warheads" to strike border radar systems.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/young-blue-collar-workers-key-us-voters-who-will-decide-donald-trump-or-kamala-harris-fate-6883061]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Young Blue-Collar Workers: Key US Voters Who Will Decide Presidential Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/young-blue-collar-workers-key-us-voters-who-will-decide-donald-trump-or-kamala-harris-fate-6883061]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 08:33:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Young blue-collar workers are being courted in a tight US presidential election that is forcing voters to weigh competing claims on immigration, inflation and other hot-button issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Young blue-collar workers like Luke Gonzalez are being courted in a tight US presidential election that is forcing voters to weigh competing claims on immigration, inflation and other hot-button issues.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Gonzalez, a 25 year-old glazier, sat through an 80-minute presentation at his Warren, Michigan union hall where labor leaders pressed the case that Kamala Harris was better for workers than Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Gonzalez, who is undecided, is a member of the International Union of Painters and Allied Trades (IUPAT), one of several leading unions backing Harris due in part to industrial policy under the Biden-Harris administration expected to sustain building-trades employment for years.</p>

<p>Democrats also back collective-bargaining rights, in contrast to Trump who joked recently with billionaire Tesla CEO Elon Musk about firing striking workers.</p>

<p>But Trump's unconventional style has enjoyed lasting appeal with a sizeable number of blue-collar workers, who can be more conservative culturally -- that has helped keep the race tight in Michigan and other swing states with large working-class populations.</p>

<p>Trump supporters include Isaiah Goddard, 24, who is part of a group of insurgent United Auto Workers members who back Trump.</p>

<p>Trump "is not a politician," he said. "He knows how to run the country and he can do it again."</p>

<p>Goddard, who works at Ford, doesn't believe Harris' support for electric vehicles will be good for Michigan.</p>

<p>He also endorses Trump's stance on abortion and immigration, saying "these illegal immigrants are going to be taking American jobs."</p>

<p>Nick Nabozny, another Ford worker, sold 32 red "Auto Workers for Trump" t-shirts at his Wayne, Michigan plants this week.</p>

<p>"There's more people in the union that support Trump than they truly believe," Nabozny said of the UAW. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Turned off by politicians</strong></h3>

<p>Trump in 2016 became the first Republican candidate since Ronald Reagan to cut significantly into the Democratic lead among union households.</p>

<p>Besides immigration, Trump in 2016 blasted international trade deals that led to industrial job loss in states like Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>Biden won back enough of these voters in 2020 to flip those states, although this year's race is neck-and-neck.</p>

<p>Democratic pollster David Mermin expects a big gender gap, with working-class women supporting Harris based in part over abortion rights.</p>

<p>Young voters are the most "persuadable" part of the working-class population, said Mermin, who works at Lake Research Partners. "They don't like the parties. They don't like politicians."</p>

<p>They "are the ones you can influence, they're learning still," said Jeff Tricoff, 39, a refinery worker at the Teamsters union in Detroit who is undecided.</p>

<p>Lucas Hartwell, 22, a labor organizer with the Operating Engineers union who backs Harris tells peers to "vote your interests, even if the social issues don't match up for you."</p>

<h3><strong>Debating immigration</strong></h3>

<p>While the national Teamsters union made no endorsement, other prominent unions such as IUPAT and the UAW are campaigning hard for the Democrat, distributing lawn signs, phone banking and canvassing door to door.</p>

<p>IUPAT president Jimmy Williams attributes the Democratic Party's slippage to decades of failures to deliver.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Williams, a fourth-generation member of his union who became a glazier after high school, considers Biden to be a turning point because the outgoing president became the first to join a strikers' picket line, and because of big legislative successes.</p>

<p>At the Warren event, Williams described to apprentices that Trump talked about infrastructure, but didn't get anything done, adding that Harris will continue Biden's ambitious initiatives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But when Williams polled the audience of around 30, about a third raised their hands for Trump. Inflation, cost of living," explained one bearded young worker.</p>

<p>Williams acknowledged that costs are "going through the roof," as he blamed big business and described inflation as a global phenomenon due to supply chain problems.</p>

<p>Williams got more pushback on immigration, but he argued workers should aim their outrage at the businesses that exploit cheap labor.</p>

<p>"As a union, we just can't stand for that," Williams told the group. "The biggest tool that the bosses use to divide workers is race."</p>

<p>After the event, Robert Gonzalez, head of IUPAT's Michigan district, estimated the room as "50-50 split."</p>

<p>His son, Luke, was drawn to the idea that "Kamala is for the working union" in contrast to "big business" candidate Trump, before adding, "I still have a lot of reading up to do."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6ivehmr8_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Young voters are the most "persuadable" part of the working-class population]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-vows-countermeasures-over-us-arms-sales-to-taiwan-6882964]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Vows "Countermeasures" Over US Arms Sales To Taiwan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-vows-countermeasures-over-us-arms-sales-to-taiwan-6882964]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 08:06:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China will take "countermeasures" to defend its sovereignty and territorial integrity, the government said, lambasting a $2 billion arms sale package by the United States to Taiwan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China will take "countermeasures" to defend its sovereignty and territorial integrity, the government said, lambasting a $2 billion arms sale package by the United States to Taiwan.</p>

<p>The United States is bound by law to provide Chinese-claimed Taiwan with the means to defend itself despite the lack of formal diplomatic ties, to the constant anger of Beijing.</p>

<p>On Friday, the Pentagon said the United States had approved a potential $2 billion arms sale package to Taiwan, including the delivery for the first time to the island of an advanced air defence missile system battle-tested in Ukraine.</p>

<p>In a statement late Saturday, China's foreign ministry said it strongly condemns and firmly opposes the sales and has lodged "solemn representations" with the United States.</p>

<p>China urges the United States to immediately stop arming Taiwan and stop its dangerous moves that undermine peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait, it added.</p>

<p>"China will take resolute countermeasures and take all measures necessary to firmly defend national sovereignty, security and territorial integrity," the ministry said, without elaborating.</p>

<p>China has over the past five years stepped up its military activities around democratically governed Taiwan, whose government rejects Beijing's sovereignty claims, including staging a new round of war games earlier this month.</p>

<p>Taiwan's government has welcomed the new arms sale, the 17th of the Biden administration to the island.</p>

<p>"In the face of China's threats, Taiwan is duty-bound to protect its homeland, and will continue to demonstrate its determination to defend itself," Taiwan's foreign ministry said, responding to the arms sale.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/as2ocbe_us-arms-sales-to-taiwan_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States is bound by law to provide Chinese-claimed Taiwan with the means to defend itself.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-white-house-genuine-fear-michelle-obama-on-donald-trump-being-re-elected-as-us-president-6882935]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Genuine Fear": Michelle Obama On Trump Being Re-Elected As US President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-white-house-genuine-fear-michelle-obama-on-donald-trump-being-re-elected-as-us-president-6882935]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 07:59:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Michelle Obama on Saturday aired her "genuine fear" that Donald Trump could retake the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Michelle Obama on Saturday aired her "genuine fear" that Donald Trump could retake the White House as the popular former first lady made a passionate appeal to voters in the desperately close US election.</p>

<p>Both Trump and Kamala Harris were in Michigan searching for holdout votes ahead of the November 5 election, with Harris focused on abortion rights and Trump returning to his anti-immigrant campaign theme.</p>

<p>Obama said Democratic candidate Harris would be an "extraordinary president of the United States" if elected in just 10 days.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But, with polls forecasting a virtual dead heat, she also spoke of a sense of frustration and anxiety that few on Harris's team dare express after she lost some momentum in recent weeks.</p>

<p>"My hope about Kamala is also accompanied by some genuine fear," Obama said, ripping into Trump's record and asking, "Why is this race even close?"</p>

<p>"I'm a little angry that we are indifferent to his erratic behavior, his obvious mental decline, his history as a convicted felon, a known slum lord, a predator found liable for sexual abuse."</p>

<p>Obama, appearing alongside Harris, hammered home the vice president's message that abortion rights -- and women's health care overall -- are at stake on the ballot.</p>

<p>"Please do not hand our fates over to the likes of Trump," Obama said, adding he could effectively ban abortion nationwide.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump on the attack</strong></h3>

<p>At his rally, Trump launched bitter personal attacks on Harris and accused her of pushing an "open border" migration policy.</p>

<p>"She's a dope," he said. "This person cannot be president."</p>

<p>"She will destroy our country. Everyone knows it. No one respects her. The United States is now occupied country. Kamala broke it, we will fix it."</p>

<p>With more than 38 million people already casting early ballots, Americans are deciding whether to elect the country's first-ever woman president, or its oldest commander in chief.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, still refuses to accept his defeat in the vote four years ago and is expected to reject the result if he loses again -- potentially pitching the United States into chaos.</p>

<p>Trump swept the three Blue Wall states -- Michigan, Wisconsin and Pennsylvania -- in his shock victory in 2016 only to see Joe Biden reclaim them four years later.</p>

<p>He hopes to claw back one or more of the trio, and win the so-called Sun Belt swing states to propel him back into power.</p>

<p>After his Michigan event, Trump headed straight to Pennsylvania for another rally on Saturday evening.</p>

<h3><strong>Abortion rights</strong></h3>

<p>Harris further highlighted abortion rights -- a weak point for Republicans -- by visiting a local doctor's office and meeting with physicians, staff and medical students.</p>

<p>"Because of Trump and what he did with the Supreme Court, we are looking at a health care crisis in America," she told reporters, referring to justices chosen by Trump who tipped the court into ending the national right to abortion in 2022.</p>

<p>The penultimate weekend before the vote began on Friday evening with Harris appearing alongside superstar Beyonce, and Trump giving a three-hour interview to Joe Rogan, America's most popular podcaster.</p>

<p>On Sunday Harris, 60, will campaign in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, the largest city in the largest of the swing states likely to determine the election winner.</p>

<p>She will criss-cross the city, especially historically Black and Latino districts, trying to persuade uncommitted residents to cast their vote.</p>

<p>Trump will rally his supporters on Sunday evening in Madison Square Garden, the famous arena in the heart of heavily Democratic New York.</p>

<p>The brash billionaire and onetime reality television star appears keen to orchestrate a grand spectacle, and demonstrate he can fill an arena in a liberal bastion.</p>

<p>But critics, including Trump's 2016 rival Hillary Clinton, have noted that Madison Square Garden was also the scene of a 1939 pro-Nazi rally organized by a group supportive of Adolf Hitler.</p>

<p>Part of Harris's election strategy is to peel moderate Republicans away from Trump, who often demeans some Americans as the "enemy."</p>

<p>Harris told her supporters that as a prosecutor she "took on perpetrators of all kinds -- predators, fraudsters and repeat offenders. I took them on and I won.</p>

<p>"In 10 days, it's Donald Trump's turn."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/v2fv3ee_michelle-obama-afp_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Michelle Obama made a passionate appeal to voters in the desperately close US election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-worked-illegally-in-us-at-start-of-his-career-report-6882902]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Worked "Illegally" In US At Start Of His Career: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-worked-illegally-in-us-at-start-of-his-career-report-6882902]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 07:44:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk, a staunch supporter of Donald Trump who has for years portrayed migrants as invaders and criminals, worked "illegally" in the United States during the start of his career.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, a powerful critic of illegal immigrants and a staunch supporter of Donald Trump who has for years portrayed migrants as invaders and criminals, worked "illegally" in the United States during the start of his career, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/26/elon-musk-immigration-status/?fbclid=IwY2xjawGJ9X9leHRuA2FlbQIxMQABHTxa8uBiCwmifkowiNsJ2E0SrB2EVxmPJA-P-gIo8JdXg-I39oXvIAsAkw_aem_1Jbv1FA3AMBanjGB1v0s7Q" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">reported</a> The Washington Post.</p>

<p>According to the report, Musk, whose origin is from South Africa, dropped out of Stanford University in 1995 to work on his debut company, Zip2 for four years before it sold for around 300 million dollars. During this time, he was working without correct authorization.</p>

<p>Two of Musk's former colleagues also said that Musk received his US work authorisation around 1997, the report said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-vladimir-putin-in-secret-communications-since-2022-report-6877055">Musk</a>, being a foreign student in US, could not have dropped out of school to build a company as per the rules.</p>

<p>Overstaying a student visa is common in most cases, however, it still remains illegal, the Post said.</p>

<p>Despite this, Musk has always maintained that his time from turning into an entrepreneur from a student is a "legal grey area".</p>

<p>The report also cited a 2020 podcast in which Musk had said that he was legally in US but he was meant to be doing student work. "I was allowed to do work sort of supporting whatever," he said.</p>

<p>Several of the Tesla and SpaceX boss' recent posts on social media platforms have been on immigration and voter fraud, accusing White House nominee and Vice-President Kamala Harris of "importing voters" through illegal immigrants. Last week, he also compared the US-Mexico border - where several Mexican immigrants enter America - to a "zombie apocalypse".&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jb57vagg_elon-musk_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk's recent posts on social media have been on immigration and voter fraud.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-after-israeli-strikes-iran-vows-to-defend-itself-10-points-6882838]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Israel Braces For Iran's Response, A Warning By Pentagon Chief: 10 Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-after-israeli-strikes-iran-vows-to-defend-itself-10-points-6882838]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 07:28:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel waited for almost four weeks to avenge the ballistic missile attack from Iran on October 1. Yesterday, Israeli fighter jets flew for over 1,000 kilometres and conducted "precise strikes" on military facilities in Tehran and nearby provinces.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Over 100 Israeli fighter jets including the F-35 stealth fighters, took off for the mission just before dawn. They flew for 1,000 kilometres and struck the radar and air defence systems of Iran to render them defenceless and hit other military sites including a missile manufacturing unit.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel said it conducted "precise strikes". At the same time, Iran, initially claimed that the explosions across the capital Tehran were due to the activation of air defence systems, but later admitted that the strikes caused "limited damage" to military sites. Two Iranian soldiers were killed in the attack.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">"We are prepared to respond to any Israeli "aggression," Iran's semi-official Tasnim news agency reported, citing sources in the government. "There is no doubt that Israel will face a proportional reaction for any action it takes," they added. The Israeli army has warned Iran of paying a "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-it-has-right-to-defend-itself-after-todays-strikes-israel-warns-of-heavy-price-6880052">heavy price</a>" if it begins a new round of escalation.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The US has termed Israel's attack an "exercise of self-defence" and urged Tehran to avoid any further escalation. 'The US was informed by Israel beforehand about the attacks and there is no involvement of Washington in the strikes,' AFP reported quoting sources in the US government. Meanwhile, US Defence Secretary, Lloyd J Austin, in a warning said, "Iran should not make the mistake of responding to Israel's strikes, which should mark the end of this exchange."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel attacked at the time of its choosing, the tit-for-tat move has led to a volatile situation in the region, drawing condemnation from states in the area and outside. Hamas, Iraq, Pakistan, Syria and Saudi Arabia condemned the strikes. Turkey went a step ahead and called for an end to "terror created by Israel".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Russia urged both sides to restrain and avoid a "catastrophic scenario". Moscow has been at war with Ukraine for over two years, with no sign of a de-escalation. India said it is "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/deeply-concerned-by-evolving-escalation-in-west-asia-india-6881871">deeply concerned</a> by the evolving escalation in West Asia and its ramifications for peace and stability in the region and beyond."&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In an interview with NDTV,<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-strikes-reuven-azar-could-have-inflicted-much-more-damage-israel-envoy-to-ndtv-after-iran-strikes-6881332"> Israeli envoy to India, Reuven Azar</a>, said, "What Israel did is a very precise strike that took out Iran's air defence systems, and targeted military installations connected to their missile and drone programmes. The signal here is very clear: Israel will not agree to continue to be attacked by Iran either directly or indirectly."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Lebanon reported an Israeli raid today on southern Beirut after Israel's army issued an evacuation call. Lebanon's National News Agency said Israel "targeted the southern suburbs of Beirut". The Israeli army had earlier urged residents of two neighbourhoods in the southern suburbs of the Lebanese capital to evacuate their homes.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel attacked Syria too. Explosions were heard in the capital Damascus. Syrian authorities said Israel launched attacks from the occupied Golan Heights and parts of Lebanon, prompting them to activate air defence systems. Syria is part of the Iran-led 'Axis of Resistance', a group of Shia militias and political groups, against Israel and the US in the region.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-aftermath-of-israeli-air-strikes-airspace-shut-in-these-3-countries-6877007">The airspace</a> in three countries was under a temporary lockdown after the strikes. Iran, Iraq and Syria shut the airspace in response to the strike to preserve the safety of civil aviation. Prohibiting airspace after attacks is part of standard operation procedures of states for security reasons to prevent intrusion of enemy aircraft in the territory and make it easy for air defence systems to identify friendly aircraft in the airspace.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/np9d7e3o_israel-offensive-against-iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel said it conducted "precise strikes".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-salt-typhoon-chinese-espionage-group-that-targeted-donald-trump-6882834]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Salt Typhoon, Chinese Espionage Group That Targeted Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-salt-typhoon-chinese-espionage-group-that-targeted-donald-trump-6882834]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 07:22:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese hackers have targeted the communication devices of US presidential candidates, including former President Donald Trump and his running mate, JD Vance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese hackers have targeted the communication devices of US presidential candidates, including former President Donald Trump and his running mate, JD Vance. This sophisticated hacking attempt was reportedly orchestrated by a Chinese cyber espionage group known as 'Salt Typhoon'. According to the New York Times, the group infiltrated telecommunication networks and may have accessed critical data from major service providers, including Verizon.</p>

<p>According to reports, Salt Typhoon's targets in the US include not only Trump's campaign but also Democratic contenders, including Vice President Kamala Harris and her running mate Tim Walz.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The attack on Verizon's infrastructure is considered part of a broader Chinese intelligence-gathering campaign. Although it remains uncertain whether the hackers succeeded in extracting specific communications, US federal agencies are now working to uncover the nature and extent of any data breach. "We are aware that a highly sophisticated nation-state actor has reportedly targeted several US telecommunications providers to gather intelligence," Rich Young, a spokesperson for Verizon, told news agency AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Salt Typhoon?</strong></h3>

<p>Salt Typhoon, the designation coined by Microsoft's cybersecurity team, is a group of state-sponsored Chinese hackers. Microsoft labels Chinese hacker groups with the term "typhoon," while using "sandstorm" for Iranian and "blizzard" for Russian cyber actors. The term "salt" in this context denotes the group's specialised focus on counterintelligence rather than conventional cybercrime involving corporate data theft or financial fraud.</p>

<p>Salt Typhoon's operations appear exclusively aimed at collecting intelligence on critical American assets and institutions, especially during sensitive political seasons. In this case, Salt Typhoon targeted specific phone numbers linked to top political figures and their staff, as well as individuals with deep governmental ties.&nbsp;</p>

<p>U.S. officials are still in the early stages of assessing the full scope of the Salt Typhoon breach. The FBI and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) released a joint statement acknowledging the severity of the threat, confirming that US government agencies are actively engaged in "investigating the unauthorised access to commercial telecommunications infrastructure by actors affiliated with the People's Republic of China."</p>

<p>In their statement, the FBI and CISA said that ongoing collaborative efforts with private sector companies are underway to bolster cybersecurity defences. "After the FBI identified specific malicious activity targeting the sector, the FBI and CISA immediately notified affected companies, rendered technical assistance, and rapidly shared information to assist other potential victims," the agencies said.</p>

<p>A significant concern is that Salt Typhoon may have obtained critical metadata, which can be as revealing as actual content in intelligence terms. For instance, metadata related to call patterns, times, and frequencies can reveal insights into relationships, strategic discussions, and even security vulnerabilities in communication channels. For Chinese intelligence, this data could provide clues about the inner workings and key figures in US decision-making circles, especially in the lead-up to the 2024 election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-07/hboe549o_hacking-generic-unsplash-650_625x300_19_July_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Salt Typhoon is a group of state-sponsored Chinese hackers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-irans-nuclear-facilities-not-impacted-in-israeli-strikes-un-6882699]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's Nuclear Facilities 'Not Impacted' In Israeli Strikes: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-irans-nuclear-facilities-not-impacted-in-israeli-strikes-un-6882699]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 06:45:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations atomic energy watchdog on Saturday said that Iran's nuclear programme was not affected by Israel's deadly air strike on its arch-rival's military facilities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations atomic energy watchdog on Saturday said that Iran's nuclear programme -- a source of international controversy -- was not affected by Israel's deadly air strike on its arch-rival's military facilities.</p>

<p>"Iran's nuclear facilities have not been impacted," IAEA director general Rafael Grossi wrote on X, urging "prudence and restraint from actions that could jeopardize the safety and security of nuclear and other radioactive materials."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0a94e6e_iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel hit Iran with airstrikes in latest attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-few-israelis-remain-in-sri-lanka-surfing-town-despite-terrorism-warning-6881460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Few Israelis Remain In Sri Lanka Surfing Town Despite Terrorism Warning]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-few-israelis-remain-in-sri-lanka-surfing-town-despite-terrorism-warning-6881460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:49:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The last of the Israelis left in a scenic surfing hotspot in Sri Lanka said they felt safe and would stay put despite a warning from the Israeli government to immediately leave due to the threat of a possible terrorist attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The last of the Israelis left in a scenic surfing hotspot in Sri Lanka said they felt safe and would stay put despite a warning from the Israeli government to immediately leave due to the threat of a possible terrorist attack.</p>

<p>Israel's national security council called on Israelis on Wednesday to get out of tourist areas in the south of the Indian Ocean island nation, saying it had information about a terrorist threat focused on tourist areas and beaches.</p>

<p>The agency did not specify the nature of the threat but said the warning pertained to the Arugam Bay area - a popular haunt for Israelis - and beaches in the south and west of the country.</p>

<p>The US embassy in Sri Lanka and the German foreign ministry also followed with similar warnings, prompting Colombo to step up security and go on high alert.</p>

<p>Sri Lankan police have arrested three suspects for questioning in connection with an unspecified threat.</p>

<p>"We are working to ensure that all tourists are protected and their safety assured at all times," police spokesman Nihal Thalduwa told Reuters.</p>

<p>There were about 600-700 Israeli tourists through September to early October in Arugam Bay, local authorities said, but that number had dwindled to just 20 when the security warning was issued this week which came at the tailend of the tourist season.</p>

<p>By Friday, 17 had moved out of the area with some of them flying out of the country, leaving behind three Israelis in the south-eastern town of about 7,000 residents.</p>

<p>One of them, who has been coming to Sri Lanka since 1991 and is a long-term resident, said he feels safe and is expecting his wife and 17-year-old twin sons to join him in a week's time.</p>

<p>"I love coming here and my family loves coming here, and we surf for about three to four hours every day when my sons are here," he told Reuters on Friday after returning home from his morning surfing. "I don't think there is a serious security threat."</p>

<p>The man, who declined to be identified, said two policemen showed up after the first security warnings. Now, there are 16 security personnel, including police special forces, stationed around his small, blue-painted house in Arugam Bay.</p>

<p>Two other Israeli men, brothers who were lounging in their room at a nearby homestay, surrounded by about eight police and special forces personnel, also said they would remain until the end of the month and then relocate to nearby Ahangama town.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka has nevertheless tightened security, with the memory of Easter Sunday bombings of 2019 still fresh. Those attacks blamed on Islamic State targeted churches and three hotels, killing 267 people, including at least 45 foreign nationals.</p>

<p><strong>UNPRECEDENTED SECURITY</strong></p>

<p>Checkpoints have sprung up on the main roads and bridges in Arugam Bay and the surrounding area, and as many as 500 police, military and special forces were deployed.</p>

<p>Police stopped vehicles and checked identification cards of passengers.</p>

<p>Israeli officials have warned of an increase in threats of attacks on Israelis outside their country since the start of the war in Gaza. &nbsp; &nbsp; There has also been a surge in reports of antisemitic incidents in many parts of the world since war broke out in the Middle East after Palestinian Islamist group Hamas attacked Israel on Oct. 7, 2023.</p>

<p>Arugam Bay residents dismissed social media speculation of tensions in the Muslim-majority town over the presence of Israelis in the wake of the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"I started renting out rooms to foreigners last year and they are happy to stay here because they are not scared," said Abubakar Rinosha, 41, who owns the homestay of the Israeli brothers.</p>

<p>Other residents said Israeli tourists are a major source of income, accounting for 70% of the town's revenue.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/eg19dnp8_arungam-bay-sri-lanka_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were 600-700 Israeli tourists through September to early October in Arugam Bay, authorities said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-blows-up-houses-in-border-villages-in-lebanon-report-6881380]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Blows Up Houses In Border Villages In Lebanon: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-blows-up-houses-in-border-villages-in-lebanon-report-6881380]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:32:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanese state media said the Israeli army dynamited houses in Lebanese border villages on Saturday, as Israel said it used 400 tonnes of explosives to destroy a Hezbollah tunnel, more than a month into an all-out war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese state media said the Israeli army dynamited houses in Lebanese border villages on Saturday, as Israel said it used 400 tonnes of explosives to destroy a Hezbollah tunnel, more than a month into an all-out war.</p>

<p>The official National News Agency said "the army of the Israeli enemy has since dawn blown up and destroyed houses" in the border village of Adaisseh.</p>

<p>The NNA also reported "large explosions" in the border village of Kfar Kila, saying the blasts were heard across the south as columns of smoke rose above the area.</p>

<p>Israeli military spokesman Avichay Adraee said 400 tonnes of explosives were used to blow up a "strategic underground facility" in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>The "tunnel" was more than 1.5 kilometres (around a mile) long, Adraee said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military had earlier reported "the explosion of a large quantity of explosives in Lebanon" that was strong enough to trigger earthquake warnings in large parts of Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli army published a video showing massive detonations at the border.</p>

<p>Lebanese state media has reported several incidents of Israeli blasts targeting houses in border villages in recent days.</p>

<p>Israel's Channel 12 broadcast footage on Friday that appeared to show one of its presenters detonating a building while embedded with Israeli troops in the south Lebanon village of Aita al-Shaab.</p>

<p>Hezbollah says it is fighting Israeli troops at close quarters in Lebanese border villages.</p>

<p>The two sides began exchanging cross-border fire last year, but all-out war erupted on September 23, when Israel ramped up its air campaign against Hezbollah strongholds in south Lebanon, the capital Beirut and the eastern Bekaa Valley.</p>

<p>The war has left at least 1,615 people dead in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally of health ministry figures though the real number is likely to be higher due to gaps in the data.</p>

<p>The war has displaced at least 1.3 million people, according to the International Organization for Migration. More than 800,000 have sought refuge inside Lebanon while more than half a million have fled to Syria, most of them Syrians, according to Lebanese authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i95ri4vo_lebanon-afp_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah says it is fighting Israeli troops at close quarters in Lebanese border villages.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-strikes-reuven-azar-could-have-inflicted-much-more-damage-israel-envoy-to-ndtv-after-iran-strikes-6881332]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Could Have Inflicted Much More Damage": Israel Envoy After Iran Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-strikes-reuven-azar-could-have-inflicted-much-more-damage-israel-envoy-to-ndtv-after-iran-strikes-6881332]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:26:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel wants peace in the region but is not ready to be attacked by Iran directly or indirectly, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel wants peace in the region but is not ready to be attacked by Iran directly or indirectly, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV on Saturday, Mr Azar said this was one of the signals that his country wanted to send with its strikes on Iran earlier in the day and the other message is that it has the capability to hit many more targets in Iran if Tehran chooses to escalate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What Israel did is a very precise strike that took out Iran's air defence systems, and targeted military installations connected to their missile and drone programmes. The signal here is very clear: Israel will not agree to continue to be attacked by Iran either directly or indirectly," the ambassador said, hinting at Iran's proxies like Hamas and Hezbollah, with which Israel is already engaged in conflicts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran had earlier launched 200 ballistic missiles at Israeli targets on October 1.</p>

<p>Claiming that Iran is now exposed, Mr Azar said Israel is not worried about comments from the regime in Tehran warning of a "proportionate reaction" to the Israeli strike.</p>

<p>"We are ready for it. We are completely coordinating with our allies, especially the United States, which is completely backing our moves. It is very clear that Israel could have done much more to inflict damage on Iran but it chose to limit its response out of responsibility because we want to stay focused on this operation that the Israeli cabinet has determined - to completely eradicate the military capabilities of Hamas, to bring back our hostages and make sure Hamas doesn't rearm," the ambassador said.</p>

<p>In the north, where Israel shares a border with Lebanon, the ambassador said that the objective is to resettle Israeli communities in the areas from which they were evacuated because of attacks from Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"We are operating there as well, we have uprooted the military infrastructure that Hezbollah has created there for decades. And we will not agree that Iran will try to intervene in that and attack Israel. If they continue doing that, Israel will feel free to act in a much more decisive manner," he warned.</p>

<p><strong>'Will Pay The Price'</strong></p>

<p>To a question on whether Israel is locked in a never-ending war, Mr Azar said while that may seem to be the case, his country is defending itself and has created a situation in which Hamas can no longer attack it with missiles and the leadership of Hezbollah has been eliminated - and it is now for Iran to "accept the new reality".</p>

<p>"If they don't accept the new reality and come to the table to create a more stable situation in our region, they will pay the price," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ambassador said routes of diplomacy are always available and insisted that Israel did not start the war, which began after the October 7, 2023, attacks by Hamas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We want to restore peace in our region. We are prepared for diplomacy, but it has to lay on the foundation of the understanding of the other side that Israel will be relentless. We will not rest until we are sure that assurances for our security are met and we will maintain the right to self-defence against any aggression in the future," he said.</p>

<p><strong>'Downplaying Is Good'</strong></p>

<p>On Iran claiming that the Israeli attack caused limited damage and its defence systems worked, Mr Azar said he was happy that Tehran was "downplaying" it because it could be a sign that it was not interested in continuing the aggression.</p>

<p>"Anybody that knows something about military capabilities knows that the S-300 (air defence system) that the Iranians have is not capable of stopping the F-35s and the F-16s of the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) and not capable of stopping our pilots from hitting any targets they want. So they can continue saying what they want but the situation is very clear and the message has been conveyed in a very clear way," he said. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/htj4obo8_reuven-azar-marya-shakil_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Azar said Israel is pursuing a list of stated objectives.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-killed-after-cargo-truck-collides-with-passenger-bus-in-mexico-6881324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[24 Killed After Cargo Truck Collides With Passenger Bus In Mexico]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-killed-after-cargo-truck-collides-with-passenger-bus-in-mexico-6881324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:21:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A cargo truck collided with a passenger bus in northern Mexico on Saturday, leaving at least 24 people dead and five others injured, local authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A cargo truck collided with a passenger bus in northern Mexico on Saturday, leaving at least 24 people dead and five others injured, local authorities said.</p>

<p>"So far, the preliminary information available is that 24 passengers have died and five people are injured and are being treated," Rodrigo Reyes, a senior official in the government of Zacatecas state, said in a video on social media.</p>

<p>The accident, on a highway that connects Zacatecas with the central state of Aguascalientes, occurred when a container filled with corn fell off the truck, causing the bus to overturn.</p>

<p>The bus was traveling between the city of Tepic, in western Nayarit state, and Ciudad Juarez on the US border.</p>

<p>The highway was closed to traffic, Reyes said, adding that army, National Guard and civil protection forces were deployed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/s625qv4o_accident-generic-_625x300_16_December_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bus was traveling between the city of Tepic and Ciudad Juarez on the US border (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/town-of-kyle-saskatchewan-this-canadian-town-cant-find-anyone-to-run-for-mayor-6880885]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Canadian Town Can't Find Anyone To Run For Mayor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/town-of-kyle-saskatchewan-this-canadian-town-cant-find-anyone-to-run-for-mayor-6880885]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 21:51:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With Kyle, Saskatchewan's November municipal election approaching, the town faces a notable obstacle: no candidates have stepped up to run for mayor or fill an open Town Council seat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the November municipal election draws near, Kyle, a small town in Saskatchewan, Canada, is facing an unforeseen problem: there are no contenders for the mayorship, according to <em>CKOM.COM.</em></p>

<p>This year, current Mayor George Williams, who assumed office in November 2021, is scheduled to resign, leaving his position unfilled and without any candidates. Furthermore, there are still no nominees for a Town Council position.</p>

<p>Two rounds of candidate applications have been released to promote mayor nominations, but thus far, no one has shown interest, according to Chief Administrative Officer Amber Dashney.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's a little concerning, but I am confident that someone will step forward," Dashney told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ckom.com/2024/10/24/its-not-unusual-town-of-kyle-looking-for-mayor-candidate/"><em>CKOM.COM.</em></a></p>

<p>The council will designate a deputy mayor to assume the duties of mayor if the post is not filled by the election on November 13.</p>

<p>"At that meeting, we will decide on a date for a by-election, and we will continue calling a by-election until we fill the mayor spot and the other councilor spot, as well," Dashney said.</p>

<p>Gordon Barnhart, former President of the Saskatchewan Urban Municipalities Association (SUMA), said it can occur from time to time were nobody steps forward for council or mayoral nominations.</p>

<p>"I'm not sure that it's common, but it's not unusual," he said.</p>

<p>He said it can be hard for small communities to find enough people willing and able to run for mayor or for council.</p>

<p>In 2016, Barnhart was elected as a councillor for the Town of Saltcoats - a community 30 kilometres southeast of Yorkton - through a byelection after some convincing from local community members.</p>

<p>Due to several vacant councillor positions, Barnhart said the town risked not meeting quorum at council meetings. He would go on to serve as a councillor in Saltcoats until 2020, before being elected as mayor where he sat until 2022.</p>

<p>"It is really a dedication to your community where you feel that you can make a difference," Barnhart said.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www12.statcan.gc.ca/census-recensement/2021/dp-pd/prof/index.cfm?Lang=E">2021 Statistics Canada census data,</a> the Town of Kyle has population of 413, and the Town of Saltcoats has a population of 473.</p>

<p>While towns and villages have smaller populations to choose from, Barnhart said people's time and confidence may be factors that prevent people from running for a seat.</p>

<p>In a statement, SUMA said as long as council can maintain quorum, it can continue with meetings.</p>

<p>"While it's rare, it's not unheard of for no one to put their name forward for mayor, or for too few people to put their names forward for council," the statement read. "In nearly all cases, someone will put their name in for the following byelection and the spot will be filled."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e2ea6348_town-of-kyle-saskatchewan_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite two rounds of applications, no one has stepped up.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>