<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 22:22:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-tells-putin-china-russia-partnership-force-of-stability-amid-chaos-6849899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping Tells Putin China-Russia Partnership "Force Of Stability" Amid Chaos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-tells-putin-china-russia-partnership-force-of-stability-amid-chaos-6849899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 22:16:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping told Russia's Vladimir Putin that the international situation was gripped by chaos but that Beijing's strategic partnership with Moscow was a force for stability amid the most significant changes seen in a century.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping told Russia's Vladimir Putin that the international situation was gripped by chaos but that Beijing's strategic partnership with Moscow was a force for stability amid the most significant changes seen in a century.</p>

<p>Xi and Putin in May pledged a "new era" of partnership between the two most powerful rivals of the United States, which they cast as an aggressive Cold War hegemon sowing chaos across the world.</p>

<p>"At present, the world is going through changes unseen in a hundred years, the international situation is intertwined with chaos," Xi told Putin in the Russian city of Kazan at the opening of the BRICS summit.</p>

<p>"But I firmly believe that the friendship between China and Russia will continue for generations, and great countries' responsibility to their people will not change."</p>

<p>Russia, waging war against NATO-supplied Ukrainian forces, and China, under pressure from a concerted U.S. effort to counter its growing military and economic strength, increasingly have found common geopolitical cause.</p>

<p>Russia and China, pushing back against perceived humiliations of the 1991 Soviet collapse and centuries of European colonial dominance of China, have sought to portray the West as decadent and in decline.</p>

<p>The United States casts China as its biggest competitor and Russia as its biggest nation-state threat, and President Joe Biden has said the democracies face a challenge from autocracies such as China and Russia.</p>

<p>Biden has referred to Xi as a "dictator" and has said Putin is a "killer" and even a "crazy SOB". Beijing and Moscow have scolded Biden for the comments.</p>

<p>Putin called Xi "dear friend" and said the partnership with China was a force for stability in the world.</p>

<p>"Russian-Chinese cooperation in world affairs is one of the main stabilising factors on the world stage," Putin said.</p>

<p>"We intend to further enhance coordination on all multilateral platforms in order to ensure global security and a just world order."</p>

<p>Xi said cooperation in the BRICS group was "the most important platform for solidarity and cooperation between emerging market countries and developing countries in the world today."</p>

<p>He said it was "a mainstay force in promoting the realization of equal and orderly global multipolarity, as well as inclusive and tolerant economic globalisation."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c1br8ao_xi-and-putin_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin and Chinese President Xi Jinping at BRICS Summit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abercrombie-ex-ceo-michael-jeffries-arrested-in-sex-trafficking-probe-report-6849832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Abercrombie Ex CEO Michael Jeffries Arrested In Sex Trafficking Probe: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abercrombie-ex-ceo-michael-jeffries-arrested-in-sex-trafficking-probe-report-6849832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 22:05:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Michael Jeffries, former CEO of Abercrombie & Fitch, was arrested by federal agents investigating allegations that he ran a sex-trafficking operation, the Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday, citing people familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Michael Jeffries, former CEO of Abercrombie &amp; Fitch, was arrested by federal agents investigating allegations that he ran a sex-trafficking operation, the Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday, citing people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>He was arrested on Tuesday in Florida as part of an investigation being led by federal prosecutors in Brooklyn, New York, the report said.</p>

<p>Abercrombie &amp; Fitch declined to comment to Reuters queries, while Jeffries was not immediately reachable.</p>

<p>Last year, a group of once-aspiring Abercrombie &amp; Fitch male models sued the retailer and the former CEO alleging that the company had benefited from a sex-trafficking operation led by Jeffries.</p>

<p>The proposed class action filed by former model David Bradberry in Manhattan federal court claims Jeffries forced models to take drugs and engage in sexual acts with him and others for the chance to be featured in Abercrombie's provocative catalogs.</p>

<p>The lawsuit had alleged that company officers knew about the conduct and Abercrombie paid settlements to people who accused Jeffries of sexual abuse or harassment.</p>

<p>Jeffries, who was CEO from 1992 to 2014, was credited with turning around the retailer into a successful teen apparel maker known for its cologne-filled stores and ads featuring semi-nude models. He, however, resigned amid criticism that he had failed to keep pace with the tastes of teen shoppers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vs1hpvm8_abercrombie-ex-ceo_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Abercrombie & Fitch male models sued the retailer and the former CEO last year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/even-without-a-translator-putin-on-how-well-pm-narendra-modi-understands-him-6849637]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Even Without A Translator": Putin On How Well PM Modi Understands Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/even-without-a-translator-putin-on-how-well-pm-narendra-modi-understands-him-6849637]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:35:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ties between India and Russia have been time-tested and has had a strong foundation since Independence in 1947, but another factor that bonds the two nations together is the friendship between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Vladimir Putin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ties between India and Russia have been time-tested and has had a strong foundation since Independence in 1947, but another factor that bonds the two nations together is the friendship between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>The two leaders met today in Russia's Kazan where they will attend the 16th BRICS Summit today and tomorrow. After a handshake and a hug, PM Modi and Putin held India-Russia talks.</p>

<p>Highlighting his friendship with Prime Minister Modi, President Putin said that the bond between the two countries and the two leaders is so strong that PM Modi would understand him even without the help of any translator.</p>

<p>"Our relationship is so strong that you will understand me without any translation," President Putin said, sparking laughter in the room at the Governor's Palace. He further noted that "In Kazan we must make a number of important decisions aimed at further improving the activities of the association and strengthening multifaceted cooperation within its framework. And we greatly value our cooperation in this area, I mean that our states stood at the origins of the association's creation."</p>

<p>President Putin also hailed Russia and India's "privileged strategic partnership" and vowed to build ties further. "Interaction between legislative bodies is strengthening. Our foreign ministers are in constant contact. Trade turnover is in good condition. And the next meeting of the intergovernmental commission is scheduled for November 12 in New Delhi," he said.</p>

<p>"Major projects are being developed consistently, and we welcome your decision to open the Consulate General of India in Kazan. Expanding India's diplomatic presence in Russia will contribute to the further development of bilateral relations," he added.</p>

<h2><strong>MEDIATING PEACE BETWEEN RUSSIA AND UKRAINE</strong></h2>

<p>In his opening statement during his meeting with Vladimir Putin, PM Modi said he wanted the Ukraine conflict to be resolved "peacefully and quickly", adding that "We have been in constant touch over the conflict between Russia and Ukraine."</p>

<p>"We believe that disputes should only be resolved peacefully. We totally support efforts to quickly restore peace and stability," the prime minister further said.</p>

<p>PM Modi visited Kyiv in August and Moscow in July in an effort to encourage talks, as India cast itself as a potential mediator. In both countries he was welcomed with a warm embrace. Both Putin and Zelenskyy have remained in close contact with PM Modi over the duration of the Ukraine conflict - as India has a unique position maintaining friendly relations with both nations.</p>

<p>After his visit to Kyiv, Prime Minister Modi reportedly sent National Security Adviser Ajit Doval to Moscow with a "peace plan", which was reportedly handed over to President Putin when Mr Doval had a meeting with him.</p>

<p>During his meeting with President Zelenskyy, Prime Minister Modi reiterated his commitment to peace and sustainable development.</p>

<p>"He emphasised that without peace, long-term progress is impossible. While the outcome of the war remains uncertain, India continues to advocate for a peaceful resolution," said Mr. Misri.</p>

<p>India's initiative to broker peace between Russia and Ukraine has been praised by US President Joe Biden and several European leaders too. President Biden had also praised India's prominent global role, including Prime Minister Modi's leadership in the G20 and Global South, as well as his efforts to strengthen the Quad, ensuring a free, open, and prosperous Indo-Pacific.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tler06io_pm-modi-vladimir-putin-modi-putin-talks-pti_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Our relationship so strong, you'll understand me without a translation," Putin said, sparking laughter.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-to-meet-tomorrow-at-brics-first-meeting-since-border-breakthrough-6849554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi, Xi To Meet Tomorrow At BRICS, A First Since Border Breakthrough]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-to-meet-tomorrow-at-brics-first-meeting-since-border-breakthrough-6849554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:26:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi will hold a bilateral meet with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the BRICS summit in Russia on Tuesday, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will hold a bilateral meet with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the BRICS summit in Russia on Tuesday, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri has said. The meet will underscore the upturn in the India-China relation following a consensus on patrolling arrangement along the Line of Actual Control that had faced multiple hiccups over the last few years.</p>

<p>"I can confirm that there will be a bilateral meeting held between Prime Minister Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping tomorrow on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit," Mr Misri was quoted as saying by news agency ANI.</p>

<p>Both leaders are currently in Russia's Kazan, where Russian President Vladimir Putin, Brazil's Lula da Silva, and South Africa's Cyril Ramaphosa are also attending the summit.</p>

<p>The breakthrough in the patrolling arrangement comes four years after the Galwan Valley clash and signals a move towards de-escalation in a region where both countries stationed tens of thousands of troops.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The arrangement, which would involve a return to the pre-2020 system, is also a move to stabilize the situation and work as a confidence-building measure between New Delhi and Beijing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Indian and Chinese troops had clashed in Galwan Valley on June 15, 2020 amid a major escalation along the Line of Control. Both sides had sustained casualties, which had led to tension in bilateral ties.<br />
While a gradual de-escalation was effected, a return to the pre-Galwan status had proved elusive.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Besides bilateral relations, it had also led to strain in other areas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There had been no direct flight between the two nations for four years. Visa for Chinese technicians was granted after extra layers of security and investments from companies based in neighbouring countries needed extra vetting and security clearances.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q4ktklm4_pm-modi-xi-jinping-meeting-ians_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-set-to-announce-new-sanctions-aimed-at-russia-treasury-secretary-yellen-6849489]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Set To Announce "Strong New Sanctions" Aimed At Russia: Treasury Secretary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-set-to-announce-new-sanctions-aimed-at-russia-treasury-secretary-yellen-6849489]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:18:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States is set to announce "strong new sanctions" as early as next week, with targets including parties in countries that support Russia's military, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States is set to announce "strong new sanctions" as early as next week, with targets including parties in countries that support Russia's military, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said Tuesday.</p>

<p>"We will unveil strong new sanctions targeting those facilitating the Kremlin's war machine, including intermediaries in third countries that are supplying Russia with critical inputs for its military," she said in opening remarks to a press conference.</p>

<p>Her comments come as world financial leaders gather in Washington this week for the annual meetings of the International Monetary Fund and World Bank.</p>

<p>They also come more than 2.5 years after Russia's invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, which prompted a series of US actions taking aim at Russia's revenues and industrial complex.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Yellen also appeared to take aim at former president Donald Trump's economic approach, adding that the United States has "rejected isolationism that made America and the world worse off."</p>

<p>The world's biggest economy is two weeks away from its presidential election, which sees Republican candidate Trump running against Democrat Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Yellen stressed that under the current Democratic administration, Washington has "pursued global economic leadership that supports economies around the world and brings significant benefits to the American people and the US economy."</p>

<p>The economy has proven to be a critical issue for US voters according to polls.</p>

<p>Households have been feeling the pinch from higher costs of living after the pandemic, even as inflation has cooled from high levels seen in 2022 and the central bank started cutting interest rates -- with borrowing costs set to ease in turn.</p>

<p>The race between Harris and Trump is neck-and-neck, with some polls suggesting voters favor the former president on economic issues.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, as the IMF and World Bank meetings take place, Yellen urged countries to do more for nations struggling with debt.</p>

<p>She said US President Joe Biden's administration will continue pushing for improvements to a framework to aid countries in debt distress.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pm5sdp6_janet-yellen_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Janet Yellen speaks during a press conference at the Treasury Department in Washington, DC.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-introduces-stab-proof-umbrellas-to-protect-passengers-from-knife-attacks-6849187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Introduces Stab-Proof Umbrellas On Trains To Protect Passengers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-introduces-stab-proof-umbrellas-to-protect-passengers-from-knife-attacks-6849187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 20:35:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This initiative by West Japan Railway Co (JR West) comes in response to several violent incidents on trains, including a knife attack in July 2023.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of blade-resistant umbrellas will soon be deployed on Japanese trains to boost passenger safety following a series of knife attacks.&nbsp;A Japanese company is set to introduce around 1,200 stab-proof, lightweight umbrellas on 600 trains in the Kansai region. These umbrellas are about 20cm longer than standard ones, featuring reinforced canopies and thicker handles for enhanced protection, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3283201/blade-proof-umbrellas-be-deployed-japanese-trains-fend-knife-attacks" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>South China Morning Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This initiative by West Japan Railway Co (JR West) comes in response to several violent incidents on trains, including a knife attack in July 2023 that left three passengers injured. In a separate incident last year, a 37-year-old man was arrested after stabbing three people on a train in Osaka.</p>

<p>The attacker, who was found carrying three knives, was arrested at Rinku Town station shortly after the assault. The victims, including a train conductor in his 20s and two male passengers aged 23 and 79, were hospitalised but did not suffer life-threatening injuries.</p>

<p>According to <em>Mainichi</em>, the blade-proof umbrellas are designed to act as shields in the event of an attack, extending about 20cm longer than regular umbrellas to help create distance between the user and the assailant.</p>

<p>The added length of these umbrellas is intended to provide passengers behind the shield extra time to escape to safety.</p>

<p>A JR West official stated, "Previous protective shields were bulky and designed for close-range use. We've developed a shield that's lightweight and easier for female employees to handle."</p>

<p>The umbrella-like design makes it more compact, lightweight, and easier to store and use compared to other defense tools, such as the traditional Japanese sasumata-a long forked polearm-which was used during an attempted robbery in Tokyo late last year.</p>

<p>JR West president, Kazuaki Hasegawa, stated, "These umbrellas can be effectively used inside a train carriage and are durable. In an emergency, we want the crew to respond quickly and ensure passengers evacuate safely."</p>

<p>While violent crimes are uncommon in Japan, recent concerns over random knife attacks have led train operators to step up security measures, such as installing more cameras and conducting safety drills.</p>

<p>"We will continue to enhance passenger safety ahead of next year's Osaka-Kansai Expo," a JR West official told <em>The Japan News</em>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ehggd5k_umbrella_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The blade-proof umbrellas will act as shield in case of an attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-snapdeal-co-founder-kunal-bahls-success-mantra-no-iit-didnt-get-h1b-visa-but-6849022]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No IIT, Didn't Get H-1B Visa But...": Snapdeal Co-Founder's Success Mantra]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-snapdeal-co-founder-kunal-bahls-success-mantra-no-iit-didnt-get-h1b-visa-but-6849022]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 20:13:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The road to success is often paved with failure. At least that's how things turned out for entrepreneur and investor Kunal Bahl. He didn't get into IIT (something his parents were hoping for) but that didn't stop him from achieving massive success.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The road to success is often paved with failure. At least that's how things turned out for entrepreneur and investor Kunal Bahl. He didn't get into IIT (something his parents were hoping for) but that didn't stop him from achieving massive success in life.</p>

<p>"Many things that I wanted didn't go as per plan at that point in time but it set me on a path that was better for me. I didn't get into IIT but I got into a good US college that opened my mind and really helped me blossom," Mr Bahl said at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569">NDTV World Summit 2024</a>.</p>

<p>"So, at that point in time, it feels like you have failed, that's how society will make you feel. Like I said earlier come out of the bottom of that abyss, find that little bit of courage to continue. I remember the day I didn't get into IIT, everyone was upset in my family. I went and played three hours of cricket and picked up from where I left off," he added.</p>

<p>The Snapdeal and Titan Capital co-founder also said that his H-1B visa application was rejected but that led to the beginning of his entrepreneurial journey.</p>

<p>"I was working at Microsoft in the US and they applied for my H-1B visa. I thought I would live in the US for a few years. But one day I was sitting in my office and I got a one-line email that my H1b visa had been rejected and that's how I came back and started my journey as an entrepreneur. If you keep working with hardwork and sincerity, eventually success will follow," he said.</p>

<p>The H-1B visa is a non-immigrant visa that allows US companies to employ foreign workers in speciality occupations that require theoretical or technical expertise.</p>

<p>After returning to India, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ratan-tata-remembered-promise-made-in-passing-many-years-later-snapdeal-co-founder-kunal-bahl-at-ndtv-world-summit-6846414">Kunal Bahl</a> co-founded Snapdeal - a major e-commerce platform and Titan Capital, a venture capital firm that supports early-stage startups.</p>

<p>At the summit, he also explained why India should celebrate 'Indicorns'. "The term unicorn has emerged from the US, suited more to the American context, and India needs to celebrate 'Indicorns' with its own benchmarks of success and business goals tailored to the Indian context."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/shg97d48_kunal-bahl_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kunal Bahl speaking at NDTV World Summit 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/royal-caribbean-sued-after-former-staff-installs-hidden-camera-filming-1-000-passengers-6848883]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cruise Ship Sued After Ex-Staff Installs Hidden Camera, Films Passengers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/royal-caribbean-sued-after-former-staff-installs-hidden-camera-filming-1-000-passengers-6848883]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:51:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The complaint alleges the crew member transmitted images of passengers without consent, causing severe mental distress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A passenger on a Royal Caribbean International cruise has filed a class-action lawsuit against the company and a former crew member after a hidden camera was found in a bathroom, possibly filming up to 960 people, according to <em>USA Today.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p>The Southern District of Florida received the case, which was filed on behalf of a passenger known as "Jane Doe" and other impacted passengers from the Symphony of the Seas cruise, as per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/travel/cruises/2024/10/16/royal-caribbean-guest-sues-class-action/75704159007/?tbref=hp"><em>news portal.</em></a></p>

<p>The case comes after Arvin Joseph Mirasol, a Filipino stateroom attendant, was found guilty of creating child pornography and given a 30-year sentence in federal prison.</p>

<p>On February 25, a visitor reported the camera to ship security after finding it concealed beneath the bathroom sink. When the ship anchored in Fort Lauderdale, Mirasol was taken into custody.</p>

<p>Authorities found videos on Mirasol's devices showing children aged 2 to 17 in various stages of undress. However, the lawsuit alleges his illegal surveillance also targeted adult passengers.</p>

<p>"Upon information and belief, Mirasol transmitted and/or uploaded images of the Plaintiff while undressed and engaging in private activities, to third parties and/or to the world wide web, including, but not limited to, the dark web, without Plaintiff's prior knowledge or consent," the complaint filed this week states.</p>

<p>As a result, the traveller has experienced severe mental turmoil, which has led to physical symptoms like dizziness, insomnia, and discomfort.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/u2g76ut8_symphony-of-the-seas_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The lawsuit was filed on behalf of Symphony of the Seas passenger "Jane Doe."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-succeeded-despite-my-political-opinion-nas-daily-on-israel-question-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848841]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Succeeded Despite My Political Opinion": Nas Daily On 'Israel' Question]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-succeeded-despite-my-political-opinion-nas-daily-on-israel-question-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848841]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:48:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli vlogger Nuseir Yassin, who took the world of video content by storm with his Nas Daily channel, took a difficult personal question head-on.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli vlogger Nuseir Yassin, who took the world of video content by storm with his Nas Daily channel, took a difficult personal question head-on when, at the NDTV World Summit, somebody asked him whether he'd have found the kind of success he enjoys today had his political opinion been something else.</p>

<p>After Nas Daily gave a presentation at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569">NDTV World Summit</a> held in Delhi on the evolution of content creation and delivery, he agreed to take questions from the audience.</p>

<p>"You're an Israeli citizen of Palestinian descent. Do you think - you can say yes or no - the kind of success you have and the sort of political opinion, if you had a different political opinion, do you think you'd have been successful this way?" a member of the audience asked.</p>

<p>Nas Daily responded, "That's a great question. Did I succeed because of my political opinion?"</p>

<p>"So, my friend, I succeeded despite my political opinion, not because of it," Nas Daily said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hpblvfv_nas-daily_625x300_22_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"And you have no idea how difficult it is. Israel is eight million people; the Muslim world is a billion people. There's 200 million in Indonesia, 200 million in Pakistan, 100 million in Egypt, 100 million in Libya and Tunisia, another 200 million in Bangladesh, right?</p>

<p>"If I just make what is popular, and say 'oh yeah yeah yeah free Palestine, I'm with everybody', then I'd literally gain followers, I'd succeed more. I wouldn't need security. But that is what I believe in. I believe that the truth is a little bit more nuanced, that it's not black and white. It's actually grey because unfortunately, I spent 30 years studying and living this conflict.</p>

<p>"So, somebody sitting in Pakistan or Indonesia telling me what to think about this conflict, I wouldn't listen to him," said Nas Daily, who rose to global fame with his Facebook page and YouTube channel, where he ran a project to create and publish a daily one-minute video for 1,000 consecutive days.</p>

<p>Each video, known as a "Nas Daily" video, featured him sharing stories, experiences, and insights from his travels around the world. He eventually launched a media company, Nas Daily Corporation.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gb9uu9s8_nas-daily_625x300_22_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"... My political opinion, which I make very clear, that we need two states for two people, but also we need to free Palestine from Hamas, from radicalism, from terrorism. I am not for that at all. I think Israel should exist. Every time I say the 'I' word, which is Israel, I lose followers. Every time I say the 'I' word, which is the country I am from, I lose brand deals.</p>

<p>"So, I succeeded despite being cancelled more than 10 times. Because the videos are just so damn good, you're willing to listen to somebody from Israel even though you hate Israel so much. And the lesson here I think for everybody is - there is this amazing picture of one guy standing and a 10,000 people and the guy says 'You're all wrong'. I want everybody to think about this picture, 'You're all wrong'.</p>

<p>"What are you willing to stand in front of 10,000 people who disagree with you and tell them 'You're all wrong'? What is something you deeply believe in, that is deeply, deeply unpopular? For me, it is the Israel-Palestine conflict. But for you it is something else. It is a great exercise for every single person sitting here.</p>

<p>"What is something you deeply believe in that everybody around you still disagrees with? Yet for some reason you still believe in it. I think that is what you should make videos about," Nas Daily said.</p>

<p>At the event, continuing NDTV's legacy of pioneering media, NDTV World was launched; it aims to be a leading voice from Asia and India on the global stage.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lhu7oif8_nas-daily_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nas Daily at the NDTV World Summit in New Delhi on Tuesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/semiconductor-mission-amitabh-kant-on-why-it-is-dangerous-to-rely-solely-on-chip-imports-6848816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amitabh Kant On Why It Is "Dangerous" To Rely Solely On Chip Imports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/semiconductor-mission-amitabh-kant-on-why-it-is-dangerous-to-rely-solely-on-chip-imports-6848816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:42:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Rs 76,000 crore "Semiconductor Mission" of the government is a critical move in view of possible Chinese control of the semiconductor market, G20 Sherpa Amitabh Kant told NDTV in an exclusive interview today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Rs 76,000 crore "Semiconductor Mission" of the government is a critical move in view of possible Chinese control of the semiconductor market, G20 Sherpa Amitabh Kant told NDTV in an exclusive interview today. Speaking at the "NDTV World Summit", Mr Kant said it is a very risky proposition for countries to be dependent on chip manufacturers from abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Calling the government's Semiconductor Mission a "most dynamic measure", he said it would be transformational in the years to come.<br />
To explain this, he referred to a book on "chips war" by Chris Miller. "It says if China were to annex Taiwan tomorrow, it would control automobiles, batteries, defence and aerospace," he said. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Because the whole world will be running on chips. That's why for countries to be totally dependent on chip manufacturing from abroad is a dangerous proposition and therefore India must build its own ecosystem because we are a very large consumer of automobiles, of mobiles... every Indian has a smartphone and you need chips for that," he said.</p>

<p>Even now, global supply chains across the world are badly disrupted because the US imposed huge duty on imports from China, he said -- 100 per cent on electric vehicles, 50 per cent on batteries, on solar imports, to name a few.</p>

<p>The logic US applies is that China subsidises manufacturing, their government supports it. "Therefore they are doing extra production to penetrate global markets and that is why China is controlling 70 per cent EV market, 75 per cent of solar market, 74 per cent of the battery market... So we must put an end to this power supply on global market," he added. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Semiconductor is a foundational industry and semiconductor chips are used in medical instruments, mobile phones, laptops, cars, trucks, trains, televisions and practically every device. India's semiconductor-related market will reach 64 billion dollars in 2026, nearly triple the size in 2019.</p>

<p>Earlier today, participating in the Summit, Mark Mobius, the founder of Mobius Capital Partners LLP, expressed hope that India would be tomorrow's leader in semiconductor production, given its strong software base and the availability of labour.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The government is working towards making the country the next big semiconductor hub. The Central government has cleared five semiconductor manufacturing proposals, with a total combined investment of around Rs 1.52 lakh crore.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/80j4upu_amitabh-kant-_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-challenge-is-to-create-2-americas-in-5-decades-amitabh-kant-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848711]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India's Challenge Is To Create 2 Americas In 5 Decades": Amitabh Kant]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-challenge-is-to-create-2-americas-in-5-decades-amitabh-kant-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848711]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:29:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's road to becoming a developed country will require immense ambition and a focus on manufacturing, urbanisation and "firing on all cylinders", the country's G20 Sherpa Amitabh Kant has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's road to becoming a developed country will require immense ambition and a focus on manufacturing, urbanisation and "firing on all cylinders", the country's G20 Sherpa Amitabh Kant has said.</p>

<p>In a conversation during the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569">NDTV World Summit</a> on Tuesday, Mr Kant said 500 million people will get into the process of urbanisation in India in the next five decades, which means India will have to create "two Americas" in the same time period.</p>

<p>Responding to a question on India's demographic dividend and the need for reskilling, Mr Kant, who is also a former CEO of the Niti Aayog, said, "India can't grow only on the back of services, it needs to become a manufacturing nation. 17.5% of your GDP comes from manufacturing, you need to take it to 25%. You need to urbanise because 500 million people are going to get into the process of urbanisation in the next five decades, that means India's challenge is to create two Americas in the next five decades."</p>

<p>Mr Kant stressed that there is a need to improve agricultural productivity and bring down the proportion of people involved in agriculture from the nearly 45% it is now.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"So you need to fire on all cylinders - services, manufacturing, urbanisation, agriculture, all of them. And for manufacturing and urbanisation, you need to provide skills. You need to get them (the workforce) into completely new areas of growth - artificial intelligence, machine learning, quantum computing - and that's why India has rolled out these new missions in all these areas, including a mission for semiconductors and a mission for green hydrogen," he said. &nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Number Crunching</strong></p>

<p>On the question of <em>'atmanirbharta'</em> or self-reliance, the former Niti Aayog CEO said it involves India being an integral part of global value chains.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You can't grow at rates of 9-10% year after year for three decades or more - that's what you need to do - so when we are talking of a <em>'viksit'</em> (developed) Bharat or a $30-trillion economy in &nbsp;2047, growing from 4 trillion to 30 trillion means that your GDP has to grow nine times, your per capita income has to grow 8 times and your manufacturing has to grow 16 times, that's the challenge. And to overcome that challenge, India needs to become a very integral part of global value chains," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Kant said India needs to export in a big way and that is why there has been a thrust on the production-linked investment scheme.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;"You need 10,000 large manufacturing companies here to penetrate global markets. You need size and scale of manufacturing, and you need 12 Indian states to grow at 10% plus. So you need ambition and hunger in states to grow rapidly and you need large companies to penetrate global markets," he said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/spfnlfdg_amitabh-kant_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The former Niti Aayog CEO said there is also a need to improve agricultural productivity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-newborns-to-wear-patriotism-national-flag-as-first-outfit-for-babies-6848617]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Newborns To Wear Patriotism: National Flag As Outfit For Babies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-newborns-to-wear-patriotism-national-flag-as-first-outfit-for-babies-6848617]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:18:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new initiative in Russia proposes draping newborns in the national tricolour flag at birth to promote patriotism from an early age.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A contentious new program in Russia suggests draping newborns in the flag after they are born, according to <em>The Metro</em>. Although patriotism is a noble virtue, some people wonder if it is acceptable to begin such symbolic demonstrations at such a young age.</p>

<p>Tatyana Butskaya, a fervent pro-war MP, advocated for patriotic presents in the Russian tricolour of white, blue, and red for every newborn child. The gifts should be given to babies nationwide starting next year, according to Butskaya, deputy chairperson of the Russian parliament's committee on Family Protection, Fatherhood, Motherhood, and Childhood.</p>

<p>"This is when you are a patriot from birth. This is when you have a tricolour, a coat of arms, your first clothes, which say that you were born in Russia, that you are needed for Russia, that you are important, that you are loved from birth," Mr Butskaya told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/10/21/putin-mps-bizarre-drive-wrap-newborn-babies-russian-flag-21837095/"><em>The Metro.</em></a> "We really want every child born in any region to be able to receive such a gift."</p>

<p>According to <em>The Metro,</em> 49-year-old Butskaya has also drawn up a blueprint for Russian employers to coerce women to have babies to meet the Kremlin dictator's aim to massively boost the birth rate.</p>

<p>She added, "Large families are becoming the new elite. [Regional] governors should report on the birth rate...Each employer should look at their workplace; what is your birth rate? Here on your team. Do you have one more child this year from each person who can give birth to a child this year-or not?"</p>

<p>"This is exactly how we should pose this question... we will monitor it. In a year, our task is, of course, to increase it."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s2f7k0jo_russian-newborns_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The idea aims to provide patriotic gifts to every child born in the country starting next year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-reveals-wartime-food-stockpiling-strategy-amid-tensions-with-china-6848599]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taiwan Reveals Wartime Food Stockpiling Strategy Amid Tensions With China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-reveals-wartime-food-stockpiling-strategy-amid-tensions-with-china-6848599]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:13:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwan's government offered rare details on Tuesday of its wartime food plan, saying it is taking monthly inventories of crucial supplies like rice and making sure they are properly stored across the island in case of a Chinese blockade.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan's government offered rare details on Tuesday of its wartime food plan, saying it is taking monthly inventories of crucial supplies like rice and making sure they are properly stored across the island in case of a Chinese blockade.</p>

<p>China, which views democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory, has over the past fives years staged almost daily military activities around the island, including war games that have practised blockades and attacks on ports. Taiwan's government rejects Beijing's sovereignty claims.</p>

<p>China's latest war games around the island, carried out last week, included blockading key ports and areas, and assaulting maritime and ground targets, Beijing said.</p>

<p>In a report to parliament about preparations in case of a Chinese blockade, a copy of which was reviewed by Reuters, Taiwan's agriculture ministry said it has ensured that rice stock piles were above a three-month level as required by law and that food supplies were stored across the island in a bid to "lower attack risks".</p>

<p>The ministry said Taiwan's current rice stocks were enough to support the island for at least seven months and plans on rice rationing through supply stations across the island were being made in case of a food crisis.</p>

<p>During a blockade, more farmland will be used to grow rice, the ministry said, adding it will also prioritise growing sweet potatoes, soy beans and fresh vegetables as well as using more ponds for aquaculture.</p>

<p>In a scenario in which sea fishing is not allowed, the ministry said the island's fish feed inventory will be enough to support fishing in ponds for more than three months.</p>

<p>The ministry said it was planning to set up a task force to ensure food supply safety by taking a monthly inventory of the island's food resources.</p>

<p>Taiwan, a farming powerhouse during Japanese colonial rule from 1895 to 1945, depends on imports for the majority of its food needs as farm land was taken over for factories during rapid industrialisation starting in the 1960s.</p>

<p>Taiwan's food self-sufficiency rate in 2023 dropped to 30.3%, the lowest level in 18 years, according a previous report from the ministry.</p>

<p>In a separate report to parliament on preparations for the same scenario, the National Security Bureau said China's cyber forces were honing their skills to infiltrate key online infrastructure like telecoms in a bid to destabilise Taiwan with misinformation during a conflict with China.</p>

<p>Additionally, over the past two years, China has carried out "joint combat readiness patrols" near Taiwan three to four times per month, the bureau added.</p>

<p>The number of tanker aircraft used for aerial refuelling, landing ships and other forces participating in the training has been gradually increased, it said.</p>

<p>"This underscores that the communist military has continued to escalate its military threat against Taiwan in an effort to establish a blockade and control of our external sea lines of communication," the bureau said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e6mstr5_taiwan-wartime-food_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taiwan plans to set up a task force to ensure food supply . (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-after-outcome-in-border-talks-pm-narendra-modi-xi-jinping-arrive-in-russia-6848369]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Day After Outcome In Border Talks, PM Modi, Xi Jinping Arrive In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-after-outcome-in-border-talks-pm-narendra-modi-xi-jinping-arrive-in-russia-6848369]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:05:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi today began his two-day official visit to Russia, his second in three months, to attend the BRICS Summit. The prime minister will attend the summit in Russia's Kazan with Russia's Putin, China's Xi Jinping, Brazil's Lula.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today began his two-day official visit to Russia, his second in three months, to attend the BRICS Summit. The prime minister will attend the summit in Russia's Kazan with Russia's Putin, China's Xi Jinping, Brazil's Lula da Silva, and South Africa's Cyril Ramaphosa.</p>

<p>Besides the key international forum, the prime minister's visit assumes significance on two accounts - the role India is playing to broker peace between Russia and Ukraine, and the breakthrough in talks with China over the situation along the Line of Actual Control in Ladakh.</p>

<p>Ahead of the BRICS summit, PM Modi emphasised the importance of close cooperation by member states. Upon his arrival in Kazan, the prime minister wrote in a post on X saying "This is an important summit, and the discussions here will contribute to a better planet."</p>

<h2><strong>WILL PM MODI AND XI JINPING MEET IN RUSSIA?</strong></h2>

<p>India and China have established a patrolling mechanism along the Line of Actual Control (LAC), marking a potential step towards easing tensions that escalated in May 2020," Vikram Misri, India's Foreign Secretary announced yesterday.</p>

<p>The External Affairs Minister, S Jaishankar hailed the recent LAC agreement as a positive outcome of "patient and persistent diplomacy."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"... At various points of time people almost gave up. We have always maintained on the one hand we obviously had to do counter deployment, and we have been negotiating since September 2020. It has been a very patient process, though more complicated than how it should have been," Mr. Jaishankar said at the NDTV World Summit.</p>

<p>"The important thing is if we have reached an understanding, I think what it does is it creates a basis for peace and tranquility along the border, which were there before 2020. That was a major concern. If there is no peace and tranquility, how can other areas of bilateral ties improve?" Mr. Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>With both PM Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping attending the BRICS Summit in Russia a day after India and China had a breakthrough in talks over the standoff along the Line of Actual Control, it is to be seen if both leaders will meet or hold talks on the sidelines of the summit. Neither side has confirmed a meeting yet.</p>

<h3><strong>MEDIATING PEACE BETWEEN RUSSIA AND UKRAINE</strong></h3>

<p>In his opening statement during his meeting with Vladimir Putin, PM Modi said he wanted the Ukraine conflict to be resolved "peacefully and quickly".</p>

<p>The two leaders shook hands and followed that up with a hug when they met for talks on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit. At the meeting PM Modi said, "We have been in constant touch over the conflict between Russia and Ukraine."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5n47205s_modi-putin-hug-pti_625x300_22_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"We believe that disputes should only be resolved peacefully. We totally support efforts to quickly restore peace and stability," PM Modi added.</p>

<p>New Delhi has walked a diplomatic tightrope since the Ukraine conflict began, pledging humanitarian support for Kyiv while avoiding explicit condemnation of Russia's offensive.</p>

<p>In his opening remarks, President Putin hailed Russia and India's "privileged strategic partnership" and vowed to build ties further.&nbsp;</p>

<p>PM Modi visited Kyiv in August and Moscow in July in an effort to encourage talks, as India cast itself as a potential mediator. In both countries he was welcomed with a warm embrace. Both Putin and Zelensky have remained in close contact with PM Modi over the duration of the Ukraine conflict - as India has a unique position maintaining friendly relations with both nations.</p>

<p>After his visit to Kyiv, Prime Minister Modi reportedly sent National Security Adviser Ajit Doval to Moscow with a "peace plan", which was reportedly handed over to President Putin when Mr Doval had a meeting with him.</p>

<p>During his meeting with President Zelenskyy, Prime Minister Modi reiterated his commitment to peace and sustainable development. He emphasised that without peace, long-term progress is impossible. While the outcome of the war remains uncertain, India continues to advocate for a peaceful resolution," said Mr. Misri.</p>

<p>India's initiative to broker peace between Russia and Ukraine has been praised by US President Joe Biden and several European leaders too. President Biden had also praised India's prominent global role, including Prime Minister Modi's leadership in the G20 and Global South, as well as his efforts to strengthen the Quad, ensuring a free, open, and prosperous Indo-Pacific.</p>

<h3><strong>AGENDA FOR THE 16th BRICS SUMMIT</strong></h3>

<p>Apart from leaders of the 5 founding member states, some two dozen other leaders are also attending the summit, including Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan and UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres.</p>

<p>The main issues on the agenda include Vladimir Putin's idea for a BRICS-led payment system to rival SWIFT, an international financial network that Russian banks were cut off from in 2022, and the escalating conflict in the Middle East.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vgklbbbk_narendra-modi-xi-jinping-modi-xi-ians_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping arrived in Russia for the BRICS Summit (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-claims-drone-attack-on-netanyahu-says-some-of-its-fighters-captured-6848518]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Claims Drone Attack On Netanyahu's Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-claims-drone-attack-on-netanyahu-says-some-of-its-fighters-captured-6848518]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:03:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah claimed responsibility Tuesday for a drone attack last week targeting the home of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, and acknowledged that some of its fighters have been taken captive by the Israeli army.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah claimed responsibility Tuesday for a drone attack last week targeting the home of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, and acknowledged that some of its fighters have been taken captive by the Israeli army.</p>

<p>Hezbollah spokesman Mohammed Afif made the remarks during a press conference in Beirut's southern suburbs that was cut short following an Israeli evacuation warning for the area.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike hit a target hundreds of metres (yards) away from the site of the conference just minutes after journalists left, an AFP video journalist said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah "declares its full, complete and exclusive responsibility for the Caesarea operation targeting... Netanyahu", Afif said.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Netanyahu accused Hezbollah of attempting to assassinate him and his wife after a drone was launched towards his residence in the central town of Caesarea.</p>

<p>Afif also acknowledged that some of the group's fighters were captured by the Israeli army without giving numbers.</p>

<p>"On the issue of captives currently held by the enemy, I say: I know that the enemy is not committed to the ethics of war and international conventions but it bears the responsibility of preserving the lives of the captives," Afif said.</p>

<p>Previously, the Israeli army said it has captured a total of four Hezbollah fighters since the start of its ground offensive in Lebanon, and released video footage it said showed one of them answering questions.</p>

<p>Afif also said the group's micro-financing firm Al-Qard al-Hassan took all necessary precautions ahead of Israeli strikes last week, vowing to "fulfil its obligations" towards depositors.</p>

<p>The firm "had anticipated such... an aggression and has taken all precautions and will do everything that is necessary to fulfil its obligations towards depositors," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d6gt7fbo_netanyahu-home-attack_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier, drone was launched towards Netanyahu's residence in Caesarea. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-is-inevitable-will-bring-in-new-kinds-of-jobs-amitabh-kant-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848500]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["AI Inevitable, Will Bring In New Kinds Of Jobs": Amitabh Kant At NDTV Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-is-inevitable-will-bring-in-new-kinds-of-jobs-amitabh-kant-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848500]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:01:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The advance of AI, or Artificial Intelligence, is inevitable, and will bring in "new kinds of jobs", Amitabh Kant, India's G20 Sherpa, said Tuesday night at the NDTV World Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The advance of AI, or <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/artificial-intelligence" target="_blank">Artificial Intelligence</a>, is inevitable, and will bring in "new kinds of jobs... new scales of jobs", <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/amitabh-kant" target="_blank">Amitabh Kant</a>, India's G20 Sherpa, said Tuesday night at the NDTV World Summit.</p>

<p>Artificial Intelligence, Mr Kant also said, must be used to create a "better society (and) improve human development in place of creating LLMs", referring to Large Language Models, which are a type of machine learning that can carry out natural language processing, or NLP, tasks.</p>

<p>"All this talk about AI is about LLMs. But AI should impact the lives of the citizens. So, you need AI for improving learning outcomes, health outcomes... you need it for improving nutritional standards... AI should be used to improve the quality of lives," he said at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569" target="_blank">NDTV World Summit</a>.</p>

<p>"AI should not be used just to create LLMs which could be in conflict tomorrow over ethical concerns because of assumptions on which they are based," Mr Kant added, "Therefore it is very critical that we divert AI for transforming the lives of citizens."</p>

<p>Asked if AI will take over existing jobs - a worrying scenario for critics of the technology - Mr Kant responded, "AI is inevitable... but it will bring in new kinds of jobs... and therefore we need to create many more skilled people in these areas (referring to data sciences, machine learning, etc.)."</p>

<p>"And that is what many of our IITs are doing today," he said.</p>

<p>AI has been a recurring topic at the NDTV Summit, right from the opening remarks by Prime Minister Narendra Modi. Speaking on Monday, Mr Modi said his government is committed to increase the use of AI in each sector of the economy.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/second-ai-in-india-aspirational-india-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836601" target="_blank">"India Has Double AI Power": What PM Said At NDTV World Summit</a></p>

<p>"This is the era of AI and the future of the world is linked with it," he said, pointing out also, "India is powered by two AIs. For the world, it is Artificial Intelligence but for us it is 'aspirational India' + Artificial Intelligence. When the two meet, it accelerates India's growth."&nbsp;</p>

<p>And, earlier today, in a panel discussion on AI innovation in the country,&nbsp;top business leaders from the private sector called for AI to become part of the education system.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-ai-innovation-is-yet-to-take-root-in-india-panel-at-ndtv-world-summit-answers-6847678" target="_blank">Panel At NDTV Summit On Why AI Innovation Is Yet To Take Off In India</a></p>

<p>As India, and the world, explores the world of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, there were also some voices of caution at the NDTV World Summit.&nbsp;Bharti Group Chairman Sunil Mittal&nbsp;acknowledged AI will become among the most important drivers of the world economy, but also&nbsp;said new tech will pose new challenges, including potential for misuse and hence need vigilance.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/have-to-protect-society-from-ai-sunil-bharti-mittal-at-ndtv-world-summit-6839752" target="_blank">"Have To Protect Society From AI": Sunil Bharti Mittal At NDTV Summit</a></p>

<p>Mr Mittal&nbsp;cited a personal anecdote on how a senior finance official stationed in Dubai received a fraudulent call that seemed to mimic Mittal's voice and tone, and directed a large fund transfer.</p>

<h3><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-challenge-is-to-create-2-americas-in-5-decades-amitabh-kant-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848711" target="_blank"><strong>"Challenge Is To Create 2 Americas In 5 Decades"</strong></a></h3>

<p>On the larger question of India's economic development - specifically the target of becoming the world's third-largest economy by 2030 - Mr Kant stressed the need for reskilling and taking advantage of the country's younger demographic, as well as jumpstarting manufacturing.</p>

<p>"Growing from a $4 trillion to a $30 trillion economy means your GDP has to grow nine times... your per capita income eight times... and the manufacturing sector by 16 times. That is the challenge... and to overcome that India needs to become a key part of the (global) value chain," he told NDTV.</p>

<p>"You need to urbanise because 500 million people are going to get into the process of urbanisation in the next five decades (and) that means India's challenge is to create two Americas..." he said.</p>

<p>Mr Kant also stressed on the need to make the agriculture sector more efficient and allow India to bring down the proportion of people involved in that sector - from the nearly 45 per cent it is now - without affecting food security.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aq2fvj28_amitabh-kant-_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/budget-social-work-like-monthly-expenses-philanthropist-nidarshana-gowani-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848382]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Budget Social Work Like Monthly Expenses: Philanthropist Nidarshana Gowani]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/budget-social-work-like-monthly-expenses-philanthropist-nidarshana-gowani-at-ndtv-world-summit-6848382]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:50:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Like monthly electricity bills and a monthly budget for shopping, people should also earmark funds on a regular basis for social work,Nidarshana Gowani, founder of AnkhibaiGhamandiram Gowani Trust, advised.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like monthly electricity bills and a monthly budget for shopping, people should also earmark funds on a regular basis for social work,&nbsp;Nidarshana Gowani, founder of Ankhibai&nbsp;Ghamandiram Gowani Trust, advised.</p>

<p>Ms Gowani detailed the work her organisation does for tribals, transgenders, sex workers and for making the HPV vaccine reach maximum benefactors. "Transgenders have their woes. They are getting educated, they are often back dancers in music videos. But they complain about not getting their rights, or access to schemes or employment equitably," she said at the NDTV World Summit 2024.</p>

<p>Sex workers also live far from their home and work to care for their parents and educate their children, she said. "We do fixed deposits for them from the post office, which mature in three years. Those funds can be used by the sex workers to start businesses," Ms Gowani said.</p>

<p>Ms Gowani said technology plays an important role in making philanthropic initiatives reach the people, while also making the youth aware about the sufferings of people and how we need to give back to the society. She added that charity begins at home and imparting values of giving to children at home imprints on their personality. "The social work you do will be carried on as legacy by your kids," she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9sndo1jo_nidarshana-gowani_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-peace-talks-may-hinge-on-us-election-outcome-zelensky-6848294]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine-Russia Peace Talks May Hinge On US Election Outcome: Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-peace-talks-may-hinge-on-us-election-outcome-zelensky-6848294]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:38:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said the prospect of peace talks with Russia "depends" on the outcome of next month's US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said the prospect of peace talks with Russia "depends" on the outcome of next month's US presidential election.</p>

<p>Asked whether he thought Moscow was ready for negotiations with Kyiv, Zelensky told journalists in comments released Tuesday: "First of all, it depends on the elections in the United States. I think they will be watching the policy of the United States."</p>

<p>Zelensky said based on conversations with the two candidates, he expects the United States to "demonstrate the policy very quickly, after the elections... they will not wait until January."</p>

<p>Donald Trump has repeatedly expressed scepticism of Washington's military and financial support for Kyiv, and there are fears a victory for the Republican candidate could create problems for Kyiv as it battles Russian forces in the east and south.</p>

<p>But Zelensky said he had held "good" meetings with both Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic candidate.</p>

<p>"I had a good meeting with Trump. It was very positive. And I'm glad about that. I had a very good meeting with Harris, not the first one," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian leader also said he believed that Germany was "afraid" of how Russia would react if Ukraine were invited to join the NATO military alliance.</p>

<p>"It is a fact that the German side is sceptical about us joining NATO," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>"They are afraid of the NATO-Germany issue in terms of the Russian reaction."</p>

<p>The Ukrainian leader has called for an immediate invite to join NATO as part of his "victory plan," triggering a furious reaction in Moscow.</p>

<p>He said he believed France and Britain supported him, and said the response of Germany and other NATO countries like Hungary and Slovakia also "depends on the United States."</p>

<p>Zelensky was speaking to reporters in Kyiv on Monday, in remarks embargoed until Tuesday.</p>

<p>Kyiv relies on Western support to fight the Russian invasion, dragging through its third year.</p>

<p>Moscow's forces are advancing on the battlefield, where they have superiority in manpower and equipment against Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7ccbgih8_zelensky-afp_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky said he had held "good" meetings with both Trump and Kamala Harris. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-lawmaker-andy-kerbrat-caught-buying-designer-drug-in-street-deal-6848149]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Lawmaker Caught Buying Designer Drug In Street Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-lawmaker-andy-kerbrat-caught-buying-designer-drug-in-street-deal-6848149]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:17:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A French far-left lawmaker admitted on Tuesday to having been caught by police after purchasing a synthetic drug from an underage supplier in a street deal, earning him a sharp rebuke from France's law-and-order interior minister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A French far-left lawmaker admitted on Tuesday to having been caught by police after purchasing a synthetic drug from an underage supplier in a street deal, earning him a sharp rebuke from France's law-and-order interior minister.</p>

<p>Andy Kerbrat, 34, a member of parliament for the France Unbowed (LFI) party was picked up by police on October 17 carrying 1.35 grams of 3-Methylmethcathinone, prosecutors told AFP.</p>

<p>The teenage seller had one gram of the synthetic drug on him, as well as 200 euros ($216) in cash, they added.</p>

<p>3-MMC is a designer drug intended to mimic the effects of cocaine at about half the street price.</p>

<p>Kerbrat, who was not detained, is being investigated for illicit narcotics use.</p>

<p>Posting his admission on X, Kerbrat said he would seek medical attention for his addiction.</p>

<p>LFI's parliamentary leader Mathilde Panot said that "addiction is a health issue", adding she hoped Kerbrat could quickly return to his National Assembly post.</p>

<p>Green party MP Sandrine Rousseau was also supportive, saying: "You admitted everything. You are getting treatment. Come back to us in good shape."</p>

<p>But hardline Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau, known for his law-and-order credentials, said Kerbrat needed to "draw the consequences of his actions".</p>

<p>Also on X, Retailleau said MPs had "a duty" to show "exemplary" behaviour.</p>

<p>"It is intolerable to see a deputy of the French republic buy synthetic drugs from a street dealer," the minister said.</p>

<p>The popularity of 3-MMC is growing fast in France, where it is mostly used as a party drug.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f5o8jhj8_andy-kerbat_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andy Kerbrat, who was not detained, is being investigated for illicit narcotics use.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/brics-wants-to-reshape-us-led-economic-order-it-wont-be-easy-6848088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: BRICS+ Wants To Reshape US-Led Economic Order. It Won't Be Easy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/brics-wants-to-reshape-us-led-economic-order-it-wont-be-easy-6848088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:10:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With Western sanctions faced by Russia in the wake of its war in Ukraine, Moscow is most keen to push the idea through not just to break the dollar's dominance but also to showcase to the West that it still has allies and partners on its side.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hifkia7o_brics_625x300_22_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It is 15 years since its first summit. Back then. BRICS was BRIC. And now, it's not just BRICS but BRICS+. The summit in Kazan is seeing the member nations go up from five to nine, with one more, Saudi Arabia, having been invited to join. According to Russian foreign minister Sergei Lavrov, there are 30 more countries that have been in touch over joining the BRICS+ in some format or the other.</p>

<p>When Goldman Sach's economist Jim O'Neill coined the acronym BRIC and predicted that the economies of the four member countries - Brazil, Russia, India, and China - would dominate the global economy by 2050, his projection was based only on the growth of the four nations. The grouping now represents a combined GDP that exceeds the G7's by "about 5 percentage points", said the Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov on the eve of the Summit. A briefing note of the European Parliament, titled <em>Expansion of BRICS: A Quest for Greater Global Influence</em>, says that BRICS+ accounts for 37.3% of the world's GDP. That is more than half as much as the European Union's 14.5%.</p>

<h2><strong>"Artificial Efforts To Maintain Dollar's Position"</strong></h2>

<p>Lavrov also lashed out at the US-led world order, saying, "The United States is unwilling to relinquish the reins of power that they have held since World War II through the Bretton Woods institutions and through the role assigned to the US dollar in the international monetary system, even after the free exchange of US dollars for gold had been cancelled. The leading position of this currency is maintained by efforts that are largely artificial."</p>

<p>The BRICS+ is in the process of taking the first step to break the dominance of the dollar, by a proposed launch of an international payment system that can circumvent the dollar. India's foreign secretary, Vikram Misri, confirmed that there had been discussions that had been underway on settlement systems and payment systems. However, he added that as per his understanding, no final agreements have been arrived at yet. "Yes, fundamentally, I think it is a fact that the countries have stressed the importance of the use of local currencies for settlement purposes especially as it comes to or as it pertains to trade. So, strengthening of correspondent banking networks amongst the BRICS partners and enabling settlements in local currencies is being encouraged," he added.</p>

<h2><strong>The Threat Of Sanctions</strong></h2>

<p>With Western sanctions faced by Russia in the wake of its war in Ukraine, Moscow is most keen to push the idea through not just to break the dollar's dominance but also to showcase to the West that it still has allies and partners on its side. Iran, the new BRICS+ member, also faces crippling US sanctions and Moscow hopes for support from the members that have increasingly felt that the West-dominated economic order has short-changed the rest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ahead of the Summit, Russian Finance Minister Anton Siluanov also called for new institutions, similar to the Bretton Woods institutions, saying the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank are not performing their roles. However, the big question is whether a member country like China, which has been a beneficiary of the current global world order, will seek a new parallel system altogether when it is pushing for reforms along with countries like India.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Reforming The IMF</strong></h2>

<p>In a recent IMF publication by India's former Governor of the Central Bank, Raghuram Rajan sought not just quota reforms in IMF but also a change in the body's governance to make it both fair and more representative of the current global realities. He said if members reform quotas and governance simultaneously, an independent IMF could bring a fragmenting world together on key issues. "Such comprehensive reforms should happen soon; else the rest could well believe this is an attempt by the Western alliance to hold on to some influence just when power is finally shifting."</p>

<p>However, the BRICS+ also has its task cut out. Much will depend on the US presidential election outcome too. For example, Donald Trump has said that he will penalise countries that move away from the dollar by imposing a 100% tariff on their goods.</p>

<p>According to the IMF, the dollar remains a dominant force, with 59% of official foreign exchange reserves in the first quarter of 2024, and the euro second at approximately 20%.</p>

<p>Amidst all the speculation, all eyes are keenly trained on Russia for any indication in this direction during the two-day event. The announcement, if any, will have even greater significance because it will come from a country that is at direct loggerheads with the Western world.</p>

<p><em>(Maha Siddiqui is a journalist who has extensively reported on public policy and global affairs.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5rvms9lo_brics_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>