<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:17:36 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-can-influence-end-of-ukraine-war-volodymyr-zelenskyy-6891324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Can Influence End Of Ukraine War: Volodymyr Zelenskyy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-can-influence-end-of-ukraine-war-volodymyr-zelenskyy-6891324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:17:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Let PM Modi bring back 1,000 Ukrainian children at least, President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says in an interview.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has said he believes Prime Minister Narendra Modi can help end the war with Russia. “This is the huge value of him in any conflict. This is a huge value of India,” he said in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sUkmGyn_SSk" rel="nofollow,noindex">an exclusive interview with the Times of India</a>.</p>

<p>At the recent BRICS Summit, PM Modi had expressed his desire to work for peace in the context of the Ukraine war. Sharing his thoughts on the Prime Minister's speech, Zelenskyy said, “Modi is the PM of a really huge country - from the perspective of population, impact, influence and economy. Such a country cannot just say that it is interested in the end of a war. We are all interested in that. All of the leaders will tell you tomorrow that they would like to end the war… this is a very common thing, especially for such a huge country as India.”</p>

<p>Countries like India could easily facilitate the end of the war by blocking the Russian economy, the Ukraine president stressed.</p>

<p>“Real influence on blocking of the Russian economy, blocking of cheap energy resource, blocking of the defence-industrial complex of Russia will lead to the decrease in capacity of Moscow to wage wars against us,” he said. “Twenty great economies can put Putin in his place to end the war. They can do that. Not just incentivizing it but vice versa to slow down all of his desires and you don't need to say we would like peace. You need to act because daily war is killing people,” he added.</p>

<p>On what India can do specifically for Ukrainian children, he said PM Modi should bring back at least 1,000 children who were forcibly deported. “You can join the coalition of the bring back of children. You can call Putin and ask him who he is. You can force him to bring the children back. Prime Minister Modi can do that. He has really huge influence. He can just say specifically, how many Ukrainian children will be given to me so that I can bring them back to Ukraine. Just say that directly. Give me 1,000 children who will be brought back to Ukraine. This is the real step. Let PM Modi bring back only 1,000 at least,” he said.</p>

<p>If every such influential person as Prime Minister Modi can bring back 1,000, we will be able to bring back the majority of our children, said Zelenskyy, that's what's needed to be done.</p>

<p>“You need to raise this issue at the G20 meet,” he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ll34cfv_narendra-modi-with-volodymyr-zelenskyy-_625x300_21_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[20 great economies can put Putin in his place to end the war: President Volodymyr Zelenskyy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/google-to-develop-ai-that-takes-over-computers-the-information-reports-6891266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google To Develop AI That Takes Over Computers, The Information Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/google-to-develop-ai-that-takes-over-computers-the-information-reports-6891266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:07:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anthropic and Google are trying to take the agent concept a step further with software that interacts directly with a person's computer or browser, the report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alphabet's Google is developing artificial intelligence technology that takes over a web browser to complete tasks such as research and shopping, The Information reported on Saturday.</p>

<p>Google is set to demonstrate the product code-named Project Jarvis as soon as December with the release of its next flagship Gemini large language model, the report added, citing people with direct knowledge of the product.</p>

<p>Microsoft backed OpenAI also wants its models to conduct research by browsing the web autonomously with the assistance of a "CUA," or a computer-using agent, that can take actions based on its findings, Reuters reported in July.</p>

<p>Anthropic and Google are trying to take the agent concept a step further with software that interacts directly with a person's computer or browser, the report said.</p>

<p>Google didn't immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pupkjjvg_google-ai_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google is set to demonstrate the product code-named Project Jarvis as soon as December.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-apologies-no-excuses-rodrigo-duterte-on-philippine-drug-war-6891195]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Apologies, No Excuses": Rodrigo Duterte On Philippine Drug War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-apologies-no-excuses-rodrigo-duterte-on-philippine-drug-war-6891195]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:58:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Philippine president Rodrigo Duterte strongly defended his deadly drug war as he testified on Monday at a senate probe of the crackdown.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Philippine president Rodrigo Duterte strongly defended his deadly drug war as he testified on Monday at a senate probe of the crackdown.</p>

<p>Police said the campaign left more than 6,000 people dead, but rights groups estimate tens of thousands of mostly poor men were killed by officers and vigilantes, often without proof they were linked to drugs.</p>

<p>The International Criminal Court (ICC) is investigating allegations that the killings were a state-sanctioned "crime against humanity".</p>

<p>"Do not question my policies because I offer no apologies, no excuses. I did what I had to do, and whether or not you believe it or not, I did it for my country," Duterte, 79, said in an opening statement at the public hearing.</p>

<p>"I hate drugs, make no mistake about it."</p>

<p>During the anti-drug campaign he launched shortly after taking office in 2016, Duterte ordered police to shoot dead suspects if officers believed their lives were in danger.</p>

<p>While the crackdown has been widely condemned and sparked an international investigation, only nine police officers have been convicted for killing drug suspects.</p>

<p>The drug war has continued under Duterte's successor, Ferdinand Marcos, though he has pushed for more emphasis on prevention and rehabilitation.</p>

<p>While the current and former president have had a bitter falling out, Marcos has stressed his government will not cooperate with the ICC investigation.</p>

<p>The Philippines quit the ICC in 2019 on Duterte's instructions, but the tribunal has said it has jurisdiction over killings before the pullout, as well as killings in the southern city of Davao when Duterte was mayor there, years before he became president.</p>

<p>Duterte claimed Monday that "drug-related crimes are on the rise again", with daily reports of "children being raped, people getting killed" because "the purveyors of this menace are back in business".</p>

<p>"The Filipinos are anxious and distressed," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-04/8nboh3hs_philippine-president-rodrigo-duterte-reuters_625x300_02_April_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The drug war has continued under Duterte's successor, Ferdinand Marcos.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-man-dies-as-boat-deflates-while-trying-to-cross-english-channel-6891094]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Man Dies As Boat Deflates While Trying To Cross English Channel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-man-dies-as-boat-deflates-while-trying-to-cross-english-channel-6891094]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:42:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Record 56 people have so far died on the France-Britain route across the Channel in 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian man died on Sunday in an attempt to cross the Channel to Britain, French officials said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He had set off from the beach of Tardinghen in northern France but died when the vessel, which was in "very poor condition", deflated "immediately" after leaving the beach, officials said.</p>

<p>Not all the passengers had life jackets, but most on board were able to swim back to shore.</p>

<p>The man, around 40 years old, was in "cardio-respiratory arrest" and could not be revived by emergency services, officials said.</p>

<p>Record 56 people have so far died on the France-Britain route across the Channel in 2024.</p>

<p>Last week, two men and a woman were killed when their boat was wrecked around two kilometres offshore near the port city of Calais. The previous week, a four-month-old baby had died after a boat disintegrated.</p>

<p>According to officials, over 29,000 migrants have made it across the Channel since the start of 2024.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6v5mq5mg_english-channel-migrants_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Officials said he was in "cardio-respiratory arrest" (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/seven-states-that-will-decide-us-presidency-6890990]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Seven States That Will Decide US Presidency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/seven-states-that-will-decide-us-presidency-6890990]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:30:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris and former president Donald Trump are hurtling toward their November 5 election showdown, one of the closest contests in modern American history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris and former president Donald Trump are hurtling toward their November 5 election showdown, one of the closest contests in modern American history.</p>

<p>And in the handful of critical states framing the 2024 race, there is little daylight between the rivals with barely a week before Election Day.</p>

<p>Under the US Constitution, America's founding fathers established that each of the 50 states would hold its own vote for president.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Under the complex Electoral College system, each state has a certain number of "electors," based on population. Most states have a winner-take-all system that awards all electors to whoever wins the popular vote.</p>

<p>With candidates needing 270 of the 538 electoral votes to win, elections tend to be decided in the hotly contested "swing states" with a history of alternating between Republican and Democratic candidates.</p>

<p>This year, there are seven such battlegrounds, and every one is a toss-up within the margin of error. Here is a look:</p>

<p><strong>Pennsylvania (19 Electoral College votes)</strong></p>

<p>Pennsylvania was once reliably Democratic, but these days, they don't come much tighter than the Keystone State.</p>

<p>Republican Trump won the most populous battleground, with 13 million residents, by 0.7 percentage points in 2016. Joe Biden claimed it by 1.2 percentage points in 2020.</p>

<p>Known for its "Rust Belt" cities like Philadelphia and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania has been blighted for decades by the steady decline of its industrial manufacturing base.</p>

<p>Trump and Harris have campaigned repeatedly in the eastern state, where the pair held their one and only presidential debate. Trump, who survived an assassination attempt at a July rally in Pennsylvania, is courting the rural white population and warning that migrants are overwhelming small towns.</p>

<p>Harris is touting recent infrastructure wins, and in Pittsburgh she outlined plans to invest $100 billion in manufacturing, a key issue for state residents.</p>

<p><strong>Georgia (16)</strong></p>

<p>This southeastern state was an election flashpoint at the end of Trump's first term, and the controversy simmers.</p>

<p>Prosecutors in Georgia indicted Trump in an election interference case after he called state officials urging them to "find" enough votes to overturn Biden's narrow 2020 victory.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But in a boost for Trump, the case is paused until after the election.</p>

<p>Biden was the first Democrat to win the Peach State since 1992. Demographic changes are likely to benefit Harris, who has courted minority voters across Georgia.</p>

<p><strong>North Carolina (16)</strong></p>

<p>The southeastern state has voted Democratic only once since 1980, but Harris believes it's back in play.</p>

<p>The population, now over 10 million, is expanding and growing more diverse, benefiting Democrats.</p>

<p>Complicating matters for Trump, a scandal involving the state's Republican gubernatorial candidate has infuriated party officials who worry it could sink Trump in a close race.</p>

<p>As in neighboring Georgia, one wild card is how the devastation from storm Helene, which recently laid waste to towns in western North Carolina, might impact the vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Michigan (15)</strong></p>

<p>Trump flipped Michigan, a former Democratic stronghold, on his way to defeating Hillary Clinton in 2016.</p>

<p>Biden returned it to the blue column in 2020, buoyed by unionized workers and a large Black community.</p>

<p>But this time, Harris risks losing the support of a 200,000-strong Arab-American community that has denounced Biden's -- and by extension her -- handling of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.</p>

<p><strong>Arizona (11)</strong></p>

<p>The Grand Canyon state was among 2020's tightest races, with Biden triumphing by just 10,457 votes.</p>

<p>Trump hopes frustrations over the Biden-Harris administration's immigration policy will swing Arizona, which shares a border with Mexico, back in his favor.</p>

<p>Harris visited Arizona's border in September vowing to crack down on migration and work on reviving last year's bipartisan border bill, which she said Trump "tanked" for political purposes.</p>

<p><strong>Wisconsin (10)</strong></p>

<p>Clinton lost Wisconsin after giving the state a wide berth during the 2016 campaign.</p>

<p>As with Midwestern neighbor Michigan, it was a different story when Trump's opponent was Biden, who turned a 23,000-vote deficit into a winning margin of 21,000 for Democrats.</p>

<p>Trump considers it winnable, and his party held its summer national convention there.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While Trump led early against Biden, Harris has made the state race a nailbiter.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Nevada (6)</strong></p>

<p>The Silver State, with a population of 3.1 million, hasn't voted Republican since 2004. Conservatives, buoyed by Trump's headway with Hispanic voters, are convinced they can flip the script.</p>

<p>Trump held a significant lead here against Biden.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But within weeks of becoming the Democratic nominee, Harris -- promoting her economic plans to help small businesses and combat inflation -- has erased that advantage in the western state, whose largest city Las Vegas is dominated by the hospitality industry.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0t0a1ifg_us-election_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In the critical states framing the 2024 race, there is little daylight between the rivals.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-secret-train-evacuating-wounded-ukrainian-soldiers-6890901]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Secret Train Evacuating Wounded Ukrainian Soldiers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-secret-train-evacuating-wounded-ukrainian-soldiers-6890901]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:18:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nearly three years after Russian forces invaded Ukraine, many medical facilities in war-battered eastern Ukraine have been damaged or destroyed, while those left untouched are overcrowded.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It looks like an ordinary train waiting to depart an ordinary station, but through its fogged windows, a Ukrainian serviceman with face injuries lies stretched out on a gurney.</p>

<p>All of the other blue-and-yellow carriages of this train operated by the military are carrying wounded soldiers to hospitals away from the precarious front line.</p>

<p>Nearly three years after Russian forces invaded Ukraine, many medical facilities in war-battered eastern Ukraine have been damaged or destroyed, while those left untouched are overcrowded.</p>

<p>For Oleksandr, the army doctor overseeing the evacuation, there are clear benefits to rail: many people can be moved at once and it is safer than transporting wounded soldiers by helicopter, given Russian superiority in Ukraine's airspace.</p>

<p>But there are risks too.</p>

<p>"Our adversary in the war does not distinguish between what's medical and military, so we take certain security measures," the 46-year-old said.</p>

<p>AFP was recently granted rare media access to the train, whose points of departure and arrival are not being disclosed for security reasons.</p>

<p><strong>'Everything on the move'</strong></p>

<p>Ambulances arrived at the station carrying dozens of wounded troops who were then hauled onto the train on stretchers and settled on beds with floral-patterned sheets.</p>

<p>Ukrainian flags and hand-drawn pictures by children annotated with patriotic messages lined the walls inside the train.</p>

<p>The carriages resemble a hospital until the train rolls away from the platform and gently rocks patients and staff -- and everything else inside -- as it crawls farther from the front.</p>

<p>"We do everything on the move, everything. Starting from the usual intravenous injections, ending with incubations," said Viktorya, a nurse dressed in khaki and wearing blue medical gloves.</p>

<p>"We get dizzy afterwards," the 25-year-old said, standing in front of a window, the sweeping Ukrainian landscape rolling by.</p>

<p>The journeys to and from the front, where Ukraine is coming under increasing pressure, have given Viktorya a painful insight into the cost of the conflict grinding through its third year.</p>

<p>"I understand the number of wounded now. It's very hard to see it every day," she said.</p>

<p>Kyiv -- like Moscow -- is tight-lipped about its soldier casualty count.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky in February said the number of Ukrainian servicemen confirmed killed was around 31,000 -- a figure observers say is likely an underestimate -- but the number of missing and wounded has never been disclosed.</p>

<p><strong>Worried about others</strong></p>

<p>Most of those wounded were struck in artillery or drone attacks, staff explained, and many have had arms or legs amputated or were unconscious.</p>

<p>One carriage is designated for patients who have been in intensive care and doctors can even operate on patients in case of "force majeure," doctor Oleksandr said.</p>

<p>Things can go wrong and mass bleeding -- an unpredictable and rapid killer -- is a major concern for staff.</p>

<p>"Staff are always near the patient," Oleksandr explained, adding that they take turns using the toilet or eating.</p>

<p>Despite the logistical issues around caregiving on moving trains, the wounded soldiers' preoccupations lie elsewhere.</p>

<p>"Their psychological state is not good," Olena, a medical staff worker, told AFP.</p>

<p>"They're not worried about losing a limb or whatever else. What depresses them is how their comrades are and how their family is," Olena added.</p>

<p><strong>'A sigh of relief'</strong></p>

<p>One Ukrainian serviceman on the train was being treated for a gunshot wound after being caught in a Russian ambush that also killed one of his fellow soldiers.</p>

<p>"Four of us left but not all of us returned," the 28-year-old who identified himself as Murchyk said.</p>

<p>But he was already gauging when he might be able to make his way back to the front, where Ukraine's outnumbered forces have been ceding ground to determined Russian advances.</p>

<p>Whether Murchyk can return to combat will be decided by a medical commission, but he said he was clear-eyed about his wish.</p>

<p>"I'd like to go back," he told AFP.</p>

<p>The train evacuations in Ukraine began when the war did, in February 2022.</p>

<p>It revives a process used in World War II, with several refitted trains now taking wounded troops from the front.</p>

<p>When Oleksandr's train arrives at its destination, ambulances are already waiting for the patients to be loaded off and taken onwards to hospital.</p>

<p>"It is of course very stressful and yes, you breathe a sigh of relief when you arrive and unload," he said, "when you see that all the ambulances have left, when the platform is empty and the train is empty."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k218c7m_wounded-ukrainian-soldiers_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Olena, a military medic, checks on injured Ukrainian soldiers on a military evacuation train.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-five-key-moments-in-an-extraordinary-campaign-6890900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Election: Five Key Moments In An Extraordinary Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-five-key-moments-in-an-extraordinary-campaign-6890900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:18:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Courts, bullets and verbal stumbles have made their mark on this year's US election campaign -- one of the most extraordinary in the nation's history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Courts, bullets and verbal stumbles have made their mark on this year's US election campaign -- one of the most extraordinary in the nation's history.</p>

<p>Here are five key moments so far as candidates Donald Trump and Kamala Harris edge towards Election Day on November 5.</p>

<p><strong>Trump The Felon</strong></p>

<p>"Trump Guilty," is splashed across the world's front pages. On May 30 the Republican becomes the first former US president to be convicted of felony crimes -- 34 counts to be exact.</p>

<p>He is found to have falsified business records to hide a hush money payment to porn star Stormy Daniels on the eve of his 2016 election win, so that she would not publicize their alleged sexual encounter.</p>

<p>In the explosive six-week trial, Daniels shares excruciating details about their apparent one-night stand, including the sex position and Trump's silky pajamas.</p>

<p>The ordeal pulls him from the campaign trail, but huge media attention ensures he keeps the spotlight -- even if it is on his criminality.</p>

<p>Nothing in US law prevents Trump from running for the White House after the guilty verdict, and Republicans double down their unwavering support for the party standard-bearer, who still faces three other criminal cases.</p>

<p><strong>Debate Drama</strong></p>

<p>Democratic hopes appear shattered after President Joe Biden, the party's presumptive nominee, delivers a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump on June 27.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old fumbles his words and often appears to forget what he is saying, bolstering fears that he is not fit to run again for president.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden brushes it off as a "bad night" but dissenters say otherwise, with donors threatening to pull funding if he does not step aside.</p>

<p>Post-debate polling shows Trump pulling away from Biden but the White House insists there is zero chance he will withdraw.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Assassination Attempt</strong></p>

<p>A sun-baked Trump rally in Pennsylvania on July 13 provides the election campaign's most shocking moment yet.</p>

<p>Popping sounds ring out, Trump touches his ear, sees blood, and drops to the stage floor. Secret Service officers surround him as screams ring out in the crowd.</p>

<p>Within seconds Trump is helped back to his feet. "Fight, fight, fight!" he mouths to a now cheering audience, raising his fist to create one of the most iconic images in US political history.</p>

<p>The gunman, 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks, is shot dead at the scene by the Secret Service, and Trump survives with a minor graze to his right ear.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump's base is galvanized. "I took a bullet for democracy," he tells his supporters at a later rally.</p>

<p><strong>Biden Says 'Bye'</strong></p>

<p>At 1.46 pm on Sunday, July 21, a beleaguered President Biden announces in a tweet that he will not seek reelection, yielding to intense concerns over his ability to defeat Trump in November.</p>

<p>It makes him the first sitting president since 1968 not to seek reelection, and upends the White House race.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris, the first female, Black and Asian-American to serve as US vice president, gains Biden's endorsement to replace him in the campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Within two weeks she formally secures the Democratic nomination, making her the first woman of color to lead a major party ticket.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris re-energizes Democrats and delivers immediate results in opinion polls by clawing back Trump's gains, including in the election-deciding swing states.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Trump's Second Scare</strong></p>

<p>Trump's weekend round of golf in Florida on September 15 is shattered by the sound of gunshots -- this time fired by a Secret Service agent foiling what the FBI calls an apparent assassination attempt.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Republican nominee is unharmed in the second such scare in two months.</p>

<p>Investigators say the gunman, Ryan Routh, did not shoot at Trump but instead fled when a security agent opened fire after seeing his rifle pointing through a tree line at the golf course.</p>

<p>Trump attributes the assassination scare to the allegedly provocative "rhetoric" of Biden and Harris.</p>

<p>The Democrats say they condemn political violence, but the incident highlights the volatility of US politics just weeks before voters head to the polls.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8mon83b_us-election_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump escaped two assassination attempts, while Kamala Harris entered the race mid-campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-teen-hit-by-speeding-train-while-filming-video-internet-horrified-6890710]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Teen Hit By Speeding Train While Taking Video, Internet Stunned]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-teen-hit-by-speeding-train-while-filming-video-internet-horrified-6890710]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 12:48:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The video has sparked a range of reactions, with many finding the accident terrifying and others blaming the boy's carelessness.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The rise of social media has led to a deluge of reels and videos, with millions of people sharing content online. However, the craze has taken a disturbing turn as many&nbsp;prioritise likes and followers over their safety. The desire for the perfect shot has led people to take risks, often with disastrous consequences Insta Reels and other social media platforms are filled with videos of people taking videos and selfies in precarious locations, such as train tracks, mountains, waterfalls, and busy roads.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Recently, a similar video went viral showing a teen getting struck by a speeding train. The footage is said to be shot at&nbsp;Shingimari Railway Bridge in Bangladeshi's Rangpur, but the date of the incident could not be confirmed.&nbsp;The footage shows a group of boys trying to take a TikTok video near a speeding train. In a split second, the situation turns tragic as one of them is accidentally hit by the train while standing too close to the tracks. Fortunately, according to subsequent social media posts, the teen survived the horrific accident.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">While Making Tiktok Videos A Train Hits the guy in Bangladesh<br />
<a href="https://t.co/06kZEovLGn">https://t.co/06kZEovLGn</a></p>
— Ghar Ke Kalesh (@gharkekalesh) <a href="https://twitter.com/gharkekalesh/status/1850417137283723326?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The video has sparked a range of reactions, with many finding the accident terrifying and others blaming the boy's carelessness. While some have expressed relief that the kid survived, others have used the incident as a cautionary tale, highlighting the importance of being mindful and responsible when taking videos.</p>

<p>One user wrote, ''pls dont make such mistakes stay safe.'' Another commented, ''It's hard to believe how people can become so absorbed in making content that they ignore everything happening around them.'' A third said, ''I don't understand why people are so obsessed with taking selfies close to a moving train. It's not as if it's a monument or a heritage site worthy of a photo.''</p>

<p>Earlier this year, a woman died after coming too close to a train while <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-camera-woman-struck-dead-by-train-in-mexico-while-taking-selfie-5830443">clicking a selfie in Mexico</a>.&nbsp; According to local outlets, some people had gathered to click a photo of a vintage train with a steam engine near Hidalgo as it was passing by. The woman came too close to the tracks while positioning herself for a selfie with the approaching train, known as the 'Empress'.&nbsp;She dropped to one knee and the corner of the train engine hit her on the back of her head, sending her crashing forward.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1e7c72g8_teen-hit-by-train_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The teen survived the horrific incident.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chatgpt-copy-and-paste-ai-generated-job-application-leaves-jane-lu-in-shock-6890163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[When Shark Tank's Jane Lu Received The "Worst Job Application Ever"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chatgpt-copy-and-paste-ai-generated-job-application-leaves-jane-lu-in-shock-6890163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 12:34:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jane Lu, the founder of online fashion retailer Showpo, has shared the "worst job application ever" she received. The application, to assist her, appears to have been written with artificial intelligence (AI), the Australian businesswoman said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jane Lu, the founder of online fashion retailer Showpo, has shared the "worst job application ever" she received. The application, to assist her, appears to have been written with artificial intelligence (AI), the Australian businesswoman said. She discovered blatant errors and likened it to “ChatGPT copy and paste.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/27/lifestyle/ceo-slams-embarrassing-gen-z-job-application-trend/">video on TikTok</a>, Ms Lu, a panellist on Shark Tank, read out the application, highlighting the lack of attention to various details in it. "I am confident that my experience in (relevant experience/skill) positions me as a strong candidate,” read the job application.<br />
<br />
In the document, key details such as the skills on “specific projects, courses or initiatives” were left blank, indicating how the applicant failed to proofread it before submitting it to the company.<br />
<br />
The applicant did not remove part of the prompt generated by the AI platform at the top of the cover letter, which read, “Here is a more polished and articulate version of your cover letter”.<br />
<br />
Lu noted that the applicant "copied and pasted this thing that's, like, half-filled”.<br />
<br />
She later apologised to the applicant for failing to make it to the next round (interviews), besides reminding others to "use a little bit of this", pointing to her head.<br />
<br />
As per the data released by YouGov, almost half of the people in Australia -- 48% -- are aware of major AI platforms, like ChatGPT, but it does not mean they are as likely to use them.<br />
<br />
Data show how youngsters were most likely to rely on AI platforms, with two-fifths of 'Gen Z' (40%) and millennials (37%) using ChatGPT at least once.</p>

<p>Jane Lu, a well known fashion guru, started Showpo in 2010 from her parent's garage. Over the last couple of years, the brand has emerged into a big name in the industry. It is known for its trendy and affordable clothing. She has also launched the Lazy Ceo's guide to starting and growing an online business.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8tlsqt1g_jane-lu-_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jane Lu noted that the applicant "copied and pasted this thing that's, like, half-filled".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-william-shares-how-dianas-compassion-led-him-to-tackle-homelessness-6890461]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Prince William Shares How Diana's Compassion Led Him To Tackle Homelessness]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-william-shares-how-dianas-compassion-led-him-to-tackle-homelessness-6890461]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 12:11:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prince William has opened up about how a childhood experience with his late mother, Princess Diana, influenced him to help the homeless.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prince William has opened up about how a childhood experience with his late mother, Princess Diana, influenced him to help the homeless.&nbsp;In his upcoming documentary,<em> Prince William: We Can End Homelessness,</em> the 42-year-old recalls his first visit to 'The Passage', a London charity dedicated to helping homeless people. Accompanied by his brother, Prince Harry, and Diana, William first visited the organisation when he was 11.</p>

<p>“My mother took me to The Passage; she took Harry and I both there,” the Prince of Wales recalled in a newly released clip from the two-part series, as per <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/27/uk/prince-william-diana-photos-homelessness-intl/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>. “I'd never been to anything like that before, and I was a bit anxious as to what to expect.” His mother lightened the mood, “having a laugh and joking with everyone,” putting him at ease, the Royal added.</p>

<p>The visit had a profound impact on Prince William. “I remember thinking, 'Well, if everyone's not got a home, they're all going to be really sad.' But it was incredible how happy an environment it was... That's when it dawned on me that there are other people out there who don't have the same life as you do.”</p>

<p>The documentary, directed by BAFTA winner Leo Burley, chronicles the Prince's Homewards initiative — a five-year project launched in June 2023 aimed at ending homelessness in six flagship locations across the UK. It also highlights the stories of individuals experiencing homelessness or struggling with it.</p>

<p>Homelessness is “a complex societal issue”, he stressed, but added it can be eradicated. “Achieving this will require a movement that creates systemic change. A change that focuses on prevention rather than management. And one that ensures all young people have truly affordable options to live and thrive independently.”</p>

<p>The documentary also addresses criticisms over the Prince's privileged background and whether he is suited to tackle such issues. In another clip, he responded that he had “no other agenda than desperately trying to help people” who are in need. “I see that as part of my role.”</p>

<p>The documentary will premiere on ITV at 2:30 am IST on Thursday, October 31. The second episode will air at the same time the following day.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9lq14feg_princess-diana-prince-william-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Britain's Diana, Princess of Wales and her son Prince William visit The Passage in London.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/states-candidates-votes-2024-us-presidential-polls-explained-in-numbers-6890441]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[States, Candidates, Votes: 2024 US Presidential Polls Explained In Numbers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/states-candidates-votes-2024-us-presidential-polls-explained-in-numbers-6890441]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 12:00:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: here is the US election, broken down by numbers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: here is the US election, broken down by numbers.</p>

<h2><strong>Two</strong></h2>

<p>Several independents ran -- and at least one, Robert F. Kennedy Jr, stumbled into a number of eyebrow-raising headlines.</p>

<p>But in the end, the presidential race comes down to a binary choice, with the two candidates from the major parties -- Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump -- seeking to lead a polarized America.</p>

<h2><strong>Five</strong></h2>

<p>November 5 -- Election Day, traditionally held on the Tuesday following the first Monday in November.</p>

<h2><strong>Seven</strong></h2>

<p>The number of swing states -- those which don't clearly favor one party over the other, meaning they are up for grabs.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are courting voters in Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin, concentrating their campaign efforts there in an effort to ensure victory.</p>

<p>In a razor-tight election, just a handful of votes in any of those states could decide the outcome.</p>

<h2><strong>34 and 435</strong></h2>

<p>Voters won't just decide the White House occupant on Election Day -- they will also hit refresh on the US Congress.</p>

<p>Thirty-four Senate seats and all 435 spots in the House of Representatives are up for grabs.</p>

<p>In the House, members serve a two-year term. Republicans currently have the majority, and Harris's Democrats will be hoping for a turnaround.</p>

<p>In the Senate, 34 seats out of 100 are available, for a six-year term. Republicans are hoping to overturn the narrow Democratic majority.</p>

<h2><strong>538</strong></h2>

<p>Welcome to the Electoral College, the indirect system of universal suffrage that governs presidential elections in the United States.</p>

<p>Each state has a different number of electors -- calculated by adding the number of their elected representatives in the House, which varies according to population, to the number of senators (two per state).</p>

<p>Rural Vermont, for example, has just three electoral votes. Giant California, meanwhile, has 54.</p>

<p>There are 538 electors in total scattered across the 50 states and the District of Columbia. To take the White House, a candidate must win 270 votes.</p>

<h2><strong>774,000</strong></h2>

<p>The number of poll workers who volunteered to make sure the 2020 election ran smoothly, according to the Pew Research Center.</p>

<p>There are three types of election staff in the United States.</p>

<p>The majority are poll workers -- recruited to do things like greet voters, help with languages, set up voting equipment, and verify voter IDs and registrations.</p>

<p>Election officials are elected, hired or appointed to carry out more specialized duties such as training poll workers, according to Pew.</p>

<p>Poll watchers are usually appointed by political parties to observe the ballot count -- expected to be particularly contentious this year, thanks to Trump's refusal to agree to unconditionally accept the result.</p>

<p>Many election workers have already spoken to AFP about the pressure and threats they are receiving ahead of the November 5 vote.</p>

<h2><strong>270 million and 78 million</strong></h2>

<p>Harris's team spent $270 million on her campaign in September, while Trump's spent much less -- only $78 million, official filing show.</p>

<p>According to the New York Times, Harris's campaign set a record for the biggest fund-raising quarter ever this fall, raising $1 billion since she entered the race following Joe Biden's withdrawal in July.</p>

<h2><strong>244 million</strong></h2>

<p>The number of Americans who will be eligible to vote in 2024, according to the Bipartisan Policy Center.</p>

<p>How many of those will actually cast their ballot remains to be seen, of course. But the Pew Research Center says that the midterm elections of 2018 and 2022, and the presidential vote of 2020, produced three of the highest turnouts of their kind seen in the United States in decades.</p>

<p>"About two-thirds (66%) of the voting-eligible population turned out for the 2020 presidential election - the highest rate for any national election since 1900," Pew says on its website.</p>

<p>That translated to nearly 155 million voters, according to the Census Bureau.</p>

<h2><strong>41 million</strong></h2>

<p>As of October 27, more than 41 million Americans had voted early, according to a University of Florida database.</p>

<p>Most US states permit in-person voting or mail-in voting to allow people to deal with scheduling conflicts or an inability to cast their ballots on election day itself on November 5.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ldflnci8_kamala-harris-donald-trump-harris-trump-reuters_625x300_12_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thirty-four Senate seats and all 435 spots in the House of Representatives are up for grabs.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-family-rift-prince-william-discusses-bond-with-prince-harry-in-documentary-6890105]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Rift, Prince William Discusses Bond With Prince Harry In Documentary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-family-rift-prince-william-discusses-bond-with-prince-harry-in-documentary-6890105]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:57:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prince William publicly acknowledged his brother, Prince Harry, in a recent documentary. This was the first time he mentioned him amid the ongoing familial rift.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prince William publicly acknowledged his brother, Prince Harry, in a recent documentary. This was the first time he mentioned him amid the ongoing familial rift. In his new ITV documentary titled ‘Prince William: We Can End Homelessness,' the Prince of Wales reflected on a significant childhood memory he shared with Harry during a visit to a homelessness charity.</p>

<p>According to a report in the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/27/entertainment/prince-william-publicly-mentions-prince-harry-for-first-time-since-ongoing-riff/" rel="nofollow,noindex">New York Post</a>, William recalled, “My mother took me to The Passage; she took Harry and I both there. I must have been 11 at the time, maybe 10. I had never been to anything like that before, and I was a bit anxious about what to expect.”</p>

<p>A photograph from the visit shows the young princes at the charity, with Harry sitting on their mother, Princess Diana's lap, both smiling for the camera.</p>

<p>The Prince&nbsp;remembered how Princess Diana's presence created a cheerful atmosphere at the centre; she made the people “feel relaxed,” laughing and joking with them. He said, “I remember at the time kind of thinking, ‘Well, whoever's not got a home, they're all going to be really sad,' but it was incredible how happy an environment it was.”</p>

<p>The relations between the two brothers strained after Harry's marriage to Meghan Markle. While Kensington Palace's official account posted a 40th birthday wish for Harry, William's comments in the documentary represent a rare public reference to his brother in recent years.</p>

<p>Tensions increased when Harry and Meghan relocated to California in 2020, followed by their high-profile interview with Oprah Winfrey in 2021, where they made allegations of racism against an unnamed royal family member. The release of their Netflix docuseries, ‘Harry &amp; Meghan,' in 2022 and Harry's memoir, ‘Spare,' have further complicated family dynamics, particularly after Harry accused William of physically attacking him during an argument over Meghan.</p>

<p>In June, Harry declined an invitation to the wedding of Hugh Grosvenor, the Duke of Westminster, due to William's expected attendance. Although Harry was invited, he declined to attend out of concern for an “awkward” confrontation with William, a royal expert told <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/prince-harry-skipped-royal-wedding-avoid-awkward-encounter-estranged-brother-prince-william-expert" rel="nofollow,noindex">Fox News Digital</a>.</p>

<p>Although Harry made a brief visit to London in February 2024 for a meeting with King Charles following the monarch's cancer diagnosis, he did not meet with William at that time. It is believed that their last conversation took place in 2022, after the death of Queen Elizabeth II.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/p9j3oqto_prince-harry-prince-william-afp_625x300_17_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Britain's Diana, Princess of Wales and her son Prince William visit The Passage in London.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-guilty-of-killing-boyfriend-after-zipping-him-in-a-suitcase-during-hide-and-seek-game-6890288]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Convicted Of Murder After Boyfriend Dies Zipped In Suitcase]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-guilty-of-killing-boyfriend-after-zipping-him-in-a-suitcase-during-hide-and-seek-game-6890288]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:39:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sarah Boone said her boyfriend got trapped in the suitcase during a hide-and-seek game.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida woman has been convicted of second-degree murder following a 2020 incident in which she zipped her boyfriend into a suitcase causing his death. The jury reached the verdict on October 25 after a trial revealed the circumstances surrounding the case.<br />
<br />
Sarah Boone, now 47, said her boyfriend, 42-year-old Jorge Torres Jr, was trapped in the suitcase during a hide-and-seek game. The couple had been drinking wine and working on puzzles in their apartment. According to an arrest affidavit from the Orange County Sheriff's Office, the couple believed it would be “funny” to fit inside the suitcase as part of their game, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/26/us/florida-woman-boyfriend-suitcase-guilty-murder/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>.<br />
<br />
When Boone zipped Torres into the blue suitcase, she noticed two of his fingers protruding from the opening and assumed he would free himself. After zipping him inside, she went to bed, expecting him to join her.<br />
<br />
Upon waking, Boone found Torres unresponsive inside the suitcase and immediately called 911. When deputies from the Orange County Sheriff's Office arrived, they discovered Torres lying near the front door of the residence, next to the blue suitcase. Boone initially said she did not believe he was trapped inside when she left him there.<br />
<br />
A release from the attorney's office said, “Evidence presented during the trial included videos found on Boone's phone where Torres could be heard frantically pleading to be released while Boone laughed and rebuffed him several times. In the videos she recorded, the victim could be heard telling the defendant he could not breathe and asking to be let out of the suitcase. Boone responded with, ‘That's what you get. ‘That's what I feel like when you cheat on me,' and other taunts.”<br />
<br />
During the trial, Boone took the stand in her own defence, saying she had no intention of killing Torres. She claimed her actions were in self-defence, alleging Torres previously abused her and insisting she did not mean to cause him harm. But her testimony was undermined by her earlier statements and video evidence that showed her mocking the victim as he pleaded to be freed from the suitcase.<br />
<br />
After a 10-day trial, the jury found Boone guilty of second-degree murder.<br />
<br />
Describing her reaction, Boone's attorney told <a href="https://www.wesh.com/article/sarah-boone-trial-verdict-guilty/62716043" rel="nofollow,noindex">WESH</a>, an affiliate of CNN, “Just shock. She's shocked, you know. She felt like, you know, she had a defence, as you know. We're obviously very disappointed.”<br />
<br />
For Torres's family members, the verdict provided some sense of closure, said state attorneys. “I think they were finally just happy to see this case go to trial and be able to put this one in the books,” said an attorney.<br />
<br />
Boone is set to receive her sentence on December 2, according to the statement from the attorney's office.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9efd1378_sarah-boone_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-says-he-can-cut-2-trillion-from-budget-at-trump-rally-6890262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Says He Can Cut $2 Trillion From Budget At Trump Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-says-he-can-cut-2-trillion-from-budget-at-trump-rally-6890262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:30:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump turned to the home stretch of his campaign with a marathon rally in the heart of Manhattan, flanked by Elon Musk and other allies aiming to frame voters' decision around who can fix America's woes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump turned to the home stretch of his campaign with a marathon rally in the heart of Manhattan, flanked by Elon Musk and other allies aiming to frame voters' decision around who can fix America's woes.</p>

<p>Trump's event at the fabled Madison Square Garden, which lasted for nearly six hours Sunday, featured criticisms of Vice President Kamala Harris over the border, crime and the economy. Trump mused about safely Democratic New York flipping to his column, painting a view of an America gripped in crisis.</p>

<p>"We must defeat Kamala Harris and stop the radical left agenda with a landslide that is too big to rig," Trump said.</p>

<p>He was joined by roughly two dozen speakers, from celebrity wrestler Hulk Hogan to House Speaker Mike Johnson to Musk himself, who is campaigning for Trump and pouring money into the race. Some of the speeches included fraught remarks about Puerto Rico, Palestinians and Black Americans.</p>

<p>Musk predicted he could find $2 trillion in cuts in a Trump administration, a massive target that would fundamentally reshape government spending.</p>

<p>"Your money is being wasted," said Musk, the final speaker aside from Trump and his wife Melania in a rare appearance during the campaign. "We're going to get the government off your back and out of your pocket book."</p>

<p>The event at the iconic venue was intended to command the media spotlight and mobilize the former president's supporters about a week before Election Day. Trump's campaign had promised a spectacle, and thousands of people lined up along city streets hours before the rally kicked off shortly around 3 p.m. at the packed arena that has a 20,000-person capacity.</p>

<p><strong>Government Spending</strong></p>

<p>New York isn't considered a battleground state for a presidential race polls show is close between Trump and Harris, though it has several competitive House races that could decide control of the chamber. Still, the distinctive setting of Madison Square Garden - host to some of the nation's biggest cultural moments - offered a stage to help the Republican nominee amplify his message beyond his base, including undecided voters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was something of a capstone for Trump, who rose to fame in New York only to be shunned by many of its figures as president. It's also the city where a jury earlier this year found him guilty of 34 felony accounts of falsifying business records.</p>

<p>Trump has said he would ask Musk, the world's richest person and a major donor to his campaign, to head up an effort to cut government spending, nicknamed the Department of Government Efficiency, or DOGE, a reference to a cryptocurrency Musk has embraced.</p>

<p>Critics have said this position would represent a conflict of interest for Musk. The companies he runs, including Tesla Inc. and SpaceX, have billions of dollars worth of federal contracts and have benefited from federal spending, including electric vehicle tax credits and infrastructure investments.</p>

<p>Cantor Fitzgerald LP's Howard Lutnick asked Musk on stage how much he could "rip out of" the budget under President Joe Biden and Harris. Musk responded, "Well, I think we can do at least $2 trillion, yeah."</p>

<p>The $2 trillion target represents nearly a third of existing spending. The federal government spent $6.75 trillion in fiscal year 2024, according to the Treasury Department.</p>

<p>Musk has spent at least $132 million to elect Trump and other Republicans in 2024, federal filings show. That level of giving has vaulted him into the upper echelon of political donors, making Musk one of the most prolific contributors of the entire 2024 cycle.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Controversial Speakers</strong></p>

<p>The speeches also included controversial comments that undercut what at other points were messages of national unity from Trump. Tucker Carlson, the former Fox News host, joked that Harris was a trailblazer as the first "Samoan-Malaysian low-IQ" person who could be elected. Harris would actually be the first Black woman and the first Indian-American in the White House.</p>

<p>Several speakers also urged supporters to be sure to vote, to bring people to the polls and to vote early. "You line up like you're the third monkey in line for the ark, and it's starting to rain," Trump's son Donald Trump Jr. said.</p>

<p>At the event, Trump unveiled a credit for caregivers who take care of family members. The Republican nominee didn't provide details or say how he would pay for it. His litany of tax proposals already includes benefits for tipped workers, hourly employees, senior citizens and higher-income residents of Democratic-led states whose tax breaks he took away while president.</p>

<p>Harris has proposed expanding Medicare to cover home care services. She's also proposed to expand tax credits for parents and boost deductions for startup businesses, offset by increasing levies on corporations and wealthy households.</p>

<p>Trump has said he would raise fresh revenue from across-the-board tariffs, which he aims to impose on imports from US allies and adversaries alike. Economists have warned tariffs won't offset the price tag of his tax cut ideas and could increase costs on US households.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ohhgd5i8_elon-musk-bloomberg_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has spent at least $132 million to elect Trump and other Republicans in 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-deleted-linkedin-post-ignited-misinformation-and-mass-unrest-before-the-southport-riot-6890231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Deleted LinkedIn Post Ignited Misinformation And Mass Unrest In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-deleted-linkedin-post-ignited-misinformation-and-mass-unrest-before-the-southport-riot-6890231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:29:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The stabbings at a children's dance party on July 29 led to a wave of unrest fuelled by misinformation, particularly the false narrative that the suspect was an illegal migrant. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A single LinkedIn post, removed for false claims, was viewed millions of times, causing riots across England and Northern Ireland. The stabbings at a children's dance party on July 29 ignited a wave of unrest fuelled by misinformation, particularly the false narrative that the suspect was an illegal migrant.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Just hours after the attack, misinformation spread widely through various unofficial news sources and personal accounts. Among them was a LinkedIn post from Eddie Murray, a local who posted three hours after the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“My two youngest children went to a holiday club this morning in Southport for a day of fun only for a migrant to enter and murder/fatally wound multiple children,” he wrote. While Murray was relieved that his children were safe, he called for drastic measures, saying, “If there's any time to close the borders completely, it's right now! Enough is enough.”</p>

<p>Despite LinkedIn removing the post for harmful content, the damage was done. The post was copied and reshared widely, leading to over two million views across platforms, reported the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c99v90813j5o" rel="nofollow,noindex">BBC</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The misinformation spread like wildfire, partly due to the lack of detailed information from the Merseyside Police. Following protocol, the police couldn't reveal specifics about the suspect, who was a minor. After the attack, they only released a brief statement, saying armed officers arrested a male and seized a knife. But this limited update did little to stop the intense speculation, which had already taken off on social media.</p>

<p>Murray's post became just one among many fuelling the narrative. Shortly after, an Indian online news account ‘Upuknews' retweeted a screenshot of Murray's claims as “confirmed,” drawing over half a million views, as per the BBC.&nbsp;</p>

<p>High-profile figures, including Paul Golding, co-leader of Britain First, and Nicholas Lissack, a Reform Party activist, who claimed he had “confirmed the authenticity” of Murray's statement, amplified this misinformation. By this time, a fabricated name, “Ali Al-Shakati,” emerged as the supposed identity of the suspect.&nbsp;</p>

<p>By the evening of July 30, a Telegram group named “Southport Wake Up” was established, calling for gatherings that turned violent. Activists and far-right groups used the chaos to fan the anti-immigrant sentiments. Reports from the scene captured the protesters chanting slogans against the police, fuelled by the false narratives circulating online.</p>

<p>Experts have noted the profound implications of such misinformation. Jonathan Hall KC, the government's independent reviewer of terrorism legislation, stated that the law currently “stokes the risk of online disinformation,” claiming that false claims about the suspect's identity are plausibly connected to the violence that followed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In response to the chaos, Ofcom, the media regulator, confirmed that there was a “clear connection” between the violence in England and Northern Ireland and the spread of disinformation on social media.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/sm7223c_uk-anti-racism-protests-afp-_625x300_11_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-uncertain-us-election-2-top-newspapers-refuse-to-pick-sides-6890230]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Uncertain US Election, 2 Top Newspapers Refuse To Pick Sides]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-uncertain-us-election-2-top-newspapers-refuse-to-pick-sides-6890230]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:29:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Days ahead of a close presidential election, two of the most prestigious liberal American newspapers have declined to give their usual endorsements to the Democratic Party candidate, sparking furious reactions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Days ahead of a close presidential election, two of the most prestigious liberal American newspapers have declined to give their usual endorsements to the Democratic Party candidate, sparking furious reactions.</p>

<p>The Los Angeles Times and Washington Post announced they had ended their decades-long practice of officially backing a presidential contender.</p>

<p>That drew a pointed retort from the Post's former top editor Marty Baron, who suggested his old newspaper was giving in to intimidation from Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"This is cowardice," Baron said on X, "with democracy as its casualty."</p>

<p>The generally left-leaning newspaper -- owned by the billionaire Jeff Bezos, the founder and owner of Amazon -- was about to back Kamala Harris but said Friday that it would no longer endorse presidential candidates in any future election.</p>

<p>That decision, following a similar move by the Los Angeles Times, sent shock waves through politics and journalism.</p>

<p>The Post, in seeking to justify its choice, said: "Our job as the newspaper of the capital city of the most important country in the world is to be independent. And that is what we are and will be."</p>

<p>But the newspaper's guild, representing its journalists, said it was "deeply concerned," adding that "an endorsement for Kamala Harris was already drafted, and the decision to not publish was made by The Post's owner, Jeff Bezos."</p>

<p>A source close to the paper's leadership denied that to AFP.</p>

<p>Earlier in the week, the billionaire owner of the Los Angeles Times, Patrick Soon-Shiong, overruled the paper's editorial staff, which also wanted to endorse Vice President Harris.</p>

<p>Several Times employees of both papers resigned in protest, including editorials editor Mariel Garza.</p>

<p>"I want to make it clear that I am not okay with us being silent," she said in an interview.</p>

<p>"In dangerous times, honest people need to stand up."</p>

<p><strong>Billionaires' power</strong></p>

<p>The Trump campaign responded with delight, saying, "Kamala is such an empty vessel, the Washington Post has decided to nuke presidential endorsements altogether rather than back her candidacy.</p>

<p>Many readers of both papers expressed outrage, vowing to cancel their subscriptions.</p>

<p>The decision not to endorse stemmed partly from the papers "not wanting to alienate potential readers," said Dannagal Young, a professor of communications at the University of Delaware.</p>

<p>But "let's be clear," she added. "The media mogul class is probably not very inclined to want to alienate (a person) who could be the president.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"People want to be on the good side of Donald Trump."</p>

<p>Many media owners have financial interests linked to the government. Bezos holds shares in companies with substantial contracts with the administration, including the Pentagon.</p>

<p>Dan Kennedy, a journalism professor at Northeastern University, said media owners were engaging in "anticipatory obedience."</p>

<p>For them "to take a pass on the presidential race this late in the campaign smacks of giving in to the punishment they might be subjected to if Trump returns to office," he added in a blog.</p>

<p><strong>Fading print giants </strong></p>

<p>Nonetheless, Harris this year won endorsements from the New York Times, the Boston Globe, Rolling Stone magazine and the Philadelphia Inquirer.</p>

<p>Trump, for his part, won the backing of the conservative Washington Times and the New York Post, a tabloid owned by magnate Rupert Murdoch.</p>

<p>But while the campaigns have increasingly bet on the influence of newer platforms like podcasts and TikTok, endorsements from prestige media "still matter," said Jane Hall, a communications professor at American University.</p>

<p>The reluctance to endorse comes at "a moment when Donald Trump is talking about going after the licenses of television stations, punishing journalists further and attacking the free press in an administration that hasn't even started."</p>

<p>In recent days, Trump has again blasted the news media as "the enemy of the people."</p>

<p>Hall said the Washington Post -- which in 2017 added the phrase "Democracy Dies in Darkness" to its masthead -- was "courageous in covering the January 6 insurrection and in standing up to threats against the media."&nbsp;</p>

<p>So its decision now to withhold an endorsement "will send a chilling effect to journalists," she said. "It's very shocking."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-03/embg8qlk_newspaper-generic_625x300_06_March_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many readers of both papers expressed outrage, vowing to cancel their subscriptions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stein-oliver-west-know-the-third-party-candidates-contesting-us-elections-6890205]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stein, Oliver, West: Know The US Third-Party Candidates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stein-oliver-west-know-the-third-party-candidates-contesting-us-elections-6890205]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:22:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US presidential election is a toss-up between Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump. However, the two-party system still left room this year for three fringe players who could yet influence an ultra-tight election on November 5.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A scion of the famed Kennedy family. A Green Party activist. A self-proclaimed "armed and gay" libertarian.</p>

<p>The US presidential election is toss-up between Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>However, the two-party system still left room this year for three fringe players who could yet influence an ultra-tight election on November 5.</p>

<p><strong>Leftists Jill Stein, Cornel West</strong></p>

<p>Jill Stein, 74, ran for president as the Green Party candidate in 2012 and then in 2016, winning just 0.4 percent and one percent respectively.</p>

<p>This time, the Chicago-born physician and environmental activist will be on the ballot in nearly 40 states, presenting a headache for the Democrats as she could peel off a crucial handful of votes from Harris in contests where she is neck and neck against Trump.</p>

<p>Last week, the Democratic National Committee released a television ad against Stein in the battleground states of Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin, which says that "a vote for Stein is really a vote for Trump."</p>

<p>Stein has sought to distance herself from President Joe Biden's administration and vowed to stop supporting what she called Israel's "genocide" in Gaza.</p>

<p>She has advocated for raising taxes for the richest Americans, canceling student debt and reducing defense spending.</p>

<p>Cornel West, another candidate from the green camp, chose to run independently of the Green Party.</p>

<p>The 71-year-old academic and anti-racism activist who calls Biden a "war criminal" and describes Trump as a "neofascist" will be on the ballot in nearly a dozen states. He too will siphon a tiny, but potentially painful number of votes from Harris.</p>

<p><strong>Chase Oliver, Libertarian</strong></p>

<p>The Libertarian Party received a little over one percent of the vote in 2020 and this year will be on the ballot in almost all 50 states, also acting as a potential spoiler.</p>

<p>The new face of the party, which advocates for free trade and limited government, is Chase Oliver, a 39-year-old former Democrat, who ran for a Senate seat from Georgia in 2022.</p>

<p>Unknown at the time, the science fiction fan who describes himself as "armed and gay" got around two percent of the vote, forcing a runoff between the incumbent Democrat and his Republican challenger.</p>

<p>Oliver favors pro-gun, fiscally conservative policies, but also supports abortion rights, the legalization of cannabis and is against the death penalty.</p>

<p>Oliver who will be on the ballot in three battleground states.</p>

<p><strong>Kennedy for Trump</strong></p>

<p>Robert F. Kennedy Jr, scion of America's storied political clan, was polling at four to five percent nationally, before he pulled out of the race in late August and endorsed Trump -- to the great chagrin of his family.</p>

<p>The environmental lawyer, conspiracy theorist and vaccine skeptic was for a time seen as a threat to Harris, with some of her supporters potentially migrating to RFK Jr. But he is also likely to draw away at least some Trump votes.</p>

<p>On quitting, he tried to get himself taken off the ballot in battleground states. But several of those states have refused to remove him as a candidate.</p>

<p>While he has since campaigned vigorously alongside Trump, it remains unclear what his ultimate impact on the election will be.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kh2oavk_us-elections_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US presidential election is a toss-up between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-whats-on-the-minds-of-us-voters-across-the-country-6890171]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What's On The Minds Of US Voters Across The Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-whats-on-the-minds-of-us-voters-across-the-country-6890171]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:18:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Voters in the handful of states expected to decide the US election wield outsized power in whether Donald Trump or Kamala Harris becomes the next president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Voters in the handful of states expected to decide the US election wield outsized power in whether Donald Trump or Kamala Harris becomes the next president.</p>

<p><strong>Here are what some voters in the key battleground states told AFP ahead of the November 5 election:</strong></p>

<p><strong>Pessimism in Nevada</strong></p>

<p>Leticia Chaparro, a 62-year-old bed and breakfast employee in the town of Dyer, said she sees "lots of division" now and voiced concerns about the future.</p>

<p>"I want better life for everybody, because I'm really scared for the kids, for the future."</p>

<p>"The new generations, you know, I feel sorry for them."</p>

<p>Stamp dealer Nadia Beekun of Goldfield, who gave her age as "too much," expressed frustration at the choice, but said she hopes people can begin "working together."</p>

<p>"Right now, I don't like any of the candidates that we have been offered."</p>

<p>"It is going to have to be a choice of who is a lesser of all evils, and I don't know who that is yet."</p>

<p>"I'm going to have to hold my nose and choose."</p>

<p><strong>Abortion and prices in Arizona</strong></p>

<p>At 18, medical student Madeline Tena, who identifies as Latina, will be casting her first vote for Kamala Harris, saying women's rights was a key factor.</p>

<p>"I'm worried about women's rights, and especially women's healthcare. It's like, they're already trying to take away our right for an abortion, what else can they take away? What's next?"</p>

<p>"I'm going to vote for Kamala because based on what I've seen on social media, Kamala looks a lot better than Trump. She's just really well read and looks a lot better than Trump. He looks really childish sometimes."</p>

<p>Graduate student Whitney Brown, a 35-year-old African American, similarly said abortion rights played a key role in her decision.</p>

<p>"The main thing for me is abortion rights, so I'll vote for Kamala."</p>

<p>"I have two daughters, they're now 11 and 13, and I want them to be able to have autonomy over their own body when they grow up, and not have the government in the exam room with them."</p>

<p>On the other hand, health sciences student Drew Roby says he will probably vote for Trump, expressing concerns about high prices but reservations over some of the ex-president's radical supporters.</p>

<p>"This is my first election, but I'm not really pumped up," said the 21-year-old African American.</p>

<p>"I'm probably gonna roll with Trump, because I see how the country's been run for the past four years, and honestly it was better when he was president."</p>

<p>"Life is very expensive now, between rent, groceries and gas, I don't have much to spend on myself."</p>

<p>"I worry about hate and racism spreading in this country."</p>

<p>"I only have a choice between Trump and Kamala, so I'm going for his policies, but Trump has crazy fans that really take it too far."</p>

<p><strong>Immigration in Michigan</strong></p>

<p>Brenda Adams of Sterling Heights, a 53-year-old hospital worker and part-time bakery employee, will be casting her ballot for Trump after switching from Democrat to Republican four years ago.</p>

<p>"A lot of that has to do with border patrol and inflation."</p>

<p>"Things have not changed at all in the last four years. It's gotten worse. So hopefully this year we can make a difference."</p>

<p>"I hope the prices of food, grocery, gas, hopefully things start to level out."</p>

<p><strong>'Do what's right' in North Carolina</strong></p>

<p>Shelley Hughes, 64, of Swannanoa, a mountain town impacted recently by a major hurricane, said she has some concerns about Trump but would still be voting for him.</p>

<p>"I don't care for a lot of things that he's done in the past, or even his personality sometimes," but "I just feel like he's going to do a better job."</p>

<p>"I just always feel like he's going to do what's right, regardless of what other people in government tell him. He's not a puppet."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/c9dj4vlg_us-voting-afp_625x300_04_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A hospital worker and part-time bakery employee, will be casting her ballot for Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-us-presidential-candidate-can-win-more-votes-but-still-lose-6890145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A US Presidential Candidate Can Win More Votes But Still Lose]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-us-presidential-candidate-can-win-more-votes-but-still-lose-6890145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:12:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When political outsider Donald Trump defied polls and expectations to defeat Hillary Clinton in the 2016 US presidential election, he described the victory as "beautiful."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When political outsider Donald Trump defied polls and expectations to defeat Hillary Clinton in the 2016 US presidential election, he described the victory as "beautiful."</p>

<p>Not everyone saw it that way -- considering that Democrat Clinton had received nearly three million more votes nationally than her Republican rival. Non-Americans were particularly perplexed that the second-highest vote-getter would be crowned president.</p>

<p>But Trump had done what the US system requires: win enough individual states, sometimes by very narrow margins, to surpass the 270 Electoral College votes necessary to win the White House.</p>

<p>Now, as the 2024 election showdown between Trump and Democrat Kamala Harris approaches, the rules of this enigmatic and, to some, outmoded system is coming back into focus.</p>

<p><strong>Why an Electoral College?</strong></p>

<p>The 538 members of the US Electoral College gather in their state's respective capitals after the quadrennial presidential election to designate the winner.</p>

<p>A presidential candidate must obtain an absolute majority of the "electors" -- or 270 of the 538 -- to win.</p>

<p>The system originated with the US Constitution in 1787, establishing the rules for indirect, single-round presidential elections.</p>

<p>The country's Founding Fathers saw the system as a compromise between direct presidential elections with universal suffrage, and an election by members of Congress -- an approach rejected as insufficiently democratic.</p>

<p>Because many states predictably lean Republican or Democratic, presidential candidates focus heavily on the handful of "swing" states on which the election will likely turn -- nearly ignoring some large states such as left-leaning California and right-leaning Texas.</p>

<p>Over the years, hundreds of amendments have been proposed to Congress in efforts to modify or abolish the Electoral College. None has succeeded.</p>

<p>Trump's 2016 victory rekindled debate. And if the 2024 race is the nail-biter that most polls predict, the Electoral College will surely return to the spotlight.</p>

<p><strong>Who are the 538?</strong></p>

<p>Most are local elected officials or party leaders, but their names do not appear on ballots.</p>

<p>Each state has as many electors as it has members in the US House of Representatives (a number dependent on the state's population) plus the Senate (two in every state, regardless of size).</p>

<p>California, for example, has 54 electors; Texas has 40; and sparsely populated Alaska, Delaware, Vermont and Wyoming have only three each.</p>

<p>The US capital city, Washington, also gets three electors, despite having no voting members in Congress.</p>

<p>The Constitution leaves it to states to decide how their electors' votes should be cast. In every state but two (Nebraska and Maine, which award some electors by congressional district), the candidate winning the most votes theoretically wins all that state's electors.</p>

<p><strong>Controversial institution</strong></p>

<p>In November 2016, Trump won 306 electoral votes, well more than the 270 needed.</p>

<p>The extraordinary situation of losing the popular vote but winning the White House was not unprecedented.</p>

<p>Five presidents have risen to the office this way, the first being John Quincy Adams in 1824.</p>

<p>More recently, the 2000 election resulted in an epic Florida entanglement between Republican George W. Bush and Democrat Al Gore.</p>

<p>Gore won nearly 500,000 more votes nationwide, but when Florida -- ultimately following a US Supreme Court intervention -- was awarded to Bush, it pushed his Electoral College total to 271 and a hair's-breadth victory.</p>

<p><strong>True vote or simple formality?</strong></p>

<p>Nothing in the Constitution obliges electors to vote one way or another.</p>

<p>If some states required them to respect the popular vote and they failed to do so, they were subjected to a simple fine. But in July 2020, the Supreme Court ruled that states could impose punishments on such "faithless electors."</p>

<p>To date, faithless electors have never determined a US election outcome.</p>

<p><strong>Electoral College schedule</strong></p>

<p>Electors will gather in their state capitals on December 17 and cast votes for president and vice president. US law states they "meet and cast their vote on the first Tuesday after the second Wednesday in December."</p>

<p>On January 6, 2025, Congress will convene to certify the winner -- a nervously watched event this cycle, four years after a mob of Trump supporters attacked the US Capitol attempting to block certification.</p>

<p>But there is a difference. Last time, it was Republican Vice President Mike Pence who, as president of the Senate, was responsible for overseeing the certification. Defying heavy pressure from Trump and the mob, he certified Biden's victory.</p>

<p>This time, the president of the Senate -- overseeing what normally would be the pro forma certification -- will be none other than today's vice president: Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>On January 20, the new president is to be sworn in.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/t3knd5so_why-us-elections-are-held-on-1st-tuesday-of-november_625x300_18_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-from-immigration-to-abortion-5-issues-at-stake-in-the-us-election-6890136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Immigration To Abortion: 5 Issues At Stake In The US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-from-immigration-to-abortion-5-issues-at-stake-in-the-us-election-6890136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:11:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From taxes, to immigration, to abortion -- here are the five key issues which are at stake as Donald Trump and Kamala Harris enter a final sprint in the race for the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tax breaks for families with children? Supporting Ukraine? Drilling for oil?</p>

<p>From taxes, to immigration, to abortion -- here are the five key issues which are at stake as Donald Trump and Kamala Harris enter a final sprint in the race for the White House.</p>

<p><strong>Economy</strong></p>

<p>Trump, who cut taxes for businesses and the wealthy during his 2017-2021 presidency, plans to impose tariffs of more than 10 percent on all US imports, which he says will enable him to lower taxes for Americans. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The Republican has also vowed to make the United States the "crypto capital of the planet," and launched his own cryptocurrency platform with his sons in September.</p>

<p>Democrat Harris, meanwhile, is appealing to the middle class with her promise to create an "opportunity economy," while pitching moderate tax hikes for the richest people.</p>

<p>The 60-year-old has also promoted child tax credits, support for first-time homebuyers, and help for small businesses.</p>

<p><strong>Immigration</strong></p>

<p>Trump has taken a hard-line approach on immigration, saying that he will order mass deportations of millions of undocumented migrants if reelected.</p>

<p>The former president, who in 2016 promised to build a wall along the US-Mexico border, has accused immigrants of "poisoning the blood of our country."</p>

<p>For her part, Harris has pledged a tough stance and warned of "consequences" for people who enter the country illegally.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She has supported President Joe Biden's plan to tighten up immigration policy, notably by investing in physical barriers on the border.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Abortion</strong></p>

<p>Reproductive rights are a big issue for some US voters after the federal right to abortion was removed in 2022 with the overturning of Roe v Wade, resulting in total abortion bans in some states.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump has often boasted of his role in appointing the Supreme Court justices who scrapped the 1973 decision, and has further hinted that he may restrict access to drugs used in medical abortions if reelected.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 78-year-old, who was found liable last year for sexually assaulting writer E. Jean Carroll, has nonetheless promised to be "great for women."</p>

<p>Harris wants to pass a federal law to reinstate nationwide abortion rights, making the issue a key part of her presidential campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On November 5, voters in 10 states will decide whether to adopt constitutional amendments that could shape the future of abortion access in their states. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Foreign politics</strong></p>

<p>With wars raging in the Middle East and in Ukraine, Trump has promised to quickly resolve both conflicts -- though without explaining how.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He has denounced the huge amount of US funding for Kyiv since it was invaded by Russia in 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris has pledged her enduring support for Ukraine if reelected.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Both Trump and Harris offer continued backing for Israel, though the vice president has drawn more attention to the suffering of Palestinians.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Climate</strong></p>

<p>The United States is the world's second-biggest greenhouse gas emitter behind China, but neither candidate has outlined a comprehensive platform on the issue.</p>

<p>Trump, who has long denounced climate change as a "hoax" despite overwhelming scientific evidence, plans to cut subsidies for renewable energies and electric vehicles, which he says harm businesses.</p>

<p>The Republican has vowed to "drill, baby, drill" for oil, and to again remove the United States from the Paris climate agreement.</p>

<p>Harris has promoted the "Inflation Reduction Act" of President Joe Biden, which has driven investment in green energy.</p>

<p>She "is committed to continuing and building upon the United States' international climate leadership," according to her campaign website.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7v0s9c6o_donald-trump-and-kamala-harris-in-second-presidential-debate_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris wants to pass a federal law to reinstate nationwide abortion rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>