<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 11:27:51 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-population-to-peak-in-early-2060s-to-1-7-billion-then-decline-un-6088019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's Population To Peak In Early 2060s To 1.7 Billion, Then Decline: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-population-to-peak-in-early-2060s-to-1-7-billion-then-decline-un-6088019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 11:27:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's population is projected to peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion and then decline by 12 per cent, but the country will remain the world's most populous throughout the century, the United Nations has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's population is projected to peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion and then decline by 12 per cent, but the country will remain the world's most populous throughout the century, the United Nations has said.</p>

<p>The World Population Prospects 2024 report, released here on Thursday, said that the world's population is expected to continue growing over the coming 50-60 years, reaching a peak of around 10.3 billion people in the mid-2080s, up from 8.2 billion in 2024. After peaking, the global population is projected to start declining gradually, falling to 10.2 billion people by the end of the century.</p>

<p>India, which surpassed China as the world's most populous nation last year, will continue to hold that position through 2100.</p>

<p>"The population of India, which is expected to remain the world's largest throughout the century, will likely decline by 12 per cent after reaching its peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion," the UN report published by the United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs (DESA), Population Division said.</p>

<p>According to the report, India's population in 2024 is projected at 1.45 billion and this will peak to 1.69 billion in 2054. After this, India's population is projected to decline to 1.5 billion by the end of the century in 2100, but the country will still remain the most populous nation on Earth.</p>

<p>Responding to a question by PTI on population projections for India, Senior Population Affairs Officer, Population Division, UN DESA Clare Menozzi said at a press conference that "India is currently the largest country in the world in terms of population, and it is projected to stay so throughout the century. The population is currently estimated at 1.45 billion, and it's supposed to increase further" to 1.69 billion.</p>

<p>"It's supposed to peak around the 2060s in size and then it starts to slightly decline. So by the end of the century, India is projected to be around 1.5 billion, but still the largest country in the world by a large margin." The report said that China's population, currently 1.41 billion in 2024, will fall to 1.21 billion in 2054 and further decline to 633 million by 2100.</p>

<p>"It is anticipated that China, the country currently with the world's second-largest population, will likely experience the largest absolute population loss between 2024 and 2054 (204 million)," followed by Japan (21 million) and Russia (10 million). "Longer-range population projections are more uncertain" for China, it said.</p>

<p>"However, due to its large size and sustained low level of fertility, China is also likely to record the largest population decline of any country through the end of the century (786 million people). By 2100, China is projected to have lost more than a half of its current population and to have returned to a population size comparable to that recorded in the late 1950s (50 per cent probability)."</p>

<p>Responding to a question on the significantly low population projection for China, Director of the Population Division at UN DESA John Wilmoth said that "it really relates to the level of fertility that's observed currently in China. The current number is right around one birth per woman on average over a lifetime."</p>

<p>"Given that you need 2.1 births to maintain the current population without migration, if fertility levels remain at such a low level, even if they come up slightly, any fertility level if it's below two, or especially below 1.8 or below 1.5, you're really getting into low levels of fertility and it produces a long run decline that's quite significant. And that's true for China. It's true for some other countries in this analysis," Wilmoth said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/jrmv5a_population-generic-india-ians_625x300_09_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India's population is projected to peak in the early 2060s at about 1.7 billion and then decline by 12%]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-seeks-absolute-immunity-wants-hush-money-conviction-tossed-out-6088343]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Seeks "Absolute Immunity", Wants Hush Money Conviction Tossed Out]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-seeks-absolute-immunity-wants-hush-money-conviction-tossed-out-6088343]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 10:50:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lawyers for Donald Trump on Thursday asked the judge who presided over his hush money trial to throw out his conviction, citing the recent Supreme Court ruling that a former US president enjoys broad immunity from prosecution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lawyers for Donald Trump on Thursday asked the judge who presided over his hush money trial to throw out his conviction, citing the recent Supreme Court ruling that a former US president enjoys broad immunity from prosecution.</p>

<p>"The jury's verdicts must be vacated and the indictment dismissed," Trump's attorneys said in a court filing with New York Judge Juan Merchan.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was convicted in New York in May of 34 counts of falsifying business records to cover up hush money payments made to porn star Stormy Daniels, who alleged she had a sexual encounter with the real estate tycoon.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers, in asking Merchan for the conviction to be dismissed, cited the landmark Supreme Court ruling from earlier this month that a president enjoys "absolute immunity" for official acts.</p>

<p>Some of the evidence introduced by prosecutors during the hush money trial involved actions taken while Trump was in the White House and testimony from White House aides, they said.</p>

<p>Trump, who is expected to be formally named the Republican Party nominee for president next week, had been scheduled to be sentenced in the case on Thursday, but Merchan postponed sentencing following the Supreme Court ruling.</p>

<p>Merchan said he would rule on the Trump dismissal motion on September 6 and hold sentencing -- if still necessary -- on September 18.</p>

<p>Manhattan prosecutor Alvin Bragg said in an earlier court filing that he was not opposed to the sentencing delay, but that he believed the "defendant's (dismissal) arguments to be without merit."</p>

<p>Trump, the first former US president convicted of a crime, faces four criminal cases and has been doing everything in his power to delay the trials until after the November election.</p>

<p>He faces charges in Washington and Georgia related to efforts to overturn the results of the 2020 election he lost to Democrat Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Trump is also accused in an indictment filed in Florida of endangering national security by holding onto top secret documents after leaving the White House.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/trbnmngo_donald-trump_625x300_02_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump, the first former US president convicted of a crime, faces four criminal cases.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/openai-chatgpt-ai-problem-solving-openai-scale-ranks-progress-toward-human-level-problem-solving-6088297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Scale Ranks Progress Toward Human-Level Problem Solving]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/openai-chatgpt-ai-problem-solving-openai-scale-ranks-progress-toward-human-level-problem-solving-6088297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 10:44:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI has said for years that it's working to build what's often referred to as artificial general intelligence, or AGI - essentially, computers that can do a better job on most tasks than people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI has come up with a set of five levels to track its progress toward building artificial intelligence software capable of outperforming humans, the startup's latest effort to help people better understand its thinking about safety and the future of AI.</p>

<p>The ChatGPT maker, seen by many as a leader in the race to build more powerful AI systems, shared the new classification system with employees on Tuesday during an all-hands meeting, an OpenAI spokesperson said. The tiers, which OpenAI plans to share with investors and others outside the company, range from the kind of AI available today that can interact in conversational language with people (Level 1) to AI that can do the work of an organization (Level 5).</p>

<p>OpenAI executives told employees that the company believes it is currently on the first level, according to the spokesperson, but on the cusp of reaching the second, which it calls "Reasoners." This refers to systems that can do basic problem-solving tasks as well as a human with a doctorate-level education who doesn't have access to any tools.</p>

<p>At the same meeting, company leadership gave a demonstration of a research project involving its GPT-4 AI model that OpenAI thinks shows some new skills that rise to human-like reasoning, according to a person familiar with the discussion who asked not to be identified because they were not authorized to speak to press. Reached for comment about the demonstration, the spokesperson said OpenAI is always testing new capabilities internally, a common practice in the industry.</p>

<p>OpenAI has said for years that it's working to build what's often referred to as artificial general intelligence, or AGI - essentially, computers that can do a better job on most tasks than people. Such systems do not currently exist. OpenAI Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman has previously said he expects AGI could be reached this decade.</p>

<p>AI researchers have long debated how to determine the criteria for reaching AGI. In a November 2023 paper, several researchers at Google DeepMind proposed a framework of five ascending levels of AI, including tiers such as "expert" and "superhuman." The rankings resemble a system often referred to in the automotive industry in order to assess the degree of automation for self-driving cars.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eev1j57o_openai-imagines-future_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>According to the levels OpenAI has come up with, the third tier on the way to AGI would be called "Agents," referring to AI systems that can spend several days taking actions on a user's behalf. Level 4 describes AI that can come up with new innovations. And the most advanced level would be called "Organizations."</p>

<p>The levels were put together by executives and other senior leaders at OpenAI, and it is considered a work in progress. The company will gather feedback from people including employees, investors and its board, and may tweak the levels over time.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/hptnt2j_sam-altman_625x300_22_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[CEO Sam Altman previously said he expects artificial general intelligence could be reached this decade]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apart-from-biden-and-trump-these-are-5-other-key-candidates-in-us-elections-6087973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apart From Biden And Trump, These Are 5 Other Key Candidates In US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apart-from-biden-and-trump-these-are-5-other-key-candidates-in-us-elections-6087973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:46:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic President Joe Biden and Republican former President Donald Trump will face each other in the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, after a divisive, closely fought contest. Several third-party hopefuls are also running.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic President Joe Biden and Republican former President Donald Trump will face each other in the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, after a divisive, closely fought contest. Several third-party hopefuls are also running.</p>

<p>Here is a list of the candidates:</p>

<h3><strong>REPUBLICAN PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>DONALD TRUMP</strong></h4>

<p>Trump, 78, became the first former U.S. president to be convicted of a crime when a Manhattan jury in May found him guilty of falsifying documents to cover up a payment to a porn star to silence her ahead of the 2016 election. He says he is innocent and will appeal the conviction.</p>

<p>Trump's July 11 sentencing was postponed until Sept. 18 after he asked for a chance to argue he should have been immune from prosecution following a July Supreme Court ruling that presidents are entitled to immunity from criminal prosecution for official acts.</p>

<p>On Monday, the Republicans National Convention convenes to formally nominate the former president to face Biden in what would be the first presidential rematch in nearly 70 years. The party mirrored Trump's views in its new policy platform.</p>

<p>Trump, in office from 2017-2021, has leveraged his unprecedented legal challenges to solidify support among his base and has cast his third bid for the White House in part as "retribution" against perceived political enemies.</p>

<p>But after his felony conviction, 10% of Republican and 25% of independent registered voters said they were less likely to vote for him, Reuters/Ipsos polling found.</p>

<p>Trump faces 54 charges in three other criminal cases: a federal case involving efforts to subvert the 2020 election, a Georgia election interference case and a federal case in Florida over his handling of classified documents after leaving office. He denies any wrongdoing.</p>

<p>However, he is unlikely to face any other trials before the Nov. 5 election. July's Supreme Court ruling on presidential immunity makes it improbable that Trump will be tried on federal criminal charges regarding efforts to undo the 2020 election loss to Biden before voters cast their ballots.</p>

<p>Trump has refused to commit to accepting the 2024 election results or to rule out possible violence around the Nov. 5 contest or his sentencing and is already laying the groundwork to contest a potential election loss.</p>

<p>He calls his supporters jailed for the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the U.S. Capitol "hostages" and "warriors," and uses increasingly dystopian rhetoric, including calling his enemies "vermin."</p>

<p>If elected, Trump has vowed "revenge" on his political enemies and said he would not be a dictator except "on day one," later calling that "a joke."</p>

<p>He also wants the power to replace federal civil service workers with loyalists, while a consortium of Trump-friendly think tanks touts a sweeping policy agenda known as "Project 2025" that takes aim at diversity programs and the Justice Department's independence, among other reported plans. Trump has sought to distance himself from the plan.</p>

<p>On foreign policy, Trump sparked criticism from Western leaders for saying the U.S. would not defend NATO members that did not spend enough on defense and that he would encourage Russia to attack them. He has also questioned military aid for Ukraine.</p>

<p>Trump has made immigration a top domestic campaign issue, vowing to carry out mass deportations with the National Guard and possibly federal troops, end birthright citizenship, and expand a travel ban on people from certain countries.</p>

<p>He has referred to some migrants as "animals" who are "poisoning the blood of our country," among other inflammatory remarks, and has not ruled out building detention camps on U.S. soil. But foreigners who graduate from a U.S. college would get a green card allowing them to stay, he said, which his campaign later said would only apply to the "most skilled" graduates who had been vetted.</p>

<p>On abortion, Trump takes credit for the U.S. Supreme Court ruling overturning Roe v. Wade and has said abortion should remain a state issue.</p>

<p>While he has criticized some Republican-led state actions such as those in Florida and Arizona, he said he would allow Republican-led states to track women's pregnancies and prosecute those who violate their state bans. Trump has said he does not support a ban on access to birth control.</p>

<p>He promised to eliminate Obamacare health insurance before saying on April 11 that he would not "terminate" it. On education, he has pledged to halt federal funding to schools with vaccine mandates and to eliminate the U.S. Department of Education. He has also vowed to undo much of the Biden administration's work to fight climate change.</p>

<h3><strong>DEMOCRATIC PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>JOE BIDEN</strong></h4>

<p>Biden has cast himself as the country's best hope to defend American liberties and protect democracy, saying Trump is unhinged and threatens the future of the country.</p>

<p>While he faced no serious challenger in the Democratic primaries, his weak performance at the first presidential debate against Trump has prompted some Democrats to call for him to step aside as the party prepares to formally nominate him.</p>

<p>Already the oldest U.S. president ever at 81, Biden must now convince his own party as well as voters that he is more fit for office than Trump, who is just three years his junior.</p>

<p>One in three Democrats think Biden should end his reelection bid following the debate, but no prominent elected Democrat does any better than Biden in a hypothetical match-up against Trump, according to a Reuters/Ipsos poll released in July.</p>

<p>The July Reuters/Ipsos poll puts both Biden and Trump on 40% among registered voters, suggesting that Biden had not lost ground since the debate. Trump leads Biden in many battleground states, several other polls have shown.</p>

<p>The economy will also likely be a major factor in determining whether Biden returns to the White House amid low approval ratings.</p>

<p>While the U.S. escaped an anticipated recession and is growing faster than economists expected, voters have been disenchanted with rising food costs, higher fuel prices and elevated interest rates, even as more recent data shows consumer prices moderating and inflation cooling.</p>

<p>Biden pushed through massive economic stimulus and infrastructure spending packages to boost U.S. industrial output but has received next to no credit from voters so far.</p>

<p>His campaign has highlighted new semiconductor manufacturing plants, housing plans and other economic efforts. Two labor groups, the United Auto Workers Union and the North America's Building Trade Union, have endorsed him while the Teamsters have yet to announce which candidate they are backing. Three groups representing older Americans have also endorsed Biden.</p>

<p>Along with Vice President Kamala Harris, Biden has zeroed in on abortion as a top issue. They also created a new coalition to court Black voters, a critical voting bloc.</p>

<p>Biden's handling of immigration policy has been criticized by Republicans and some Democrats as he has struggled with millions of migrants crossing the U.S.-Mexico border.</p>

<p>In June, he signed an executive order to curb migration along the southern border. He also announced a new path for citizenship for certain immigrants in the country illegally who are married to U.S. citizens.</p>

<p>The president has led the response of Western governments to Russia's invasion of Ukraine, persuading allies to punish Russia and support Kyiv, including at NATO's summit in Washington. He also secured additional funding from Congress.</p>

<p>Biden has provided military aid to Israel after Hamas' Oct. 7 attack while urging more humanitarian assistance for Palestinians as a May Reuters/Ipsos poll found Democrats remain divided over the issue.</p>

<p>He has faced criticism from many Democrats and younger voters for continuing to give weapons to Israel while largely failing to curb Israel's deadly military offensive in Gaza. Biden has presented a new Israeli proposal for a fresh Gaza ceasefire in exchange for the release of hostages while talks to end the conflict continue.</p>

<h4><strong>MARIANNE WILLIAMSON</strong></h4>

<p>Best-selling author and self-help guru Marianne Williamson, 72, relaunched her long-shot 2024 presidential bid earlier this year focusing on "justice and love" less than one month after dropping out.</p>

<p>In a February statement, she said she was getting back in to fight Trump's "dark and authoritarian vision" after earlier suspending it because she was losing "the horse race."</p>

<p>Williamson previously ran as a Democrat in the 2020 presidential primary but dropped out before voting began.</p>

<h3><strong>INDEPENDENTS</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>ROBERT F. KENNEDY JR.</strong></h4>

<p>An anti-vaccine activist and environmental advocate, Kennedy, 70, is running as an independent after initially challenging Biden for the Democratic nomination but missed the deadline to qualify for the first presidential debate.</p>

<p>While he lags in overall polling, Kennedy could siphon votes from Trump and Biden, with a June Reuters/Ipsos poll showing he was backed by 10% of respondents.</p>

<p>The son of Democratic U.S. Senator Robert F. Kennedy, who was assassinated in 1968 during his own presidential bid, Kennedy has drawn rebukes from his famous family, which endorsed Biden.</p>

<p>Kennedy, who chose wealthy lawyer Nicole Shanahan as his running mate, supports Israel and questioned a six-week ceasefire backed by Biden.</p>

<p>He said he views the U.S. southern border situation as a humanitarian crisis and opposes Trump's border wall. He has also vowed to repeal parts of Biden's climate bill over tax breaks he says help the oil industry.</p>

<p>Kennedy has taken different positions on abortion rights, including restrictions on when a woman can access an abortion. He told Reuters he thought every abortion was a "tragedy" but that it should be a woman's right "throughout the pregnancy."</p>

<p>He has been criticized for making false medical claims over the years on vaccines but says he would still allow Americans to access them.</p>

<p>Asked about an alleged sexual assault, he said in July that he has "so many skeletons in my closet." His campaign has also said Kennedy had a brain worm more than a decade ago but he has fully recovered.</p>

<p>Kennedy's campaign has said he is officially on the ballot in a handful of states so far, including California, Michigan and Utah, although he faces a challenging, costly battle to be listed in all 50.</p>

<h4><strong>CORNEL WEST</strong></h4>

<p>The political activist, philosopher and academic is making a third-party bid for president that is most likely to appeal to progressive, Democratic-leaning voters.</p>

<p>West, 71, initially ran as a Green Party candidate but said in October that people "want good policies over partisan politics" and declared himself an independent. He has promised to end poverty and guarantee housing.</p>

<h3><strong>GREEN PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>JILL STEIN</strong></h4>

<p>Jill Stein, a physician who ran under the Green Party in 2016, is trying once again in 2024.</p>

<p>She launched her current campaign accusing Democrats of betraying their promises "for working people, youth and the climate again and again - while Republicans don't even make such promises in the first place."</p>

<p>Stein, 74, raised millions of dollars for recounts after Trump's surprise 2016 victory. Her allegations yielded only one electoral review in Wisconsin that showed Trump had won.</p>

<h3><strong>LIBERTARIAN PARTY</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>CHASE OLIVER</strong></h4>

<p>While the Libertarian Party invited both Trump and Kennedy to speak at their convention in late May, it ultimately selected Chase Oliver, 38. Oliver ran for a Georgia state Senate seat in 2022 and garnered 2% of the vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/svuvbrhc_trump-biden-split-reuters_625x300_06_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden is being called to step aside after his weak performance in the debate against Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/air-vistara-an-aviation-icon-fades-away-6086551]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Air Vistara: An Aviation Icon Fades Away, And The Chaos It Leaves Behind]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/air-vistara-an-aviation-icon-fades-away-6086551]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:30:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vistara, with its reputation for service excellence and 70 new planes, contrasts sharply with Air India's outdated fleet. It is baffling that the Civil Aviation Ministry allowed the merger of a modern, well-functioning airline like Vistara with an ou]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j7auhnbg_vistara_625x300_12_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On December 10, 2022, we were booked in Business Class to Dubai on Air India. Upon reaching the check-in counter, we were informed that five seats in business class were broken. Consequently, we were offered extra legroom seats in economy class while retaining our business class seats for the next flight.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The staff tried to reassure us that it would be fine for a short flight, but we had important meetings scheduled in Dubai the following morning, so we declined. After learning that the issue was with the TVs, we expressed that we didn't mind as we just wanted to sleep. Despite this, we were forced to write a letter stating we had no objection to flying with broken seats in business class to avoid future claims for compensation.</p>

<p>This was my first experience with Air India post the Tata takeover. As we boarded the flight, we saw empty business-class seats. Interestingly, just before take-off, five people in pilots' uniforms occupied the supposedly broken seats, leaving business class fully occupied. The TV in my seat, which was claimed to be non-functional, worked perfectly fine. It was clear this was done to accommodate their own team.</p>

<p>While it's easy to dwell on negative experiences, there was a positive aspect to this journey. On our return flight on December 13, which was a midnight flight, it was my daughter's birthday. The Air India crew overheard this and, instead of the usual welcome drink, they brought champagne for all of us to celebrate even before we took off. This thoughtful gesture was indeed touching. When I inquired whether this change was due to the Tata takeover, the crew responded that this was always how Air India operated, which was intriguing.</p>

<h2><strong>What Does Air India Stand For?</strong></h2>

<p>Although I am not an aviation expert, my background in hospitality and customer service makes me appreciate organisations focused on service excellence. Transforming Air India is indeed an uphill task, but with dedicated efforts, it holds the potential for significant improvement and success. My friends working in the transformation team are committed to changing the airline, but culture is not built in a day. It takes years and positive reinforcement of company values. What does Air India stand for? Even they are struggling with that.</p>

<p>It's important to understand where Air India was before the Tata Group buyout. Air India operates over 140 aircraft, most of which are over a decade old and have never been refurbished. Airline veterans say that every seven to eight years, there should be a full refurbishment to keep the cabin fresh and functional. With broken seats and worn-out interiors, there is a significant problem, as there are no spare parts available, taking up to 18 months to get replacements. For example, even when the new flight on the Zurich to Delhi sector launched on June 16, my daughter was informed that 12 seats in business class were broken. Competing with Swiss Air from Zurich, which has great aircraft and service, Air India's branding suffers as people are unlikely to return after a poor first experience.</p>

<h2><strong>The Vistara Shutdown</strong></h2>

<p>One of the biggest blunders by the Tata Group is shutting down Vistara. The merger with Air India is poorly executed and ill-timed. The government and the Tata Group were aware that Air India was a defunct asset with old, tired planes, yet they approved the merger plan for short-term financial gain. Why couldn't the merger have been postponed for two years? The financial burden of maintaining Vistara could have been justified by its operational excellence and newer planes.</p>

<p>Vistara, with its reputation for service excellence and 70 new planes, contrasts sharply with Air India's outdated fleet. It is baffling that the Civil Aviation Ministry allowed the merger of a modern, well-functioning airline like Vistara with an outdated one and has approved Tata's decision to rebrand it as Air India.</p>

<p>Poor product and poor communication are two significant issues. Air India should conduct a masterclass on how not to communicate while running a consumer company. I recently travelled from Delhi to Hyderabad on Air India. The aircraft was fine and the service was great. But there was a communication problem. The flight was supposed to take off at 9:40 am, but it took off 40 minutes later without any announcement. The crew later informed us that a connecting flight from Amsterdam had passengers boarding this flight. This could have been communicated to all passengers so everyone knows the reason for the delay.</p>

<h2><strong>Respecting Public Opinion</strong></h2>

<p>Air India needs a communication protocol. Weekly updates on the fleet, on-time performance, and consistency on social media channels can help shift consumer opinion. Public opinion overwhelmingly suggests that the merger was a mistake. The Tata Group, the Competition Commission of India, and the Civil Aviation Ministry could have conducted a small consumer survey. My tweet on this received overwhelming responses - over 95% felt that Vistara and Air India should not have merged. Recent mishandling cases in Air India, whether it is long waits or lack of communication, highlight this.</p>

<p>The transformation team at Air India is under immense pressure, trying their best. Building a culture of service excellence takes time. With the sudden merger of a well-functioning airline with an old one, the hope is that the amalgamation will create a better airline. However, why couldn't this merger wait for 24 months? In a resurgent India, this is a classic case of ignoring public opinion. Flying in India is becoming restricted to a duopoly, so the consumer's choice is limited.</p>

<p>In conclusion, India faces challenging times in aviation. As a consumer, you have everything to lose post-September, when Vistara fades away. All you can do is pray that your Air India flight takes off on time and that you have a new plane. And do remember, good times don't last forever, the new feeling of flying Vistara is gone and dead too soon. The only silver lining is that even bad times don't last forever, and maybe Indigo and Akasa will take service excellence to new heights, till a resurgent Air India becomes the airline that you really want to be proud of.</p>

<p><em>(Kapil Chopra is the Founder of EazyDiner, India's most loved restaurant reservation app and The Postcard Hotel.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/57vgdbuo_vistara_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-good-reason-to-talk-to-putin-says-us-president-biden-6087873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Good Reason" To Talk To Putin, Says US President Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-good-reason-to-talk-to-putin-says-us-president-biden-6087873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:26:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has said that he has "no good reason" to talk to Vladimir Putin at the moment unless the Russian leader changes his behaviour.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden has said that he has "no good reason" to talk to Vladimir Putin at the moment unless the Russian leader changes his behaviour.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old president made these remarks on Thursday at a highly-anticipated solo press conference at the end of the NATO Summit in Washington.</p>

<p>“I have no good reason to talk to Putin right now. There's not much that he is prepared to do in terms of accommodating any change in his behaviour, but there isn't any world leader I'm not prepared to deal with,” Biden told reporters when asked if he is ready to talk to Putin.</p>

<p>“But I understand your generic point is, is Putin ready to talk? I'm not ready to talk to Putin unless Putin's ready to change his behaviour and the idea -- look, Putin's got a problem," Biden said, dismissing concerns about his health despite a growing list of Democratic leaders urging him to step aside from the 2024 presidential election following last month's disastrous debate with his Republican rival, Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"First of all, in this war that he supposedly has won, and by the way, I think, don't hold me to the exact number, but I think that Russia had 17.3 per cent of Ukraine that they've conquered, now it's 17.4. I mean, in terms of percentage of territory,” he said.</p>

<p>“They've not been very successful. They've caused horrible damage, and loss of life, but they've also lost over 350,000 troops, military, killed or wounded. They have over a million people, particularly young people with technical capability leaving Russia because they see no future there. They've got a problem,” said the president.</p>

<p>“But what they do have control of is they are very good at controlling and running the public outcry that relates to how they use mechanisms to communicate with people. They lie like hell to the constituencies. They lie like hell about what's going on. So the idea that we're going to be able to fundamentally Change Russia in the near term is not likely,” he told reporters.</p>

<p>“But one thing for certain. If we allow Russia to succeed in Ukraine, they're not stopping in Ukraine...I'm prepared to talk to any leader who wants to talk, including if Putin calls me and wants to talk. The last time, I talked to Putin was trying to get him to work on an arms control agreement related to nuclear weapons and space. That didn't go very far,” he said.</p>

<p>“So, my point is I'm prepared to talk to anybody, but I don't see any inclination. There is an inclination on the part of the Chinese to keep in contact with me because they're not sure where this all goes. Look what's happened in Asia. We have strengthened the Asian-Pacific area more than anyone else has,” he said.</p>

<p>“I asked our NATO allies that we bring on the group from the South Pacific, Australia, New Zealand, Japan, Australia. I've met twice now, with the 14 leaders of the Pacific island nations, and we've slowed down what's going on there. We've slowed down China's reach. But there's a lot of work to do. This is a moving target, and I don't take it lightly,” Biden said.</p>

<p>He used the press conference to deliver a forceful defence of his foreign and domestic policies and batted away questions about his ability to serve another four years, declaring, "I'm not in this for my legacy. I'm in this to complete the job." There have been concerns about Biden's ability to serve another four-year term as president since his stumbling performance in a presidential debate opposite Donald Trump last month.</p>

<p>Age and mental fitness have recently become a major issue in the US presidential race.</p>

<p>While the issue has troubled President Biden, and his Republican rival Trump, 78, in the past, things reached a tipping point after Biden's disastrous debate performance last month.</p>

<p>While Biden is the oldest president in US history, Trump, if elected in November, would be the second oldest.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opt29ctk_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-set-to-deploy-starwars-laser-weapons-to-take-down-n-korean-drones-6087822]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Set To Deploy 'StarWars' Laser Weapons For Drone Defence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-set-to-deploy-starwars-laser-weapons-to-take-down-n-korean-drones-6087822]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:11:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea on Thursday announced that it is ready to start mass-producing laser weapons like those in the 'Star Wars' franchise to shoot down North Korean drones.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea on Thursday announced that it is ready to start mass-producing laser weapons like those in the<em> 'Star Wars' </em>franchise to shoot down North Korean drones. According to <em>Newsweek</em>, the drone-killing system, called the Block-I, will be deployed later this year. With this, South Korea will become the world's first country to deploy a technology that is being developed by several armed forces. Moreover, the country's Defense Acquisition Program Administration (DAPA) announced that an even more powerful version is also being planned, which could be a "game changer" in the future.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/south-korea-develops-laser-drone-defense-1923766"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, South Korea has named its laser program the "StarWars Project". The country's DAPA, which handles defence procurement, development and production, announced a 100 billion won contract to build the drone-killing weapon. It touted the weapon as effective and cheap and revealed that the laser is quiet and invisible, and one shot costs only 2,000 won.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our country is becoming the first country in the world to deploy and operate laser weapons, and our military's response capabilities on North Korea's drone provocation will be further strengthened," the agency said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thetimes.com/world/asia/article/south-koreas-star-wars-laser-to-bring-down-drones-at-110-a-shot-fscqswpks"><em>Times </em></a>reported that Block-I uses fibre optic cables to generate a laser beam intended to be fired at relatively close range against small drones. Each shot is silent and invisible to the naked eye. It lasts 10 to 20 seconds and creates a temperature of more than 700 Celsius, which is enough to damage and disable a drone's engine or battery. It can be fired wherever there is a sufficient supply of electricity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Cost per fire is extremely cheap compared with other guided weapons," Jo Yong-jin, a spokesman for the DAPA, told reporters in Seoul. "Responses to low-cost strike assets and weapons, such as small drones, will be able to take place very effectively and efficiently," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>South Korean aerospace company Hanwha Aerospace Co. is contracted to manufacture the weapons. <em>Newsweek </em>reported that DAPA is already planning to develop a more powerful, longer-ranged anti-aircraft laser weapon: the Block-II. This weapon will involve boosting the power of the laser beam to hundreds of kilowatts, with the aim of taking down larger targets like ballistic missiles and planes.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/switzerland-halts-rollout-of-sarco-suicide-pods-dubbed-tesla-of-euthanasia-6085239">Switzerland Halts Rollout Of 'Sarco' Suicide Pods, Dubbed "Tesla Of Euthanasia"</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, several countries, including the US, UK, Israel, Turkey, Germany and Japan have also developed laser weapons. Earlier this year, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-shows-uks-first-laser-weapon-that-can-hit-a-coin-from-a-kilometre-away-5223169">UK's Ministry of Defence</a> tested a laser weapon, DragonFire, which reportedly destroyed incoming drones from several miles away during a trial. With this, the ministry hopes that it will pave the way for a low-cost alternative to missiles to shoot down targets like drones. It further said that the weapon is precise enough to hit a coin from a kilometre away.&nbsp;</p>

<p>DragonFire will be used both by the Army and the Royal Navy as part of their future air defence capabilities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8s9gfsv_laser-_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[South Korea has named its laser program the "StarWars Project". (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-man-25-arrested-for-groping-at-canada-water-park-6087794]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Man, 25, Arrested For Groping At Canada Water Park]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-man-25-arrested-for-groping-at-canada-water-park-6087794]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:10:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian origin man was arrested for groping women at a public water park in Canada on July 7, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian origin man was arrested for groping women at a public water park in Canada on July 7, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 25-year-old walking at a public water park on Mountain Road in Moncton, and groping people. According to the police, there were at least twelve victims, some of whom were under the age of 16.</p>

<p>Police located the man who was still on the premises, and arrested him. He was later released from custody, and is now scheduled to appear in Moncton Provincial Court on October 24.</p>

<p>"This is still an active investigation, and we are working diligently to understand if there were other victims," police said in an official press release.</p>

<p>Police also asked people to come forward in case they know anything related to the case.</p>

<p>"We are asking parents to speak to their children if they attended this location on July 7. We also want people to know that a sexual assault complaint can be made at any time. If you are a victim of sexual misconduct, please contact us. You will be listened to, and you will be believed", the press release said.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/gg48gv18_canada-police_625x300_09_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police located the man who was still on the premises, and arrested him.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/they-spared-nothing-israel-bombs-gaza-killing-25-in-fiercest-week-of-war-6087783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Spared Nothing": Israel Bombs Gaza Killing 25 In "Fiercest" Week Of War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/they-spared-nothing-israel-bombs-gaza-killing-25-in-fiercest-week-of-war-6087783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:04:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel rained bombs on Gaza City during a week that residents described as comparable to the fiercest battle of the war, while a Palestinian Islamic Jihad official on Thursday said a new round of peace talks ended with no agreements yet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel rained bombs on Gaza City during a week that residents described as comparable to the fiercest battle of the war, while a Palestinian Islamic Jihad official on Thursday said a new round of peace talks ended with no agreements yet.</p>

<p>Israel has been bombarding the Gaza Strip for 10 months in a war that has laid waste to the territory and killed more than 38,000 Palestinians, according to medical authorities in Gaza.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Israeli airstrikes killed at least six people in Gaza City and 19 in the rest of the Gaza Strip, according to Palestinian authorities. The civil emergency service said the bodies of at least 30 Palestinians killed in the previous three days also laid scattered on unreachable roads in Gaza City.</p>

<p>The latest round of peace talks ended with no agreements, while Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accused Palestinian operative group Hamas of making demands that contradicted a framework deal brokered by Washington. Netanyahu did not say what those demands were.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Palestinian Islamist operative&nbsp;group said mediators had yet to provide it with updates on the state of the talks since it made concessions last week in response to a U.S.-backed Israeli peace offer.</p>

<p>Washington is pushing for a peace deal at talks in Egypt and Qatar to end the Gaza war, now in its 10th month. The head of Israel's Shin Bet intelligence agency was headed to Cairo to pursue the negotiations, Netanyahu's office said.</p>

<p>In Washington, White House National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan said many details still need to be hammered out to secure a deal.</p>

<p>In its statement on Thursday, Hamas accused Israel of "stalling to buy time to foil this round of negotiations, as it has done in previous rounds", all of which have ended in failure since a week-long truce in November.</p>

<p>As peace talks dragged on, Gaza City residents endured a fierce night of bombing.</p>

<p>Home to more than a quarter of Gaza's residents before the war, Gaza City was largely razed to the ground in late 2023, but hundreds of thousands of Palestinians have returned to homes in the ruins. Israel has once again ordered them out, though it is unclear where residents can go safely. Israel controls most of Gaza's borders.</p>

<p>Many say they will not leave.</p>

<p>"We will die but not leave to the south. We have tolerated starvation and bombs for nine months and we are ready to die as martyrs here," said Mohammad Ali, 30, reached by text message.</p>

<p>Ali, whose family has relocated several times within the city, said they had been running short of food, water and medicine.</p>

<p>"The occupation (Israel) bombs Gaza City as if the war was restarting. We hope there will be a ceasefire soon, but if not then is God's will."</p>

<p>The Israeli army told Gaza City residents on Wednesday to use two "safe routes" to head south. Some posted a hashtag on social media: "We are not leaving".</p>

<p>Asked by Reuters to comment on its operations in Gaza City, the Israeli military said in a statement its forces were working to dismantle Hamas capabilities, and that it "follows international law and takes feasible precautions to mitigate civilian harm." It said the same was not true of Hamas.</p>

<p>Critics have accused Israel of committing genocide against Palestinians, which Israel denies. It characterizes its actions as self-defense, though the International Court of Justice ordered Israel in January to take action to prevent acts of genocide.</p>

<p>Israel launched its assault on the Gaza Strip last year after Hamas-led&nbsp;operatives&nbsp;entered southern Israel, killing 1,200 people and capturing more than 250 hostages according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>An Israeli military report on Thursday acknowledged that it had failed to protect the citizens of one of the worst-hit communities, Kibbutz Be'eri, where more than 100 people were killed.</p>

<h3><strong>PALESTINIAN CIVILIANS CALL FOR WAR TO END</strong></h3>

<p>The negotiations in Qatar and Egypt follow important concessions last week from Hamas, which accepted that a truce could begin and some hostages be released without Israel first agreeing to end the war.</p>

<p>Just east of Gaza City in the Shejaia suburb, residents were returning on foot to a desolate moonscape of destroyed buildings after Israeli forces withdrew following a two-week offensive.</p>

<p>The territory's main cemetery had been bulldozed by the army. People wheeled supplies on the back of bicycles across rubble-strewn tracks, passing the remains of burnt-out and blasted Israeli armoured vehicles.</p>

<p>"We have returned to Shejaia after 15 days. You can see the destruction. They spared nothing, even trees, there was a lot of greenery in this area. What is the guilt of stones and trees? And what is my guilt as a civilian?" resident Hatem Tayeh told Reuters in the ruins.</p>

<p>"There are bodies of civilian people. What is the guilt of the civilian? Who are you fighting?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ojngdn18_israel-hamas-war-gaza-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As peace talks dragged on, Gaza City residents endured a fierce night of bombing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madan-ashrit-highway-landslide-sweeps-two-passenger-bus-in-central-nepal-highway-five-dozen-people-suspected-missing-6087525]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Landslide Sweeps Two Passenger Bus In Central Nepal Highway, 60 Missing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madan-ashrit-highway-landslide-sweeps-two-passenger-bus-in-central-nepal-highway-five-dozen-people-suspected-missing-6087525]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 08:31:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least five dozen people are suspected to be missing after a landslide along the Madan-Ashrit Highway in Central Nepal swept two passenger buses in early Friday morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least five dozen people are suspected to be missing after a landslide along the Madan-Ashrit Highway in Central Nepal swept two passenger buses in early Friday morning.</p>

<p>As per the officials on the site of the incident, the bus is assumed to have been swept down to the Trishuli River which has swollen hampering the search and rescue operation.</p>

<p>"As per the preliminary information both the buses were carrying a total of 63 people, including the bus drivers. The landslide swept the buses at around 3:30 AM. We are at the incident site and a search operation is underway. Incessant rain is hampering our efforts to search for the missing buses," Indradev Yadav, Chief District Officer, Chitwan confirmed ANI over the phone.</p>

<p>As per the official, the landslide swept the Kathmandu-bound Angel bus and Ganpati Deluxe, which was heading from Kathmandu to Rautahat's Gaur. As per the preliminary reports of the officials, there were 24 people onboard the bus that was heading to Kathmandu and 41 people were travelling in another bus.</p>

<p>Taking to X, Nepal PM Pushpa Kamal Dahal stated, "I am deeply saddened by the reports of about five dozen passengers that are missing when bus was washed away by a landslide on the Narayangadh- Muglin road section and the loss of properties due to floods and landslides in different parts of the country. I direct all agencies of the government, including the home administration, to search and effectively rescue the passengers."</p>

<p>All the flights from Kathmandu to Chitwan's Bharatpur has been cancelled for the day as the weather remains grim.</p>

<p>Three of the passengers on the Ganpati Deluxe managed to escape after jumping out of the vehicle. Nepal Police and Armed Police Force personnel are heading towards the incident sites for rescue operations, Superintendent of Police Bhawesh Rimal informed. Debris from landslides at various places has obstructed traffic on the Narayanghat-Mugling road section.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j8qj6h7_madanashrit-highway-nepal-landslide-ani-twitter_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As per the official, the landslide swept the Kathmandu-bound Angel bus and Ganpati Deluxe.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alec-baldwin-charged-with-involuntary-manslaughter-had-live-rounds-on-set-6087627]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alec Baldwin, Charged With Involuntary Manslaughter, Had Live Rounds On Set]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alec-baldwin-charged-with-involuntary-manslaughter-had-live-rounds-on-set-6087627]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 08:28:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Live rounds were found in the cartridge belts of Alec Baldwin and another actor on the set of a Western movie that was the scene of a fatal shooting, a police technician testified Thursday at the trial of the Hollywood star.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Live rounds were found in the cartridge belts of Alec Baldwin and another actor on the set of a Western movie that was the scene of a fatal shooting, a police technician testified Thursday at the trial of the Hollywood star.</p>

<p>Baldwin, 66, is charged with involuntary manslaughter in connection with the October 2021 death of cinematographer Halyna Hutchins during filming of the movie "Rust."</p>

<p>The actor -- known for the television comedy "30 Rock" -- was holding a prop revolver during a rehearsal in a church when it fired a live round, killing Hutchins and wounding the movie's director.</p>

<p>Marissa Poppell, a crime scene technician, testified that a number of live rounds were mixed in with dummy rounds on the set of the movie being filmed in New Mexico, where the trial is taking place.</p>

<p>Poppell, under questioning from Baldwin's attorney, Alex Spiro, on the second day of the trial said a live round was found in Baldwin's bandolier.</p>

<p>"You had no reason to think that Mr Baldwin had any idea that was there?" Spiro asked.</p>

<p>"Correct," Poppell replied.</p>

<p>She said another actor on the set, Jensen Ackles, also had a live bullet in his bandolier and also had no reason to believe that he knew it was there either.</p>

<p>The jury was also shown photographs of ammunition boxes on a prop cart with live rounds mixed in with dummy bullets. The bullets are largely indistinguishable.</p>

<p>During opening arguments on Wednesday, prosecutor Erlinda Ocampo Johnson accused Baldwin of violating basic gun safety rules and playing "make-believe" with a deadly weapon.</p>

<p>Baldwin had behaved in "a reckless manner" and "without due regard for the safety of others" on set, Johnson said, allegedly failing to take weapons training seriously and regularly pointing firearms at people on set.</p>

<p>Baldwin faces up to 18 months in prison if found guilty.</p>

<p>Spiro, whose other clients include Elon Musk and Jay-Z, said Baldwin had no reason to believe the gun might be loaded and was not responsible as an actor for checking the weapon's contents.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Armorer convicted&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Hutchins, the victim, was originally from Ukraine, and her career as a Hollywood cinematographer was thriving when she was killed at the age of 42.</p>

<p>The tragedy occurred during a rehearsal in a small chapel on the Bonanza Creek Ranch, a historic location for Western movies, midway through the filming of "Rust."</p>

<p>Baldwin was practising a scene in which his outlaw character, trapped by two marshals, brandishes his Colt six-shooter.</p>

<p>In his opening arguments, Spiro focused blame on the movie's safety officials, including armourer Hannah Gutierrez, for allowing live rounds to be brought on set.</p>

<p>Gutierrez was convicted by the same court this year and is serving an 18-month sentence.</p>

<p>It is not known if Baldwin will take the stand in his defense. Legal experts say it would be a risky move, exposing the allegedly temperamental actor to hostile cross-examination.</p>

<p>The trial is scheduled to conclude on Friday of next week, with jury deliberations to follow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/vdq3r1f8_alec-baldwin_625x300_24_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alec Baldwin faces up to 18 months in prison if found guilty.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-donald-trump-nato-summit-slips-of-tongue-happen-allies-back-gaffing-biden-6087496]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Slips Of Tongue Happen": NATO Allies Back Gaffing Joe Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-donald-trump-nato-summit-slips-of-tongue-happen-allies-back-gaffing-biden-6087496]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:48:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[All was going according to plan. President Joe Biden was projecting himself as the leader of the free world as he hosted a NATO summit and then, in a moment, an embarrassing slip of the tongue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All was going according to plan. President Joe Biden was projecting himself as the leader of the free world as he hosted a NATO summit and then, in a moment, an embarrassing slip of the tongue.</p>

<p>With Biden struggling to convince many Americans that he remains fit for office, NATO leaders have been offering him votes of confidence, however delicately, at least in part out of fear of another <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-job-joe-donald-trump-mocks-joe-biden-gaffes-in-middle-of-nato-press-meet-6087136#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories">Donald Trump</a> presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden was closing out NATO's three-day 75th-anniversary summit in Washington, vowing forcefully, "Ukraine will prevail" against Russian President Vladimir Putin and hailing the courage of Ukraine's iconic wartime leader, Voldymyr Zelensky.</p>

<p>Turning to Zelensky in his war fatigues, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-introduces-zelensky-as-putin-at-nato-press-meet-corrects-himself-6086831">Joe Biden</a> said, "Ladies and gentlemen, President Putin."</p>

<p>Biden quickly corrected himself and Zelensky, a former comedian, promptly made light of the gaffe, saying, "I am better than Putin."</p>

<p>But the momentary lapse quickly revived memories of his debate two weeks earlier against Trump -- he had failed in his own task, to reassure the public he still had his wits.</p>

<h3><strong>Biden 'in charge'</strong></h3>

<p>Whether motivated by direct observation, fear of the return of Donald Trump or a simple reluctance to offend their host, no leaders openly questioned the competence of Biden, who at 81 is six years older than the alliance itself.</p>

<p>French President Emmanuel Macron said he spoke to Biden at length at a White House dinner for leaders.</p>

<p>"I saw as always a president who is in charge, clear on the issues he knows well," Macron said.</p>

<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz similarly said that Biden "showed leadership for our common alliance."</p>

<p>"Slips of the tongue happen, and if you keep a close enough eye on everyone, you will find enough," Scholz said.</p>

<p>New UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer said that senility allegations against Biden were misguided and that the two allies covered wide ground for nearly one hour in the Oval Office, longer than expected.</p>

<p>"We did it at pace. He was on good form," Starmer, whose Labour Party last week swept out the Conservatives and has no love lost with Trump, told British media before the summit gaffe.</p>

<p>Polish President Andrzej Duda, who had forged close ties with Trump but has appreciated Biden's support for Ukraine, told reporters: "I talked with President Biden, and there is no doubt that everything is ok."</p>

<p>Finnish President Alexander Stubb, asked if he had concerns about the United States, said that in democracies there is "always turmoil before elections."</p>

<p>"I have absolutely no concern about the capacity of the current president of the United States to lead his country and to lead our fight for Ukraine and to lead NATO," he said.</p>

<p>"The only thing I'm worried about is that the political climate in the United States right now is too toxic, is very polarized, and that doesn't leave enough room for a civilized and constructive debate" on policy, he told reporters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Many NATO leaders privately fear a victory in November of Trump, who has loudly criticized the alliance, with its promise of collective defense, as an unfair burden to the United States.</p>

<p>Trump aides have mused about conditioning aid to Ukraine to force Kyiv to surrender territory and make a quick deal to end the war, which they call a distraction from a larger challenge of China.</p>

<p>Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen, while saying she would not comment on the US election, stressed that the United States and Europe would remain united no matter who wins the election.</p>

<p>"You saved us once," she said of the United States. "Please stick to that way of working."</p>

<p>One discordant voice in NATO has been Hungary's populist prime minister Viktor Orban.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He traveled to Russia and China, as well as Ukraine, before the NATO summit and, after it is over, was heading to Florida to see Trump.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1dd3c4_joe-biden-olaf-scholz-_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[German Chancellor Olaf Scholz said Joe Biden "showed leadership for our common alliance."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-claims-he-is-most-qualified-to-be-president-amid-series-of-gaffes-6087429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Latest Gaffe, Biden Calls Kamala Harris "Vice President Trump"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-claims-he-is-most-qualified-to-be-president-amid-series-of-gaffes-6087429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:26:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden defiantly insisted Thursday that he will run for another term and win, as a series of verbal gaffes while leading a major summit threw a harsh new spotlight on his fitness.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden defiantly insisted Thursday that he will run for another term and win, as a series of verbal gaffes while leading a major summit threw a harsh new spotlight on his fitness.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old president sought to show himself in command as he led the NATO summit in Washington two weeks after a disastrous debate performance raised fears among Democrats that he may lose to Donald Trump.</p>

<p>But Biden mistakenly introduced Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky as his Russian foe Vladimir Putin before quickly correcting himself.</p>

<p>At a high-stakes evening news conference afterward, Biden mistakenly referred to "Vice President" Trump.</p>

<p>But he vowed to stay in the race.</p>

<p>"I think I'm the most qualified person to run for president. I beat him once, and I will beat him again," Biden said of Trump.</p>

<p>Biden, already the oldest person to be elected the first time to the White House, said he was "not in this for my legacy" but to "complete the job I started."</p>

<p>Biden has faced a steady drumbeat of Democrats calling for him to abandon his 2024 candidacy, fearing that Trump is in a position to beat him.</p>

<p>Biden made clear he supported Harris -- who as vice president would take over from him, but is also seen by a growing number of Democrats as a stronger candidate at the top of the ticket.</p>

<p>Biden said he would not have picked Kamala Harris, whom he accidentally referred to as Trump, if "she was not qualified to be president."</p>

<p>He also denied reports that he needed to go to bed by 8 pm, a time at which he was still holding his news conference on Thursday.</p>

<p>"Instead of my every day starting at 7:00 am and going to bed at midnight, it would be smarter for me to pace myself a little more," Biden said.</p>

<h2>'Slips of the tongue happen'</h2>

<p>Biden's error on Zelensky's name drew gasps from the room but Zelensky, Ukraine's wartime leader against Russia's 2022 invasion, laughed it off.</p>

<p>Fellow leaders at the summit have fielded questions about Biden, and their answers have largely been supportive.</p>

<p>"Slips of the tongue happen, and if you keep a close enough eye on everyone, you will find enough," German Chancellor Olaf Scholz said after the president's latest gaffe.</p>

<p>French President Emmanuel Macron said Biden had appeared "in charge," while British Prime Minister Keir Starmer said he "was on good form."</p>

<p>But key American supporters have moved away from the diplomatic niceties.</p>

<p>Hollywood actor and well-connected Democratic supporter George Clooney called on Biden to exit the race, and party grandee Nancy Pelosi has stopped short of fully backing him.</p>

<p>Around 14 Democratic members of the House of Representatives have openly urged the man who beat Trump four years ago to drop out, along with one Democratic senator.</p>

<p>A poll released on Thursday showed more than half of Democrats say Biden should end his bid for a second term, and two-thirds of Americans believe he should quit the race.</p>

<p>But the former president and the incumbent remain in a dead heat on 46 percent, according to the Washington Post-ABC News-Ipsos survey.</p>

<p>Biden's campaign was however quietly testing the strength of Harris in a potential match-up against Trump, The New York Times reported.</p>

<p>Some of the president's longtime aides are meanwhile discussing how to convince him that he should step aside, the paper also said, citing anonymous sources.</p>

<p>The White House said the report was "unequivocally" false.</p>

<p>The once-talkative Biden has given fewer news conferences than his predecessors, but he was speaking at unusual length Thursday in what his aides called a "big boy" press event.</p>

<p>Biden has called his debate meltdown a "bad night," blaming it on a cold and jet lag.</p>

<p>But Clooney tried to torpedo the narrative that it was a one-off, saying it was "devastating" to admit but the signs were also clear at a June 15 fundraiser in Los Angeles he hosted.</p>

<p>Biden's campaign fought back Thursday with a new ad campaign on the last day of the NATO summit portraying Trump as a "lap dog" of Putin.</p>

<p>NATO allies have also been seeking reassurance about Biden's leadership abilities and over their fears that a return of the isolationist, Putin-praising Trump could spell trouble for the alliance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c68fmg1o_joe-biden_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-seizes-foreign-cargo-ship-that-looted-grain-from-crimea-6087426]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Seizes Foreign Cargo Ship That "Looted" Grain From Crimea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-seizes-foreign-cargo-ship-that-looted-grain-from-crimea-6087426]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:25:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kyiv said Thursday that it had seized a foreign cargo ship and detained its captain, alleging that the vessel had illegally exported Ukrainian grain from the annexed Crimean peninsula.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kyiv said Thursday that it had seized a foreign cargo ship and detained its captain, alleging that the vessel had illegally exported Ukrainian grain from the annexed Crimean peninsula.</p>

<p>Since Russia's capture of swaths of agricultural land in Ukraine in early 2022, Kyiv has accused Moscow of illegally harvesting and shipping grain produced on occupied territory to third countries.</p>

<p>The office of the prosecutor general in Ukraine said it had seized the vessel in the southern Odesa region, and that the ship had earlier exported agricultural products via Sevastopol -- a key Russian Black Sea naval hub in Crimea.</p>

<p>The waterway has become a fierce battleground of the war, and Ukraine has beaten back a formidable Russian naval blockade of its ports with a fleet of relatively cheap maritime drones.</p>

<p>The Security Services of Ukraine (SBU) said in a separate statement that it had detained the ship's captain, accusing him of violating rules on entering occupied territory.</p>

<p>It also claimed that the grain exported by the vessel -- Usko Mfu -- had been "looted" from southern Ukraine.</p>

<p>The charges against the captain carry a maximum penalty of five years in prison, the SBU said, while prosecutors identified him as a citizen of Azerbaijan, an ex-Soviet country in the South Caucasus.</p>

<h3><strong>Shipments to Turkey&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Prosecutors said 12 other foreign crew members were on board at the time of the vessel's seizure, without elaborating on their nationality or whether they too would face charges.</p>

<p>The Cameroonian-flagged vessel illegally docked at Sevastopol in November 2023 and loaded more than 3,000 tonnes of agricultural products "intended" for a Turkish company, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>"To conceal the illegal activity, the ship's Automatic Identification System (AIS) was turned off before entering the port of Sevastopol, which is a gross violation of maritime safety requirements," their statement added.</p>

<p>Prosecutors said the ship returned to Sevastopol a second time in May this year.</p>

<p>It was seized at the Ukrainian port of Reni, they added, where they discovered documents issued by Sevastopol port authorities.</p>

<p>The port on the Danube in west Ukraine was one of several systematically targeted by Russian aerial attacks after Moscow last year scrapped a UN and Turkish-brokered deal allowing Ukrainian grain exports via the Black Sea.</p>

<p>Igor Delanoe -- deputy director of the Franco-Russian Observatory -- said this was the first time Ukraine had seized an internationally-flagged vessel over the shipments.</p>

<h3><strong>'Sends a signal'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"The signal is that they want to make third countries face up to their responsibilities," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"From the Ukrainian point of view, these countries are supporting Russia by their silence, while at the same time benefiting from grain that Ukrainians consider stolen," he added.</p>

<p>Prosecutors said later on state television they had issued 21 warrants to seize cargo ships in absentia they believe have docked at Ukrainian ports under Russian occupation.</p>

<p>Igor Ponochovny, a Ukrainian official in the prosecutor's office working on issues related to the Crimean peninsula, which was annexed by Russian forces in 2014, said the seizure was a "signal to countries that help Russia to circumvent sanctions."</p>

<p>The European Union in May imposed "prohibitive" duties on grain imports from Russia in a bid to cut off revenues to Moscow for its war on Ukraine.</p>

<p>The bloc's trade commissioner said the measure would "tackle illegal Russian exports of stolen Ukraine grain into EU markets".</p>

<p>The head of Ukraine's southern Kherson region, which the Kremlin claims is part of Russia, said Thursday that Russian forces caused fires on dozens of hectares of Ukrainian land growing grain.</p>

<p>He also said that Russian forces had struck a grain storage facility in the region and attacked firefighters who arrived to extinguish the fire with drones.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/ur1n6b5g_ukraine-cargo-ship-reuters_625x300_16_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The cargo ship was seized at the Ukrainian port of Reni (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-ready-to-undergo-neurological-exam-if-doctors-recommend-6087318]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Ready To Undergo Neurological Exam If Doctors Recommend": Joe Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-ready-to-undergo-neurological-exam-if-doctors-recommend-6087318]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:15:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid the mounting pressure from fellow Democrats to end his re-election campaign, US President Joe Biden has indicated willingness to undergo a neurological exam to address concerns about his mental fitness for office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid the mounting pressure from fellow Democrats to end his re-election campaign, US President Joe Biden has indicated willingness to undergo a neurological exam to address concerns about his mental fitness for office, but only if his doctors recommend it, CNN reported.</p>

<p>"I am not opposed, if my doctors tell me I should have another neurological exam, I'll do it," he said at a rare solo news conference Thursday at the conclusion of the NATO Summit.</p>

<p>He further added, "Every single day I'm surrounded by good docs. If they think there's a problem, I promise you - or even if they don't think it's a problem and think I should have a neurologic exam again, I'll do it. No one's suggesting that right now," as per CNN.</p>

<p>But, the president lamented growing concerns about his age, "No matter what I did, no one's gonna be satisfied."</p>

<p>Biden said he has had three brain health checks while in office, with the most recent one happening in February."</p>

<p>"I'm tested every single day on my neurological capacity - the decisions I make every day," he said, pointing to age as a source of wisdom.</p>

<p>Further, Biden told reporters Thursday he's committed to remaining in the race ahead, but acknowledged he has to make his case to detractors and American voters concerned over his fitness for office following a disastrous debate performance.</p>

<p>"I'm determined on running, but I think it's important that I allay fears by seeing -- letting them see me out there," Biden said.</p>

<p>He cited his robust travel schedule in the days since the debate, pointing to "over 20 major events, from Wisconsin and North Carolina," emphasizing he's "going out to the areas where we can persuade people to move our way or people are already there."</p>

<p>"I'm going to be going around making the case of the things that I think we have to finish and how we can't afford to lose what we've done," he said, citing efforts under his administration.</p>

<p>After the CNN debate with former US President Donald Trump on June 28, the leaders have been pushing Biden to step down from the presidential race despite this he has declared that he is staying and expressed confidence that he would defeat former President Trump.</p>

<p>On July 8, a leadership call was organised by House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries, where several top House Democrats urged President Joe Biden to step aside from the 2024 campaign, expressing deep concerns about his potential impact on the Democratic Party's chances in the upcoming elections.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/id1lgo5k_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden lamented growing concerns about his age.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-joe-biden-is-ignoring-fellow-democrats-calls-to-leave-race-6087324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Biden Is Ignoring Fellow Democrats' Calls To Leave Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-joe-biden-is-ignoring-fellow-democrats-calls-to-leave-race-6087324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 06:56:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shortly after President Joe Biden's halting debate with Donald Trump on June 27, his exit from the 2024 U.S. presidential race seemed all but inevitable to some longtime allies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after President Joe Biden's halting debate with Donald Trump on June 27, his exit from the 2024 U.S. presidential race seemed all but inevitable to some longtime allies.</p>

<p>Donors called it a disaster and held frantic calls to discuss next steps. Newspaper columnists demanded he bow out. Some Democratic lawmakers said plainly their party leader must step aside.</p>

<p>Two weeks later, Biden hasn't budged.</p>

<p>While acknowledging that at 81, he is no longer a young man and blaming exhaustion for his performance, he failed in a defiant follow-up televised interview to quell concerns it was more than just one bad debate night.</p>

<p>More Democrats are expected to ask Biden to leave the race in coming days. For now, the White House says it plans to "turn the page" on the incident, despite some opinion polls showing Trump's lead widening and swing states leaning Republican.</p>

<p>Why is Biden ignoring fellow Democrats and insisting he will beat Trump, 78, in the Nov. 5 election?</p>

<p>The reasons range from the deeply personal to party politics, interviews with more Democratic officials, aides, strategists and donors show.</p>

<p><strong>BIDEN BELIEVES IN BIDEN</strong></p>

<p>Biden's decision to run for reelection in the first place, despite his age, centered around his belief that he was the best Democratic candidate to defeat Trump, officials and allies told Reuters at the time.</p>

<p>Biden was skeptical about the ability of his vice president, Kamala Harris, to win over middle-of-the road voters, especially in critical swing states, and also of the ability of any of the deep bench of Democratic governors and lawmakers who are likely to be the party's future leaders, these sources said.</p>

<p>Explaining his decision to stay the course, Biden told George Stephanopoulos of ABC News last week: "I'm the most qualified person to beat him (Trump)." He later added that only the "Lord almighty" could convince him differently.</p>

<p>A defining principle of Biden's grief-stricken personal life and long political career has been perseverance, which he says he learned from his parents.</p>

<p>"My dad, who fell on hard times, always told me, though, 'Champ, when you get knocked down, get up. Get up," he told the 2008 Democratic National Convention when he accepted the nomination as Barack Obama's running mate.</p>

<p>He said his mother taught him: "Failure at some point in your life is inevitable, but giving up is unforgivable."</p>

<p>Actor George Clooney echoed the concerns of many Democrats about this principle, writing in a New York Times opinion piece on Wednesday that it was time for Biden to leave the race. Clooney said that "the one battle he cannot win is the fight against time. None of us can."</p>

<p><strong>BIDEN'S CLOSEST AIDES ARE DUG IN</strong></p>

<p>Biden's inner circle of top aides has reinforced his determination to hold on, according to sources close to them.</p>

<p>Biden has surrounded himself for decades with a small cadre of senior aides, such as political adviser Mike Donilon, counselor Steve Ricchetti, and deputy chief of staff Bruce Reed, who have steered him through previous crises and urged him to hang on.</p>

<p>That dynamic has only been amplified since the fallout from the debate.</p>

<p>"I have heard that Steve and Bruce and Mike are more dug in than he is," said one former Biden aide with ties to the White House. "They have grown roots and are not moving."</p>

<p>A White House official confirmed that characterization and said the dug-in approach applied to Biden's full senior staff.</p>

<p>Many of his aides, including senior adviser Anita Dunn, reinforce a sense of grievance and resolve around Biden: that he has been treated unfairly by the media, that he does not get the credit he deserves for toppling Trump in 2020, and that he has been underestimated before and proven his critics wrong.</p>

<p>Many people in Biden's orbit feel that way, the White House official said.</p>

<p>A memo circulated on Thursday by Jen O'Malley Dillon and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, Biden's campaign chair and manager, respectively, said there was no better alternative to Biden.</p>

<p>"Surveys do not take into account the negative media environment that any Democratic nominee will encounter. The only Democratic candidate for whom this is already baked in is President Biden," they wrote.</p>

<p><strong>SOME DEMOCRATS FEAR CHANCES WITH HARRIS</strong></p>

<p>Biden's ability to beat back Democratic calls for him to exit the race may have less to do with his own candidacy than the lackluster feeling some Democrats have about the potential alternatives to replace him.</p>

<p>In interviews, about a dozen Democrats, including elected officials and activists, many of them in the battleground state of Pennsylvania, all expressed deep concerns about Biden's mental fitness and ability to beat Trump.</p>

<p>But they also had little trust in a bench of Democrats led by Harris.</p>

<p>If Biden were to step down, they believe the party could not bypass Harris – the nation's first Black vice president and first woman vice president – without risking the diverse coalition needed to win the White House.</p>

<p>"It has to be Harris and I don't think that puts us in a better position to win than with a hobbled Joe Biden," said one senior Democrat in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>On the other hand, some Democrats say Harris could bring new enthusiasm to the party and reenergize youth and Black voters.</p>

<p><strong>CONGRESS FEARS AND TRADITIONS</strong></p>

<p>Soon after Biden's debate, the leaders of both the Congressional Black Caucus and the Congressional Hispanic Caucus issued statements of support for Biden, which appeared to slow the trickle of criticism.</p>

<p>With their endorsement, rank-and-file Democrats were hard-pressed this week to publicly abandon Biden.</p>

<p>As of Thursday, only 11 of the 213 Democrats in the House of Representatives and one of the Senate's 51 Democrats had appealed to the president to withdraw from the race.</p>

<p>But multiple House members said they believed there was more to come, noting that they were expecting Democratic Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries to pass on the criticisms from within the party to Biden.</p>

<p>"I wish more people were less scared," said Democratic Representative Seth Moulton, one of the House members who have called for Biden to end his campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opt29ctk_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden has been facing pressure to drop out of the presidential race since his debate against Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-hed-still-be-able-to-deal-with-vladimir-putin-xi-jinping-in-3-years-6087166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says He'd Still Be Able To "Deal" With Putin, Xi Jinping In 3 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-hed-still-be-able-to-deal-with-vladimir-putin-xi-jinping-in-3-years-6087166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 06:06:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Thursday he would still be ready to deal with Russian leader Vladimir Putin and China's Xi Jinping well into a second term as he faced questions over his advancing years and fitness for office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said Thursday he would still be ready to deal with Russian leader Vladimir Putin and China's Xi Jinping well into a second term as he faced questions over his advancing years and fitness for office.</p>

<p>"I'm ready to deal with them now and three years from now... there isn't any world leader that I'm not prepared to deal with," he told reporters at the White House.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opt29ctk_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said Thursday he would still be ready to deal with Vladimir Putin and China's Xi Jinping.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-job-joe-donald-trump-mocks-joe-biden-gaffes-in-middle-of-nato-press-meet-6087136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Great Job Joe": Trump Mocks Biden Gaffes In Middle Of NATO Press Meet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-job-joe-donald-trump-mocks-joe-biden-gaffes-in-middle-of-nato-press-meet-6087136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 05:54:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Thursday mocked Joe Biden while the US president, who is under huge pressure due to concerns over his mental fitness, made verbal slips during a high-stakes press conference.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Thursday mocked Joe Biden while the US president, who is under huge pressure due to concerns over his mental fitness, made verbal slips during a high-stakes press conference.</p>

<p>"Crooked Joe begins his 'Big Boy' Press Conference with, 'I wouldn't have picked Vice President Trump to be vice president... Great job, Joe!" Trump said on his Truth Social site.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/tif74i68_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Thursday mocked Joe Biden after he made verbal slips during a press conference.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-the-most-qualified-person-to-run-for-president-biden-at-key-press-meet-6087049]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['I'M The Most Qualified Person To Run For President", Says Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-the-most-qualified-person-to-run-for-president-biden-at-key-press-meet-6087049]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 05:30:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Thursday he was the "most qualified" American to take on Donald Trump in November's presidential election as he faced growing calls from within his own party to step down.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said Thursday he was the "most qualified" American to take on Donald Trump in November's presidential election as he faced growing calls from within his own party to step down.</p>

<p>"I think I'm the most qualified person to run for president. I beat him once, and I will beat him again," Biden said, adding that he is "not in this for my legacy" but to "complete the job I started."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/id1lgo5k_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden said that he will beat Donald Trump again in Presidential elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emmanuel-macron-says-france-will-continue-to-support-ukraine-as-long-as-necessary-6086962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Macron Says France Will Continue To Support Ukraine "As Long As Necessary"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emmanuel-macron-says-france-will-continue-to-support-ukraine-as-long-as-necessary-6086962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 04:56:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden was "in charge" and on top of matters at a NATO summit with fellow leaders in Washington, French President Emmanuel Macron said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was "in charge" and on top of matters at a NATO summit with fellow leaders in Washington, French President Emmanuel Macron said Thursday.</p>

<p>"I was able to talk with President Biden at length yesterday at dinner," Macron told reporters. "I saw as always a president who is in charge, clear on the issues he knows well."</p>

<p>The French leader was also asked about a gaffe made by Biden just minutes earlier when he mistakenly introduced Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky as his Russian foe Vladimir Putin, before quickly correcting himself.</p>

<p>The blunder intensified concerns about Biden's age and mental acuity after a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump two weeks ago.</p>

<p>"We all slip up sometimes," Macron said. "It's happened to me and it could happen again tomorrow. I would ask for your indulgence."</p>

<p>Macron also said that France will continue to support Ukraine "as long as necessary."</p>

<p>Asked about recent visits to Russia and China by Viktor Orban, Macron said the Hungarian prime minister did not go there with any "mandate" from the EU.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2c802dbc_macron-nato-summit_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Macron said that France will continue to support Ukraine "as long as necessary."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>