<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 01:17:53 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-killed-in-las-vegas-shooting-suspect-arrested-report-5969903]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Five Killed In Las Vegas Shooting, Suspect Arrested: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-killed-in-las-vegas-shooting-suspect-arrested-report-5969903]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 01:12:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police in North Las Vegas on Tuesday captured a man they suspect shot and killed five people in an apartment complex, according to local media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police in North Las Vegas on Tuesday captured a man they suspect shot and killed five people in an apartment complex, according to local media reports.</p>

<p>The Las Vegas Review-Journal newspaper, citing a police statement, said that in addition to the five dead, a 13-year-old girl was also shot and is in critical condition at a nearby hospital.</p>

<p>North Las Vegas police did not return requests for comment.</p>

<p>Police identified the suspect as Eric Adams, 57, according to the Review-Journal. He is suspected of carrying out the shooting late on Monday in two different apartments within the same apartment complex.</p>

<p>Police did not provide details on any possible motive for the shooting, nor did they say when or how they arrested Adams.</p>

<p>Names of the victims have not been released, though police said that four women and one man were among those killed, according to the newspaper.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/6835sp0g_us-police-generic_625x300_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police said that four women and one man were among those killed in shooting. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-says-will-gauge-india-china-proposals-on-teesta-project-5967879]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh PM Says Will Gauge India, China Proposals On Teesta Project]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-says-will-gauge-india-china-proposals-on-teesta-project-5967879]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:01:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said on Tuesday that Bangladesh would gauge proposals from both India and China to build a mega project on the cross-border Teesta River involving a reservoir and accept the better one for her country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said on Tuesday that Bangladesh would gauge proposals from both India and China to build a mega project on the cross-border Teesta River involving a reservoir and accept the better one for her country.</p>

<p>PM Hasina, who visited India last week at the invitation of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, described her trip as "very fruitful" and said the outcome of her talks with India's top leadership will play a "pivotal role" in strengthening the existing bilateral relations and opening new avenues of cooperation.</p>

<p>"We undertook the Teesta projects. China has proposed, and so has India. We will evaluate both proposals and accept the one that is most beneficial and acceptable in terms of the interests of our people," the 76-year-old leader said while addressing a press conference here.</p>

<p>Asked which side she favoured more as far as India and China were concerned regarding the Teesta Project, PM Hasina said, "We maintain our friendships based on the developmental needs of our country”.</p>

<p>"When we receive a proposal, we consider factors such as its suitability for us, our capacity to repay any loans, the returns we will enjoy after project completion, and how it will benefit the people of our country," she said.</p>

<p>China has completed a physical survey on the project while India expressed its willingness to do another study regarding the implementation of the Teesta project.</p>

<p>India is presumed to have a reservation over China's involvement in a major project near its strategic Siliguri Corridor, also known as the Chicken's Neck, while Bangladesh's foreign ministry earlier said Dhaka would "take into cognizance the geopolitical issues" in proceeding with the proposal.</p>

<p>According to Bangladesh officials, China in 2020 proposed a major dredging work on the Teesta River and building reservoirs and embankments without India having to play any role, but Bangladesh has kept the billion-dollar project on hold.</p>

<p>Several analysts said the Chinese involvement in the project could complicate the India-Bangladesh dispute over the major common river.</p>

<p>The Teesta water sharing agreement has been in the talks since the Awami League government returned to power in 2009 while PM Hasina today said “Bangladesh has a longstanding issue over Teesta River water sharing with India”.</p>

<p>"So, it will be easy for Bangladesh if India does the Teesta project. In that case, we won't need to talk about the Teesta water sharing always," she added.</p>

<p>PM Hasina simultaneously said Bangladesh has a longstanding issue with India over water sharing of the 54 common rivers but added that “if there are problems, there are solutions as well".</p>

<p>"India has agreed to cooperate with us on the Teesta project. A joint committee will be formed to decide not only how the water will be shared but also how to revive the river, use it for cultivation in the northern region, and enhance its navigation," she said.</p>

<p>She said the water-sharing discussion included river dredging, constructing embankments and water conservation measures as well.</p>

<p>"India will send a technical team after the 1996 Ganges water treaty expires in 2026. The team (with their Bangladesh counterparts) will explore options and negotiate the terms," she added.</p>

<p>Dhaka and New Delhi were set to ink the Teesta Agreement during former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh's Bangladesh visit in 2011 when West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee was also supposed to be his entourage member.</p>

<p>But Ms Banerjee precluded her from his entourage at the last minute, opposing the treaty.</p>

<p>India and Bangladesh agreed to sign the deal but it could not be materialised due to opposition from the West Bengal government.</p>

<p>Indian media reports have suggested that the West Bengal government decided in principle to dig two new canals to divert the Teesta waters for irrigation purposes in the Jalpaiguri and Cooch Behar districts.</p>

<p>Replying to another query about Ms Banerjee's objection to the Indian government's move over the Teesta and Ganges rivers water sharing with Bangladesh, PM Hasina said she doesn't want to make any comment over the issue as it is solely their internal matter.</p>

<p>But PM Hasina said she has a good relationship with all the political parties in India, including PM Modi and Ms Banerjee.</p>

<p>Asked how she wanted to strike a balance regarding ties between India and China in her fifth term, four in a row, the premier said there was nothing to balance as her government was following a foreign policy principle that suggests -- "Friendship to all, malice to none".</p>

<p>Mr Hasina said India is very important for Dhaka as they along with the Freedom Fighters shed blood for the independence of Bangladesh during the 1971 Liberation War.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, she said, there were many things to learn from China about how the country could be developed.</p>

<p>"We maintain the relations considering all these aspects," she said, adding that she never interfered with what relations the two countries have.</p>

<p>"I work for the welfare and development of the country and people maintaining friendly relations with all." She also said she didn't see any problem with maintaining relations with India and China.</p>

<p>The premier said she went to New Delhi as she was first invited to visit India to attend the swearing-in ceremony of Prime Minister Modi and later invited for a state visit to India and now, she would visit China as that country has also invited her.</p>

<p>Replying to a question about rail transit to India, she said Bangladesh and India decided to resume the rail connectivity considering their trade and commerce and socio-economic development.</p>

<p>The premier said Bangladesh is an independent country and “we liberated the country through the Liberation War”.</p>

<p>She said everyone should keep in mind that India was the only force in the world which left a country after helping in its liberation and referred to the American troops of allied forces which were still staying in Japan and Russian troops in Germany.</p>

<p>"Even then, some talk about the rail issue that Bangladesh will be sold to India. How do they say this? Those who talk like this are themselves sold to India," she said.</p>

<p>They criticise India publicly and flatter secretly, she added.</p>

<p>"Look at Europe where there are no borders. Is one country selling itself to another country there? …will we keep our doors shut in Bangladesh?" she added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/ndjlqm4_sheikh-hasina_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Hasina had visited India last week at the invitation of PM Modi. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/setback-for-canadas-trudeau-liberals-lose-stronghold-in-key-polls-5969262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Setback For Canada's Trudeau, Liberals Lose Stronghold In Key Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/setback-for-canadas-trudeau-liberals-lose-stronghold-in-key-polls-5969262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 23:50:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a stunning blow to Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, his Liberal Party lost a closely-watched federal by-election on Tuesday to the Conservatives from a longtime Liberal stronghold.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a stunning blow to Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, his Liberal Party lost a closely-watched federal by-election on Tuesday to the Conservatives from a longtime Liberal stronghold, prompting opposition leader Pierre Poilievre to demand a snap election.</p>

<p>In a nail-biting finish, Conservative candidate Don Stewart won the Liberal stronghold of Toronto-St. Paul's by defeating Liberal Party's Leslie Church by 590 votes. The contest also featured Amrit Parhar, an Indian-origin candidate from the New Democratic Party.</p>

<p>Toronto-St. Paul's is a federal electoral district in Toronto, Ontario province. The Liberal Party had held Toronto-St Paul's since 1993. It is one of 338 seats in the House of Commons.</p>

<p>Stewart's victory over Church is shocking because the seat has been held by the Liberals for more than 30 years, Canadian media commented.</p>

<p>Before Monday, the seat was held by the Liberals for 10 successive elections. Former MP Carolyn Bennett — whose appointment as ambassador to Denmark triggered the byelection — had been the local representative for over 25 years.</p>

<p>"Thank you, Toronto-St. Paul's! I am beyond humbled for the trust you have put in me and I will never take it for granted. I promise to be YOUR voice on Parliament Hill," Stewart posted on X.</p>

<p>His rival, Church in her remarks after she lost the race, noted that the Liberals have got 16 months until the next election. "I plan to be the Liberal candidate in St. Paul's. We start working to earn back the trust of voters...," she posted on X.</p>

<p>"Congratulations to Don Stewart on a well run campaign. We look forward to the rematch," she wrote.</p>

<p>According to the preliminary results, Stewart won 42.1 per cent of the vote with 15,555 votes cast for him, while Church received 40.5 per cent of the vote, with 14,965 ballots cast for her. The NDP candidate Parhar came a distant third with 10.9 per cent of the votes. Christian Cullis, who ran for the Green Party, received 2.9 per cent of the votes.</p>

<p>Losing the historic stronghold is likely to pile pressure on Prime Minister Trudeau, Global News reported.</p>

<p>"The Liberals' poor showing in a stronghold like this could prompt some soul-searching for Trudeau, who has seen his popularity plummet as inflation, the cost of living crisis, high home prices and surging immigration levels drive voter discontent," CBC News commented.</p>

<p>This Conservative upset is likely to lead to some anxiety in the Liberal caucus because such a dramatic vote swing could put other supposedly "safe" seats in play for the Conservatives in the next general election, expected to be in 2025, it said.</p>

<p>Conservative Leader Poilievre demanded Prime Minister Trudeau call a snap election after what he described as a “shocking upset” on social media Tuesday.</p>

<p>“Here is the verdict: Trudeau can't go on like this. He must call a carbon tax election now,” Poilievre wrote on X.</p>

<p>Voters in Toronto-St. Paul's told CBC News throughout the campaign that the government's handling of the housing crisis, inflation and the Israel-Hamas conflict were sore spots.</p>

<p>But it wasn't just about the issues - several voters expressed a desire for change and fatigue with Trudeau.</p>

<p>Even past and present Liberal supporters told CBC News Trudeau should resign as leader if the party loses this one-time ruby-red Liberal seat.</p>

<p>Trudeau, whose allegations in September last year of "potential" involvement of Indian agents in the killing of a Sikh terrorist in Canada caused a severe strain in Ottawa's relations with New Delhi, has given no indication he's stepping down.</p>

<p>The 52-year-old prime minister has repeatedly said he will lead the Liberal Party into the federal election that is expected sometime next year.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, national polling shows Trudeau's Liberal Party struggling to attract and retain support, with Conservative support growing.&nbsp; A poll conducted by Ipsos for Global News suggested Trudeau's waning popularity appears to be “dragging” the Liberals' fortunes down.</p>

<p>A majority of voters (68 per cent) want him to step down, with Ipsos CEO Darrell Bricker describing the numbers as “close to rock bottom,” while Conservative Leader Poilievre, 45, is gaining ground.</p>

<p>That poll put the Conservatives at 42 per cent of the decided vote, with the Liberals at 24 per cent.&nbsp;Almost half - 44 per cent - said they felt Conservative Leader Poilievre would make the best prime minister, while 75 per cent of Canadians want another party to take government from the Liberals.</p>

<p>Just 25 per cent think the Liberals “deserve reelection,” Global News reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/cvt02ck8_justin-trudeau_625x300_09_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Opposition leader Pierre Poilievre has demanded that Trudeau call a snap election. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gun-violence-a-public-health-crisis-in-us-declares-surgeon-general-5969055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gun Violence A Public Health Crisis In US, Declares Surgeon General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gun-violence-a-public-health-crisis-in-us-declares-surgeon-general-5969055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 23:14:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a new advisory released on Tuesday, US Surgeon General Dr Vivek Murthy said that gun violence in the country is an urgent public health crisis that demands the "collective commitment of the nation" to put an end to it, reported CNN.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a new advisory released on Tuesday, US Surgeon General Dr Vivek Murthy said that gun violence in the country is an urgent public health crisis that demands the "collective commitment of the nation" to put an end to it, reported CNN.</p>

<p>This is the first Office of the Surgeon General publication that specifically addresses gun violence and its "deep consequences" for victims, communities, and mental health.</p>

<p>The US Department of Health and Human Services states that a surgeon general's advice is usually used to highlight important public health issues.</p>

<p>The advise released on Tuesday outlines the terrible effects of gun violence in the US and provides information on how public health initiatives can be helpful.</p>

<p>Provisional data indicates that over 48,000 US citizens lost their lives as a result of firearm-related injuries in 2022 alone. Homicides, suicides, and accidental deaths were all included in that total. The recommendation states that the number of firearm-related deaths in the US has been increasing and will peak in 2021 at three decades, reported CNN.</p>

<p>According to the advice, since then, there has been a decline in gun-related killings but the number of gun-related suicides has remained relatively constant. The caution states that although mass shootings are still uncommon--they account for only 1 per cent of gun fatalities--the frequency of these events has been increasing.</p>

<p>The Surgeon General's advisory underlined, how people of colour are "disproportionately impacted" by gun violence, reported CNN.</p>

<p>The recommendation states that firearm violence can have a negative impact on mental health in addition to the physical issues it can cause.</p>

<p>According to the advisory, youngsters are especially prone to fearing gun violence, with many of them believing that their school will be the scene of such carnage. It states that in order to understand how to lower and prevent firearm violence in the US, additional funding for guns research is required. Investments should be made with a focus on improving data gathering and preventative tactics, CNN reported.</p>

<p>The guideline calls on healthcare providers and communities to take proactive measures to support populations that are most at risk of this type of violence.</p>

<p>"There are no federal standards or regulations regarding the safety of firearms produced in the US," the advisory says.</p>

<p>In the past few weeks, the US has witnessed several shooting incidents, with at least 21 other mass shootings recorded by the Gun Violence Archive since last Friday. According to CNN report, the Gun Violence Archive regards mass shootings as ones in which four or more people are shot, excluding the shooter.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/qn6uc1s8_gun-violence_625x300_21_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Provisional data indicates that over 48,000 US citizens died due to gun-related injuries in 2022. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-distribution-of-81-eu-news-outlets-in-retaliatory-step-5969267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Bans Distribution Of 81 EU News Outlets In Retaliatory Step]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-distribution-of-81-eu-news-outlets-in-retaliatory-step-5969267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 22:56:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia said on Tuesday it was banning access inside Russia to the broadcasts of 81 different media outlets from the European Union including Agence France-Presse and Politico in retaliation for a similar EU ban on several Russian media outlets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia said on Tuesday it was banning access inside Russia to the broadcasts of 81 different media outlets from the European Union including Agence France-Presse and Politico in retaliation for a similar EU ban on several Russian media outlets.</p>

<p>The European Union said in May it was suspending the distribution of what it described as four "Kremlin-linked propaganda networks," stripping them of their broadcasting rights in the bloc.</p>

<p>It said at the time that the ban applied to Voice of Europe, to the RIA news agency and to the Izvestia and Rossiyskaya Gazeta newspapers.</p>

<p>The Russian Foreign Ministry hit back on Tuesday, releasing a list of 81 media outlets from 25 EU member states, as well as pan-European outlets, whose broadcasts it said would no longer be available on Russian territory.</p>

<p>It accused the outlets of "systematically distributing inaccurate information" about what Russia calls its special military operation in Ukraine.</p>

<p>France's Agence France-Presse (AFP) news agency, Austria's ORF state TV company, Ireland's RTE broadcaster, and Spain's EFE news agency were among the outlets affected by the Russian move along with many other national broadcasters, newspapers, and Politico.</p>

<p>"The Russian Federation has repeatedly warned at various levels that politically motivated harassment of domestic journalists and unjustified bans on Russian media in the EU will not go unanswered," the foreign ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>"In spite of this, Brussels and the capitals of the bloc's countries preferred to follow the path of escalation, forcing Moscow to adopt mirror and proportional countermeasures."</p>

<p>It said it would review its own ban if the EU lifted its restrictions on RIA, Izvestia and the Rossiyskaya Gazeta newspaper, all of which it described as Russian media outlets.</p>

<p>Vyacheslav Volodin, the speaker of the State Duma lower house of parliament, said in May that the EU move had shown that the West refused to accept any alternative point of view and was destroying freedom of speech.</p>

<p>Italy's foreign ministry on Tuesday condemned the Russian decision to ban access to dozens of European media outlets, including Italian broadcasters Rai and La7 and newspapers La Repubblica and La Stampa.</p>

<p>"We regret the unjustified measure taken against these Italian broadcasters and newspapers, which have always provided objective and unbiased information on the conflict in Ukraine," the ministry said.</p>

<p>AFP declined to comment. Politico and RTE did not immediately reply to requests for comment on the move, which comes a day before the Russian trial of U.S. journalist Evan Gershkovich on espionage charges is due to begin.</p>

<p>The first American journalist to be detained on spy charges in Russia since the Cold War more than three decades ago, Gershkovich, a reporter for the Wall Street Journal, has denied he is a Central Intelligence Agency spy. The Journal says Gershkovich was doing his job and denies he is a spy.</p>

<p>Many Western news organisations pulled staff out of Russia after it launched its full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022 and passed laws soon afterwards that set long prison sentences for "discrediting" the armed forces.</p>

<p>Russian officials say large parts of the Western media spread false and excessively unbalanced stories about Russia, and that Western media organisations are engaged in an information war against Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/6op53pqo_european-union-generic_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Italy's foreign ministry on Tuesday condemned the Russian decision. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-boeings-starliner-can-bring-astronauts-back-to-earth-5969239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Boeing's Starliner Can Bring Astronauts Back To Earth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-boeings-starliner-can-bring-astronauts-back-to-earth-5969239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 22:50:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Problems with Boeing's Starliner capsule, still docked at the International Space Station (ISS), have upended the original plans for its return of its two astronauts to Earth]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Problems with Boeing's Starliner capsule, still docked at the International Space Station (ISS), have upended the original plans for its return of its two astronauts to Earth, as last-minute fixes and tests draw out a mission crucial to the future of Boeing's space division.</p>

<p>NASA has rescheduled the planned return three times, and now has no date set for it. Since its June 5 liftoff, the capsule has had five helium leaks, five maneuvering thrusters go dead and a propellant valve fail to close completely, prompting the crew in space and mission managers in Houston to spend more time than expected pursuing fixes mid-mission.</p>

<p>Here is an explanation of potential paths forward for Starliner and its veteran NASA astronauts, Barry "Butch" Wilmore and Sunita "Suni" Williams.</p>

<p><strong>THE CURRENT SITUATION</strong></p>

<p>Starliner can stay docked at the ISS for up to 45 days, according to comments by NASA's commercial crew manager Steve Stich to reporters. But if absolutely necessary, such as if more problems arise that mission officials cannot fix in time, it could stay docked for up to 72 days, relying on various backup systems, according to a person familiar with flight planning.</p>

<p>Internally at NASA, Starliner's latest targeted return date is July 6, according to this source, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Such a return date would mean that the mission, originally planned for eight days, instead would last a month.</p>

<p>Starliner's expendable propulsion system is part of the craft's "service module." The current problems center on this system, which is needed to back the capsule away from the ISS and position it to dive through Earth's atmosphere. Many of Starliner's thrusters have overheated when fired, and the leaks of helium - used to pressurize the thrusters - appear to be connected to how frequently they are used, according to Stich.</p>

<p>Stich said recent test-firings of the thrusters while Starliner remains docked gave mission teams confidence in a safe return, though tests and reviews are ongoing. The mission management team, made up of NASA and Boeing personnel, is scrutinizing data on the propulsion issues, running simulations in Houston and considering how to fix them, such as by updating software or changing how the hardware is used.</p>

<p>Once NASA officials give the team a go-ahead for a return, Starliner's thrusters would be used to undock the capsule from the ISS and begin a roughly six-hour journey home, gradually tightening its orbit before plunging into Earth's atmosphere for a landing, assisted by parachutes and airbags, at one of several potential locations in the southwestern United States.</p>

<p>This is Starliner's first mission to orbit carrying astronauts - the final test needed before NASA can certify it as the U.S. space agency's second ride to the ISS. It would join SpaceX's Crew Dragon, which has dominated the government and nascent private markets for human spaceflight amid Starliner's years-long delays.</p>

<p><strong>IF THE UNEXPECTED HAPPENS</strong></p>

<p>Even with the propulsion system issues, NASA has said Starliner still would be capable of returning the astronauts to Earth if absolutely necessary - that is, if the capsule must serve as an escape pod from the ISS in an emergency or if any of Starliner's perishable items - such as its solar panels - show signs of expiring earlier than planned.</p>

<p>Unlike Starliner's current mission, NASA did not set a scheduled return date for Crew Dragon's first mission carrying astronauts in 2020. That mission ultimately lasted 62 days because the astronauts needed to help out on ISS maintenance because the space station was short-staffed at the time.</p>

<p><strong>IF STARLINER CANNOT BE USED</strong></p>

<p>If Starliner is deemed incapable of safely returning Wilmore and Williams to Earth, one option would be sending them home aboard Crew Dragon, which ferried four astronauts to the station in March and is able to fit more people in an emergency.</p>

<p>That scenario, considered unlikely, would undoubtedly be embarrassing for Boeing. But NASA and Boeing officials, as well as engineers familiar with the program, told Reuters nothing about Starliner's current problems indicates this would be needed.</p>

<p>In such a scenario, Starliner's fate would depend on various factors including the extent of its technical issues.</p>

<p>The last time a NASA astronaut needed an alternative ride home came in 2022, when Russia's Soyuz capsule sprang a coolant leak after delivering to the station two cosmonauts and American astronaut Frank Rubio.</p>

<p>NASA had considered Crew Dragon as an alternative ride home for Rubio but he eventually used an empty Soyuz capsule that Russia launched as a rescue craft. Rubio's mission was extended from six months to a bit more than a year - 371 days - a record-breaking duration for an American in space.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nc9v6568_sunita-williams_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NASA has rescheduled the planned return three times, and now has no date set for it. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-welcomes-japans-emperor-naruhito-wife-for-state-visit-5969195]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles Welcomes Japan's Emperor Naruhito, Wife For State Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-welcomes-japans-emperor-naruhito-wife-for-state-visit-5969195]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 22:42:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's King Charles and Queen Camilla welcomed Japan's Emperor Naruhito and his wife to London on Tuesday, marking the start of a three-day state visit which includes a military parade, carriage procession and state banquet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's King Charles and Queen Camilla welcomed Japan's Emperor Naruhito and his wife to London on Tuesday, marking the start of a three-day state visit which includes a military parade, carriage procession and state banquet.</p>

<p>Charles' son and heir to the throne Prince William had earlier travelled to the hotel where the 64-year-old emperor and Empress Masako were staying, before the trio arrived for a ceremonial welcome at Horse Guards Parade on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The two heads of state, Charles wearing a top hat, then inspected the Guard of Honour as the rows of soldiers in their traditional scarlet uniforms and black bearskin hats stood in the summer heat.</p>

<p>They then travel onto Buckingham Palace in a gold-edged horse-driven carriage.</p>

<p>The emperor's trip seeks to celebrate and deepen the military, cultural and scientific ties between the two countries, and was postponed from 2020 due to the pandemic.</p>

<p>It is now taking place in the run up to an election in Britain on July 4, meaning that some of the usual political elements will be missing.</p>

<p>There will be no meeting at Downing Street between the emperor and British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak, although Sunak and opposition leader Kier Starmer will both attend the state banquet at Buckingham Palace on Tuesday evening.</p>

<p>The visit comes at a difficult time for the British monarchy, after Charles, 75, was diagnosed with cancer earlier this year, and as William's wife Catherine undergoes preventative chemotherapy treatment for cancer.</p>

<p>In another setback, Princess Anne, Charles' younger sister suffered a head injury on Sunday after an incident believed to have involved a horse. While she is expected to make a full recovery, she has pulled out of attending the state banquet.</p>

<p>Emperor Naruhito came to London in 2022 to attend Queen Elizabeth's funeral, and is fond of Britain, having studied here in the early 1980s.</p>

<p>He has spoken of the kindness the British royals showed him at that time, including a visit to the royal family at Balmoral Castle in Scotland, where Charles took him fly fishing.</p>

<p>The pair will have time to discuss those memories over lunch at Buckingham Palace on Tuesday. They will then view Japanese-related items from the royal collection before a tour of Westminster Abbey in the afternoon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hvpc1qm_king-charles-welcomes-japan-emperor-naruhito_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The emperor's trip seeks to deepen the military and scientific ties between the two countries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-children-losing-1-or-both-legs-on-average-in-gaza-says-un-agency-5969145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Children Losing 1 Or Both Legs On Average In Gaza, Says UN Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-children-losing-1-or-both-legs-on-average-in-gaza-says-un-agency-5969145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 22:36:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ten children per day are losing one or both of their legs in the war in Gaza, the head of the UN agency supporting Palestinian refugees said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ten children per day are losing one or both of their legs in the war in Gaza, the head of the UN agency supporting Palestinian refugees said Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Basically we have every day 10 children who are losing one leg or two legs on average," UNRWA chief Philippe Lazzarini told reporters in Geneva.</p>

<p>Citing figures from the UN children's agency UNICEF, he said that figure "does not even include the arms and the hands, and we have many more" of these.</p>

<p>"Ten per day, that means around 2,000 children after the more than 260 days of this brutal war," Lazzarini said.</p>

<p>He said amputation often takes place "in quite horrible conditions", sometimes without anaesthesia.</p>

<p>Save the Children said on Monday that up to 21,000 children are estimated to be missing in the chaos of the war.</p>

<p>The Gaza Health ministry says at least 37,658 people have been killed in Israel's retaliatory offensive following Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>That attack resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian operatives also took 251 people hostage in the attack, 116 of whom remain captive in the Gaza Strip, according to Israel. The army says 42 of those are dead.</p>

<p>UNRWA coordinates nearly all aid to Gaza, but Lazzarini warned the agency was facing relentless attack and a deep funding crisis.</p>

<p>"We have cash until end of August," he said Tuesday, adding that the agency still had "a shortfall of about $140 million... to bridge the end of the year".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/0vlg7p5_gaza-children_625x300_18_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UNRWA coordinates nearly all aid to Gaza. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chanel-holds-fashion-week-show-after-abrupt-departure-of-creative-director-5968962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chanel Holds Fashion Week Show After Abrupt Departure Of Creative Director]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chanel-holds-fashion-week-show-after-abrupt-departure-of-creative-director-5968962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 22:07:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Awkward! Chanel held its haute couture show on Tuesday just three weeks after the very abrupt departure of creative director Virginie Viard after almost 30 years with the brand.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Awkward! Chanel held its haute couture show on Tuesday just three weeks after the very abrupt departure of creative director Virginie Viard after almost 30 years with the brand.</p>

<p>Viard worked alongside the legendary Karl Lagerfeld for years before taking over at the helm after his death in 2019.</p>

<p>She oversaw record sales of nearly $20 billion last year.</p>

<p>But a crisis had been brewing for months, with sceptical pouts on the front row and murmurs that her shows were growing repetitive, and she was unceremoniously booted out in early June.</p>

<p>Viard, 62, did not even get a swansong on Tuesday.</p>

<p>There was no mention of her in the show notes, which said the latest collection was created by the 150 artisans of its workshop on Rue Cambon.</p>

<p>It was a typically sophisticated and theatrical collection, staged in the Opera Garnier, with mediaeval capes, evening dresses with puffed sleeves, matador outfits and a velvet tuxedo alongside the house's classic tweeds -- with a touch of Lagerfeld-ian vinyl thrown in.</p>

<p>Viard's tenure looked doomed in May when a mid-season "cruise" show in Marseille failed to impress fans -- not helped by the unseasonably cold weather on the Cote d'Azur.</p>

<p>A month later, her departure was announced in less than elegant form -- revealed to the specialist press in the middle of the night.</p>

<p>Paris-based designer Lutz Huelle told AFP that replacing "one of the biggest and best-loved designers at the biggest brand in the world (was) a literally impossible task."</p>

<p><strong>Discreet presence</strong></p>

<p>Viard's takeover was seen as a temporary appointment at the time, although she was only the third creative director in Chanel's 114-year history after Lagerfeld and its founder Gabrielle "Coco" Chanel.</p>

<p>Always dressed simply, in a T-shirt and black trousers, she was a far more discreet presence than "The Kaiser", known for his provocative statements and her shows were less spectacular than Lagerfeld's extravaganzas.</p>

<p>While critics sometimes derided her cuts, buyers still flocked to Chanel stores -- ready-to-wear sales increased 23 percent during Viard's tenure.</p>

<p>"It underscored the fact the brand is much stronger than the individual designer," wrote Business of Fashion.</p>

<p>The fashion world now turns to its favourite pastime -- speculation over who will succeed.</p>

<p>Hedi Slimane (Celine), Sarah Burton, Marine Serre and Simon Porte Jacquemus are all considered possible replacements.</p>

<p><strong>Dita Von Teese</strong></p>

<p>Discretion was not on offer at another show on Tuesday, as France's Alexis Mabille invited fans for a glass of champagne in the home of burlesque, Lido 2 Paris.</p>

<p>It was a classic gala soiree wardrobe of sophisticated evening dresses, with lots of sequins, flowing gold and silver -- some models swinging glasses of champagne on a string like a handbag.</p>

<p>And it culminated in the queen of striptease, Dita Von Teese, emerging from the ground inside a huge glass of champagne.</p>

<p>"The idea was to have a good time, have fun, forget for a few moments everything that is happening around us," Mabille told AFP after the show.</p>

<p>In the audience was actor Jean-Christophe Bouvet, who plays a tormented couturier in Netflix hit "Emily in Paris".</p>

<p>"I've seen about 50 shows in three years," he told AFP, saying it "inspires me a lot" for his work on the series.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/rei6p05_sadie-sink-chanel_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Virginie Viard, 62, did not even get a swansong on Tuesday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-hikers-3-hour-trek-turns-into-10-day-ordeal-drinks-boot-water-to-survive-5968817]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hiker's 3-Hour Trek Turns Into 10-Day Ordeal, Drinks Boot Water To Survive]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-hikers-3-hour-trek-turns-into-10-day-ordeal-drinks-boot-water-to-survive-5968817]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:43:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lukas McClish, a 34-year-old from Boulder Creek, California, went missing for 10 days in the Santa Cruz Mountains after setting out for a day hike on June 11th.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lukas McClish, 34, from Boulder Creek, California, is back home after spending 10 days lost in the Santa Cruz Mountains, according to <em>ABC 7 Los Angeles.</em> McClish had set out for a day hike on June 11th but became disoriented and lost his way. After he failed to show up for a planned dinner on Father's Day, he was reported missing on June 16th. A search effort was launched, and McClish was fortunately rescued four days later.</p>

<p>"I left with just a pair of pants, and my pair of hiking shoes, and a hat. I had a flashlight, and a pair of folding scissors, like a Leatherman tool. And that was about it," the Boulder Creek resident told the station on Friday.</p>

<p>"I'm tired and a little sore, I lost my voice," McClish said.</p>

<p>"I just make sure I drank a gallon of water every day, but then after, getting close to the end of it, my body needed food and some kind of sustenance," McClish told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abc7.com/post/missing-hiker-lukas-mcclish-found-alive-after-spending/14989475/"><em>ABC 7 Los Angeles.</em></a></p>

<p>The Santa Cruz County Sheriff's Office used drones to help search for McClish. They were assisted by Cal Fire San Mateo-Santa Cruz, the Boulder Creek Fire Department, and CA State Parks.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">With <a href="https://twitter.com/SantaCruzSO1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SantaCruzSO1</a> drone Lukas McClish, 34, was located in ? between Empire Grade &amp; Big Basin Hwy near Foreman Creek in <a href="https://twitter.com/sccounty?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@sccounty</a>. McClish was reported missing 5 days ago by family. CDCR<br />
and <a href="https://twitter.com/CAStateParks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CAStateParks</a> assisted.<br />
We are grateful he's home. <a href="https://t.co/oSE7GY5wCe">pic.twitter.com/oSE7GY5wCe</a></p>
— CAL FIRE CZU (@CALFIRECZU) <a href="https://twitter.com/CALFIRECZU/status/1804211725614592110?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Witnesses heard someone shouting for help around 3 pm on Thursday, according to the Sheriff's Office. McClish was discovered in a faraway canyon in Big Basin State Park.He felt grateful to see so many people and search dogs looking for him.</p>

<p>"It was just really humbling and I don't know, it was an awesome experience," McClish said.</p>

<p>"I did enough hiking for probably the whole rest of the year," he said</p>

<p>"Me too," his dad said.</p>

<p>"We've all hiked a lot," his mom said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/uvs9ok2g_lukas-mcclish-_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lukas McClish spent ten days stranded in the Santa Cruz Mountains.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obamas-half-sister-among-protesters-tear-gassed-in-kenya-report-5968395]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Barack Obama's Half-Sister Among Protesters Tear-Gassed In Kenya: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obamas-half-sister-among-protesters-tear-gassed-in-kenya-report-5968395]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:37:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kenyan activist Auma Obama, the half-sister of former U.S. President Barack Obama, was among protesters tear-gassed on Tuesday during demonstrations outside the parliament building in Nairobi, a CNN interview showed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan activist Auma Obama, the half-sister of former US President Barack Obama, was among protesters tear-gassed on Tuesday during demonstrations outside the parliament building in Nairobi, a CNN interview showed.</p>

<p>Police opened fire on demonstrators trying to storm Kenya's legislature on Tuesday, with at least five protesters killed, dozens wounded and sections of the parliament building set ablaze as lawmakers inside passed legislation to raise taxes.</p>

<p>Auma Obama was taken aside by a CNN reporter and asked why she was there.</p>

<p>"I'm here because - look at what's happening. Young Kenyans are demonstrating for their rights. They're demonstrating with flags and banners. I can't even see anymore," she said, beginning to cough and shield her eyes from the spreading smoke.</p>

<p>"We are being tear-gassed."</p>

<p>A man behind her carried a sign reading, "Colonialism never ended in Kenya," while another yelled, "This is our country. This is our nation."</p>

<p>Auma Obama earlier posted photos of herself on Twitter at the protest.</p>

<p>The office of former President Obama did not immediately return a call seeking comment on the incident involving his sister or the violence in Kenya.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nf2bamm8_auma-obama_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Auma Obama earlier posted photos of herself on Twitter at the protest. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-migrant-on-bail-and-under-surveillance-rapes-and-kills-12-year-old-girl-5968317]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Illegal Migrant, On Bail And Under Surveillance, Rapes, Kills 12-Year-Old]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-migrant-on-bail-and-under-surveillance-rapes-and-kills-12-year-old-girl-5968317]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:25:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During the hearing, the judge set Ramos' bail at $10 million, which exceeded the $5 million requested by prosecutors.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Franklin Jose Pena Ramos, 26, a suspect in the murder of 12-year-old Jocelyn Nungaray in Houston last week, appeared in Harris County Criminal Court on Monday. It was disclosed during the court proceedings that he was wearing an ankle monitor from the Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency (ICE) at the time of the alleged murder.</p>

<p>He was issued the ankle bracelet after being arrested by Border Patrol agents for illegal entry into the country and subsequently released from custody. In a statement to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/illegal-immigrant-accused-raping-murdering-girl-12-wore-ice-ankle-monitor-when-crime-occurred"><em>Fox News</em></a> on Friday, ICE indicated that he "illegally entered the U.S. without inspection, parole, or admission by a U.S. immigration officer at an unspecified date and location."</p>

<p>ICE also has a retainer on Ramos, the agency said.</p>

<p>Judge Josh Hill, overseeing Monday's proceedings, also remarked that Ramos and 21-year-old Johan Jose Rangel Martinez, the other suspect in the case, were accused of attempting to collect funds to leave town.</p>

<p>During the hearing, the judge set Ramos' bail at $10 million, which exceeded the $5 million requested by prosecutors.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NEW: One of the illegal Venezuelan migrants who allegedly r*p*d 12-year-old Jocelyn Nungaray appears in court where a $10 million bond was set.<br />
<br />
The judge noted that Franklin Jose Pena Ramos was an "astronomical" flight risk.<br />
<br />
New court documents reveal horrifying new details,… <a href="https://t.co/Aw3sHBCKXL">pic.twitter.com/Aw3sHBCKXL</a></p>
— Collin Rugg (@CollinRugg) <a href="https://twitter.com/CollinRugg/status/1805413537436795375?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Pena's defence had proposed a $1 million bail, but the judge argued that he posed an "astronomical" risk of flight and suggested the likelihood of his return to court was "almost nonexistent."</p>

<p>If Ramos were to post bail, the judge ordered him to wear a GPS monitor, be under 24/7 house arrest, stay within Harris County, refrain from contacting the other suspect or the victim's family, avoid contact with minors, abstain from possessing firearms, drugs, or alcohol, and surrender his passport.</p>

<p>Ramos and Martinez allegedly enticed the young girl under a bridge in Houston, where they proceeded to restrain and fatally harm her.</p>

<p>"In this case, the defendant lured a 12-year-old under a bridge, where he and his co-defendant remained with her for over 2 hours, took her pants off, tied her up, and killed her, then threw her body into the bayou," Harris County Assistant District Attorney Michael Abner wrote.</p>

<p>Police stated that investigators utilized surveillance footage to monitor the activities of the two individuals both before and after the homicide.</p>

<p>Both suspects face charges of capital murder, with Martinez scheduled to make his initial court appearance on Tuesday.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ad3j2kco_franklin-jose-pena-ramos_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was issued the ankle bracelet after being arrested by Border Patrol agents]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-slater-all-about-uk-teen-missing-in-tenerife-for-over-a-week-5967775]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jay Slater: All About UK Teen Missing In Tenerife For Over A Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-slater-all-about-uk-teen-missing-in-tenerife-for-over-a-week-5967775]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:09:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jay Slater, a 19-year-old from Oswaldtwistle, Lancashire, disappeared while on vacation in Tenerife after attending a music festival with friends.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A major search and rescue operation has been launched on Tenerife in response to the disappearance of British teenager Jay Slater, who has been missing for more than a week.</p>

<p>During a vacation with friends, it is thought that the 19-year-old apprentice bricklayer from Oswaldtwistle, Lancashire vanished while attempting to return home from a rave.</p>

<p>Additionally, Jay's friend Lucy Law, who was his last contact, started a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-us-get-jay-home">GoFundMe page.</a> Over 33,000 pounds have been raised thus far, however according to Jay Duncan's mother Debbie Duncan, none of it has been taken back yet.</p>

<p><strong>Here's a closer look at the timeline of events surrounding Jay Slater's disappearance:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>On Sunday, June 17, Jay attended the NRG music festival with his friend, Lucy Law, who was the last to hear from him. At 8:35 pm, Jay posted a Snapchat video from the event in the island's southwest. Lucy left early, but Jay stayed, leaving later with two other Brits between Sunday night and Monday morning.</li>
	<li>On Monday, June 18, Jay remained at an Airbnb near Masca in Teno Rural Park, posting on Snapchat at 7:30 am. He attempted to take a bus back to Los Cristianos where he was staying. The last sighting of Jay was by the Airbnb owner, who described him walking briskly alone. Jay later called Lucy at 8:30 am, lost and in need of water after walking for some time. A missing persons report was filed at 9 am, initiating an extensive search effort with drones, dogs, and a helicopter. Lucy joined the search after receiving assistance from a local woman.</li>
	<li>On Tuesday, June 18, Jay's mother Debbie Duncan learned of his disappearance at 2 am and immediately flew to Tenerife with his older brother Zak at 7 am. Debbie received disturbing prank calls claiming to have taken Jay, while her partner speculated Jay may have simply lost his way.</li>
	<li>By Wednesday, June 19, police investigated a false sighting of Jay in Los Cristianos, redirecting the search initially south before refocusing north around Masca. His hotel room was searched, yielding only his belongings. Debbie described the ordeal as a "living nightmare" and pleaded for Jay's return, while Lucy described his disappearance as "suspicious and weird."</li>
	<li>On Thursday, June 20, new footage emerged showing Jay at the NRG rave, wearing sunglasses on his head as he walked through the crowd.</li>
	<li>By Friday, June 21, search efforts focused on the 2,000ft Masca ravine, known for its steep trail leading to the sea. Meanwhile, the individuals Jay stayed with returned to the UK. The Tenerife Civil Guard declined assistance from the Lancashire Constabulary, a decision that Debbie criticized, citing the need for more resources in the search.</li>
	<li>On Saturday, June 22, an unconfirmed sighting of Jay was reported in Santiago del Teide, approximately 3.5 miles from Masca. A witness claimed to have seen him with two men outside a church around 6 pm on Monday, nine hours after the missing persons report was filed. Jay's father, Warren Slater, visited the search area in response.</li>
	<li>By Sunday, June 23, search efforts concentrated on outbuildings in Masca. A journalist involved in the Madeleine McCann case offered assistance, and a GoFundMe campaign organized by Lucy exceeded 30,000 pounds in donations.</li>
	<li>On Monday, June 24, Jay's family shared a screenshot of CCTV footage capturing a figure walking past the church in Santiago del Teide, corroborating the reported sighting. Debbie expressed her deep concern, stating, "I really hope I am not taking my son home in a body bag."</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/clni9cko_jay-slater_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite efforts by authorities and volunteers, Jay Slater's whereabouts remain unknown.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unacceptably-high-alcohol-kills-nearly-3-million-people-every-year-says-who-5967660]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Unacceptably High": Alcohol Kills Nearly 3 Million Every Year, Says WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unacceptably-high-alcohol-kills-nearly-3-million-people-every-year-says-who-5967660]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:52:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alcohol kills nearly three million people annually, the World Health Organization said on Tuesday, adding that while the death rate had dropped slightly in recent years it remained "unacceptably high".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol kills nearly three million people annually, the World Health Organization said on Tuesday, adding that while the death rate had dropped slightly in recent years it remained "unacceptably high".</p>

<p>The United Nations health agency's latest report on alcohol and health said alcohol causes nearly one in 20 deaths globally each year, through drink driving, alcohol-induced violence and abuse, and a multitude of diseases and disorders.</p>

<p>The report said 2.6 million deaths were attributed to alcohol consumption in 2019 -- the latest available statistics -- accounting for 4.7 percent of all deaths worldwide that year.</p>

<p>Nearly three-quarters of those deaths were in men, it said.</p>

<p>"Substance use severely harms individual health, increasing the risk of chronic diseases, mental health conditions, and tragically resulting in millions of preventable deaths every year," WHO director general Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said.</p>

<p>He pointed out that there had been "some reduction in alcohol consumption and related harm worldwide since 2010".</p>

<p>"(But) the health and social burden due to alcohol use remains unacceptably high," he continued, highlighting that younger people were disproportionately affected.</p>

<p>The highest proportion of alcohol-attributable deaths in 2019 -- 13 percent -- were among people aged 20 to 39, the WHO said.</p>

<p><strong>Cancer, car crashes</strong></p>

<p>Drinking is linked to a slew of health conditions, including cirrhosis of the liver and some cancers.</p>

<p>Of all fatalities it caused in 2019, the report found that an estimated 1.6 million were from noncommunicable diseases.</p>

<p>Of these, 474,000 were from cardiovascular diseases, 401,000 from cancer and a huge 724,000 from injuries, including traffic accidents and self-harm.</p>

<p>Alcohol abuse also makes people more susceptible to infectious diseases such as tuberculosis, HIV and pneumonia, the report found.</p>

<p>An estimated 209 million people lived with alcohol dependence in 2019 -- 3.7 percent of the global population.</p>

<p>Total per capita consumption worldwide decreased slightly to 5.5 litres of alcohol in 2019 from 5.7 litres nine years earlier, the report found.</p>

<p>But alcohol consumption overall is unevenly distributed around the globe.</p>

<p>Well over half of the world's population over the age of 15 abstains completely.</p>

<p>Europe accounted by far for the highest levels of per capital drinking, at 9.2 litres, followed by the Americas at 7.5 litres.</p>

<p>The lowest consumption was in predominantly Muslim countries in Northern Africa, the Middle East and Asia, the report said.</p>

<p><strong>Heavy drinkers</strong></p>

<p>Among people who drank alcohol in 2019, the report determined they consumed 27 grammes of pure alcohol per day on average.</p>

<p>That is roughly equivalent to two glasses of wine, two small bottles of beer or two shots of spirits.</p>

<p>"This level and frequency of drinking is associated with increased risks of numerous health conditions and associated mortality and disability," the WHO warned.</p>

<p>In 2019, a full 38 percent of current drinkers acknowledged having engaged in heavy episodic drinking, defined as consuming at last 60 grammes of pure alcohol on one or more occasions in the preceding month.</p>

<p>Globally, 23.5 percent of 15- to 19-year-olds were considered current drinkers.</p>

<p>That jumped to more than 45 percent for people in this age group living in Europe, and to nearly 44 percent in the Americas.</p>

<p>The WHO said it was essential to improve access to quality treatment for substance use disorders.</p>

<p>In 2019, the proportion of people contacting such treatment services ranged from below one percent to 35 percent in countries providing this data.</p>

<p>"Stigma, discrimination and misconceptions about the efficacy of treatment contribute to these critical gaps in treatment provision," Vladimir Poznyak, head of WHO's unit for alcohol, drugs and addictive behaviours, told reporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/aaod9lbk_alcohol-generic-istock_625x300_23_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Drinking is linked to a slew of health conditions. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-re-install-maharaja-ranjit-singhs-statue-at-kartarpur-sahib-5967598]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan To Re-Install Maharaja Ranjit Singh's Statue At Kartarpur Sahib]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-re-install-maharaja-ranjit-singhs-statue-at-kartarpur-sahib-5967598]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:41:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Punjab government said on Tuesday that it will install the restored statue of the first ruler of the Sikh Empire, Maharaja Ranjit Singh, at Kartarpur Sahib on Wednesday so that visiting Sikhs from India would get to view it too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Punjab government said on Tuesday that it will install the restored statue of the first ruler of the Sikh Empire, Maharaja Ranjit Singh, at Kartarpur Sahib on Wednesday so that visiting Sikhs from India would get to view it too.</p>

<p>Kartarpur Sahib is also known as Gurdwara Darbar Sahib and is situated about 150 km northeast of Lahore, close to the Indian border.</p>

<p>The nine-foot-tall bronze statue of Maharaja Ranjit Singh was first installed at the Lahore Fort near his Samadhi in 2019. It was twice vandalised by activists of the Tehreek-e-Labbaik Pakistan (TLP), a far-right Islamic political party in Pakistan.</p>

<p>“We are going to install Maharaja Ranjit Singh's statue at Gurdwara Darbar Sahib, Kartarpur on Wednesday afternoon in the presence of local and Indian Sikhs,” Punjab's first Sikh Minister and President (pardhan) of the Pakistan Sikh Gurdwara Parbandhak Committee (PSGPC) Sardar Ramesh Singh Arora told PTI.</p>

<p>The restored statue is being placed at Kartarpur Sahib so that Indian Sikhs visiting there could see it, Arora said. He also assured better security to protect the restored statue.</p>

<p>The minister said restoration work of Maharaja Ranjit Singh's statue has already begun which will soon be completed.</p>

<p>Maharaja Ranjit Singh was the founder of the Sikh Empire, which ruled the northwest Indian subcontinent in the early half of the 19th century with his headquarters at Lahore.</p>

<p>Currently, 455 Sikhs, who arrived here from India last week to take part in festivities in connection with Maharaja Ranjit Singh's death anniversary, will also be present at Kartarpur Sahib on Wednesday when Singh's statue will be unveiled.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-11/40i71itg_shri-kartarpur-sahib-gurudwara_625x300_22_November_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-court-clears-man-of-sexual-assault-charges-as-victim-took-20-seconds-to-react-5967455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Court Frees Man Of Rape Charges As Woman Took 'Too Long' To React]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-court-clears-man-of-sexual-assault-charges-as-victim-took-20-seconds-to-react-5967455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:23:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The case centres around Raffaele Meola, a former trade union official, who was accused of groping the attendant in 2018.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Italian judge is receiving criticism for clearing a man accused of groping a flight attendant. The controversial verdict hinged on the woman's alleged delayed reaction, which the judge inexplicably deemed too slow to be evidence of a genuine assault, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vanityfair.it/article/vittima-aspetta-20-secondi-no-violenza-sessuale"><em>Vanity Fair Italy </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This justification has sparked outrage from women's rights groups and the attendant's legal team, who argue it sets a dangerous precedent and discourages victims from coming forward.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The case centres around Raffaele Meola, a former trade union official, who was accused of groping the attendant in 2018. This is reportedly not the first time the judge has ruled in Meola's favour based on the attendant's reaction time, raising concerns about potential bias. The verdict is being challenged, with the attendant's legal team vowing to fight for justice.</p>

<p>Her lawyer said following the verdict, "We will appeal to the Supreme Court because this sentence takes us back 30 years."</p>

<p>The lawyer said that the verdict went against Supreme Court precedent which 'for over ten years stated that a sexual act, carried out unexpectedly without ascertaining the woman's consent, is a crime of sexual violence and must be judged as such.'</p>

<p>Despite claiming to believe the victim, the judge, Nicoletta Guerrero, threw out the case due to a lack of "sufficient evidence." This justification stemmed from a detail from the alleged assault: Mr. Meola, standing behind the woman, reportedly touched, kissed, and massaged her for 30 seconds. The critical point? The court argued her continued reading of documents during this time implied a lack of immediate objection.</p>

<p>This supposed "slow reaction," according to Il Fatto Quotidiano, led the judge to believe Mr Meola might have misinterpreted the situation.</p>

<p>These are his words reported by <em>Corriere della Sera</em>. "This judicial case highlights once again the urgency of a reform of the law provided for by article 609 bis of the penal code which clearly defines that the crime of rape is any sexual act carried out without the consent of the woman, whose dissent is always presumed, as provided for by the Istanbul Convention. The burden of proving the woman's consent to the sexual act must be provided by the accused. Currently, the current law, together with non-specialised jurisprudence, favours the secondary victimization of women who report and this is unacceptable."</p>

<p>Elisa Ercoli, president of Differenza donna, also intervened, "This sentence is proof of how our law 66/96 is the cause of serious and continuous institutional violence, we reject a democracy that effectively prevents women from obtaining justice following rape. We urgently ask for a new law with evolved parameters of justice without having our institutions against us anymore."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/foj8vs9g_flight-attendant-generic_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The lawyer said that the verdict went against Supreme Court precedent]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reacts-to-video-of-injured-palestinian-tied-to-israeli-military-jeep-5967378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Reacts To Video Of Injured Palestinian Tied To Israeli Military Jeep]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reacts-to-video-of-injured-palestinian-tied-to-israeli-military-jeep-5967378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:15:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US State Department on Monday said a video of a wounded Palestinian man strapped on a military jeep by Israeli forces was "shocking" and urged a swift investigation to hold those responsible to account.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US State Department on Monday said a video of a wounded Palestinian man strapped on a military jeep by Israeli forces was "shocking" and urged a swift investigation to hold those responsible to account.</p>

<p>At a State Department news briefing, a reporter asked: "Isn't that basically the army using Palestinians as human shields?"</p>

<p>State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller responded: "I will say we saw that video. It was shocking. The practice was absolutely unacceptable. Humans should never be used as human shields."</p>

<p>"The IDF should swiftly investigate what happened, hold people accountable," Miller said, using an acronym for the Israel Defense Forces.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Israeli forces tied a wounded Palestinian man to the hood of a military jeep during an arrest raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin, the Israeli military said.</p>

<p>The video circulating on social media and verified by Reuters showed a Palestinian resident of Jenin, Mujahed Azmi, on a military jeep that passed between two ambulances.</p>

<p>The Israeli military in a statement said Israeli forces were fired at and exchanged fire, wounding a suspect and detaining him.</p>

<p>Soldiers then violated military protocol, the statement said.</p>

<p>The military said the "conduct of the forces in the video of the incident does not conform to the values" of the Israeli military and the incident will be investigated and dealt with. The military said the man was transferred to medics for treatment.</p>

<p>"I saw the statement they put out that the actions were inconsistent with the orders those soldiers received and that is being investigated and the people involved will be dealt with accordingly. That is absolutely appropriate," Miller said.</p>

<p>Violence in the West Bank, already on the rise before the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza began in October, has escalated since then with frequent army raids on Palestinian groups, rampages by Jewish settlers in Palestinian villages, and deadly street attacks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/14eup9ns_palestinian-man-jeep_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli forces tied a wounded Palestinian to the hood of a military jeep during an arrest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protesters-breach-parliament-barricade-enter-compound-report-5967290]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Shot Dead, Parts Of Kenya Parliament On Fire During Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protesters-breach-parliament-barricade-enter-compound-report-5967290]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:02:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kenyan protesters breached parliament barricades on Tuesday and entered the complex where lawmakers were debating contentious tax hike proposals that have sparked widespread anger, AFP journalists saw.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan police shot dead five during a protest near parliament Tuesday, a rights group said, with AFP journalists seeing three people lying motionless on the ground as crowds opposed to proposed tax hikes breached barricades to enter the parliamentary complex where a fire erupted.</p>

<p>The mainly Gen-Z-led rallies, which began last week, have caught the government off guard, with President William Ruto saying over the weekend he was ready to talk to the protesters.</p>

<p>But tensions sharply escalated on Tuesday afternoon, as crowds began to throw stones at police and push back against barricades, making their way towards the parliament complex, which was sealed off by police in full riot gear.</p>

<p>Police fired at crowds massing outside the parliament building, where lawmakers had been debating a contentious bill featuring tax hike proposals.</p>

<p>Shortly before, Irungu Houghton, the executive director of Amnesty International Kenya, told AFP that "human rights observers are now reporting the increasing use of live bullets by the National Police Service in the capital of Nairobi".</p>

<p>"Safe passage for medical officers to treat the many wounded is now urgent," he said.</p>

<p>Anger over a cost-of-living crisis spiralled into nationwide rallies last week, with demonstrators calling for the finance bill to be scrapped. The people are angry over the rising prices of bread and nappies.</p>

<p>Despite a heavy police presence, thousands of protesters had earlier marched through Nairobi's business district, pushing back against barricades as they headed towards parliament.</p>

<p>Police in full riot gear were firing tear gas and rubber bullets into the crowd, according to AFP journalists.</p>

<p>As protesters gained ground in their push towards parliament, many were livestreaming the action earlier in the day as they sang, chanted and beat drums.</p>

<p>Crowds also marched in the port city of Mombasa, the opposition bastion of Kisumu, and Ruto's stronghold of Eldoret, images on Kenyan TV channels showed.</p>

<p><strong>- 'At a crossroads' -</strong></p>

<p>The Independent Policing Oversight Authority watchdog and rights groups said that two people had died following Thursday's rallies in Nairobi.</p>

<p>Several organisations, including Amnesty International Kenya, said at least 200 people were wounded in last week's protests in Nairobi.</p>

<p>Amnesty's Kenya chapter posted on X Tuesday that "the pattern of policing protests is deteriorating fast", urging the government to respect demonstrators' right to assembly.</p>

<p>On Monday, ahead of the rallies, the rights body said Kenya was "at a crossroads".</p>

<p>"Despite mass arrests and injuries, the protests have continued to grow, emphasising the public's widespread discontent," it said, warning that "the escalation of force could lead to more fatalities and legal repercussions."</p>

<p>Rights watchdogs have accused the authorities of abducting protesters in violation of the law.</p>

<p>The Kenya Human Rights Commission said the abductions had mostly occurred at night and were "conducted by police officers in civilian clothes and unmarked cars", calling for the "unconditional release of all abductees."</p>

<p>Police have not responded to AFP requests for comment on the allegations.</p>

<p>The protesters have also deployed unconventional tactics, including asking bars to stop playing music at midnight on the weekend as partygoers burst into chants of "Ruto must go" and "Reject finance bill."</p>

<p>Their demonstrations have drawn support from some Anglican and Catholic church leaders.</p>

<p><strong>- Debt mountain -</strong></p>

<p>The cash-strapped government agreed last week to roll back several tax increases.</p>

<p>But it still intends to raise other taxes, saying they are necessary for filling the state coffers and cutting reliance on external borrowing.</p>

<p>Kenya has a huge debt mountain whose servicing costs have ballooned because of a fall in the value of the local currency over the last two years, making interest payments on foreign-currency loans more expensive.</p>

<p>The tax hikes will pile further pressure on Kenyans, with well-paid jobs remaining out of reach for many young people.</p>

<p>After the government agreed to scrap levies on bread purchases, car ownership and financial and mobile services, the treasury warned of a budget shortfall of 200 billion shillings ($1.56 billion).</p>

<p>The government now intends to target an increase in fuel prices and export taxes to fill the void left by the changes, a move critics say will make life more expensive in a country already saddled with high inflation.</p>

<p>Kenya has one of the most dynamic economies in East Africa but a third of its 52 million people live in poverty.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/flna2alo_kenya-protests_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several have been wounded in police firing, Amnesty International said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-what-pilot-does-after-planes-canopy-bursts-opens-mid-air-5966411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: What Pilot Does After Plane's Canopy Bursts Open Mid-Air]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-what-pilot-does-after-planes-canopy-bursts-opens-mid-air-5966411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:42:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dutch pilot Narine Melkumjan faced a dangerous situation during her aerobatic training flight when her aircraft's canopy unexpectedly opened mid-air.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dutch pilot Narine Melkumjan faced a frightening situation when her aircraft's canopy unexpectedly opened mid-air. A video she shared on social media showed the terrifying moment Melkumjan grappled to maintain control of her Extra 330LX aircraft.</p>

<p>Melkumjan, on her second aerobatic training flight a couple of years ago, appeared visibly distraught in the clip, toiling to keep her eyes open against the wind. After the canopy, a transparent enclosure that protects the cockpit of an aircraft, unexpectedly burst open, she applied all her skills to land the two-seater safely.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">*PLEASE MIND WHEN WATCHING. AT 2:17 MINUTE MARK VIDEO FOOTAGE BECOMES RATHER INTENSE*<br />
<br />
A couple of years ago during my second aerobatic training flight of that day, on a very hot summer day, the canopy of the Extra 330LX that I was flying opened in flight and shattered. As you… <a href="https://t.co/nLhvDqVnII">pic.twitter.com/nLhvDqVnII</a></p>
— Narine Melkumjan (@NarineMelkumjan) <a href="https://twitter.com/NarineMelkumjan/status/1804507833506931086?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Reflecting on the ordeal, Melkumjan acknowledged that the experience could have been avoided had she conducted proper pre-flight checks.</p>

<p>She admitted that the canopy locking pin was not properly secured before takeoff.</p>

<p>“I also made the mistake of going to the training camp right after recovering from COVID, without allowing my body enough time to fully regain strength. Additionally, flying without any eye protection made the flight even more challenging than it already was,” she wrote in a lengthy post on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She said she experienced some “buffet and controllability challenges,” revealing the “most difficult part was to keep the power in, thus trading my vision and breathing for kinetic energy.”</p>

<p>Amid the chaos, communication with her coach became almost impossible due to the noise, yet she distinctly remembered the crucial advice – "Just keep flying."</p>

<p>She described the distressing aftermath, including the overwhelming noise, difficulties breathing and impaired visibility that followed.</p>

<p>"It took me nearly 28 hours to fully recover my vision," Melkumjan revealed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Melkumjan, known for her frequent posts of flying videos on social media, revealed that sharing the footage of her dramatic flight served as a "cautionary tale" for other pilots and that she regretted not sharing it sooner.</p>

<p>“If you are a pilot watching this, I hope that my story serves as a cautionary tale and that you will learn from my mistakes,” she wrote.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/28rqijuo_plane-canopy-opens_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Narine Melkumjan was on her second aerobatic training flight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antarctic-study-reveals-tipping-point-for-runaway-melting-of-ice-sheets-5967122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Antarctic Study Reveals "Tipping Point" For Runaway Melting Of Ice Sheets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antarctic-study-reveals-tipping-point-for-runaway-melting-of-ice-sheets-5967122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:36:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have discovered a new tipping point toward "runaway melting" of Antarctic ice sheets, caused by warm ocean water intruding between the ice and the land it sits on, according to a study published on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have discovered a new tipping point toward "runaway melting" of Antarctic ice sheets, caused by warm ocean water intruding between the ice and the land it sits on, according to a study published on Tuesday.</p>

<p>While this type of melting has been previously studied, models used by the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) to project the impact of global warming on the Antarctic have yet to factor in this phenomenon.</p>

<p>They have also systematically underestimated ice loss seen thus far, said the study, published in the journal Nature Geoscience.</p>

<p>As ocean temperatures rise due to human-caused global warming, Antarctic ice sheets are melting, threatening a rise in global sea levels and putting coastal communities at risk.</p>

<p>"Increases in ocean temperature can lead to a tipping point being passed, beyond which ocean water intrudes in an unbounded manner beneath the ice sheet, via a process of runaway melting," the study said.</p>

<p>Antarctic ice sheets sit atop the bedrock and extend beyond the coast to float on the sea.</p>

<p>Previous studies have shown that warm seawater is seeping into the "grounding zone" -- where land and ice meet -- and further inland from under the floating ice.</p>

<p>As the water warms, even by a fraction, the intrusion accelerates from short distances of 100 metres (330 feet) to tens of kilometres (miles), melting ice along the way by heating it from below, explained the study's lead author Alexander Bradley.</p>

<p>"Every 10th of a degree (of warming) makes these kind of processes closer, these tipping points closer," said Bradley, a researcher with the British Antarctic Survey.</p>

<p>The risk to sea-level rise comes when the accelerated melting outpaces the formation of new ice on the continent.</p>

<p>Some areas of Antarctica are more vulnerable to this process than others due to the shape of the land mass, which has valleys and cavities where sea water can pool beneath the ice.</p>

<p>The Pine Island glacier, currently Antarctica's largest contributor to sea-level rise, is at high risk of melting due to the slope of the land that allows in more seawater, the study said.</p>

<p>Scientific models need to be updated to take into account the element of melt to better predict the risk of sea-level rise in the future and prepare for it, Bradley said.</p>

<p>"And it really just stresses the need for urgent climate action in order to prevent these tipping points from being passed," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/h4p22gho_antarctic-ice_625x300_25_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ocean temperatures rise due to human-caused global warming. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>