<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:10:36 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-volkswagen-group-allegedly-evaded-billions-in-taxes-in-india-7157818]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Volkswagen Group Allegedly Evaded Billions In Taxes In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-volkswagen-group-allegedly-evaded-billions-in-taxes-in-india-7157818]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:52:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Volkswagen Group, which include the brands Volkswagen, Audi, Skoda, Porche, and Lamborghini has been accused by Indian authorities of evading $1.4 billion (Rs 118.6 billion) in taxes, which is roughly Rs 11,865 crore.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Volkswagen Group, which include the brands Volkswagen, Audi, Skoda, Porche, and Lamborghini has been accused by Indian authorities of evading $1.4 billion (Rs 118.6 billion) in taxes, which is roughly Rs 11,865 crore.</p>

<p>The companies within the Volkswagen Group accused of import duty manipulation include the Indian unit Skoda Auto Volkswagen and the models of cars involved in the alleged scam include Audi's A4 and A6 sedans and Q5 and Q7 SUVs. It also includes Skoda's Octavia and Superb sedans, its Kodiaq SUV, and Volkswagen's Tiguan SUV.</p>

<p>Relevant authorities in India have claimed after detailed scrutiny that Volkswagen has deliberately and "wilfully" manipulated its import in such a way that it evaded a higher tax slab by categorising parts to be imported under a lower tax category. This is something Volkswagen has denied, saying it complies with all local laws and is cooperating with Indian authorities.</p>

<h2><strong>UNDERSTANDING THE IMPORT DUTIES</strong></h2>

<p>To promote local manufacturing, India levies an import duty of 35 per cent on Completely Knocked-Down units or CKDs. These are imported as a kit and then assembled into cars at the manufacturing plants across India.</p>

<p>For other parts of the vehicle that are manufactured locally, but require components within it to be imported, the import duty for such components varies from 5 per cent to 15 per cent.</p>

<p>Should a 'ready-to-drive' car be imported in its entirety from another country, 100% import duty is charged. This steep duty, imposed for decades, is credited behind auto manufacturing plants being set up in India.</p>

<h2><strong>WHAT VOLKSWAGEN ALLEGEDLY DID</strong></h2>

<p>Upon detailed scrutiny, Indian authorities have claimed they found that to bypass the 30-35 per cent import duty on CKDs, Volkswagen intentionally "mis-declared and mis-classified" its component imports by declaring them as "individual parts" - which, as mentioned above, attracts a much-lower import duty of 5-15 per cent.</p>

<p>The authorities claimed that over time, Volkswagen imported 97 per cent of all parts of the car models mentioned above by declaring them as "individual components", accumulating to nearly a billion-and-a-half dollars of import duty evasion.</p>

<h2><strong>HOW VOLKSWAGEN IMPORTS AUTO COMPONENTS AND PARTS</strong></h2>

<p>Volkswagen has an international inventory management system called NADIN for all its brands. It also has a separate software called ProCKD which it has developed to track and manage all inventory for manufacturing plants based in India.</p>

<p>Based on the feedback and projections sent by its sales and operations teams across India, the Volkswagen Group uses the these software - NADIN and ProCKD - to place orders for its various vehicle models across brands. This is how the manufacturing and assembly flow is managed.</p>

<p>Using the information entered in both software, an order is placed which NADIN then divides into a range of between 700 and 1,500 components which are necessary for a vehicle to be manufactured. The NADIN software is directly connected to international suppliers of three of Volkswagen's brands - Audi, Skoda, and VW - in Germany, Czech Republic, and Hungary.</p>

<p>Once these brands receive the orders for components from India, the suppliers in these countries send the parts&nbsp; to a "consolidation centre" for each brand from where it is shipped to India. Components are stamped with unique IDs that helped the production teams in India to identify which part goes where in the said car.</p>

<p>A 17-digit alpha-numeric number is also printed on the parts to identify them for each vehicle. A separate 16-digit ID number was also given so that factory workers could know that these parts need to be assembled together before being installed in the car.</p>

<h2><strong>WHAT VOLKSWAGEN CLAIMS AS COMPARED TO AUTHORITIES</strong></h2>

<p>These individual parts mentioned above then reach various Indian ports as multiple consignments and multiple invoices, all separate from one another, but usually arrive on consecutive days within a week. Authorities claim that the vehicle body is supplied along with the main components and the rest of the parts arrive separately in different packages to avoid detection as CKDs.</p>

<p>Volkswagen says this is purely a logistical model which it has adopted over the years to improve efficiency. However, authorities call this "intentional and deliberate" to avoid paying higher import duties.</p>

<p>The notice sent by Indian authorities to Volkswagen Group has been accessed by news agency Reuters. If the allegations are proven correct, it would be one of the biggest cases of import duty evasion in India's history. It would also significantly impact the Volkswagen Group, which is already facing tough competition in the Indian auto market.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/69gpddqk_volkswagen-group-vw-audi-skoda_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian authorities have claimed that the Volkswagen Group has been evading import duties.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bleeding-eye-virus-that-has-killed-15-in-rwanda-so-far-7157802]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is "Bleeding Eye" Virus That Has Killed 15 In Rwanda So Far]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bleeding-eye-virus-that-has-killed-15-in-rwanda-so-far-7157802]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:50:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Marburg or "bleeding eye" virus in Rwanda has killed at least 15 people so far and infected hundreds others, ever since its outbreak and spread across 17 African countries over the past two months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Marburg or "bleeding eye" virus in Rwanda has killed at least 15 people so far and infected hundreds others, ever since its outbreak and spread across 17 African countries over the past two months.</p>

<p>An advisory issued by Travel Health Pro, which is run by the UK Health Security Agency, has warned travellers against the spread of Marburg in Rwanda, Burundi, Central African Republic, Congo, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Gabon, Kenya, Uganda, Bolivia, Brazil, Colombia, Cuba, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Guyana, Panama and Peru.</p>

<p>Besides Marburg, the advisory has also cautioned against Clade 1 and Oropouche fever, two other serious infectious diseases that have also spread across the above countries.</p>

<p>People travelling to these regions have been advised to exercise additional vigilance.</p>

<p><strong>What Is "Bleeding Eye" Virus?</strong></p>

<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) defines the Marburg virus disease, formerly known as Marburg hemorrhagic fever, as a severe and often fatal illness in humans. Rousettus aegyptiacus, a fruit bat of the Pteropodidae family, is considered the natural host of Marburg virus.</p>

<p><strong>Symptoms</strong></p>

<p>According to WHO, the incubation period (interval from infection to onset of symptoms) varies from two to 21 days. It is marked by high fever, severe headache and malaise. Muscle aches and pains are common features. Diarrhoea, abdominal pain, cramping, nausea and vomiting is likely to begin on the third day.</p>

<p>From day 5 of the disease, patients may develop haemorrhagic manifestations, including fresh blood in vomit and faeces, and bleeding from the nose, eyes, ears, mouth, gums or vagina. Orchitis (inflammation of one or both testicles) has been reported occasionally in the late phase of the disease.</p>

<p>In fatal cases, death occurs most often between eight to nine days after symptom onset, usually preceded by severe blood loss and shock.</p>

<p><strong>Transmission</strong></p>

<p>The "bleeding eye" virus can spread through human-to-human transmission via direct contact (through broken skin or mucous membranes) with the blood, secretions, organs or other bodily fluids of infected people, and with surfaces and materials (e.g. bedding, clothing) contaminated with these fluids.</p>

<p>Healthcare workers have frequently been infected while treating patients with suspected or confirmed Marburg virus. Funeral services that involve direct contact with the body of a victim can also contribute to the transmission of the virus.</p>

<p><strong>Treatment</strong></p>

<p>Currently, there are no vaccines or antiviral treatments approved for the "bleeding virus" but early supportive care with rehydration, and symptomatic treatment can improve survival.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qc2iv4h_marburg-virus_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In fatal cases, death occurs most often between eight to nine days after symptom onset.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-is-the-legal-effect-of-joe-bidens-pardon-of-his-son-7157789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Is The Legal Effect Of Joe Biden's Pardon Of His Son?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-is-the-legal-effect-of-joe-bidens-pardon-of-his-son-7157789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:50:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden pardoned his son Hunter Biden after repeatedly pledging not to. Below is a look at the circumstances leading up to the pardon and its legal consequences.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden pardoned his son Hunter Biden after repeatedly pledging not to. Below is a look at the circumstances leading up to the pardon and its legal consequences.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT DID THE PARDON COVER?</strong></p>

<p>Hunter Biden was pardoned for his conviction by a jury in Delaware and a guilty plea in California. Hunter Biden was also pardoned for federal crimes "he committed or may have committed" between Jan. 1, 2014 through the end of this year.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT CRIMES WAS HUNTER BIDEN CONVICTED OF?</strong></p>

<p>A Delaware jury in June found the president's son guilty of lying about his addiction to illegal drugs on a disclosure form that is required to purchase a firearm. The trial included hours of embarrassing testimony about Hunter Biden's addiction to crack and reckless behavior. He was scheduled to be sentenced on Dec. 12.</p>

<p>Biden separately pleaded guilty to criminal charges of failing to pay $1.4 million in taxes while spending lavishly on drugs, sex workers and luxury items. He was scheduled to be sentenced on Dec. 16.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT SENTENCE WAS BIDEN FACING?</strong></p>

<p>He was facing decades in prison, although sentencing guidelines suggested he was likely to receive a much less severe punishment.</p>

<p>For the gun charges, sentencing guidelines are 15 to 21 months, although legal experts said defendants in similar situations receive shorter sentences and are less likely to be incarcerated if they abide by the terms of their pretrial release. Hunter Biden's attorney had told the judge that he was complying with terms of his bail, which included drug testing to show he was not using illegal drugs.</p>

<p>A juror told CNN after the trial they did not think Hunter Biden belonged in prison.</p>

<p><strong>WASN'T THERE A PLEA DEAL?</strong></p>

<p>Yes. In June last year Hunter Biden agreed to plead guilty to two misdemeanor charges of willfully failing to pay income taxes and an agreement that would have spared him a conviction on a gun-related charge. The agreement prompted accusations by Republicans that Hunter Biden is receiving favorable treatment as the president's son. A federal judge questioned the breadth of that agreement and declined to accept it, paving the way for Hunter Biden's trial on gun charges.</p>

<p><strong>COULD HUNTER BIDEN BE CALLED TO TESTIFY IN ANOTHER CASE?</strong></p>

<p>If the US House of Representatives or the Justice Department decides to probe the Biden family business dealings, as some Republicans have promised to do, Hunter Biden could potentially be called to testify. Before he was pardoned, he could have declined to do so, citing his Fifth Amendment right against self-incrimination. The pardon could limit his ability to invoke that right, because he no longer faces criminal jeopardy for any federal crimes committed during the period covered. Presidential pardons do not protect people from prosecution for state crimes.</p>

<p><strong>ARE PRESIDENTIAL PARDONS UNUSUAL?</strong></p>

<p>No. Presidents beginning with George Washington, the first US president, have granted pardons. Gerald Ford pardoned his predecessor Richard Nixon, who had resigned in disgrace, Bill Clinton pardoned his brother-in-law and Donald Trump pardoned Charles Kushner, a real estate developer and the father of Trump's son-in-law, Jared Kushner.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jvjosq38_joe-biden-hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hunter Biden pleaded guilty to criminal charges of failing to pay $1.4 million in taxes (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/white-house-defends-joe-bidens-pardon-of-his-son-7157721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[White House Defends Joe Biden's Pardon Of His Son]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/white-house-defends-joe-bidens-pardon-of-his-son-7157721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:41:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The White House on Monday defended President Joe Biden's decision to pardon his son, Hunter, and said the president believed his political opponents would have kept persecuting his son going forward.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The White House on Monday defended President Joe Biden's decision to pardon his son, Hunter, and said the president believed his political opponents would have kept persecuting his son going forward.</p>

<p>"They would continue to go after his son," White House spokesperson Karine Jean-Pierre told reporters on Air Force One during a trip to Angola.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre said this was not the first time a president had pardoned a family member.</p>

<p>Biden said in June that he would not pardon his son. In an interview with ABC News, Biden replied "yes" when asked if he would rule out pardoning Hunter.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre declined to give details on why or how Biden had changed his mind.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden pleaded guilty in September to federal tax charges in federal court in Los Angeles and was due to be sentenced Dec. 16 under Mark C. Scarsi, a judge nominated by Republican President-elect Donald Trump. A jury found him guilty in June of making false statements on a gun background check; he was due to be sentenced for those charges this month as well.</p>

<p>Biden said on Sunday that his son had been selectively prosecuted and treated differently than others with similar situations.</p>

<p>Late on Sunday, Hunter Biden's attorney filed to dismiss the indictments against him.</p>

<p>The president's full and unconditional pardon "requires dismissal of the indictment against" Hunter Biden, the lawyer wrote in filings related to criminal tax and gun cases against him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/d9edn52o_hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hunter Biden pleaded guilty in September to federal tax charges (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/did-venus-ever-have-oceans-scientists-have-an-answer-7157689]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Did Venus Ever Have Oceans? Scientists Have An Answer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/did-venus-ever-have-oceans-scientists-have-an-answer-7157689]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:38:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Earth is an ocean world, with water covering about 71% of its surface. Venus, our closest planetary neighbor, is sometimes called Earth's twin based on their similar size and rocky composition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earth is an ocean world, with water covering about 71% of its surface. Venus, our closest planetary neighbor, is sometimes called Earth's twin based on their similar size and rocky composition. While its surface is baked and barren today, might Venus once also have been covered by oceans?</p>

<p>The answer is no, according to new research that inferred the water content of the planet's interior - a key indicator for whether or not Venus once had oceans - based on the chemical composition of its atmosphere. The researchers concluded that the planet currently has a substantially dry interior that is consistent with the idea that Venus was left desiccated after the epoch early in its history when its surface was comprised of molten rock - magma - and thereafter has had a parched surface.</p>

<p>Water is considered an indispensable ingredient for life, so the study's conclusions suggest Venus was never habitable. The findings offer no support for a previous hypothesis that Venus may have a reservoir of water beneath its surface, a vestige of a lost ocean.</p>

<p>Volcanism, by injecting gases into a planet's atmosphere, provides clues about the interior of rocky planets. As magma ascends from an intermediate planetary layer called the mantle to the surface, it unleashes gases from deeper parts of the interior.</p>

<p>Volcanic gases on Earth are more than 60% water vapor, evidence of a water-rich interior. The researchers calculated that gases in Venusian eruptions are no more than 6% water vapor, indicative of a desiccated interior.</p>

<p>"We suggest that a habitable past would be associated with Venus' present interior being water-rich, and a dry past with Venus' present interior being dry," said Tereza Constantinou, a doctoral student at the University of Cambridge's Institute of Astronomy and lead author of the study published on Monday in the journal Nature Astronomy.</p>

<p>"The atmospheric chemistry suggests that volcanic eruptions on Venus release very little water, implying that the planet's interior - the source of volcanism - is equally dry. This is consistent with Venus having had a long-lasting dry surface and never having been habitable," Constantinou added.</p>

<p>Venus is the second planet from the sun, and Earth the third.</p>

<p>"Two very different histories of water on Venus have been proposed: one where Venus had a temperate climate for billions of years, with surface liquid water, and the other where a hot early Venus was never able to condense surface liquid water," Constantinou said.</p>

<p>The Venusian diameter of about 7,500 miles (12,000 km) is just a tad smaller than Earth's 7,900 miles (12,750 km).</p>

<p>"Venus and Earth are often called sister planets because of their similarities in mass, radius, density and distance from the sun. However, their evolutionary paths diverged dramatically," Constantinou said.</p>

<p>"Venus now has surface conditions that are extreme compared to Earth, with an atmospheric pressure 90 times greater, surface temperatures soaring to around 465°C (869°F), and a toxic atmosphere with sulfuric acid clouds. These stark contrasts underscore the unique challenges of understanding Venus as more than just Earth's counterpart," Constantinou said.</p>

<p>The story appears to have been different on Mars, the fourth planet from the sun.</p>

<p>Surface features on Mars indicate it had an ocean of liquid water billions of years ago. No such features have been detected on Venus. Mars, according to research published in August based on seismic data obtained by NASA's robotic InSight lander, may harbor a large reservoir of liquid water deep under its surface within fractured igneous rocks, holding enough to fill an ocean that would cover its entire surface.</p>

<p>While Venus has been studied less than Mars, new explorations are planned. NASA's planned DAVINCI mission will examine Venus during the 2030s from its clouds down to its surface using both flybys and a descent probe. Also during the 2030s, the European Space Agency's EnVision orbital mission is due to conduct radar mapping and atmospheric studies.</p>

<p>"Venus provides a natural laboratory for studying how habitability - or the lack of it - evolves," Constantinou said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/14b8430o_venus-surface-model_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Venus is the second planet from the sun, and Earth the third.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/advocate-defending-hindu-priest-in-bangladesh-attacked-says-iskcon-7157679]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Advocate Defending Hindu Priest In Bangladesh Attacked, Says ISKCON]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/advocate-defending-hindu-priest-in-bangladesh-attacked-says-iskcon-7157679]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:32:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A lawyer defending Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, the Hindu priest arrested and accused of sedition in Bangladesh, has been attacked, the ISKCON (International Society for Krishna Consciousness) has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lawyer defending Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, &nbsp;the Hindu priest arrested and accused of sedition in Bangladesh, has been attacked, the ISKCON (International Society for Krishna Consciousness) has said.&nbsp; In a post on X, Radharaman Das, the spokesperson for ISKCON, said, "Please pray for Advocate Ramen Roy. His only 'fault' was defending Chinmoy Krishna Prabhu in court. Islamists ransacked his home and brutally attacked him, leaving him in the ICU, fighting for his life".</p>

<p>Many lawyers in Bangladesh, however, have denied any such event.</p>

<p>Last month too, there were claims on social media and a few news outlets that a lawyer defending Chinmoy Krishna Das was killed. But investigations revealed that the murdered lawyer, Saiful Islam, was an assistant public prosecutor and he was not defending Chinmoy Das.</p>

<p>The post from Radharaman Das read:&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Please pray for Advocate Ramen Roy. His only 'fault' was defending Chinmoy Krishna Prabhu in court.<br />
<br />
Islamists ransacked his home and brutally attacked him, leaving him in the ICU, fighting for his life.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SaveBangladeshiHindus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SaveBangladeshiHindus</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FreeChinmoyKrishnaPrabhu?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FreeChinmoyKrishnaPrabhu</a> <a href="https://t.co/uudpC10bpN">pic.twitter.com/uudpC10bpN</a></p>
— Radharamn Das राधारमण दास (@RadharamnDas) <a href="https://twitter.com/RadharamnDas/status/1863593503609303469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, a prominent former leader of the International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON) in Bangladesh, was arrested in Dhaka last month after protests by the Hindu community in Rangpur, demanding stronger legal protections for minority groups. He has been accused of sedition and was denied bail by a Dhaka court on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Bangladesh has seen widespread political violence and protests over minority rights since the ouster of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Amid attacks on minority Hindus in the neighbouring coutry, Radharaman Das had earlier posted on X that two disciples of Chinmoy Krishna Das have gone missing in Chattogram after a second Hindu monk, Shyam Das Prabhu, was arrested.</p>

<p>India has condemned the arrest and urged Bangladeshi authorities to ensure the safety and security of Hindus and other minorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The arrest has also been strongly criticised by Indian religious leaders and members of the civil society.</p>

<p>Protest rallies have been held in West Bengal and several other staes that share border with Bangladesh.</p>

<p>In Tripura, the criticism has taken the form of boycott. Hotels and restaurants have decided not to accept bookings from tourists from Bangladesh, the top association of the travel sector has said.</p>

<p>Earlier today, more than 50 protesters allegedly entered the premises of the Bangladeshi mission in Tripura capital Agartala, leading to panic among the officials and staff at the complex. India has described the incident as "deeply regrettable".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/as2juek8_bangladesh-iskcon_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-unveils-fresh-export-curbs-targeting-chinas-chip-sector-7157555]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Unveils Fresh Export Curbs Targeting China's Chip Sector]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-unveils-fresh-export-curbs-targeting-chinas-chip-sector-7157555]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:11:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States announced new export restrictions Monday targeting China's ability to make advanced semiconductors, drawing swift condemnation from Beijing as competition deepens between the world's two biggest economies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States announced new export restrictions Monday targeting China's ability to make advanced semiconductors, drawing swift condemnation from Beijing as competition deepens between the world's two biggest economies.</p>

<p>The moves step up US efforts to tighten curbs on exports of state-of-the-art chips to China, aiming to hinder the country's ability to make chips that can be used in advanced weapons systems and in artificial intelligence.</p>

<p>The announcement comes weeks before President-elect Donald Trump returns to the White House, where he is expected to advance Washington's hawkish stance on China.</p>

<p>"The United States has taken significant steps to protect our technology from being used by our adversaries in ways that threaten our national security," said National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan in a statement.</p>

<p>He added that Washington will keep working with allies and partners "to proactively and aggressively safeguard our world-leading technologies and know-how so they aren't used to undermine our national security."</p>

<p>Beijing vowed Monday to defend its interests, with a Chinese commerce ministry spokesperson saying the United States "abuses export control measures" and has "hindered normal economic and trade exchanges."</p>

<p>The latest US rules include a restriction of exports to 140 companies, including Chinese chip firms Piotech and SiCarrier Technology.</p>

<p>They also impact Naura Technology Group, which makes chip production equipment, according to the Commerce Department.</p>

<p>Others include entities in Japan, South Korea and Singapore.</p>

<p>Being added to the "entity list" restricts US suppliers from exporting to them without additional permission.</p>

<p>The new US rules also include controls on two dozen types of chipmaking equipment and three kinds of software tools for developing or producing semiconductors.</p>

<p>"We are constantly talking to our allies and partners as well as reassessing and updating our controls," noted Under Secretary of Commerce for industry and security Alan Estevez.</p>

<p><strong>Military focus</strong></p>

<p>The efforts further a policy beginning under Trump's first administration, to hold back Beijing's ability to gain ground and become a leading tech economy.</p>

<p>On Monday, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo stressed that President Joe Biden's government has been especially tough in "strategically addressing China's military modernization through export controls."</p>

<p>"The semiconductor manufacturing equipment controlled by today's rules is needed to produce advanced-node integrated circuits, which are necessary for advanced weapon systems and advanced AI used in military applications," the Commerce Department said.</p>

<p>It added that overall, the actions are to slow China's development of advanced AI that could "change the future of warfare," and impair China's development of its own semiconductor ecosystem.</p>

<p>But the department maintained that this is in line with Washington's "small yard, high fence" strategy -- an approach that Chinese President Xi Jinping last month urged against.</p>

<p>Calls to further close the semiconductor supply chain have grown since the world became increasingly aware of the powers of AI, with the launch of ChatGPT.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/el6jo8cg_us-china-generic_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The announcement comes weeks before Donald Trump returns to the White House (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-ceo-strikes-significant-uk-pact-to-combat-cancer-dementia-7157276]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin CEO Strikes "Significant" UK Pact To Combat Cancer, Dementia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-ceo-strikes-significant-uk-pact-to-combat-cancer-dementia-7157276]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 22:23:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The root causes of diseases like cancer, dementia and heart disease are expected to be better understood following a "significant" research partnership involving an Indian-origin entrepreneur's genetics initiative.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The root causes of diseases like cancer, dementia and heart disease are expected to be better understood following a "significant" research partnership involving an Indian-origin entrepreneur's genetics initiative.</p>

<p>Gordon Sanghera, CEO of Oxford Nanopore Technologies, said the development of a world-first "epigenetic map" of the human genome could lead to breakthroughs in new diagnoses and treatments.</p>

<p>The new resource for medical researchers will be created following the UK government's strategic partnership with the Oxford-headquartered life science company, UK Biobank, NHS England and Genomics England unveiled last week.</p>

<p>"This project represents a significant leap forward in epigenetic research, an increasingly important area of study related to disease progression and response to treatment," said Sanghera, born in the UK to a Punjabi family.</p>

<p>"Working with UK Biobank to create the world's largest epigenetic dataset aligns with our commitment to drive discovery in healthcare and genomics. By capturing comprehensive methylation data, we aim to open new doors for understanding disease, especially cancer, and ultimately enable more personalised, effective treatments for patients," he said.</p>

<p>Epigenetics is the emerging study of how inheritable traits, such as the risk of developing a certain disease, can emerge and change without actual changes in our DNA code, but rather as a result of modifications that change how our genes are expressed. These modifications can arise randomly, but also in response to environmental factors like smoking or UV exposure.</p>

<p>According to the UK's Department for Science, Innovation and Technology (DSIT), put simply, if our DNA is the instructions in the cookbook, our epigenome is the chef; different chefs will interpret the cooking method in their own way, and as a result, the meal produced will be different.</p>

<p>"Diseases like cancer and dementia have brought heartache to every family in the country. By bringing government, the NHS (National Health Service), researchers and leading businesses together in partnership, we can transform our understanding of these conditions," said Science and Technology Secretary Peter Kyle.</p>

<p>Health and Social Care Secretary Wes Streeting said the government's '10 Year Health Plan' wants to shift the focus of healthcare from sickness to prevention, to tackle the root causes of diseases such as cancer and dementia.</p>

<p>"We will marry the care and compassion of the NHS with the ingenuity of our country's leading scientific minds, to develop new cutting-edge treatments and technologies, and make our NHS fit for the future," he said.</p>

<p>For the UK Biobank Epigenetics Project, Oxford Nanopore Technologies will use its pioneering technology to conduct genetic sequencing of 50,000 samples from UK Biobank - the world's most advanced source of data for health research.</p>

<p>This work is expected to deliver the world's first "comprehensive dataset of epigenetic modification in the human genome", dubbed a potentially game-changing resource for health researchers worldwide.</p>

<p>According to DSIT, recent studies have shown that epigenetics can play a major role in uncovering cancer's underlying causes, enabling more targeted treatments and improved patient care by addressing the non-inherited factors driving tumour progression and resistance.</p>

<p>This could pave the way to the development of new diagnostic and therapeutic approaches for patients, giving hope to the millions of people who live with conditions like these.</p>

<p>Professor Naomi Allen, Chief Scientist at UK Biobank, explained: "Our lifestyle and environment can cause chemical changes to our DNA, which can contribute to disease by altering the ways genes tell the body which proteins to produce.</p>

<p>By understanding these chemical changes, known as epigenetics, we can learn why some people fall ill and others don't, even when they share the same genes.</p>

<p>"Right now, researchers only have small amounts of epigenetic data to study - this project will create a dataset unlike anything else in the world. It is orders of magnitude bigger, and because of the technology, the data will be much more detailed. Combining epigenetic data with the existing genetic, imaging, proteomic and lifestyle data that UK Biobank holds for our participants, will lead to a much better understanding of how diseases develop in mid- to old age."</p>

<p>Oxford Nanopore is hailed as one of the UK's most successful spinout companies, having been founded at Oxford University in 2005.</p>

<p>The latest work will utilise the company's novel sequencing technology, which uniquely analyses a wide range of epigenetic changes during the DNA sequencing process.</p>

<p>The project will see them continue to improve the insights from their data and translate these into impact for NHS patients in the country.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/lt12md7g_gordon-sanghera_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Oxford Nanopore Technologies will use its technology to conduct genetic sequencing of UK Biobank samples.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgian-president-seeks-europes-support-as-she-defies-her-own-government-7156899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Georgian President Seeks Europe's Support As She Defies Her Own Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgian-president-seeks-europes-support-as-she-defies-her-own-government-7156899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 21:27:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Georgia's president, locked in a standoff with her own government, appealed to European countries on Monday to confront what she described as a Russian attempt to impose control on her nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Georgia's president, locked in a standoff with her own government, appealed to European countries on Monday to confront what she described as a Russian attempt to impose control on her nation.</p>

<p>President Salome Zourabichvili was speaking after a fourth night of clashes between protesters and police after the governing Georgian Dream party announced last week that it was suspending talks on joining the European Union.</p>

<p>Critics saw that as confirmation of a Russian-influenced shift away from pro-Western policies and back towards Moscow's orbit, something the ruling party denies.</p>

<p>"We want our European destiny to be returned to us," Zourabichvili, who has personally remonstrated with riot police, told France Inter radio. "This is the revolt of an entire country."</p>

<p>Zourabichvili, whose powers are mainly ceremonial, said Russia, already at war in Ukraine, was conducting a "hybrid strategy" against Georgia and other countries such as Moldova and NATO and EU member Romania.</p>

<p>"There is a very strong need for very clear moral and political support" from Europe, said the 72-year-old president, who was born in France to Georgian parents and once served as French ambassador to Georgia.</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov denied Russia was interfering in the situation in Georgia, which he compared to the 2014 "Maidan" revolution in Ukraine that overthrew a pro-Russian president.</p>

<p>Former Russian president Dmitry Medvedev warned on Sunday that Georgia was "moving rapidly along the Ukrainian path, into the dark abyss", predicting it would end "very badly".</p>

<p>The United States and the EU have voiced alarm at what they see as democratic backsliding by Georgia, a South Caucasus country of 3.7 million people that lies at the intersection of Europe and Asia and was once part of the Soviet Union.</p>

<p>The government, which earlier this year enacted a law against "foreign agents" and introduced curbs on LGBT rights, say it is acting to protect Georgia against outside interference and prevent it from being dragged, like Ukraine, into a war with Russia.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze accused the opposition of "coordinated violence" aimed at overthrowing the constitutional order.</p>

<h2><strong>FIREWORKS AND TEAR GAS</strong></h2>

<p>On Sunday night, thousands of protesters gathered again in the capital Tbilisi and some tossed fireworks at police, who responded with volleys of water cannon and tear gas.</p>

<p>"I'm here for a very simple reason, to defend my European future and the democracy of my country," said one of the demonstrators, Nikoloz Miruashvili.</p>

<p>Some protesters stayed out all night, but police eventually ended the standoff by moving them away from the parliament building.</p>

<p>Georgia's interior ministry said 21 police officers had been injured in the overnight protest, with 113 hurt since the beginning of the current unrest.</p>

<p>Scores of protesters have also been injured in recent days, and the United States has condemned what it called the excessive use of police force.</p>

<p>Georgia's public ombudsman said 124 out of 156 people arrested at rallies had complained of the police using violence against them, calling this a "very disturbing number".</p>

<p>Zurab Japaridze, a leader of the opposition movement Coalition for Change, was briefly detained by police but later posted on social media that he had been released.</p>

<p>Hundreds of diplomats and civil servants have signed open letters protesting the decision to suspend talks with the EU and stop receiving any funds from the bloc for four years. At least four Georgian ambassadors have resigned.</p>

<p>Ilia Topuria, a martial arts fighter with a major following in the country, wrote in an Instagram post: "I am opposed to the decision to terminate our accession negotiations to the European Union. I am ashamed to see how the children of Georgia are treated. This is not called freedom."</p>

<p>Zourabichvili says she will not step down as president when her term expires this month because the parliament that will select her successor was chosen in October elections that the opposition says were rigged.</p>

<p>The election commission says the vote was fair. Prime Minister Kobakhidze on Sunday said Zourabichvili was reacting emotionally to the opposition's election defeat and would have to leave the presidential palace at the end of the month.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7pumltjs_georgia-president-salome-zourabichvili_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Georgia's President appealed to EU to confront alleged Russian attempt to impose control]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-china-gets-death-penalty-after-pushing-wife-into-sea-for-insurance-money-7156464]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Man Gets Death Penalty For Pushing Wife Into Sea For Insurance Money]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-china-gets-death-penalty-after-pushing-wife-into-sea-for-insurance-money-7156464]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 20:23:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Li had purchased four life insurance policies for his wife just two months after their marriage, naming himself as the sole beneficiary.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 47-year-old man in China was sentenced to death after he pushed his wife into the sea to claim an insurance payout.&nbsp;According to a report by China's state broadcaster CCTV on November 21, the man, identified by his surname Li, planned to&nbsp;collect his wife's life insurance payout to settle his debts and fund his use of prostitutes. Last year, the Liaoning Higher People's Court handed down capital punishment for intentional homicide. However, it is unclear whether the sentence has been executed.</p>

<p>As per a report by the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3288483/man-sentenced-death-china-pushing-wife-sea-using-insurance-payout-prostitutes">South China Morning Post</a></em>, the incident&nbsp;occurred on May 5, 2021, on a&nbsp;ferry travelling from Dalian, Liaoning Province, to Yantai, Shandong Province, in eastern China. During the journey, the wife of the accused, also surnamed Li, fell over the ferry's railing and into the sea.&nbsp;Following a 45-minute search, authorities recovered her body. Upon learning of her death, her husband appeared to be in shock, sitting on the ground in a state of paralysis.</p>

<p>Initially, he claimed the incident was accidental. However, investigators grew suspicious due to the location of the incident being in a blind spot of the ferry's extensive surveillance system, which comprises over 200 cameras. Furthermore, forensic experts discovered bruises on the victim's face.</p>

<p>Additionally, Li demonstrated an unusual eagerness to obtain his wife's death certificate from the authorities, citing local customs that dictated cremation within three days of death. Unknown to Li, the police had devised a plan to invite him to Dalian under the pretence of providing the certificate, while simultaneously dispatching officers to Shanghai, where Li resided, to conduct a discreet investigation into his activities.</p>

<p>Investigations uncovered that Li owned a restaurant in Shanghai, but he struggled with debt. Li remained unmarried until October 2020, when he wed a 46-year-old woman, also surnamed Li, who had two children from her previous two marriages. Interestingly, the woman had been employed at Li's restaurant since 2016. However, police inquiries revealed that the restaurant staff were unaware of their marriage, and neighbours observed that the couple did not appear to be in a romantic relationship.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">During the investigation, officers also tracked down a 19-year-old girlfriend of the husband. Just half a month later, he solicited a prostitute in a hotel room arranged by the police, who were surveilling him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Further investigation revealed that Li had purchased four life insurance policies for his wife just two months after their marriage, naming himself as the sole beneficiary. If she died in a transport-related incident, he would have received a whopping 12 million yuan (US$1.6 million) in compensation.</p>

<p>Despite the evidence, Li continued to claim innocence. However, forensic experts analysed footage from surveillance cameras and concluded that the victim's body fell in a manner consistent with being pushed, rather than an accidental fall. Enhanced footage also revealed another person's arm in black, matching Li's attire that day.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">Li was sentenced to death for murder in the first trial in July 2022, and a higher court upheld the verdict following his appeal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vhq45n2g_ferry_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident occurred on May 5, 2021, on a ferry travelling from Dalian to Yantai.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-georgia-rocked-by-violent-protests-over-russia-eu-divide-within-country-7156344]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pics: Georgia Rocked By Protests Over Russia-EU Divide Within Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-georgia-rocked-by-violent-protests-over-russia-eu-divide-within-country-7156344]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 20:10:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protesters and police clashed in Georgia's capital Tbilisi for a fifth straight night on Monday, with signs of opposition spreading across the country over the government's decision to suspend talks on joining the European Union.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protesters and police clashed in Georgia's capital Tbilisi for a fifth straight night on Monday, with signs of opposition spreading across the country over the government's decision to suspend talks on joining the European Union. Tension in the Black Sea nation has been simmering for months between the ruling Georgian Dream party and opponents, who accuse it of pursuing increasingly authoritarian, anti-Western and pro-Russian policies.</p>

<p>The crisis deepened on Thursday after Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze announced that Georgia would freeze accession talks with the EU for four years, until 2028. This speaker a wave of protests in the country of 3.7 million people, with tens and thousands of demonstrators stepping on roads in Tbilisi and tossing fireworks at police, who responded with volleys of water cannons and tear gas.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2mmf18b_georgia-protest-afp_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>AFP</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>Now, there are signs that opposition was spreading across the country in at least eight cities and towns, according to reports. Demonstrators had blocked an access road into the country's main commercial port in the Black Sea city of Poti, according to Georgian news agency Interpress.</p>

<p>Opposition TV channel Formula showed footage of people in Khashuri, a town of 20,000 in central Georgia, throwing eggs at the local Georgian Dream office.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Reuters" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/5q5flq8o_georgia-protest-reuters_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Reuters" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>Reuters</small></em></p>
</div>

<h2><strong>President Seeks Europe's Support&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Georgia's President Salome Zourabichvili, locked in a standoff with her own government, appealed to European countries on Monday to confront what she described as a Russian attempt to impose control on her nation. "We want our European destiny to be returned to us," Ms Zourabichvili, who has personally remonstrated with riot police, told France Inter radio.</p>

<p>"This is the revolt of an entire country," she said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Reuters" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/helvt0ng_georgia-protest-reuters_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Reuters" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Reuters</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>Ms Zourabichvili, whose powers are mainly ceremonial, said Russia, already at war in Ukraine, was conducting a "hybrid strategy" against Georgia and other countries such as Moldova and NATO and EU member Romania.</p>

<p>"There is a very strong need for very clear moral and political support" from Europe, said the 72-year-old president, who was born in France to Georgian parents and once served as French ambassador to Georgia.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/e8b6vv5_georgia-protest-afp_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>AFP</small></em></p>
</div>

<h2><strong>What Led Georgia Here?</strong></h2>

<p>According to a poll conducted by the US non-profit National Democratic Institute in December last year, nearly 80 per cent of Georgians support European integration. Russia invaded Georgia in 2008 and still occupies nearly 20 per cent of its internationally recognised territory. Due to this, most Georgians harbour a feeling of hostility towards Moscow.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moreover, since the beginning of the Russia-Ukraine war in 2022, thousands of Russians - especially men of service age - have fled to Georgia to avoid conscription, according to a report by CNN. This tore the Black Sea nation's social fabric with Georgians fearing a Russification of their culture.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Georgia has been rocked by turmoil since the ruling Georgian Dream party claimed victory in the October 26 parliamentary election that both the opposition and Ms Zourabichvili called rigged.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7l9kjoa_georgia-protest-afp_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>AFP</small></em></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The party, which ruled Georgia since 2012, is reportedly founded by a billionaire who made his fortune in Russia. The party is often accused by critics of trying to move the country closer to Russia and away from the EU. Ahead of October's elections, it pushed through legislation targeting independent civil society and curbing LGBTQ rights.</p>

<p>The EU and the United States see this as Georgia's shift away from a pro-Western path and back towards Russia's orbit. Georgian Dream says it is acting to defend the country's sovereignty against outside interference and prevent it from being dragged, like Ukraine, into a war with Russia.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze accused the opposition of "coordinated violence" aimed at overthrowing the constitutional order.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ftf3u6jo_georgia-protest-afp_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">AFP</p>
</div>

<h2><strong>Protest In Georgia</strong></h2>

<p>On Sunday night, thousands of protesters gathered again in the capital Tbilisi and some tossed fireworks at police, who responded with volleys of water cannon and tear gas. Some protesters stayed out all night, but police eventually ended the standoff by moving them away from the parliament building.</p>

<p>Georgia's interior ministry said 21 police officers had been injured in the overnight protest, with 113 hurt since the beginning of the current unrest. Scores of protesters have also been injured in recent days, and the United States has condemned what it called the excessive use of police force.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/37c3v7q_georgia-protest-afp_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>AFP</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>Georgia's public ombudsman said 124 out of 156 people arrested at rallies had complained of the police using violence against them, calling this a "very disturbing number".<br />
<br />
However, more rallies were planned on Monday and strikes and other protests have also started. Hundreds of diplomats and civil servants have signed open letters protesting the decision to suspend talks with the EU and stop receiving any funds from the bloc for four years. At least four Georgian ambassadors have resigned.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/oht3j4ao_georgia-protest-afp_625x300_02_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>AFP</small></em></p>
</div>

<h2><strong>Russia's Stand</strong></h2>

<p>Russia on Monday defended the crackdown on protesters, with Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov saying authorities are taking "measures to stabilise" the situation, accusing protesters of trying to "stir up" unrest.</p>

<p>Russia sees "the most direct parallel" with Ukraine's "Maidan" protest that ousted a Kremlin-backed leader in 2014 after he suspended talks on closer EU ties, Peskov said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7fdr1bpo_georgia-protest-reuters_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protest has spread to at least eight cities and towns in Georgia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-actress-24-dies-after-being-swept-away-by-wave-while-doing-yoga-on-thai-island-7156141]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Actress Dies After Being Swept Away By Giant Wave While Doing Yoga]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-actress-24-dies-after-being-swept-away-by-wave-while-doing-yoga-on-thai-island-7156141]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 19:43:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 24-year-old was on vacation with her boyfriend when the incident occurred.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian actress Kamilla Belyatskaya has died after being swept away by a giant wave while practising yoga on a beach on Koh Samui Island, Thailand, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/12/02/actress-24-swept-death-giant-wave-yoga-beauty-spot-22103152/" rel="nofollow, noindex">Metro</a></em> reported.&nbsp;The 24-year-old was on vacation with her boyfriend when the incident occurred. A video capturing her final moments before the wave struck has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/vincent31473580/status/1863367392749129955">been widely shared</a>, showing her engrossed in meditation when the wave unexpectedly pulled her into the sea.&nbsp;A bystander attempted to rescue her, but unfortunately, failed to save her.&nbsp;Her body was later recovered a few kilometres away from the spot where she was swept away.</p>

<p>The Russian tourist had previously expressed her deep love for the exact spot where the accident occurred. She had repeatedly visited the particular location during her trips to the island, which she fondly referred to as her "home" and "the best place on earth". Admiring the place, she wrote on social media, "I love Samui so much. But this place, this rocky beach is the best thing I've ever seen in my life. Thank you, the universe, for me being here right now. I'm very happy. I'm happy."</p>

<p>On the day of the tragic incident, Ms Belyatskaya had travelled to the Lad Ko Viewpoint to admire the waves, arriving in a red car captured on CCTV. She then appeared to walk alone to the rocks, retrieving a pink foam mat from her car's trunk. The mat was later spotted floating in the turbulent waters off Koh Samui.</p>

<p>Rescue teams responded swiftly, arriving within 15 minutes of the actress being swept into the sea. However, the intense conditions hindered their efforts, and they were unable to save her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Chaiyaporn Subprasert, the head of the Samui Rescue Centre, stated that warning systems were in place across the beaches of Koh Samui, aimed at alerting visitors of potential hazards and dangers. He said, "During monsoon season, we constantly warn tourists, especially in high-risk areas like Chaweng and Lamai beaches, where red flags indicate no swimming. While the incident's location is not a swimming area but rather a viewpoint for scenery, the victim may have been caught off guard by the unexpected wave surge."</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ldgcbeuo_kamilla-belyatskaya_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident occurred at a popular spot, where she had expressed gratitude for its beauty.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maryam-faisal-becomes-fifth-victim-in-series-of-pakistani-influencer-video-leaks-7155785]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Maryam Faisal Becomes Fifth Victim In Series Of Pak Influencer Video Leaks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maryam-faisal-becomes-fifth-victim-in-series-of-pakistani-influencer-video-leaks-7155785]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:52:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The leaked video has sparked debates about digital privacy and the growing problem of online harassment targeting influencers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maryam Faisal, a prominent Pakistani Tiktoker, has become the fifth Pakistani influencer to fall victim to a private video leak, following similar incidents involving celebrities like Kanwal Aftab, Minahil Malik, Imsha Rehman, and Mathira Khan.&nbsp;A private video allegedly featuring Ms Faisal has surfaced online, generating widespread debate and speculation, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://en.dailypakistan.com.pk/02-Dec-2024/tiktoker-maryam-faisals-alleged-private-video-leaked-online" rel="nofollow, noindex">Daily Pakistan</a></em> reported. The video, which appears to show a woman resembling Ms Faisal in an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/Saweera2067514/status/1863241540706898339">intimate moment with a partner</a>, has sparked numerous reactions across social media platforms. However, the influencer has not publicly commented on or confirmed the authenticity of the video.</p>

<p>The leaked video has sparked debates about digital privacy and the growing problem of online harassment targeting influencers.</p>

<p><strong>Who is&nbsp;Maryam Faisal?</strong></p>

<p>Maryam Faisal is a Pakistani TikToker who has gained significant popularity on the platform. Known for her engaging content, she has amassed millions of followers. Her TikTok account (@maryamfaisal100) features a variety of videos, including dances, lip-syncs, and lifestyle content.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Fifth such breach</strong></p>

<p>This recent string of privacy violations started with social media influencer Minahil Malik after intimate videos allegedly featuring her were leaked and rapidly spread online, sparking extensive public debate. She claimed that the video was "fake" and lodged a complaint with the&nbsp;Federal Investigation Agency (FIA).</p>

<p>After that,&nbsp;a private video of Pakistan TikTok star&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-imsha-rehman-pakistani-tiktok-star-caught-in-video-leak-scandal-7030925">Imsha Rehman</a>&nbsp;went viral, showing her in an intimate position. She faced a lot of backlash from social media users, who accused her of intentionally making the video public to gain attention. In response, she also deactivated her social media accounts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Later, a private video of Pakistani TV host and influencer Mathira Mohammad was also leaked on social media.&nbsp;Several explicit clips allegedly showed Ms&nbsp;Mohammad in a compromising position. However, the videos could not be verified.&nbsp;The 32-year-old influencer said that people are misusing her name and photoshoot pictures and creating fake photos.</p>

<p>Last week,&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kanwal-aftab-becomes-latest-victim-in-series-of-pakistani-influencer-video-leaks-7111466">Kanwal Aftab</a>, a prominent Pakistani influencer, became the fourth victim of the leak. The clips allegedly featured Ms Aftab in a "compromising situation", sparking widespread attention and controversy.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8m200egg_maryam-faisal_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maryam Faisal is a Pakistani TikToker who has gained significant popularity on the platform.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flagrant-violation-lebanon-says-2-killed-in-israeli-strikes-despite-truce-7155448]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Flagrant Violation": Lebanon Says 2 Killed In Israeli Strikes Despite Truce]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flagrant-violation-lebanon-says-2-killed-in-israeli-strikes-despite-truce-7155448]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:06:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least two people were killed on Monday in Israeli strikes on southern Lebanon, Lebanese authorities said, as a ceasefire ending more than a year of hostilities between Israel and Lebanese armed group Hezbollah appeared increasingly fragile.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least two people were killed on Monday in Israeli strikes on southern Lebanon, Lebanese authorities said, as a ceasefire ending more than a year of hostilities between Israel and Lebanese armed group Hezbollah appeared increasingly fragile.</p>

<p>The truce, which came into effect early on Nov. 27, stipulates that Israel will not carry out offensive military operations against civilian, military or other state targets in Lebanon, while Lebanon will prevent any armed groups, including Hezbollah, from carrying out operations against Israel.</p>

<p>Lebanon and Israel have already traded accusations of breaches, and on Monday Lebanon said the violations had turned deadly.</p>

<p>One person was killed in an Israeli air attack on the southern Lebanese town of Marjayoun, about 10 km (six miles) from the border with Israel, Lebanon's health ministry said.</p>

<p>Lebanon's state security said an Israeli drone strike had killed a member of its force while he was on duty in Nabatieh, 12 km from the border. State security called it a "flagrant violation" of the truce.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Israeli officials.</p>

<p>Public broadcaster Kan and other Israeli media outlets said on Monday that U.S. envoy Amos Hochstein, who brokered the ceasefire after weeks of shuttle diplomacy, had warned Israel against alleged violations.</p>

<p>The Israeli government did not immediately comment on the reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The truce came into effect early on November 27. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidens-u-turn-on-son-raises-questions-about-us-justice-department-action-against-adani-group-7155429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Move Raises Questions About US Department, Action Against Adani Group]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidens-u-turn-on-son-raises-questions-about-us-justice-department-action-against-adani-group-7155429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:02:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden's latest move has revived allegations raised by Donald Trump of the US Department of Justice being manipulated by political powerhouses.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden's latest move has revived allegations raised by Donald Trump of the US Department of Justice being manipulated by political powerhouses. In a stunning volte face, Mr Biden today extended the Presidential pardon to his convicted son Hunter Biden, who was days away from being sentenced to decades in prison.</p>

<p>Joe Biden's move has raised questions about the US Department of Justice and its charges in the Adani case, as many geopolitical experts have pointed out on several occasions.</p>

<h2><strong>HUNTER BIDEN'S CASE</strong></h2>

<p>Hunter Biden, Joe Biden's son, was not just an accused, but found guilty and convicted for gun crimes in the US and for tax evasion of over $1.4 million. He was facing separate prison sentences of 17 years in the gun crime case and up to 25 years for tax evasion.</p>

<p>He has also been accused of using his father's political clout and influence to get exclusive rights to drill for oil in Ukraine as well as have a handful of murky deals with China - for which there can now no longer be a case pursued against him as his father's Presidential pardon gives him immunity for whatever he has done between January 1, 2014, to December 1, 2024.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden's sentencing in court to serve time in prison was scheduled for separate hearings starting December 12, 2024. But his father, President of the United States, went back on his word of "not interfering" in the case by extending the Presidential pardon.</p>

<p>On six occasions over the last year, Joe Biden had assured the US citizens of an "impartial" functioning of the US Department of Justice, but his move today is seen as a clear U-turn from his earlier resolve.</p>

<p>President-elect Donald Trump tore into Joe Biden's move of using the Presidential office to benefit family by calling it a "miscarriage of justice".</p>

<p>Hunter Biden is now a free man with a "full and unconditional" pardon for any action between 2014 and 2024. He cannot face action in future as well on his actions over the last 10 years - the time in which his father was the Vice President and then President of the US.</p>

<h2><strong>US DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE WEAPONISED FOR FOREIGN POLICY?</strong></h2>

<p>The US Department of Justice faces criticism about being weaponised against political opponents in the US and also misused for foreign policy that benefitted those in power. Geopolitical experts and former diplomats have highlighted how Hunter Biden used his father's political clout to gain in Ukraine and China and how the US foreign policy was reportedly moulded by the Biden Administration to suit such personal gains.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President Joe Biden grants 'unconditional' pardon to son Hunter Biden in federal convictions; Experts Question Outgoing administration's credibility point to DoJ's Vindictive Action against Adanis.<br />
<br />
On the panel: <a href="https://twitter.com/Chellaney?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Chellaney</a> and former diplomat Yogesh Gupta with NDTV's… <a href="https://t.co/v7k9jGlmOQ">pic.twitter.com/v7k9jGlmOQ</a></p>
— NDTV (@ndtv) <a href="https://twitter.com/ndtv/status/1863487076790063328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Joe Biden's move has also raised serious questions over the US Department of Justice's action against the Adani Group. There is a wider feeling among diplomats that the Adani indictment by the US Department of Justice is also politically driven by the outgoing Biden administration.</p>

<p>While US President's son Hunter Biden was found guilty and convicted of his charges, there has not been a shred of evidence against Gautam Adani, Sagar Adani and senior executive Vneet Jaain who have been accused by the DoJ and SEC, suspected of acting on the orders of the Biden administration.</p>

<p>The DOJ and the SEC had filed an indictment and a civil complaint in the New York District Court against Gautam Adani, Sagar Adani, and Vneet Jaain, key executives of Adani Green Energy Ltd (AGEL). The Adani Group had rejected the allegations, terming it totally "baseless", and said it would seek legal recourse to defend itself.</p>

<p>Finding itself on the back-foot due to the lack of any evidence, the US Department of Justice in a recent public statement in the Adani case said "The defendants are always innocent unless and until proven guilty."</p>

<p>Joe Biden's move today has sparked off a fierce debate in the United States's power corridors on whether the Department of Justice is indeed "controlled" by political powerhouses.</p>

<h2><strong>WHAT NEW FBI DIRECTOR 'KASH' PATEL SAID</strong></h2>

<p>Kashyap Patel, lawyer, investigator and a stern critic of the US deep state, has spoken out openly about "partisan" and "motivated" practices and also called for a drastic overhaul of the US law enforcement and Intelligence agencies.</p>

<p>"All people in the Department of Justice are just looking for their next promotion," said Mr Patel, who has been named as the next FBI Director by Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Many believe that these "baseless" allegations and "motivated and partisan" foreign policy of the Biden administration will be rectified by the incoming Trump administration. Donald Trump has already announced a complete overhaul of the US foreign policy, including how NATO functions. His administration's DOGE, a department headed by Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy is looking to clean up the bureaucracy, while 'Kash' Patel looks to "clean up" the investigating agencies to rid them of working for "political powerhouses".<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ij3s7378_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden today extended the Presidential pardon to his convicted son Hunter Biden.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/george-clooney-furious-at-barack-obama-for-manipulating-him-heres-what-happened-7155428]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[George Clooney "Furious" At Obama For Manipulating Him. Here's What Happened]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/george-clooney-furious-at-barack-obama-for-manipulating-him-heres-what-happened-7155428]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:01:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Actor George Clooney is reportedly 'furious' at former President Barack Obama for "abandoning" him after using The American star to push President Joe Biden out of the presidential race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following Democrats' devastating losses in the 2024 US presidential election, actor George Clooney is reportedly 'furious' at former President Barack Obama using The American star to push President Joe Biden out of the poll race. Days before Mr Biden ended his Presidential campaign, George Clooney wrote a strongly worded op-ed questioning if the 81-year-old could remain president, casting a shadow of doubt over his health and cognitive abilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Ocean's Eleven actor has reportedly been a close confidante of former President Obama, and it was the latter that allegedly convinced Mr Clooney to publicly ask Mr Biden to step out of the race.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, after Donald Trump officially secured a second term in the White House, the actor has been facing a backlash from the Democrats' loss, as it was his article that was widely credited for changing the course of the election.</p>

<p>Mr Clooney is now "complaining that Obama who sort of manipulated him into doing the dirty work on his behalf has left him to take most of the blame for the election loss," according to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.skynews.com.au/opinion/george-clooney-furious-at-obama-for-manipulating-him-into-forcing-biden-out-of-election-race/video/1c67669f6565e7ffd4ad1395341add2c" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Sky News.</a></p>

<p>A report by OK! Magazine said, "Obama and Clooney have been tight for years, and George became Barack's surrogate in leading the charge for Joe to step away."</p>

<p>"George is furious with Obama for disappearing after the election disaster and leaving him holding the bag for pushing the plan with his Hollywood pals," the article quoted an insider as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per the report, Mr Obana knew "he would look like a traitor if he publicly called for Joe to be cut loose. And now, he's trying to walk away from it all."</p>

<p>Now, amid public backlash over his article, the actor is reportedly feeling "duped" and "vows he's not going to be anyone's political water boy anymore."</p>

<p>"George feels he stepped up and took a bullet for the team," the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://okmagazine.com/p/george-clooney-furious-barack-obama-disappear-election/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">report </a>said.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>George Clooney's Op-ed</strong></h2>

<p>Days before Mr Biden endorsed his Vice President Kamala Harris for the presidential race, Mr Clooney wrote a widely read opinion article for the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/10/opinion/joe-biden-democratic-nominee.html" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">New York Times</a>, highlighting the President's poor performance during his debate against his Democratic rival. The article claimed it would not be possible for the 81-year-old leader to win the head-on-head competition against Mr Trump.</p>

<p>"It's devastating to say it, but the Joe Biden I was with three weeks ago at the fund-raiser was not the Joe "big F-ing deal" Biden of 2010. He wasn't even the Joe Biden of 2020. He was the same man we all witnessed at the debate," the article read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Was he tired? Yes. A cold? Maybe. But our party leaders need to stop telling us that 51 million people didn't see what we just saw. We're all so terrified by the prospect of a second Trump term that we've opted to ignore every warning sign," it added</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2lqhgu18_george-clooney-reuters_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[George Clooney is now "complaining" that Mr Obama "manipulated him into doing the dirty work"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-accuses-philippine-ships-of-illegally-gathering-at-disputed-reef-7155418]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Accuses Philippine Ships Of "Illegally Gathering" At Disputed Reef]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-accuses-philippine-ships-of-illegally-gathering-at-disputed-reef-7155418]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:00:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China on Monday said it had taken "control measures" against Philippine ships it accused of "illegally gathering" near a disputed reef in the South China Sea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China on Monday said it had taken "control measures" against Philippine ships it accused of "illegally gathering" near a disputed reef in the South China Sea.</p>

<p>"Recently, several Philippine ships... illegally gathered under the pretence of fishing in the waters near Houteng Reef of China's Nansha Islands," China Coast Guard spokesperson Liu Dejun said in a statement, using the Chinese names for the Iroquois Reef and Spratly Islands.</p>

<p>"The Chinese Coast Guard took necessary control measures against the Philippine ships in accordance with the law," Liu said.</p>

<p>"We warn the Philippine side to immediately stop its infringements and provocations."</p>

<p>China claims almost all of the South China Sea, despite an international ruling in 2016 concluding its claims have no legal basis.</p>

<p>Beijing has deployed navy, coast guard and so-called maritime militia forces -- allegedly Chinese fishing vessels -- in a bid to bar the Philippines from strategically important reefs and islands in the South China Sea.</p>

<p>Vessels from the two sides have clashed frequently in the past year, resulting in injuries and damages.</p>

<p>Tensions escalated in November when Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos signed two laws defining the country's sea waters and imposing fixed lanes for foreign ships.</p>

<p>That sparked a sharp riposte by China, which summoned Manila's envoy "to lodge solemn representations" over their passage.</p>

<p>Tensions rose again earlier this month when the United States and the Philippines signed a security agreement that allows the two sides to share classified information.</p>

<p>Earlier on Monday, Marcos said a Russian attack submarine was spotted off the country's coast in the disputed South China Sea, describing its presence as "very worrisome".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3ipd01vs_chinese-navy-ships-and-helicopter-ians_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vessels from the two sides have clashed frequently in the past year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/you-guys-are-indian-american-family-faces-racist-attack-at-la-airport-7155186]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You Guys Are...": Indian-American Family Faces Racial Slurs At LA Airport]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/you-guys-are-indian-american-family-faces-racist-attack-at-la-airport-7155186]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 17:34:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman passed racist comments at a celebrated wedding photographer and his Indian-American family while they were in a shuttle bus of United Airlines at the Los Angeles Airport last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman passed racist comments at a celebrated wedding photographer and his Indian-American family while they were in a shuttle bus of United Airlines at the Los Angeles Airport last week.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.instagram.com/ptaufiqphotography/" rel="noindex,nofollow" target="_blank">Pervez Taufiq</a> was accompanied by his wife and their three children when they arrived in Los Angeles from Cancun. The woman, who was on the same flight as Mr Taufiq's family, boarded the same bus to the terminal.</p>

<p>"Mortified, we just went through this. This lady was harassing our son on the flight, unbeknownst to us, asking him if he was Indian and making comments. When we landed in LA and got on the transfer bus, she told our son to 'shut up', I told her she didn't have a right to speak to my son that way and her husband got in my face trying to tell me to not speak to his wife," Mr Taufiq wrote on Instagram and shared a video of the entire incident.</p>

<p>In the video, the photographer expressed his outrage over the incident, saying his "blood is boiling right now".</p>

<p>"I honestly can't even believe that something like this is a real thing. We were just having an altercation with this lady who was giving us a really hard time telling the kids to 'Shut Up', I lost it and said, you know, you don't have a right to talk to my kids like that."</p>

<p>The situation escalated after the woman verbally attacked him and said, "Your family is from India, you have no respect, you have no rules, you think you can push everyone, push, push, push... That's what you think you are. You guys are f*****g crazy."</p>

<p>In response, Mr Taufiq asked if she wanted him to have "more curry". To this, she said, "I am going to record your f******g tandoori a**... your tandoori stinky a**."</p>

<p>As Mr Taufiq asked the security personnel to remove her, she interrupted him and said, "He does not care that I am a racist, you are racist towards me. I am American."</p>

<p>"So are we," he replied to her.</p>

<p>She reacted, "You are not American... Not originally no, you are from...India."</p>

<p>Mr Taufiq insisted he was born in America.</p>

<p>In his post, Mr Taufiq thanked the airline and said the lady was taken "off the bus ultimately and a few fellow passengers stood up for us."</p>

<p>"Blown away these types of people still exist," he added.</p>

<p>Speaking with <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/02/us-news/wedding-photographer-and-family-shocked-by-sickening-insults-from-fellow-united-passenger/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Post</a>, Mr Taufiq, who grew up in Boston, said he first interacted with her during the flight.</p>

<p>Mr Taufiq believed the woman was "clearly" drunk at the time of the incident.</p>

<p>He and his wife work as photographers at events, including over 200 weddings per year, worldwide.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pbmj5hn_racist-us-woman_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In the video, the photographer expressed his outrage over the incident]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apocalyptic-un-chief-on-situation-in-gaza-amid-israel-hamas-war-7154882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Apocalyptic": UN Chief On Situation In Gaza Amid Israel-Hamas War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apocalyptic-un-chief-on-situation-in-gaza-amid-israel-hamas-war-7154882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 16:50:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations chief said Monday the situation in war-torn Gaza was "appalling and apocalyptic", warning conditions faced by Palesti]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations chief said Monday the situation in war-torn Gaza was "appalling and apocalyptic", warning conditions faced by Palestinians in the territory may amount to the "gravest international crimes".</p>

<p>In remarks read out on his behalf at a Cairo conference aimed at increasing humanitarian aid, UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres urged the international community to "build a foundation for sustainable peace in Gaza and across the Middle East".</p>

<p>The war in Gaza broke out when Palestinian group Hamas attacked southern Israel on October 7, 2023, resulting in 1,208 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed 44,429 people in Gaza, according to figures from the territory's health ministry that the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>Guterres highlighted the devastating toll of the conflict and the urgent need for international action.</p>

<p>"Malnutrition is rampant... Famine is imminent. Meanwhile, the health system has collapsed," he said.</p>

<p>The UN chief added that Gaza now has "the highest number of children amputees per capita anywhere in the world", with "many losing limbs and undergoing surgeries without even anesthesia".</p>

<p>The secretary-general also criticised the severe restrictions on aid delivery, calling the current levels "grossly insufficient".</p>

<p>According to UNRWA's count, only 65 aid trucks per day had been able to enter Gaza this past month, compared to a pre-war average of 500.</p>

<p>International aid organisations have repeatedly raised alarm over the deteriorating conditions in Gaza, warning that civilians are on the brink of famine.</p>

<p>They have said aid shipments reaching the enclave are now at their lowest since the start of the war.</p>

<p>Israel, which early in the conflict imposed a complete siege for a period on the Hamas-ruled territory, has blamed aid issues on what it says is the inability of relief organisations to handle and distribute large quantities of aid.</p>

<p>UN's Guterres said on Monday that the blockade of aid to Gaza "is not a crisis of logistics" but rather "a crisis of political will and of respect for fundamental principles of international humanitarian law".</p>

<p>UNRWA said all the attempts it made to deliver aid into northern Gaza had either been "denied" or "impeded" between October 6, 2024 and November 25, amid fierce fighting in the area.</p>

<p>Guterres said UNRWA is an "irreplaceable lifeline for millions of Palestinians", adding that "if UNRWA is forced to close, the responsibility of replacing its vital services ... would rest with Israel".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8rhc66g_gaza-reuters_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to UNRWA, only 65 aid trucks per day have been able to enter Gaza this past month. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-die-32-hospitalised-after-eating-endangered-sea-turtle-in-philippines-7154375]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Dead, 32 Hospitalised After Eating Endangered Sea Turtle In Philippines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-die-32-hospitalised-after-eating-endangered-sea-turtle-in-philippines-7154375]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:50:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Although hunting or consuming sea turtles is prohibited under the Philippines' environmental protection laws, these marine creatures continue to be consumed in some communities where they are considered a traditional delicacy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three people have died, and at least 32 others were hospitalized in the Philippines after consuming a stew made from an endangered sea turtle, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2y8xz9nweo">BBC</a></em> reported. Officials reported that dozens of indigenous Teduray people began experiencing symptoms such as diarrhoea, vomiting, and abdominal spasms after eating the dish last week in a coastal town in Maguindanao del Norte Province.&nbsp;Although hunting or consuming sea turtles is prohibited under the Philippines' environmental protection laws, these marine creatures continue to be consumed in some communities where they are considered a traditional delicacy.</p>

<p>However, eating sea turtles, particularly their meat or organs, can be extremely dangerous and potentially fatal. Sea turtles often carry toxins such as chelonitoxin, a naturally occurring biotoxin. Consumption of their meat, fat, or other parts can lead to poisoning symptoms like nausea, vomiting, diarrhoea, difficulty breathing, and even death in severe cases. Though the exact cause is unknown, it is thought to be linked to poisonous algae that the turtles eat, according to the Turtle Foundation charity.</p>

<p>A local official, Irene Dillo told the <em>BBC </em>that some dogs, cats, and chickens fed the same sea turtle meat also died. She added that authorities are currently investigating the deaths.</p>

<p>According to local media, most of the residents hospitalised have since been discharged, while the three people who died were buried immediately, adhering to local traditions.</p>

<p>Councilor Datu Mohamad Sinsuat Jr. emphasised the need to strictly enforce the ban on hunting sea turtles in the region. He vowed, "This food poisoning incident will never happen again."</p>

<p>Earlier this year,&nbsp;eight children and an adult died after eating sea turtle meat on Pemba Island in the Zanzibar archipelago,&nbsp;<em><a href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/03/11/eight-children-a-woman-die-eating-sea-turtle-meat-20443027/?ico=top-stories_home_top">Metro</a></em>&nbsp;reported.&nbsp;A further 78 people were hospitalised after consuming the meal on March 5, according to Mkoani District medical officer, Dr Haji Bakari.</p>

<article>
<p>Similar cases have also been reported in Indonesia, Micronesia and India's Indian Ocean islands. So far, no antidote for the poisoning has been found.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>
</article>

<aside id="stk_cnt"></aside>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/p1745ld_sea-turtle_625x300_12_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Turtle meat can be toxic because of a type of food poisoning known as chelonitoxism]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>