<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 13:50:31 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jack-karlson-the-man-behind-democracy-manifest-meme-dies-at-82-6298568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jack Karlson, The Man Behind 'Democracy Manifest' Meme, Dies At 82]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jack-karlson-the-man-behind-democracy-manifest-meme-dies-at-82-6298568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 12:56:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jack Karlson, famed for the classic "democracy manifest" and "succulent Chinese meal" clip, died on August 7, aged 82.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jack Karlson, famed for the classic "democracy manifest" and "succulent Chinese meal" clip, died on August 7, aged 82. In a statement, Karlson's family confirmed his death, saying he had prostate cancer.</p>

<p>"He walked a full and colourful path and despite the troubles thrown at him, he lived by his motto - to keep on laughing," they said in a statement.</p>

<p>Karlson had been in the hospital for the past three weeks, trying to break free several times, according to his niece Kim Edwards, who told The Independent that, "he asked us many times to sneak in his pipe."</p>

<p>She also mentioned that as a final farewell, they gave Karlson a "last taste of red wine through his drip".</p>

<p>Karlson was a small-time criminal and serial jail escapee. There's still debate over whether or not this was his true name. He became popular in 2009 when a 1991 news tape of his arrest at a Chinese restaurant in Brisbane's Fortitude Valley was posted online.</p>

<p>Karlson was suspected of using a stolen credit card, but he always claimed it was a case of misidentification.</p>

<p>"What is the charge? Eating a meal? A succulent Chinese meal?" Karlson resisted a group of cops and yelled dramatically.</p>

<p>Among his other now-iconic phrases was "Gentlemen, this is democracy manifest."</p>

<p>Numerous memes, music remixes, response videos, and even a few tattoos have been inspired by this pivotal event. Additionally, there is a racehorse -- a purebred Australian -- named Democracy Manifest. Karlson died a day after his 82nd birthday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, filmmaker Heath Davis is directing a documentary on Karlson called The Man Who Ate a Succulent Chinese Meal. The film is slated to be released in early 2025. In an interview with The Guardian, Davis referred to Karlson as "the last Australian larrikin."</p>

<p>Mark Depin, documentary's associate producer and author of a nonfiction book inspired by Karlson's life, says the 82-year-old's real name was Cecil George Edwards.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e3b3e2n_jack-karlson-_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jack Karlson had been in the hospital for the past three weeks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-agrees-to-debate-kamala-harris-what-latest-polls-suggest-6298163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Agrees To Debate Kamala Harris: What Latest Polls Suggest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-agrees-to-debate-kamala-harris-what-latest-polls-suggest-6298163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 12:18:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has agreed to debate his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris on September 10.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has agreed to debate his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris on September 10. The showdown is set to be hosted by ABC, with additional debates proposed for September 4 and September 25 on Fox and NBC, respectively.</p>

<p>This will be the first face-off between the two rivals, with polls indicating a closely contested race.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Trump vs Harris: What polls predict</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Ipsos poll</strong></h3>

<p>A recent Ipsos poll published on August 9, shows Kamala Harris leading Donald Trump 42 per cent to 37 per cent for the November 5 elections. This shows growth in her popularity since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37 per cent to 34 per cent over Trump.</p>

<p>In a separate poll, Ipsos found Harris leading Trump 42 per cent to 40 per cent in the seven states where the election was closest in 2020 - Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<h3><strong>YouGov poll</strong></h3>

<p>A CBS/YouGov poll released on August 4 shows Kamala Harris levelling up with Donald Trump. She has erased Trump's growing lead since President Joe Biden dropped his reelection bid. The poll indicates Harris has a 1 per cent advantage over Trump nationwide, compared to Trump's previous five-point edge over Biden. In swing states, Harris and Trump are equal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moreover, the poll shows only 51 per cent of respondents thought Trump was mentally capable of the presidency, compared to 64 per cent for Harris.</p>

<h3><strong>Marist poll</strong></h3>

<p>An NPR/PBS News/Marist poll shows Harris has a 51-48 per cent edge over Trump among key demographics such as Black voters, white women with college degrees and women who identify as political independents. Independent women voters are crucial swing voters. Harris has made significant inroads with this group, leading Trump by 9 points (53-44 per cent).</p>

<p>The poll also states that Harris has made significant gains in suburban areas and among white voters overall, which has helped her improve her standing compared to earlier polls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, Trump still maintains an advantage on economic issues, leading Harris by 3 points (51-48 per cent). Trump also leads Harris on handling immigration, with a 52-46 per cent advantage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the issue of abortion, Harris has a clear advantage, leading Trump by 15 points.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kamala Harris, who entered the presidential race on July 21 after receiving President Joe Biden's endorsement, has selected Tim Walz, the Governor of Minnesota, as her running mate. This move comes after Biden folded his campaign and exited the race following a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump on June 27.</p>

<p>Harris and Walz debuted their joint campaign at a rally in Philadelphia, marking the beginning of their bid to take on Republican Trump and his running mate, JD Vance, in the upcoming presidential election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has agreed to debate his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris on September 10.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-advances-10-km-into-russias-kursk-region-thousands-evacuated-6298425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Advances 10 km Into Russia's Kursk Region, Thousands Evacuated]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-advances-10-km-into-russias-kursk-region-thousands-evacuated-6298425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 12:14:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian troops have advanced up to 10 kilometres (six miles) into Russia in possibly the most serious border incursion of the conflict, the Institute for the Study of War said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian troops have advanced up to 10 kilometres (six miles) into Russia in possibly the most serious border incursion of the conflict, the Institute for the Study of War said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Pro-Kyiv forces stormed into Russia's southwestern Kursk region on Tuesday morning, deploying around 1,000 troops and more than two dozen armoured vehicles and tanks, according to the Russian army.</p>

<p>Kyiv has not officially commented on the operation.</p>

<p>Russia's top general vowed on Wednesday to crush the incursion and push the Ukrainian fighters back to the border.</p>

<p>"Ukrainian forces have made confirmed advances up to 10 kilometres (six miles) into Russia's Kursk Oblast amid continued mechanised offensive operations on Russian territory," the US-based Institute for the Study of War (ISW) said in its latest update.</p>

<p>"The current confirmed extent and location of Ukrainian advances in Kursk Oblast indicate that Ukrainian forces have penetrated at least two Russian defensive lines and a stronghold," it added.</p>

<p>The advance has centred on the logistical hub of Sudzha, a town of around 5,000 inhabitants located eight kilometres from the Ukrainian border.</p>

<p>There have been scant updates from officials in Moscow.</p>

<p>But Russian military bloggers, who have links to the army, also reported Kyiv had made significant advances and lamented deteriorating circumstances.</p>

<p>"The situation is complicated and continues to worsen," blogger Yury Podolyaka said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>He said the town of Sudzha was "full of Ukrainian soldiers".</p>

<p>"Sudzha has been completely lost," he said.</p>

<p>"The enemy is entrenching, indicating that the fighting is likely to be long-term," the Dva Mayora Telegram channel said.</p>

<p>Multiple military bloggers reported Ukrainian troops had advanced towards the town of Korenevo, more than 25 kilometres from the Ukrainian border.</p>

<p>Russian energy giant Gazprom said on Thursday it would continue shipping gas through the Sudzha metering station, the last transit point for Russian gas heading to Europe via Ukraine.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry said its forces had destroyed a US-made Bradley Fighting Vehicle that Ukraine was using in the incursion and that it had downed Ukrainian drones over the region.</p>

<p>The governor of the Kursk region introduced a local state of emergency on Wednesday evening, a move that gives authorities the power to restrict movement in a bid to bring the situation under control.</p>

<p>Several thousand have been evacuated on both sides of the border.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q2msta7g_ukraine-incursion-into-russia_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The governor of the Kursk region introduced a local state of emergency on Wednesday (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-prepare-for-possible-megaquake-that-could-kill-many-6298154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explainer: Why Did Japan Scientists Issue 'Megaquake' Advisory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-prepare-for-possible-megaquake-that-could-kill-many-6298154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 11:27:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's earthquake scientists say the country should prepare for a possible "megaquake" one day that could kill hundreds of thousands of people -- although they stress the warning does not mean a colossal tremor is imminent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's earthquake scientists say the country should prepare for a possible "megaquake" one day that could kill hundreds of thousands of people -- although they stress the warning does not mean a colossal tremor is imminent.</p>

<p>The Japan Meteorological Association (JMA) warning is the first issued under new rules drawn up after a 2011 earthquake, tsunami and nuclear disaster killed around 18,500 people.</p>

<h3><strong>What does the warning say?</strong></h3>

<p>The JMA's "megaquake advisory" warns that "if a major earthquake were to occur in the future, strong shaking and large tsunamis would be generated".</p>

<p>"The likelihood of a new major earthquake is higher than normal, but this is not an indication that a major earthquake will definitely occur during a specific period of time," it added.</p>

<p>The advisory concerns the Nankai Trough "subduction zone" between two tectonic plates in the Pacific Ocean, where massive earthquakes have hit in the past.</p>

<h3><strong>What is the Nankai Trough?</strong></h3>

<p>The 800-kilometre (500-mile) undersea trough runs from Shizuoka, west of Tokyo, to the southern tip of Kyushu island.</p>

<p>It has been the site of destructive quakes of magnitude eight or nine every century or two.</p>

<p>These so-called "megathrust quakes", which often occur in pairs, have been known to unleash dangerous tsunamis along Japan's southern coast.</p>

<p>In 1707, all segments of the Nankai Trough ruptured at once, unleashing an earthquake that remains the nation's second-most powerful on record.</p>

<p>That quake -- which also triggered the last eruption of Mount Fuji -- was followed by two powerful Nankai megathrusts in 1854, and then a pair in 1944 and 1946.</p>

<h3><strong>How much is at stake?</strong></h3>

<p>Japan's government has previously said the next magnitude 8-9 megaquake along the Nankai Trough has a roughly 70 percent probability of striking within the next 30 years.</p>

<p>In the worst-case scenario 300,000 lives could be lost, experts estimate, with some engineers saying the damage could reach $13 trillion with infrastructure wiped out.</p>

<p>"The history of great earthquakes at Nankai is convincingly scary," geologists Kyle Bradley and Judith A Hubbard wrote in their Earthquake Insights newsletter.</p>

<p>And "while earthquake prediction is impossible, the occurrence of one earthquake usually does raise the likelihood of another", they explained.</p>

<p>"A future great Nankai earthquake is surely the most long-anticipated earthquake in history -- it is the original definition of the 'Big One'."</p>

<h3><strong>How worried should people be?</strong></h3>

<p>Japan is reminding people living in quake zones to take general precautions, from securing furniture to knowing the location of their nearest evacuation shelter.</p>

<p>Many households in the country also keep a disaster kit handy with bottled water, long-life food, a torch, radio and other practical items.</p>

<p>But there's no need to panic -- there is only a "small probability" that Thursday's magnitude 7.1 earthquake is a foreshock, according to Bradley and Hubbard.</p>

<p>"One of the challenges is that even when the risk of a second earthquake is elevated, it is still always low," they said.</p>

<p>"For instance, in California, the rule of thumb is that any given earthquake has around five per cent chance of being a foreshock."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/0vdfur1o_earthquake-generic_625x300_10_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This warning was first issued under new rules drawn up after a 2011 earthquake (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-rocket-ends-up-as-300-piece-space-junk-after-satellite-constellation-launch-6297963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Rocket Ends Up As 300-Piece Space Junk After Satellite Launch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-rocket-ends-up-as-300-piece-space-junk-after-satellite-constellation-launch-6297963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 11:22:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's Long March 6A rocket broke apart creating over 300 pieces of trackable debris in low Earth orbit, after achieving a significant milestone of launching 18 Qianfan satellites, the US Space Command (USSPACECOM) said today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's Long March 6A rocket broke apart creating over 300 pieces of trackable debris in low Earth orbit, after achieving a significant milestone of launching 18 Qianfan satellites, the US Space Command (USSPACECOM) said today.</p>

<p>The 18 satellites were part of the first batch aimed to establish China's "own version of Elon Musk's Starlink", called the Qianfan ("Thousand Sails") broadband network.</p>

<p>The satellites were launched on Tuesday on the Long March 6A rocket from the Taiyuan Satellite Launch Center in North China's Shanxi Province.</p>

<p>The satellites were designed and built by the Chinese Academy of Sciences' Innovation Academy for Microsatellites in Shanghai.</p>

<p>While the rocket successfully delivered the satellites at an altitude of about 800 kilometres, soon after its upper stage broke apart. The breakup generated a cloud of debris that is trackable around Earth, the USSPACECOM said.</p>

<p>"USSPACECOM can confirm the breakup of a Long March 6A rocket launched on Aug. 6, 2024, resulting in over 300 pieces of trackable debris in low Earth orbit," the organisation said in a statement, posted on social media platform X.com on Friday.</p>

<p>"USSPACECOM has observed no immediate threats and continues to conduct routine conjunction assessments to support the safety and sustainability of the space domain," it added.</p>

<p>China launched the Qianfan mega constellation project in 2023 to provide more extensive and high-quality communication services for domestic users.</p>

<p>Developed by the Shanghai-based company SpaceSail, the Qianfan network is reported to establish a network of over 15,000 low earth orbit (LEO) wide-screen multimedia satellites in the long run, of which 108 satellites will be launched this year and 648 satellites by 2025 end.</p>

<p>By 2027, the constellation aims to provide global network coverage, and ultimately by 2030, encompass 15,000 satellites providing integrated services such as direct mobile connections, Global Times reported.</p>

<p>On the other hand, SpaceX's Starlink currently has more than 6,000 satellites in space and has more than 3 million customers in 100 countries.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p1u6k208_space-junk-generic-space-debris-generic-pixabay_625x300_09_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China's rocket broke apart creating 300 pieces of trackable debris in low Earth orbit (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-pm-shehbaz-sharif-congratulates-bangladesh-pm-muhammad-yunus-aims-to-deepen-cooperation-6298096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan PM Congratulates Muhammad Yunus, Aims To "Deepen Cooperation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-pm-shehbaz-sharif-congratulates-bangladesh-pm-muhammad-yunus-aims-to-deepen-cooperation-6298096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 11:18:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistani Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif on Friday congratulated the new interim leader of Bangladesh, Muhammad Yunus, and expressed hopes for deeper ties with the nation that separated from Pakistan in 1971.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif on Friday congratulated the new interim leader of Bangladesh, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-resignation-bangladesh-violence-muhammad-yunus-nobel-laureate-to-lead-bangladeshs-army-backed-interim-government-6280806" target="_blank">Muhammad Yunus</a>, and expressed hopes for deeper ties with the nation that separated from Pakistan in 1971.</p>

<p>"Heartiest felicitations to professor Muhammad Yunus," Sharif tweeted. "Wishing him great success in guiding Bangladesh towards a harmonious and prosperous future. I look forward to working with him to deepen cooperation between Pakistan and Bangladesh in the days ahead."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6pvcte1_shehbaz-sharif-ians_625x300_06_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pakistani Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif congratulated the new interim leader of Bangladesh (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-pm-fumio-kishida-cancels-central-asia-trip-amid-megaquake-warnings-6298093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan PM Fumio Kishida Cancels Central Asia Trip Amid Megaquake Warnings]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-pm-fumio-kishida-cancels-central-asia-trip-amid-megaquake-warnings-6298093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 11:17:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's Prime Minister Fumio Kishida on Friday cancelled a trip to Central Asia after earthquake scientists warned the country should prepare for a possible "megaquake".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's Prime Minister Fumio Kishida on Friday cancelled a trip to Central Asia after earthquake scientists warned the country should prepare for a possible "megaquake".</p>

<p>The Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA) issued the advisory on Thursday after eight people were injured by a tremor of magnitude 7.1 in the south.</p>

<p>Kishida was due Friday to travel to Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan and Mongolia and had planned to attend a regional summit.</p>

<p>"As the prime minister with the highest responsibility for crisis management, I decided I should stay in Japan for at least a week," he told reporters.</p>

<p>Kishida added that the public must be feeling "very anxious" after the JMA issued its first advisory under a new system drawn up following a major magnitude 9.0 earthquake in 2011 which triggered a deadly tsunami and nuclear disaster.</p>

<p>"The likelihood of a new major earthquake is higher than normal, but this is not an indication that a major earthquake will definitely occur," the JMA said.</p>

<p>Traffic lights and cars shook and dishes fell off shelves during Thursday's earthquake off the southern island of Kyushu, but no serious damage was reported.</p>

<p>The Fire and Disaster Management Agency said eight people were hurt -- including several hit by falling objects.</p>

<p>Sitting on top of four major tectonic plates, the Japanese archipelago of 125 million people sees some 1,500 quakes every year, most of them minor.</p>

<p>Even with larger tremors the impact is generally contained thanks to advanced building techniques and well-practised emergency procedures.</p>

<p>The government has previously said a megaquake has a roughly 70 percent probability of striking within the next 30 years.</p>

<p>It could affect a large swath of the Pacific coastline of Japan and threaten an estimated 300,000 lives in the worst-case scenario, experts say.</p>

<h3><strong>'Risk elevated, but low'</strong></h3>

<p>"While earthquake prediction is impossible, the occurrence of one earthquake usually does raise the likelihood of another," experts from Earthquake Insights said.</p>

<p>But they added that even when the risk of a second earthquake is elevated, it is "still always low".</p>

<p>On January 1, a 7.6-sized jolt and powerful aftershocks hit the Noto Peninsula on the Sea of Japan coast, killing at least 318 people, toppling buildings and knocking out roads.</p>

<p>In 2011, a mammoth 9.0-magnitude undersea quake off northeastern Japan triggered a tsunami that left around 18,500 people dead or missing.</p>

<p>It sent three reactors into meltdown at the Fukushima nuclear plant, causing Japan's worst post-war disaster and the most serious nuclear accident since Chernobyl.</p>

<p>A future megaquake could emanate from the vast Nankai Trough off eastern Japan that in the past has seen major jolts, often in pairs, with magnitudes of eight and even nine.</p>

<p>This included one in 1707 -- until 2011 the largest recorded -- when Mount Fuji last erupted, in 1854, and then a pair in 1944 and 1946.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/0u4t8puo_fumio-kishida-afp_625x300_15_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Japan's PM was due to travel to Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan and Mongolia to attend a regional summit (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-megaquake-advisory-follows-7-1-magnitude-tremor-6297730]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan's Megaquake Advisory Follows 7.1 Magnitude Tremor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-megaquake-advisory-follows-7-1-magnitude-tremor-6297730]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 10:16:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's earthquake scientists have warned of the possibility of a coming "megaquake" after eight people were injured Thursday by one of magnitude 7.1 in the south.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's earthquake scientists have warned of the possibility of a coming "megaquake" after eight people were injured Thursday by one of magnitude 7.1 in the south.</p>

<p>"The likelihood of a new major earthquake is higher than normal, but this is not an indication that a major earthquake will definitely occur," the Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA) said.</p>

<p>It was the first advisory issued under a new system drawn up following a major quake in 2011.</p>

<p>A government spokesman declined to comment on a report by broadcaster NHK that Prime Minister Fumio Kishida will cancel a trip to Central Asia from Friday following the warning.</p>

<p>Traffic lights and cars shook and dishes fell off shelves during Thursday's tremor off the southern island of Kyushu, but no serious damage was reported.</p>

<p>The Fire and Disaster Management Agency said eight people were hurt -- including several hit by falling objects.</p>

<p>Sitting on top of four major tectonic plates, the Japanese archipelago of 125 million people sees some 1,500 quakes every year, most of them minor.</p>

<p>Even with larger tremors the impact is generally contained thanks to advanced building techniques and well-practised emergency procedures.</p>

<p>The government has previously said a megaquake has a roughly 70 per cent probability of striking within the next 30 years.</p>

<p>It could affect a large swath of the Pacific coastline of Japan and threaten an estimated 300,000 lives in the worst-case scenario, experts say.</p>

<h3><strong>'Risk elevated, but low'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"While earthquake prediction is impossible, the occurrence of one earthquake usually does raise the likelihood of another," experts from Earthquake Insights said.</p>

<p>But they added that even when the risk of a second earthquake is elevated, it is "still always low".</p>

<p>On January 1, a 7.6-sized jolt and powerful aftershocks hit the Noto Peninsula on the Sea of Japan coast, killing at least 318 people, toppling buildings and knocking out roads.</p>

<p>In 2011, a mammoth 9.0-magnitude undersea quake off northeastern Japan triggered a tsunami that left around 18,500 people dead or missing.</p>

<p>It sent three reactors into meltdown at the Fukushima nuclear plant, causing Japan's worst post-war disaster and the most serious nuclear accident since Chernobyl.</p>

<p>A future megaquake could emanate from the vast Nankai Trough off eastern Japan that in the past has seen major jolts, often in pairs, with magnitudes of eight and even nine.</p>

<p>This included in 1707 -- until 2011 the largest recorded -- when Mount Fuji last erupted, in 1854, and then a pair in 1944 and 1946.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/78f74ep_earthquake_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This was the first advisory issued under a new system after a major quake in 2011 (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-proposes-law-to-reduce-legal-age-of-marriage-for-girls-to-9-6297596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iraq Proposes Law To Reduce Legal Age Of Marriage For Girls To 9]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-proposes-law-to-reduce-legal-age-of-marriage-for-girls-to-9-6297596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:52:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A proposed bill in Iraq's parliament has sparked widespread outrage and concern, as it seeks to reduce the legal age of marriage for girls to just 9 years old.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A proposed bill in Iraq's parliament has sparked widespread outrage and concern, as it seeks to reduce the legal age of marriage for girls to just 9 years old. The controversial legislation, introduced by the Iraq Justice Ministry, aims to amend the country's Personal Status Law, which currently sets the minimum age for marriage at 18.</p>

<p>The bill would allow citizens to choose between religious authorities or the civil judiciary to decide on family affairs. Critics fear this will lead to a slashing of rights in matters of inheritance, divorce, and child custody.</p>

<p>If passed, the bill would allow girls as young as 9 and boys as young as 15 to wed, sparking fears of increased child marriage and exploitation. Critics argue that this regressive move would undermine decades of progress in promoting women's rights and gender equality.</p>

<p>Human rights organizations, women's groups, and civil society activists have vehemently opposed the bill, warning of serious consequences for young girls' education, health, and well-being. They argue that child marriage leads to increased dropout rates, early pregnancies, and a heightened risk of domestic violence.</p>

<p>According to the United Nations children's agency, UNICEF, 28 percent of girls in Iraq are already married before the age of 18.</p>

<p>"Passing this law would show a country moving backward, not forwards," Human Rights Watch (HRW) researcher Sarah Sanbar said.</p>

<p>Amal Kabashi of the Iraq Women's Network also voiced strong opposition, stating that the amendment "provides huge leeway for male dominance over family issues" in an already conservative society.</p>

<p>In late July, parliament withdrew the proposed changes when many lawmakers objected. They resurfaced in an August 4 session after receiving the support of powerful Shia blocs that dominate the chamber.</p>

<p>The proposed changes would mark a shift from the 1959 legislation. This law, enacted after the fall of the Iraqi monarchy, transferred family law authority from religious figures to the state judiciary. The new bill would reintroduce the option to apply religious rules, primarily from Shia and Sunni Islam, but does not mention other religious or sectarian communities within Iraq's diverse population.</p>

<p>Proponents of the bill claim it aims to standardize Islamic law and protect young girls from "immoral relationships." However, opponents counter that this reasoning is flawed and ignores the harsh realities of child marriage.</p>

<p>By giving power over marriage to religious authorities, the amendment would "undermine the principle of equality under Iraqi law," Sanbar of HRW said.</p>

<p>It also "could legalise the marriage of girls as young as nine years old, stealing the futures and well-being of countless girls."</p>

<p>"Girls belong on the playground and in school, not in a wedding dress," she said.</p>

<p>It is still unclear if this bid to change the law will succeed where several earlier attempts have failed.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jgmnhh3g_iraq-women-protest_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pm-sheikh-hasina-will-return-to-bangladesh-for-elections-says-her-son-6297509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina To Return To Bangladesh For Elections, Says Son]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pm-sheikh-hasina-will-return-to-bangladesh-for-elections-says-her-son-6297509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:34:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will return to her country when its new caretaker government decides to hold elections, her son has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will return to her country when its new caretaker government decides to hold elections, her son has said.</p>

<p>Hasina fled to India on Monday after weeks of deadly protests forced her to quit. A caretaker government led by Nobel Peace laureate Muhammad Yunus was sworn in on Thursday, which will be tasked with holding elections.</p>

<p>Speaking to the Times of India, her son Sajeeb Wazed Joy, who is based in the US, said, "For the time being, she (Hasina) is in India. She will go back to Bangladesh the moment the interim government decides to hold an election."</p>

<p>Hasina's Awami League party does not feature in the interim government, following a student-led uprising against the long-time former prime minister whose exit came after nationwide violence killed about 300 people and injured thousands.</p>

<p>She is sheltering in a safe house in the New Delhi area. Indian media has reported that she plans to seek asylum in Britain, but the British Home Office has declined to comment.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said on Thursday he spoke to his British counterpart about Bangladesh but did not share any details.</p>

<p>Joy said that he will not refrain from joining politics if that is needed. "I am sure the Awami League will take part in the election and we might even win," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/81hfi6o_sheikh-hasina_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's party does not feature in the interim government after a student-led uprising (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/criminal-shortage-leads-to-near-empty-prisons-in-this-european-country-6297422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Criminal Shortage Leads To Near-Empty Prisons In This European Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/criminal-shortage-leads-to-near-empty-prisons-in-this-european-country-6297422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:14:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Netherlands faces a unique challenge of underpopulated prisons due to declining crime rates, unlike many countries grappling with overcrowding.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While many countries grapple with overcrowded prisons, the Netherlands faces a unique challenge: too few inmates. Unlike the UK and other nations, the Dutch prison system struggles with empty cells due to low crime rates.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-37904263"><em>BBC report,</em></a> in the past few years, 19 prisons have closed down, and more are slated for closure next year. How has this happened, and why do some people think it's a problem? A decade ago, the Netherlands had one of the highest incarceration rates in Europe, but it now claims one of the lowest.</p>

<p>One empty prison was turned into a fancy hotel south of Amsterdam, with its four most expensive suites named The Lawyer, The Judge, The Governor, and The Jailer. But others, converted into asylum reception centres, have provided work for some former prison guards.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/oct/06/prison-lessons-from-the-netherlands"><em>The Guardian,</em></a> since 2014, 23 prisons have been shut down, turning into temporary asylum centres, housing, and hotels. The country has Europe's third-lowest incarceration rate, at 54.4 per 100,000 inhabitants. According to the justice ministry's WODC Research and Documentation Centre, the number of prison sentences imposed fell from 42,000 in 2008 to 31,000 in 2018, along with a two-thirds drop in jail terms for young offenders. Registered crimes plummeted by 40% in the same period, to 785,000 in 2018.</p>

<p>Miranda Boone, a professor of criminology at Leiden University, has studied the collapse in the prison population. "There is no doubt that the prison population has been reduced very significantly in the last 13 years-an amazing and, in the western world, unparalleled development," she says.</p>

<p>Interestingly, one vacant prison in south of Amsterdam was transformed into a luxury hotel, with its four premium suites aptly named The Lawyer, The Judge, The Governor, and The Jailer. Meanwhile, other empty prisons were repurposed into asylum reception centers, offering employment opportunities to former prison guards. This creative reuse of space reflects the Netherlands' unique approach to addressing its shortage of inmates.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gqiq853g_jails_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Empty jails have been repurposed as asylum centers, providing employment for former guards.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-muhammad-yunus-led-bangladesh-interim-government-who-are-its-key-members-6297421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inside Bangladesh Interim Government: Who Are Its Key Members]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-muhammad-yunus-led-bangladesh-interim-government-who-are-its-key-members-6297421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:13:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus on Thursday took oath as the head of an interim government, days after student-led protests ended the 15-year rule of Sheikh Hasina.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Nobel laureate <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-extends-best-wishes-after-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-as-head-of-interim-bangladesh-government-6294569" target="_blank">Muhammad Yunus</a> on Thursday took oath as the head of an interim government, days after student-led protests ended the 15-year rule of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-his-uk-counterpart-david-lammy-discuss-situation-in-bangladesh-west-asia-6294020#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a>.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old was sworn in as the chief advisor - a position equivalent to prime minister. He swore to "uphold, support and protect the constitution", in front of political and civil society leaders, generals and diplomats at the presidential palace in the capital Dhaka.</p>

<p>More than a dozen members of his cabinet -- given the title of advisers, not ministers -- also took the oath. The caretaker administration is a civilian team, bar one retired brigadier-general.</p>

<h3><strong>Bangladesh Interim Government&nbsp;Members</strong></h3>

<p>A 16-member council of advisers was announced in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bangladeshs-caretaker-leader-muhammad-yunus-economic-thinking-6294710" target="_blank">Muhammad Yunus-led interim government</a>, which will lead the crisis-stricken Bangladesh for a certain period and oversee the election to transition power to an elected government.</p>

<p>Brigadier General (retd) M Sakhawat Hossain, women's rights activist Farida Akhtar, right-wing party Hefazat-e-Islam's deputy chief AFM Khalid Hossain, Grameen Telecom trustee Nurjahan Begum, freedom fighter Sharmeen Murshid, chairman of Chittagong Hill Tracts Development Board Supradip Chakma, Prof Bidhan Ranjan Roy and former foreign secretary Touhid Hossain are also among the advisory council members.</p>

<p>Besides Md Nazrul Islam, Adilur Rahman Khan, AF Hassan Ariff, Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Supradip Chakma and Farooq-e-Azam, the group also included two top leaders of the Students Against Discrimination group that led the weeks-long protests against the Sheikh Hasina government, Nahid Islam and Asif Mahmud,&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Violent Protests In Bangladesh</strong></h3>

<p>The new interim government was formed after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-ahead-of-oath-ceremony-bangladesh-got-second-independence-6291591" target="_blank">Bangladesh witnessed weeks of violence</a> and clashes, forcing Sheikh Hasina, a five-time prime minister, to resign and flee to India on Monday.</p>

<p>Trouble had been brewing in Bangladesh since before the January 7 elections, which was won by Ms Hasina's Awami League in a landslide, but the electoral exercise was widely seen as being far from free and fair.</p>

<p>A fresh wave of protests led by students began in June - in which over 450 people have been killed so far - &nbsp;after a Bangladeshi high court reinstated 30 per cent reservation in government jobs for family members of freedom fighters and veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 War of Independence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The quota was later scaled back by the country's Supreme Court but Ms Hasina's handling of the protests and her alleged use of an offensive label for the protesters infuriated students.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Protests continued with students demanding that Ms Hasina step down and clashes between agitators and the police left over 100 dead and dozens injured across the country on Sunday. A day later, lakhs of students flooded the streets and headed towards the prime minister's official residence, Ganabhaban, forcing Ms Hasina to resign and flee to India.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/bqlfmhv8_muhammad-yunus_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus has been sworn in as chief advisor]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shes-barely-competent-donald-trump-on-kamala-harris-ahead-of-debate-6297328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Is Barely Competent, Says Donald Trump Ahead Of Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shes-barely-competent-donald-trump-on-kamala-harris-ahead-of-debate-6297328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 08:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and Democratic opponent Kamala Harris will debate on Sept. 10 on ABC, setting up the first face-to-face match-up between the rivals in what polls show is a close race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and Democratic opponent Kamala Harris will debate on Sept. 10 on ABC, setting up the first face-to-face match-up between the rivals in what polls show is a close race.</p>

<p>In a news conference at his Palm Beach, Florida, residence, Trump said he wanted additional debates on Sept. 4 and Sept. 25 that would air on Fox and NBC.</p>

<p>Harris said in a post on X that she was looking forward to the Sept. 10 debate after Trump "finally committed."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I hear that Donald Trump has finally committed to debating me on September 10.<br />
<br />
I look forward to it.</p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1821656821662134368?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>She told reporters after a Detroit-area campaign stop that she was open to discussing more debates, but a campaign official reiterated their position that a Sept. 4 Fox debate is off the table.</p>

<p>Discussions on future debates depend on Trump's participation in the Sept. 10 debate on ABC, the official said. The Harris campaign had already opposed a Fox debate, saying the host network should be one that sponsored recent primary debates by both parties.</p>

<p>Trump previously suggested he might back out of the ABC debate, scheduled before Harris, the US vice president, replaced President Joe Biden as the Democratic presidential candidate less than three weeks ago, upending the contest. The Sept. 10 debate on ABC was to be the second of two agreed upon between Biden and Trump, following their June 27 debate on CNN.</p>

<p>An Ipsos poll published on Thursday found Harris has widened her lead over Trump since late July. She leads Trump 42% to 37%, compared with a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey that showed her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>Thursday's Palm Beach news conference was Trump's first public appearance since Harris selected Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as her running mate on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Harris and Walz have headlined rallies in the battleground states of Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin this week, drawing tens of thousands of attendees in a fresh sign of how her late entry into the race has galvanized Democrats. Thursday's stop by the Democratic pair at a union hall came as the campaign said it sees labour groups as a key to tipping the balance in the election.</p>

<p>Harris' rapid rise has sent Trump's team scrambling to recalibrate its strategy and messaging. Opinion polls show Harris has erased the lead Trump had built over Biden, and Democrats have raked in hundreds of millions of dollars from voters and big donors since she became the party's candidate.</p>

<p>Trump insisted on Thursday he has not altered his approach to the race. In a question-and-answer session with reporters that stretched beyond an hour, Trump hopped from topic to topic and said Harris and Walz are weak candidates.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, Trump lamented that he isn't able to face Biden in the Nov. 5 election, suggesting the president was a victim of a plot to dislodge him from atop the Democratic ticket.</p>

<p>Biden dropped his faltering reelection bid under pressure from fellow Democrats worried about his chances of victory after a poor debate performance against Trump.</p>

<p>Asked about his controversial comments last week that Harris, who is of Black and Indian decent, recently "happened to turn Black," Trump said: "You'll have to ask her that question because she's the one that said it, I didn't say it. ... To me, it doesn't matter. But to her, from her standpoint, I think it's very disrespectful to both, really, whether it's Indian or Black, I think it's very disrespectful to both."</p>

<p>Trump's initial comments, delivered to an audience of Black journalists, drew widespread condemnation and left donors and aides baffled and alarmed. The Trump campaign didn't immediately comment further to provide evidence of remarks by Harris that Trump said he was referring to.</p>

<p>Trump on Thursday also mocked the size of Harris' campaign crowds, even though they have matched his of late. He falsely claimed the size of the crowd he addressed on Jan. 6, 2021 - the day his supporters stormed the US Capitol - was as large as those who packed the National Mall in Washington for Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.'s "I Have a Dream" speech in 1963.</p>

<p>"We actually had more people," Trump said. "But I'm ok with it because I liked Dr. Martin Luther King."</p>

<p>King delivered his speech to an estimated 250,000 people in August 1963, according to the National Constitution Center. Trump's rally on Jan. 6, 2021, drew about 53,000 supporters, according to the House of Representatives Select Committee's "187 minutes of dereliction" report.</p>

<p>Echoing a recent attack line from his campaign, Trump criticized Harris for not doing a press interview since launching her campaign.</p>

<p>"She can't do an interview. She's barely competent," Trump said, later again calling her "nasty," a go-to line that he often uses to disparage female critics.</p>

<p>Trump has conducted a steady stream of media interviews, though they are usually with friendly, right-leaning outlets and reporters. On Wednesday, he called into the "Fox &amp; Friends" morning program and took questions from the program's hosts.</p>

<p>Trump announced the Palm Beach news conference on Thursday morning on his social media platform. Only a select group of reporters were given the advance notice needed to travel to his Florida resort in time. Reuters was not extended an invitation.</p>

<p>Harris answered a handful of questions from reporters after meeting with auto workers in Wayne, Michigan, on Thursday, following the United Auto Workers union's endorsement of her candidacy. She said she wants to schedule a sit-down interview "before the end of the month."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kqs5e0o4_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump had previously suggested he might back out of the ABC debate (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-suspect-pakistani-spy-agency-isi-incited-protests-in-bangladesh-sheikh-hasinas-son-6291041]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Sheikh Hasina's Son Said When Asked If She'll Return To Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-suspect-pakistani-spy-agency-isi-incited-protests-in-bangladesh-sheikh-hasinas-son-6291041]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 08:43:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh went into a tailspin after nationwide protests over job quota flared up. Following the agitation, Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh's Prime Minister and fled the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh went into a tailspin after nationwide protests over job quota flared up. Following the agitation, Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh's Prime Minister and fled the country.</p>

<p>In an exclusive interview, the former Prime Minister's son, Sajeeb Wazed, told news agency IANS that the protests went out of hand as some groups kept inciting the demonstrators and he suspects the involvement of Pakistan's ISI or Western groups in it.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What is your take on the current situation in Bangladesh?</strong></p>

<p>A: Our government had removed the quota two to three years ago, but the families of freedom fighters reached court. That's why the protests started. Initially, it was a minor protest, but, I think all along Western groups kept inciting it. We wanted a peaceful resolution. We wanted the judicial committee to resolve the problem, and investigate, and we suspended police officers.</p>

<p>But, I think there was some group that kept inciting the protesters. Ultimately, the protests turned violent and it became an issue of my mother's safety. They were marching on the Prime Minister's residence. My mother didn't want to leave the country even at the last minute. She went to the military air base and she told her sister that she didn't wish to leave. But, I talked to her and convinced her to leave. I told her 'leave because they will kill you.' So, this is the situation in Bangladesh. This situation was escalated deliberately. First of all, there was no reason for the protests as it was not the decision of our government. It was the decision of the courts. Our government was appealing against the decision of the courts.</p>

<p>The protest was peaceful at the start, but on the night of July 15, someone started marching at Dhaka University chanting 'We are Razakars.' They started saying that my mother had called students 'Razakars' but she didn't say this.</p>

<p>The students got angry and started protesting and police used excessive force to stop them. Our government immediately suspended those police officers. Our government formed a judicial team to investigate. But, the whole incident was designed to flare up. The protest escalated and they demanded the resignation of the Prime Minister. Many of the protesters had firearms. They attacked police stations with guns. From where did they get the guns?</p>

<p><strong>Q: Reports suggest that whatever is happening in Bangladesh is because of the US, China, and Pakistan. Do you agree?</strong></p>

<p>A: I don't think China is involved in this as it has never been involved in our internal matters. We were friends with every country. With China and India, we had good relations. We consider India our best friend. The US also had good relations but Pakistan (ISI) was always against the independence of Bangladesh. We fought for independence from them. So, I suspect that ISI was involved in inciting protests.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Is it true that the Army Chief had given an ultimatum to Sheikh Hasina to leave the country within 45 minutes?</strong></p>

<p>A: That's not true. They met, and I was there with my mother before and after the meeting. There was no ultimatum from the Army Chief. My mother had ordered the police and military not to kill the protesters. When they started demonstrating, the military barricaded Dhaka city. So, at the time when the protesters were marching, the military took my mother to safety. So, the allegations are completely false.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Sheikh Hasina was giving a speech to the nation and in the middle of it she had to stop as the protesters were marching towards her residence. What do you want to say about this?</strong></p>

<p>A: No, she was planning to resign. She told me that she didn't want bloodshed anymore. She would resign, make a statement, and arrange for a peaceful transfer of power as per the Constitution. But, unfortunately, the protesters declared their march on the Prime Minister's residence. She didn't have time to make a statement or speech.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus will be the chief of the interim government. What are your comments on this?</strong></p>

<p>A: Unfortunately, the whole situation is unconstitutional. There is no constitutional provision for an interim government. In fact, our Supreme Court has ruled that any unconstitutional situation has to be dealt with but you cannot fulfill all the demands of protesters. It has to happen within the Constitution. However, nothing matters, as there is no law and order in the country now. Riots, looting, and vandalism are going on throughout the city. There is a little bit of security in Dhaka city as the military is deployed there. But, outside Dhaka, if you look at social media, there is complete anarchy. There is no police and there is no law and order. I am waiting to see how an interim government is going to control this because an interim government cannot bring law and order. Then Bangladesh will become Afghanistan.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Muhammad Yunus said that this is the second liberation day of Bangladesh, the first was in 1971. Your comments?</strong></p>

<p>A: He is talking about liberation from whom? Riots? Vandalism or anarchy? Is this freedom for Bangladesh? If this is the freedom that he thinks Bangladesh wants, then that's fine. Good luck to them. People are dying. There is no law and order in the country. There is looting. Everyone is being looted. That's freedom!</p>

<p><strong>Q: Yunus is claiming that students will get jobs, as they were not getting them due to reservation.</strong></p>

<p>A: Well, that's fine, let him take over. Let him prove it. We will see the results soon.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What is the future of Bangladesh now?</strong></p>

<p>A: Well, today Bangladesh looks like Syria or Afghanistan. There is no law and order. After this, it's up to Mr Yunus' government, if they think they can control it. Maybe we will have democracy again. If they can't, then Bangladesh will become like Afghanistan.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Will Sheikh Hasina return to Bangladesh?</strong></p>

<p>A: She will return as my mother loves Bangladesh. It is her country and she will definitely return when the situation is in control.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What is your message via our platform?</strong></p>

<p>A: I want to see a democratic Bangladesh soon. I want India to use its powers to ensure free and fair elections in Bangladesh.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What's your take on minorities being killed in Bangladesh?</strong></p>

<p>A: Our government wants the safety of minorities of Bangladesh as we believe they are also our voters. The BNP should leave Jamaat-e-Islami. They have to accept that we have minorities in Bangladesh. If they cannot accept this and if they come to power, the minorities in Bangladesh will never be safe.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Why did the protests not stop after the Supreme Court's order?</strong></p>

<p>A: Exactly, that is my point. I am sure someone is provoking all this, even after the Supreme Court's order, they didn't stop. Despite all efforts to control the situation in Bangladesh, they wanted my mother's resignation. That means it was pre-planned.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gnshs24c_sheikh-hasina-son-sajeeb-wazed_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's son Sajeeb Wazed suspects the involvement of Pakistan's ISI.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/argentina-money-heist-metal-rod-foils-repetition-of-argentinas-heist-of-the-century-6297249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Metal Rod Foils Repetition of Argentina's 'Heist Of The Century']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/argentina-money-heist-metal-rod-foils-repetition-of-argentinas-heist-of-the-century-6297249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 08:37:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It could have been a new heist of the century -- if it hadn't been for a metal rod popping up in the middle of a cobblestone street.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It could have been a new heist of the century -- if it hadn't been for a metal rod popping up in the middle of a cobblestone street.</p>

<p>Authorities in San Isidro, Argentina -- the location of the fabled 2006 "heist of the century" -- announced Thursday that they had prevented a repeat crime.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, a parked driver heard a noise in the chassis of his car that turned out to be caused by the rod emerging from the street surface.</p>

<p>After police arrived at the scene on the northern outskirts of Buenos Aires, an excavation found a tunnel beginning in a warehouse about 220 meters from a branch of Macro Bank.</p>

<p>Large amounts of earth had been moved and extraction machines were discovered.</p>

<p>The tunnel was lined with wood, had ventilation and electric light, and ended almost at the door of the bank, according to police. So far, police have not found the would-be robbers.</p>

<p>Investigators said construction took between six and nine months and called the tunnel an engineering feat "better than the one El Chapo Guzman" used to escape from prison in 2015 in Mexico.</p>

<p>The incident was reminiscent of the so-called "heist of the century," which took place in 2006 in the same upmarket town, when criminals, with meticulous planning, stole nearly $19 million from a bank and escaped through a tunnel.</p>

<p>In that robbery, which spawned books, TV series and films, the robbers used toy weapons and left a note in the vault that read "In a neighbourhood of rich people, with no weapons or grudges, it's just money."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cjndsbfg_argentina-heist-afp-_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tunnel had ventilation and electric light, and ended almost at the door of the bank, said the police.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rising-whooping-cough-cases-in-the-uk-lead-to-tenth-child-death-6297111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rising Whooping Cough Cases In The UK Lead To Tenth Child Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rising-whooping-cough-cases-in-the-uk-lead-to-tenth-child-death-6297111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:58:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The outbreak is part of a global resurgence of the disease, which has seen cases and deaths in countries like China, the Philippines, the Czech Republic, and the Netherlands.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another baby has died from an infection of whooping cough, bringing the total number of deaths of infants in England since the outbreak began to 10, officials at the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) said.</p>

<p>This death coincides with recent UKHSA data showing that confirmed laboratory cases of whooping cough in England topped 10,000 in this year. While most cases are in people aged 15 or older, more than 300 have been in babies under three months - the most at-risk group from the infection.</p>

<p>It is believed that the outbreak started in England last November, and 10 infant deaths have now been confirmed. The first death was reported in December 2023, and the rest occurred between January and June 2024.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-whooping-cough-outbreak-spreads-globally-heres-all-you-need-to-know-5418315"><em>Bloomberg report,</em></a> Whooping cough is making a comeback in several parts of the world, with deaths reported in China, the Philippines, Czech Republic and the Netherlands, and outbreaks in countries including the US and UK.</p>

<h3><strong>What is whooping cough?</strong></h3>

<p>The highly-contagious disease is caused by the bacterium Bordetella pertussis, which targets the upper respiratory system, releasing toxins which can cause the airways to swell, according to the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</p>

<h3><strong>What are the symptoms?</strong></h3>

<p>Early symptoms of whooping cough look very much like the common cold - with a stuffy nose, low-grade fever and a mild cough often reported. That makes it difficult to diagnose until more severe symptoms emerge.</p>

<p>After a week or two symptoms can progress to "rapid, violent, and uncontrolled coughing fits," according to the CDC, accompanied by a high-pitched "whoop" sound upon inhalation at the end of the fit. Coughing fits can go on for up to 10 weeks.</p>

<h3><strong>Who is most at risk?</strong></h3>

<p>Children are more likely to suffer the most violent symptoms of whooping cough, while babies don't usually cough but can stop breathing. Teenagers and adults often exhibit more mild symptoms, but even then, debilitating coughing fits can keep them up at night. One complicating factor is that adults with no obvious signs of the disease can continue to spread the infection.</p>

<h3><strong>How do you treat it?</strong></h3>

<p>Once diagnosed, preferably before coughing begins, doctors will generally treat the infection with antibiotics. If a patient has been coughing for more than three weeks, antibiotics are not required as the bacteria has likely left the body and the coughing is a result of damage done to the airways.</p>

<h3><strong>Is there a whooping cough vaccine?</strong></h3>

<p>In China, free vaccines are usually given in a combined shot that also protects infants against diphtheria and tetanus. In the US there are two vaccines available - one for children under the age of seven, and one for people older than seven. In the UK, shots are routinely given to babies, while the Philippines has warned of a potential shortage in supply by May.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4mgtf2u8_whooping-cough_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Whooping cough is a highly contagious disease.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-doesnt-support-israel-arms-embargo-says-top-aide-6296769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Doesn't Support Israel Arms Embargo, Says Top Aide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-doesnt-support-israel-arms-embargo-says-top-aide-6296769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:02:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris does not support an arms embargo on US ally Israel, a top aide said Thursday, in one of the first substantive statements on her Gaza war policy since her July entry to the 2024 White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris does not support an arms embargo on US ally Israel, a top aide said Thursday, in one of the first substantive statements on her Gaza war policy since her July entry to the 2024 White House race.</p>

<p>The comment came a day after the US vice president was heckled by pro-Palestinian protesters at a rally for the first time since she became the Democratic candidate less than three weeks ago.</p>

<p>Harris also met with groups opposed to the war after the rally in Detroit, Michigan. Participants reportedly said they brought up the issue of halting US arms supplies to Israel.</p>

<p>"She does not support an arms embargo on Israel," Harris's national security advisor Phil Gordon said on X.</p>

<p>He added that the vice president "has been clear: she will always ensure Israel is able to defend itself against Iran and Iran-backed terrorist groups."</p>

<p>Harris faces pressure from the left wing of the Democratic party to change course from President Joe Biden's strong military and political support for Israel's war in Gaza since the October 7 attacks by Hamas.</p>

<p>The issue is also critical in Michigan, a battleground state in November's election with a large population of Arab Americans who are vocally opposed to the war.</p>

<p>In Detroit on Wednesday, Harris found herself repeatedly interrupted by Gaza protesters.</p>

<p>"If you want Donald Trump to win, then say that. Otherwise, I'm speaking," she said, her expression hardening as she sought to quell the disruptions.</p>

<p>Harris will also be keen not to alienate the majority of US voters whom polls say support Israel.</p>

<p>As vice president, Harris has sometimes been more critical than Biden of the civilian casualties caused by Israel's offensive in Gaza.</p>

<p>Harris then made a major shift in tone after Biden dropped out of the 2024 election, saying in a strongly worded statement after she met Israeli premier Benjamin Netanyahu that she would "not be silent" on the situation.</p>

<p>But the comments by Harris's adviser appeared to make it clear she would not go as far as endorsing any kind of all-out pause in arms transfers.</p>

<p>Under Biden, the White House has only halted the delivery of a single shipment of heavy bombs to Israel over concerns about how they would be used.</p>

<p>On Wednesday in Detroit, Harris and her new running mate Tim Walz briefly met the leaders of the "Uncommitted" group that mobilized people to cast protest votes against Biden in this year's Democratic primary, US media reported.</p>

<p>Its founders told the New York Times that they had asked Harris for a full meeting to discuss their calls for an embargo, and Harris told them she was open to a meeting.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/f31c6agc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will also be keen not to alienate the majority of US voters whom polls say support Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-agrees-to-resume-gaza-truce-talks-on-august-15-6296739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Agrees To Resume Gaza Truce Talks On August 15]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-agrees-to-resume-gaza-truce-talks-on-august-15-6296739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 05:51:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has agreed to resume Gaza ceasefire talks on August 15 at the demand of US, Qatari and Egyptian mediators, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said on Thursday, as regional tensions skyrocket over the war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has agreed to resume Gaza ceasefire talks on August 15 at the demand of US, Qatari and Egyptian mediators, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said on Thursday, as regional tensions skyrocket over the war.</p>

<p>Gaza's Hamas-controlled civil defence agency said Israeli bombardment killed more than 18 people in strikes on two schools on Thursday, as Iran accused Israel of wanting to spread war in the Middle East.</p>

<p>After a week-long pause in November, US, Qatari and Egyptian mediators have endeavoured to secure a second truce in the 10-month-old war sparked by Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>In a joint statement on Thursday, the three countries' leaders invited the warring parties to resume talks on August 15 in Doha or Cairo "to close all remaining gaps and commence implementation of the deal without further delay".</p>

<p>A framework agreement was "now on the table, with only the details of implementation" left to conclude, and the mediators were "prepared to present a final bridging proposal" to resolve remaining issues, they said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's office said later Thursday Israel would send a negotiating team on August 15 "to the agreed place to conclude the details of implementing a deal".</p>

<p>A prospective cessation of hostilities also involving the release of hostages held in Gaza and scaled-up aid deliveries has centred around a phased deal beginning with an initial truce.</p>

<p>Recent discussions have focused on a framework outlined by US President Joe Biden in late May which he said had been proposed by Israel.</p>

<p>"It's not like the agreement's going to be ready to sign on Thursday. There's still a significant amount of work to do," a senior Biden administration official said of the talks that come after calls between Biden and the Egyptian and Qatari leaders this week.</p>

<p>Israel had been "very receptive" to the idea of the talks, the official told reporters on condition of anonymity, rejecting suggestions that Netanyahu was stalling on a deal.</p>

<p>The announcement of the talks came after Hamas named Yahya Sinwar -- the alleged mastermind of the October 7 attack -- as its new leader, sparking fears the torturous negotiations have become even more difficult.</p>

<p>- 'Strategic mistake' -<br />
On the ground in Gaza, the Hamas-controlled civil defence agency said Israeli strikes hit Al-Zahra and Abdel Fattah Hamoud schools in Gaza City, killing more than 18 people.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Senior agency official Mohammad al-Mughayyir said 60 people were wounded and more than 40 still missing.</p>

<p>"This is a clear targeting of schools and safe civilian facilities in the Gaza Strip," he said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the schools housed Hamas command centres.</p>

<p>At least 13 people were killed elsewhere in Gaza, rescuers and medics reported, as the Israeli military issued its latest evacuation order, for parts of the main southern city of Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>Diplomats pressed efforts to defuse tensions in the region, sky-high after the killing of two top militant leaders in attacks blamed on Israel that the militants and their Iranian backers have vowed to avenge.</p>

<p>Iran's acting foreign minister, Ali Bagheri, told AFP that Israel had committed "a strategic mistake" by killing Hamas's political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week -- hours after the assassination in Beirut of Hezbollah's military chief.</p>

<p>Although Israel has not admitted to killing Haniyeh, Iran and its allies have vowed to retaliate.</p>

<p>Israel seeks "to expand tension, war and conflict to other countries", but has neither "the capacity nor the strength" to fight Iran, Bagheri said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, speaking at a military base on Wednesday, said Israel was "prepared both defensively and offensively" and "determined" to defend itself.</p>

<p>- 'Cycle of reprisals' -<br />
Officials in the Middle East and beyond have called for calm, with Britain's minister for international development, Anneliese Dodds, telling AFP on a visit to Jordan: "We must see a de-escalation."</p>

<p>The United States, which has sent extra warships and jets to the region, has urged both Iran and Israel to avoid an escalation.</p>

<p>France's President Emmanuel Macron spoke Wednesday with his Iranian counterpart Masoud Pezeshkian and later with Israel's Netanyahu, telling both to "avoid a cycle of reprisals", according to the French presidency.</p>

<p>The Israel-Hamas war in the Gaza Strip has already drawn in Tehran-aligned militants in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Lebanese Hamas ally Hezbollah, which has traded near-daily cross-border fire with Israeli troops throughout the Gaza war, has vowed retaliation for military chief Fuad Shukr's killing.</p>

<p>- Israel PM 'sorry' -&nbsp;<br />
The unprecedented Hamas attack that triggered the war in Gaza resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,699 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, who has resisted making an apology for security failures over Israel's worst-ever attack, said in an interview published Thursday that he was "sorry, deeply, that something like this happened".</p>

<p>"You always look back and you say, 'Could we have done things that would have prevented it?'" Netanyahu told Time magazine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/i85alm98_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu's office said Thursday Israel would send a negotiating team on August 15 for Gaza peace talks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-blocks-social-media-platform-x-for-10-days-in-country-6296687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Venezuela President Blocks Social Media Platform X For 10 Days In Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-blocks-social-media-platform-x-for-10-days-in-country-6296687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 05:37:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, who has claimed reelection following a disputed vote, said Thursday that social media platform X would be blocked in the country for 10 days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, who has claimed reelection following a disputed vote, said Thursday that social media platform X would be blocked in the country for 10 days.</p>

<p>The state agency in charge of telecommunications will "remove the social network X, formerly known as Twitter, from circulation in Venezuela for 10 days," Maduro said, after previously accusing the site's owner Elon Musk of an "attack" against his reelection.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-03/president-nicolas-maduro_650x400_41426377989.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nicolas Maduro had accused Elon Musk of an "attack" against his reelection.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-5-points-in-latest-survey-6296461]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Leads Trump By 5 Points In Latest Poll Survey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-5-points-in-latest-survey-6296461]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 04:10:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>The nationwide poll of 2,045 U.S. adults, conducted Aug. 2-7, found 4% of those surveyed backed independent candidate Robert Kennedy Jr., down from 10% in July.</p>

<p>Ipsos conducted the August poll independently from Reuters. The poll, conducted online, had a margin of error of around 3 percentage points.</p>

<p>Harris entered the race on July 21 when President Joe Biden, 81, folded his campaign and endorsed Harris following a disastrous debate performance on June 27 against Trump.</p>

<p>Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>The nationwide poll of 2,045 U.S. adults, conducted Aug. 2-7, found 4% of those surveyed backed independent candidate Robert Kennedy Jr., down from 10% in July.</p>

<p>Ipsos conducted the August poll independently from Reuters. The poll, conducted online, had a margin of error of around 3 percentage points.</p>

<p>Harris entered the race on July 21 when President Joe Biden, 81, folded his campaign and endorsed Harris following a disastrous debate performance on June 27 against Trump.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/jhmacdl_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_19_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>