<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 11:59:40 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/thesis-linking-body-odor-with-racism-goes-viral-internet-reacts-7146062]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thesis Linking Body Odor With Racism Goes Viral. Internet Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/thesis-linking-body-odor-with-racism-goes-viral-internet-reacts-7146062]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 11:59:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the post went viral, users questioned OP for spending time and money, researching a topic that may not have any real-life implications.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A social media user recently took to X (formerly Twitter) to share they had completed their doctorate by presenting the dissertation and acing the "viva with no corrections". While the news of acquiring a PhD would have been fairly innocuous and not invited much traction, the post instead went viral due to the choice of thesis topic by the OP. Dr Ally Louks, the X user, who claims to be teaching at the University of Cambridge, revealed that her thesis topic was "Olfactory Ethics: The Politics of Smell in Modern and Contemporary Prose", which instantly grabbed the internet's attention.</p>

<p>"Thrilled to say I passed my viva with no corrections and am officially PhDone," Dr Louks captioned the post whilst posing with her dissertation. She also shared the abstract of her research to provide "more context for anyone interested in learning" about her work.</p>

<p>"This thesis studies how literature registers the importance of olfactory discourse-the language of smell and the olfactory imagination it creates in structuring our social world," read the brief.</p>

<p>"The broad aim of this thesis is to offer an intersectional and wide-ranging study of olfactory oppression by establishing the underlying logics that facilitate smell's application in creating and subverting gender, class, sexual, racial and species power structures," it added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thrilled to say I passed my viva with no corrections and am officially PhDone. <a href="https://t.co/4qwCyFYocX">pic.twitter.com/4qwCyFYocX</a></p>
— Dr Ally Louks (@DrAllyLouks) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrAllyLouks/status/1861872149373297078?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Chapter one of the thesis explored how "smell can be used to indicate class antipathies, partly as they relate to homelessness", by examining George Orwell's work as well as other popular media creations.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-phd-student-alleges-forcible-transfer-to-master-s-course-at-oxford-university-6876916" rel="noindex, nofollow">Also Read | "Feeling Betrayed": Indian PhD Student Moved To Master's Course At Oxford</a></strong></p>

<h3><strong>Internet reacts</strong></h3>

<p>As the post went viral, thousands of users descended on Dr Louks' profile and questioned her for spending time and money, researching a topic that may not have any real-life implications.</p>

<p>"For those of you who can't translate this academic gobbledygook, let me be your guide: sis literally wrote a PhD thesis on why it's racist and/or classist to not like it when people stink," wrote one user, while another added: "How did this dissertation get accepted? It provides nothing of value, and really only sets this woman up to exploit students for their loans...or an email job somewhere.</p>

<p>A third commented: "Tax money well spent. Good luck with the debt."</p>

<p>While the majority of users criticised the OP for her post, some came to her defence, with one stating: "People are being so mean to this woman for no reason. Some people just want to study books, that's not a crime."</p>

<p>"That looks like a super interesting piece of research. I can see people being straight up cruel in replies and quotes and most of them are the usual suspects- racists, misogynists and people who would rather have all education be like trade school," another added.</p>

<p>As of the last update, the post had garnered 3.2 million views and over 2,000 comments.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/302i3n98_dr_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Ally Louks posing with her dissertation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-museum-invites-public-to-visit-art-exhibition-naked-heres-why-7145843]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Museum Invites Public To Visit Art Exhibition Naked, Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-museum-invites-public-to-visit-art-exhibition-naked-heres-why-7145843]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 11:15:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The collection, comprising 600 pieces from both public and private collections, offers a rich exploration of the history and cultural significance of naturism.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Marseille Museum of European and Mediterranean Civilisations (Mucem) is currently exhibiting a comprehensive collection of artworks exploring the theme of naturism. In a novel approach to audience engagement, the museum invites visitors to view the exhibition naked, facilitating a more intimate and visceral experience of the artworks. The collection, comprising 600 pieces from both public and private collections, offers a rich exploration of the history and cultural significance of naturism.</p>

<p>"France is the world's leading tourist destination for naturists: its temperate climate and the presence of three seas have facilitated the establishment of communities, which - with the exception of Switzerland - have few real equivalents elsewhere in Europe, where naturism is practised more freely, outside established communities," the museum told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/27/arts/design/naturism-exhibition-naked-mucem-marseille.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>New York Times</em></a>.</p>

<p>"Today, there is a new craze for nudity in nature, a craze that goes hand in hand with the quest for healthy, vegetarian diets and the use of natural therapies, meditation and yoga in the open air. These lifestyles, along with the rejection of the diktats that weigh down our bodies, are all keys to understanding the issues at stake in the naturism of yesterday and today."</p>

<p>Since opening in July, the museum's exhibition has attracted nearly 100,000 visitors, with around 600 attending five special viewings in the nude. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Some participants were seasoned naturists, distinguishable by their tan-line-free and often weathered appearances. Others, however, had little to no experience being nude in public, apart from the occasional skinny dip. For these individuals, nudity was typically limited to locker rooms or intimate settings. Attending the exhibit in the nude offered a unique opportunity to engage with art and their own bodies in a new way-promoting a sense of acceptance or, perhaps, neutrality.</p>

<p>Naked museum events aren't entirely new. Similar gatherings have taken place in cities like Paris, Vienna, Montreal, Barcelona, Milan, and even Dorchester in England. However, Mucem may be the first major museum to dedicate an entire exhibition to the history, culture, and symbolism of naturism-a movement akin to nudism but rooted in principles of self-respect, respect for others, and harmony with the natural world.</p>

<p>"I always say that nudity is a tool - a very effective tool - to get people to achieve body acceptance," said Stephane Deschenes, the president of the International Naturist Federation. "But it's not the objective."</p>

<p>The exhibit, Naturist Paradises, chronicles the evolution of naturism in Europe over the past century. It begins with its origins as a groundbreaking social health movement and explores its modern alignment with the body positivity movement. The exhibition features an array of artefacts, including vintage magazine covers, black-and-white photographs, archival videos, paintings, and informative text displays.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jq1skppg_french-museum-_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Naked museum events arent entirely new]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cheryl-hines-invites-backlash-for-posting-video-of-husband-rfk-jr-showering-7145691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cheryl Hines Faces Backlash For Posting Clip Of Husband RFK Jr. Taking Shower]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cheryl-hines-invites-backlash-for-posting-video-of-husband-rfk-jr-showering-7145691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 10:39:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The video did not go down well with social media users who called out Cheryl Hines for being a 'grifter'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Robert F. Kennedy Jr.'s actress wife Cheryl Hines is facing flak online after she posted a video of her hubby showering partially naked while filming a video for her beauty line in the couple's bathroom. RFK Jr., the nominee for President-elect Donald Trump's Health and Human Services department, appeared oblivious as the "Curb Your Enthusiasm" star tried to plug her Hines &amp; Young line, which she founded with daughter Catherin. Though the post was meant to be a promotional strategy, it backfired as social media users called her out for the 'cringy video'.</p>

<p>Captioning her post on Instagram as "H+Y content interruption", Ms Hines said, "You [RFK Jr.] can't take a shower, I'm doing a video! No, no, no, I'm doing a...you've gotta give me a second I'm doing a video for Hines+Young. Honey... 60% off."</p>

<p>She added "Oh Bobby" as a caption, followed by heart and smiley face emojis.</p>

<p>In a follow-up post, Ms Hines also included a still photo of products from her line, including a MAHA candle, apparently referencing her husband's "Make America Healthy Again" campaign.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Cheryl Hines posts video of RFK Jr in the shower to promote her line of “MAHA” branded candles, body sprays, and creams. <a href="https://t.co/jd4DwQFOmL">pic.twitter.com/jd4DwQFOmL</a></p>
— PatriotTakes ?? (@patriottakes) <a href="https://twitter.com/patriottakes/status/1862654092058747103?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<h3><strong>Social media reacts</strong></h3>

<p>The video and Ms Hines' attempt at promoting her brand at the cost of RFK Jr. did not go down well with social media users who called out the actress for being a 'grifter'.</p>

<p>"This is one of the cringiest things I've ever seen...lost all respect for Cheryl Hines," said one user while another added: "Lame. Very lame. Maybe don't follow your husband into the bathroom while he showers to do an advertisement, if you're going to complain about him taking a shower in the bathroom while you're doing an advertisement."</p>

<p>A third commented: "Jesus, gotta give them credit, they are the most consistent grifters in history."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-grabbed-reporter-olivia-nuzzis-hand-before-sexting-scandal-report-6660199" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Robert Kennedy Jr "Grabbed" Reporter's Hand Before Scandal: Report</strong></a></p>

<p>While most criticised the video, some said it was an attempt by Ms Hines to show that the couple were as strong as ever after it was revealed that RFK Jr. had a "digital affair" with journalist Olivia Nuzzi. The pair allegedly began communicating after the publication of Nuzzi's profile on Kennedy in<em> New York Magazine.</em> The publication and Ms Nuzzi have since parted ways.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6hk6abto_bobby_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Screengrab of the video shared by Cheryl Hines.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rashid-khalidi-s-son-blasts-biden-blood-soaked-hands-don-t-belong-on-father-s-book-7145596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Genocidal Maniac": Author's Son After Biden Pictured With Father's Book]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rashid-khalidi-s-son-blasts-biden-blood-soaked-hands-don-t-belong-on-father-s-book-7145596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 10:37:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ismail Khalidi, son of Columbia University professor emeritus Rashid Khalidi, has labelled US President Joe Biden a "genocidal maniac" after the latter was spotted holding a copy of his father's book, 'The Hundred Years' War on Palestine'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ismail Khalidi, son of Columbia University professor emeritus Rashid Khalidi, has labelled US President Joe Biden a “genocidal maniac” after the latter was spotted holding a copy of his father's book, '<em>The Hundred Years' War on Palestine'</em>.</p>

<p>President Biden, currently wrapping up his term, drew attention during a Black Friday outing in Nantucket when he was photographed carrying the book. The choice of reading material surprised many, given Biden's long-standing pro-Israel stance.&nbsp;Rashid Khalidi, a prominent scholar of Palestinian and Lebanese descent, reacted to the unexpected publicity, calling it <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-buys-book-on-israels-settler-colonial-conquest-palestinian-author-reacts-7139154 ">“four years too late.”</a> The author, whose work critiques US foreign policy and frames the establishment of Israel as a “settler-colonial conquest,” seemed skeptical about Biden's sudden interest in his work.</p>

<p>His son, Ismail, took a harsher tone. In a post on X, he lashed out at Biden, writing, “Hey, [Joe Biden], get my father's book out of your blood-soaked hands, you genocidal maniac.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hey, <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JoeBiden</a>, get my father's book out of your blood soaked hands, you genocidal maniac. <a href="https://t.co/Ud9vsVhRU3">https://t.co/Ud9vsVhRU3</a></p>
— Ismail Khalidi (@IsmailKhalidi) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsmailKhalidi/status/1862659766427820535?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Published in 2020, '<em>The Hundred Years' War on Palestine'</em> critiques Israeli policies and staunch US support for the state, describing the conflict as a prolonged colonial struggle. Rashid Khalidi, a vocal critic of US-Israel relations, labelled the Israeli government under Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu as “the most extreme” in the country's history. He also criticised the Donald Trump administration in his book, calling it a “mouthpiece for Israel.”</p>

<p>The book advocates for justice and equality for Palestinians, proposing that peace can only be achieved by dismantling systemic oppression. It talks about the historical narrative of Palestinian resistance and highlights discriminatory policies against Palestinians, including Muslims and Christians.</p>

<p>The book outlines three potential outcomes for settler-colonial conflicts – the full subjugation of Indigenous populations, the expulsion of colonisers, or compromise and reconciliation.</p>

<p>The book's nuanced examination of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict has drawn both praise and criticism, making Biden's public endorsement – intentional or not – all the more surprising.</p>

<p>Joe Biden has often described himself as a Zionist, declaring famously, “You don't have to be a Jew to be a Zionist. <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-a-zionist-how-bidens-lifelong-bond-with-israel-shapes-war-policy-4503653 ">I am a Zionist</a>.” His administration, while providing military aid to Israel, has faced backlash for its handling of the ongoing war in Gaza and perceived complicity in Palestinian suffering. Protests have erupted across the US, with demonstrators branding him “Genocide Joe” for his perceived failure to check Israeli military actions.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Biden paused shipments of heavy munitions to Israel amid rising tensions, but he also visited the country in solidarity after the October 2023 attacks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ca30ih4o_biden-khalid-rashidi-_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The book advocates for justice and equality for Palestinians.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-spiritual-leaders-arrest-being-misconstrued-bangladesh-to-un-forum-7145634]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hindu Spiritual Leader's Arrest Being 'Misconstrued': Bangladesh To UN Forum]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-spiritual-leaders-arrest-being-misconstrued-bangladesh-to-un-forum-7145634]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 10:21:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The arrest of a Hindu leader in Dhaka has been "misconstrued" and he was arrested on specific charges, Bangladesh has told a UN forum on minority issues, claiming that there has been no systematic attack on minorities in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The arrest of a Hindu leader in Dhaka has been "misconstrued" and he was arrested on specific charges, Bangladesh has told a UN forum on minority issues, claiming that there has been no systematic attack on minorities in the country.</p>

<p>Hindu priest Chinmoy Krishna Das, a former member of International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON), was arrested from Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday. He was denied bail and sent to jail by the Chattogram's Sixth Metropolitan Magistrate court in a sedition case on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"With utter dismay, we note that the arrest of Chinmoy Das has been misconstrued by some speakers, although he was actually arrested on specific charges. The matter is being dealt with by our court of law," Ambassador and Permanent Representative of Bangladesh to the UN Offices and other international organisations in Geneva Tareq Md Ariful Islam said.</p>

<p>Islam made the statement during the 17th session of the Forum on Minorities Issues that took place in Geneva on November 28-29.</p>

<p>After Das, the leader of the Hindu group Sammilita Sanatani Jote, was sent to prison, it triggered protests by Hindus in various locations, including the capital Dhaka and the port city of Chattogram.</p>

<p>India has noted the developments with deep concern even as a diplomatic row has erupted between the two South Asian neighbours.</p>

<p>During the session, some Bangladeshi NGOs and individuals spoke about the situation in the country. A representative of the International Forum for Secular Bangladesh (IFSB) said that the situation right now in the country is "very alarming" and a "very burning issue." Referring to Das' arrest, the representative said that ISKCON is a very popular and peaceful organisation but the former ISKCON leader has been arrested with "nothing accused against him. He was arrested three days before in Dhaka and now Bangladesh every day .... the police, army ... every day, they are torturing the minority."</p>

<p>Islam said that Bangladesh reaffirms that every Bangladeshi, regardless of religious identity, has the right to practice their respective religion or express views freely. "Ensuring safety and security of every citizen, including from the minority community, remains the cornerstone of the interim government of Bangladesh," Islam said.</p>

<p>"This has been repeatedly reassured to minority religious leaders by our top leadership, and proved time and again in the first 100 days" of the interim government led by the Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus, he added.</p>

<p>The post August 5 violence in Bangladesh was rooted in political and personal factors, not sectarian, he noted. "The violence affected people, mostly with partisan political affiliations, almost all of them being Muslims, and only a few from other religious minority groups." Deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina fled to India on August 5 following widespread protests against her Awami League-led government over a controversial job quota system. Three days later, Yunus, a Nobel laureate, took over as the Chief Adviser of the interim government.</p>

<p>Ariful Islam said that "there was no systematic attack on minorities" and following the mass uprising in July, the world witnessed "how the entire society of Bangladesh came forward to protect its minorities." He added that "unfortunately" there have been "a fiery of exaggerated, unfounded and fake reports and deliberate spread of misinformation and disinformation by vested quarters regarding minority persecution. Sadly, we saw it happening at this forum too." He said the Bangladeshi government "remains vigilant and will continue to act promptly to maintain religious harmony at any cost and thwart any attempt to undermine rights of minorities." Following this week's anti-Hindu incidents -- including Das' arrest and attacks on Hindu temples and community members -- India on Friday said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus as well as attacks on temples.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told Parliament that India has taken serious note of incidents of violence against minorities in Bangladesh and that it is the primary responsibility of Dhaka to protect the life and liberty of all the citizens, including minorities.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Bangladesh on Friday expressed deep concern over the violent protest at the Deputy High Commission in Kolkata and urged New Delhi to ensure the safety of all its diplomatic missions in India.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6khpcn04_isckon-priest-chinmoy-krishna-das-twitter_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hindu priest Chinmoy Krishna Das was arrested in asedition case.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-central-kitchen-member-among-2-killed-in-israeli-airstrikes-on-gaza-7145553]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Central Kitchen Member Among 2 Aid Workers Killed In Gaza Airstrikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-central-kitchen-member-among-2-killed-in-israeli-airstrikes-on-gaza-7145553]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 10:05:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two aid workers were killed in Israeli airstrikes in Gaza on Saturday, with Israel saying it had killed an operative who took part in the October 7, 2023 Hamas attacks on Israel and who it said was employed by a US-based charity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two aid workers were killed in Israeli airstrikes in Gaza on Saturday, with Israel saying it had killed an operative who took part in the October 7, 2023 Hamas attacks on Israel and who it said was employed by a US-based charity.</p>

<p>The first was a World Central Kitchen member, who was hit in a vehicle in Khan Younis in Southern Gaza. The Israeli military said that he had taken part in the attack on Kibbutz Nir Oz in southern Israel and was under surveillance but did not offer any evidence.</p>

<p>Reuters could not independently verify whether he took part in the attack last year.</p>

<p>The family of the man, Ahed Azmi Qdeih, said the Israeli allegations were false and meant to justify his unlawful killing. They said he was an engineer who dedicated his life to charitable work.</p>

<p>World Central Kitchen confirmed the airstrike and said it had no knowledge about an employee involved in the Oct. 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p>"We are heartbroken to share that a vehicle carrying World Central Kitchen colleagues was hit by an Israeli airstrike in Gaza," it said in a statement posted on X. "World Central Kitchen had no knowledge that any individual in the vehicle had alleged ties to the October 7th Hamas attack."</p>

<p>The charity group said it was pausing operations in Gaza, adding that it was working with incomplete information and was urgently seeking more details. The official Palestinian news agency WAFA reported that three employees of the charity were killed in the strike, with medics saying a total of five people were killed.</p>

<p>Hamas did not immediately comment.</p>

<p>Later in the day, international aid agency Save the Children also said in a statement that a 39-year-old staffer, who it identified as Ahmad Faisal Isleem Al-Qadi, was killed in an airstrike in Khan Younis.</p>

<p>It was unclear if the two men were killed in the same strike. Israel has not immediately commented on Save the Children's statement.</p>

<p>"There are not strong enough words to express the grief and outrage we feel at the loss of Ahmad in an Israeli airstrike. He was a valued member of our team and loved by all who met him," Inger Ashing, the Save the Children chief executive, said in the statement.</p>

<p>In another attack in Khan Younis, medics said at least nine Palestinians were killed when an Israeli airstrike hit a car near a crowd receiving flour, a vehicle that was used by security personnel tasked with overseeing aid deliveries into Gaza.</p>

<p>The Israeli military says that it does not target civilians and accuses Hamas of operating from civilian facilities and using Gaza's population as human shields, which the group denies.</p>

<p>At least 32 Palestinians were killed in Israeli strikes across the enclave overnight and into Saturday, Gaza medics said, including seven killed in a strike on a house in central Gaza City, according to Gaza officials.</p>

<h2><strong>New Ceasefire Efforts</strong></h2>

<p>Meanwhile, leaders of Hamas were expected to arrive in Cairo on Saturday for ceasefire talks with Egyptian officials, days after Israel and Hezbollah agreed to a ceasefire in Lebanon, two officials of the group told Reuters.</p>

<p>The visit is the first since the United States announced earlier this week it would revive efforts in collaboration with Qatar, Egypt, and Turkey to negotiate a ceasefire in Gaza.</p>

<p>The Hamas delegation is expected to meet with Egyptian security officials to explore ways to reach a ceasefire deal with Israel that could secure the release of hostages in return for Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>Progress before now has been limited in a series of on-off talks over months.</p>

<p>Hamas is seeking an agreement that would end the war while Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has stated that the war will end only when Hamas is eradicated.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 44,382 people and displaced nearly all of the enclave's population at least once, Gaza officials say. Vast swathes of Gaza lie in ruins.</p>

<p>The conflict was triggered more than 13 months ago when Hamas-led operatives attacked southern Israeli communities, killing about 1,200 people and abducting over 250 hostages, according to Israeli officials.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8rhc66g_gaza-reuters_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas leaders were expected to arrive in Cairo on Saturday for ceasefire talks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-president-gets-red-carpet-welcome-in-us-china-reacts-7145543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taiwan President Gets 'Red Carpet' Welcome In US, China Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-president-gets-red-carpet-welcome-in-us-china-reacts-7145543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 10:01:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwan President Lai Ching-te was feted with a red carpet, garlands of flowers and "alohas" as he kicked off his two-day stopover in Hawaii on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan President Lai Ching-te was feted with a red carpet, garlands of flowers and "alohas" as he kicked off his two-day stopover in Hawaii on Saturday, part of a Pacific tour that has sparked fiery rhetoric from Beijing.</p>

<p>China claims Taiwan as part of its territory and has responded to Lai's first overseas trip as president with threats to "resolutely crush" any attempt for independence.</p>

<p>Looking relaxed in a Hawaiian shirt, Lai flitted around the US island state, visiting a Pacific island history museum, an emergency management centre and the USS Arizona Memorial in Pearl Harbour.</p>

<p>Earlier, he was given the "red carpet treatment" on the tarmac of Honolulu's international airport, according to his office, which said it was the first time a Taiwanese president had been given such a welcome.</p>

<p>He was met by Ingrid Larson, managing director in Washington of the American Institute in Taiwan, Hawaii Governor Josh Green, and others.</p>

<p>At every turn, Lai was presented with garlands of brightly coloured flowers or leaves known as leis, greetings of "aloha", and other Hawaiian gifts.</p>

<p>In the evening, Lai is expected to deliver his first public speech of the week-long trip at a dinner attended by US government officials and Taiwanese people living abroad.</p>

<p>Beijing opposes any international recognition of Taiwan and its claim to be a sovereign state and especially bristles at official contact between the island and the United States.</p>

<p>Like most countries, Washington does not recognize Taiwan diplomatically but is its most important backer and biggest supplier of arms.</p>

<p>In a statement, China's foreign ministry said it "strongly condemns" the United States for Lai's stopover and that it had "lodged serious protests with the US".</p>

<p>"China will closely follow the developments and take resolute and strong measures to defend our nation's sovereignty and territorial integrity," it said.</p>

<p>After Hawaii, Lai will visit Taiwan's allies the Marshall Islands, Tuvalu and Palau -- the only Pacific island nations among the 12 countries that recognize Taiwan's claim to statehood -- and stop over for one night in the US territory of Guam.</p>

<p>Lai said shortly before take-off in Taipei that the trip "ushered in a new era of values-based democracy" and thanked the US government for "helping to make this trip a smooth one".&nbsp;</p>

<p>He said he wanted to "continue to expand cooperation and deepen partnerships with our allies based on the values of democracy, peace and prosperity."</p>

<p>"I once again emphasize that we are all Team Taiwan. We all work together, and we can successfully achieve our goals," Lai told reporters on board the plane.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist is travelling with the president for the duration of the trip.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Threat of invasion</strong></h3>

<p>Taiwan lives under the constant threat of an invasion by China, which has refused to rule out using force to bring the island under its control.</p>

<p>Beijing deploys fighter jets, drones and warships around Taiwan on a near-daily basis to press its claims, with the number of sorties increasing in recent years.</p>

<p>Lai's aircraft was accompanied by Taiwanese Air Force F-16 fighter jets for part of its route to Hawaii.</p>

<p>"I think this is very meaningful and also makes us feel that we have a long way to go on this trip and bear heavy responsibilities," Lai told reporters on board, referring to the escort.</p>

<p>Taiwanese government officials have previously stopped over on US soil during visits to the Pacific or Latin America, angering China, which has sometimes responded with military drills around the island.</p>

<p>In a swift response to news of Lai's trip on Thursday, Wu Qian, a spokesperson for China's defense ministry said: "We firmly oppose official interaction with China's Taiwan region in any form" and vowed to "resolutely crush" any attempts for Taiwan independence.</p>

<p>Lai's trip follows the US approval on Friday of a proposed sale to Taiwan of spare parts for F-16s and radar systems, as well as communications equipment, in deals valued at $385 million in total.</p>

<p>The Taiwan president's trip comes as Republican US President-elect Donald Trump prepares to take office in January.</p>

<p>Taipei has publicly congratulated Trump on his victory, joining other governments around the world in trying to get onside with the mercurial magnate, whose diplomatic style is often transactional.</p>

<p>During his campaign, Trump caused jitters by suggesting Taiwan should pay the United States for its defense.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vqlk7u8o_hawaii_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[After Hawaii, Lai will visit Taiwan's allies the Marshall Islands, Tuvalu and Palau.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/old-video-of-justin-trudeau-mocking-donald-trump-viral-as-they-meet-amid-tariff-threat-7145418]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Old Video Of Trudeau Mocking Trump Viral As They Meet Amid Tariff Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/old-video-of-justin-trudeau-mocking-donald-trump-viral-as-they-meet-amid-tariff-threat-7145418]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:36:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A five-year-old video of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau reportedly mocking US President-elect Donald Trump in front of other world leaders is making rounds on social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A five-year-old video of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau reportedly mocking US President-elect Donald Trump in front of other world leaders is making rounds on social media as the two leaders met and dined in Florida after Trump's tariff threat on Canada on Saturday.</p>

<p>The video shows Trudeau standing in a huddle with former UK President Boris Johnson and French President Emmanuel Macron at a Buckingham Palace function.</p>

<p>The 30-second footage from 2019 shows Johnson asking Macron, "Is that why he was late?"</p>

<p>To this, Trudeau responded mockingly: "He was late because he talked a 40-minute press conference off the top". He went on to add, "You just watched his team's jaws drop to the floor".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I will never forget when Justin Trudeau mocked Trump behind his back.<br />
<br />
I hope President Trump concedes nothing to this fraud at their meeting. <a href="https://t.co/LmsZx8SUlp">pic.twitter.com/LmsZx8SUlp</a></p>
— George (@BehizyTweets) <a href="https://twitter.com/BehizyTweets/status/1862640795834032638?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>While no name was mentioned, it was assumed that they were talking about <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-100-tariff-warning-for-brics-countries-if-they-undercut-dollar-7144959" target="_blank">Trump</a> who is known for his long press conferences.</p>

<p>However, a few days later when the incident created a big stir, Trudeau had admitted that they were, in fact, talking about Trump.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump imposes tariff on Canada, Mexico</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier this week, the 78-year-old US President-elect, who will take office on January 10, said he would slap a 25 percent tariff on imports from Canada and Mexico, accusing them of allowing an "invasion" of the US by illicit drugs and undocumented migrants. He also said a 10 percent tariff on imports would be imposed on China.</p>

<p>For Canada, the stakes of any new tariffs are high as more than three-quarters of Canadian exports went to the US last year and nearly two million Canadian jobs are dependent on trade, reported news agency AFP.</p>

<p>A day after the announcement, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-pm-justin-trudeau-arrives-in-florida-to-meet-donald-trump-amid-tariff-threats-7137838" target="_blank">Trudeau rushed to the US</a> to meet Trump when the duo dined together at Mar-a-Lago in Florida.</p>

<p>On Saturday morning, Trudeau said that he had an "excellent conversation" with Trump, while leaving to catch a flight back to Canada.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1vafltmo_trudeau_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said he would slap a 25 percent tariff on Canada.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/world-aids-day-2024-difference-between-hiv-and-aids-7145415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World AIDS Day 2024: Difference Between HIV And AIDS]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/world-aids-day-2024-difference-between-hiv-and-aids-7145415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:34:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[World AIDS Day 2024: On World AIDS Day 2024 (December 1), understanding the distinction between HIV and AIDS remains critical.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>World AIDS Day 2024: </strong>HIV, or Human Immunodeficiency Virus, targets the body's infection-fighting cells, weakening the immune system and increasing vulnerability to severe complications. After exposure, acute HIV infection typically develops within 2-4 weeks, presenting symptoms such as fever, headache, and rash. During this stage, the virus multiplies rapidly, spreading throughout the body and compromising the immune system. This is also the period when the individual is most infectious.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Without timely treatment, HIV can progress to AIDS (Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome). In this advanced stage, the viral load is extremely high, symptoms become severe, and survival without treatment is typically limited to a few years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Between acute HIV infection and AIDS, there is a chronic HIV infection stage where the virus continues to replicate but at a slower rate. Although this stage cannot lead to a cure, disease progression can be significantly slowed with antiretroviral therapy (ART). ART enables individuals with HIV to live longer, healthier lives.</p>

<p>On World AIDS Day 2024 (December 1), understanding the distinction between HIV and AIDS remains critical.</p>

<p>One of the most significant global public health concerns in recorded history, AIDS has killed between 27.2 million and 47.8 million people globally as of 2020, while an estimated 37.7 million people are living with HIV.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.who.int/southeastasia/news/detail/01-12-2024-world-aids-day" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>WHO</em></a>, there are 80,000 children and adolescents aged 0-14 estimated to be living with HIV, comprising 2% of total HIV cases in the Region, predominantly due to vertical transmission (mother-to-child). Approximately 53,000 infants are born with congenital syphilis. These children are one too many as there are effective interventions to eliminate mother-to-child transmission during pregnancy, labour, and childbirth. They face a multitude of complex issues while growing up, living with HIV. WHO's 'triple elimination' initiative of vertical transmission of HIV, syphilis and hepatitis B virus is a critical public health priority to prevent the next generation of young from these infectious diseases. Three champion countries - Maldives, Sri Lanka, and Thailand - have already achieved elimination of HIV and syphilis vertical transmission.</p>

<h3><strong>What is HIV?&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) is a virus that targets immune system cells, making an individual more susceptible to various illnesses and infections.</p>

<p>HIV spreads more easily in the first few months after a person is infected, but many are unaware of their status until the later stages. In the first few weeks after being infected people may not experience symptoms. Others may have an influenza-like illness including fever, headache, rash and sore throat. The infection progressively weaken the immune system. This can cause other signs and symptoms swollen lymph nodes, weight loss, fever, diarrhoea and&nbsp;<br />
cough.&nbsp;</p>

<p>HIV can be transmitted via the exchange of body fluids from people living with HIV, including blood, breast milk, semen, and vaginal secretions. HIV can also be transmitted to a child during pregnancy and delivery. &nbsp;People cannot become infected with HIV through ordinary day-to-day contact such as kissing, hugging, shaking hands, or sharing personal objects, food or water.</p>

<p>While it cannot be cured, it can be kept in control through medications. HIV medication is lifelong and reduces or even eliminates your ability to transmit the virus to others.</p>

<h3><strong>What is AIDS?&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) is a term that applies to the most advanced stages of HIV infection. It is defined by the occurrence of any of the more than 20 life-threatening cancers or "opportunistic infections", so named because they take advantage of a weakened immune system. AIDS was a defining feature of the earlier years of the HIV epidemic, before antiretroviral therapy (ART) became available. Now, as more people access ART, the majority of people living with HIV will not progress to AIDS.</p>

<p>Advanced HIV disease (AHD), defined as having a CD4 cell count less than 200 copies, having an AIDS-defining illness, or all children less than 5 years old with confirmed HIV infection, is more likely to occur in people with HIV who have not been tested, in people who are diagnosed late, and in people who have stopped or never started taking ART, according to WHO.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2tpn9nqo_aids_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[World AIDS Day: HIV can be transmitted via the exchange of body fluids from people living with HIV]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-taps-charles-kushner-father-of-his-son-in-law-as-envoy-to-france-7145381]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Taps Charles Kushner, Father Of His Son-In-Law, As Envoy To France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-taps-charles-kushner-father-of-his-son-in-law-as-envoy-to-france-7145381]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:27:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump nominated Charles Kushner, the father of his son-in-law Jared Kushner, as the US ambassador to France, in the latest of several controversial picks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump on Saturday nominated Charles Kushner, the father of his son-in-law Jared Kushner, as the US ambassador to France, in the latest of several controversial picks.</p>

<p>Kushner "is a tremendous business leader, philanthropist, &amp; dealmaker, who will be a strong advocate representing our Country &amp; its interests," Trump said on his Truth Social website, adding that Jared "worked closely with me in the White House."</p>

<p>The choice is in keeping with Trump's pattern, so far, of selecting people, often wealthy, who are close to his family or of proven loyalty. Kushner is a multimillionaire real estate executive and former attorney; his son was a senior adviser during Trump's first term.</p>

<p>Trump did not mention, however, that the elder Kushner once served jail time -- a two-year sentence, most of it served in a federal prison.</p>

<p>Kushner, who is now 70, pleaded guilty in 2004 to 18 counts of tax evasion, witness tampering and making illegal campaign contributions.</p>

<p>The case, which was prosecuted by then US attorney Chris Christie, included sordid details, to which Kushner admitted: that he had hired a prostitute to seduce his brother-in-law, a man cooperating in a campaign finance inquiry, and then videotaped the encounter and sent it to the man's wife, Kushner's sister, to dissuade her from testifying against him.</p>

<p>Christie, who worked on Trump's first presidential transition team and then opposed him in this year's Republican primary contests, later said Kushner had committed a "loathsome" and "disgusting crime."&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2020, Trump issued a pardon to Kushner, whose conviction had resulted in him being disbarred in three states.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nominees for key ambassadorships are often business associates of a president-elect, or major political donors. But it is rare, if not unprecedented, to name a convicted felon.</p>

<p>The first two men to fill the prestigious Paris post were famed inventor and statesman Benjamin Franklin and a future president, Thomas Jefferson.</p>

<p>If confirmed, Kushner would succeed Denise Bauer, a former ambassador to Belgium who was a major Democratic fundraiser and donor.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4t4547jo_charles-kushner_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kushner would succeed Denise Bauer, a former ambassador to Belgium and a major Democratic fundraiser.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-teams-up-with-musk-s-spacex-to-explore-saturn-s-moon-with-dragonfly-mission-7145377]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[SpaceX To Launch NASA's 'Dragonfly' To Saturn's Moon In 2028: What We Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-teams-up-with-musk-s-spacex-to-explore-saturn-s-moon-with-dragonfly-mission-7145377]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:26:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's SpaceX will launch NASA's groundbreaking Dragonfly mission to Saturn's largest moon, Titan, using a Falcon Heavy rocket.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's SpaceX will launch NASA's groundbreaking Dragonfly mission to Saturn's largest moon, Titan, using a Falcon Heavy rocket. Scheduled to lift off between July 5 and 25, 2028, from Kennedy Space Centre in Florida, the launch contract is valued at $256.6 million.</p>

<p>This mission, part of <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-awards-launch-services-contract-for-dragonfly-mission/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">NASA's New Frontiers Programme</a>, will cost $3.35 billion and aims to explore Titan's unique environment with a drone-like rotorcraft lander.</p>

<p>Dragonfly will travel to Titan over six years, arriving in 2034. It will explore Titan's methane seas, icy landscapes, and organic-rich dunes, landing in a new location every Titan day (16 Earth days). The rotorcraft will collect samples and analyse Titan's prebiotic chemistry, searching for biosignatures of life, whether water-based or hydrocarbon-based. Titan, the only known celestial body besides Earth with stable surface liquids, presents a unique opportunity to study environments that may support life.</p>

<p>Originally planned for a 2026 launch, the mission was delayed by the COVID-19 pandemic. NASA chose SpaceX's Falcon Heavy to shorten the cruise phase and meet the 2034 arrival target.</p>

<p>While Titan's dense atmosphere and low gravity make it ideal for rotorcraft flight, the moon's surface receives only 1 per cent of the sunlight that Earth does. This creates challenges for solar-powered operations, which Dragonfly will tackle using advanced autonomous systems, drawing lessons from the Mars Helicopter, Ingenuity.</p>

<p>Dragonfly follows the legacy of the Cassini-Huygens mission, which in 2005 provided humanity's first close-up look at Titan. Cassini-Huygens revealed a world shaped by methane rivers, ancient shorelines, and ice. Dragonfly will expand on those discoveries by exploring Titan's active methane cycle and studying how water and carbon-rich materials may have interacted to create prebiotic conditions.</p>

<p>The mission is managed by NASA's Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Laboratory, with contributions from experts worldwide in planetary science, rotorcraft design, and autonomous systems. NASA's Marshall Space Flight Centre oversees the project as part of the New Frontiers Programme.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/03qsl8c8_elon-musk_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dragonfly will travel to Titan over six years, arriving in 2034.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/high-testosterone-levels-may-not-imply-high-sex-drive-as-previously-thought-study-finds-7145267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[High Testosterone Levels May Not Imply High Sex Drive As Previously Thought]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/high-testosterone-levels-may-not-imply-high-sex-drive-as-previously-thought-study-finds-7145267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:01:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[41 men aged 18 to 26 of varying relationship statuses (27 single, 14 committed to a partner) were recruited for a 31-day trial.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having higher levels of testosterone does not mean men have a higher sex drive, as previously thought -- a new study published in the journal <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rspb.2024.1508" rel="Noindex, nofollow"><em>Proceedings of the Royal Society B</em></a> has claimed. Testosterone is a hormone, produced primarily in the testicles of men and in smaller amounts in the ovaries of women. It plays an important role in the development of male secondary sexual characteristics such as body hair growth, and increased muscle and bone mass. While its role in reproductive behaviour has been significantly documented, an international team of researchers led by the University of California, Santa Barbara believe that day-to-day changes in testosterone levels had no real link to sexual desire in men.</p>

<p>"A man experiencing higher-than-usual testosterone concentrations on a given day does not typically exhibit higher-than-usual sexual desire on that same day," the study stated.</p>

<p>As per the researchers, their study corroborated with prior findings suggesting that men's sexual desire requires only a threshold amount of baseline testosterone.</p>

<p>Interestingly, the researchers found that there was a positive relationship between testosterone levels and the degree of effort men put into wooing their significant other.</p>

<p>"We propose that the evolved functions of testosterone in human males are more closely associated with courtship efforts than with sexual desire," the study highlighted.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://food.ndtv.com/health/how-to-boost-testosterone-levels-naturally-10-natural-ways-toboost-testosterone-levels-5668212" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Feeling Sluggish? It Could Be Low Testosterone. Here's How To Boost It Naturally</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>How was the study conducted?</strong></h3>

<p>41 men aged 18 to 26 of varying relationship statuses (27 single, 14 committed to a partner) were recruited for a 31-day trial. A daily saliva analysis was taken to measure testosterone concentrations with the participants required to fill answers to questions such as: "How much sexual desire did you experience?" "How much effort did you put into attracting a possible romantic and/or sexual partner yesterday?" and "How much did you have sexual fantasies?"</p>

<p>On days when the single men interacted with prospective partners, testosterone concentrations were higher, suggesting more effort was made to seek out a mate.</p>

<p>"Testosterone fluctuations in the normal range may positively predict day-to-day changes in men's mate attraction efforts among single men, especially given social interactions with potential mates."</p>

<p>Despite the findings, the researchers said they needed more data to further develop their understanding of the matter.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7lfqamo8_men_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Study stated that testosterone levels increased when men searched for prospective partners.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/ancient-egyptians-consumed-psychedelic-cocktails-mixed-with-bodily-fluids-alcohol-7145156]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ancient Egyptians Drank Cocktails Of Psychedelic, Bodily Fluids And Alcohol]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/ancient-egyptians-consumed-psychedelic-cocktails-mixed-with-bodily-fluids-alcohol-7145156]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:34:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The research combined chemical and DNA analyses uncovered the first physical evidence of plants with psychotropic and medicinal properties in an Egyptian mug.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have identified traces of psychedelic substances, bodily fluids, and alcohol in a 2,000-year-old mug, providing evidence that ancient Egyptians consumed hallucinogenic beverages during rituals, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/26/science/egyptian-bes-mug-hallucinogens/index.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This marks the first time scientists have detected chemical signatures of the liquid mixtures once consumed from mugs adorned with the image of Bes, an ancient Egyptian deity associated with fertility, protection, healing, and magical purification. Bes-shaped vessels were crafted over an extended period in Egypt, but few have survived, and those that remain have been discovered in varied archaeological contexts, adding to their intrigue.</p>

<p>The findings, published on November 13 in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-78721-8/figures/1" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Scientific Reports</em></a>, stem from an analysis of residue found in a preserved Bes mug displayed at the Tampa Museum of Art.</p>

<p>"For a very long time now, Egyptologists have been speculating what mugs with the head of Bes could have been used for, and for what kind of beverage, like sacred water, milk, wine or beer," said study coauthor Branko van Oppen, curator of Greek and Roman art at the Tampa Museum of Art, in a statement. "Experts did not know if these mugs were used in daily life, for religious purposes or in magic rituals."</p>

<p>The research combined chemical and DNA analyses uncovered the first physical evidence of plants with psychotropic and medicinal properties in an Egyptian mug. This discovery supports both written records and myths about ancient Egyptian rituals, according to lead author Davide Tanasi, a professor and director of the Institute for Digital Exploration at the University of South Florida.</p>

<p>"Religion is one of the most fascinating and puzzling aspects of ancient civilizations," Tanasi said in a statement. "With this study, we've found scientific proof that the Egyptian myths have some kind of truth and it helps us shed light on the poorly understood rituals that were likely carried out in the Bes Chambers in Saqqara, near the Great Pyramids at Giza."</p>

<p>Bes mugs have long puzzled researchers due to the lack of contextual clues about their use, making it difficult to theorize their role in rituals or the substances they contained, Tanasi explained.</p>

<p>"Overall, the Bes vessels were not ordinary artefacts but rather ritual objects that were manufactured in limited numbers and acquired just by those individuals who worshipped Bes and participated in the rituals revolving around him," Tanasi said. "Very likely, those individuals got to keep the Bes vessels after they were used to perform the rituals, as a reminder that the ritual was actually performed."</p>

<p>As part of a broader investigation into ancient Mediterranean nutrition, the team analyzed a Bes mug donated to the Tampa Museum of Art in 1984. After scraping the mug's walls, they pulverized the sample and identified a recipe-like composition based on overlapping residues.</p>

<p>Initially, researchers expected to find traces of a strong alcoholic beverage, given the vessel's small size- just 1.7 inches (4.5 centimetres) tall and capable of holding 4.2 fluid ounces (125 millilitres). However, the analysis revealed a complex mixture of substances.</p>

<p>The team identified four main categories of ingredients: an alcoholic base, flavouring agents, human bodily fluids, and medicinal or psychotropic components.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The presence of fermentation yeasts indicated that the base was likely beer or wine, flavoured with honey, royal jelly, sesame seeds, pine nuts, liquorice, and grapes. Grapes were commonly used by ancient Egyptians to give beverages a blood-like appearance, the study noted.</p>

<p>The bodily fluids, potentially a combination of blood, breast milk, and mucus (from nasal, vaginal, or salivary sources), appeared to have been deliberately added based on their concentrations.</p>

<p>Among the plants detected were Egyptian blue water lily and Syrian rue, both known for their hallucinogenic, medicinal, intoxicating, and sedative properties, which could alter perception and enhance visionary experiences. The Cleome plant, also found in the residue, is known for its medicinal uses, including labour induction or, in high doses, causing abortion.</p>

<p>"This research teaches us about magic rituals in the Greco-Roman period in Egypt," van Oppen said. "Egyptologists believe that people visited the so-called Bes Chambers at Saqqara when they wished to confirm a successful pregnancy because pregnancies in the ancient world were fraught with dangers. So, this combination of ingredients may have been used in a dream-vision-inducing magic ritual within the context of this dangerous period of childbirth."</p>

<p>According to records, Egyptians were familiar with the plants and the side effects of consuming them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We were surprised by the complex recipe of the concoction and shocked by the discovery (of) the human fluids that added a new religious/magical angle," Tanasi said. "The identified substances would likely have induced dream-like visions, heightened meditative states and possibly euphoria."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/i13h06a_ancient-egyptians-_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The findings, published on November 13 in Scientific Reports]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-city-paying-220-million-to-pakistan-owned-hotel-vivek-ramaswamy-says-nuts-7145122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York City Paying $220 Million To Pakistan-Owned Hotel; Vivek Ramaswamy Says...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-city-paying-220-million-to-pakistan-owned-hotel-vivek-ramaswamy-says-nuts-7145122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:25:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The City of New York pays $220 million to rent a hotel owned by the Government of Pakistan to house illegal immigrants, a report claimed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The City of New York pays $220 million to rent a hotel owned by the Government of Pakistan to house illegal immigrants, a report claimed on Saturday.</p>

<p>Vivek Ramaswamy described the purported revelation as "Nuts." "A taxpayer-funded hotel for illegal migrants is owned by the Pakistani government which means NYC taxpayers are effectively paying a foreign government to house illegals in our own country. This is nuts,"Ramaswamy, a Republican, said in a social media post.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A taxpayer-funded hotel for illegal migrants is owned by the Pakistani government which means NYC taxpayers are effectively paying a foreign government to house illegals in our own country. This is nuts. <a href="https://t.co/Oy4Z9qoX45">https://t.co/Oy4Z9qoX45</a></p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1863022250498125866?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Ramaswamy along with Tesla Owner Elon Musk have been tasked by President-elect Donald Trump to improve government efficiency and remove wasteful expenditure under a Department of Government Efficiency built for the purpose.</p>

<p>The Indian American let out his outburst after author John LeFevre reported about it on X.</p>

<p>"The city of New York pays $220 million to rent the entire Roosevelt Hotel in Manhattan to house illegal migrants," he said.</p>

<p>The Roosevelt Hotel is owned by Pakistan International Airlines, a Pakistani government-owned airline.</p>

<p>"The hotel is owned by the government of Pakistan, and the deal was part of a $1.1 billion IMF bailout package to help Pakistan avoid defaulting on their international debt," LeFevre said.</p>

<p>"Prior to this sweetheart deal, the hotel had been closed since 2020, having long-struggled with occupancy and in dire need of renovation," he wrote.</p>

<p>Named after former US president Theodore Roosvelt, the 19-story hotel now is rented by New York City to provide shelter to illegal immigrants. It has over 1,200 rooms. The hotel was shut down for renovation, before it was rented out by New York City.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/5agrcogg_roosevelt-hotel_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Indian American let out his outburst after author John LeFevre reported about it on X.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-powered-death-clock-promises-more-exact-prediction-of-day-youll-die-7145051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI-Powered 'Death Clock' Promises Better Prediction Of When You May Die]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-powered-death-clock-promises-more-exact-prediction-of-day-youll-die-7145051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:09:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Death Clock, an AI-powered longevity app, has proved a hit with paying customers - downloaded some 125,000 times since its launch in July.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For centuries, humans have used actuarial tables to figure out how long they're likely to live. Now artificial intelligence is taking up the task - and its answers may well be of interest to economists and money managers.</p>

<p>The recently released Death Clock, an AI-powered longevity app, has proved a hit with paying customers - downloaded some 125,000 times since its launch in July, according to market intelligence firm Sensor Tower.</p>

<p>The AI was trained on a dataset of more than 1,200 life expectancy studies with some 53 million participants. It uses information about diet, exercise, stress levels and sleep to predict a likely date of death. The results are a "pretty significant" improvement on the standard life-table expectations, says its developer, Brent Franson.</p>

<p>Despite its somewhat morbid tone - it displays a "fond farewell" death-day card featuring the Grim Reaper - Death Clock is catching on among people trying to live more healthily. It ranks high in the Health and Fitness category of apps. But the technology potentially has a wider range of uses.</p>

<p>Life expectancy is key to all kinds of financial and economic calculations, by governments, companies and individuals - from retirement income needs, to policy coverage at life insurance and pension funds, and financial planning.</p>

<p>In the US - which has lagged behind other developed economies in the life expectancy of its citizens in recent years - the Social Security Administration has its own table for mortality rates, which features in the annual financial report to trustees.</p>

<p>The government agency currently predicts that an 85-year-old man in the US has a 10% probability of dying within a year, and an average 5.6 years to live. But averages like that can be off by wide margins, says Franson, and the new algorithms can deliver a more tailored measure - a customized death clock.</p>

<p>That such findings are of interest in economics is demonstrated by the publication - in just the past month or so - of two papers around the topic by the National Bureau of Economic Research.</p>

<p><strong>'Harness The Benefits'</strong></p>

<p>One of them, titled "On the Limits of Chronological Age," looks at the diverse ways that the aging process affects physiological capacities. It finds that many aspects of economic behavior, like readiness to join the labor force, may not be well captured by people's calendar age - even though that's what policies such as statutory retirement are typically based on.</p>

<p>By continuing to rely on chronological age as a proxy for how well people can function, societies may end up failing to "fully harness the benefits of increasing longevity," the researchers from Harvard and the London Business School conclude.</p>

<p>Another working paper examined the "value per statistical life" or VSL - a callous-sounding measure that's used for cost-benefit analysis in areas like regulation of pollution or compensation for workplace accidents. It's typically calculated based on compensation for workers in high-risk jobs.</p>

<p>The researchers behind the NBER study "The value of Statistical Life for Seniors" drew on a different dataset: the propensity of older Americans to spend money on medical services that reduce mortality risk. They found a mean VSL at age 67 of just under $2 million for people reporting their health as "excellent," compared with $600,000 for those in "good" health.</p>

<p>When it comes to personal finances, better measures of life expectancy will have profound implications for people saving for retirement, according to Ryan Zabrowski, a financial planner with investment advisory firm Krilogy.</p>

<p>"A huge concern for elderly people, our retirees, is outliving their money," says Zabrowski, who touches on the issue in his soon-to-be-released book, "Time Ahead".</p>

<p><strong>'Out The Window'</strong></p>

<p>Decisions such as how much to save and how fast to withdraw assets are often based on broad-brush and unreliable averages for life expectancy. AI-driven tests that can potentially reduce that uncertainty are largely unheard-of now, but likely won't be such an unusual idea in the future.</p>

<p>What's more, the AI technology itself along with advances in medicine has the potential to boost life expectancy - and with it the risk of running out of savings. Zabrowski reckons one consequence is clear: longer retirements will mean savers need higher-return investments for their old age, which will push them to allocate more stocks over fixed-income securities.</p>

<p>"The conventional method of measuring demand for equities will be thrown out the window," he writes his forthcoming book. As people start expecting to live longer, there will be a "massive escalation in demand for equities."</p>

<p>There are plenty of technologies already out there - like heart-rate monitors and maximal oxygen-consumption gauges from wearables - that have the potential, in tandem with new AI-powered devices, to reduce the uncertainty around personal mortality.</p>

<p>Of course, there'll always be limits. On top of entirely unpredictable variables, like accidents or even pandemics, there are plenty of intangibles.</p>

<p><strong>Longevity Gap</strong></p>

<p>Loneliness, for instance, is often reckoned to reduce life expectancy. Gratitude may increase it. A Harvard study found that women who reported feeling the most grateful had a 9% lower risk of dying within three years than those who reported feeling the least.</p>

<p>Then there's the question of inequality. For life expectancy, money matters. Multiple studies - including the work of Nobel prize-winning economist Angus Deaton on "Deaths of Despair" - have found a clear gap between rich and poor Americans.</p>

<p>Research published by the American Medical Association found the longevity gap between the wealthiest and poorest 1%, at age 40, was nearly 15 years for men and 10 for women.</p>

<p>For Death Clock users, who have to pay $40 a year to subscribe, the app suggests lifestyle changes that can hold mortality at bay - along with a second-by-second countdown of estimated time remaining.</p>

<p>"There's probably not a more important date in your life than the day that you're going to die," Franson says.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/lphvs3jg_wall-clocks_625x300_24_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Life expectancy is key to all kinds of financial and economic calculations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-edan-alexander-video-hamas-releases-footage-of-crying-israeli-hostage-his-mother-reacts-7145029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Hamas Releases Footage Of Crying Israeli Hostage, His Mother Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-edan-alexander-video-hamas-releases-footage-of-crying-israeli-hostage-his-mother-reacts-7145029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:00:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian group Hamas released a video on Saturday featuring an American-Israeli hostage, Edan Alexander.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian group Hamas released a video on Saturday featuring an American-Israeli hostage, Edan Alexander. Held in Gaza since the devastating October 7, 2023 attack on Israel, Alexander directly addresses US President-elect Donald Trump in English and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu in Hebrew, pleading for intervention and urging Israelis to pressure their government for the release of hostages.</p>

<p>The video, released by Hamas's military wing, the Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, has not been independently verified for authenticity or date. Yael Alexander, Edan's mother, spoke at a rally in Tel Aviv the same evening.</p>

<p>"This video has upset me, but beyond the hope it gives us, it shows how bad the situation is for Edan and the other hostages and how much they are crying out and hoping to be saved now," she declared.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The family of Edan Alexander, the Israeli-American held hostage in Gaza, has authorized the release of the heartbreaking proof of life video published by terrorists earlier today. <a href="https://t.co/pYp8vttt8t">pic.twitter.com/pYp8vttt8t</a></p>
— Aviva Klompas (@AvivaKlompas) <a href="https://twitter.com/AvivaKlompas/status/1862897435917402244?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>She revealed that she had spoken directly with Netanyahu, urging him to honour his commitment to secure the hostages' release. &nbsp;"You must keep your promise and free them. This state is strong enough to end the war and bring them all back, including my Edan," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Netanyahu's office later confirmed the conversation, reiterating that Israel remains resolute in its determination to bring back all hostages. Describing the video as "cruel psychological warfare," the Prime Minister said that such tactics would not deter Israel from its mission.</p>

<p>The Hostage Families Forum, an advocacy group for those captured, also weighed in, stating that the only viable solution for the return of hostages lies in a negotiated agreement. "One year after the first and only deal, it's clear to everyone: returning the hostages is only possible through a deal," the group's statement read.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack, which saw 1,207 deaths-mostly civilians-resulted in the kidnapping of 251 hostages. Around 97 hostages remain in Gaza, including 34 whose deaths have been confirmed but whose bodies have not been returned. A brief truce in November 2023 led to the release of 80 Israeli hostages in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners, alongside the release of 25 predominantly Thai captives. However, efforts since then to broker further exchanges or a ceasefire have largely faltered.</p>

<p>Israel's military response has claimed the lives of 44,382 people in Gaza, according to figures from the Hamas-run health ministry.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9i0h9k58_hamas-hostage-edan-alexander-_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yael Alexander, Edan's mother, spoke at a rally in Tel Aviv the same evening.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/gene-edited-pig-kidney-keeps-monkey-alive-for-6-months-in-china-7144992]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gene-Edited Pig Kidney Keeps Monkey Alive For 6 Months In China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/gene-edited-pig-kidney-keeps-monkey-alive-for-6-months-in-china-7144992]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:46:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The monkey's kidney functioned normally for five months but developed some complications afterwards.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A monkey with a gene-edited pig kidney managed to survive for over six months in China as scientists continue to make breakthroughs in their research of transplantation of organs from one species into another. According to researchers at the Huazhong University of Science and Technology's affiliated Tongji Hospital, the team transplanted a single gene-edited pig kidney into a macaque monkey that had its own kidneys removed in May, earlier this year. The monkey managed to live for 184 days which is believed to be the benchmark for long-term survival.</p>

<p>The monkey's kidney functioned normally for five months but developed some complications afterwards as the primate's immune system started rejecting the newly installed organ. Notably, even when a human donates an organ to another human, the recipient has to take drugs to suppress their immune system for the rest of their lives so their body does not reject the donor organ.</p>

<p>The experiment's success is important as previously, the lack of long-term animal tests on gene-edit pig organs limited the number of clinical trials that can be carried out on Human patients. Chen Gang, who led the project, told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3288814/chinese-scientists-keep-monkey-alive-6-months-gene-edited-pigs-kidney" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>South China Morning Post</em></a> that his team's success could drive forward clinical research in the field.</p>

<p>Pig organs are of similar size to human organs and have similar metabolism mechanisms as well -- making them an ideal candidate for organ transplantation.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/tech-millionaire-bryan-johnson-claims-he-edited-his-dna-on-secret-island-to-live-forever-5929376" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Tech Millionaire Claims He ''Edited'' His DNA On Secret Island To ''Live Forever''</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Previous instances</strong></h3>

<p>Throughout the globe, there have been only 20 cases of a monkey surviving long-term after the transplant of a gene-edited pig kidney. Last year, a study in the US claimed that it had managed to keep monkeys alive for two years following the transplantation of the alien organ.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in 2022, researchers at the University of Maryland transplanted a heart from a genetically modified pig into a 57-year-old man who had terminal heart disease, and his medical history made him ineligible to receive a heart from a human donor.</p>

<p>According to a Government of India (GoI) response in the Parliament, the average waiting time for a kidney transplant at the All Indian Institue of Medical Sciences (AIIMS) was 8-9 months from the date of registration. However, for a cadaver kidney transplant, the waiting time can't be predicted.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-09/macaque-monkey-afp_650x400_51442972870.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A single gene-edited pig kidney was transplanted into a macaque monkey.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-pushing-agenda-for-x-australias-anthony-albanese-amid-under-16-ban-criticism-7144990]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Elon Musk Pushing Agenda...": Anthony Albanese Amid Under-16 Ban Criticism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-pushing-agenda-for-x-australias-anthony-albanese-amid-under-16-ban-criticism-7144990]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:45:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said on Sunday that criticism by Elon Musk of Australia's social media ban on children under 16 was the X owner pushing an agenda for the social platform.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said on Sunday that criticism by Elon Musk of Australia's social media ban on children under 16 was the X owner pushing an agenda for the social platform, while indicating he was open to talk to the billionaire about the ban, legislated this week.</p>

<p>Australia approved the social media ban for children late on Thursday after an emotive debate that has gripped the nation, setting a benchmark for jurisdictions around the world with one of the toughest regulations targeting Big Tech.</p>

<p>The ban, which the centre-left government says is world-leading, could strain Australia's relationship with key ally the United States, where Musk, a central figure in the administration of president-elect Donald Trump, said in a post this month it seemed a "backdoor way to control access to the Internet by all Australians".</p>

<p>Albanese, asked on Sunday if he was prepared to talk to Musk about the social media ban said: "We'll talk to anyone".</p>

<p>"With regard to Elon Musk, he has an agenda, he's entitled to push that as the owner of X, formerly known as Twitter," Albanese added in remarks on Australian Broadcasting Corp. television.</p>

<p>The law forces tech giants from Instagram and Facebook owner Meta, to TikTok to stop minors logging in or face fines of up to A$49.5 million ($32 million). A trial of enforcement methods starts in January with the ban to take effect in a year.</p>

<p>"We are determined to get this done, the parliament has overwhelmingly passed this legislation," Albanese told the broadcaster.</p>

<p>X did not immediately reply to a Reuters request for comment outside of business hours.</p>

<p>Albanese's Labor party won crucial support from the opposition conservatives for the bill that was fast-tracked through the country's parliament as part of 31 bills pushed through in a chaotic final day of parliament for the year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/032155l8_australian-pm-anthony-albanese_625x300_29_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia approved the social media ban for children on Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-100-tariff-warning-for-brics-countries-if-they-undercut-dollar-7144959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Go Find Another Sucker": Trump's Big Warning For India, China, Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-100-tariff-warning-for-brics-countries-if-they-undercut-dollar-7144959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:39:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has threatened a 100% tariff on the BRICS countries, including India, if they undercut the US dollar or replace it with another currency for international transactions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world could see a second wave of tariff war as Donald Trump takes office this January. The US President-elect has threatened a 100% tariff on the BRICS countries, including India, if they undercut the US dollar or replace it with another currency for international transactions. His remarks follow a BRICS meeting in October that discussed boosting non-dollar transactions. The BRICS grouping comprises Brazil, Russia, India, China, South Africa, and other countries.</p>

<p>In a scathing online post, Trump said this morning he is not going stand and watch the BRICS move away from the dollar.</p>

<p>"The idea that the BRICS Countries are trying to move away from the Dollar while we stand by and watch is OVER. We require a commitment from these Countries that they will neither create a new BRICS Currency, nor back any other Currency to replace the mighty U.S. Dollar or, they will face 100% Tariffs, and should expect to say goodbye to selling into the wonderful US Economy," said the Republican leader who won a decisive victory in the presidential elections held last month.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-new-tariff-policies-can-affect-asian-economies-including-india-6984737">How Trump's New Tariff Policies Can Affect Asian Economies Including India</a></p>

<p>The President-elect suggested that the BRICS countries can go find another "sucker", but the group won't be able to replace the dollar in international trade with another currency. "They can go find another "sucker!" There is no chance that the BRICS will replace the US Dollar in International Trade, and any Country that tries should wave goodbye to America," said Trump.</p>

<h2><strong>BRICS and Dollar</strong></h2>

<p>The BRICS countries - which now include Egypt, Iran, and UAE as well - discussed boosting non-dollar transactions and strengthening local currencies at a summit held in Russia's Kazan in October.</p>

<p>A joint declaration for the "strengthening of correspondent banking networks within BRICS and enabling settlements in local currencies in line with BRICS Cross-Border Payments Initiative" was secured at the summit in October.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-chinas-new-policy-aims-to-evade-donald-trumps-tariffs-7073735">How China's New Policy Aims To Evade Trump's Tariffs</a></p>

<p>However, Russia's President Vladimir Putin indicated at the summit's end that no alternatives have been made so far to compete with the Belgium-based SWIFT financial messaging system.</p>

<p>India, too, has said it's against de-dollarisation. In October, Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said that's neither a part of India's economic policy nor the country's political or strategic policies. But in cases where trade partners do not take dollars or when issues emerge due to trade policies, workarounds are looked at, he had said.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump, Tariffs, and India</strong></h2>

<p>India's tariff regime has roiled Trump in the past, and so have Brazil and China. His tariff plan for 2025 includes the concept of reciprocity against protectionist regimes. A month before the elections, Trump had clarified that this was the most important element in his plan to make the US "extraordinarily wealthy".</p>

<p><strong>Read -&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-india-is-biggest-tariff-charger-and-he-will-reciprocate-if-elected-to-power-6764073">"India Biggest Tariff Charger", Will Reciprocate If Elected To Power: Trump</a></p>

<p>"Reciprocity is a word that's very important in my plan because we generally don't charge tariffs. I started that process, it was so great, with the vans and the small trucks, etc. We really don't charge. China will charge us a 200 per cent tariff. Brazil is a big charger," he had said in October.</p>

<p>"The biggest charger of all is India," he had asserted, but along with praises for Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the India-US ties.</p>

<p>"I mean, I think they probably charge more than, in many ways, China. But they do it with a smile. They do it... Sort of a nicer charge. They said thank you so much for purchasing from India," he had said at the Detroit Economic Club.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0g874728_donald-trump-afp-_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[BRICS comprises Brazil, Russia, India, China, South Africa, and other countries. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turn-to-love-not-fear-kate-middletons-christmas-letter-after-cancer-battle-7144925]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Turn To Love, Not...": Kate Middleton's Christmas Letter After Cancer Battle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turn-to-love-not-fear-kate-middletons-christmas-letter-after-cancer-battle-7144925]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:27:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kate, Britain's Princess of Wales, says love is the greatest gift people can give each other in a message to guests who will attend her annual Christmas carol service next week at London's Westminster Abbey.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kate, Britain's Princess of Wales, says love is the greatest gift people can give each other in a message to guests who will attend her annual Christmas carol service next week at London's Westminster Abbey.</p>

<p>The December 6 carol concert, the fourth she has hosted, marks Kate's most prominent return to royal engagements since she underwent a course of preventative chemotherapy for cancer.</p>

<p>In a letter to the 1,600 invited guests, Kate, 42, the wife of heir to the throne Prince William, returned to themes of love and the need for empathy about which she has spoken in previous very personal statements and video updates on her health.</p>

<p>Christmas, her letter said, was not only a time for celebration, but also for reflection and relief from the pressures of daily life.</p>

<p>She said the Christmas story reflected "our own vulnerabilities", and how much people needed each other despite their differences.</p>

<p>"Above all else it encourages us to turn to love, not fear," she wrote. "It is this love which is the greatest gift we can receive. Not just at Christmas, but every day of our lives," she said.</p>

<p>William, who earlier this month said the year had been "brutal" for the royal family with Kate's treatment coming in the wake of his father King Charles' own cancer diagnosis, will give a reading at the service.</p>

<p>Six-time Olympic track cycling champion Chris Hoy, who revealed he had terminal cancer himself in October, will light a candle.</p>

<p>The "Together At Christmas" service will be broadcast on Britain's ITV on Christmas Eve.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/v8se7gl_kate-middleton_625x300_25_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The December 6 carol concert marks Kate's most prominent return to royal engagements after cancer battle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>