<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 16:50:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-limits-outdoor-activities-to-curb-air-pollution-related-illness-6993744]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Limits Outdoor Activities To Curb Air-Pollution Related Illness]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-limits-outdoor-activities-to-curb-air-pollution-related-illness-6993744]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 16:48:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Punjab province banned most outdoor activities and ordered shops, markets and malls in some areas to close early from Monday to curb illnesses caused by intense air pollution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Punjab province banned most outdoor activities and ordered shops, markets and malls in some areas to close early from Monday to curb illnesses caused by intense air pollution.</p>

<p>The province has closed educational institutions and public spaces like parks and zoos until Nov. 17 in places including Lahore, the world's most polluted city in terms of air quality, according to Swiss group IQAir's live ratings.</p>

<p>The districts of Lahore, Multan, Faisalabad and Gujranwala have seen an unprecedented rise in patients with respiratory diseases, eye and throat irritation, and pink eye disease, the Punjab government said in an order issued late on Sunday.</p>

<p>The new restrictions will also remain in force until Nov. 17.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Image credit: Reuters" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n9mbnod8_pakistan-pollution_625x300_11_November_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Image credit: Reuters" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Image credit: Reuters</p>
</div>

<p>"The spread of conjunctivitis/ pink eye disease due to bacterial or viral infection, smoke, dust or chemical exposure is posing a serious and imminent threat to public health," the Punjab government said.</p>

<p>While outdoor activities including sports events, exhibitions and festivals, and dining at restaurants have been prohibited, "unavoidable religious rites" are exempt from this direction, the order said.</p>

<p>Outlets like pharmacies, oil depots, dairy shops and fruit and vegetable shops have similarly been exempted from the directions to close by 8 p.m. local time.</p>

<p>Lahore's air quality remained hazardous on Monday, with an index score of more than 600, according to IQAir, but this was significantly lower than the 1,900 that it touched in places earlier this month.</p>

<p>A score of 0-50 is considered good.</p>

<p>UNICEF on Monday also called for greater efforts to reduce pollution and protect children's health in Punjab, saying that more than 11 million children under five years of age are in danger as they breathe the toxic air.</p>

<p>"In addition, schools in smog-affected areas have been closed...the learning of almost 16 million children in Punjab has been disrupted," said Abdullah Fadil, UNICEF Representative in the country.</p>

<p>"Pakistan, already in the grips of an education emergency...cannot afford more learning losses," he said.</p>

<p>Several parts of South Asia are engulfed by a toxic haze each winter as cold air traps dust, emissions and smoke from farm fires.</p>

<p>Punjab has blamed its toxic air this year on pollution wafting in from India, where northern parts have also been battling hazardous air, and has said it will take the issue up with the neighbouring country through its foreign ministry.</p>

<p>India's Supreme Court on Monday directed the Delhi government to decide by Nov. 25 on imposing a perpetual ban on firecrackers, legal news portal Bar and Bench reported.</p>

<p>Firecrackers set off by revellers on Diwali, the Hindu festival of lights celebrated on Oct. 31 this year despite a ban, have aggravated the region's pollution problem.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f4rhljeg_pakistan-air-pollution_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new restrictions will also remain in force until Nov. 17.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/blog/galwan-1962-when-60-indian-jawaans-fought-a-10-times-bigger-enemy-6993485]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blog: Galwan Battle, 1962: When Bullets Rained At The Break Of Dawn]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/blog/galwan-1962-when-60-indian-jawaans-fought-a-10-times-bigger-enemy-6993485]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 16:16:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It was never the plan to send the Alphas to Galwan. But they ended up at the post in October: unexpectedly and without much preparation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(1962) An Mi-4 in the Galwan Valley, as seen from the Chinese side." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pki6m07_galwan_625x300_11_November_24.jpg" title="(1962) An Mi-4 in the Galwan Valley, as seen from the Chinese side." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">(1962) An Mi-4 in the Galwan Valley, as seen from the Chinese side.</p>
</div>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody" dir="ltr">It was August 1962. The Alpha company of 5 Jat was in Chushul when it received a directive to take control of Hot Springs. It was never the plan to send the Alphas further down from there, to Galwan. Major Ajit Singh's Bravo company was to take that post. However, when he insisted that his company remain at Hot Springs, the task befell the Alphas. And that is how, in October, about 60 soldiers ended up at the Galwan post: unexpectedly and without much preparation.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody" dir="ltr">Numerous difficulties would beset the Alphas at Galwan. Apart from heavy snowfall, Chinese posts closed off the land route completely. The post was entirely dependent on air supplies, which meant that on occasion, supplies would also land on the enemy side. The Chinese also kept up their attacks to demoralise the Alphas by circling the posts and yelling propaganda slogans like <em>‘Hindi Chini Bhai Bhai'.</em></p>

<p dir="ltr">The Jats prepared four posts in the complex: the company headquarters with one section under Major Srikant Sitaram Hasabnis, a platoon under Subedar Hoshiar Singh, another section under Naik Inder Singh, and a post comprising the remaining men under Subedar Nihal Singh. There was no communication between these posts. Supplies were in limited numbers too, with 16 soldiers reportedly lacking any kind of weaponry. Even the radio communication between the headquarters of the company and that of the battalion was only as per schedule. Every soldier was scared and felt as though they had been thrown into a death trap.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>When Bullets Rained</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">A week passed eventlessly after the last soldier landed in Galwan. But it was an eerie peace, not to last too long. In the early hours of October 20, Major Hasabnis, who was in his tent then, heard a machine gun being fired at his post. As he peeked outside, he was met with a barrage of firing from the Chinese side.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">In no time, firing from all directions engulfed the area. Bullets from rifles, machine guns, and artillery were pelting the ground. Major Hasabnis approached the tent with the radio to alert the battalion and brigade headquarters that they had been attacked by the Chinese. Except, it was radio silence period at the headquarters, which meant that there was no one to alert or ask for help from. The Alphas, thus, with no contact with the outside world, were now left to tackle the Chinese all by themselves.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The remaining company positions were out of sight. Amid heavy gunfire, a company headquarters soldier was seen sitting outside, in the open. Someone questioned him, "Why are you doing this?" He replied, "<em>Intezaar, Saab</em>" ("Waiting, Sir"). One of the 16 unarmed men, he was waiting for the shot that would kill him. Even Major Hasabnis had but just a pistol on him.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Deterred By Nothing</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Subedar Nihal Singh's post was also pounded. After the shelling stopped for a while, the infantry launched a battalion-sized assault on the forward defences. Troops kept fighting from their crumbling defences, and amidst that, Nihal Singh went from man to man, encouraging them to fight till the end.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Not too far away, the JCO was fatally wounded in shelling. Upon noticing this, Sepoy Bhopal Singh immediately ran to him, gave him aid, and moved him to a safe location. He found his LMG-1 severely wounded when he returned to his trench. Even so, he took control of the weapon and dealt severe casualties to the enemy. Ultimately, when he was left with only grenades, he lobbed them at the enemy defiantly, causing numerous fatalities. Eventually, however, as the front-line defences crumbled completely, Bhopal Singh was killed.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Fighting Till The End</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, Major Hasabnis, in the rear position, continued to take on the Chinese with his remaining troops. Captain Doctor HN Paul was advised to exit the tent and enter the trench. But before he could do so, the tent caught fire due to an incendiary round; he was presumed to have died. Company Havildar Major Banwari Lal, who was charged with organising ammunition, was also killed by a shell when he was sprinting to supply ammo.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Left, Major S.S. Hasabnis, and right, Subedar Nihal Singh" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u207i6k8_hasabnis_625x300_11_November_24.jpg" title="Left, Major S.S. Hasabnis, and right, Subedar Nihal Singh" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Left, Major S.S. Hasabnis, and right, Subedar Nihal Singh</p>
</div>

<p dir="ltr">Subedar Hoshiar Singh's isolated location wasn't spared either. Although the initial wave of the attack was repelled, the sheer extent of it was overwhelming. It was clear to Singh that it was a dire moment. After his LMG operators sustained fatal injuries, he personally fired the weapon and took on the adversary, before being shot.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Naik Inder Singh's weak section also took on a four times larger enemy valiantly. The section gave it all it had, but after an hour, when they had nothing left, they fell, with the enemy taking on their position.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>When The Chinese Seized The Post</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">The hail of gunfire ended quickly, just as it had begun. Unsettling silence suddenly descended over the Galwan complex. Hand-to-hand combat broke out as soon as the adversary closed. Soldiers who were hurt could be heard screaming. After several hours of fighting, the Chinese took complete control of the post, killing 30 Indian soldiers, including Dr. Paul. Eighteen men suffered serious injuries.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The men fought until the last bullet was shot. And even though they knew death and defeat were staring them in the eye, they did not raise the white flag of surrender. Major Hasabnis and his surviving soldiers were taken prisoner by the enemy. Galwan had been seized. Subedar Nihal Singh and one OR died in captivity, while Sepoy Roshan Lal lost his limbs.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="A picture of 5 Jat when it reached Chushul to relieve 1/8 Gorkha Rifles from several forward posts. " id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9kutdgto_jats_625x300_11_November_24.jpg" title="A picture of 5 Jat when it reached Chushul to relieve 1/8 Gorkha Rifles from several forward posts. " /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">A picture of 5 Jat when it reached Chushul to relieve 1/8 Gorkha Rifles from several forward posts.</p>
</div>

<p dir="ltr">On October 21, Chinese soldiers again opened fire on Indian helicopters as they flew over the Galwan position. The pilot, after seeing no sign of life at the post, concluded that every single man had either been killed or taken prisoner.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">It was only in May 1963 that the captives were finally repatriated. Among them, Subedar Nihal Singh was posthumously awarded Vir Chakra in recognition of his bravery and leadership.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><em>(All photos courtesy of the author)</em></p>

<p dir="ltr"><em>(Jai Samota is a student and writer from Barisadri, Chittorgarh, Rajasthan, and author of 'Major Shaitan Singh, PVC: The Man in Half Light')</em></p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kkp1eg1g_galwan_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-will-qatars-suspension-from-mediation-impact-israel-hamas-war-6993479]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Will Qatar's Suspension From Mediation Impact Israel-Hamas War?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-will-qatars-suspension-from-mediation-impact-israel-hamas-war-6993479]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 16:15:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Qatar's suspension of its crucial mediation between Israel and Hamas has crushed hopes for a long-stalled truce in the Gaza war and hostage release deal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Qatar's suspension of its crucial mediation between Israel and Hamas has crushed hopes for a long-stalled truce in the Gaza war and hostage release deal.</p>

<p>The wealthy Gulf country hosts the largest US base in the Middle East and Hamas's political office, and has played a pivotal role in indirect talks since the October 7 attack on Israel that sparked the war.</p>

<p>The negotiations offered the only hope for freeing Israeli hostages held by Hamas and ending a war that has left 43,603 people dead in Gaza, according to a toll from the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p>But Qatar announced last week that it has put its mediation on hold until Israel and Hamas show "willingness and seriousness" to end the conflict.</p>

<p><strong>- Where do talks stand? -</strong></p>

<p>Since a one-week pause in fighting last year, when scores of hostages were released in exchange for hundreds of Palestinian prisoners, successive rounds of negotiations have made no headway.</p>

<p>This month, Hamas rejected a proposal from Egypt and Qatar for a short-term truce, as it did not offer a lasting ceasefire.</p>

<p>Israel has repeatedly vowed it will not stop fighting until it achieves its war objectives -- to crush Hamas and bring the hostages home.</p>

<p>While Egypt borders Gaza and the United States is Israel's main backer, Qatar's role in the talks was unique in that was the only player able to claim neutral ground.</p>

<p>It has mediated numerous international crises in Ukraine, Syria and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>Negotiations on Gaza need a broker, and "I can't see how that would be anyone else," says Andreas Krieg, a senior lecturer at King's College London.</p>

<p>The talks are "now in a situation where there is no negotiation process anymore", he added.</p>

<p>Hamas has been weakened by the killings of leaders Yahya Sinwar in October and Ismail Haniyeh in July, to a point where it is unclear "how you maintain a negotiation process with all the main interlocutors dead", he said.</p>

<p>Anna Jacobs, a Gulf analyst with the International Crisis Group think tank, said "Hamas feels they already agreed to a US ceasefire plan over the summer".</p>

<p>But that proposal never produced an agreement.</p>

<p>Jacobs said Hamas thinks Israel is "sabotaging negotiations by constantly adding on new conditions", including keeping a military presence in Gaza.</p>

<p><strong>- Could Hamas leave Qatar? -</strong></p>

<p>Qatari foreign ministry spokesman Majed Al-Ansari on Saturday pushed back against reports suggesting that Hamas would be ejected from the country.</p>

<p>The "main goal of the (Hamas) office in Qatar is to be a channel of communication", Ansari said, adding that it had "contributed to achieving a ceasefire in previous stages".</p>

<p>A senior Hamas official told AFP that the group had received no indication from Qatar that it should leave.</p>

<p>Earlier, a diplomatic source told AFP that with Qatar pulling back in its mediation role, the Hamas office "no longer serves its purpose".</p>

<p>Given the Hamas and Qatari denials, Jacobs said that "it's unlikely that there will be a big, public closing of the Hamas office and kicking out the leadership."</p>

<p>Qatar gave Hamas a similar message in April, prompting several group members to leave for Turkey -- only to return two weeks later at the request of the United States and Israel, when negotiations proved unworkable.</p>

<p>Krieg said Hamas now appeared to be in "limbo" and that demands were mounting for expulsion in "a fairly short window of maybe a few weeks", with the most likely destination being Iran.</p>

<p>Turkey has been touted as a new host but the NATO member is unlikely to want to upset the United States, Krieg added.</p>

<p>According to Jacobs, it is possible that until US President-elect Donald Trump's January 20 inauguration, "Hamas officials will stay out of Doha until more serious negotiations resume".</p>

<p><strong>- Will Qatar bow out for good? -</strong></p>

<p>Qatar had already signalled its unhappiness in April when it said it was re-evaluating its mediator role.</p>

<p>But it has signalled its willingness to return to the table when conditions permit.</p>

<p>"This is primarily about... signalling to the world, we are mediating, we're happy to continue it, but we're also willing to put all the weight, all the leverage that we have over Hamas," Krieg said.</p>

<p>Jacobs said Qatar's relationship with Hamas had come under scrutiny from American policymakers, especially Republicans in Congress.</p>

<p>"It makes sense that they are trying to protect themselves and preemptively remove any vulnerability that Trump and a likely Republican-controlled Congress could attack," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/82cb0je_alloush-family-home-gaza_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has repeatedly vowed it will not stop fighting until it achieves its war objectives.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-challenges-dont-see-borders-as-nasa-pic-shows-smog-covered-lahore-delhi-6993387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Challenges Don't See Borders As NASA Pics Show Lahore, Delhi Smog]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-challenges-dont-see-borders-as-nasa-pic-shows-smog-covered-lahore-delhi-6993387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 16:05:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The hazardous level of pollution has forced authorities in Pakistan to close schools till November 17 in a bid to lower children's exposure to the pollution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A thick toxic blanket of smog covering eastern Pakistan and entire northern India is seen in a striking satellite image released by American <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://worldview.earthdata.nasa.gov/?v=64.49116547151472,25.4299555277525,81.23650026844116,33.3752680277525&amp;s=74.3507,31.558%2B77.2188,28.6324&amp;t=2024-11-10-T00%3A00%3A00Z">space agency NASA</a>. It shows location pins for Lahore in Pakistan's Punjab and New Delhi, with both cities under huge cloud of grey smog. Lahore - a city of 14 million people stuffed with factories on the border with India - regularly ranks among the world's most polluted cities, but it has hit record levels this month.</p>

<p>Last week, live rankings by Swiss group IQAir gave the city a pollution index score of 1165. In New Delhi and neighbouring areas, it is hovering around 350. An Air Quality Index (AQI) of 50 or below is considered good with little risk of pollution.</p>

<p>The hazardous level of pollution has forced authorities in Pakistan to close schools till November 17 in a bid to lower children's exposure to the pollution.</p>

<p>In Multan, another city of several million people some 350 kilometres away, the AQI level passed 2,000 last week, according to news agency AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Access to parks, zoos, playgrounds, historic monuments, museums and recreational areas has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistans-punjab-shuts-amusement-parks-museums-for-10-days-due-to-severe-smog-6977921">also been banned</a> along with tuk-tuks with polluting two-stroke engines and restaurants that operate barbecues without filters.</p>

<p>A "smog war room" has been set up in Pakistan's Punjab province where staff members from eight departments work towards controlling burning of farm waste and managing traffic.</p>

<p>A mix of low-grade fuel emissions from factories and vehicles and agricultural stubble burning blanket the city each winter, trapped by cooler temperatures and slow-moving winds.</p>

<p>According to World health Organisation (WHO), air pollution can trigger strokes, heart disease, lung cancer and other respiratory diseases.</p>

<p>It is particularly punishing for children and babies, and the elderly.</p>

<p>The chief pollutant is PM2.5, the fine particulate matter that poses greatest risk to health. It comes from sources like the combustion of fossil fuels, dust storms and wildfires, and has been linked to asthma, heart and lung disease, cancer, and other respiratory illnesses, as well as cognitive impairment in children.</p>

<p>PM2.5 travels deep into lung tissue where it can enter the bloodstream.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/74pblnqg_lahore-delhi-pollution_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Schools in Lahore have been closed till November 17.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/racist-texts-referencing-slavery-sent-to-black-people-across-us-fbi-starts-probe-6992818]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Racist Texts Referencing Slavery Sent To Black People Across US, Probe On]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/racist-texts-referencing-slavery-sent-to-black-people-across-us-fbi-starts-probe-6992818]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:51:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[These offensive messages have been reported in more than a dozen states, including California, Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Michigan, North Carolina, Virginia, and Alabama.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reports have been flooding in of Black people across the United States receiving disturbing text messages referencing slavery and "picking cotton", following Donald Trump's presidential election win. These racist messages have been reported in over a dozen states, including California, Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Michigan, North Carolina, Virginia, and Alabama, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/09/us/racist-texts-black-people-investigation-what-we-know/index.html"><em>CNN.</em></a>&nbsp;The messages, sent anonymously, instructed recipients to report to a "plantation" or board a bus, sparking widespread alarm and prompting investigations by the FBI and other agencies.</p>

<p>The messages often instruct recipients to report to a specific address, sometimes mentioning the incoming presidential administration. Some even target children, with reports of middle school students receiving these hateful messages. For instance, a 16-year-old girl in California received a text directing her to report to a "plantation" in North Carolina.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A friend in San Francisco received this racist text today, and after looking on social media, it seems many Black people are receiving it too. <a href="https://t.co/eDyFf3a6Ix">pic.twitter.com/eDyFf3a6Ix</a></p>
— John Ryan E (@RyanElward) <a href="https://twitter.com/RyanElward/status/1854339655245889984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The FBI is working with the Justice Department to address these incidents, while the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) is investigating alongside federal and state law enforcement. TextNow, the platform through which some of these messages were sent, told <em>CNN </em>this is a "widespread, coordinated attack".&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">FBI Statement on Offensive and Racist Text Messages<a href="https://t.co/vpQYAO6LT7">https://t.co/vpQYAO6LT7</a> <a href="https://t.co/iDtN36WhX4">pic.twitter.com/iDtN36WhX4</a></p>
— FBI (@FBI) <a href="https://twitter.com/FBI/status/1854660425607983495?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p data-analytics-observe="off" data-article-gutter="true" data-component-name="paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="cms.cnn.com/_components/paragraph/instances/cm39kvh2500303b6myksp6y0n@published">''TextNow is working alongside our industry partners to uncover more details and continue to monitor patterns to actively block any new accounts attempting to send these messages. We do not tolerate or condone the use of our service to send harassing or spam messages and will work with the authorities to prevent these individuals from doing so in the future,'' the company said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Civil rights organisations, including NAACP, one of the largest Black civil rights organisations in the US, have condemned these messages. The Southern Poverty Law Center has also weighed in, calling the messages "deeply disturbing"&nbsp;</p>

<p>''We've said it before and we'll say it again - there is no place for hate in a democracy. The threat — and the mention of slavery in 2024 — is not only deeply disturbing, but perpetuates a legacy of evil that dates back to before the Jim Crow era, and now seeks to prevent Black Americans from enjoying the same freedom to pursue life, liberty, and happiness,'' NAACP President and CEO Derrick Johnson<strong>&nbsp;</strong>said in a<em> <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://naacp.org/articles/naacp-president-condemns-racist-text-messages-sent-black-americans-across-country">press release.</a>&nbsp;</em></p>

<p>Whoever is sending the racist text messages is using anonymizing software to obscure their location, Louisiana Attorney General Liz Murrill told CNN on Friday.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j7tiapig_text-message_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The messages, sent anonymously, instructed recipients to report to a "plantation" or board a bus.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-did-not-speak-to-trump-over-phone-kremlin-denies-media-reports-news-agency-afp-6992758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Completely False": Kremlin Denies Putin, Trump Spoke Over Phone]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-did-not-speak-to-trump-over-phone-kremlin-denies-media-reports-news-agency-afp-6992758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:45:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Calling it "completely false", Moscow today rejected claims of a phone call between Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calling it "completely false", Moscow today rejected claims of a phone call between Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump last week. A report by US's Washington Post had claimed on Sunday that Trump had called up Putin, and that the two leaders had discussed the conflict in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"This is completely false information," Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov said today, adding that there has been no phone call whatsoever, between the Russian President and his US counterpart.</p>

<p>In its report, now flagged as 'fake news' by Moscow, The Washington Post had claimed that Donald Trump had called Vladimir Putin from his residence-cum-resort Mar-a-Lago in Palm Beach, Florida. The call was reportedly made on Thursday, a day after Trump and his close aide Elon Musk had spoken to Ukraine's Zelensky.</p>

<p>According to the Washington Post report, which was based on 'anonymous sources familiar with the matter', Trump had allegedly "reminded Putin" of America's sizable military presence in Europe. The report went on to claim that Trump had allegedly expressed an interest in further conversations with Putin to discuss "the resolution of Ukraine's war soon."</p>

<h2><strong>DONALD TRUMP CALLS UKRAINE'S ZELENSKY</strong></h2>

<p>Notably, in his victory speech after the 2024 US Election result was declared last week, Donald Trump had said that "I will not start wars, I will help end them", and within a few days of winning the presidential election, President-elect Trump had called his Ukrainian counterpart Zelensky.</p>

<p>After the phone call last Wednesday, President Zelensky had shared a post on X which read: "I had an excellent call with President Trump and congratulated him on his historic landslide victory - his tremendous campaign made this result possible."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cl3gesag_trump-musk_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Notably, that phone call was attended by Elon Musk too. Elon Musk was with Donald Trump at the President-elect's residence and luxury resort Mar-a-Lago. During the phone call, Donald Trump reportedly <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-asks-elon-musk-to-join-call-with-ukraines-zelensky-in-big-hint-at-his-possible-role-6976601" target="_blank">handed the phone over to Elon Musk</a> and supposedly asked the SpaceX founder to join the call with President Zelensky.</p>

<p>It is not known yet, if they discussed any change in policy the United States has towards Ukraine.</p>

<p>According to the news report by Axios, there were two surprises that day - the first being that Elon Musk spoke with Zelensky, and the second, that Zelensky was reportedly "somewhat reassured by what he heard." This shows just how important and influential a role Elon Musk could end up playing in the Trump administration 2.0.</p>

<h3><strong>ELON MUSK'S POSSIBLE ROLE</strong></h3>

<p>The report further stated that the phone call between Trump, Musk, and Zelensky lasted for nearly half-an-hour. After being congratulated by Zelensky, Mr Trump reportedly said he will support Ukraine, but didn't reveal much else.</p>

<p>Elon Musk then reassured President Zelensky that he will continue to help Ukraine via his Starlink satellite constellation. Since the Russian invasion in 2022, Elon Musk's Starlink satellite system has provided Ukraine with significant frontline advantage by allowing its armed forces to share real-time drone coordinates, data and footage between units. It also gave Ukraine's military communications support in areas where mobile phone networks were destroyed.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ab1idtb8_trump-zelenskyy-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Zelensky and Trump had met recently in New York on the sidelines of the United Nations General Assembly meet in September. The two leaders had discussed ways in which the war with Russia could end and a diplomatic solution be found. "I promise you will be happy with me," Trump had reportedly told Zelensky at that meeting.</p>

<h3><strong>PUTIN AND ZELENSKY'S DEMANDS</strong></h3>

<p>The Russian president had recently demanded that Ukraine withdraw from swathes of its eastern and southern territory as a precondition to peace talks. The Washington Post reported that people familiar with "Thursday's call" said Trump had briefly raised the question of land with Putin.</p>

<p>President Zelensky has said there should be "no concessions" to Putin. Ceding land or giving in to any of Moscow's other hard line demands would only embolden the Kremlin and lead to more aggression, President Zelensky had said.</p>

<p>The outgoing Democratic administration of President Joe Biden has confirmed that it will send as much aid as possible to Ukraine before Trump's inauguration on January 20.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Biden's National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said the White House aims "to put Ukraine in the strongest possible position on the battlefield so that it is ultimately in the strongest possible position at the negotiating table."</p>

<p>This would include using the remaining $6 billion of funding for Ukraine available, Mr Sullivan said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/trump-putin_650x400_61522134039.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kremlin denied that Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump had spoken on the phone about the Ukraine conflict]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barbie-maker-mattel-mistakenly-prints-porn-site-address-on-dolls-package-apologises-6992507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Barbie Maker Mistakenly Prints Porn Site Address On Dolls Package. Apologises]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barbie-maker-mattel-mistakenly-prints-porn-site-address-on-dolls-package-apologises-6992507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:38:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Toy manufacturer Mattel has apologised for mistakenly printing the web address of an adult site on the packaging of dolls released in tie-up with the new Wicked movie.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Toy manufacturer Mattel has apologised for mistakenly printing the web address of an adult site on the packaging of dolls released in tie-up with the new Wicked movie. The company said it was taking “immediate action” in this regard.</p>

<p>Over the weekend, the Wicked film merchandise became a nightmare for the company after people started sharing images of the dolls' packaging on social media, highlighting how it shows a link to '<a data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://wicked.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1731400754787000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2pA5Xlffn8OwYyA2-4PmJc" href="http://wicked.com/" target="_blank">wicked.com</a>', instead of '<a data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://wickedmovie.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1731400754787000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0n2dobdvQX14zmJsC4J8RC" href="http://wickedmovie.com/" target="_blank">wickedmovie.com</a>', <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2024/nov/11/mattel-apologises-after-mistakenly-linking-to-porn-website-on-wicked-dolls">The Guardian</a> reported.</p>

<p>The link was printed on the boxes of Glinda and Elphaba dolls -- the two lead characters in Wicked, played by Ariana Grande and Cynthia Erivo in the film adaptation.</p>

<p>Addressing the error, Mattel released a statement on Sunday and said, "Mattel was made aware of a misprint on the packaging of the Mattel Wicked collection dolls, primarily sold in the US, which intended to direct consumers to the official WickedMovie.com landing page".</p>

<p>The company noted that it "deeply regrets this unfortunate error" and was taking immediate action to remedy this.&nbsp;Further, it advised parents that the "misprinted, incorrect website is not appropriate for children."</p>

<p>"Consumers who already have the product are advised to discard the product packaging or obscure the link and may contact Mattel customer service for further information," the statement added.</p>

<p>It seems that the misprint on the dolls' packaging affected the ones being sold on platforms like Target, Kohls and Amazon, the film's official retail partners.</p>

<p>On Amazon's US website, these dolls have now been listed as “currently unavailable”. The collection included fashion dolls, singing figurines as well as deluxe collectible models.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/wicked-dolls-mattel-mistakenly-link-to-adult-porn-site-1236058013/">The Hollywood Reporter</a>, the entire Mattel-manufactured doll collection was no longer available on Target by Sunday afternoon.</p>

<p>It added that products, having misprinted websites, are present on eBay for sale, anywhere between $100 to $800.</p>

<p>Directed by Jon M. Chu, the adaptation of the popular Broadway musical is all set to hit screens in the US on November 22.</p>

<p>The epic musical fantasy film also features Jonathan Bailey, Ethan Slater, Bowen Yang, Marissa Bode, Peter Dinklage, Michelle Yeoh and Jeff Goldblum.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lu6de20g_wicked-doll_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company Mattel said it was taking "immediate action" in this regard.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-police-use-hologram-to-solve-2009-amsterdam-sex-workers-murder-6992272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dutch Police Use Hologram To Solve 2009 Amsterdam Sex Worker's Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-police-use-hologram-to-solve-2009-amsterdam-sex-workers-murder-6992272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:31:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Netherlands Police are using an innovative life-size hologram of a sex worker, killed in Amsterdam in February 2009, to uncover new information about the cold case and bring her killer or killers to justice.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands Police are using an innovative life-size hologram of a sex worker, killed in Amsterdam in February 2009, to uncover new information about the cold case and bring her killer or killers to justice. The hologram has been placed behind a window in Amsterdam's Red Light district. Sitting on a stool, it looks at people passing by and appears to knock on the window. The glass fogs up, while the word “help” appears on it, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/10/europe/dutch-police-hologram-sex-worker-cold-case-intl/index.html">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>The hologram is modelled on Bernadett Szabó, known as Betty, who was found murdered in the Dutch capital in 2009.&nbsp;Created using 3D visualisation technology, it also features a large dragon tattoo covering Betty's stomach and chest.</p>

<p>A house in the area has been dedicated entirely to Betty's murder, with large stickers on the windows and TV screens showing the crime scene, a documentary and images of the woman.</p>

<p>This holographic has been created to reach out to people, who may have knowledge about the murder case but did not come forward at the time of the incident.</p>

<p>In the official statement, Benjamin van Gogh, coordinator of the Amsterdam Wanted and Missing Persons Team, noted that it was "difficult to determine what it takes to get possible witnesses, in this case, to share their information with us”.</p>

<p>“Betty's hologram may create a certain connection with her and thus convince a person to come forward. In this type of case, we always try to put a face on a victim, so that informants know who they're doing it for, and the hologram is a way of taking this a step further," CNN quoted the official as saying.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Dutch police said that Szabó was born and brought up in poverty in the Hungarian city of Nyíregyháza, before shifting to Amsterdam at the age of 18. After landing in the city, she began earning money as a sex worker in the red light district. After becoming pregnant, she continued to work throughout her pregnancy and later gave birth to a son in November 2008. The child was later placed with a foster family.</p>

<p>Betty was found dead on the night of February 19, 2009, when two of her fellow sex workers reached her workroom on Oudezijds Achterburgwal. They realised they didn't see her or hear the music she usually played. At around 1 AM, they found her body stabbed dozens of times. She was 19,<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/10/dutch-police-use-hologram-to-try-to-solve-2009-sex-worker-killing"> The Guardian </a>reported.</p>

<p>For the past 15 years, police carried out a large-scale investigation into the case, monitoring CCTVs and interviewing witnesses. The case remained unsolved.</p>

<p>The reward for any information related to the case has been hiked to €30,000 (around $32,160).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/scq145k8_amsterdam-sex-workers-murder_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The hologram has been placed behind a window in Amsterdam's Red Light district.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sabae-this-small-city-is-the-eyeglasses-capital-of-japan-why-you-must-visit-6992093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Small City Is The 'Eyeglasses Capital' Of Japan: Why You Must Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sabae-this-small-city-is-the-eyeglasses-capital-of-japan-why-you-must-visit-6992093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:30:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sabae, a small city in Japan's Fukui Prefecture, has earned the title eyeglasses capital' for producing over 90% of the nation's frames.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sabae, a small city in Japan's Fukui Prefecture, has earned the title ‘eyeglasses capital' for producing over 90% of the nation's frames. Sabae offers visitors an opportunity to explore the craft behind its spectacles.</p>

<p>The city's journey into the eyeglass industry began in 1905 when a local government official invited skilled artisans to the city to create new economic opportunities for farmers. This initiative has since flourished, and today, the city is home to over 100 companies specialising in eyeglass production, according to a report on <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/sabae-eyeglasses-capital-of-japan-fukui-hnk-intl/index.htm">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>The process combines cutting-edge technology with the expertise of skilled artisans. That it is still largely manual sets the city apart from so many other parts of the world known for its expertise in the industry. Takeshi Yamae, a frame designer for the Japanese company Boston Club, says a single pair of glasses may need more than 200 steps. “From the time I start designing, to the time I have the perfect product, it takes more than a year. I start by thinking about who I want to wear it. I often get inspiration from very Japanese things, for example, houses, gardens and tableware,” Yamae says.</p>

<p><strong>Why visit Sabae?</strong></p>

<p>Though frames created by Sabae are found across Japan, there's something unique about the city and seeing the process firsthand. Some artisans who work on the frame production process focus exclusively on one expertise throughout their careers, including machine cutting, polishing or nose pad attachment.</p>

<p>“Everyone in factories in Sabae wants to make beautiful, high-quality products that can be used around the world,” Yamae adds.</p>

<p>The Megane Museum in Sabae offers visitors an in-depth look at the craft, with displays illustrating the numerous stages of frame creation. The museum also hosts workshops where tourists can design and create their frames — an ideal souvenir. For those short on time, the museum shop offers thousands of frames from around 50 local manufacturers.</p>

<p>Apart from this, visitors can also explore the city's eyewear-themed street signs, exhibits, and events, further cementing Sabae's reputation as the eyeglasses capital.</p>

<p>Recent upgrades to transportation have made it simpler than ever to visit Sabae. A new bullet train extension, launched in 2024, connects the Hokuriku region with Tokyo, making Sabae and Fukui province more accessible to international tourists. The extension includes a stop at Fukui Station, where visitors can easily reach Sabae.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ga3fabao_sabae-japan_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sabae's journey into the eyeglass industry began in 1905.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-or-canada-which-way-will-trump-look-6992629]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India Or Canada: Which Way Will Trump Look?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-or-canada-which-way-will-trump-look-6992629]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 14:29:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With Trump's return to the Oval Office just weeks away, some in India are already hoping that he will put New Delhis new adversary, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, in his place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7lgvhhno_trump_625x300_11_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It's no surprise that many Indians—including some former diplomats—are celebrating Donald Trump's reelection. After all, Trump's bond with India, and particularly with Prime Minister Narendra Modi, was the envy of many countries and leaders during his first term. Granted, some might say they were mere optics: remember appearances at rallies like “Howdy, Modi!” and “Namaste, Trump!” in Houston and Ahmedabad?</p>

<p>With Trump's return to the Oval Office just weeks away, some in India are already hoping that he will put New Delhi's new adversary, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, in his place. After all, Trump's past comments on Trudeau range from “weak” to “two-faced", to even “far-left lunatic”—hardly a subtle hint of his opinion of his neighbouring country's leader.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Canadians Are Worried</strong></h2>

<p>For Canadians, though, Trump's second term has sparked more shock than celebration. Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland (also the country's finance minister) held two press conferences post his election to calm Canadian nerves, saying Canada will be “absolutely fine”. Yet, many Canadians remain uneasy over Trump's return to the White House, and for good reason. There are three big areas of anxiety: tariffs, NATO contributions and the looming renegotiation of the US-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA).</p>

<p>First, Trump has hinted at slapping a blanket 10% tariff on all imports to the US, which would hit Canada hard given that more than two-thirds of its exports are US-bound. Then there is Trump's expectation that NATO members chip in a full 2% of their GDP on defence. Canada is currently far behind and contributing only 1.23%—a potential sticking point if Trump insists on the required contributions like he did during the last term. Lastly, there's the USMCA, which Trump himself strong-armed Canada and Mexico into renegotiating in 2020. Trump has hinted that the deal is set for review in 2026. Canadians worry that the President-elect could push for even stricter terms this time around.</p>

<h2><strong>Will Trump Side With India?</strong></h2>

<p>Biden's team and its Western European pals are clearly frustrated with India's refusal to oppose Russia over the Ukraine war. They have not said it out loud, but it's hard not to suspect that they are quietly backing Trudeau behind the scenes in his finger-pointing at India, accusing officials of involvement in the killing of Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar. Let's be real—it wasn't without Big Brother's nod that Trudeau stood in Parliament last year hurling accusations at India. Furthermore, if Canada decides to move forward with these allegations, the possibility is it won't be acting alone. The US and the UK, key members of the Five Eyes alliance, have often helped manage diplomatic and security issues with countries outside the alliance. Since both countries have close ties with India, they may help Canada weigh the strength and possible impact of these accusations before taking any official steps. Still, accusing a powerful country like India could affect important strategic interests.</p>

<p>Moreover, the possible egging on by Big Brother suits Trudeau too, giving him a shot at placating his Sikh voter base and propping up his waning popularity. However, only a rookie diplomat, I would say, can fully trust the self-serving strategy that the US usually follows.</p>

<p>We cannot underplay US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller's blunt statement last month: “When it comes to the Canadian matter, we have made clear that the allegations are extremely serious and they need to be taken seriously. We wanted to see the government of India cooperate with Canada in its investigation. Obviously, they have not chosen that path.” &nbsp;The statement did not reflect India's position that there was complete disregard for New Delhi's request to Ottawa to share evidence. And now, with allegations of India's involvement in an attempted assassination, the Biden administration has another card to play. Nonetheless, India is cooperating with the US on the investigation and neither side wants to blow it out of proportion.</p>

<p>Now, as Trump re-enters his office, his promise to end the war in Ukraine, if fulfilled, will be a game-changer. Without Ukraine in the equation, the US pressure on India to pick a side goes out of the window, and Biden's “cold-shoulder” tactics would become a non-issue. Trump, however, we all know, is a wildcard. While he may want closer ties with India, we know how that “America First” agenda translates: tariffs, immigration restrictions and a hard line on H-1B visas. Fortunately though, Trump's stance on Russia (to end the war) aligns with India's, as does his anti-China focus. It's quite possible he might ask Trudeau to either produce proof in the Nijjar case or drop the offensive. Who knows.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>But Don't Underestimate US-Canada Bond</strong></h2>

<p>Even so, we should never underestimate America's deep-rooted ties with Canada—they are in a league of their own. Sure, Trump and Trudeau have clashed publicly, but Trudeau is not one to be caught off guard. On Thursday, he revealed that his officials had been quietly talking to Trump's campaign team for months, readying for a potential return. Trudeau didn't waste a minute—he reinstated a Cabinet committee on US-Canada relations, led by Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland, to deal with anything Trump 2.0 might throw at them. And he was among the first to call Trump after the win, showing that when it comes to the US, Trudeau is all about pragmatism, or, dare I say, even subservience. His office spelt it out well: “Following the election of President Donald Trump for a second term, the Cabinet Committee will focus on critical Canada-US issues.”</p>

<p>The US-Canada relationship is unlike anything else in the world. The two countries are more like siblings rather than neighbours, no matter who sits in the Oval Office. They are two very prosperous countries: Canada's per capita income is over $58,000, while America's is $81,000. They have got each other's backs on defence, border security, and law enforcement. The overlap is everywhere—from culture and sports to leisure and shared traditions. They have much more in common between them than either of them has with India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Consider this: in 2023, the US-Canada trade hit over a trillion dollars, with $2.8 billion crossing their border every single day. They are each other's biggest trade partners, with Canada sending 78% of its goods and services to the US every year, and over 400,000 people moving across their shared 5,525-mile border daily.</p>

<h2><strong>Canada Has Five Eyes By Its Side&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Let's keep in mind that Canada is a NATO member and the countries in the grouping are quite united and usually back each other against any third party. Then there is the intelligence-sharing bond under the Five Eyes institution. The Five Eyes alliance—a formidable network comprising the US, the UK, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand—has been at the forefront of global intelligence operations for decades. The alliance was built to facilitate intelligence collection and sharing among its members, ensuring a near-seamless flow of critical security information. In light of Canada's recent allegations against Indian officials, the alliance ought to have played a crucial role in sharing information with Canadian intelligence officials.</p>

<p>Also, as a core member of the Five Eyes, Canada has access to intelligence and insights that most nations can only aspire to attain. If Canada believes it has intelligence linking Indian officials to Nijjar's assassination, it is likely benefiting from the information-sharing protocols within the Five Eyes network. Notably, Canada may be leveraging Five Eyes capabilities to cross-reference signals intelligence (SIGINT) and other classified insights, allowing them to build a stronger case against India, should any concrete evidence exist.</p>

<h2><strong>Let Canada's Voters Decide</strong></h2>

<p>Anyway, India might just have to play the waiting game until Canada's next general election, now less than a year away. Trudeau's grip on power since he took office in 2015 is looking shakier than ever today. If he is out of the picture, the new government's stance on India could breathe fresh life into those frosty bilateral ties.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/58f320r_trump-canda_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baltasar-engonga-the-equatorial-guinea-official-involved-in-massive-sex-tapes-row-6992158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Baltasar Engonga: The Equatorial Guinea Official Involved In Sex Tapes Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baltasar-engonga-the-equatorial-guinea-official-involved-in-massive-sex-tapes-row-6992158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:28:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of videos showing Baltasar Ebang Engonga having sex with different women have gone viral.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Baltasar Ebang Engonga, a high-ranking Equatorial Guinea official, has been fired after hundreds of videos showing him having sex with women went viral on social media.</p>

<p>In the videos, Engonga, who is married and is said to be in his 50s, is seen with different partners &nbsp;-- including the wives of prominent officials -- at his office in the finance ministry and other places.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to reports, around 400 of his sex tapes - which were filmed on unknown dates - have been leaked.</p>

<p>Authorities have warned the telecommunications ministry, regulator and telephone companies "to curb the distribution of pornographic videos that are flooding social networks".</p>

<p>#BaltasarEbangEngonga has been trending as one of the most discussed themes online.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Baltasar Ebang Engonga</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/equatorial-guinea-civil-servant-baltasar-ebang-engonga-under-scanner-over-hundreds-of-sex-tapes-6949028">Baltasar Ebang Engonga</a> is the director of the National Financial Investigation Agency (ANIF). He is nicknamed "Bello" because of his good looks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Engonga is the son of Baltasar Engonga Edjo, the current Chairman of the Commission of the Central African Economic and Monetary Community. He is also related to the country's long-serving president.</p>

<p>Tasked to tackle crimes such as money laundering, he himself was arrested on October 25 for embezzling a huge sum of money from state coffers and depositing it in secret accounts in the Cayman Islands.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was taken to the infamous Black Beach prison in the capital, Malabo.</p>

<p>His phones and computers were seized, and a few days later, his sex clips went viral online.</p>

<p>Chief prosecutor Anatolio Nzang Nguema has said that if medical exams revealed that Engonga was "infected with a sexually transmitted disease", he would be prosecuted for an offence against "public health".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3jst2ug8_baltasar-ebang-engonga_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Baltasar Ebang Engonga is the director of the National Financial Investigation Agency]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kai-trump-plays-golf-with-grandpa-donald-trump-bonus-elon-musk-6991962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kai Trump Plays Golf With Grandpa Donald Trump. Bonus: Elon Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kai-trump-plays-golf-with-grandpa-donald-trump-bonus-elon-musk-6991962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:16:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump spent his Sunday afternoon on the golf course with two granddaughters, Kai and Chloe Trump, days after securing a historic win against Democrat rival Kamala Harris in US Election 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump spent his Sunday afternoon on the golf course with two granddaughters, Kai and Chloe Trump, days after securing a historic win against Democrat rival Kamala Harris in US Election 2024.</p>

<p>Kai shared photographs and videos from the family outing on X and Instagram. Her post also featured Tesla CEO Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Sharing an image with her grandfather, she wrote, "Sundays with Grandpa," accompanied by a yellow heart emoji.</p>

<p>In another photograph, Kai, 17, and her sister Chloe, 10, posed with their grandfather.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sundays with Grandpa ???? <a href="https://t.co/UfKdu0RJI7">pic.twitter.com/UfKdu0RJI7</a></p>
— Kai Trump (@KaiTrumpGolfs) <a href="https://twitter.com/KaiTrumpGolfs/status/1855728246253580514?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The family was at the Trump International Golf Club West Palm Beach, a few miles west of the Mar-a-Lago resort, Fox News reported.</p>

<p>Donald Trump, 78, was seen in a white polo t-shirt with his campaign slogan, “Make America Great Again”. He also wore a white hat with the same phrase. His granddaughters wore golf skirts and white sneakers for their session.</p>

<p>Along with the two photographs, Kai also shared a few videos of her golfing skills.</p>

<p>In another post on X, Kai posed with Musk and his 4-year-old son, X Æ A-12.</p>

<p>"Elon achieving uncle status," she captioned the image along with a laughing emoji.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Elon achieving uncle status ???? <a href="https://t.co/vufSffziZN">pic.twitter.com/vufSffziZN</a></p>
— Kai Trump (@KaiTrumpGolfs) <a href="https://twitter.com/KaiTrumpGolfs/status/1855734110062272874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
Musk's son, whom the richest person in the world shared with his ex Grimes, can be seen holding a golf ball over his eye in the image.</p>

<p>Earlier, Kai Trump shared a family photograph of Donald Trump, his five children, five grandchildren as well as Elon Musk. However, Melania Trump was nowhere to be seen in the image.</p>

<p>"The whole squad," read the caption.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The whole squad <a href="https://t.co/5yQVkFiney">pic.twitter.com/5yQVkFiney</a></p>
— Kai Trump (@KaiTrumpGolfs) <a href="https://twitter.com/KaiTrumpGolfs/status/1854274706448199849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Musk is believed to have spent a whopping $119 million to mobilise support for Trump during his presidential bid in 2024. He even actively campaigned for Trump in swing states.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d2e8e4io_kai-trump-donald-trump-twitter_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kai Trump Sharing an image with her grandfather, Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/system-glitch-leads-to-vpn-disruption-across-pakistan-6991859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["System Glitch" Leads To VPN Disruption Across Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/system-glitch-leads-to-vpn-disruption-across-pakistan-6991859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:16:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Internet users across Pakistan faced disruptions in accessing virtual private networks (VPNs) over the weekend, impacting both fixed broadband and mobile data connections, Dawn reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Internet users across Pakistan faced disruptions in accessing virtual private networks (VPNs) over the weekend, impacting both fixed broadband and mobile data connections, Dawn reported.</p>

<p>The report stated citing industry sources, that an "issue with the system" temporarily affected VPN connectivity. However, the Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA) has yet to comment on the matter, with its spokesperson not responding to inquiries on Sunday.</p>

<p>Since the government banned the social media platform X in February, VPN use has grown among users who rely on it to bypass local restrictions. Earlier this year, prolonged internet disruptions also led many to use proxy networks.</p>

<p>Over the weekend, unconfirmed social media reports suggested that the PTA might have banned certain VPNs; however, authorities attributed the disruption to a "brief" glitch in the system rather than any official restriction.</p>

<p>"We have been told by officials that access to VPNs was briefly disrupted for 30 minutes to an hour due to a glitch in the system," an industry insider told Dawn, emphasising that the disruption was short-lived.</p>

<p>Downdetector, a platform that monitors internet disruptions, confirmed complaints from users of VPN Unlimited, with reports peaking at 6:15 pm, and Tunnelbear users logging issues as late as 7:29 pm, reported Dawn.</p>

<p>Enterprises with registered VPNs also experienced connectivity issues, according to two industry sources. PTA has previously asked businesses, including software houses, call centres, freelancers, and foreign missions, to register their VPNs and IP addresses with the authority to maintain "uninterrupted" service during any network disruption.</p>

<p>In a statement issued in September amid complaints of slow internet speeds, PTA emphasised its commitment to supporting the tech industry, noting that "IP addresses for VPNs are being registered for software houses, business and IT companies."</p>

<p>Since 2020, more than 20,000 VPNs and IP addresses have reportedly been registered, according to Dawn.</p>

<p>Digital rights advocate Farieha Aziz criticised the lack of transparency surrounding the interruptions, stating, "It's completely arbitrary, disrupting everyday life and work and no one in the PTA and government has yet given a straight answer."</p>

<p>Another activist, Usama Khilji, expressed concerns that such disruptions align with "the state's plans to clamp down on VPNs" and warned that these actions could adversely affect sectors reliant on VPNs, particularly in finance and tech.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6s4542g8_computer-generic_625x300_02_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[VPN use has grown among users who rely on it to bypass local restrictions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arab-leaders-meet-in-saudi-arabia-likely-to-discuss-donald-trumps-win-6992006]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Arab Leaders Meet In Saudi Arabia, Likely To Discuss Donald Trump's Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arab-leaders-meet-in-saudi-arabia-likely-to-discuss-donald-trumps-win-6992006]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:06:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Arab and Muslim leaders gather in Saudi Arabia Monday for a summit addressing the wars in Gaza and Lebanon, a chance to send a message to US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Arab and Muslim leaders gather in Saudi Arabia Monday for a summit addressing the wars in Gaza and Lebanon, a chance to send a message to US President-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The Saudi foreign ministry announced plans for the summit in late October during a meeting, also in Riyadh, of a new "international alliance" to press for the establishment of a Palestinian state.</p>

<p>It comes one year after a similar gathering in Riyadh of the Cairo-based Arab League and the Jeddah-based Organisation of Islamic Cooperation during which leaders condemned Israeli forces' actions in Gaza as "barbaric".</p>

<p>This time around, Trump's election last week for a second term in the White House is likely to be on leaders' minds, said Anna Jacobs, senior Gulf analyst for the International Crisis Group think tank.</p>

<p>"This summit is very much an opportunity for regional leaders to signal to the incoming Trump administration what they want in terms of US engagement," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The message will likely be one of dialogue, de-escalation and calling out Israeli military campaigns in the region."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The war in Gaza erupted with Hamas's unprecedented attack on southern Israel on October 7 last year, which resulted in 1,206 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed more than 43,600 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to data from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry that the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>Lebanon-based Hezbollah, which like Hamas is backed by Iran, began firing on Israel after the October 7 attack. The regular cross-border exchanges escalated in late September when Israel intensified its air strikes and sent ground troops into southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Despite criticism of the impact Israel's military campaign has had on Gaza civilians, outgoing US President Joe Biden ensured that Washington remained Israel's most important military backer during more than a year of fighting.</p>

<h3><strong>'Rely on the Saudis'</strong></h3>

<p>In his first term, Trump's actions showed him as an even firmer supporter of Israel. He defied international consensus by recognising Jerusalem as Israel's capital and moving Washington's embassy there.</p>

<p>He also endorsed Israeli settlements in the occupied West Bank, which are illegal under international law.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Under the Abraham Accords, Trump oversaw the establishment of diplomatic relations between Israel, the United Arab Emirates and Bahrain, as well as Morocco.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though Saudi Arabia did not join those agreements, Trump cultivated warm ties with the Gulf kingdom while in office and has deepened his business connections to the region during the Biden years.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia has pressed pause on a US-brokered deal where it would recognise Israel in return for security and economic benefits, insisting there will be no diplomatic ties without a Palestinian state.</p>

<p>Umer Karim, an expert on Saudi politics at the University of Birmingham, said Riyadh will use Monday's summit to signal to the incoming Trump team that it remains a strong partner.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The message is that Trump "can rely on the Saudis as being representatives of the Muslim world", and that "if you want to extend American interests in the region, Saudi Arabia is your bet", he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 57-member OIC and 22-member Arab League include countries which recognise Israel and those firmly opposed to its regional integration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last year's summit in Riyadh saw disagreement on measures like severing economic and diplomatic ties with Israel and disrupting its oil supplies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Karim said the post-summit statement on Monday will likely "strongly condemn Israel...while also pushing for greater American leverage and diplomacy on the issue."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The November 2023 meeting featured an appearance by Iran's then-president Ebrahim Raisi, highlighting how regional diplomacy has changed since Trump was last in office.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March 2023, Iran and Saudi Arabia announced a China-brokered rapprochement after seven years of severed ties. The Middle East heavyweights have maintained regular high-level contact as part of efforts to contain the ongoing conflicts.</p>

<p>Iranian state media said the chief of staff of the Saudi armed forces was to arrive in Tehran Sunday for talks, a rare high-level visit.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdrhbtag_arab-leaders_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/musk-to-ackman-the-growing-opposition-to-inclusive-hiring-6991985]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Musk To Ackman, Why Are Companies Opposing 'Inclusive' Hiring?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/musk-to-ackman-the-growing-opposition-to-inclusive-hiring-6991985]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:00:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The whole concept of DEI  which encompasses women, people of colour, and those in the LGBTQ+ community  has come under attack in the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qjip1lco_hiring_625x300_11_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On November 1, US aircraft manufacturer Boeing made the controversial decision to dismantle its DEI (Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion) department. The company's former Vice President of Global DEI, Sara Bowen, announced her resignation on the social media platform LinkedIn.</p>

<p>Boeing has faced significant criticism for its quality and safety practices following two incidents in January this year. In the first, the door plug of a Boeing 737 Max blew off mid-flight, leaving a large hole in the side of an Alaska Airlines plane. In the same month, another Boeing aircraft had its nose wheel fall off just before a Delta flight took off.</p>

<p>Since then, the company has been explicitly targeted on social media by billionaire Elon Musk and other traditional critics, who suggest that some of Boeing's quality issues stem from its decision to include diversity targets in its 2022 bonus plan. After facing these criticisms, Boeing revised its incentive plan to focus more on quality and safety earlier this year.</p>

<p>The whole concept of DEI — which encompasses women, people of colour, and those in the LGBTQ+ community — has come under attack in the US. Detractors argue openly that DEI employees lack the qualifications, skills, or intelligence to contribute to society through jobs, education, or leadership.</p>

<p>One must also consider whether the anti-DEI sentiment has had any impact in India.</p>

<h2><strong>Resentment In US</strong></h2>

<p>Following the Alaska Airlines incident, Elon Musk posted on X: "Do you want to fly in an airplane where they prioritised DEI hiring over your safety? That is actually happening." He added later: "People will die due to DEI."</p>

<p>Reports indicate that investigations into the incidents pointed to other factors, including a lack of quality control, outdated technology, and financial irregularities. However, these findings did not satisfy DEI critics, who celebrated Boeing's November 1 announcement of dismantling its DEI department.</p>

<p>Although the step may seem exaggerated, there is a growing anti-DEI movement in the US. Another American billionaire, Bill Ackman, wrote on X that DEI policies were "inherently racist" and "illegal", despite claims that they work "on behalf of the oppressed". Musk endorsed these views, even as his company Tesla reportedly removed all outreach programmes for minority communities from its annual filing.</p>

<p>This pushback against DEI programmes has led companies like Toyota, Ford, and others to re-evaluate or even close down their DEI departments. Experts attribute this backlash to social tension, largely coming from ‘white Americans' who feel disadvantaged in the job market.</p>

<h2><strong>The Indian Scenario</strong></h2>

<p>In India, DEI was an alien concept until multinational companies (MNCs) introduced it, mostly due to mandates from their foreign parent companies. Since then, the IT and services sectors have implemented formal DEI policies.</p>

<p>In India, DEI initiatives tend to focus on the inclusion of women, queer people, and, to some extent, those with physical disabilities. Given that the policy is largely US-inspired, are Indian companies facing similar challenges?</p>

<p>DEI expert Saundarya Rajesh, founder-president of the Avtar Group, states: “It is unfortunate that some global organisations are choosing to dismantle DEI. However, this is not a phenomenon that has severe local implications in India Inc.”</p>

<p>“Corporate India continues to recognise that inclusion is an integral part of organisational culture and a non-negotiable employee experience that needs to be delivered.” Indian subsidiaries of MNCs and some prominent Indian conglomerates have set diversity hiring as a goal. This is often driven by investor pressure or requirements from global partners, and the easiest way to meet these demands is by reserving roles for women in HR, ESG, finance, digital, communications, and other areas, as talent in these functions is readily available in the local job market.</p>

<p>However, roles in infrastructure and other front-facing sectors rarely see diversity hiring, as companies do not specifically reserve positions for women in these areas. Though diversity in such roles is often selected on merit, some companies aim to prioritise diversity in hiring, which can inadvertently exclude male candidates. This leads to discontent among those who feel overlooked.</p>

<p>“Positive discrimination must always ensure that merit is never compromised. If we can uphold this principle, much of the political hijacking associated with DEI can be addressed. You may still select a DEI nominee, but only if they are on par with the rest. Not one bit less,” says Prabir Jha, founder &amp; CEO of Prabir Jha People Advisory.</p>

<h2><strong>Loss of Talent?</strong></h2>

<p>DEI policies were originally designed to foster inclusivity by ensuring diverse representation in workplaces. However, their implementation has raised concerns about compromising meritocracy, as seen in the US. This has led to the loss of potential talent and opportunity costs.</p>

<p>"Focusing on DEI does not necessitate a compromise on meritocracy. What it requires is an inclusive and equitable strategy, where decisions around hiring and advancement are diversity-sensitive, delivering on the vision of equal opportunities for all,” says Saundarya Rajesh.</p>

<p>In the West, DEI is meant to give a voice to the voiceless. It is also intended to ensure that the views of the most junior employee are heard in meetings.</p>

<p>In India, however, diversity is often viewed narrowly through the lens of ‘female hiring', which means there is a significant opportunity to broaden the focus to policies that promote a truly inclusive workplace. Experts suggest that certain areas remain sacrosanct, where positive discrimination should have no place. Merit should always be the sole criterion for selection, as the impact of an incorrect decision, whether by omission or commission, could have far-reaching consequences.</p>

<p>“Never give away board positions, management roles, promotions, and hire ‘only diversity candidates'. This does more harm to the cause than good. Inclusion must always feel inclusive. If you remain true to the principles of meritocracy, you will eliminate any bias against diversity,” says Jha.</p>

<p>Americans have displayed their resistance to this form of affirmative action, as evidenced by the rejection of Kamala Harris, a Black and South Asian woman, who critics labelled a "DEI hire". Let's hope that India's approach to DEI avoids the pitfalls of unconscious bias.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i371ppl8_hiring_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cheese-heists-on-the-rise-how-organised-crime-is-exploiting-dairy-industry-6991793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cheese Heists On The Rise: How Organised Crime Is Exploiting Dairy Industry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cheese-heists-on-the-rise-how-organised-crime-is-exploiting-dairy-industry-6991793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:51:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A daring heist in the UK in October put the spotlight on the profitable but risky world of luxury cheese.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A daring heist in the UK in October put the spotlight on the profitable but risky world of luxury cheese. The incident, dubbed “the grate cheese robbery,” saw 22 tonnes of premium British cheese disappear after a fraudulent order was placed under the guise of a French supermarket chain. The stolen consignment, valued at over £300,000 (around Rs 3.26 crore), comprised specialty cheese from farms in Somerset, including Hafod, a rare cheddar aged for 18 months.</p>

<p>Patrick Holden, the dairy farmer behind Hafod, was initially thrilled by what he believed to be the largest order his farm had ever received. “It was the biggest order for our cheese we've ever received,” Holden told <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/crmz42pjpnjo">BBC</a>, adding, “And, because it was from France, I thought, ‘finally, people on the continent are appreciating what we do'.”</p>

<p>His excitement waned when the order turned out to be a scam, and the cheese disappeared after being collected by a courier. In late October, a 63-year-old man was arrested in London, he was later released on bail. Since then, there have been no updates, and the 950 truckles of cheese – around the weight of four full-size elephants – disappeared without a trace.</p>

<p>The stolen cheese, including £35,000 (around Rs 38.13 lakh) worth of Hafod, was processed through Neal's Yard Dairy, an upmarket London wholesaler. The heist shocked the cheese industry, which the criminals have targeted due to the rising value of luxury dairy products.</p>

<p>While the scale of the cheese theft was extraordinary, it is part of a broader rise in food-related crimes that cost the global food industry billions each year. Cheese, especially high-end varieties, has become an attractive target for organised criminals. From smuggling and counterfeiting to outright theft, food-related crimes have flourished, with some gangs specialising in stealing valuable products like Parmigiano Reggiano and cheddar.</p>

<p>“Cheesemaking is an energy-intensive business,” the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cje03dq2pyyo">BBC</a> quoted Patrick McGuigan, a dairy sector specialist, as saying. “There was a big price increase following the disruption caused by Russia's invasion of Ukraine,” added McGuigan. The economic impact of the war and ongoing inflation has made cheese increasingly expensive, driving demand among criminals seeking to profit from this lucrative market.</p>

<p>Notably, the price of cheese in the UK has increased of late, with some varieties seeing price hikes of up to 6.5% in just 2024. “Based on price alone, cheese is one of the most desirable foods a criminal can steal,” McGuigan said.</p>

<p>Luxury cheese theft is not only about high prices. Food holds additional appeal for criminal networks. Andy Quinn of the National Food Crime Unit (NFCU) said, “They (criminals) know crimes involving food result in less severe convictions than for importing drugs, but they can still make similar amounts of money.” It's especially true when it comes to premium cheese.</p>

<p>The black market for stolen cheese is global. In 2016, £80,000 worth of Parmigiano Reggiano was stolen in Italy.</p>

<p>“Cheese and wine are two of the most common products being transported illegally into Russia,” says Professor Chris Elliott, founder of the Global Institute for Food Security.</p>

<p>The Parmigiano Reggiano Consortium is tackling black market theft of its prized cheese by embedding tiny tracking chips in the rind. These chips, no bigger than a grain of rice, contain unique digital IDs to verify authenticity and detect stolen cheese. Buyers can scan the cheese to check its legitimacy, though the consortium has not yet released data on the impact of this technology on fraud.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/l19ui3mo_cheese-1200_625x300_24_January_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luxury cheese theft is not only about high prices.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-win-means-for-future-of-heat-pump-ev-incentives-6991884]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Donald Trump's Win Means For Future of Heat Pump, EV Incentives]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-win-means-for-future-of-heat-pump-ev-incentives-6991884]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:47:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has pledged to rescind funding for the Biden administration's signature 2022 climate law, which includes more than $8.5 billion in incentives for individuals and families to decarbonize their lives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you're thinking of buying an electric car or an energy-saving heat pump eligible for federal tax credits and rebates, now might be the time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President-Elect Donald Trump has labeled the US Inflation Reduction Act the "green new scam." He's pledged to rescind funding for the Biden administration's signature 2022 climate law, which includes more than $8.5 billion in incentives for individuals and families to decarbonize their lives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Clawing back funds already dispersed would be difficult, but that doesn't mean the Trump administration won't try," said Romany Webb, deputy director of the Sabin Center for Climate Change Law at Columbia University. "From a strictly legal perspective, there may be more avenues for the administration to withhold funds that haven't been awarded yet."</p>

<p>But "failing to move forward with announced awards may be politically unpopular," she added.</p>

<p>The IRA's benefits are manifold. The law offers up to $14,000 for low- and moderate-income households to install heat pumps, induction stoves and other high-efficiency electric appliances. Wealthier families can receive a $2,000 federal tax credit for replacing a fossil-fuel furnace or water heater with a heat pump. Some electric vehicles qualify for a $7,500 tax credit issued at the time of purchase, and a 30% tax credit is available for homeowners to install solar panels and battery storage systems.</p>

<p>US Representative Ro Khanna, a California Democrat, said on Thursday's Zero podcast that he doubts that the new Trump administration and Congressional Republicans will seek the wholesale repeal of the IRA, given the billions of dollars in benefits it funnels to their constituents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>IRA funding is distributed through the states through US Department of Energy-approved rebate programs. The federal government has paid out $1.4 billion to nine states and the District of Columbia that have begun to offer up to $8,000 for a heat pumps and $1,750 for a heat pump water heaters. They also provide $840 cash back for induction stoves and heat pump clothes dryers and $4,000 for electrical system upgrades.</p>

<p>Another 10 states have received $1.2 billion but have yet to start issuing rebates. Nine more states are awaiting federal review of their applications, which usually takes about 60 to 90 days. The rest of the states are still preparing their applications except for South Dakota, which isn't participating in the program. Florida initially declined $175 million in funding but now has submitted an application.</p>

<p>Short of repealing the IRA, though, taking those lucrative incentives away from taxpayers would prove legally difficult and politically problematic, according to David Friedman, senior policy director for Rewiring America, a nonprofit that advocates for community electrification.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The law is pretty clear that once this money is authorized, this money is required to be spent," said Friedman, a former acting assistant secretary for energy efficiency and renewable energy at the Energy Department. "Politically, it would just be a terrible move to roll these things back as every state and territory but one have applied for these rebates."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The $7,500 EV tax credit is more vulnerable as it may be subject to a law that allows Congress to review and reverse recently enacted regulations, according to a September paper by Webb and her colleagues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If we end up with a Republican-controlled Congress, there may be attempts to repeal or revise the IRA tax credits themselves," Webb said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That too could prove politically perilous. The 30% tax credit for residential solar installations, for instance, dates to 2006 and was set to expire in 2023 before the IRA extended it until 2032. Homeowners claimed $6 billion in tax credits for solar installations and battery storage last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Friedman said now is always a good time for families to take advantage of the IRA and go electric. "Regardless of what's going to happen in the future, you should do it today because it's a great deal."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r92i04ro_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The $7,500 EV tax credit is more vulnerable.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-torture-tactics-reportedly-caught-on-camera-civilians-chained-beaten-6991315]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Torture Tactics Allegedly Caught On Camera: Civilians Chained, Beaten]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-torture-tactics-reportedly-caught-on-camera-civilians-chained-beaten-6991315]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:47:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) has released CCTV footage purportedly showing brutal interrogation tactics and extreme measures Hamas operatives subject Palestinian civilians to control them, reported the New York Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) has released CCTV footage purportedly showing brutal interrogation tactics and extreme measures Hamas operatives subject Palestinian civilians to control them, reported the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/10/world-news/brutal-hamas-torture-tactics-caught-in-cctv-footage-idf/">New York Post</a>. The footage, captured between 2018 and 2020 in northern Gaza, was retrieved from a former Hamas base in Jabalia and sheds light on the terror group's tactics, the IDF said in a statement.</p>

<p>“The materials uncovered, expose Hamas's brutal methods for interrogating civilians, violating human rights, and systematically oppressing residents suspected of opposing the organization's rule,” read the IDF statement.</p>

<p>The nearly 47-minute video compilation, shared by the IDF on X, shows interrogators chaining suspects by their wrists and feet, suspending them from ceilings, covering their heads with sacks, and inflicting beatings during questioning.</p>

<p>Some civilians, bound by their wrists and ankles, can be seen suspended upside down as interrogators strike their soles with sticks. In some visuals, detainees struggle to stand on one foot while the other leg is restrained, adding to the physical torment. The footage also shows detainees in cramped, dark, and unsanitary rooms, often with interrogators ignoring them or casually conversing among themselves.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The same civilians that Hamas outspokenly claimed to be fighting for, are the same civilians being tortured in this video.<br />
<br />
Hamas is not only Israel's enemy—they're Gaza's enemy also. <a href="https://t.co/J4kasDlOCu">pic.twitter.com/J4kasDlOCu</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1855587044421947706?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
Before releasing the footage to the public, the IDF provided the clips to the <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-14063545/gaza-hamas-torture-palestine-israel.html">Daily Mail</a>, which said that it was unable to independently verify the videos.</p>

<p>Hamas has long been accused of targeting civilians suspected of collaborating with Israel or opposing the group's authority. Human rights groups and advocates have reported incidents of arbitrary detention, with allegations of torture and repression.</p>

<p>In 2022, UN Watch highlighted patterns of abuse by Hamas against human rights activists, women, LGBTQ individuals, and political opponents, describing systematic punishments in the form of physical and psychological abuse.</p>

<p>A survivor of such abuses, interviewed by<a href="https://www.i24news.tv/en/news/middle-east/palestinian-territories/1660138495-exclusive-gay-man-who-fled-gaza-speaks-about-experience-with-hamas"> i24News</a> in 2022, recounted the repeated torture he endured after being identified as gay. “They would torture me so badly,” he said, adding his feet were tied and beaten with sticks, alongside further restrictions on food, sleep, and bathroom access. “They made me swear on the Quran that I won't be gay again,” he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dosor9io_hamas-torture_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The footage, captured between 2018 and 2020 in northern Gaza, was retrieved from a former Hamas base.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hypocritical-canadian-journalist-slams-government-over-khalistani-issue-6991786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hypocritical": Canadian Journalist Slams Government Over Khalistani Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hypocritical-canadian-journalist-slams-government-over-khalistani-issue-6991786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:33:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian journalist Terry Milewski has criticized Canada's approach to the Khalistani issue, calling it "hypocritical" and a "national disgrace."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian journalist Terry Milewski has criticized Canada's approach to the Khalistani issue, calling it "hypocritical" and a "national disgrace." Speaking to ANI, Milewski expressed his concerns about Canada's handling of the issue, stating, "I have been saying for 20 years that Canada has been hypocritical in its approach to the Khalistani menace. The Khalistan issue, as it's been treated by Canada over the years, has been a national disgrace."</p>

<p>He disputed claims about Australia Today being blocked and attributed the issue to a long-standing commercial negotiation between Facebook and Canadian regulators, who insist that content creators should be paid.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-cops-arrest-banned-groups-member-over-hindu-temple-attack-6985737">Canada Cops Arrest Banned Group's Member Over Hindu Temple Attack</a></p>

<p>"All you have to do is click on the site and see if it's blocked. I can tell you that it's not; it hasn't been since the very beginning...It hasn't been blocked, it hasn't been banned, it hasn't been censored. Australia Today is an excellent publication. They serve the Indian diaspora in Australia very well. They and their supposed defenders have been fooled," Milewski said.</p>

<p>"The only problem with access to the site is if you insist on getting it only on Facebook. But if you just go to the site, there's no problem. The issue is a long-standing commercial negotiation, a difference of opinion between Facebook and Canadian regulators, who insist that content creators should be paid," he added.</p>

<p>Milewski also condemned the recent Khalistani attack on Hindu Sabha Temple in Brampton, attributing these incidents to the failure of Canadian politicians to address the growing influence of Khalistani separatism over the past 40 years.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/avoiding-mention-of-khalistanis-canadian-mp-chandra-arya-slams-politicians-6981617">"Avoiding Mention Of Khalistanis": Canadian MP Slams Politicians</a></p>

<p>"This is extremely disturbing, and it arises from the utter folly of Canadian politicians over 40 years," he said.</p>

<p>"It is an open aggression by Khalistanis aimed at Hindu temples in this case, and it is extremely worrying," he added.</p>

<p>Milewski also shared his insights on the potential impact of the US presidential election on India-Canada relations. Speaking about Donald Trump's "unpredictability", Milewski noted that Trump has a good relationship with Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who has been praising the incoming administration and looking forward to working with Trump.</p>

<p>"Trump is nothing if not unpredictable. He gets along very well with PM Modi and Modi has been very assiduous in peppering the incoming administration with praise and looking forward to working with his friend Donald Trump," he said.</p>

<p>Diplomatic ties between Canada and India have been strained since Ottawa alleged New Delhi's role behind the killing of Gurpatwant Singh Pannun, an India-designated terrorist. New Delhi has strongly denied the charge, calling it "absurd" and "motivated".</p>

<p>The ties deteriorated further following the Khalistani attack on the Hindu Sabha Temple in Brampton.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/con2p7lg_terry-milewski_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Canadian journalist also condemned the recent attack on a Hindu Sabha Temple.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/when-world-war-1-ended-on-november-11-armistice-day-history-and-significance-6991774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World War I Ended On November 11, Armistice Day: History And Significance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/when-world-war-1-ended-on-november-11-armistice-day-history-and-significance-6991774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 12:31:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The armistice was an agreement to down the weapons as a precursor to the peace negotiations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On this day, 106 years ago, World War I ended on the 11th hour of the 11th day of the 11th month of 1918. The date is now known as Armistice Day when Axis and Allies signed an agreement for peace, bringing end to a war that had been waging for over four years and led to the death of over 15 million people. An armistice was preferred over a surrender as both sides believed it was the fastest way to end the war's misery and carnage. The armistice was an agreement to down the weapons as a precursor to the peace negotiations that would conclude with the signing of the Treaty of Versailles in June of the subsequent year.</p>

<p>Prior to the armistice, Germans had suffered heavy casualties as British, French and US forces pushed them steadily. Despite the Germans on the back foot and an opportunity to take over Berlin on the cards, the Allies preferred to walk away as an invasion would have required too much in terms of manpower, logistics and resources.</p>

<h3><strong>Armistice negotiations</strong></h3>

<p>Germans knew they had run their race. As early as September of 1918, they started to make overtures about an armistice. The German government approached the US with a request for an agreement and hoped that the finer details would be based on the 'peace without victory' plan laid down by US President Woodrow Wilson in January.</p>

<p>Commander-in-chief of the Allied forces, Marshal Ferdinand Foch led the negotiations from a position of leverage -- ensuring that Germans could not dictate the terms. When the Deutsch side asked if he had an Allied offer, Foch <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.history.com/news/world-war-i-armistice-germany-allies" rel="noindex, nofollow">said</a>: "I have no proposals to make.</p>

<h3><strong>What did Germany give up?</strong></h3>

<p>As part of the armistice, Germans agreed to pull their troops out of France, Belgium and Luxembourg within 15 days, or risk becoming prisoners of the Allies. They were also required to return all the prisoners of war without reciprocity.</p>

<p>The Germans had to hand over their arsenal, which included 5,000 artillery pieces, 25,000 machine guns and 1,700 airplanes, along with 5,000 railroad locomotives, 5,000 trucks and 150,000 wagons.It also had to give up the contested territory of Alsace-Lorraine. And they agreed to the indignity of Allied forces occupying German territory along the Rhine, where they would stay until 1930.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-miyazaki-airport-reopens-after-world-war-ii-bomb-explodes-near-runway-6704271" rel="noindex, nofollow">Also read | Japan Airport Reopens After World War II Bomb Explodes Near Runway</a></p>

<h3><strong>How is it remembered?</strong></h3>

<p>In 1919, King George V of England proclaimed that Armistice Day be marked with two minutes of silence at 11 am, the hour the agreement had gone into effect. "The thoughts of everyone may be concentrated on reverent remembrance of the glorious dead," the king said during the ceremony held in the palace grounds.</p>

<p>Since then, 11 November has been referred to as Remembrance Day in the Commonwealth. In London, a National Service of Remembrance is held each year at the Cenotaph, a war memorial, and bright red paper poppies are worn as a symbol of support for the armed forces. Sporting events also witness teams standing in silence as the military bugle is blasted during this period.</p>

<p>A few days after King George V's announcement, the then-US president, Woodrow Wilson declared that the Americans would also be observing the day with ceremonies across the country.</p>

<p>"With splendid forgetfulness of mere personal concerns we remodelled our industries, concentrated our financial resources, increased our agricultural output, and assembled a great army, so that at the last our power was a decisive factor in the victory," read Wilson's statement.</p>

<p>In 1953, Alvin J. King of Emporia, Kansas, proposed changing the name of the holiday to Veterans Day, to recognise veterans from all wars and conflicts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dr53cgh_world-war-1_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Red paper poppies on crosses in a cemetery]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>