<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:08:13 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-plastic-eating-worm-could-help-reduce-pollution-faster-more-efficiently-7151959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Plastic-Eating Worms Could Be The Solution To Faster Reduction Of Pollution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-plastic-eating-worm-could-help-reduce-pollution-faster-more-efficiently-7151959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:47:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A plastic-eating insect may help solve the trash problem that has choked the Earth for a long time, scientists have concluded in a new study.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A plastic-eating insect may help solve the trash problem that has choked the Earth for a long time, scientists have concluded in a new study. The larvae of the lesser-eating Kenyan mealworm can digest plastic, making it the only insect species native to Africa capable of doing it, The New York Post reported. The study was published in the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-72201-9" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Nature Journal</a>.</p>

<p>"By studying these natural 'plastic-eaters,' we hope to create new tools that help get rid of plastic waste faster and more efficiently," Fathiya Khamis, a senior scientist at the International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology and the person behind the study, said.</p>

<p>Mr Khamis and his team found the worm is the pupae of an Alphitobius darkling beetle. It possesses enzymes which can break down polystyrene, a major ingredient in styrofoam. It runs rampant in aquatic ecosystems and has a long durability.</p>

<p>The mealworm might provide an efficient and eco-friendly alternative to the traditional recycling methods that are usually expensive and can paradoxically increase pollution.</p>

<p>To test the capabilities of the worm, the researchers held a month-long trial and showcased their gut bacteria.</p>

<p>During the study period, the worms were given plastic polystyrene and bran -- a nutrient-dense food.</p>

<p>The results showed the worms consumed polystyrene more efficiently when given with bran, compared with the polystyrene-only diet. They managed to break down 11.7% of the total polymer.</p>

<p>They also survive at a higher rate, indicating the importance of a nutritious diet.</p>

<p>Khamis said the worms that broke down polymer had higher levels of certain bacteria, the enzymes of which they now look forward to isolating to "create microbial solutions that will address plastic waste on a larger scale".</p>

<p>"Instead of releasing a huge number of these insects into trash sites (which is not practical), we can use the microbes and enzymes they produce in factories, landfills, and cleanup sites," Khamis added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nlebjg9g_worms_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During the study period, the worms were given plastic polystyrene and bran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-joe-bidens-pardon-for-son-hunter-miscarriage-of-justice-7151849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Miscarriage Of Justice": Donald Trump Slams Joe Biden For Pardoning Son]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-joe-bidens-pardon-for-son-hunter-miscarriage-of-justice-7151849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:25:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Outgoing US President Joe Biden has pardoned his son Hunter Biden, who had been convicted on charges related to gun crimes and tax violations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has responded to outgoing US President Joe Biden's decision to pardon his son Hunter Biden who had been convicted on charges related to gun crimes and tax violations, calling it a "miscarriage of Justice".</p>

<p>In a post on Truth Social, Trump said, "Does the Pardon given by Joe to Hunter include the J-6 Hostages, who have now been imprisoned for years? Such an abuse and miscarriage of Justice!"</p>

<p>The J6 hostages is a reference to those people imprisoned for their role in the January 6, 2021 riots on Capitol Hill, Trump and his supporters have called the imprisoned people hostages claiming they were acting peacefully and patriotically.</p>

<p>It has been speculated that once Donald Trump takes over as President he will issue a pardon for those who are imprisoned for their role in the siege of Capitol Hill on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-pardons-son-hunter-in-2-criminal-cases-hope-americans-will-understand-7151191#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> on Sunday signed a pardon for his son, Hunter Biden, who had been convicted on charges related to gun crimes and tax violations. The pardon ensures that Hunter Biden will not face sentencing for these offences and removes the possibility of prison time.</p>

<p>In a statement, President Biden addressed the charges against his son, arguing that individuals in similar situations--such as those with tax payment issues due to addiction--typically receive non-criminal resolutions.</p>

<p>He contended that Hunter's case was treated differently, leading to felony charges despite the absence of aggravating factors. Biden also stressed his commitment to not interfere with the Justice Department's decision-making, despite his belief that his son had been "selectively and unfairly prosecuted."</p>

<p>"Today, I signed a pardon for my son Hunter. From the day I took office, I said I would not interfere with the Justice Department's decision-making, and I kept my word even as I have watched my son being selectively and unfairly prosecuted. Without aggravating factors like use in a crime, multiple purchases, or buying a weapon as a straw purchaser, people are almost never brought to trial on felony charges solely for how they filled out a gun form. Those who were late paying their taxes because of serious addictions but paid them back subsequently with interest and penalties are typically given non-criminal resolutions. It is clear that Hunter was treated differently," the statement read.</p>

<p>Biden explained that the charges against his son were initiated after political opponents in Congress pushed for the case to be brought forward. He added that a plea deal, which had been negotiated with the Department of Justice, unravelled in court due to political pressure.</p>

<p>"The charges in his cases came about only after several of my political opponents in Congress instigated them to attack me and oppose my election. Then, a carefully negotiated plea deal, agreed to by the Department of Justice, unravelled in the courtroom--with a number of my political opponents in Congress taking credit for bringing political pressure on the process. Had the plea deal held, it would have been a fair, reasonable resolution of Hunter's cases," the statement added.</p>

<p>The outgoing President maintained that the charges were politically motivated, asserting that Hunter was targeted because of his relationship with him. Biden concluded his statement by expressing his belief that, while he had faith in the justice system, the legal process had been influenced by politics, leading to a "miscarriage of justice."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ra93b5e_donald-trump-joe-biden-hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kash-patel-fbi-chief-in-donald-trump-2-0-joins-x-elon-musk-reacts-7151750]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-American Kash Patel, FBI Chief In Trump 2.0, Joins X, Elon Musk Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kash-patel-fbi-chief-in-donald-trump-2-0-joins-x-elon-musk-reacts-7151750]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:02:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-American Kashyap "Kash" Patel has been nominated as the FBI director by US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-American Kashyap "Kash" Patel, who has been nominated as the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) director by US President-elect Donald Trump, on Sunday joined social media platform X, which was previously known as Twitter.</p>

<p>"Hello X," he said in his first post, which has so far received more than seven million views and 24,000 comments.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hello <a href="https://twitter.com/X?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@X</a></p>
— Kash Patel (@Kash_Patel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Kash_Patel/status/1863285220532695481?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Billionaire and X owner Elon Musk, who has been named Trump's government efficiency chief in the incoming US administration, also congratulated Patel on being nominated to run the FBI.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Congratulations on being nominated to run the <a href="https://twitter.com/FBI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FBI</a>!</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1863298345781133439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-indian-american-kash-patel-donald-trumps-pick-to-head-fbi-7144825" target="_blank">Kash Patel</a>, a former Republican House staffer and a fierce critic of the FBI, was followed by more than three lakh people within hours of joining the social media platform.</p>

<p>He was born in New York in 1980 to parents of Gujarati descent who emigrated from East Africa. Patel completed his undergraduate studies at the University of Richmond before returning to New York to earn his law degree and a certificate in International Law from the University College London Faculty of Laws in the United Kingdom.</p>

<p>After earning his law degree, the 44-year-old worked as a public defender in Florida, representing clients in state and federal courts. He later joined the Department of Justice as a prosecutor, handling high-profile international terrorism cases across East Africa and the United States.</p>

<p>He frequently appeared on the campaign trail to rally support for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kashyap-kash-patel-indian-american-kash-patel-nominated-as-fbi-director-by-donald-trump-7144748" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> in his presidential bid against Democrat Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>During Trump's first term, he advised both the director of national intelligence and the defense secretary.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gtd3c9io_kashyap-patel_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kash Patel has so far been followed by more than three lakh people on X]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ukraine-wars-regional-tensions-boosting-arms-sales-report-7151549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza, Ukraine Wars, Regional Tensions Boosting Arms Sales: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ukraine-wars-regional-tensions-boosting-arms-sales-report-7151549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:13:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sales by major arms makers were boosted last year by wars in Ukraine and Gaza and tensions in Asia, with marked increases for manufacturers based in Russia and the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sales by major arms makers were boosted last year by wars in Ukraine and Gaza and tensions in Asia, with marked increases for manufacturers based in Russia and the Middle East, a report said Monday.</p>

<p>Sales of arms and military services by the world's 100 largest arms companies totalled $632 billion in 2023, up 4.2 percent, according to a report by the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI).</p>

<p>Revenues had dipped in 2022 as global weapons makers struggled to meet the increase in demand, but many of them managed to increase production last year, the authors of the report noted.</p>

<p>In a sign of this surge in demand, all 100 companies tracked achieved sales in excess of $1 billion last year for the first time.</p>

<p>"There was a marked rise in arms revenues in 2023, and this is likely to continue in 2024," Lorenzo Scarazzato, a researcher with the SIPRI Military Expenditure and Arms Production, said in a statement.</p>

<p>Sales from the world's top 100 arms companies "still did not fully reflect the scale of demand, and many companies have launched recruitment drives, suggesting they are optimistic about future sales," Scarazzato added.</p>

<p>Smaller producers have been more effective in meeting the demand linked to the wars in Gaza and Ukraine, growing tensions in East Asia and rearmament programmes in other regions, the institute said.</p>

<p>"A lot of them specialise in either a component of something or build systems that require one set of supply chains," allowing them to react more quickly, Nan Tian, Director of SIPRI's Military Expenditure and Arms Production Programme, told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the leading producers, US companies recorded a 2.5 percent increase in their sales last year and still account for half the world's arms revenues, with 41 US weapons producers in the world's top 100.</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin and RTX (formerly Raytheon Technologies), the world's two largest arms makers, on the other hand, reported a fall in revenue of 1.6 percent and 1.3 percent respectively.</p>

<p>Such behemoths "often depend on complex, multi-tiered supply chains, which made them vulnerable to lingering supply chain challenges in 2023," Tian said.</p>

<h3><strong>Russia's Rostec surges</strong></h3>

<p>In Europe, home to 27 of the top 100, arms makers on average saw an increase of just 0.2 percent.</p>

<p>But European groups manufacturing complex weapons systems were still in the process of honouring old contracts last year, so the revenues do not reflect the influx of orders since then.</p>

<p>"At the same time, a number of other European producers saw their arms revenues grow substantially, driven by demand linked to the war in Ukraine, particularly for ammunition, artillery and air defence and land systems," SIPRI noted.</p>

<p>The figures for Russia, though incomplete, give a clear signal of an economy increasingly geared toward war.</p>

<p>Sales by the two Russian groups in the ranking rose by 40 percent, mainly thanks to a 49 percent increase in sales for state-owned conglomerate Rostec, according to the report.</p>

<p>Manufacturers in the Middle East were buoyed by the war in Ukraine and by the first months of the Israeli offensive in Gaza after Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack -- and saw on average an 18 percent lift in sales.</p>

<p>The three Israeli manufacturers in the ranking posted record sales of $13.6 billion, up 15 percent from the year before, while the three groups based in Turkey, such as drone producer Baykar, saw their sales jump by 24 percent -- boosted by Ukraine and Turkey's investments in its defence.</p>

<p>In Asia, the trend toward rearmament was particularly evident in the growth in sales by the four South Korean manufacturers, with revenues rising 39 percent on average, and five Japanese firms that saw an average increase of 35 percent.</p>

<p>The nine Chinese producers meanwhile saw revenue increase by only 0.7 percent "amid a slowing economy," but their sales still totalled $103 billion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-07/us-arms-sales_650x400_81468433101.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smaller producers have been effective in meeting the demand linked to the wars. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-searching-for-her-birth-parents-discovers-father-in-facebook-friends-list-7151512]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Looking For Her Birth Parents Finds Father In Facebook Friends List]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-searching-for-her-birth-parents-discovers-father-in-facebook-friends-list-7151512]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:02:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tamuna Museridze had been looking for her birth parents since 2016 but only made the breakthrough earlier this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An adopted woman in Georgia received the surprise of a lifetime after she found she had been Facebook friends with her birth father all these years. Tamuna Museridze made the astonishing discovery while she was on a mission to find her birth parents, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c36p9drnrdlo" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC</em></a>. Ms Museridze's search started in 2016 after the woman who raised her died. While clearing out the house, she found her birth certificate but noticed that it had the wrong birth date, leading to suspicion that she may have been adopted.</p>

<p>After doing some digging, Ms Museridze set up a Facebook group called Vedzeb, or I'm Searching, hoping to reconcile with her birth parents. It wasn't up until this year that she received a message from a woman in rural Georgia, claiming that her aunt had concealed a pregnancy in Tbilisi in September 1984, which matched the time around Ms Museridze's birthdate.</p>

<p>After some correspondence, the unnamed woman agreed to take a DNA test. While waiting for the tests, Ms Museridze decided to call her mother.</p>

<p>"She started screaming, shouting - she said she hadn't given birth to a child. She didn't want anything to do with me," Ms Museridze told the publication about her first interaction with her mother.</p>

<p>"I was ready for anything, but her reaction was beyond anything I could imagine."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/two-south-korean-sisters-separated-at-birth-reunited-after-nearly-40-years-6899460" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Two South Korean Sisters Separated At birth Reunited After Nearly 40 Years</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>The epilogue</strong></h3>

<p>A week later, the DNA test arrived, confirming that Ms Museridze and the woman on Facebook were indeed cousins. With the hard evidence by her side, Ms Museridze confronted her mother again and convinced her to acknowledge the truth. She also got her to reveal the name of the father. It was a man called Gurgen Khorava.</p>

<p>"The first two months were shocking, I couldn't believe these things were happening to me. I couldn't believe I had found them," Ms Museridze said.</p>

<p>Once Ms Museridze had Mr Khorava's name, she quickly tracked him down on Facebook. It turned out that he had been following her story on social media with the pair being friends for three years.</p>

<p>"[He had] been in my friend list for three years. He didn't even know my birth mother had been pregnant. It was a huge surprise for him," she added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_qWUi1s1dS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_qWUi1s1dS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_qWUi1s1dS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_qWUi1s1dS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Tamuna Museridze (@tamuna_museridze)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The father-daughter duo soon met in Mr Khorava's hometown where Ms Museridze was introduced to her cousins and half-siblings. She said out of all of her father's children, she looked the most like him.</p>

<p>Ms Museridze also found that her mother was ashamed of having a child out of wedlock. She hid her pregnancy and eventually travelled to a nearby city to have the baby in secret.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mevnkm1o_georgia_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tamuna Museridze with her father Gurgen Khorava.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadas-trudeau-promises-trump-tougher-border-controls-during-florida-meet-7151484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trudeau Promises Trump 'Tougher Border Controls' During Florida Meet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadas-trudeau-promises-trump-tougher-border-controls-during-florida-meet-7151484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 07:59:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau promised President-elect Donald Trump that Canada would toughen controls over the long undefended joint border, a senior Canadian official said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau promised President-elect Donald Trump that Canada would toughen controls over the long undefended joint border, a senior Canadian official said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Trudeau flew to Florida on Friday to have dinner with Trump, who has promised to slap tariffs on Canadian imports unless Ottawa prevents migrants and drugs from crossing the frontier.</p>

<p>Canada sends 75% of all goods and services exports to the United States and tariffs would badly hurt the economy.</p>

<p>Public Safety Minister Dominic LeBlanc, who sat at the head table with Trudeau and Trump, said the two men discussed additional security measures Canada would be introducing.</p>

<p>"We're going to look to procure, for example, additional drones, additional police helicopters, we're going to redeploy personnel ... we believe that the border is secure," he told the Canadian Broadcasting Corp.</p>

<p>"It's important, I think, to show Canadians and the Americans that we're stepping up in a visible and muscular way, and that's exactly what we're going to do," he added, promising more details in the days and weeks to come.</p>

<p>Canada, he said, would continue to make the case that tariffs would damage both nations, given how interconnected the two economies are.</p>

<p>"I'm confident that the Americans will understand that it's not in their interest ... to proceed in this way," he said, describing the dinner meeting as very warm and cordial.</p>

<p>Trump said on Saturday he discussed the border, trade and energy in a "very productive" meeting with Trudeau.</p>

<p>The friendly nature of the dinner contrasts with previous exchanges between the two men.</p>

<p>Trump called Trudeau "a far left lunatic" in 2022 for requiring truck drivers crossing the border to be vaccinated against COVID. In June 2018, Trump walked out of a G7 summit in Quebec and blasted Trudeau for being "very dishonest and weak."</p>

<p>At the end of the dinner, LeBlanc said, Trump walked Trudeau to his car and said "Keep in touch. Call me anytime. Talk soon."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h56mbjsg_donald-trumpjustin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canada sends 75% of all goods and services exports to the United States.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bob-bryar-former-my-chemical-romance-drummer-dies-at-age-44-7151481]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bob Bryar, Former My Chemical Romance Drummer, Dies At Age 44]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bob-bryar-former-my-chemical-romance-drummer-dies-at-age-44-7151481]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 07:56:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Law enforcement sources indicated that all his belongings, including weapons and music equipment, remained undisturbed, further ruling out foul play.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bob Bryar, the former drummer of the rock band My Chemical Romance, died at 44. Few details about his death have been disclosed, but a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.tmz.com/2024/11/29/bob-bryar-original-my-chemical-romance-drummer-dead-44/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>TMZ</em></a>, citing law enforcement sources, states there is no indication of foul play.&nbsp;</p>

<p>TMZ reported Bryar's death on Friday evening, revealing that he was found dead in his Tennessee home on Tuesday. He was last seen alive on November 4. Law enforcement sources indicated that all his belongings, including weapons and music equipment, remained undisturbed, further ruling out foul play.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Animal Control was reportedly called to remove two dogs from the home after Bryar's heavily decomposed body was discovered. The medical examiner is currently investigating the cause and manner of his death.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for My Chemical Romance told Rolling Stone, "The band asks for your patience and understanding as they process the news of Bob's passing."</p>

<p>Born in Chicago in 1979, Bryar began playing drums at an early age. Initially a sound engineer and tour manager, he transitioned to being a musician after meeting the members of My Chemical Romance in 2004. He joined the band during their Japan tour, replacing drummer Matt Pelissier, and remained with them for six years. During his tenure, he contributed to three albums, including their iconic 2006 release, *The Black Parade*.</p>

<p>After leaving the band, Bryar shifted to behind-the-scenes roles in the music industry, supporting tours for various artists. In recent years, he maintained a low profile.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/b4eao05o_bob-bryar_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was last seen alive on November 4]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-terrorist-attacks-deadliest-month-for-security-forces-in-pakistan-68-die-in-terror-attacks-7151478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deadliest Month For Security Forces In Pakistan, 68 Die In Terror Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-terrorist-attacks-deadliest-month-for-security-forces-in-pakistan-68-die-in-terror-attacks-7151478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 07:55:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 257 people, including 104 security personnel and 119 civilians, were injured in clashes and bombings in Pakistan in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 245 people, including 68 security personnel, were killed in a series of terrorist attacks and clashes across Pakistan in November, said Dawn, citing a report by the Islamabad-based think tank, the Pakistan Institute for Conflict and Security Studies (PICSS), released on Sunday. The casualties included 127 terrorists and 50 civilians.</p>

<p>November ranked as the second deadliest month of the year, following August, which saw 254 deaths, including 92 civilians, 108 terrorists, and 54 security personnel. In terms of security personnel casualties, November was the deadliest month of 2024, surpassing October, which saw 62 security force deaths.</p>

<p>Additionally, 257 people were injured in clashes and bombings, including 104 security personnel and 119 civilians. This period reflects a sharp increase in terrorist attacks across the country in recent years.</p>

<p>The report detailed that 131 fatalities occurred in terrorist attacks, including 54 security personnel, 50 civilians, and 27 terrorists.</p>

<p>Terrorist activity showed an increase in November, with 71 recorded attacks, compared to 68 in October.</p>

<p>Khyber Pakhtunkhwa was the hardest-hit region, with 50 terrorist attacks leading to 71 deaths and 85 injuries. The Kurram district witnessed one of the worst tribal clashes in recent history, with over 120 people killed, Dawn, citing the Islamabad think tank, said.</p>

<p>Further, according to the report, Balochistan reported 20 terrorist attacks, resulting in 60 deaths, including 26 security personnel, 25 civilians, and nine terrorists. The 127 terrorist fatalities in November marked the highest monthly toll since February 2017, when 148 terrorists were killed, Dawn, citing the think tank, added.</p>

<p>The Pakistani security forces also suffered major losses, with 68 personnel killed--the highest toll since January 2023, when 114 security force members died.</p>

<p>The data also revealed that terrorist-related fatalities in 2024 have surpassed 1,000, reaching 1,082 in the first 11 months, with 856 terrorist attacks reported so far this year, compared to 645 attacks in 2023, reflecting the worsening security situation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4kupviuo_pak-terrorists_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-killed-amid-clashes-between-fans-at-football-match-in-guinea-7151471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 100 Killed Amid Clashes Between Fans At Football Match In Guinea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-killed-amid-clashes-between-fans-at-football-match-in-guinea-7151471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 07:50:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of people were killed Sunday in clashes between fans at a football match in N'Zerekore, Guinea's second largest city.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of people were killed Sunday in clashes between fans at a football match in N'Zerekore, Guinea's second largest city, hospital sources told AFP, describing scenes of mass carnage.</p>

<p>"There are bodies lined up as far as the eye can see in the hospital. Others are lying on the floor in the hallways. The morgue is full," one doctor said on condition of anonymity because he was not authorised to speak to the media.</p>

<p>He said "there are around 100 dead", with bodies filling the local hospital and morgue. Another doctor said there were "dozens of dead".</p>

<p>Videos circulating on social media, which AFP was unable to immediately verify, showed scenes of chaos in the street outside the match and numerous bodies lying on the ground.</p>

<p>Angry demonstrators also vandalised and set fire to the N'Zerekore police station, according to witnesses.</p>

<p>"It all started with a contested decision by the referee. Then fans invaded the pitch," a witness told AFP, asking that his name be withheld for safety reasons.</p>

<p>Local media said the match was part of a tournament organised in honour of Guinea's junta leader, Mamadi Doumbouya, who seized power in a 2021 coup and has installed himself as president.</p>

<p>Such tournaments have become common in the West African nation as Doumbouya eyes a potential run in presidential elections expected next year and political alliances form.</p>

<h3><strong>Prolonged transition</strong></h3>

<p>Doumbouya seized power by force in September 2021 by overthrowing President Alpha Conde, who had placed the then-colonel in charge of an elite force tasked with protecting the head of state from such coups.</p>

<p>Under international pressure, he pledged to hand power back to a civilian government by the end of 2024 but has since made clear he will not.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The military leader "exceptionally" promoted himself to the rank of lieutenant general in January and last month he elevated himself to the rank of army general.</p>

<p>Doumbouya has presided over an ongoing crackdown on dissent, with many opposition leaders detained, brought before the courts or forced into exile.</p>

<p>A "transitional charter" drawn up by the junta shortly after the coup said that no member of the junta could stand in either national or local elections.</p>

<p>But Doumbouya's backers have recently expressed their support for his candidacy in the next presidential election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the end of September, authorities indicated that elections intended to restore constitutional order would be held in 2025.</p>

<p>Despite its considerable natural resources, Guinea remains an impoverished nation.</p>

<p>It has been ruled by authoritarian governments for decades.</p>

<p>Doumbouya is one of several officers who have seized power in West Africa since 2020, along with fellow military leaders in Mali, Burkina Faso and Niger.</p>

<p>N'Zerekore, where the clashes took place in Guinea's southeast, has a population of about 200,000 people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mq642k4o_africa_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[N'Zerekore, where the clashes took place in Guinea's southeast, has a population of about 200,000 people.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/norway-halts-plans-to-conduct-deep-sea-mining-7151411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Norway Halts Plans To Conduct Deep-Sea Mining]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/norway-halts-plans-to-conduct-deep-sea-mining-7151411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 07:35:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Norway will not proceed with plans to conduct deep-sea mining, the SV party which supports the minority centre-left government said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Norway will not proceed with plans to conduct deep-sea mining, the SV party which supports the minority centre-left government said on Sunday, after it concluded negotiations over next year's budget with the coalition.</p>

<p>"We are stopping plans to open mining on the sea bed," Kirsti Bergstoe, leader of the green leftwing SV party, told reporters.</p>

<p>Until now, Norway, whose vast hydrocarbon reserves made it one of the world's wealthiest countries, had taken a leading role in the global race to mine the ocean floor for metals that are in high demand as nations transition away from fossil fuels.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/cfjrobk8_deep-sea_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Norway's vast hydrocarbon reserves made it one of the world's wealthiest countries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-allegedly-kills-sneezing-roommate-after-he-came-close-to-thanksgiving-dinner-7151279]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Allegedly Kills 'Sneezing' Roommate After He Came 'Close' To Dinner]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-allegedly-kills-sneezing-roommate-after-he-came-close-to-thanksgiving-dinner-7151279]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 06:59:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Richard Lombardi and Frank Griswold had been friends since the early 1990s when they worked together at a company.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man in the US state of Massachusetts has been charged with involuntary manslaughter, assault and battery after he allegedly killed a 'sneezing' elderly roommate for being too close to the Thanksgiving turkey dinner he was cooking last week. The man, identified as Richard Lombardi, 65, argued with his roommate, Frank Griswold, 80, telling him not to wash the dishes as he was concerned that the latter's chronic sneezing would contaminate the turkey sitting nearby, according to court documents accessed by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wcvb.com/article/man-charged-in-death-of-80-year-old-in-marshfield-massachusetts/63050612" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>WCVB</em></a>.</p>

<p>According to the official version given to the police by Mr Lombardi, he returned to the kitchen later, only to find Mr Griswold washing dishes near the turkey, not heeding his request. Overcome by anger, Mr Lombardi grabbed his roommate from behind and pushed him aside. As Mr Griswold's feet allegedly got "tangled up," he fell to the floor and hit his head.</p>

<p>Mr Lombardi said he called 911 after his roommate remained unresponsive and started bleeding from the head. Mr Griswold was taken to South Shore Hospital, where he was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>"He did see the victim, Mr Griswold, near that food doing dishes, said that he went over and grabbed Mr Griswold from behind, grabbed his back and threw Mr Griswold to the right and tossed him to the side," said prosecutor Joseph Presley.</p>

<p>"He was seen laying face-up on the floor in the kitchen in a pool of blood," added Mr Presley.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-convicted-after-dismembering-burning-victims-in-ritualistic-sacrifice-7093114" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | US Man Guilty Of Killing 3, Mutilating, Eating Victim's Heart For "Ritualistic Sacrifice"</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>'Not guilty'</strong></h3>

<p>As the police conducted the investigation, Mr Lombardi was charged and arraigned in Plymouth District Court last week where he pleaded not guilty.</p>

<p>"It sounds like an accident based on what the evidence was that was revealed in court," said Mr Lombardi's public-appointed attorney, Marshall Johnson.</p>

<p>According to a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/01/us-news/mass-man-kills-elderly-roommate-for-being-too-close-to-thanksgiving-dinner/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>NY Post</em></a>, both Mr Lombardi and Mr Griswold had been friends since the early 1990s, when they worked together at Charles River Management. They became roomies in 2001 and as per the landlord, did not have any arguments or altercations. Although Mr Lombardi was not Mr Griswold's caretaker, he helped his roommate with dinner, bills and paperwork.</p>

<p>Mr Lombardi is currently being held without bail. He is next expected to be in court on Wednesday (Dec 4).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jnka5gdg_handcuffs_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Richard Lombardi is currently being held without bail.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-pardons-son-hunter-in-2-criminal-cases-hope-americans-will-understand-7151191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hunter Was Singled Out": Joe Biden Pardons Son In 2 Criminal Cases]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-pardons-son-hunter-in-2-criminal-cases-hope-americans-will-understand-7151191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Dec 2024 06:29:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Sunday said he had issued an official pardon for his son Hunter, who is facing sentencing for two criminal cases.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said on Sunday he had pardoned his son, Hunter Biden, who had been convicted of making false statements on a gun background check and illegally possessing a firearm and pled guilty to federal tax charges.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Today, I signed a pardon for my son Hunter. From the day I took office, I said I would not interfere with the Justice Department's decision-making, and I kept my word even as I have watched my son being selectively, and unfairly, prosecuted," he said in a statement released by the White House.</p>

<p>The White House had said repeatedly that Biden would not pardon or commute the sentences of his son, a recovering drug addict who became a target of Republicans, including President-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"No reasonable person who looks at the facts of Hunter's cases can reach any other conclusion than Hunter was singled out only because he is my son," Biden said.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden faced sentencing for the false statements and gun convictions on Wednesday. In September he pled guilty to federal charges of failing to pay $1.4 million in taxes while spending lavishly on drugs, sex workers and luxury items. He faced sentencing in that case on December 16.</p>

<p>"I have admitted and taken responsibility for my mistakes during the darkest days of my addiction - mistakes that have been exploited to publicly humiliate and shame me and my family for political sport," Hunter Biden said in a statement on Sunday, adding he had remained sober for more than five years.</p>

<p>"In the throes of addiction, I squandered many opportunities and advantages ... I will never take the clemency I have been given today for granted and will devote the life I have rebuilt to helping those who are still sick and suffering."</p>

<p>The president, whose son Beau died of brain cancer in 2015, said his opponents had sought to break Hunter with selective prosecution.</p>

<p>He said people were almost never brought to trial for felony charges over how they filled out a gun form, and said others who were late in paying taxes because of addiction but paid them back with interest and penalties as his son had typically received "non-criminal resolutions" to their cases.</p>

<p>"It is clear that Hunter was treated differently. The charges in his cases came about only after several of my political opponents in Congress instigated them to attack me and oppose my election," Biden said. "In trying to break Hunter, they've tried to break me - and there's no reason to believe it will stop here. Enough is enough."</p>

<p>Biden said he had made the decision over the weekend. The president, his wife, Jill Biden, and their family including Hunter, spent the Thanksgiving holiday in Nantucket, Massachusetts and returned to Washington on Saturday night.</p>

<p>During a walk around Nantucket shops on Friday afternoon, one supporter shouted at the president from across a street to pardon his son.</p>

<p>"Here's the truth: I believe in the justice system, but as I have wrestled with this, I also believe raw politics has infected this process and it led to a miscarriage of justice - and once I made this decision this weekend, there was no sense in delaying it further," Biden said.</p>

<p>"I hope Americans will understand why a father and a President would come to this decision."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/j344tmpo_biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said he had made the decision over the weekend.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-lebanese-american-businessman-massad-boulos-as-middle-east-advisor-7149948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Names Lebanese-American Massad Boulos As Middle-East Advisor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-lebanese-american-businessman-massad-boulos-as-middle-east-advisor-7149948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 23:28:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump on Sunday named Lebanese-American businessman Massad Boulos as his senior advisor on Arab and Middle Eastern affairs, the latest family member to be appointed to a key position.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Sunday named Lebanese-American businessman Massad Boulos as his senior advisor on Arab and Middle Eastern affairs, the latest family member to be appointed to a key position.</p>

<p>"I am proud to announce that Massad Boulos will serve as Senior Advisor to the President on Arab and Middle Eastern affairs," Trump posted on Truth Social of the appointment, which puts his daughter Tiffany's father-in-law in a major White House position.</p>

<p>Boulos was a key emissary for the Trump campaign, helping to mobilize Arab American and Muslim voters, many of whom were disaffected with White House policy on the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The businessman will take over a difficult portfolio, with Israel's war raging in Gaza, a fragile ceasefire between Israel and Hezbollah in Lebanon seeing early violations, and rebel forces in Syria making advances against the government of Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<p>Massad Boulos's son, Michael, is married to Trump's daughter Tiffany.</p>

<p>A day earlier, Trump appointed Charles Kushner -- the father of his son-in-law Jared -- as the US ambassador to France.</p>

<p>"Massad is an accomplished lawyer and a highly respected leader in the business world, with extensive experience on the International scene," said Trump of his pick for the Middle East advisor job.</p>

<p>"He has been a longtime proponent of Republican and Conservative values, an asset to my Campaign, and was instrumental in building tremendous new coalitions with the Arab American Community."</p>

<p>The Republican referred to Boulos as "a dealmaker."</p>

<p>Trump often promised on the campaign trail to bring a swift end to the wars in Gaza, Ukraine and elsewhere, without specifying how he would do so.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fsngp5f_massad-boulos_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Massad Boulos's son, Michael, is married to Trump's daughter Tiffany.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-seeks-nato-security-guarantees-weapons-before-russia-talks-7149825]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Seeks NATO Security Guarantees, Weapons Before Russia Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-seeks-nato-security-guarantees-weapons-before-russia-talks-7149825]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 23:09:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Sunday that his country needed security guarantees from NATO and more weapons to defend itself before any talks with Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Sunday that his country needed security guarantees from NATO and more weapons to defend itself before any talks with Russia.</p>

<p>He made the comments after meeting the EU's new head of diplomacy Kaja Kallas and EU Council chief Antonio Costa, who were visiting Kyiv as a show of support on their first day in office.</p>

<p>"An invitation for Ukraine to join NATO is a necessary thing for our survival," Zelensky said at a press conference with Costa.</p>

<p>Ukraine faces a tough winter ahead, with Russia unleashing devastating barrages against its power grid and Kyiv's fatigued forces losing ground on the frontline.</p>

<p>Questions are also swirling around the future of US support once Donald Trump assumes the presidency in January, with fears he could force Kyiv to make painful concessions in pursuit of a quick peace deal.</p>

<p>Zelensky said his country needed to be in a "strong position" before any talks with the Kremlin, calling for "steps forward with NATO" and a "good number" of long-distance weapons to defend itself.</p>

<p>"Only when we have all these items and we are strong, after that, we have to make the very important... agenda of meeting with one or another of the killers," the Ukrainian leader said, adding that the EU and NATO should be involved in any negotiations.</p>

<p>Costa said the European Union would give Ukraine its "unwavering" support.</p>

<p>"We have stood with you since the very first day of this war of aggression, and you can count on us to continue to stand with you," he told Zelensky.</p>

<p>The European Union's new leadership team is keen to show it remains firm on backing Kyiv at a perilous moment for Ukraine nearly three years into its fight against Russia's invasion.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin threatened this week to strike government buildings in Kyiv with his new Oreshnik missile, after the US gave Ukraine approval to fire long-range ATACMS missiles into Russia for the first time.</p>

<p>A Russian drone dropped explosives on a bus in the southern Kherson region on Sunday, killing three people, authorities said, while the Russian army claimed to have captured two new frontline villages in the east.</p>

<p><strong>Ceasefire?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Zelensky on Friday appeared to begin staking out his position ahead of any potential peace talks.</p>

<p>He called on NATO to offer guaranteed protections to parts of Ukraine controlled by Kyiv in order to "stop the hot stage of the war", and implied he would then be willing to wait to regain other territory seized by Russia.</p>

<p>"If we will have a frozen conflict without any strong position for Ukraine, Putin will come back in two, three or five years," Zelensky said Sunday.</p>

<p>Kallas told journalists on the journey into Ukraine that for Kyiv "the strongest security guarantee is NATO membership".</p>

<p>"We need to definitely discuss this -- if Ukraine decides to draw the line somewhere then how can we secure peace so that Putin doesn't go any further," she said.</p>

<p>But diplomats at NATO say there appears little prospect of the alliance granting Ukraine membership soon given opposition from a raft of members cautious of getting dragged into war with Russia.</p>

<p>Zelensky insisted Kyiv was not "delusional" about its prospects with NATO and admitted there was deep reluctance from US President Joe Biden, along with leaders in countries such as Hungary.</p>

<p><strong>'Transactional language'</strong></p>

<p>Kallas said the EU "shouldn't really rule out anything" in terms of the question of sending European troops to help enforce any ceasefire.</p>

<p>"We should have this strategic ambiguity around this," she said.</p>

<p>Trump has cast doubt on continuing Washington's vast aid for Ukraine and called on EU countries to do more.</p>

<p>Europe together has spent around $125 billion on supporting Ukraine since Russia's 2022 invasion, while the United States alone has coughed up over $90 billion, according to a tracker from the Kiel Institute.</p>

<p>Kallas said the EU would use a "transactional language" to try to convince Trump that backing Kyiv was in the interest of the US.</p>

<p>"Aid for Ukraine is not charity," she said. "A victory for Russia definitely emboldens China, Iran, North Korea."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8fdco2go_zelensky_625x300_16_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky said his country needed to be in a "strong position" before any talks with the Kremlin. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rules-out-returning-nuclear-weapons-to-ukraine-says-jake-sullivan-7149666]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Rules Out Returning Nuclear Weapons To Ukraine, Says Jake Sullivan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rules-out-returning-nuclear-weapons-to-ukraine-says-jake-sullivan-7149666]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:32:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States is not considering returning to Ukraine the nuclear weapons it gave up after the Soviet Union collapsed, White House national security adviser Jake Sullivan said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States is not considering returning to Ukraine the nuclear weapons it gave up after the Soviet Union collapsed, White House national security adviser Jake Sullivan said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Sullivan made his remarks when questioned about a New York Times article last month that said some unidentified Western officials had suggested US President Joe Biden could give Ukraine the arms before he leaves office.</p>

<p>"That is not under consideration, no. What we are doing is surging various conventional capacities to Ukraine so that they can effectively defend themselves and take the fight to the Russians, not (giving them) nuclear capability," he told ABC.</p>

<p>Last week, Russia said the idea was "absolute insanity" and that preventing such a scenario was one of the reasons why Moscow sent troops into Ukraine.</p>

<p>Kyiv inherited nuclear weapons from the Soviet Union after its 1991 collapse but gave them up under a 1994 agreement, the Budapest Memorandum, in return for security assurances from Russia, the United States and Britain.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nccs8i28_ukraine-defence_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kyiv gave up nuclear weapons under a 1994 agreement in return for security assurances. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ceasefire-and-hostage-deal-not-there-yet-says-white-house-7149532]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Ceasefire And Hostage Deal  "Not There Yet", Says White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ceasefire-and-hostage-deal-not-there-yet-says-white-house-7149532]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:09:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The White House is working on a ceasefire and hostage release deal in Gaza but is "not there yet," the US National Security Advisor told NBC on Sunday, with fighting in the conflict raging on as regional leaders meet to discuss the crisis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The White House is working on a ceasefire and hostage release deal in Gaza but is "not there yet," the US National Security Advisor told NBC on Sunday, with fighting in the conflict raging on as regional leaders meet to discuss the crisis.</p>

<p>"We are working actively to try to make it happen. We are engaged deeply with the key players in the region, and there is activity even today," said Jake Sullivan, according to a transcript released by the broadcaster.</p>

<p>"There will be further conversations and consultations, and our hope is that we can generate a ceasefire and hostage deal, but we're not there yet," he added.</p>

<p>Sullivan's comments came a day after Israel hit Hezbollah targets in Lebanon, days into a fragile ceasefire in its conflict with the Iran-backed group.</p>

<p>Addressing that conflict, Sullivan lauded the ceasefire deal and said the US was working with Lebanon's military to ensure it was implemented "effectively."</p>

<p>"We need to protect it and ensure that it is fully implemented," he told NBC.</p>

<p>In an apparent reference to the Israeli strikes, Sullivan said both parties "have the right, consistent with international law, to take action in self-defense if they're facing imminent threats."</p>

<p>Speaking in Jerusalem on Sunday, Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar said there were "indications" progress could be made on a deal securing the release of hostages by Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>"There are signs we may see a greater degree of flexibility from Hamas as a result of circumstances that have developed, including the agreement with Lebanon," he said.</p>

<p>"There is a desire to move forward on this. I hope it can progress. We are committed to the return of the hostages -- it's a responsibility we must uphold."</p>

<p>Saar asserted, however, that Hamas "cannot be allowed" to continue to rule Gaza.</p>

<p>Speaking to US broadcaster CBS, Sullivan said US President Joe Biden was in close coordination with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government.</p>

<p>"He also spoke with Prime Minister Netanyahu that day (of the Israel-Hezbollah ceasefire), and Prime Minister Netanyahu told him he agreed, the time is right. The moment is now," said Sullivan, referring to the need for a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>Hamas seized 251 hostages during its October 7, 2023, attack on Israel, with 97 still being held in Gaza, including 34 who have been confirmed to be dead.</p>

<p>The armed group's attack resulted in 1,207 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>In response, Israel launched a withering military campaign on Gaza, killing at least 44,429 there, most of them civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry that the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>Much of Gaza has been reduced to rubble, with its population dependent on humanitarian aid that the UN on Sunday said it would pause delivery of through the key Kerem Shalom crossing due to security concerns.</p>

<p>Speaking to CBS on Sunday, Sullivan said the humanitarian situation in Gaza was a "crisis" and that famine was "constantly stalking" the territory.</p>

<p>"You have too many people who are suffering from shortages of food, water, medicine, access to sanitation. Innocent people who deserve a measure of peace and deserve access to all of those life-saving supplies in abundance," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/lm0l1oko_gaza_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Much of Gaza has been reduced to rubble, with its population dependent on humanitarian aid.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangaldesh-court-acquits-all-in-2004-attack-on-sheikh-hasinas-rally-case-7149526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Court Acquits All In 2004 Attack On Sheikh Hasina's Rally Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangaldesh-court-acquits-all-in-2004-attack-on-sheikh-hasinas-rally-case-7149526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:07:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bengaldesh High Court on Sunday acquitted all accused, including former Bangladesh prime minister Khaleda Zia's son Tarique Rahman and former state minister Lutfozzaman Babar, in a 2004 grenade attack in ousted premier Sheikh Hasina's rally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The High Court here on Sunday scrapped the lower court's verdict and acquitted all accused, including former Bangladesh prime minister Khaleda Zia's son Tarique Rahman and former state minister Lutfozzaman Babar, in a 2004 grenade attack in ousted premier Sheikh Hasina's rally.</p>

<p>"The High Court annulled the trial court verdict and acquitted all convicts including Tarique Rahman," a spokesman for the attorney general's office said.</p>

<p>Tarique Rahman, 57, is the acting chairman of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).</p>

<p>Two cases -- one for murder and another under the Explosives Act -- were filed after a grenade attack on an Awami League rally at Bangabandhu Avenue in Dhaka left 24 people dead and nearly 300 injured.</p>

<p>The HC bench of Justice AKM Asaduzzaman and Justice Syed Enayet Hossain acquitted all 49 accused and observed that the trial court's verdict in the cases was "illegal." The High Court's verdict comes after the bench heard the death references and appeals related to the cases filed over the attack.</p>

<p>The trial court had delivered the judgement based on a confession by Mufti Abdul Hannan, the top leader of the banned Harkat-ul-Jihad al-Islami (HuJI) outfit who was accused in the case.</p>

<p>Mufti Abdul Hannan has been executed in connection with another case.</p>

<p>The High Court said the confessional statement had no evidential value as it was taken on force and not examined properly by the magistrate concerned.</p>

<p>On November 21, the bench kept the death references (trial court documents for confirmation of death sentences) and the appeals filed by the convicted accused in the cases as curia advisari vult (meaning the verdict will be delivered any day) after it concluded a hearing on those matters.</p>

<p>During the hearing on the death references and appeals, the defence lawyers for the accused requested the High Court to scrap the trial court verdict as there was no specific allegation against them.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, appearing for the State, Deputy Attorney Generals Md Jashim Sarker and Md Russell Ahammad requested the High Court bench to uphold the lower court verdicts in the cases as the allegations against the convicted accused were proved beyond reasonable doubt.</p>

<p>Hasina, then opposition leader, narrowly escaped the attack on August 21, 2004, but 24 people were killed as several grenades were hurled when she was addressing a "rally against terrorism".</p>

<p>A Dhaka court on October 10, 2018, sentenced 19 people, including Babar, to death in the two cases filed in connection with the attacks.</p>

<p>Nineteen others, including Rahman, now in London, were given life imprisonment and 11 were handed different terms in prison.</p>

<p>Analysts previously said the incident changed Bangladesh's politics forever. In contrast, the Business Standard newspaper at the time said that "it was a premeditated barbaric act designed to wipe out the whole leadership of Awami League, including Hasina".</p>

<p>The FBI was called from the US to investigate the attack in which the assassins used grenades.</p>

<p>A former chief of Bangladesh's spy agency DGFI testified as a witness later in the trial court and said the perpetrators were protected under directives of the higher authorities.</p>

<p>The High Court decision comes nearly four months after Hasina's Awami League regime was ousted in a student-led mass upsurge and she fled to India on August 5.</p>

<p>Three days later Professor Muhammad Yunus took oath as the chief adviser of the interim government.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qmoje0c_sheikh-hasina-_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-year-old-british-man-dies-in-hotel-lift-shaft-during-holiday-in-turkey-family-seeks-probe-7149413]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[British Man Dies In Lift Shaft During Holiday In Turkey, Family Seeks Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-year-old-british-man-dies-in-hotel-lift-shaft-during-holiday-in-turkey-family-seeks-probe-7149413]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 21:43:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[His family is devastated and seeking a thorough investigation into the circumstances of his death, which remain unclear.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 20-year-old British man has died after being found injured in a lift shaft at his hotel near Lara Beach, Antalya. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2024/dec/01/british-man-tyler-kerry-dies-in-lift-shaft-during-family-holiday-in-turkey">Guardian</a></em>, Tyler Kerry was on a vacation with his grandparents, Collette and Ray Kerry, girlfriend Molly and other relatives when the incident occurred. His body was discovered at the bottom of the lift shaft in their hotel in Antalya on Friday morning. According to his uncle, Alex Price, Tyler was found at 7 am local time and was pronounced dead at the scene.</p>

<p>"I got a phone call from my sister and she just said that Tyler had been found in the lift shaft at the hotel. An ambulance team were attending to him but unfortunately, they weren't able to resuscitate him, and he was pronounced dead at the scene," Mr Price said.</p>

<p>His family is devastated and seeking a thorough investigation into the circumstances of his death, which remain unclear. "The details are limited at the moment. The family is still in the dark about what's happened and are eager for a thorough investigation to find out what's happened," Mr Price added.</p>

<p>The family is receiving support from the British consulate in Antalya and a representative from Tui, their tour operator. According to Mr Price, they are working to repatriate Tyler's body to the UK, with the hope of completing this process by Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An FCDO spokesperson said: "We are assisting the family of a British man who has died in Turkey."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a fundraiser has been launched to assist with funeral costs. On the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/tyler-kerry">GoFundMe page</a>, his family wrote, "A young man full of personality, kindness and compassion with his whole life ahead of him. He was completely devoted to his family and girlfriend Molly. We are all absolutely devastated. Tyler had travel insurance which will hopefully cover the cost of bringing him home. We are asking for any donations towards the unforseen costs of dealing with the consequences of such a tragic incident, particularly the inevitable costs of laying Tyler to rest and ensuring he has a fitting and respectful funeral/memorial."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ebc1fbm_tyler-kerry_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A fundraiser has been launched to assist with funeral costs.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgian-pm-praises-police-for-crackdown-of-protests-over-halt-of-eu-talks-7148856]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Georgian PM Praises Police For Crackdown Of Protests Over Halt Of EU Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgian-pm-praises-police-for-crackdown-of-protests-over-halt-of-eu-talks-7148856]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 20:06:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facing condemnation from the United States and defiance from his own president, Georgian Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze praised police on Sunday for cracking down on protesters who he said were acting on foreign orders to undermine the state.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facing condemnation from the United States and defiance from his own president,&nbsp;Georgian Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze praised police on Sunday for cracking down on protesters who he said were acting on foreign orders to undermine the state.</p>

<p>Georgia, a country of 3.7 million people that was once part of the Soviet Union, has been plunged into crisis since the governing&nbsp;Georgian Dream party said on Thursday it was halting European Union accession talks for the next four years.</p>

<p>The EU and the United States are alarmed by what they see as&nbsp;Georgia's shift away from a pro-Western path and back towards Russia's orbit. Big anti-government protests have taken place in the capital Tbilisi for the past three nights, and police have fired water cannon and tear gas into the crowds.</p>

<p>More protests are planned in Tbilisi for Sunday night, and local media reported demonstrations were taking place in towns and cities throughout the country.</p>

<p>Russian security official Dmitry Medvedev said on Sunday that an attempted revolution was taking place in&nbsp;Georgia. The former Russian president said on Telegram that&nbsp;Georgia&nbsp;was "moving rapidly along the Ukrainian path, into the dark abyss. Usually this sort of thing ends very badly".</p>

<p>Medvedev, once seen as a modernising reformer, has reinvented himself as an aggressive hawk since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine, often hurling dire warnings at Kyiv and its Western supporters.</p>

<p>The Kremlin has yet to comment on the latest events in&nbsp;Georgia, but it has long accused the West of fomenting revolutions in post-Soviet countries that Moscow still regards as part of its sphere of influence.</p>

<h2><strong>'FOREIGN INSTRUCTORS'</strong></h2>

<p>Georgian Prime Minister Kobakhidze dismissed criticism by the United States, which has condemned the use of "excessive force" against demonstrators.</p>

<p>"Despite the heaviest systematic violence applied yesterday by the violent groups and their foreign instructors, the police acted at a higher standard than the American and European ones and successfully protected the state from another attempt to violate the constitutional order," he told a press conference, without providing evidence of foreign involvement.</p>

<p>Kobakhidze also shrugged off Washington's announcement on Saturday that it was suspending its strategic partnership with&nbsp;Georgia. He said this was a "temporary event", and&nbsp;Georgia&nbsp;would talk to the new administration of President-elect Donald Trump when it takes office in January.</p>

<p>Deepening the constitutional crisis in the country, outgoing President Salome Zourabichvili - a critic of the government and a strong advocate of&nbsp;Georgian membership of the EU - said on Saturday that she would refuse to step down when her term ends later this month.</p>

<p>Zourabichvili said she would stay in office because the new parliament - chosen in October in elections that the opposition says were rigged - was illegitimate and had no authority to name her successor.</p>

<p>Kobakhidze said he understood Zourabichvili's "emotional state".</p>

<p>"But of course on December 29 she will have to leave her residence and surrender this building to a legitimately elected president," he said.</p>

<p>Georgian Dream has nominated Mikheil Kavelashvili, a former soccer star with a record of hardline, anti-Western statements, as its candidate for president. The head of state will be chosen on Dec. 14 by an electoral college consisting of members of parliament and local government representatives.</p>

<h2><strong>'FOREIGN AGENTS'</strong></h2>

<p>For much of the period since the 1991 collapse of the Soviet Union,&nbsp;Georgia&nbsp;has leaned strongly towards the West and tried to loosen the influence of Russia, to which it lost a brief war in 2008. It has been promised eventual NATO membership, and became an official candidate for EU entry last year.</p>

<p>But domestic opponents and Western governments have become alarmed by what they see as increasingly authoritarian and pro-Russian tendencies by the&nbsp;Georgian Dream government.</p>

<p>In June, it enacted a law obliging NGOs to register as "foreign agents" if they received more than 20% of their funding from abroad. In September, parliament approved a law curbing LGBT rights.</p>

<p>The government says it is acting to protect the country from foreign interference and avoid suffering the fate of Ukraine by being dragged into a new war with Russia.</p>

<p>New EU foreign policy chief Kaja Kallas voiced solidarity on Sunday with the demonstrators.</p>

<p>"We stand with the&nbsp;Georgian people and their choice for a European future," she posted on X.</p>

<p>"We condemn the violence against protesters &amp; regret signals from ruling party not to pursue&nbsp;Georgia's path to EU and democratic backsliding of the country. This will have direct consequences from EU side."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9nuc9m9_georgia-protest-reuters_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Georgia has been plunged into crisis after governing party halted European Union accession talks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-prosecute-dead-teen-whose-suicide-attempt-killed-another-woman-move-sparks-debate-7148783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan To Prosecute Dead Teen Whose Suicide Attempt Killed A Woman]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-prosecute-dead-teen-whose-suicide-attempt-killed-another-woman-move-sparks-debate-7148783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:50:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Many argued that pursuing charges against the dead teenager is unnecessary and a misallocation of resources, as it serves no practical purpose.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japanese authorities' decision to prosecute a 17-year-old girl who died by suicide, resulting in another woman's death, has sparked widespread controversy. The tragic accident happened on August 31 at&nbsp;at the NEWoMan shopping complex above Yokohama Station. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3288342/japans-move-charge-teen-whose-suicide-caused-womans-death-sparks-debate">South China Morning Post,</a></em> a&nbsp;teenage girl from Chiba Prefecture climbed over a 2.5-meter glass barrier on the 12th floor and jumped from the west side of the building. She landed on 32-year-old Chikako Chiba, who was walking with friends. Both were rushed to a local hospital, where the teenage girl was pronounced dead within an hour. Chiba also died of her injuries later that evening.</p>

<p>An initial investigation suggested that the student died by suicide, although the motive was unclear. Yokohama police submitted the case to prosecutors, recommending that an indictment be recorded. The police argued that the 17-year-old girl was of an age where she could reasonably understand that her actions might cause harm to others. As a result, the dead teenager has been charged with "gross negligence resulting in death", according to state broadcaster NHK.</p>

<p>The&nbsp;decision has been widely debated on social media. Many said&nbsp;that pursuing charges against the dead teenager is unnecessary and a misallocation of resources, as it serves no practical purpose. However, legal experts suggest that although the girl cannot be held legally accountable for the charge of gross negligence resulting in death, pursuing prosecution could have implications for potential civil claims filed by the victim's family. Additionally, it may serve as a deterrent to others, cautioning against actions that endanger innocent lives during suicide attempts.</p>

<p>One user wrote, "Prosecuting a dead girl is peak government ridiculousness – bureaucrats so obsessed with following their rigid, outdated rules that they've completely lost touch with common sense and human decency."</p>

<p>Another commented, "This is just another way to punish the 17-year-old's parents and family. It was a terrible accident and, let's be honest, this makes no sense." A third said, "It appears as though they are trying to discourage the behaviour in a country known for a high suicide rate."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/139vk55_teen_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An initial investigation suggested that the student died by suicide, although the motive was unclear.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>