<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:17:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-attack-in-china-kills-35-injures-43-at-zhuhai-sports-center-reports-7001964]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[35 Killed, Over 40 Injured After Car Runs Over Pedestrians In China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-attack-in-china-kills-35-injures-43-at-zhuhai-sports-center-reports-7001964]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:57:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thirty-five people were killed and 43 wounded after a car ploughed into pedestrians Monday evening in the southern Chinese city of Zhuhai, local police said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thirty-five people were killed and 43 wounded after a car ploughed into pedestrians Monday evening in the southern Chinese city of Zhuhai, local police said Tuesday.</p>

<p>"A serious and vicious attack occurred at the Zhuhai Sports Centre, in which the suspect rammed a car into people who were exercising, resulting in 35 deaths and 43 injuries," the police said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ele1fl8_zhuhai-car-incident_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A car drove into a group of people outside a sports center in Zhuhai.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/krispy-kreme-to-celebrate-world-kindness-day-with-free-doughnuts-7001866]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Krispy Kreme To Celebrate World Kindness Day With Free Doughnuts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/krispy-kreme-to-celebrate-world-kindness-day-with-free-doughnuts-7001866]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:44:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The offer is valid across the US. Some of its international locations - the chain operates in 40 countries - also have World Kindness Day promotions planned.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is very important to be kind to each other, to yourself and to the world. To remind people about the importance of the event, November 13 is observed as World kindness Day. Global doughnut chain Krispy Kreme has come up with an innovative idea to make this World Kindness Day extra sweet. It is offering free dozen original glazed doughnuts to eager customers. The offer applies to the first 500 guests in participating stores in various US locations, which means the bakery chain will be doling out approximately 6,000 free doughnuts per store.</p>

<p>"World Kindness Day is a reminder that we can all make a positive impact in people's lives, including through small gestures like sharing a sweet treat. We hope that each dozen Original Glazed doughnuts we give away enables and inspires many dozens of small acts of kindness," Krispy Kreme Global Chief Brand Office Dave Skena said in a release.</p>

<p>The offer is valid across the US. Some of its international locations - the chain operates in 40 countries - also have World Kindness Day promotions planned.</p>

<h3><strong>How to Get Your Free Doughnut</strong></h3>

<p>Participating in this sweet celebration is easy! On November 13th, simply head to your nearest Krispy Kreme store, and you'll be greeted with a warm smile and a free doughnut of your choice. Whether you prefer a classic Original Glazed, a decadent chocolate-filled treat, or something more adventurous, you can enjoy it at no cost.</p>

<p>According to UNESCO, World Kindness Day was first celebrated in 1998 by international NGO World Kindness Movement, which aims to promote goodwill around the world.</p>

<p>The UN body said that the day gives people the opportunity to reflect on one of the most important and unifying human principles - empathy, compassion and kindness. "On a day dedicated to the positive potential of acts of kindness big and small, let us collectively try to promote and spread this crucial quality that brings people of all kinds together," a note on UNESCO website says.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/sskgdkt_doughnuts_625x300_07_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[World Kindness Day is celebrated every year on November 13.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liz-truss-spent-her-finals-days-as-uk-pm-preparing-for-russian-nuclear-strike-book-7001412]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Liz Truss Spent Her Finals Days As PM Preparing For Russian Nuclear Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liz-truss-spent-her-finals-days-as-uk-pm-preparing-for-russian-nuclear-strike-book-7001412]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:51:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ms Truss was reportedly informed that the Russian president was mere hours from deploying a nuclear weapon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vladimir Putin came alarmingly close to using nuclear weapons in October 2022, prompting then-UK Prime Minister Liz Truss to prepare for potential consequences during her final days in office, according to an updated version of her biography.</p>

<p>Reports indicate that Ms Truss spent her last days as prime minister examining weather maps and preparing for radiation poisoning cases in the UK, following US intelligence suggesting an imminent nuclear strike, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/liz-truss-putin-ukraine-russia-nuclear-b2645407.html" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Independent </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>Ms Truss was reportedly informed that the Russian president was mere hours from deploying a nuclear weapon, which British officials feared could release radioactive material that would spread up to 1,700 miles from the blast. The revised edition of <em>Out of the Blue</em>, an unauthorized biography by journalists Harry Cole and James Heale, claims Truss spent "numerous hours studying satellite weather data and wind directions," concerned that unfavourable weather patterns could lead to a "direct fallout effect on Britain."</p>

<p>According to reports, US intelligence indicated a 50 per cent likelihood that Russia might use either a tactical nuclear weapon in Ukraine or a larger bomb over the Black Sea, with the intelligence described as "exquisite."</p>

<p>Excerpts from Out of the Blue, published by <em>The Sun</em>, reveal disturbing details of how narrowly the war avoided nuclear escalation. On October 18 of that year, then-Defense Secretary Ben Wallace travelled to Washington to address the crisis. Around the same time, President Joe Biden warned of a "direct threat" of Russia using nuclear weapons if the situation continued to escalate, stating, "A nuclear war cannot be won and must never be fought."</p>

<p>The updated edition of Out of the Blue was released following former Prime Minister Liz Truss's book, Ten Years to Save the West, which contained striking claims about her 49 days in office.</p>

<p>In her memoir, Ms Truss, who lost her seat in the general election, revealed that upon learning of the Queen's death, she thought, "Why me, why now?" She also mentioned that Boris Johnson's dog had left fleas in No. 10, recounting how her husband predicted that her time as prime minister "would all end in tears."</p>

<p>Ms Truss described learning about Johnson's forced resignation while she was in Bali as foreign secretary. She recalled, "As I walked along the beach in Indonesia, I started crying. Even Hugh [her husband], who had foreseen it ending in tears, agreed that this was the moment I was expected to step up. If I didn't, people would say I had backed down."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/gaphchfo_liz-truss-reuters_625x300_21_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Truss described learning about Johnson's forced resignation]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-granddaughter-shares-bts-moments-from-viral-family-photo-with-elon-musk-7001338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Behind The Scenes Of Trump's Viral Family Pic With Musk On Election Night]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-granddaughter-shares-bts-moments-from-viral-family-photo-with-elon-musk-7001338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:43:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kai Trump, the granddaughter of US President-elect Donald Trump, has shared glimpses of their family celebrations on election night following her grandfather's win over Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kai Trump, the granddaughter of US President-elect Donald Trump, has shared a glimpse of their family celebrations on election night following her grandfather's win over Kamala Harris. She also shared moments leading up to the Trump family photograph featuring Tesla CEO Elon Musk.</p>

<p>The 17-year-old is an avid vlogger on YouTube and posts moments from her life with her 1,78,000 subscribers. In her latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=smI_BS5Tujg">video</a>, the teenager shared her thoughts on Donald Trump's second term in the White House.</p>

<p>The little over 10-minute video starts with Kai getting her makeup done and sharing her thoughts about the election. "I am here in my house getting ready for the election night at Mar-a-Lago and the convention centre," she said, sitting in a makeup chair.</p>

<p>On her way to the Florida resort, she listened to ABBA's <em>'Money, Money, Money'</em> song every time she drove through the gates. Kai said she hadn't seen her grandfather in a while because he was busy campaigning, adding she was "super excited" to see him again. "He's called me almost every other day," she added.</p>

<p>As she reached the venue, the video showed the room filled with her family and close friends. Altogether, they watched across four TVs, with different channels delivering results.</p>

<p>The vlog also shows how the viral family photograph, also featuring the richest person in the world, was taken. As the family members posed for the camera, Trump is seen insisting on including Musk and his four-year-old son X Æ A-12 in another pic.</p>

<p>"Elon... You have to get Elon with his boy. Gorgeous, perfect boy," Trump can be heard saying in the video.</p>

<p>After the watch party, Kai headed to the Palm Beach Convention Center to meet her friends, who also appeared on the vlog.</p>

<p>While Kai said she was "very nervous" at the beginning of the night, she later described November 5 as a "special night".</p>

<p>"I'm extremely proud of him (Donald Trump)... I think he deserves it more than anyone in the whole world... He's such an incredible person and such a unique person," she said.</p>

<p>She noted it was "his last time running so it was so special for him to win because he really deserves this." She added that she was now "really excited" to see what Donald Trump would do for the next few years, adding "he's gonna kill it."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f5me5vf8_trump-family-photo-_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-passengers-run-for-safety-as-royal-caribbean-cruise-ship-tilts-in-the-atlantic-ocean-7001211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Passengers Run For Safety As Cruise Ship Tilts In The Atlantic Ocean]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-passengers-run-for-safety-as-royal-caribbean-cruise-ship-tilts-in-the-atlantic-ocean-7001211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:27:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dramatic footage from onboard the cruise ship captures passengers stumbling to maintain balance as the ship tilts severely to one side]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Royal Caribbean's Explorer of the Seas recently encountered severe weather on its journey from Barcelona to Miami, causing chaos on board. Strong winds and rough seas tossed bottles off bar shelves and overturned tables in the casino, sending passengers scrambling for safety. The turbulence struck Thursday night, shortly after departing Spain's Castilian coast, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cruisemapper.com/ships/Explorer-Of-The-Seas-687#google_vignette" rel="nofollow, noindex">Cruise Mapper.</a>&nbsp;The vessel was near Tenerife, the largest of Spain's Canary Islands when it was hit by an "unexpected wind gust," Royal Caribbean Cruises said in a statement. The wind caused the ship to experience "sudden movement," the cruise line said.</p>

<p>Dramatic footage from onboard the cruise ship captures passengers stumbling to maintain balance as the ship tilts severely to one side, leading to objects falling from tables and shelves across the bar.</p>

<p><strong>Here's the video:</strong><br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Cruise ship tilted 45 degrees in the Atlantic ocean ? <a href="https://t.co/4lIIxIFCkh">pic.twitter.com/4lIIxIFCkh</a></p>
— FearBuck (@FearedBuck) <a href="https://twitter.com/FearedBuck/status/1855641371752710336?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The wind jumped from 46 mph to 86 mph, a passenger on the vessel told<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/royal-caribbean-cruise-ship-weather-damage/"> CBS News.</a></em></p>

<p>Another passenger Jonathan Parrish recounted, ''I think there was about five minutes in there where everybody was wondering what was going on, but as soon as the captain came on and made the announcement of what had happened, (it) kind of gave you a sense of calmness.''</p>

<p>Following the incident, passengers were requested to return to their cabins for a headcount and safety verification. Meanwhile, the Royal Caribbean confirmed one passenger sustained injuries requiring further medical attention. The ship will make an unscheduled stop in Las Palmas, Spain, for medical disembarkation.</p>

<p>"One of our guests was injured and requires additional medical care, so the ship will make a call in Las Palmas, Spain, for medical disembarkation. We are communicating these changes directly with our guests," the cruise line wrote.</p>

<p>The Explorer of the Seas, a majestic 1,020-foot cruise liner, boasts an impressive capacity for 4,290 guests and 1,185 crew members. Built in 2000 and registered in the Bahamas, this Royal Caribbean vessel has been sailing the seas for over two decades. Onboard amenities include an ice skating rink, mini-golf course, rock climbing wall and 15-passenger decks.</p>

<p>It is scheduled to arrive in Miami in two weeks, according to Cruise Mapper data.</p>

<footer></footer>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8ralpnto_royal-caribbean-cruise-ship-_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Explorer of the Seas is scheduled to arrive in Miami in two weeks, according to Cruise Mapper data.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delphi-murders-prime-suspect-richard-allen-found-guilty-7001142]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Delphi Murders Prime Suspect Richard Allen Found Guilty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delphi-murders-prime-suspect-richard-allen-found-guilty-7001142]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:18:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The case dates back to 2017 when two teenagers - 14-year-old Liberty German and 13-year-old Abigail Williams - were killed in the town of Delphi, in the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fifty-two-year-old Richard Allen, the prime suspected in the much-publicised Delphi murders, was found guilty on Monday (November 11). The case dates back to 2017 when two teenagers - 14-year-old Liberty German and 13-year-old Abigail Williams - were killed in the town of Delphi, in United States' Indiana. Allen was accused of killing the two girls, cutting their throats and leaving their bodies behind near a trail. The case went cold for more than five years until he was arrested in 2022.</p>

<p>Allen sat in the courtroom emotionless, said a report in CNN. His sentencing is scheduled for December 20; until then, the court has issued a gag order restricting involved parties from speaking on the case.</p>

<p>Allen could be sentenced to up to 130 years in prison, the outlet further said.</p>

<p>What is the case?</p>

<p>The killings took place on February 13, 2017, when Liberty and Abigail went for a hike, the CNN report said. The teenagers went missing that afternoon. Their bodies were found the next day with throats slit and partially covered by sticks.</p>

<p>The prime suspect was caught on Liberty's phone, which the police circulated among locals. The video showed a man walking on a bridge with his hands in his pockets.</p>

<p>Allen initially evaded the police by staying in the town and working at a local pharmacy. He was finally arrested on October 26, 2022 and charged with two counts of murder while committing or attempting to commit a kidnapping.</p>

<p>The "Odinism" defence</p>

<p>During the course of the trial, Allen maintained his innocence claimed that the murders were carried out by a pagan cult hijacked by white nationalists.</p>

<p>"Members of a pagan Norse religion, called Odinism, hijacked by white nationalists, ritualistically sacrificed Abigail Williams and Liberty German," his attorneys wrote in the documents, as reported by The Independent.</p>

<p>His lawyers maintained the angle, even claiming in court that victims' bodies were covered with branches and sticks in a manner that resembled pagan symbols.</p>

<p>The lawyers even named four people claiming they are involved in Odinism. However, none of these individuals have ever been named by police as suspects or persons of interest in the case.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dq06e36g_delphi-murder-suspect_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Delphi murders: Richard Allen could be sentenced to up to 130 years in prison.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-temple-faces-extremely-high-threat-in-3rd-incident-in-canada-this-month-7001040]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hindu Temple Faces "Extremely High" Threat In 3rd Case In Canada This Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-temple-faces-extremely-high-threat-in-3rd-incident-in-canada-this-month-7001040]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:04:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As radical and extremist violence rises across Canada under Justin Trudeau's leadership, Hindus are being targeted by Khalistani terrorists across the North American nation. Temples and places of worship for Hindus are facing serious threats.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As radical and extremist violence rises across Canada under Justin Trudeau's leadership, Hindus are being targeted by Khalistani terrorists across the North American nation. Temples and places of worship for Hindus are facing serious threats from extremists.</p>

<p>The Triveni Mandir and Community Centre in Brampton, which is one of the most densely-populated cities where people of Indian origin live in Canada, has had to cancel an event after warning of an "extremely high level of violent protests".</p>

<p>The 'Life Certificate' event, a consular camp at the temple, was scheduled for November 17, where people of Indian-origin could renew essential life certificates.</p>

<p>"Please be advised that the Life Certificate Event scheduled at Brampton Triveni Mandir by the Indian Consulate on November 17, 2024, has been cancelled. This is due to official intelligence from Peel Regional Police, stating that there is an Extremely High and Imminent Threat Level of violent protests," an official statement by the temple authorities read.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/uaon34p8_brampton-triveni-temple_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Consular camps are routine operations organised by the Indian diplomatic missions in Canada, including the High Commission in Ottawa and the Consulates in Vancouver and Toronto, to assist Indian nationals with various services, such as life certificates.</p>

<p>Authorities have issued a public apology over the rising extremism and violent protests, saying, "We apologise to all community members who were depending on the event. We are deeply saddened that Canadians now feel unsafe coming to Hindu Temples in Canada."</p>

<p>"We call on Peel Police to address the threats being circulated against Brampton Triveni Mandir and provide security guarantees to the Canadian Hindu Community and the general public," the temple administration said in its statement.</p>

<h2><strong>ATTACKS ON TEMPLES</strong></h2>

<p>Earlier this month there was an attack on a temple in Brampton, following which the Government of India said it "condemns acts of violence perpetrated by extremists and separatists". Brampton is a city in the Canadian province of Ontario.</p>

<p>India has called on Canada to ensure that all places of worship are adequately protected. "We also expect that those indulging in such violence will be prosecuted," External Affairs Ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal had said earlier this month.</p>

<p>The Indian High Commission had also said that the "violent disruption" to the consular camp came despite an advance request for strong security measures, and that it feared for Indian citizens' safety.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tpgieni_brampton-temple-attack_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>In yet another incident of violence, days after the attack on a Hindu temple in Canada's Brampton, authorities had to cancel its consular camps in Toronto over security issues.</p>

<p>At the time, the spokesperson of the Ministry of External Affairs had said, "You would have seen the message posted by our consulate in Toronto that they had to cancel the consular camp they were planning to organize over the weekend because they did not receive adequate security or security assurance from the host government."</p>

<p>"That was the reason these consular camps had to be cancelled. As you know, we have a large diaspora in Canada. Many of these people, especially around November and December, need several documents for the continuation of their pensions and other activities here in India. So, this consular camp we do is helpful to the community, to both people of Indian nationality and people of Indian origin who may now be nationals of other countries," the spokesperson added.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has strongly condemned the attacks, saying "I strongly condemn the deliberate attack on a Hindu temple in Canada. Equally appalling are the cowardly attempts to intimidate our diplomats. Such acts of violence will never weaken India's resolve. We expect the Canadian government to ensure justice and uphold the rule of law."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I strongly condemn the deliberate attack on a Hindu temple in Canada. Equally appalling are the cowardly attempts to intimidate our diplomats. Such acts of violence will never weaken India's resolve. We expect the Canadian government to ensure justice and uphold the rule of law.</p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1853442198575952031?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Last year, a Hindu temple in Windsor, also in Ontario, was defaced, sparking widespread calls for action from both Canadian and Indian officials. Similar earlier incidents in Brampton saw temples targeted as well, drawing strong reactions from the Indian community in Canada.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bmuduq8o_temple-attacks-in-canada-protest-afp_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hindu temples in Canada are facing serious threats in Canada leading to prostests across India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-russia-plans-to-boost-birth-rate-with-ministry-of-sex-7000392]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Russia Plans To Boost Birth Rate With 'Ministry Of Sex']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-russia-plans-to-boost-birth-rate-with-ministry-of-sex-7000392]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:04:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia is considering establishing a "Ministry of Sex" in its latest move to tackle the country's declining birth rate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia is considering establishing a "Ministry of Sex" in its latest move to tackle the country's declining birth rate. Nina Ostanina, a loyalist to President Vladimir Putin and chairperson of the Russian parliament's committee on Family Protection, Paternity, Maternity and Childhood, is looking into a plea demanding such a ministry, according to reports.</p>

<p>Officials in the country are looking at myriad ideas to meet Putin's call to halt the demographic decline, said to have worsened by Russia's ongoing invasion of Ukraine, resulting in significant loss of lives since it began in February 2022.</p>

<p><strong>Here are some of the key proposals made to boost the birth rate in Russia:</strong><br />
<br />
<strong>1. No internet and light</strong></p>

<p>Among the suggested ideas, one is to turn off the internet and even lights between 10 PM and 2 AM to encourage couples to get involved in intimate activities.</p>

<p><strong>2. Incentives for mothers</strong></p>

<p>Paying money to stay-at-home women, who are raising their children and doing housework, is also among the suggestions. This can be included in their pension calculations.</p>

<p><strong>3. Pay for first dates</strong></p>

<p>Another suggestion is that the government start paying people for their first dates -- up to 5,000 roubles (around ₹4,395).</p>

<p><strong>4. Wedding night payment</strong></p>

<p>Public funding of wedding nights in hotels for couples is also said to be under consideration. This involves payment of up to 26,300 roubles (₹23,122) in the hope of promoting pregnancies.</p>

<p>As per local media, the proposal for the 'Ministry of Sex' to take charge of initiatives to boost birth rate was raised in a plea organised by GlavPR agency.</p>

<p>In Khabarovsk, for instance, female students in the 18 to 23 age group may receive up to £900 (roughly ₹97,311) on the birth of a child under the new initiative. The amount stands at £8,500 (around ₹9,19,052) for a firstborn in Chelyabinsk. The compensation differs depending on the region.</p>

<p>Dr Yevgeny Shestopalov, a regional health minister, said that Russians could use coffee and lunch breaks in offices and factories to engage in "procreation".</p>

<p>In Moscow, authorities have reportedly asked female public sector workers to fill out intimate questionnaires about sex and menstruation. Those who refuse to answer are being ordered to attend doctors' appointments.</p>

<p><strong>Some of the questions being asked include:</strong><br />
<br />
1. At what age did you start having sex?<br />
<br />
2. Do you use hormonal contraception (eg birth control pills)?<br />
<br />
3. Do you suffer from infertility?<br />
<br />
4. Have you ever been pregnant? If yes, how many times (indicate the quantity as a number)?<br />
<br />
5. Do you have any sexual diseases?<br />
<br />
Separately, women in Moscow have been offered free fertility tests, with 20,000 of them already taking part in it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/ikm88hdo_child-baby-generic_625x300_27_May_24.png' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia is considering establishing a "Ministry of Sex".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-offers-free-ivf-treatment-to-women-willing-to-use-his-sperm-7000635]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram CEO Offers Free IVF Treatment To Women Willing To Use His Sperm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-offers-free-ivf-treatment-to-women-willing-to-use-his-sperm-7000635]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:01:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pavel Durov, the CEO of Telegram, has launched an unusual initiative extending beyond the world of tech and messaging.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pavel Durov, the CEO of Telegram, has launched an unusual initiative extending beyond the world of tech and messaging. Durov is offering free In Vitro Fertilization (IVF) treatments to women willing to use his sperm. His offer is an effort to help women and couples struggling with infertility.</p>

<p>In addition to offering sperm, Durov is also paying for all of the participants' IVF procedures through his partnership with the Altravita fertility clinic. “We are happy to offer you a unique opportunity! Only in our clinic can you undergo IVF for free, using Pavel Durov's sperm-one of the most famous and successful entrepreneurs of our time,” states a message on Altravita's website. The clinic has pledged to offer top-tier care, working with some of the leading specialists in reproductive health and using state-of-the-art technology to ensure the best possible outcomes.</p>

<p>The process for women wishing to participate is simple but selective. Interested individuals can reach out to Altravita to schedule an initial consultation. During this meeting, a doctor will explain the IVF process, conduct necessary tests, and determine eligibility. To take part, women must be under the age of 37 and in good health. Once approved, they will embark on the IVF journey with full support from the clinic's experienced team.</p>

<p>In a post on Telegram earlier this year, the CEO disclosed he fathered “over 100 biological kids” over 15 years.</p>

<p>“I was just told that I have over 100 biological kids. How is this possible for a guy who has never been married and prefers to live alone?” he wrote. He recounted the story of how a friend first approached him for a sperm donation 15 years ago. “He said that he and his wife couldn't have kids due to a fertility issue and asked me to donate sperm at a clinic for them to have a baby,” said Pavel, adding that though he initially laughed it off, he realised later that his friend was serious. Eventually, he agreed, setting in motion a series of donations that would go on to impact many families.</p>

<p>He wrote, “Fast forward to 2024, my past donating activity has helped over a hundred couples in 12 countries to have kids. Moreover, many years after I stopped being a donor, at least one IVF clinic still has my frozen sperm available for anonymous use by families who want to have kids.”</p>

<p>Durov said he planned to open-source his DNA so that his biological children could find each other easily. “The shortage of healthy sperm has become an increasingly serious issue worldwide, and I'm proud that I did my part to help alleviate it,” Durove added.</p>

<p>Take a look at the entire post <a href="https://t.me/durov/339">here.</a></p>

<p>Durov also expressed his desire to destigmatise sperm donation, viewing it as an important resource for those facing fertility challenges.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m7qorqqs_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pavel Durov offer is an effort to help women and couples struggling with infertility.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-kai-madison-trump-all-about-donald-trumps-granddaughter-7000856]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Kai Madison Trump? All About Donald Trump's Granddaughter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-kai-madison-trump-all-about-donald-trumps-granddaughter-7000856]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:43:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kai Trump was born on May 12, 2007, in New York, and named after her maternal grandfather.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since the day Donald Trump won the US presidential election, celebrations have been going on in the family. The entire Trump family posed for a photo at the Mar-a-Lago estate after the election win that showed all the president-elect's children, their spouses and several grandchildren. The photo was shared by Kai, the daughter of Donald Trump Junior and his ex-wife Vanessa Trump. The 17-year-old has captured the public's attention by giving sneak peek into the fun side of the Trump family through her vlogs.</p>

<p>On Sunday (November 10), she posted some photos on her X handle of a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kai-trump-plays-golf-with-grandpa-donald-trump-bonus-elon-musk-6991962">family outing</a>. The pictures showed US president-elect Donald Trump playing golf with Kai and his other granddaughter, Chloe Trump.</p>

<h3><strong>Who is Kai Madison Trump?</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="For Kai Trump, her grandfather is her &quot;inspiration&quot;. (Image credit: Instagram/kaitrumpgolfer)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sm1ls1jg_kai-trump-old-photo_625x300_12_November_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="For Kai Trump, her grandfather is her &quot;inspiration&quot;. (Image credit: Instagram/kaitrumpgolfer)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">For Kai Trump, her grandfather is her "inspiration".<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Image credit: Instagram/kaitrumpgolfer</span></p>
</div>

<p>She is an internet personality and an avid golfer, like her grandfather. Kai was born on May 12, 2007, in New York, and named after her maternal grandfather. She is the niece of Ivanka Trump and Eric Trump. Kai is also the half-niece to Baron Trump and Tiffany Trump, which makes her the step-granddaughter of Melania Trump. Kai is one of the 10 grandchildren of Mr Trump.</p>

<p>As per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/trumps-granddaughter-kai-makes-rnc-debut-praises-normal-grandpa/"><em>Daily Beast</em></a>, Kai was the first member of the next Trump generation to enter the political arena when she addressed the Republican National Convention (RNC) in July this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The teenager called her grandfather an "inspiration" and sought to portray the more "normal" side of the 45th president of the United States.</p>

<p>"To me, he's just a normal grandpa... He gives us candy and soda when our parents aren't looking," she was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/09/donald-trump-family-barron-ivanka-kai-melania"><em>The Guardian</em></a>.</p>

<p>"When we play golf together, if I'm not on his team, he'll try to get inside of my head, and he's always surprised I don't let him get to me. But I have to remind him, I'm a Trump, too," Kai Trump further said.</p>

<p>In a video posted on her YouTube channel, Kai said she began golfing at the age of 2 and credited her mother for getting her into the sport.</p>

<h3><strong>All about Donald Trump's 10 grandchildren</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Trump has a large family tree - he has five children and 10 grandchildren. Donald Trump Junior, the oldest son of the 78-year-old, has five children from his first marriage to Vanessa Haydon: Kai, Donald III, Tristan, Spencer and Chloe.</p>

<p>His daughter Ivanka has three children with husband Jared Kushner. The oldest child, Arabella Rose Kushner, was born on July 17, 2011. Then comes Joseph Frederick Kushner, who was born on October 14, 2013.</p>

<p>Theodore James Kushner is Ivanka's second son and youngest child. He was born on March 27, 2016.</p>

<p>Mr Trump's third child Eric is a father of two - a son named Eric and a daughter named Carolina.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q4indsj8_kai-trump-with-donald-trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kai is one of the 10 grandchildren of Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baku-climate-talks-india-not-attending-world-leaders-climate-action-summit-7000756]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Not Attending World Leaders Climate Action Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baku-climate-talks-india-not-attending-world-leaders-climate-action-summit-7000756]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:42:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is not attending the two-day World Leaders Climate Action Summit (WLCAS) beginning Tuesday with country statements at the 2024 UN climate conference (COP29) in Baku, Azerbaijan]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India is not attending the two-day World Leaders Climate Action Summit (WLCAS) beginning Tuesday with country statements at the 2024 UN climate conference (COP29) in Baku, Azerbaijan that is focussed heavily on securing a new climate finance target for countries most vulnerable to climate impacts.</p>

<p>Ilham Aliyev, President of host Azerbaijan, has invited heads of state and governments to participate in the WLCAS when the first part of the high-level segment will also take place.</p>

<p>Eighty-two national leaders, vice-presidents and senior envoys are lined up to speak on Tuesday and Wednesday.</p>

<p>Barbados Prime Minister Mia Mottley is the pick of the bunch, but there's a host of leaders including Spain's Pedro Sanchez, Nepal's Ram Chandra Paudel and Congo's Judith Suminwa Tuluka whose countries have been battered this year.</p>

<p>Britain's Prime Minister Keir Starmer will offer the rare prospect of praise as he lands the UK's new 2035 target.</p>

<p>UK climate advisors recommended 81 per cent greenhouse gas cuts on 1990 levels last month.</p>

<p>Climate boss Ed Miliband says London is committed to “accelerating” climate action, but don't expect a hike on climate finance from a cash-strapped nation, pointed out a climate negotiator from a developing country.</p>

<p>The invitation to the WLCAS signifies the importance for world leaders to engage and enhance ambition and enable action to reduce emissions, adapt to climate change, and address loss and damage, to implement and transform key climate-related decisions into concrete actions and credible plans to tackle climate change, says the host.</p>

<p>Responding to India not attending the WLCAS, an India-origin observer at the climate talks told IANS on condition of anonymity, “These are not talks, just the country statements. Not all countries are supposed to make it. Another high-level segment is towards the end of the summit. India is very much part of it.”</p>

<p>Explaining further, the observer said, “Since leaders started coming, so a stage was created for them to make speeches, only a recent phenomenon, post-Glasgow (in 2021). So nothing normal about it.”</p>

<p>The second part of the high-level segment will take place on November 19 and 20. This will be for parties whose heads of state and governments did not deliver a national statement during the first part.</p>

<p>India's Minister of State for Environment, Forest and Climate Change Kirti Vardhan Singh will be leading a 19-member delegation and deliver India's national statement at the high-level segment in the second segment.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Minister of Environment, Forest and Climate Change Bhupender Yadav had attended COP28 last year in Dubai. PM Modi delivered the national statement at the opening ceremony of the high-level segment.</p>

<p>India has so far played a key role in shaping global climate finance frameworks to address the urgent funding needed for both mitigation and adaptation efforts.</p>

<p>At Baku, India will seek the New Collective Quantified Goal (NCQG), a framework that aims to replace the annual commitment of $100 billion by 2020 made by developed countries in 2009 -- a target met only once, in 2022.</p>

<p>Just ahead of the onset of WLCAS, COP29 President Mukhtar Babayev held a bilateral meeting with John Podesta, Senior Advisor to the U.S. President for International Climate Policy, to discuss the urgent need for enhanced global collaboration and partnerships to drive inclusive climate action solutions and build on the outcomes of the first day of COP.</p>

<p>UN Climate Change Executive Secretary Simon Stiell addressed the official opening of COP29 on Monday, making a passionate plea for urgent, global cooperation on climate change.</p>

<p>“We mustn't let 1.5 slip out of reach. Even as temperatures rise, the implementation of our agreements must claw them back,” said Stiell.</p>

<p>“Clean energy and infrastructure investment will reach two trillion dollars in 2024. Almost twice that of fossil fuels. The shift to clean-energy and climate-resilience will not be stopped. Our job is to accelerate this and make sure its huge benefits are shared by all countries and all people,” he said.</p>

<p>As part of its plan to enhance ambition and enable action, the COP29 presidency, in partnership with the International Energy Agency (IEA), on Monday shared five key opportunities for COP29 to demonstrate positive progress on energy goals identified at COP28.</p>

<p>The five opportunities identified are: Scale up energy storage and electricity grids as a key enabler to achieving the global goal of tripling renewable energy capacity this decade and ensuring that the full benefits are realised; ensure countries accelerate policy implementation to achieve the goal of doubling energy efficiency progress by 2030; maintain a focus on cutting emissions from methane and fossil fuels; implement solutions to boost clean energy investment in developing economies to support their transitions; and the next round of Nationally Determined Contributions should be informed by the Global Stocktake (GST) outcomes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2q5md86g_cop29_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The second part of the high-level segment will take place on November 19 and 20.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uterus-removal-for-women-at-30-japan-leaders-bizarre-proposal-to-boost-birth-rate-sparks-backlash-7000722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Uterus Removal At 30": Japan Leader's Bizarre Proposal To Boost Birth Rate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uterus-removal-for-women-at-30-japan-leaders-bizarre-proposal-to-boost-birth-rate-sparks-backlash-7000722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:30:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The minister suggested banning women from marrying after 25 and undergoing forced hysterectomies at 30, as well as restricting women's access to university education from the age of 18.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Japanese politician recently faced backlash and issued an apology after making a controversial comment suggesting that women might need to "remove their uteruses" after 30 to solve social issues related to fertility. This proposal was part of a broader discussion on Japan's declining birth rate and the challenges the country faces due to its ageing population, as per the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/lifestyle-culture/article/3286036/japan-call-ban-women-marrying-after-25-stirs-backlash">South China Morning Post</a></em>. The shocking suggestion was made by&nbsp;Japan's Conservative Party leader, Naoki Hyakuta in a YouTube video on November 8&nbsp;where he discussed measures to increase the nation's birthrate.</p>

<p>The minister suggested banning women from marrying after 25 and undergoing forced hysterectomies (removal of the uterus) at 30. He opined that doing so&nbsp;would prod them to have children and reverse the&nbsp;declining birthrate. The politician also proposed restricting women's access to university education from the age of 18, allegedly to focus on producing more children.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I want you to know the current state of Japanese politicians.<br />
<br />
Naoki Hyakuta, leader of the far-right Conservative Party of Japan with 3 seats in the House of Representatives<a href="https://twitter.com/BBCWorld?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BBCWorld</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/bbcnewsjapan?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@bbcnewsjapan</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/BBC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BBC</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/CNN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CNN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/NBCNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NBCNews</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/ABC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ABC</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/CBSNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CBSNews</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/FoxNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FoxNews</a><br />
<br />
<a href="https://t.co/utP5Y29veU">pic.twitter.com/utP5Y29veU</a></p>
— ⁑リコマイ ⁑ (@sakuraironoharu) <a href="https://twitter.com/sakuraironoharu/status/1855513023768940853?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This dystopian idea was met with swift backlash, prompting Mr Hyakuta to apologize, claiming his comments were merely hypothetical and not his personal views. Many slammed the minister for his regressive and discriminatory comments, sparking concerns about women's rights and reproductive freedom.</p>

<p>Mr Hyakuta later clarified that these ideas were framed as a "science-fiction storyline" to spark discussion and not meant to be taken literally. He acknowledged that his comments were "extremely harsh" and emphasised that he does not advocate for such drastic measures against women.</p>

<p>''I meant to say that we cannot transform the social structure unless we do something that goes that far. I want to retract my remarks and apologize,'' he said.</p>

<p>Expressing outrage on the matter, Chizuru Higashi, an actress, said: "The idea of taking away reproductive ability if you have not had a child by the age of 30 is terrifying, even as a joke. Besides, do you think that the declining birth rate is the fault of women? Women cannot get pregnant on their own and they have no confidence about giving birth and raising children because their employment and income are not stable.</p>

<p>Author Issui Ogawa took particular issue with Mr Hyakuta's attempt to downplay his remarks as "science fiction," arguing that such language only serves to trivialise the harm caused by his words.</p>

<p>''I'm a science fiction writer and I'm not amused that the grotesque idea of removing a girl's uterus was described as science fiction, while I'm also unhappy at the idea of forcing her to marry and give birth - with penalties attached,'' he said.</p>

<p>Japan's fertility crisis is a pressing concern, with the country struggling to address the challenges of an ageing population and shrinking workforce.&nbsp;This proposal follows other controversial measures aimed at encouraging marriage and procreation, such as incentives for women to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/japan-is-offering-single-women-financial-support-to-relocate-from-tokyo-for-marriage-6438791">marry men from rural areas</a>, which were also met with backlash for being tone-deaf and overly simplistic.</p>

<p>Japan recorded 350,074 births between January and June, 5.7 per cent fewer compared to the same period last year, the health ministry's preliminary report said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/399t9hl8_naoki-hyakuta_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Japan's fertility crisis is a complex issue, with a significantly declining birth rate in recent years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-indonesian-president-s-phone-call-with-trump-goes-viral-7000617]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Indonesian President's Phone Call With Trump Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-indonesian-president-s-phone-call-with-trump-goes-viral-7000617]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:15:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto congratulated Donald Trump on his election victory in a phone call after landing in Washington.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto congratulated Donald Trump on his election victory in a phone call after landing in Washington on an official visit that includes a meeting with President Joe Biden on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Prabowo, who has said he will pursue a non-aligned foreign policy, posted a video of his call to Trump made after he arrived from China, where he had met with President Xi Jinping on his first overseas trip since taking office last month.</p>

<p>"Wherever you are, I'm willing to fly to congratulate you personally, sir," Prabowo said in the video of the call posted on his social media accounts.</p>

<p>"We'll do that, anytime you want," Trump replied.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Glad to be connected directly with President Elect <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a> to extend my heartfelt congratulations on his election as the 47th President of the United States.<br />
<br />
I am looking forward to enhance the collaboration between our two great nations and to more productive… <a href="https://t.co/KfSVUsZSGc">pic.twitter.com/KfSVUsZSGc</a></p>
— Prabowo Subianto (@prabowo) <a href="https://twitter.com/prabowo/status/1855981733646356732?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 11, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Prabowo's office said he made the call on Monday after arriving in Washington. It did not immediately respond when asked if he is scheduled to meet Trump in person.</p>

<p>Trump described his election victory as amazing, and giving him a big mandate. "We had tremendous success. The most successful in over 100 years, they say," he said.</p>

<p>Trump also said the Indonesian President was "very respected," and praised his English, to which Prabowo, a former special forces commander, replied: "All my training is American, sir."</p>

<p>Prabowo expressed his shock over the assassination attempt on Trump during campaigning, and relief that he had survived.</p>

<p>"Yes, I got very lucky. I just happened to be in the right place with the right direction, otherwise I wouldn't be talking to you right now," Trump replied.</p>

<p>Prabowo also met with several U.S. company representatives in Washington, his office said, including from Freeport McMoRan and energy company Chevron, and urged the companies to invest in Indonesia.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/najtqni_-indonesia-president_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-the-great-american-rebellion-won-trump-the-presidency-7000536]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: How A Rebellion Born Out Of Covid Made Trump The President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-the-great-american-rebellion-won-trump-the-presidency-7000536]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:01:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trumps unfiltered, anti-institutional rhetoric offered an alternative, channelling the frustration of those who felt marginalised by an increasingly performative political culture.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Supporters of Donald Trump line up to attend a &quot;Save America&quot; rally at York Family Farms on August 21, 2021 in Alabama." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0gu37jpo_trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpg" title="Supporters of Donald Trump line up to attend a &quot;Save America&quot; rally at York Family Farms on August 21, 2021 in Alabama." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">An August 2021 photo of supporters of Donald Trump lining up to attend a "Save America" rally at York Family Farms in Alabama. (<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">AFP)</span></p>
</div>

<p>The 2024 US presidential election is more than just about a Republican resurgence. It signifies a potential realignment within the American political landscape—a “red deluge” that may indicate a foundational shift in voter behaviour and ideological preferences. With 48 out of 50 states moving rightward, including traditionally Democratic strongholds like California, New York, and Illinois, the data suggests a deep, possibly systemic shift. Such widespread gains across the ideological spectrum reveal not merely a reactionary vote against specific Democratic policies but perhaps an evolving sentiment that crosses conventional partisan boundaries. This pattern may reflect shifts in public attitudes toward governance, policy priorities, or cultural issues, signalling a reconfiguration of traditional political affiliations.</p>

<p>In New York, Republicans won significantly by flipping a state Senate seat in Brooklyn, a borough long considered a Democratic bastion. Retired NYPD Sergeant Steven Chan defeated incumbent Democrat Iwen Chu in the 17th District, marking a historic win for the GOP in this area.</p>

<h2><strong>&nbsp;A Narrative War</strong></h2>

<p>Similarly, in California, traditionally a Democratic stronghold, Republicans have made notable inroads. The GOP's focus on economic issues and public safety has resonated with voters concerned about the state's handling of these matters. This shift is evident in the increased support for Republican candidates in various local elections, indicating a broader trend of changing political allegiances.</p>

<p>In battleground states like Pennsylvania, Michigan, and Wisconsin, where political loyalties have historically been fluid, the Republican advantage was even more pronounced. The consistency of these gains across various states and regions implies more than a transient preference swing; it suggests a more profound ideological realignment that could reshape the balance of power. Theoretical models of political realignment would interpret this as a shift in the “political centre”, where structural changes—economic, demographic, or cultural—redefine voter bases and challenge established party dynamics.</p>

<p>There are several reasons for the massive Trump victory, but this column is about the “us versus them” narrative, which was responsible for the Democrats' debacle. The Democrats' commitment to a “with us or against us” mentality—born out of opposition to Trump in 2017—created a powerful, polarising lens that shaped their approach to governance, especially during the COVID-19 crisis. What started as a rallying cry to resist authoritarianism evolved into a mindset that equated disagreement with anti-democratic extremism. This was more than just political posturing. Instead, it became an institutional stance that influenced how policies were designed and justified, often sidelining more nuanced discussions.</p>

<h2><strong>Us vs Them, Good vs Bad</strong></h2>

<p>During COVID, this “all-or-nothing” framing led to some of the most rigid and divisive health policies. Lockdowns and mandates were often presented as moral imperatives, where compliance wasn't just about following health guidelines but about being on the “right side” of democracy. Questioning these policies—whether on scientific, personal, or practical grounds—was considered dangerous and almost traitorous. This mindset stifled healthy debate and sidelined legitimate concerns, making policies harder for people to trust and follow.</p>

<p>Psychology tells us that black-and-white thinking strengthens group loyalty but often deepens divisions. By framing pandemic responses as a test of democratic allegiance, Democrats created an “in-group” of loyalists and an “out-group” of dissenters, making it harder for policies to be adopted based on feedback or new information. This phenomenon is called “groupthink”, where the pressure to conform discourages questioning, even when policies could benefit from it.</p>

<p>The way COVID-19 policies became a litmus test for political loyalty also speaks to a concept called “biopower”, where institutions use control over health to enforce broader values. Public health wasn't just about health; it was about loyalty to a specific political outlook, with people who disagreed feeling sidelined. This kind of rigid, ideological enforcement strains public trust and often backfires, as we saw with the backlash against certain policies.</p>

<p>In the end, by framing so many issues through a “democracy versus authoritarianism” lens, Democrats made it harder to craft policies that felt inclusive and flexible. What was intended as a defence of democracy ended up putting it at risk, as it reduced complex issues to simple binaries, alienating people and undermining the very trust needed to make these policies effective.</p>

<h2><strong>A Backlash Against Moralising</strong></h2>

<p>Trump's appeal can be analysed through the theoretical lens of anti-institutionalism and political alienation, particularly within the framework of populism. Trump's success represents a form of&nbsp;<i>populist backlash</i>&nbsp;against what his supporters perceive as a sanctimonious institutional order that enforces restrictive norms around speech and behaviour, often called “political correctness”.</p>

<p>Sociologists and political theorists like Pierre Bourdieu argue that dominant institutions, through their “symbolic power”, enforce behavioural and linguistic norms, subtly controlling the boundaries of acceptable discourse. This enforcement often creates a sense of alienation for those constrained by these unwritten rules, particularly in spaces where awareness of microaggressions or social sensitivities is heightened.</p>

<p>Furthermore,&nbsp;<i>cultural backlash theory</i>&nbsp;explains Trump's appeal as a reaction from those who feel left behind by rapid social and cultural shifts. In ‘progressive' or “blue” states, where vigilance against microaggressions is high, individuals may feel stifled by the perceived demands of political correctness. Trump's open rejection of these norms allowed him to tap into a reservoir of resentment among individuals who viewed such standards as a threat to their freedom of expression. They saw Trump's candid style as a liberation from the “oppressive” norms imposed by institutions they believe have become too focused on social sensitivities.</p>

<h2><strong>The Limits Of Symbolic Politics</strong></h2>

<p>Additionally, this support reflects elements of&nbsp;<i>symbolic politics</i>, where Trump became a symbol of rebellion against the elite-dominated cultural establishment. Trump's directness and willingness to break norms resonated with voters who felt dismissed or condescended to by traditional elites. In this context, Trump's willingness to “go too far” was seen not as a flaw but as a badge of authenticity, embodying the frustration many felt about a system they saw as imposing unyielding standards prioritising sensitivity over free speech.</p>

<p>The American economy may appear resilient on paper, but this supposed stability is a mirage for most people. Every visit to the grocery store, every utility bill, and every tank of gas serves as a painful reminder that prices are now well beyond what they were in 2019. The government's rosy narrative about economic strength becomes meaningless against everyday struggles—a reality where inflation quietly but relentlessly erodes purchasing power and undermines any sense of financial security. Claims of economic robustness fall flat when the public feels the sting of rising costs daily.</p>

<h2><strong>Culture Wars</strong></h2>

<p>The relentless cultural crusades pushed by those in power have reached an intolerable peak, exposing a government utterly divorced from the struggles and priorities of the public. Political scientists argue that this fixation on culture wars stems from a desire to consolidate ideological bases and appeal to identity-driven voter segments, ultimately reshaping governance priorities around divisive issues rather than unifying goals. This focus can be understood through frameworks like “agenda-setting theory”, where political leaders deliberately use cultural flashpoints to dominate public discourse, often at the expense of substantive policy areas like economic stability, healthcare, or infrastructure. Such strategies exploit societal cleavages, transforming them into political tools that offer little more than rhetorical gains.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the relentless engagement in culture wars may signal an evolution, like political detachment. By perpetually immersing themselves in symbolic conflicts, leaders effectively obscure the disconnect between their priorities and the natural, measurable concerns of the populace, contributing to a form of governance described as “performance politics”. This performance-based approach erodes institutional legitimacy, leaving citizens sceptical of whether the government intends to address genuine societal challenges or merely maintain a facade of ideological purity.</p>

<p>Thus, in a landscape where political loyalty became a test of moral standing, Trump's unfiltered, anti-institutional rhetoric offered an alternative, channelling the frustration of those who felt marginalised by an increasingly performative political culture.</p>

<p><em>(Aditya Sinha is Officer on Special Duty, Research, Economic Advisory Council to the Prime Minister. Views are personal.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q2r3a1u_trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-donald-trump-casts-long-shadow-on-cop29-summit-7000458]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Analysis: Donald Trump Casts Long Shadow On COP29 Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-donald-trump-casts-long-shadow-on-cop29-summit-7000458]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 13:50:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The re-election of Donald Trump in the US has cast a shadow on climate talks at the COP29 in Baku, with the with the President-elect pledging to withdraw from the landmark Paris climate agreement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The re-election of Donald Trump in the US has cast a shadow on climate talks at the COP29 (Conference of the Parties) in Baku, with the with the President-elect pledging to withdraw from the landmark Paris climate agreement.</p>

<p>When Trump was elected in 2016, he had taken the US out of the Paris Agreement. Four years later, it was rectified by Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The ongoing COP29, the annual climate conference, began in Baku, Azerbaijan on Monday (November 11) amid worries of the US pulling out of the Paris climate agreement for the second time. The conference is focusing on strategies for the phased reduction of fossil fuels and climate aid to developing (poorer) nations.</p>

<p>At Copenhagen in 2009, developed countries made a commitment to mobilise $100 billion annually to help developing countries address climate-related challenges and build greener economies.</p>

<p>The Paris pact reaffirmed the 2009 commitment, but only $83.3billion was raised as of 2020. The target was finally met in 2023. All 196 countries, including the US, had signed the Paris Agreement in 2015 and had made non-binding pledges to reduce their earth warming pollution.</p>

<p>However, there are no penalties for not adhering to the agreement.</p>

<p>At the Baku summit, delegates are deciding on a 10-fold increase in financial flows - from the current $100 billion each year that developed countries pledged to raise, to at least a trillion dollars a year from 2026.</p>

<p><strong>Fear Of Exit</strong></p>

<p>At Baku, Washington's top climate envoy John Podesta acknowledged the next US administration would "try and take a U-turn" on climate action, but said that US cities, states and individual citizens would pick up the slack. "While the United States federal government under Donald Trump may put climate change action on the back burner, the work to contain climate change is going to continue in the United States with commitment and passion and belief," he said, according to AFP.</p>

<p>"The fight is bigger than one election, one political cycle in one country," he added.</p>

<p>Regardless of assurances, Trump believes that climate change is a 'hoax' and may go ahead with his plans quicker and without much opposition. He may even take the US out of the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change.</p>

<p>When the previous Trump government walked out of the Paris Agreement, it was just a little over a year old.</p>

<p>The exit had provoked strong international reactions and fears that other countries may also go the US way.</p>

<p>The US rejoined the Paris Agreement under Joe Biden in 2021 and then announced that by the year 2030, America would cut its emissions by half from 2005 levels.</p>

<p>If Trump goes ahead with his campaign promises, it will deal a severe blow to the entire framework for the annual global climate negotiations, causing lasting damage to efforts to limit global warming.</p>

<p>The countries that opted for the Paris Agreement are expected to furnish new plans by mid-February 2025. But if the world's biggest economy doesn't submit its plans, then it definitely sends a wrong signal to detractors of stringent climate action in China, India or Europe. The negative elements in these countries will force their governments to water down efforts towards climate ambition and continue with the dependence on fossil fuels. &nbsp;</p>

<p>US' withdrawal from climate change panels would prevent the country from participating in international discussions about the expansion of clean energy. This would give China an opportunity to elbow out America on solar panels, electric vehicles and other green technologies.</p>

<p>The Trump administration's climate strategy will be clearly known only after the inauguration of the new President on January 20.</p>

<p><strong>Impact On Baku Summit</strong></p>

<p>2024 has been the warmest year on record. According to the EU's (European Union) climate service, this is also the first time that global warming has exceeded 1.5 degrees C above pre-industrial levels.</p>

<p>In simple terms, the long-term temperature increase must be limited to below 1.5 degrees to avoid the devastating impact of climate change.</p>

<p>India, too, has had its share of extreme weather events, from intense rainfall to heatwaves, in 2024. The latest India Climate Report 2024 published on November 8 reveals that the country faced extreme weather events on 93% of the days in the first nine months of this year (from January 1 to September 30, 2024). This means extreme events occurred on 255 out of a total 274 days, leaving 3,200 people dead, affecting 3.2 million hectares of crops, destroying 2,35,862 houses and buildings, and killing 9,457 livestock across the country.</p>

<p>In the last two conferences, delegates had agreed to set up a Loss and Damage Fund to help countries deal with extreme weather events. The Baku summit aims to push further discussions.</p>

<p>At climate meetings in the run-up to Baku, developed nations have already said they are not ready to bear the cost and are asking to widen the donor base to include other rich countries like Singapore, China and the UAE.</p>

<p>Any US decision will influence other developed nations like Australia, New Zealand, Japan, Canada, the UK and the EU to rethink their stance. After the US exit during Trump's first term, these countries had decreased their share of climate finance. Even after Biden reversed Trump's move in 2021, the US did not contribute a major share of its financial pledges from 2017 to 2021.</p>

<p>This constrained the developed nations' mission to raise $100 billion annually to fund climate goals for developing countries.</p>

<p>This time around the fear is that the US may default on its $3 billion pledge to the UN's Green Climate Fund. The US has been a defaulter under other Presidents like Obama and Biden, but didn't opt out of the negotiations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US is the second biggest emitter after China and the largest contributor to historical emissions. Its role and active participation are instrumental in not only mobilising finances for climate change but also in slashing emissions. Setting climate targets will be pointless without the US on board. &nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/528jaq88_trump-coal_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[When Trump was elected in 2016, he had taken the US out of the Paris Agreement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-hits-out-at-saturday-night-live-after-being-mocked-says-show-has-been-dying-slowly-7000379]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk Hits Out At SNL After Being Mocked, Says Show "Has Been Dying Slowly"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-hits-out-at-saturday-night-live-after-being-mocked-says-show-has-been-dying-slowly-7000379]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 13:41:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The billionaire was not impressed by the SNL skit, saying "They are so mad that @realDonaldTrump won".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk has hit out at a Saturday Night Live (SNL) skit mocking him. The said episode aired on November 9, days after Donald Trump's win in the US presidential election that shocked the world. Both Mr Musk and Mr Trump were lampooned in the episode, with actors sarcastically sharing their support for the president-elect to avoid being put on his "enemies list". Mr Musk's character was portrayed by Dana Carvey, a regular SNL cast member. The episode was hosted by comedian and actor Bill Burr.</p>

<p>During the episode, comedian Kenan Thompson said, "If our planet falls apart, we can all go to Mars with the other man that we love and trust: Elon Musk." At this point, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/latenightercom/status/1855472585561289036">Carvey appears mimicking Mr Musk</a>.</p>

<p>He wore a dark MAGA hat while jumping up and down with his hands in the air.</p>

<p>"Check it out: dark MAGA. Yeah! But seriously, I run the country now. America's going to be like one of my rockets. They're super cool and super fun, but there's a slight chance it could blow up and everybody dies. Haha!" said Carvey.</p>

<p>He also threw his hands in the air and exclaimed, "See you in the White House!"</p>

<p>The billionaire was not impressed by the skit and wrote "Dana Carvey just sounds like Dana Carvey," on X, replying under a clip.</p>

<p>Responding to another post, he wrote, "They are so mad that @realDonaldTrump won," and also added a few crying-laughing emojis.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">SNL has been dying slowly for years, as they become increasingly out of touch with reality.<br />
<br />
Their last-ditch effort to cheat the equal airtime requirements and prop up Kamala before the election only helped sink her campaign further. <a href="https://twitter.com/nbcsnl?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@nbcsnl</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1855565689530331535?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"SNL has been dying slowly for years, as they become increasingly out of touch with reality. Their last-ditch effort to cheat the equal airtime requirements and prop up Kamala before the election only helped sink her campaign further," another of his comments read.</p>

<p>Mr Musk had thrown his weight behind Mr Trump, urging voters to elect the Republican leader. He had even offered cash rewards to people who vote.</p>

<p>According to Bloomberg, Mr Musk's net worth has surpassed $300 billion for the first time in almost three years, as shares of Tesla Inc. soar on bets that his close ties with President-elect Donald Trump will bolster the company.</p>

<p>Tesla's stock has jumped 28per cent since Tuesday's close, increasing his wealth by $50 billion to $313.7 billion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j013fjh8_elon-musk-trump-_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk at one of Donald Trump's rallies.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-sun-is-very-active-right-now-what-it-means-for-space-and-earth-7000378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Sun Is Very Active Right Now. What It Means For Space And Earth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-sun-is-very-active-right-now-what-it-means-for-space-and-earth-7000378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 13:41:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sun has kicked into high gear, and the Binar satellites are far from the only casualty.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week, three tiny Australian satellites from Curtin University's <a href="https://www.binarspace.com/">Binar Space Program</a> burned up in Earth's atmosphere. That was always going to happen. In fact, Binar means “fireball” in the Noongar language of the First Nations people of Perth.</p>

<p>When a satellite is in low Earth orbit (2,000km or less), it experiences orbital decay as it drags closer and closer to the surface, <a href="https://theconversation.com/new-research-shows-most-space-rocks-crashing-into-earth-come-from-a-single-source-241455">eventually burning up</a>.</p>

<p>But these <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/what-are-smallsats-and-cubesats/">cube satellites (CubeSats)</a>, known as Binar-2, 3 and 4, entered the atmosphere much sooner than originally planned. They only lasted for two months – a third of what was expected. This significantly reduced valuable time for science and testing new systems.</p>

<p>The reason for their untimely demise? Our Sun has kicked into high gear, and the Binar satellites are far from the only casualty. Recent high solar activity has been causing an unexpected headache for satellite operators in the last few years, and it's only increasing.</p>

<h2>Why is the Sun so active?</h2>

<p>Solar activity includes phenomena such as sunspots, solar flares and solar wind – the stream of charged particles that flows toward Earth.</p>

<p>This activity is a product of the Sun's ever-changing magnetic field, and approximately every 11 years, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/the-suns-magnetic-field-is-about-to-flip">it completely flips</a>. At the midpoint of this cycle, solar activity is at its highest.</p>

<p>While this cycle is known, specific solar activity is challenging to predict – the dynamics are complex and solar forecasting is in its infancy.</p>

<p>In the last few months, indicators of solar activity were more than <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/products/solar-cycle-progression">one and a half times higher than predictions</a> for this point in the current cycle, labelled <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/news/solar-cycle-25-forecast-update">solar cycle 25</a>.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="260" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E65T2AV-EjM?wmode=transparent&amp;start=0" width="440"></iframe></figure>

<h2>The impact of space weather</h2>

<p>Space weather refers to the environmental effects that originate from outside our atmosphere (mostly the Sun). It affects us on Earth in a variety of noticeable and unnoticeable ways.</p>

<p>The most obvious is the presence of auroras. In the past few months, auroras have been visible far more intensely and closer to the equator <a href="https://theconversation.com/why-are-auroras-so-hard-to-predict-and-when-can-we-expect-more-229909">than in the last two decades</a>. This is a direct result of <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/science/wondering-why-the-aurora-borealis-was-visible-so-far-south-last-night-heres-why-its-all-thanks-to-the-sun">the increased solar activity</a>.</p>

<p>Space weather, and solar activity in particular, also creates additional challenges for satellites and satellite operators.</p>

<p>Higher solar activity means more solar flares and stronger solar wind – resulting in a higher flux of charged particles that can <a href="https://www.csiro.au/en/news/all/articles/2024/january/solar-maximum">damage or disrupt electrical components on satellites</a>.</p>

<p>It also means an increase in ionising radiation, resulting in a <a href="https://nap.nationalacademies.org/read/9725/chapter/4#30">higher dose for astronauts</a> and <a href="https://www.versantphysics.com/2024/03/27/flight-crews-and-radiation-exposure/">pilots</a>, and potential disruptions to <a href="https://www.sws.bom.gov.au/Educational/1/3/6">long-distance radio communications</a>.</p>

<p>But for satellites in low Earth orbit, the most consistent effect of solar activity is that the extra energy gets absorbed into the outer atmosphere, causing it to <a href="https://www.weather.gov/news/111522-starlink">balloon outward</a>.</p>

<p>As a result, <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/226665395_The_Effect_of_Atmospheric_Drag_on_Satellite_Orbits_During_the_Bastille_Day_Event">all satellites less than 1,000km from Earth</a> experience a significant increase in <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/impacts/satellite-drag">atmospheric drag</a>. This is a force that disrupts their orbit and causes them to fall towards the planet's surface.</p>

<p>Notable satellites in this region include the International Space Station and the Starlink constellation. These satellites have thrusters to counteract this effect, but these corrections can be expensive.</p>

<p>Low Earth orbit also contains many university satellites, such as the Binar CubeSats. Cube satellites are rarely equipped with tools that can adjust their altitude, so they're entirely at the mercy of space weather.</p>

<h2>What happened to Binar?</h2>

<p>The Binar Space Program is a satellite research program operating out of Curtin University. It aims to advance our understanding of the Solar System and lower the barrier for operating in space.</p>

<p>The program began operations with its first satellite, <a href="https://theconversation.com/australias-first-binar-spacecraft-just-came-down-to-earth-as-a-fireball-heres-what-we-learned-191677">Binar-1</a>, in September 2021. This was less than a year into solar cycle 25 when solar activity was relatively low.</p>

<p>In these conditions, the ten-centimetre cube satellite started at an altitude of 420km and survived a full 364 days in orbit.</p>

<p>The program's follow-up mission – Binar-2, 3, and 4 – were three equally sized CubeSats. However, they were expected to last approximately six months owing to the extra surface area from new <a href="https://digitalcommons.usu.edu/smallsat/2024/all2024/8/">deployable solar arrays</a> and a forecast increase in solar activity.</p>

<p>Instead, they only made it to two months before burning up. While cube satellite missions are relatively cheap, the premature ending of a mission will always be costly. <a href="https://www.space.com/spacex-starlink-satellite-loss-space-weather-forecast">This is even more true for commercial satellites</a>, highlighting the need for more accurate space weather forecasting.</p>

<p>The good news is the Sun will calm down again. Despite the current unexpectedly high solar activity, it will likely slow down by 2026, and is expected to <a href="https://www.almanac.com/solar-cycle-25-sun-heating">return to a solar minimum in 2030</a>.</p>

<p>While this was not an explicit goal of the mission, the Binar Space Program has now poignantly demonstrated the dramatic effects of solar activity on space operations.</p>

<p>While the untimely loss of Binar-2, 3 and 4 was unfortunate, work has already begun on future missions. They are expected to launch into far more forgiving space weather.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/242899/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><span>(<strong>Author:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/kyle-mcmullan-2248370">Kyle McMullan</a>, PhD Candidate in Aerospace Engineering, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/curtin-university-873">Curtin University</a>)</em></span></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/right-now-the-sun-is-far-more-active-than-predicted-and-small-satellites-are-paying-the-price-242899">original article</a>.</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eh9n2bpg_sun-generic_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-what-is-the-latest-science-on-climate-change-7000333]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[COP29: What Is The Latest Science On Climate Change?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-what-is-the-latest-science-on-climate-change-7000333]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 13:37:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This year's U.N. climate summit - COP29 - is being held during yet another record-breaking year of higher global temperatures, adding pressure to negotiations aimed at curbing climate change.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year's U.N. climate summit - COP29 - is being held during yet another record-breaking year of higher global temperatures, adding pressure to negotiations aimed at curbing climate change.</p>

<p>The last global scientific consensus on climate change was released in 2021 through the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, however scientists say that evidence shows global warming and its impacts are unfolding faster than expected.</p>

<p><strong>Here is some of the latest climate research:</strong></p>

<p><strong>1.5C BREACHED?</strong></p>

<p>The world may already have hit 1.5 degree Celsius (2.7 F) of warming above the average pre-industrial temperature - a critical threshold beyond which it is at risk of irreversible and extreme climate change, scientists say.</p>

<p>A group of researchers made the suggestion in a study released on Monday based on an analysis of 2,000 years of atmospheric gases trapped in Antarctic ice cores that extends the understanding of pre-industrial temperature trends.</p>

<p>Scientists have typically measured today's temperatures against a baseline temperature average for 1850-1900. By that measure, the world is now at nearly 1.3 C (2.4 F) of warming.</p>

<p>But the new data suggests a longer pre-industrial baseline, based on temperature data spanning the year 13 to 1700, the study published in the journal Nature Geoscience said.</p>

<p>Either way, 2024 is certain to be the warmest year on record.</p>

<p><strong>SUPERCHARGED HURRICANES&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Not only is ocean warming fuelling stronger Atlantic storms, it is also causing them to intensify more rapidly, for example, jumping from a Category 1 to a Category 3 storm in just hours.</p>

<p>Growing evidence shows this is true of other ocean basins.</p>

<p>Hurricane Milton needed only one day in the Gulf of Mexico in October to go from tropical storm to the Gulf's second-most powerful hurricane on record, slamming Florida's west coast.</p>

<p>Warmer air can also hold more moisture, helping storms carry and eventually release more rain. As a result, hurricanes are delivering flooding even in mountain towns like Asheville, North Carolina, inundated in September by Hurricane Helene.</p>

<p><strong>WILDFIRE DEATHS</strong></p>

<p>Global warming is drying waterways and sapping moisture from forests, creating conditions for bigger and hotter wildfires from the U.S. West and Canada to southern Europe and Russia's Far East creating more damaging smoke.</p>

<p>Research published last month in Nature Climate Change calculated that about 13% of deaths associated with toxic wildfire smoke, roughly 12,000 deaths, during the 2010s could be attributed to the climate effect on wildfires.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>CORAL BLEACHING&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>With the world in the throes of a fourth mass coral bleaching event - the largest on record &nbsp;- scientists fear the world's reefs have passed a point of no return.</p>

<p>Scientists will be studying bleached reefs from Australia to Brazil for signs of recovery over the next few years if temperatures fall.</p>

<p><strong>AMAZON ALARM&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Brazil's Amazon is in the grips of its worst and most widespread drought since records began in 1950. River levels sank to all-time lows this year, while fires ravaged the rainforest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This adds concern to scientific findings earlier this year that between 10% and 47% of the Amazon will face combined stresses of heat and drought from climate change, as well as other threats, by 2050.</p>

<p>This could push the Amazon past a tipping point, with the jungle no longer able to produce enough moisture to quench its own trees, at which point the ecosystem could transition to degraded forests or sandy savannas.</p>

<p>Globally, forests appear to be struggling.</p>

<p>A July study found that forests overall last year failed to absorb as much carbon dioxide from the atmosphere as in the past, due largely to the Amazon drought and wildfires in Canada.</p>

<p>That means a record amount of CO2 entered the atmosphere.</p>

<p><strong>VOLCANIC SURGE&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Scientists fear climate change could even boost volcanic eruptions.</p>

<p>In Iceland, volcanoes appear to be responding to rapid glacier retreat. As ice melts, less pressure is exerted on the Earth's crust and mantle.</p>

<p>Volcanologists worry this could destabilize magma reservoirs and appears to be leading to more magma being created, building up pressure underground.</p>

<p>Some 245 volcanoes across the world lie under or near ice and could be at risk.</p>

<p><strong>OCEAN SLOWDOWN</strong></p>

<p>The warming of the Atlantic could hasten the collapse of a key current system, which scientists warn could already be sputtering.</p>

<p>The Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC), which transports warm water from the tropics to the North Atlantic, has helped to keep European winters milder for centuries.</p>

<p>Research in 2018 showed that AMOC has weakened by about 15% since 1950, while research published in February in the journal Science Advances, suggested that it could be closer to a critical slowdown than previously thought.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jjlggl0c_cop29-climate-summit-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[COP29 is being held during yet another record-breaking year of higher global temperatures]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philippines-says-its-under-pressure-from-china-to-cede-claims-in-south-china-sea-7000324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Philippines Says It's Under Pressure From China To Cede Claims In South China Sea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philippines-says-its-under-pressure-from-china-to-cede-claims-in-south-china-sea-7000324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 13:36:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China is putting ever-greater pressure on the Philippines to cede its sovereign rights in the South China Sea, Secretary of National Defense Gilberto Teodoro said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China is putting ever-greater pressure on the Philippines to cede its sovereign rights in the South China Sea, Secretary of National Defense Gilberto Teodoro said on Tuesday after a meeting with his Australian counterpart in Canberra.</p>

<p>"What we see is an increasing demand by Beijing for us to concede our sovereign rights in the area," he said, adding that the Philippines was a "victim of Chinese aggression".</p>

<p>China and the Philippines have sparred repeatedly this year over disputed areas of the South China Sea, including the Scarborough Shoal, one of Asia's most contested features.</p>

<p>Teodoro's meeting with his Australian counterpart Richard Marles, their fifth since August 2023, reflects growing security ties between the countries, both of whom have expressed concern about Chinese activity in areas of the South China Sea claimed by the Philippines and other Southeast Asian nations.</p>

<p>The two nations signed a strategic partnership in September 2023 and held their first joint sea and air patrols in the South China Sea several months later. The Philippines also joined war games in Australia this year for the first time.</p>

<p>China claims almost the entire South China Sea, a conduit for more than $3 trillion of annual ship-borne commerce, including parts claimed by the Philippines, Vietnam, Indonesia, Malaysia and Brunei. The Permanent Court of Arbitration in 2016 said China's claims had no legal basis, a ruling Beijing rejects.</p>

<p>Teodoro said China's claims and behaviour were contrary to international law and defence deals with partners such as Australia were an important way to deter Chinese incursions.</p>

<p>"Although they (China) claim to act under the aegis of international law, everybody knows that what they're doing is contrary to the tenets of international law," he said.</p>

<p>"The biggest evidence of this is that nobody has actually supported their actions or activities."</p>

<p>In addition to closer ties with countries including Australia and the United States, the Philippines also plans to spend at least $33 billion on new weapons including advanced fighter jets and mid-range missiles.</p>

<p>Marles said Australia wanted to work more closely with the Philippine defence industry and would send an engineering assessment team to the country early next year.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6g8v8eeg_south-china-sea_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China claims almost the entire South China Sea, a conduit for over $3 trillion of ship-borne commerce.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/toxic-towns-in-kyrgyzstan-battling-radioactive-danger-7000305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Toxic Towns In Kyrgyzstan Battling Radioactive Danger]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/toxic-towns-in-kyrgyzstan-battling-radioactive-danger-7000305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 13:34:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three decades on from independence, Kyrgyzstan is still dealing with the consequences of the Cold War nuclear arms race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a mask and a hazmat suit, Ermek Murataliyev drives a truck filled with Soviet-era radioactive waste along the winding mountain roads of Kyrgyzstan.</p>

<p>His is a hazardous mission: two such trucks crashed into ravines over the summer.</p>

<p>Drivers in this former Soviet Central Asian state are forbidden to stop until they reach their final destination -- a storage zone where the waste will be buried under thick layers of compacted clay and rock.</p>

<p>Murataliyev had to undergo a medical inspection and have regular health checks to get the job.&nbsp;"I have been trained on how to keep myself safe," he said.</p>

<p>Three decades on from independence, Kyrgyzstan is still dealing with the consequences of the Cold War nuclear arms race, when Central Asia provided the Soviet Union with all of its uranium.</p>

<p>Kyrgyz authorities say there are now six million cubic metres of radioactive waste in 30 sites such as Min-Kush, which require complex and costly disposal measures.</p>

<p>"When the Soviet Union collapsed, Kyrgyzstan had neither the equipment nor the money to transfer the waste to safe sites," said Ilgiz Ernis, deputy mayor of the Min-Kush municipality.</p>

<p>"The process was badly delayed," he said.</p>

<p>The disposal work is now in its final stages and is being carried out by the Russian nuclear giant Rosatom as well as the European Union and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</p>

<p><strong>'Radioactive Lake'</strong></p>

<p>Local resident Aiman Kishkenalina said "this problem is not just for Min-Kush but for all of Kyrgyzstan".</p>

<p>Kishkenalina is one of around 5,600 residents of the run-down uranium mining town -- a ticking time bomb with grave human and environmental consequences.</p>

<p>"Some experts with dosimeters found that the (radiation) level was too high in some places," she said.</p>

<p>Local officials say it is in fact up to six times higher than the norm.</p>

<p>Radioactive waste has also been found in the river running through Min-Kush that flows into the Syr Darya, the second-largest river in the region, potentially threatening up to 80 million people.</p>

<p>"The (radioactive) content of the water that passes under the disposal area breaches admissible norms," said Bakytbek Asankulov, who is in charge of radioactive security at the Kyrgyz emergency situations ministry.</p>

<p>Asankulov also warned of the risk of a landslide where natural disasters exacerbated by climate change are becoming more frequent.</p>

<p>He said a landslide triggered by either foul weather or the earthquake-prone country's tremors could block up the river and "create a radioactive lake".</p>

<p>If the water from such a lake were to burst out, it "would reach the Fergana Valley" -- the most populated part of Central Asia where Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan meet.</p>

<p><strong>'Hair Falling Out'</strong></p>

<p>Warnings from the authorities not to drink contaminated water from the river are ignored by some local inhabitants.</p>

<p>"We eat the livestock and we drink the milk of cows" that have drunk the water, said Perizat Berdaliyeva, a retired former accountant at the uranium mine.</p>

<p>Health risks from radiation were covered up in Soviet times but, unlike many other parts of the Communist bloc, atomic industry towns like Min-Kush had no food shortages.</p>

<p>"Everything was available," Berdaliyeva remembered.</p>

<p>Scientific studies have found an abnormal prevalence of illnesses such as cancer and depleted immune systems among people living close to nuclear waste sites.</p>

<p>"My two daughters' hair is falling out. They are often sick. My husband gets nose bleeds," said Nazgul Zarylbek, 25.</p>

<p>Her house was recently pulled down by the authorities because it was contaminated with radiation. She received 5,000 euros ($5,300) in compensation and was re-housed in a different part of Min-Kush.</p>

<p>Located in a picturesque valley at an altitude of 2,000 metres (6,500 feet), Min-Kush could appear relatively normal were it not for an electronic display outside the mayor's office showing the current radiation levels.</p>

<p>The town in central Kyrgyzstan wants to turn the page from its toxic past and local officials are even hoping that it could have tourism potential.</p>

<p>"The transfer of uranium waste to a safer area will allow Min-Kush to be taken off the red list for tourism," deputy mayor Ernis said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u5dt3058_kyrgyzstan_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Drivers in Kyrgyzstan are forbidden to stop until they reach their final destination.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>