<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 18:45:37 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mujiburs-joy-bangla-ceases-to-be-national-slogan-for-bangladesh-7232810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mujibur's "Joy Bangla" Ceases To Be National Slogan For Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mujiburs-joy-bangla-ceases-to-be-national-slogan-for-bangladesh-7232810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 18:15:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["Joy Bangla" or "Victory to Bangla" was the symbol of patriotism and unity especially during the birth of Bangladesh. "Joy Bangla" was more than a political slogan - it was a war cry.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Supreme Court has put a hold on a High Court verdict that declared "Joy Bangla" as the country's national slogan. This phrase, popularised by Bangbandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, has been a significant part of Bangladesh's history and identity.</p>

<p>"Joy Bangla" or "Victory to Bangla" was the symbol of patriotism and unity especially during the birth of Bangladesh. "Joy Bangla" was more than a political slogan - it was a war cry.</p>

<p>On March 2nd 2022, it was made the national slogan by the Awami League government and it became mandatory at all government offices to voice the two words during national celebrations.</p>

<p>The recent development comes after Sheikh Hasina, Rahman's daughter and the former Prime Minister, was ousted from power on August 5. Since then, the new government has taken steps to remove symbols associated with Hasina and her father, including the removal of Rahman's image from currency notes.</p>

<p>After the change of government, the state made a move to the High Court to hold the ruling and filed the leave to appeal petition with the SC on December 2nd seeking a stay on the High Court verdict of March 10, 2020.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court's decision was made on the grounds that the national slogan is a matter of government policy, and the judiciary should not interfere.</p>

<p>Additional Attorney General Aneek R Haque stated that "'Joy Bangla' will not be considered as the national slogan following this Appellate Division order".</p>

<p>This move is part of a broader effort by the new government to distance itself from the previous administration. The government has also decided not to observe August 15 as a national mourning day and public holiday, despite a High Court verdict justifying the observance.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, on August 13th, the advisory council of the interim government made a decision to not even have a national holiday on August 15th.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh Bank is also printing new currency notes that feature the July uprising, which refers to the student-led protests that forced Hasina to flee to India. Notably, these new notes will not include the image of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/75t4s75_bangladesh-protest-reuters_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Students wave flags to mark one month of the end of Awami League regime, on Sept 5, 2024]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-longer-of-this-time-miss-netherlands-pageant-scrapped-after-25-years-7232731]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Country Has Scrapped Its Beauty Pageant: "Times Have Changed"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-longer-of-this-time-miss-netherlands-pageant-scrapped-after-25-years-7232731]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 18:02:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Miss Netherlands beauty pageant is being scrapped after 25 years, organisers said on Thursday, transforming into a new platform dealing with mental health and sharing positive stories.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Miss Netherlands beauty pageant is being scrapped after 25 years, organisers said on Thursday, transforming into a new platform dealing with mental health and sharing positive stories.</p>

<p>"Times have changed and we are changing with the times," the organisers of the pageant said in a statement.</p>

<p>Instead of running the competition, director Monica van Ee has set up a platform entitled "no longer of this time."</p>

<p>This platform aims to share stories of successful women but also those struggling with, among other things, social media and unrealistic beauty standards.</p>

<p>"No more crowns, but stories that inspire. No dresses, but dreams that come to life," organisers said.</p>

<p>Van Ee said in a blog post on the new platform that her involvement in the pageant aimed to give young woman a springboard and show others what was possible.</p>

<p>"Perhaps a sash and a crown are no longer of this time. But women who support each other and help each other, that is timeless for us," she said.</p>

<p>The competition made headlines in 2023 when Rikkie Kolle, then 22, became the first transgender woman to win the pageant.</p>

<p>Kolle told AFP in an interview she hoped her victory would be an inspiration to young people from the transgender community.</p>

<p>Van Ee said the new platform should be "a place to show your authentic self and a world where we celebrate real life. Without the pressure to conform to a perfect image."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-03/beigl5ao_beauty-pageant-generic-650_625x300_03_March_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Van Ee said the new platform should be "a place to show your authentic self".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-chinese-tourist-in-sri-lanka-falls-from-moving-train-while-posing-for-selfie-7232560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Woman In Sri Lanka Falls From Moving Train While Posing For Selfie]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-chinese-tourist-in-sri-lanka-falls-from-moving-train-while-posing-for-selfie-7232560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:42:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video going viral on social media has captured a terrifying moment a tourist fell from a train after being hit by a tree while dangling out of the carriage for a snap.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The practice of taking countless selfies, creating reels and making vlogs has become a common sight. In an attempt to go viral, several people are also seen engaging in rather risky feats, putting the lives of others in danger. Now, one such video going viral on social media has captured a terrifying moment a tourist fell from a train after being hit by a tree while dangling out of the carriage for a snap. According to <em>The Sun</em>, the incident took place on a train in Sri Lanka on Saturday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The tourist, identified as a tourist from China, was holding onto the railings and leaning out of the carriage for a selfie video when she was bashed in the head by some tree branches. She was quickly dragged from the carriage, and the video captured her flailing her arms in a panic as she fell out of the train.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A Chinese tourist had a heart-stopping moment while traveling on Sri Lanka's coastal railway line. She fell from the train after being struck by a tree branch while trying to record a video," an X user wrote while sharing the video.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A Chinese tourist had a heart-stopping moment while traveling on Sri Lanka's coastal railway line. She fell from the train after being struck by a tree branch while trying to record a video.<br />
<br />
Fortunately, she landed on a bush, which broke her fall and miraculously left her… <a href="https://t.co/GmKnViyC0U">pic.twitter.com/GmKnViyC0U</a></p>
— Daily Sherlock ?? ?? (@dailysherlock0) <a href="https://twitter.com/dailysherlock0/status/1867095491600589115?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/32252438/idiot-tourist-falls-off-train-video/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>The Sun</em></a>, when the train stopped at the next station, a few fellow passengers returned to the accident scene to help the woman. After being dragged out of the train, she fell on some bush and survived the fall.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Fortunately, she landed on a bush, which broke her fall and miraculously left her unharmed. The police confirmed that she didn't sustain any injuries," the caption of the post read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Local cops have reminded passengers on trains to pay attention to their surroundings at all times. They also urged people to follow safety precautions.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/rs-2000-ki-plate-this-honest-wedding-invitation-card-takes-internet-by-storm-7231027">"Rs 2,000 Ki Plate": This Honest Wedding Invitation Card Takes Internet By Storm</a></strong></p>

<p>The video has gone viral on social media, with many users criticising the woman for putting herself in danger just for a reel. Reacting to the clip, one user wrote, "She is lucky that it is only a bush." "No sense of fear?" commented another. "This is so silly," expressed a third.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, this is not the first time a person has attempted a dangerous stunt to go viral on social media. Earlier this year, a woman was slammed after a video captured her sitting on the edge of a well with a child clinging to her leg. The video captured the woman lip-syncing a song. A little child, on the other hand, clung to one of her legs while his body dangled in the air above an open well.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The video prompted varied comments, with users calling it reckless, unnecessary and pointless to form such an act and risk their lives. Some social media users also demanded that the woman should be arrested for putting the child's life in danger.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/t24vc6oo_chinese-tourist-in-sri-lanka_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Social media users criticised the woman for putting herself in danger just for a reel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2025-likely-to-be-among-top-three-warmest-years-uk-met-office-7232482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2025 'Likely' To Be Among Top Three Warmest Years: UK Met Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2025-likely-to-be-among-top-three-warmest-years-uk-met-office-7232482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:34:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK weather service forecast Thursday that 2025 would likely be among the top three warmest years globally, falling just behind the record-breaking temperatures set in the past months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK weather service forecast Thursday that 2025 would likely be among the top three warmest years globally, falling just behind the record-breaking temperatures set in the past months.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Meteorological Office's 2025 forecast, average global temperatures next year will be 1.29 to 1.53 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels (1850-1900), slightly cooler than in 2024 and 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Met also said 2024 was expected to be the warmest year on record, confirming findings released this week by Europe's climate monitor Copernicus.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The reports come at the end of a year in which rich and poor countries were devastated by climate disasters that scientists link to human activity that is rapidly warming the Earth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Met forecast, 2024 is also "almost certain to exceed" for the first time the 1.5C (2.7 degrees Fahrenheit) threshold to protect the planet from dangerously overheating, following the 1.45C reached in 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The major contribution" to warming temperatures is the rise of greenhouse gas emissions, driven by human activity like burning fossil fuels, according to the report.&nbsp;</p>

<p>2024 and 2023 temperatures were also "elevated slightly" by El Nino, a natural phenomenon that moves around warm water.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the Met warned that 2025 would remain warm, despite not experiencing the warming El Nino effect.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Years, such as 2025, which aren't dominated by the warming influence of El Nino, should be cooler," said Adam Scaife, who led the Met's 2025 forecast.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Sobering milestone'</strong></p>

<p>Scaife compared 2025 to a decade earlier, when 2016, which was an El Nino year, was the warmest year on record at the time.</p>

<p>"In comparison to our forecast for 2025 though, 2016 is now looking decidedly cool," Scaife said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The average global temperature for 2025 is forecast to be between 1.29C and 1.53C above pre-industrial levels, with a central estimate of 1.41C. In 2016, the average was 0.77C.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Met's scientists also said 2024 crossing 1.5C was a "sobering milestone".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The world agreed under the 2015 Paris climate agreement to limit warming to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels, with scientists warning that crossing the threshold for decades would be catastrophic for the planet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's important to recognise that a temporary exceedance of 1.5C doesn't mean a breach of the Paris Agreement," said the Met's Nick Dunstone, who worked on the forecast.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"But the first year above 1.5C is certainly a sobering milestone in climate history."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The report comes days after the UK was battered by its fourth named storm of the season, causing flooding and deaths and knocking out power to tens of thousands of homes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Climate scientists say storms are becoming more powerful as the world heats up. Warmer ocean surfaces release more water vapour that provides additional energy for storms, strengthening winds.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/059pkdkg_warmer-summer-heatwave-temperature-rise-global-warming-istock_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[2024 and 2023 temperatures were also "elevated slightly" by El Nino.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-pakistan-pm-imran-khan-wife-indicted-in-another-graft-case-7232279]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Former Pakistan PM Imran Khan, Wife Indicted In Another Graft Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-pakistan-pm-imran-khan-wife-indicted-in-another-graft-case-7232279]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:08:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani court indicted imprisoned former prime minister Imran Khan and his wife on fresh charges of illegally selling state gifts on Thursday, local broadcaster Geo reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani court indicted imprisoned former prime minister Imran Khan and his wife on fresh charges of illegally selling state gifts on Thursday, local broadcaster Geo reported.</p>

<p>The indictment was the latest in dozens of cases against the 72-year-old former cricket star, who has been in jail since late last year.</p>

<p>Khan and his wife Bushra Bibi have already been granted bail in the case, which is one of a series of state treasury charges known as "Toshakhana".</p>

<p>These charges revolve around allegations that Khan and his wife illegally procured and then sold gifts worth more than 140 million rupees ($501,000) in state possession, which he received during his 2018-22 premiership. They have denied committing an offence.</p>

<p>Khan and Bibi were both handed a 14-year sentence on those charges days before a national election earlier this year, following a three-year sentence handed to him in late 2023 in another version of the same case.</p>

<p>However, their sentences have been suspended in appeals at the high court.</p>

<p>The gifts included diamond jewellery and seven watches, six of them Rolexes - the most expensive being valued at 85 million rupees ($305,000).</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Khan was also indicted on charges of inciting attacks against the military, a case stemming from deadly anti-government rallies led by his party last year.</p>

<p>Bibi also led a deadly protest march by thousands of supporters in the capital Islamabad on Nov. 25, escalating a face-off with the government and its military backers.</p>

<p>Khan has been fighting court cases since he was ousted from power in 2022. He and his party say the cases were made up to keep him out of politics at the behest of the military after he had fallen out with the army's generals. The army denies the accusation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3a5hhu9_imran-khan_625x300_27_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former Pakistan prime minister Imran Khan]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insufficient-evidence-sweden-ends-rape-investigation-against-kylian-mbappe-7232268]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Insufficient Evidence": Sweden Ends Rape Investigation Against Kylian Mbappe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insufficient-evidence-sweden-ends-rape-investigation-against-kylian-mbappe-7232268]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:04:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An investigation into alleged rape and sexual assault in Stockholm which targeted Real Madrid forward Kylian Mbappe has been closed due to insufficient evidence, the Swedish prosecutor said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An investigation into alleged rape and sexual assault in Stockholm which Swedish media said targeted Real Madrid forward Kylian Mbappe has been closed due to insufficient evidence, the Swedish prosecutor said Thursday.</p>

<p>Mbappe, the 25-year-old Frenchman who is one of the highest-profile players in world football, visited the Swedish capital October 9-11 with a group of people after he was left out of his country's squad for a Nations League match.</p>

<p>Sweden's prosecution authority announced on October 15 that it was investigating an alleged incident that occurred at an upscale Stockholm hotel on October 10, without mentioning the suspect by name.</p>

<p>Several Swedish media outlets, including newspapers Aftonbladet and Expressen and public broadcaster SVT, identified Mbappe as the suspect.</p>

<p>"My assessment is that the evidence is not sufficient to proceed and the investigation is therefore closed," prosecutor Marina Chirakova said in a statement that also did not mention Mbappe by name.</p>

<p>Ms Chirakova said the person in question had not been interrogated and "not been notified of suspicion of a crime".</p>

<p>"I have concluded, based on what has emerged in the case, that new evidence, including interrogations of the person in question, would not change the evidence situation right now," she told AFP.</p>

<p>She said her team had nonetheless "conducted a large number of interviews in the investigation".</p>

<p>Petra Eklund, the lawyer for the plaintiff, whose name has not been disclosed, told AFP she had "no comment" to the news that the case had been closed.</p>

<p>Mbappe's lawyer said in October that he was "shocked" to see his name linked to the investigation.</p>

<p>Speaking for the first time about the case on Sunday, he told French television show Clique he was "not involved".</p>

<p>"I haven't received anything, no summons... I'm not involved," he said.</p>

<p>According to Aftonbladet, Mbappe and his entourage dined at a restaurant one evening before going on to a nightclub.</p>

<p>The complaint was filed on October 12 after the alleged victim had sought medical attention, according to the newspaper.</p>

<p>Expressen reported that police had seized some clothing as evidence, saying it consisted of women's underwear, a pair of black trousers and a black top. Photographs showed police officers leaving the hotel with brown bags.</p>

<p><strong>Difficult season</strong></p>

<p>Mbappe joined Madrid this summer after seven years at Paris Saint-Germain and has stayed clear of scandal in his private life.</p>

<p>The forward, who is known for carefully managing his image through a close network of family, lawyers and spokespeople, has become one of the world's highest paid players after a stellar career that began when he was barely into his teens.</p>

<p>He has had a difficult season since moving to reigning European champions Real Madrid from PSG in the summer, failing to find his top form.</p>

<p>However the Frenchman scored in Madrid's 3-2 win against Italian side Atalanta on Tuesday which revived Real's flagging bid to regain their Champions League title.</p>

<p>Mbappe, Vinicius Junior and Jude Bellingham were all on the scoresheet in Bergamo as Madrid moved up to 20th place in the Champions League table, on nine points from six matches.</p>

<p>The Spanish giants would have been at risk of dropping out of the Champions League play-off places if they had lost.</p>

<p>Mbappe won the World Cup as a teenager in 2018 in Russia and scored a hat-trick in the 2022 final in Qatar which France lost on penalties to Lionel Messi's Argentina.</p>

<p>At PSG he was part of a superstar trio with Messi and Brazilian forward Neymar, but the Qatar-owned club were unable to win the Champions League.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2154psa8_kylian-mbappe_625x300_26_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kylian Mbappe, the 25-year-old Frenchman is one of the highest-profile players in football.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-whose-selfie-with-merkel-went-viral-wants-to-stay-in-germany-7232213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syrian Whose Selfie With Merkel Went Viral Wants To Stay In Germany]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-whose-selfie-with-merkel-went-viral-wants-to-stay-in-germany-7232213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:59:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Almost a decade ago, a Syrian refugee's selfie with Germany's then chancellor Angela Merkel went viral. Today, Anas Modamani has a job, a German passport and a fiancee and no plans to return to his war-ravaged country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Almost a decade ago, a Syrian refugee's selfie with Germany's then chancellor Angela Merkel went viral. Today, Anas Modamani has a job, a German passport and a fiancee and no plans to return to his war-ravaged country.</p>

<p>While right-wing politicians in Europe have been quick to demand that Syrians "go home" after the fall of president Bashar al-Assad, Modamani's story typifies how many have put down roots in their host countries.</p>

<p>"I am a Berliner, I have my life here," said the 27-year-old cameraman who arrived in the German capital in 2015 at the age of 18, and is now part of the biggest Syrian refugee community in Europe.</p>

<p>Having financed his studies in communication with a part-time job at a supermarket, Modamani is now working as a freelancer video journalist for public broadcaster Deutsche Welle.</p>

<p>He lives with his Ukrainian fiancee, a mechanical engineer who herself arrived in Germany a few months before Russia launched its full-scale invasion of her country in February 2022.</p>

<p>"I have a wonderful apartment and a very beautiful woman, I have everything I need here," Modamani told AFP.</p>

<p>He said he originally fled Syria because he "did not want to perform military service" for Assad's regime, and that now he doesn't want to return as he had "experienced terrible things there".</p>

<p>"I lost friends," he said. "Members of my family died because of the regime."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Worried' for friends</strong></p>

<p>Less than three months before early elections are expected in Germany on February 23, far-right and conservative politicians have made the repatriation of Syrians a campaign issue.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock of the Greens party on Wednesday criticised such calls, saying they revealed "a lack of realism about the situation in the Middle East".</p>

<p>Modamani said that "for my friends who, unlike me, don't have a German passport, I am worried".</p>

<p>"The war is over but the situation is uncertain, we have to see how it develops."</p>

<p>While he has "more friends in Berlin than in Syria", his parents and siblings still live in Syria, around half an hour's drive from Damascus.</p>

<p>He said he also worries about the air strikes Israel has carried out since Assad was overthrown, targeting the ousted regime's military assets.</p>

<p>"It could affect anyone," Modamani said, noting that "when I phoned my mother recently, she was hiding in the cellar".</p>

<p><strong>'Part of history'</strong></p>

<p>Modamani is safely settled but the fate of others hangs in the balance after German authorities this week decided to freeze issuing decisions on pending asylum applications from Syrian nationals.</p>

<p>Since his famous Merkel selfie, Modamani has become something of a celebrity in the Syrian community and says he want to use his platform of more than 50,000 followers on TikTok to be a "voice for people who come from Syria".</p>

<p>The selfie at the time became a symbol of Berlin's welcome of almost a million people escaping the war-torn country.</p>

<p>But it also attracted some negative attention as it was used in disinformation linking him to terror attacks.</p>

<p>In 2017 he took Facebook to court in an effort to make the social media giant remove such photos but he lost the case.</p>

<p>While Modamani and Merkel have not crossed paths again, the former chancellor still remembers the incident.</p>

<p>In her memoirs published last month, Merkel admitted she had been surprised by the stir the photo caused, when supporters and critics used it as a symbol of Germany's migrant policy.</p>

<p>"Even now, I cannot understand how anyone could assume that a friendly face on a photo could encourage people to flee their homeland in droves," she wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Or that, conversely, the grimmest possible expression would have stopped them from doing so."</p>

<p>Modamani thinks it's "great" that his photo found its way into Merkel's tome.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My picture is going to be part of history forever."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/inrea3qo_anas-modamani_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Syrian refugee Anas Modamani displays the selfie he took with former German chancellor Angela Merkel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktok-user-helps-us-cops-arrest-suspect-who-fatally-shot-ex-girlfriend-3-years-ago-7232029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[TikTok User Helps US Cops Arrest Suspect Who Fatally Shot Woman 3 Years Ago]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktok-user-helps-us-cops-arrest-suspect-who-fatally-shot-ex-girlfriend-3-years-ago-7232029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:38:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Social media platform TikTok has helped US police solve a case and arrest a suspect who fatally shot a woman three years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media platform TikTok has helped US police solve a case and arrest a suspect who fatally shot a woman three years ago. According to <em>CNN</em>, the suspect, identified as Benjamin Williams, allegedly killed his estranged girlfriend Joana Peca three years ago in Florida. US Marshals arrested him in Mexico City after a TikTok user recognised him from a photo in a video. The clip was posted by Jasmeen Alexander, a TikTok influencer whose true-crime account has more than 2.8 million followers. The video showed a Florida news channel's coverage of the killing and search for the suspect.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The police said Williams, 41, shot Joana Peca in the face in July 2021. He convinced her to meet him at a cemetery in St Petersburg. He told her that he wanted to meet his infant son, but while she was sitting in a van with the baby, Williams allegedly shot her multiple times in the face, killing her. Ms Peca's older son, 4, was also inside the vehicle at the time but both children were unharmed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the cops, Ms Peca was holding her 4-month-old son in her arms when it happened. On the other hand, her older son witnessed the entire incident from the backseat.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now, three years after the incident, Williams has been arrested and charged with first-degree murder and two counts of child abuse. He is being held without bond in the Pinellas County Jail, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/12/05/us/bambi-williams-joana-peca-florida-cec/index.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-intel-ceo-says-will-fast-this-week-for-100-000-employees-heres-why-7228856">Ex-Intel CEO Says Will Fast This Week For 100,000 Employees. Here's Why</a></strong></p>

<p>Ms Peca's family is grateful he's been arrested. "I feel a Christmas present for me and my little boys came early this year, and I couldn't ask for more than that phone call I got from the police department," Eleni Peca, the victim's mother," said per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/crime/tiktok-crime-police-murder-mother-b2662028.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>The Independent</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Three years and three months is too long. He was running, but he couldn't hide anymore. All eyes on him, and finally, he is behind bars where he belongs," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, St Petersburg Police Chief Anthony Holloway told Ms Peca's family: "Nothing we do can replace the loss of your daughter, but at least, we have a dangerous person off the street."</p>

<p>"At least a loving mother ... and the family can know now that we have him in custody. He is behind bars where he belongs," the police chief added.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3u2v66r_benjamin-williams_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police said Williams, 41, shot Joana Peca in the face in July 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netflix-star-jos-de-la-torre-dead-at-37-after-battle-with-serious-mystery-illness-7231665]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netflix Star Dies At 37 After Battle With 'Serious' Mystery Illness]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netflix-star-jos-de-la-torre-dead-at-37-after-battle-with-serious-mystery-illness-7231665]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:59:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tributes have poured in from colleagues and fans, expressing shock and sadness at his untimely death.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spanish actor Jose de la Torre, best known for his role as Ivan in Netflix's '<em>Toy Boy,'</em> has died at 37.&nbsp;The cause of the actor's death has not been publicly disclosed. However, in June, he shared that he had been diagnosed with a serious illness, although the specific condition was not revealed. He subsequently began treatment and stepped back from the public eye to focus on his health. His funeral was held on December 6 in his hometown of Montilla in Spain's Cordoba Province,&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.montilladigital.com/2024/12/fallece-los-37-anos-el-actor-montillano.html">Montilla Digital&nbsp;</a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Torre is survived by his parents and sister in his hometown of Montilla, Cordoba Province, Spain. Tributes have poured in from colleagues and fans, expressing shock and sadness at his untimely death.</p>

<p>Spanish actress Luisa Martín paid tribute to José de la Torre on Instagram, posting a heartfelt photo of the actor smiling. She wrote, "I don't think about you in the past baby! No because I know you'll keep organizing every dinner and every space. Fly as high as you know, you are light, a very bright light that will illuminate us all. It breaks my heart to think I'll never hear your voice again, but I'll keep talking to you. I love you infinitely Jose."</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNdca3umU6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNdca3umU6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNdca3umU6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNdca3umU6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Luisa Martín (@luisa_martinactrizoficial)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"I can't believe you're gone so soon. I'm devastated by your departure. I'm sending kisses to all of your family and friends. We'll never forget you Jose. Wherever you are, I'm sure you're wearing a Hawaiian shirt, a killer moustache, and those sunglasses like the ones we wore that day," Spanish singer Pablo Alboran wrote via Instagram.</p>

<p>The actor gained widespread recognition for his portrayal of Ivan in the Netflix Spanish thriller series <em>'Toy Boy.'</em> The show, which aired from 2019 to 2021, follows the story of a stripper wrongly accused of a crime. De la Torre's acting career was relatively short-lived, having made his debut just two years prior to landing the role of Ivan. His first role was as Goyo in the police drama <em>'Serve and Protect.' </em>He also appeared in <em>'Vis a Vis: El Oasis' and 'Amar es para siempre'</em> in 2020.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9p5ssoj8_jose-de-la-torre_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He also appeared in 'Vis a Vis: El Oasis' and 'Amar es para siempre' in 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/to-combat-overcrowding-japan-airlines-announces-luggage-delivery-to-hotels-in-tokyo-7229530]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Airlines Combats Overcrowding With Same-Day Luggage Delivery Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/to-combat-overcrowding-japan-airlines-announces-luggage-delivery-to-hotels-in-tokyo-7229530]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:37:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The airline promises to deliver the luggage the same day, excluding weather or traffic-related delays]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan Airlines has launched a same-day luggage delivery service that offers foreign tourists arriving at Haneda Airport's Terminal 3 an option to transport their bags straight to their hotels for a fee of 4,500 yen (about USD 29) per suitcase, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/jal-baggage-delivery-service-tokyo-haneda-intl-hnk/index.html" rel="nofollow noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a>. The airline promises to deliver the luggage the same day, excluding weather or traffic-related delays.</p>

<p>The new service, unveiled on December 5, intends to provide passengers with a more convenient and enjoyable arrival experience while reducing traffic on Tokyo's public transit networks.</p>

<p>“The ‘Baggage-Free' travel service from Haneda Airport aims to address social issues such as congestion in public transportation and the shortage of storage lockers, providing a more convenient travel experience for tourists,” the airline said.</p>

<p>In addition to foreign tourists, the service is also available to Japanese citizens as well as those who do not fly with JAL. However, you can use it only for hotel drop-offs and not for private residences, Airbnbs, rented apartments, or any other type of lodging. Travellers staying at hotels in 14 different districts -- Shinjuku, Shinagawa, Chiyoda, Chuo, Minato, Koto, Ota, Shibuya, Taito, Toshima, Bunkyo, Sumida, Meguro and Edogawa -- can avail same-day delivery service.</p>

<p>When JAL passengers use this amenity, their accounts will be credited with 50 frequent flyer points. The service is offered daily from 4 am to 6 pm in the Terminal 3 arrivals hall at Haneda Airport.</p>

<h2><strong>How to avail of the service</strong></h2>

<p>To avail of the delivery assistance, passengers must reserve and pay in advance. The travellers can scan the 2D barcode on the poster in front of the JAL ABC counter. They must fill out the application, pick up a baggage sticker from a nearby machine, attach it to their luggage, and check in their bags at the desk.</p>

<p>Since Japan's reopening after the pandemic, overtourism has been a major problem in the country. According to the Japanese National Tourism Organisation, Japan hosted 3.2 million tourists in July, roughly 66% more than the same month in 2023. The Japanese government is expecting to surpass its target of 32 million visitors this year.</p>

<p>Authorities have been urging tourists to spread out and visit less-travelled areas of Japan. JAL also offered complimentary connecting flights to lesser-known Japanese destinations to customers flying in from North America.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/a90931is_japan-airlines-facebook_625x300_26_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-secret-plan-to-evacuate-bashar-al-assad-from-syria-revealed-7231400]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia's Secret Plan To Evacuate Bashar al-Assad From Syria Revealed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-secret-plan-to-evacuate-bashar-al-assad-from-syria-revealed-7231400]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:25:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Assad's departure marks a significant shift in Middle East power dynamics, weakening Iran and Russia's influence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ousted Syrian leader Bashar al-Assad is being hosted in Russia, and he had been transported there "in the most secure way possible" after the swift collapse of his regime, Russia's deputy foreign minister, Sergei Ryabkov, has said in an interview to <em>NBC News</em>. The Kremlin said on Monday that President Vladimir Putin had made the decision to grant asylum in Russia to Assad. His fall is a big blow to Iran and Russia, which had intervened in Syria's 13-year civil war to try to shore up his rule despite the West's demands that he leave power.</p>

<p>"He is secured, and it shows that Russia acts as required in such an extraordinary situation," Sergei Ryabkov told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/syria-bashar-assad-russia-rebels-ryabkov-sanctuary-rcna183594"><em>NBC News,</em></a> becoming the first Russian official to confirm Assad's presence in the country.</p>

<p>"I have no idea what is going on with him right now," Ryabkov said, adding that it "would be very wrong for me to elaborate on what happened and how it was resolved."</p>

<p>Asked whether Russia would hand over Assad for trial, Ryabkov said, "Russia is not a party to the convention that established the International Criminal Court."</p>

<p>He also advised Israel "to seriously consider what is going on in the Golan Heights" and "not to infringe" on Syrian territory.</p>

<p><strong>How Russia Planned A Safe Escape For Bashar al-Assad</strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2024-12-11/russia-pushed-assad-to-flee-syria?srnd=undefined"><em>Bloomberg, </em></a>Russia was unable to prop up the regime any longer but persuaded Assad that he would lose the fight against armed groups led by the former al-Qaeda offshoot HTS and offered him and his family safe passage if he left immediately. Russian intelligence agents organised the escape, flying Assad out via its air base in Syria. Within hours of his departure, the militants swept unopposed into Damascus, ending the Assad family's dynasty of more than half a century.</p>

<p>Assad's departure removes a bastion from which Iran and Russia wielded power across the Middle East. Assad's father, Hafez al-Assad, sided with the Soviet Union to try to achieve parity with U.S.-backed Israel.</p>

<p>The Kremlin said Syria was subject to "extreme instability," and it was too early to speak about the future of Russian bases in the country.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ossoeipo_russian-president-vladimir-putin-and-syrian-president-bashar-alassad_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bashar al-Assad was granted asylum in Russia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-man-swims-across-river-to-enter-india-caught-by-border-forces-7231327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Man Swims Across River To Enter India, Caught By Border Forces]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-man-swims-across-river-to-enter-india-caught-by-border-forces-7231327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:14:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Another Bangladeshi national attempted to flee to India by swimming across a river, a day after a Hindu girl crossed over to the Indian side.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another Bangladeshi national attempted to flee to India by swimming across a river, a day after a seventeen-year-old Hindu girl crossed over to the Indian side.</p>

<p>The student, identified as 21-year-old Jiban Barman, was caught by the Border Security Force after he fled Bangladesh following alleged torture. He swam across the Korotwa river and reached West Bengal's Rajganj, where he was handed over to the police. He is a resident of Rangpur district and a student of Thakurgaon Government College.</p>

<p>His escape comes a day after a girl from Bangladesh ran through the night and crossed over to the Indian side, where she was detained and handed to the police. An ISKCON devotee, she said her family has been facing threats for being from the minority community for the past several weeks, but the situation got out of hand when fundamentalists in Bangladesh threatened to kidnap her and kill the rest of her family.</p>

<p>Incidents of communal violence are being widely reported across Bangladesh and people from the Hindu minority are being targeted. ISKCON devotees are the latest target since the arrest of Hindu priest Chinmoy Krishna Das in Dhaka on November 25. There have been incidents of mob violence and vandalism of property targeting the minority community.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kc8777c_bangladesh-protest_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Incidents of communal violence are being widely reported across Bangladesh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-justin-trudeau-over-his-jab-at-donald-trump-such-an-insufferable-tool-7231081]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Such An Insufferable Tool": Musk Slams Trudeau Over His Jab At Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-justin-trudeau-over-his-jab-at-donald-trump-such-an-insufferable-tool-7231081]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 14:40:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's reaction came after Justin Trudeau said Kamala Harris's loss in the US presidential election was a setback for women's progress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has yet again attacked Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, saying he is "such an insufferable tool", after the latter took an inapparent jibe at US President-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Speaking at an Ottawa gala for Equal Voice, an organization that works to get more women elected to public office, Trudeau on Tuesday said Kamala Harris's loss in the US presidential election was a setback for women's progress. He also cited various recent incidents that he said suggest women's rights are under attack by "regressive" and "reactionary" political forces.</p>

<p>"It wasn't supposed to be that way. We were supposed to be on a steady, if difficult sometimes, march towards progress. And yet, just a few weeks ago, the United States voted for a second time to not elect its first woman president," Trudeau said.</p>

<p>"Everywhere, women's rights and women's progress were under attack, overtly and subtly. And I want you to know that I am, and always will be a proud feminist," he said in remarks that came shortly after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/governor-justin-trudeau-of-state-of-canada-trump-jibe-follows-tariff-warning-7214544" target="_blank">Trump</a> called him the "governor" of a state, rather than the prime minister of the US neighbour.</p>

<p>His comments drew a sharp retort from one of Trump's closest allies, Musk, who spent at least $270 million to help the Republican win the US presidency.</p>

<p>"He's such an insufferable tool," Musk said in a response to a post on X. "Won't be in power for much longer."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">He's such an insufferable tool.<br />
<br />
Won't be in power for much longer.</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1866918806578401721?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This was not the first time that the billionaire has slammed Trudeau on the social media platform.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last month, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-replies-to-we-need-your-help-removing-trudeau-post-6970273" target="_blank">Musk said Trudeau "will be gone"</a> in the Canadian election, scheduled to take place next year.</p>

<p>"He will be gone in the upcoming election," he wrote on X while responding to a user's request to help Canada "get rid" of Trudeau.</p>

<p>Last year, when the Canadian government made it compulsory for online streaming services to formally register with the government for 'regulatory controls', &nbsp;the X owner called it "shameful" and charged that Trudeau was "trying to crush free speech" in Canada.</p>

<p>In 2022, when Trudeau invoked emergency powers for the first time in the country's history to arm his government with more power to respond to truckers protesting the COVID-19 vaccine mandates at that time, Musk compared him to Adolf Hitler. He later deleted the post.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/d82cc8fo_elon-musk-justin-trudeau_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is not the first time that Elon Musk has attacked Justin Trudeau]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-unveils-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-7231053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Unveils Latest AI Model, Gemini 2.0]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-unveils-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-7231053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 14:39:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google on Wednesday announced the launch of Gemini 2.0, its most advanced artificial intelligence model to date, as the world's tech giants race to take the lead in the fast developing technology.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google on Wednesday announced the launch of Gemini 2.0, its most advanced artificial intelligence model to date, as the world's tech giants race to take the lead in the fast developing technology.</p>

<p>CEO Sundar Pichai said the new model would mark what the company calls "a new agentic era" in AI development, with AI models designed to understand and make decisions about the world around you.</p>

<p>"Gemini 2.0 is about making information much more useful," Pichai said in the announcement, emphasizing the model's enhanced ability to understand context, think multiple steps ahead and take supervised actions on behalf of users.</p>

<p>The developments "bring us closer to our vision of a universal assistant," he added.</p>

<p>The release sent shares in Google soaring by more than four percent on Wall Street a day after the stock already gained 3.5 percent after the release of a breakthrough quantum chip.</p>

<p>The tech giants are furiously taking steps to release more powerful AI models despite their immense cost and some questions about their immediate usefulness to the broader economy.</p>

<p>An AI "agent," the latest Silicon Valley trend, is a digital helper that is supposed to sense surroundings, make decisions, and take actions to achieve specific goals.</p>

<p>The tech giants promise that agents will be the next stage of an AI revolution that was sparked by the 2022 launch of ChatGPT, which took the world by storm.</p>

<p>Gemini 2.0 is initially being rolled out to developers and trusted testers, with plans for broader integration across Google's products, particularly in Search and the Gemini platform.</p>

<p><strong>No Nvidia </strong></p>

<p>The technology is powered by Google's sixth-generation TPU (Tensor Processing Unit) hardware, dubbed Trillium, which the company has now made generally available to customers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Google emphasized that Trillium processors were used exclusively for both training and running Gemini 2.0.</p>

<p>Most AI training has been monopolized by chip juggernaut Nvidia, which has been catapulted by the AI explosion to become one of the world's most valuable companies.</p>

<p>Google said that millions of developers are already building applications with Gemini technology, which has been integrated into seven Google products, each serving more than two billion users.</p>

<p>Gemini 2.0's powers are expected to come in early 2025 to Google's search application, still the company's main money-maker.</p>

<p>The first release from the 2.0 family of models will be Flash, offering faster performance while handling multiple types of input (text, images, video, audio) and output (including generated images and speech).</p>

<p>Gemini users worldwide can already tap into a chat-only version of Flash, the company said, with testers given access to a multimodal version that can interpret images and surroundings.</p>

<p>Google also said it was experimenting with a product that can use software apps, websites and other online tools, much like a human user. OpenAI and Anthropic have unveiled similar features.</p>

<p>The company also teased a new version of Project Astra, a smartphone digital assistant like Apple's Siri that responds to images as well as verbal commands.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/spl928f_gemini_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gemini 2.0 is initially being rolled out to developers and trusted testers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unexplained-drone-sightings-in-us-alarm-residents-baffle-officers-7230935]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Unexplained Drone Sightings In US Alarm Residents, Baffle Officers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unexplained-drone-sightings-in-us-alarm-residents-baffle-officers-7230935]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 14:23:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rash of unexplained drone sightings in the skies above New Jersey has left locals rattled and sent US officials scrambling for answers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rash of unexplained drone sightings in the skies above New Jersey has left locals rattled and sent US officials scrambling for answers.</p>

<p>Breathless local news reports have amplified the anxious sky-gazing and wild speculation -- interspersing blurry, dark clips from social media with irate locals calling for action.</p>

<p>For weeks now, the distinctive blinking lights and whirling rotors of large unmanned aerial vehicles have been spotted across the state west of New York.</p>

<p>But military brass, elected representatives and investigators have been unable to explain the recurring UFO phenomenon.</p>

<p>Sam Lugo, 23, who works in the Club Studio gym in New Jersey's Bergen county, one of the corners of the state that has seen several drone sightings, called the reports "crazy".</p>

<p>"It's pretty concerning they were sighted... without explanation. It can be alarming," he said.</p>

<p>Officials including the governor have called on people not to be alarmed but have not yet offered an explanation for the aerial activity.</p>

<p>"I've seen them every night since Thanksgiving, they're smaller than my Jeep," wrote X user Gus Seretis.</p>

<p>"They hover just about tree height or a little higher," he added, describing them as like aircraft too small for a pilot and vowing to "shoot at one if it comes low enough".</p>

<p>New Jersey congressman Chris Smith wrote to the Pentagon on Tuesday demanding answers.</p>

<p>"There have been numerous instances of unmanned aerial systems flying over New Jersey, including in close proximity to sensitive sites and critical infrastructure, to include military installations located in my district," he wrote to Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin.</p>

<p><strong>'Get abducted'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Smith said he had been told that more than a dozen drones pursued a coastguard lifeboat over the weekend.</p>

<p>The lawmaker then spent "hours" monitoring the night sky with the sheriff of Ocean County, the location of a number of sightings, according to his office.</p>

<p>The Pentagon, the nerve center of the US military, insists the objects are not "US military drones".</p>

<p>"Our initial assessment is that this is not the work of a foreign adversary or a foreign entity," said deputy Pentagon press secretary Sabrina Singh.</p>

<p>Singh also rejected claims by Republican lawmaker Jeff Van Drew on Fox News that Washington's foe Tehran was behind the spate of sightings.</p>

<p>"There is no Iranian ship off the coast of the United States, and there's no so-called mothership launching drones towards the United States," she said.</p>

<p>New Jersey native Joseph Boutros, 21, said he had seen the reports of drone activity on social media. "But I've not seen them myself," he said.</p>

<p>"It's not something that worries me as long as they aren't carrying weapons," said the suited local as he collected takeout from a Bergen county strip mall as night fell.</p>

<p>In the cloudy skies above, the only aerial vehicles with flashing lights were passenger jets on approach to New Jersey's Newark airport.</p>

<p>The FBI told AFP it was aware of the sightings "in multiple locations over the past several weeks" and said it was working with other agencies on the issue.</p>

<p>But the agency would not confirm reports of a crisis meeting between various government departments over the mounting concern.</p>

<p>Drones are permitted for both business applications and recreational use but are regulated by Federal Aviation Administration rules.</p>

<p>Witnesses stress that the unexplained aerial objects are larger than those commonly used by drone enthusiasts.</p>

<p>"I don't want to get abducted or anything like that," said Lugo with a smile.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jeajifj8_drone-sightings-in-us-twitter_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Pentagon, the nerve center of the US military, insists the objects are not "US military drones".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-puberty-blockers-and-why-has-united-kingdom-banned-them-for-minors-7230661]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Are Puberty Blockers And Why UK Banned Them For Minors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-puberty-blockers-and-why-has-united-kingdom-banned-them-for-minors-7230661]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:42:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Kingdom has announced an indefinite ban on the use of puberty blockers for people under 18 with gender dysphoria, except in clinical trials]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Kingdom has announced an indefinite <a href="https://healthmedia.blog.gov.uk/2024/12/11/puberty-blockers-what-you-need-to-know/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">ban on the use of puberty blockers</a> for people under 18 with gender dysphoria, except in clinical trials. The decision, made public on Wednesday, formalises temporary restrictions imposed earlier this year.<br />
<br />
Health Secretary Wes Streeting explained the decision came after advice from medical experts, concerned about the safety risks of prescribing puberty blockers without further research. "We need to act with caution and care when it comes to this vulnerable group of young people," Mr Streeting said in a <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/ban-on-puberty-blockers-to-be-made-indefinite-on-experts-advice " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">statement</a>.<br />
<br />
Young people, who were already receiving puberty blockers before the ban was introduced, will be allowed to continue their treatment. However, no new prescriptions will be issued outside the clinical trial setting.<br />
<br />
<strong>What are puberty blockers?</strong></p>

<p>Puberty blockers are medications designed to delay the onset of puberty. They have been used in the past for children experiencing gender dysphoria - a condition where a person's gender identity is different from the sex they were assigned at birth. The drugs are meant to give young people more time to explore their gender identity before undergoing physical changes.<br />
<br />
<strong>Why the ban?</strong><br />
<br />
The decision comes after a series of reviews and expert consultations. A landmark report by Dr Hilary Cass, published earlier this year, showed a lack of solid evidence supporting the safety and effectiveness of puberty blockers for children. The report suggested that many young people were being prescribed these medications with minimal consultation, such as completing an online form or having just one brief online consultation.</p>

<p>Health Secretary Streeting, referring to the situation as a "scandal", said that vulnerable children were being given treatments without sufficient proof of their safety or effectiveness. He also said the government would prioritise evidence-based healthcare moving forward.</p>

<p>Despite the indefinite ban, the government is going ahead with plans for a clinical trial to study the effects of puberty blockers. The trial will begin next year, with the goal of gathering more conclusive data on their use. The ban will be reviewed in 2027, taking into account any new evidence that may emerge from ongoing research.<br />
<br />
<strong>Reactions to the ban</strong></p>

<p>Supporters of the ban such as the campaign group 'Sex Matters' praised Streeting for his "integrity" in replacing the temporary ban with a permanent one. They argued it was a necessary step to protect children from treatments that lacked sufficient evidence of safety.</p>

<p>Critics, including the 'TransActual advocacy group', have condemned the move as discriminatory. They argue the ban could harm transgender minors by denying them access to potentially life-changing medical treatment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qsbifhto_puberty-blockers-_625x300_12_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Puberty Blockers have been used in the past for children experiencing gender dysphoria (Getty)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/a-power-vacuum-in-syria-is-a-threat-for-everyone-7230613]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: A Power Vacuum In Syria Is A Threat For Everyone]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/a-power-vacuum-in-syria-is-a-threat-for-everyone-7230613]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:39:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The spectre of another monstrosity like ISIS rising again in Syria may not be too far-fetched.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/0adbvo4_damascus-afp_625x300_12_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The cataclysmic events in Syria have taken the world, at least much of it, by surprise. Their full magnitude and ramifications will be understood only with time. How did proud, progressive Syria come to such a pass? The only parallel is Afghanistan, where a militant group simply strolled into Kabul and took over the country as President Ashraf Ghani fled. In Syria, rebel groups backed by Turkey, many of which had ties with Al Qaeda and other militant groups earlier, after mounting a lightning offensive from northwestern Syria, similarly walked into Damascus, where, without any fight, President Bashar Al Assad's regime gave in. Predictably, the President fled the country with his family. Syrian Prime Minister Mohammad Al Jalali announced that he had agreed to hand over power to the rebel "Salvation Government ". Main rebel commander Abu Mohammad Al Jolani met the prime minister to coordinate the transfer of power that "guarantees the provision of services".</p>

<p>The comparison with Afghanistan is both inevitable and disappointing. Syrian society was qualitatively different. The country had achieved 100% literacy; women enjoyed equal rights with men; its many minorities and the Al Assad dynasty, ruling Syria for more than five decades and being members of Syria's largest minority group, the Allawites, had kept the country secular. Syria had been at the forefront of pan-Arabism even though it was closely allied with Iran. Till the beginning of the Syrian civil war in 2011, it had been a strong champion of the Palestinian cause, had hosted Hamas and refused to make peace with Israel till the return of the Golan Heights occupied by Israel since the 1967 war. Finally, Syria had, even at enormous human cost, been a bulwark against Sunni radicalism.</p>

<h2><strong>What Went Wrong? A Myriad Explanations</strong></h2>

<p>We may never know what really happened since November 27, when rebel groups, spearheaded by the Hayat Tahrir Al Sham (HTS), mounted an offensive from Idlib, which they had been occupying since the beginning of the fratricidal war that has claimed millions of lives. Within two weeks, they were able to sail into Damascus and take over. The world has been taken by surprise because, thanks to military and economic support rendered by Russia, Iran, and Iran-backed Hezbollah, the Assad regime had once been able to reclaim over 70% of Syrian territory from the various terror organisations that occupied parts of the country. This included ISIS too.</p>

<p>Narratives abound: that Western sanctions had ruined the Syrian economy, that long years of the war, together with a lack of reforms, had rendered the Syrian army weak, tired, and without the morale to fight its co-religionists (a majority of Syrians are Sunni Muslims and the rebel groups fighting the Assad regime were almost all Sunni). Assad himself had failed to consolidate the military gains and translate them into political and social ones. Russia, Syria's main military support, was too stretched with the Ukraine conflict to intervene, while Iran had been weakened by Israel. Hezbollah was in disarray too after its war with Israel.</p>

<h2><strong>Were Iran's Warnings Ignored?</strong></h2>

<p>Russia itself has announced that Assad held talks with the rebels and decided to leave the country without consulting it. The clearest message has come from Iran. According to Iran's FARS News Agency, in June this year, Iran's Supreme Leader Syed Ali Khameini had warned Assad—that was their last meeting—that rebel factions were regrouping and planning an offensive in Syria. Such warnings and preemptive measures were, however, ignored. High-ranking Iranian officials were holding discussions with Assad even hours before he was overthrown. But Assad placed greater trust in his Arab partners, with whom he had had a reconciliation recently. This made Iran decide not to intervene further in Syria. In any case, the "Shia Crescent" created by Iran—stretching through Iraq, Syria and Lebanon—had almost collapsed by then.</p>

<p>Indeed, the last few years did see a rapprochement between Assad and Sunni powers such as Egypt, Saudi Arabia, and the UAE, all of whom had initially backed various rebel factions in the Syrian civil war. A variety of geopolitical factors—not least of which was an indifferent United States—and attacks on territory from both the Sunni radical ISIS and Iran-backed Shiite Houthis in Yemen had caused a rethink, leading to their embrace of Assad. After its ouster in 2011, Syria was reinstated into the Arab League last year; a jubilant Assad also visited Saudi Arabia, where he was given a warm welcome. The only major Sunni power to refuse the recognition of Assad-ruled Syria was Qatar, which had financed many of the Syrian rebel groups.</p>

<p>So, what happens now?</p>

<h2><strong>Making Of Another Afghanistan?</strong></h2>

<p>The HTS, which has taken control of Damascus now, was until some years ago an Al Qaeda affiliate that wanted to establish a caliphate and had engaged in brutal acts of violence. Al Jolani himself had been an Al Qaeda member who spent time in US custody and had a $10 million bounty on his head. In 2016, he announced that HTS had broken ties with Al Qaeda. While some sections in the media are positioning him and the HTS as having mutated into a more moderate rebel faction, it remains to be seen whether this change is genuine or just a tactical move. As in the case of the Taliban, for instance, while its stance regarding its external relations has changed, its attitude towards women and minorities has not.</p>

<p>In any case, any political transition usually faces teething troubles. What is important for the international community is to see that no power vacuum exists for long. For now, Assad's main allies, Russia and Iran, have had to retreat from Syria, though both have said that they are in touch with the rebel leaders. The Joe Biden administration has been bombing ISIS strongholds and monitoring Syrian weapons depots, while President-elect Donald Trump has announced that this is not America's war.</p>

<h2><strong>Advantage Turkey?</strong></h2>

<p>Israel and Turkey clearly have the upper hand. Israel has pushed into and occupied part of the demilitarised buffer zone on the Syrian side of the Golan Heights to prevent the spillover of any chaos into its own territory. The Israeli Air Force and Navy have struck missile depots, naval vessels, fighter jets and more to ensure they don't fall into the wrong hands. In a statement on Tuesday, the Israeli Defence Forces said that its Air Force and Navy had carried out over 350 strikes against “strategic targets” in Syria, taking out “most of the strategic weapons stockpiles” in an effort to prevent advanced weaponry from falling into the hands of hostile elements.</p>

<p>Turkey, on the other hand, has long been aiding the Syrian rebels; most of the foreign fighters who crossed over into Syria to join the rebels, including ISIS, have gone through the Turkish-Syrian border. It is also widely believed that the current rebel offensive would not have been possible without tacit Turkish approval. In the northwestern regions of Syria, which have been held by the rebels since the civil war began in 2012, both the Syrian revolutionary flag and the Turkish flags fly.</p>

<p>Even though Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has condemned Israel for pushing into Syrian territory and spoken out against any attempts to divide Syria, it is quite possible that Turkey itself may move deeper into Syria, even if by pushing for a bigger buffer zone between its borders and Syria. Turkey may also use some of these groups as leverage to achieve its strategic objectives in the region.</p>

<h2><strong>A Kurdish Uprising May Not Be Out Of Question</strong></h2>

<p>There is yet another possibility of an enclave in northeastern Syria being carved out for the Kurdish minority. The Syrian Kurds have been at the forefront of the battle against ISIS but also allege widespread oppression by the Assad regime. The emergence of an independent Kurdish enclave would be of strategic value to Israel as well as to the Sunni Arab states. Israel has always maintained good connections with the Kurds, a significant minority community found in countries across the region—Iran, Iraq, Syria, and Turkey. Interestingly, soon after the new Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz took charge, he made a mention of the Kurds and his support for them in his address. However, an independent Kurdish enclave would vehemently be opposed by Turkey, which has long been waging an internal battle against Kurdish insurgency. It would also be opposed by Iran.</p>

<h2><strong>Will Syria Become A Terrorist Hub?</strong></h2>

<p>The other security nightmare is that the vacuum, together with the almost defunct Syrian army, may once again draw terrorist groups to set up bases in Syria. The spectre of another monstrosity like ISIS rising again in Syria may not be too far-fetched.</p>

<p>The only hope in this quagmire can be derived from the Syrian people—the many qualified, resilient women and men who have paid a great price and made many sacrifices for their motherland over the years. They are the only ones who can ensure that Syria does not turn into another Afghanistan.</p>

<p><em>(Aditi Bhaduri is a journalist and political analyst)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/0adbvo4_damascus-afp_625x300_12_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-are-alexander-brothers-real-estate-tycoons-accused-of-sexual-assault-7229932]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Are Alexander Brothers, Real Estate Tycoons Accused Of Sexual Assault]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-are-alexander-brothers-real-estate-tycoons-accused-of-sexual-assault-7229932]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:24:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three brothers from the high-profile Alexander family, known for their influence in luxury real estate, have been arrested in Miami, US, on charges of sexual assault and rape.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three brothers from the high-profile Alexander family, known for their influence in luxury real estate, have been arrested in Miami, US, on charges of sexual assault and rape. Twin brothers Oren and Alon Alexander, aged 37, and their elder sibling Tal Alexander, 38, are accused of luring, drugging and assaulting numerous women over more than a decade.<br />
<br />
Federal prosecutors in New York allege the brothers used their wealth and social standing to exploit women from 2010 to 2021. According to the indictment, they employed “deception, fraud and coercion” to entice victims to social events, often under the pretence of romantic interest.<br />
<br />
<strong>Who are the Alexander brothers?</strong><br />
<br />
Oren and Alon Alexander have long been prominent figures in the high-society circuit, frequently seen at glamorous events in Miami, New York and lavish parties across the Mediterranean. Oren and Tal Alexander manage the Alexander Team, a real estate group that claims to have facilitated sales exceeding $7 billion (around Rs 58,000 crore) in luxury markets such as New York, South Florida and Aspen, Colorado.<br />
<br />
The duo has facilitated sales for clients such as Kim Kardashian, Kanye West, Tommy Hilfiger, billionaire Ken Griffin and ‘Hamilton' producer Sander Jacobs, according to the Los Angeles Times.<br />
<br />
Tal and Oren were prominent brokers at Douglas Elliman before launching their venture several years ago, according to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/maryroeloffs/2024/12/11/alexander-brothers-real-estate-agents-for-ultrarich-arrested-on-sex-trafficking-charges/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Forbes</a>. Their portfolio includes facilitating the sale of a condo in Miami Beach to Kim Kardashian and Kanye West in 2018 for $15.5 million (around Rs 129 crore). They also managed the sale of a mansion in London for $122 million (around Rs 1,012.6 crore).<br />
<br />
In 2016, they represented billionaire Leon Black in listing his Miami condo for $18.5 million (around Rs 1,536 crore). Apart from this, in 2019, Tal and Oren sold a $238 million (around Rs 19,800 crore) New York City penthouse to Griffin, marking the most expensive residential sale in US history.<br />
<br />
Known for their extravagant lifestyles, a Details magazine feature in 2013 described them as earning “rock-star salaries” and rubbing shoulders with the ultra-wealthy.<br />
<iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="339" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FDouglasElliman%2Fphotos%2Fa.555623937831383%2F555624101164700%2F%3Ftype%3D3&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe><br />
The Forbes report said Alon holds an executive role at the family-owned security company, Kent Security.<br />
<br />
Tal and Oren Alexander embarked on their real estate journey in New York City in 2008. The brothers cultivated a network of ultra-wealthy clients. Their now-private social media accounts once showcased their attendance at high-profile events and luxury vacations.<br />
<br />
Oren Alexander was on the prestigious Forbes 30 Under 30 real estate list in 2012.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/stnptgkg_oren-and-tal-alexander-getty_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Oren and Alon Alexander have long been prominent figures in the high-society circuit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/jwst-uncovers-baby-milky-way-galaxy-actively-shaping-the-early-universe-7230487]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[James Webb Uncovers 'Baby Milky Way' Galaxy Actively Shaping Early Universe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/jwst-uncovers-baby-milky-way-galaxy-actively-shaping-the-early-universe-7230487]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:19:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This galaxy, which is stretched and magnified, glitters with 10 distinct star clusters that formed at different times.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the first time, NASA's James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) has successfully detected and measured a galaxy that existed just 600 million years after the Big Bang, offering a striking glimpse into the early Universe. This discovery is particularly significant as the galaxy's mass closely resembles what the Milky Way's mass might have been during the same stage of its formation.</p>

<p>This galaxy, which is named the "Firefly Sparkle," is unique from the other galaxies observed by JWST at this point because it is lighter. The galaxy shines with star clusters, and researchers carefully studied 10 of these clusters to learn about its development.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDcc0gCz4ba/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDcc0gCz4ba/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDcc0gCz4ba/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDcc0gCz4ba/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by NASA Webb Telescope (@nasawebb)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>"I didn't think it would be possible to resolve a galaxy that existed so early in the universe into so many distinct components, let alone find that its mass is similar to our own galaxy's when it was in the process of forming," said Lamiya Mowla, co-lead author of the paper and an assistant professor at Wellesley College in Massachusetts. "There is so much going on inside this tiny galaxy, including so many different phases of star formation."</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://science.nasa.gov/missions/webb/found-first-actively-forming-galaxy-as-lightweight-as-young-milky-way/"><em>NASA, </em></a>Webb was able to image the galaxy in crisp detail for two reasons. One is a benefit of the cosmos: A massive foreground galaxy cluster radically enhanced the distant galaxy's appearance through a natural effect known as gravitational lensing. And when combined with the telescope's specialisation in high-resolution infrared light, Webb delivered unprecedented new data about the galaxy's contents.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/eq5u54rg_nasas-jwst_625x300_12_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Astronomers using NASA's JWST have identified a galaxy, nicknamed Firefly Sparkle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-virus-samples-missing-from-australia-lab-biosecurity-breach-sparks-probe-7229782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deadly Virus Vials Go Missing From Australia Lab, Authorities Launch Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-virus-samples-missing-from-australia-lab-biosecurity-breach-sparks-probe-7229782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:19:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities in Queensland, Australia, have confirmed a "major historical breach of biosecurity protocols" after hundreds of virus samples went missing from a public health laboratory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in Queensland, Australia, have confirmed a “major historical breach of biosecurity protocols” after hundreds of virus samples went missing from a public health laboratory. Queensland Health has been directed to launch an investigation into the incident, which is described as an unacceptable lapse in safety measures.<br />
<br />
According to an official statement by the Queensland government on Monday, 323 vials containing dangerous viruses, including Hendra virus, Lyssavirus and Hantavirus, went missing from the Queensland Public Health Virology Laboratory in August 2023.<br />
<br />
The Hendra virus, only found in Australia, is a zoonotic virus that can be transmitted from animals to humans. Lyssavirus is a family of viruses that includes rabies, which can be fatal without proper medical intervention. Similarly, Hantavirus can cause serious illness and death, as noted by the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).<br />
<br />
The laboratory where the breach occurred is responsible for providing diagnostic services, research, and surveillance for various pathogens, including viruses carried by mosquitoes and ticks. But it remains unclear whether the missing samples were stolen, destroyed or just lost. The government statement assures the public that there is “no evidence of risk to the community” at this time.<br />
<br />
In response to the breach, Queensland Health has launched an investigation to determine the circumstances surrounding the incident and prevent similar occurrences in the future. Timothy Nicholls, the Minister for Queensland Health, said in a statement, “With such a serious breach of biosecurity protocols and infectious virus samples potentially missing, Queensland Health must investigate what occurred and how to prevent it from happening again.” Nicholls added that the investigation would also examine the laboratory's current policies, procedures and staff conduct.<br />
<br />
Experts have expressed concern about the gravity of the situation. According to <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/health/deadly-virus-samples-went-missing-lab-major-biosecurity-breach-say-authorities" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Fox News Digital</a>, Sam Scarpino, director of AI and life sciences at Northeastern University, US, called the incident a “critical biosecurity lapse,” adding, “The pathogens reported missing are all high-consequence and could pose a threat to the public.”<br />
<br />
Scarpino pointed out that some strains of Hantavirus have case fatality rates of up to 15 per cent, far higher than the fatality rate of COVID-19.<br />
<br />
Despite the severity of these pathogens, Queensland's Chief Health Officer, Dr John Gerrard, reassured the public through a media statement that there is no evidence of a risk to public health, saying that the virus samples would “degrade very rapidly outside a low-temperature freezer and become non-infectious.”<br />
<br />
Dr. Gerrard also highlighted that Queensland has not had any reported human cases of Hendra or Lyssavirus in the last five years, and no confirmed Hantavirus infections have ever been recorded in Australia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/fjub5egg_research-generic_625x300_01_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia is investigating a major biosecurity breach after deadly virus samples went missing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>