<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 22:24:46 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-40-killed-230-injured-after-heavy-rainfall-in-eastern-afghanistan-6112997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nearly 40 Killed, 230 Injured After Heavy Rainfall In Eastern Afghanistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-40-killed-230-injured-after-heavy-rainfall-in-eastern-afghanistan-6112997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 22:19:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 35 people were killed and 230 injured on Monday after heavy rain in eastern Afghanistan, a local official said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 35 people were killed and 230 injured on Monday after heavy rain in eastern Afghanistan, a local official said.</p>

<p>"On Monday evening, rain caused by thunderstorms killed 35 people and injured 230 others in Jalalabad and certain districts of Nangarhar" province, Quraishi Badloon, head of the department of information and culture, told AFP.</p>

<p>The casualties were caused by heavy storms and rains that collapsed trees, walls and roofs of people's houses, Badloon said.</p>

<p>"There is a possibility that casualties might rise," he went on, adding that the wounded as well as victims' corpses were brought to Nangarhar regional hospital and Fatima-tul-Zahra hospital.</p>

<p>The tragedy comes after flash floods killed hundreds of people in Afghanistan in May and swamped agricultural lands in the country, where 80 percent of the population depends on farming to survive.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/e8u6c0u_afghanistan-floods_625x300_18_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tragedy comes after flash floods killed hundreds of people in Afghanistan in May (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/serum-institute-of-indias-new-high-efficacy-malaria-vaccine-rolls-out-in-africa-6112995]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Serum Institute's New "High Efficacy" Malaria Vaccine Rolls Out In Africa]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/serum-institute-of-indias-new-high-efficacy-malaria-vaccine-rolls-out-in-africa-6112995]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 22:17:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new "high efficacy" malaria vaccine co-developed by the Serum Institute of India (SII) and the University of Oxford was officially rolled out on Monday when Cote d'Ivoire in West Africa became the first country to begin administering R21/Matrix-M.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new "high efficacy" malaria vaccine co-developed by the Serum Institute of India (SII) and the University of Oxford was officially rolled out on Monday when Cote d'Ivoire in West Africa became the first country to begin administering R21/Matrix-M.</p>

<p>The vaccine, which was granted World Health Organisation (WHO) approval last year, is said to have undergone a rigorous regulatory process and clinical assessment and was found to be highly effective and affordable. As a low-dose vaccine, it can be manufactured at speed and scale which is seen as critical to stemming the spread of the mosquito-borne disease.</p>

<p>"Reducing the malaria burden is finally within sight. Today's start of the R21/Matrix-M vaccine roll-out marks a monumental milestone after years of incredible work with our partners at Oxford and Novavax," said SII CEO Adar Poonawalla.</p>

<p>"At Serum, we believe that it is every person's right to have access to affordable and essential disease prevention. That's why we have committed to producing 100 million doses of R21, which will protect millions of lives and alleviate the burden of this deadly disease for future generations," he said.</p>

<p>In anticipation of the roll-out, SII said it has manufactured 25 million doses of the vaccine and is committed to scaling up to 100 million doses annually. In keeping with its aim of delivering vaccines at scale and low cost, the Pune-headquartered company said it is offering the vaccine at less than USD 4 per dose.</p>

<p>"The roll-out of the R21/Matrix-M malaria vaccine marks the start of a new era in malaria control interventions with the high efficacy vaccine now accessible at a modest price and very large scale to many countries in greatest need. We hope that this vaccine very soon can be provided to all African countries who wish to use it," said Professor Adrian Hill, Director of the Jenner Institute at Oxford University.</p>

<p>R21/Matrix-M was co-developed by the university and SII leveraging Novavax's Matrix-M adjuvant technology. In December 2023, WHO granted it prequalification status after trials demonstrated that the vaccine was well tolerated, with a good safety profile, with injection site pain and fever as the most frequent adverse events.</p>

<p>Although the number of malaria-related deaths has fallen from 3,222 in 2017 to 1,316 in 2020 in Cote d'Ivoire, the deadly disease still kills four people a day, mostly small children, and "remains the leading cause of medical consultations", according to the country's Ministry of Health.</p>

<p>A total of 656,600 doses have been received, which will initially vaccinate 250,000 children aged between 0 and 23 months across 16 regions of Cote d'Ivoire. The R21/Matrix-M vaccine has also been authorised by Ghana, Nigeria, Burkina Faso and the Central African Republic.</p>

<p>R21 is the second malaria vaccine available in Sub-Saharan Africa following RTS,S and wide implementation of the malaria vaccines, in conjunction with existing prevention methods like bed nets, is expected to save tens of thousands of young lives each year. In total, 15 African countries are expected to introduce malaria vaccines with Gavi support in 2024, and countries plan to reach around 6.6 million children with the malaria vaccine in 2024 and 2025.</p>

<p>Dr Sania Nishtar, Chief Executive Officer of Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, said: "Africa has borne the brunt of malaria for far too long, and Cote d'Ivoire has suffered more than most. With two safe and effective vaccines now available alongside other interventions, we can finally turn the tide against this killer disease." John Jacobs, President and Chief Executive Officer, Novavax, added: "The introduction of the R21/Matrix-M malaria vaccine in Cote d'Ivoire marks a breakthrough in the fight to protect vulnerable children against a leading cause of death across the region while reinforcing our mission to create innovative vaccines that improve public health."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-07/op395kok_vaccine-generic_625x300_14_July_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[R21 is the second malaria vaccine available in Sub-Saharan Africa following RTS,S]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-vows-to-cooperate-with-independent-review-after-trump-rally-shooting-6112932]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Secret Service Vows To Cooperate With Review After Trump Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-vows-to-cooperate-with-independent-review-after-trump-rally-shooting-6112932]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 22:02:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Under growing pressure for a massive security failure, the US Secret Service on Monday vowed to cooperate with an independent review after a shooter was allowed to open fire on Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Under growing pressure for a massive security failure, the US Secret Service on Monday vowed to cooperate with an independent review after a shooter was allowed to open fire on Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old former president was injured but survived an assassination attempt at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania Saturday, a brazen attack that shocked a nation already deeply polarized ahead of the November vote.</p>

<p>"The Secret Service is working with all involved Federal, state and local agencies to understand what happened, how it happened, and how we can prevent an incident like this from ever taking place again," the agency's director Kimberly Cheatle said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We understand the importance of the independent review announced by President Biden yesterday and will participate fully. We will also work with the appropriate Congressional committees on any oversight action," Cheatle added.</p>

<p>Trump was speaking at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania when multiple bangs rang out. He clutched his ear, with blood visible on his ear and cheek, then ducked to the floor as Secret Service agents swarmed onto the podium, surrounding him and rushing him to a nearby vehicle.</p>

<p>The shooter and a bystander were killed, and two spectators injured.</p>

<p>Biden ordered a full review of security at the rally, as well as at this week's Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, where Trump will be crowned the party's presidential nominee.</p>

<p>The Secret Service has been under growing pressure over how a gunman aiming an assault rifle was allowed to take position on a roof some 500 feet (150 meters) from one of the most protected political figures on the planet.</p>

<p>And the questions grew louder when phone footage emerged of people sighting the gunman on the roof and trying to warn security before he opened fire.</p>

<p>With Trump set to appear at the convention Monday, Cheatle said the agency was working to toughen security at the event.</p>

<p>The Secret Service "designs operational security plans for National Special Security Events (NSSE) to be dynamic in order to respond to a kinetic security environment and the most up-to-date intelligence from our partners," her statement said.</p>

<p>On Sunday the Secret Service said it was "fully prepared" for the convention.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We understand the importance of the independent review," says Kimberly Cheatle (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/romania-approves-culling-of-nearly-500-bears-after-deadly-hiker-attack-6112844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Romania Approves Culling Of Nearly 500 Bears After Deadly Hiker Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/romania-approves-culling-of-nearly-500-bears-after-deadly-hiker-attack-6112844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 21:50:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Romania's parliament on Monday approved the culling of almost 500 bears this year in a bid to control the protected species' "overpopulation" after a deadly hiker attack sparked nationwide outcry.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Romania's parliament on Monday approved the culling of almost 500 bears this year in a bid to control the protected species' "overpopulation" after a deadly hiker attack sparked nationwide outcry.</p>

<p>Romania is home to Europe's largest brown bear population outside of Russia with 8,000, according to the environment ministry.</p>

<p>Bears have killed 26 people and severely injured 274 others over the last 20 years in the southeastern European country, the ministry said earlier this year.</p>

<p>After a young hiker was mauled to death on a popular trail in Romania's Carpathian Mountains, Prime Minister Marcel Ciolacu summoned lawmakers back from their summer recess to attend an emergency session of parliament.</p>

<p>As well as adopting legislation to control the brown bear population, the parliament held a moment of silence in the 19-year-old hiker's memory.</p>

<p>The law adopted Monday authorises the culling of 481 bears in 2024, more than twice last year's total of 220.</p>

<p>Lawmakers argued that the bears' "overpopulation" had led to an increase in attacks, while admitting that the law will not prevent attacks in the future.</p>

<p>But environmental groups have denounced the measure.</p>

<p>"The law solves absolutely nothing," World Wildlife Fund biologist Calin Ardelean told AFP, arguing that the focus should be shifted towards "prevention and intervention" as well as so-called "problem bears".</p>

<p>According to WWF Romania, culls will not remedy the problem unless measures are put in place to keep bears away from communities, such as better waste management or preventing people from feeding animals.</p>

<p>In 2023, about 7,500 emergency calls to signal bear sightings were recorded, more than double the previous year, according to data presented last week by Romanian authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/lapk18ug_bear-generic_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Romania is home to Europe's largest brown bear population outside of Russia. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-classified-documents-case-dismissed-by-florida-judge-6112050]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's Classified Documents Case Dismissed By Florida Judge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-classified-documents-case-dismissed-by-florida-judge-6112050]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:53:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida judge appointed by Donald Trump has dismissed the criminal case against the former president on charges of mishandling top secret documents, saying the way that Special Counsel Jack Smith was appointed was improper.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida judge appointed by Donald Trump has dismissed the criminal case against the former president on charges of mishandling top secret documents, saying the way that Special Counsel Jack Smith was appointed was improper.</p>

<p>The decision is a huge victory for Trump, who had been accused of endangering national security by holding onto top secret documents after leaving the White House.</p>

<p>Judge Aileen Cannon made her ruling after lawyers for the 78-year-old argued for a partial stay of proceedings to allow for an assessment of a Supreme Court ruling that a former president has broad immunity from prosecution.</p>

<p>"Former President Trump's Motion to Dismiss Indictment Based on the Unlawful Appointment and Funding of Special Counsel Jack Smith is GRANTED," Aileen wrote in her order.</p>

<p>"The Superseding Indictment is DISMISSED because Special Counsel Smith's appointment violates the Appointments Clause of the United States Constitution."</p>

<p>It comes as Trump is set to be anointed as his party's champion at the Republican National Convention, days after surviving an assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>In the Florida case, Trump was facing 31 counts of "willful retention of national defense information," each punishable by up to 10 years in prison.</p>

<p>He also faced charges of conspiracy to obstruct justice and making false statements.</p>

<p>Trump allegedly kept classified documents -- which included records from the Pentagon and CIA -- unsecured at his Mar-a-Lago home and thwarted efforts to retrieve them.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/gv9q64r8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_03_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The decision is a huge victory for Donald Trump. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-should-attend-second-ukraine-summit-says-zelensky-amid-raging-war-6111556]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Should Attend Second Ukraine Summit, Says Zelensky Amid Raging War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-should-attend-second-ukraine-summit-says-zelensky-amid-raging-war-6111556]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:41:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Monday that Russia should be represented at a second summit aiming to secure lasting peace with the Kremlin, after more than two years of war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Monday that Russia should be represented at a second summit aiming to secure lasting peace with the Kremlin, after more than two years of war.</p>

<p>Dozens of world leaders voiced support for a just peace in Ukraine after a high-level summit convened by Zelensky last month in Switzerland, to which Russia was not invited.</p>

<p>"I believe that Russian representatives should be at the second summit," Zelensky told a press conference in Kyiv, where he laid out preparatory work for a follow-up summit.</p>

<p>Zelensky announced separate meetings on key issues, including energy security, to be held in Qatar and on food security in Turkey ahead of a second summit.</p>

<p>Leaders and top officials from more than 90 states gathered at a Swiss mountainside resort on June 15 for the two-day summit dedicated to resolving the largest European conflict since World War II.</p>

<p>The Kremlin said that any discussions around ending the conflict that did not include Russia were "absurd."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/854h8fjo_zelensky-afp_625x300_18_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Russian representatives should be at the second summit," Zelensky told a press conference (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pakistan-foreign-minister-shah-mahmood-qureshi-indicted-in-may-9-violence-case-6111525]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Pakistan Foreign Minister Indicted In May 9 Violence Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pakistan-foreign-minister-shah-mahmood-qureshi-indicted-in-may-9-violence-case-6111525]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:40:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An anti-terrorism court here on Monday charged top Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf leader and former foreign minister Shah Mahmood Qureshi in a case involving the burning down of a police station during the May 9 violence last year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An anti-terrorism court here on Monday charged top Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf leader and former foreign minister Shah Mahmood Qureshi in a case involving the burning down of a police station during the May 9 violence last year.</p>

<p>Mr Qureshi, 68, who was brought to Kot Lakhpat jail here from Adiala jail in Rawalpindi under tight security, has several cases related to May 9 violence, including arson, filed against him at the Shadman police station.</p>

<p>The court had summoned Mr Qureshi to initiate indictment proceedings against him and ordered the prosecution to present witnesses in the next hearing scheduled for July 22.</p>

<p>Mr Qureshi, who was produced before ATC Judge Khalid Arshad, however, denied the charges.</p>

<p>"As Mr Qureshi was presented before the ATC judge, charges were framed against him for his alleged abetment in torching Lahore's Shadman police station. Mr Qureshi pleaded not guilty and maintained that a fake case has been instituted against him for being loyal to Imran Khan," a court official told Press Trust of India after the hearing.</p>

<p>The indictment of Mr Qureshi, who is also the vice-chairman of PTI, came hours before the Pakistan government announced its decision to ban Khan's PTI for its alleged involvement in anti-state activities.</p>

<p>The Lahore police had registered a case against several leaders and activists of the PTI on the charges of attacking and burning down the Shadman police station during the May 9 riots following the arrest of former prime minister Imran Khan by the Rangers in an alleged corruption case.</p>

<p>Besides this case, multiple cases related to the May 9 violence have been lodged against Mr Qureshi in Lahore alone.</p>

<p>Mr Qureshi has been in prison since he and Mr Khan, 71, were sentenced by a Pakistani court to 10 years in jail for violating the Official Secrets Act by making a diplomatic cable public when the PTI founder was in power.</p>

<p>Though the Islamabad High Court (IHC) on June 3 acquitted Mr Khan and Mr Qureshi in the Cipher case, suspending their 10-year sentence, the two remain in jail as they are named in multiple cases in connection with the May 9 violence across Pakistan.</p>

<p>Mr Qureshi was earlier this year indicted in eight more cases related to the May 9 violence.</p>

<p>The May 9 riots were triggered across the country after Khan was arrested by the National Accountability Bureau (NAB) in the 190-million-pound corruption case. He is currently facing over 200 cases and has been in jail since August last year.</p>

<p>Hundreds of PTI workers and senior leaders were put behind bars for their involvement in violence and attacks on military installations, including the Jinnah House, ISI building in Faisalabad and General Headquarters (GHQ) in Rawalpindi, last year on May 9.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-03/21qhr1f4_shah-mahmood-qureshi-reuters_650x400_01_March_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shah Mahmood Qureshi has denied the charges (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fight-against-terrorism-separatism-extremism-scos-priority-s-jaishankar-6111515]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fight Against Terrorism, Separatism, Extremism SCO's Priority: S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fight-against-terrorism-separatism-extremism-scos-priority-s-jaishankar-6111515]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:38:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Stating that terrorism is a major challenge faced by the world today, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said that the Shanghai Cooperation Organization (SCO) has to play a major role in the region's security.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stating that terrorism is a major challenge faced by the world today, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said that the Shanghai Cooperation Organization (SCO) has to play a major role in the region's security.</p>

<p>In an interview with Kazinform News Agency in Astana, Kazakhstan, the EAM said that SCO's priority is to fight against the three evils -- Terrorism, Separatism and Extremism.</p>

<p>"There is no doubt that the major challenge faced by the world today is terrorism. It has become a threat to regional and global peace, and it demands urgent action from all of us. In this aspect, I am happy that Kazakhstan during their Chairmanship have negotiated an updated program to combat terrorism, separatism, and extremism, which was adopted in Astana Summit," he said.</p>

<p>"Fight against the three evils- Terrorism, Separatism and Extremism- is a priority in SCO," EAM Jaishankar added.</p>

<p>He further said that some joint statements were adopted on theme during India's presidency of SCO last year.</p>

<p>Stating that Kazakhstan has also carried forward the spirit of that Joint Statement, Jaishankar also laid emphasis on the importance of implementation of these statements.</p>

<p>"During the New Delhi Summit last year, one of the two Joint Statements adopted was on 'Countering Radicalization leading to Terrorism, Separatism and Extremism'. The statements included various elements of radicalization -- including ideology, media campaigns, as well as radical and terrorist content on internet," the Foreign Minister said.</p>

<p>"Kazakhstan, during their Chairmanship, carried forward the spirit of that Joint Statement. The updated program to combat terrorism, separatism and extremism is critical and timely. But I want to emphasize that what is more important is the actual implementation of the program that we have now successfully drawn up, which includes unambiguous commitment by all the Member States in getting rid of all forms and manifestations of terrorism in the region, including cross-border terrorism," he further stated.</p>

<p>Jaishankar, represented India at the SCO Council of Heads of State (SCO Summit) held under Kazakhstan's Presidency in Astana.</p>

<p>He delivered remarks on behalf of Prime Minister Narendra Modi. The EAM also held several bilateral meetings and engagements with counterparts and other global leaders.</p>

<p>Emphasising SCO's role in the region's security, Jaishankar said SCO as an organization should be allowed to fully utilize its potential, and also highlighted the theme of SCO Summit 'Towards a SECURE SCO' in 2023 under India's presidency.</p>

<p>"In fact, India's priorities for the Chairmanship last year were on the theme 'Towards a SECURE SCO' -- with SECURE being an acronym which stands for Security, Economic cooperation, Connectivity, Unity, Respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity, and Environment," the Foreign Minister said.</p>

<p>"When we say regional security in the context of SCO, the most important issues that stand out is terrorism, including cross-border terrorism. Today, after decades of taking measures against terrorism in global forums, including through the UNSC, terrorism continues to be a threat to the region. The UN designated terror outfits are still functioning in the region," he added.</p>

<p>He further said that combating terrorism requires a very comprehensive approach, not just against the perpetrators of heinous acts of terrorism, but also against the facilitators, financiers and sponsors of terrorism.</p>

<p>"They all need to be identified and punished," he said.</p>

<p>Jaishankar said Regional Anti-Terrrorist Structure (RATS) has a reasonable standing to propose measures against terrorism in the region.</p>

<p>"We stand ready to strengthen SCO mechanisms in this front. I hope that the proposed Universal Centre to be established within the RATS in Tashkent, along with the other specialized centers under the Universal Centre, will grow to become foremost anti-terrorist structure in the region," he said.</p>

<p>Stressing on the need to build consensus, the Foreign Minister said any security related initiative or paradigm should be formulated taking into consideration territorial integrity and sovereignty of all the countries that will be involved</p>

<p>The Foreign Minister also elaborated on the threat of drug trafficking. He said there is a consensus on the establishment of Anti-Drug Centre in Dushanbe, Tajikistan and along with Universal Centre, it will be an effective weapon to combat drug trafficking.</p>

<p>"Drug Trafficking is another issue that we need to combat together, and is very closely related to two other issues in the region -- terrorism and stability in Afghanistan. There is a consensus on the establishment of Anti-Drug Centre in Dushanbe. This is a welcome move and is much needed. The Anti-Drug Centre, together with the proposed Universal Centre, will be an effective weapon in combating drug trafficking," Mr Jaishankar said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/lhp50aog_s-jaishankar-ani_625x300_29_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["There is no doubt that the major challenge faced by the world today is terrorism," he said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-worried-about-another-trump-presidency-we-will-work-together-zelensky-6111378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Not Worried About Another Trump Presidency, We Will Work Together: Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-worried-about-another-trump-presidency-we-will-work-together-zelensky-6111378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:16:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky on Monday said he was not concerned at the prospect of another Donald Trump presidency in the United States, despite indications his administration could be more sympathetic to the Kremlin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky on Monday said he was not concerned at the prospect of another Donald Trump presidency in the United States, despite indications his administration could be more sympathetic to the Kremlin.</p>

<p>A Trump victory in the US November elections would put into question Washington's continued support for Ukraine as the country struggles through a third year of fighting against Russian forces.</p>

<p>"I think that if Donald Trump becomes president, we will work together. I'm not worried about this," Zelensky said during a press conference in Kyiv.</p>

<p>The Republican Party candidate has suggested that he would end the conflict very quickly if he won back the presidency, which Kyiv fears would mean it would be forced to negotiate with Moscow from a weakened position.</p>

<p>Zelensky said that during his recent trip to the US for a NATO defence alliance summit he had met Republican governors and was assured of the party's backing.</p>

<p>"There are hawks whose messages are more right-wing or more radical," Zelensky told reporters.</p>

<p>"But I want to tell you that the majority of the Republican Party supports Ukraine and the people of Ukraine," he added.</p>

<p>Trump previously said during a debate with President Joe Biden that if elected, he would have the Ukraine conflict "settled" before he took office in January 2025.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/nr4rf32g_zelensky-reuters_625x300_04_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Majority of the Republican Party supports Ukraine," says Volodymyr Zelensky (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-scientists-decode-125-year-old-element-that-could-improve-cancer-treatments-6111331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Decode 125-Year-Old Element That Could Improve Cancer Treatments]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-scientists-decode-125-year-old-element-that-could-improve-cancer-treatments-6111331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:09:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US researchers have decoded an element that could destroy cancerous cells, and advance treatment options for the deadly disease that claims millions of lives globally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US researchers have decoded an element that could destroy cancerous cells, and advance treatment options for the deadly disease that claims millions of lives globally.</p>

<p>The element, actinium, was first discovered by French scientist Andre-Louis Debierne in 1899 and is number 89 on the Periodic Table.</p>

<p>Now after 125 years of its existence, there is a bright chance it could improve cancer treatments, as found by the Department of Energy's Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory.</p>

<p>Even after 125 years, actinium remains an enigmatic element of science because to date it is found in extremely small quantities, and special facilities are needed to work with it, not just any ordinary radioactive lab.</p>

<p>The team of scientists tried growing it and while elements can behave very similarly to their lightweight counterparts, actinium behaved differently than its counterpart lanthanum.</p>

<p>From nuclear energy to medicine, these elements can serve the purpose admirably, for both are radioactive and earthy minerals, it is not actinium itself that saves the day, it is an isotope -- a distinct nuclear species of any element -- named actinium 225 that has shown promise in a method called targeted alpha therapy (TAT).</p>

<p>The TAT technique transports radioactive elements to the cancer site via biological delivery mechanisms such as peptides or antibodies.</p>

<p>When actinium decays, it emits energetic particles that travel a short distance, killing local cancer cells while sparing healthy tissue further away.</p>

<p>"If we can engineer proteins to bind the actinium with a high affinity, and either be fused with an antibody or serve as the targeting protein that would really enable new ways to develop radiopharmaceuticals." said Rebecca Abergel, Associate Professor of nuclear engineering at the University of California- Berkeley.</p>

<p>Researchers employed a revolutionary way to create the crystals with only 5 micrograms of pure actinium, which is about one-tenth the weight of a grain of salt and unnoticeable to the naked eye.</p>

<p>They initially refined the actinium using a complicated filtration method that removed other elements and chemical contaminants.</p>

<p>They next attached the actinium to a metal-trapping molecule known as a ligand and encased the bundle inside a protein identified and purified by Roland Strong's team at the Fred Hutchinson Cancer Centre, resulting in a "macromolecular scaffold."</p>

<p>The crystals, which grew for a week inside the Heavy Element Research Laboratory, were then cryocooled in liquid nitrogen and irradiated with X-rays at Berkeley Lab's Advanced Light Source.</p>

<p>X-rays revealed the compound's three-dimensional structure and demonstrated how this elusive element works with other surrounding atoms.</p>

<p>This study used the longest-living isotope of actinium, Actinium 227 although Actinium 225 is the preferred one for the Targeted Alpha method (as it has been used for prostate cancer as well with positive results).</p>

<p>The final word has not yet been said but the initial prose is the melodious beginning of a future scientific opera which would herald a new era of cancer treatment, the researchers said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h9odgmm8_cancer-cell_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US researchers have decoded an element that could destroy cancerous cells]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/committed-to-strengthen-nepal-india-relations-newly-appointed-pm-kp-sharma-oli-6111310]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Committed To Strengthen Nepal-India Relations": Newly Appointed PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/committed-to-strengthen-nepal-india-relations-newly-appointed-pm-kp-sharma-oli-6111310]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:07:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Newly appointed Nepalese Prime Minister KP Sharma Oli on Monday said he was committed to working with his Indian counterpart Narendra Modi on strengthening Nepal-India relations and elevating the bilateral ties to new heights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Newly appointed Nepalese Prime Minister KP Sharma Oli on Monday said he was committed to working with his Indian counterpart Narendra Modi on strengthening Nepal-India relations and elevating the bilateral ties to new heights.</p>

<p>Responding to Prime Minister Modi's congratulatory message on his appointment as Nepal's prime minister for the fourth time, Mr Oli thanked the Indian leader for his warm wishes.</p>

<p>"Thank you, Prime Minister @narendramodi for your warm congratulations. I am committed to working closely with you to strengthen Nepal-India relations for our mutual benefit. Together, we can elevate our historic ties to new heights," the newly appointed prime minister said on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thank you, Prime Minister <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a>, for your warm congratulations. I am committed to working closely with you to strengthen Nepal-India relations for our mutual benefit. Together, we can elevate our historic ties to new heights.</p>
— K P Sharma Oli (@kpsharmaoli) <a href="https://twitter.com/kpsharmaoli/status/1812795306859429935?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Earlier in the day, PM Modi congratulated Oli on his appointment as prime minister of Nepal and said he looked forward to working closely with him to further strengthen the friendship between the two countries.</p>

<p>Mr Oli, Chairman of the Communist Party of Nepal-Unified Marxist Leninist (CPN-UML), was appointed Nepal's prime minister for a fourth term on Sunday to lead a new coalition government.</p>

<p>Mr Oli, 72, succeeds Pushpa Kamal Dahal 'Prachanda' who lost the vote of confidence in the House of Representatives on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-01/7sf7a9do_kp-sharma-oli-650_625x300_29_January_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[KP Sharma Oli was appointed Nepal's prime minister for a fourth term on Sunday (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/england-wales-population-rises-by-most-since-1948-after-record-immigration-6111100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[England, Wales Population Rises By Most Since 1948 After Record Immigration]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/england-wales-population-rises-by-most-since-1948-after-record-immigration-6111100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 17:39:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Record immigration caused the population of England and Wales to rise by 610,000 to 60.9 million in mid-2023, the largest annual increase in 75 years, official data showed on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Record immigration caused the population of England and Wales to rise by 610,000 to 60.9 million in mid-2023, the largest annual increase in 75 years, official data showed on Monday.</p>

<p>What statisticians term 'natural' population growth - the difference between births and deaths - fell to just 400, the lowest since 1978, while net international migration rose to 622,000, up from 548,500 in the previous 12 months.</p>

<p>A net 13,800 people also moved from England and Wales to Scotland or Northern Ireland.</p>

<p>Britain's Office for National Statistics said the population increase in England and Wales was the largest since 1948 when a post-World War Two baby boom and the return of British military personnel serving overseas caused a rise of 1.5 million.</p>

<p>The population for the whole United Kingdom was 67.6 million in mid 2022. Data for 2023 is not yet available.</p>

<p>Economic output has not kept up with the rising population. Based on provisional population figures, gross domestic product per head in 2023 was 0.7% lower than a year earlier.</p>

<p>Net migration to the United Kingdom hit a record 764,000 in 2022 and fell 10% to 685,000 in 2023, but is more than double its level in 2015, just before the Brexit referendum.</p>

<p>Reducing immigration was a key goal of many Britons who voted to leave the European Union.</p>

<p>Britain's previous Conservative government said it wanted to reduce net immigration, and Prime Minister Keir Starmer's Labour Party pledged in the election campaign to do so too by making the economy less reliant on foreign workers.</p>

<p>Post-Brexit changes to visas sharply reduced the number of EU migrants to Britain, but new work visa rules led to a surge in immigration from India, Nigeria and Pakistan, often to fill health and social care vacancies.</p>

<p>At the end of last year the government tightened rules to stop low-paid social care workers from bringing dependents.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d1cbke9g_reuters-uk_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The population for the whole United Kingdom was 67.6 million in mid 2022. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-genai-ai-improves-creativity-in-stories-reduces-diversity-study-6110674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Improves Creativity In Stories, Reduces Diversity: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-genai-ai-improves-creativity-in-stories-reduces-diversity-study-6110674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:46:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Stories created with help of ChatGPT are more creative compared to those by writers not using the tool, according to research. However, diversity in stories suffered with the use of AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stories created with help of ChatGPT are more creative, engaging their audience with more plot twists, compared to those by writers not using the tool, according to research.</p>

<p>However, researchers also found that diversity in stories by writers using generative artificial intelligence's (GenAI) suffered, therefore increasing the risk of "collective novelty".</p>

<p>GenAI can create content -- text, image, audio or video -- and is based on large language models, which are trained on massive amounts of text data and can, therefore, process, interpret and respond to requests in the natural language that humans use to communicate.</p>

<p>The authors of the study, published in the journal Science Advances, found that writers inherently more creative benefitted the least from ideas generated by ChatGPT, while those less creative became more creative due to ideas suggested by the GenAI model.</p>

<p>Therefore, AI "effectively equalised creativity" among all the writers, the team of researchers said.</p>

<p>"While these results point to an increase in individual creativity, there is risk of losing collective novelty. If the publishing industry were to embrace more generative AI-inspired stories, our findings suggest that the stories would become less unique in aggregate and more similar to each other," said study author Anil Doshi, assistant professor at the University College London's School of Management, UK.</p>

<p>For the study, 300 participants were tasked with writing a short, eight-sentence story (a 'microstory') for a target audience of young adults, of whom 600 were recruited to judge the writers' work.</p>

<p>The writers were divided into three groups. The first was allowed no help from AI, while the second was allowed to take one idea, along with the first three sentences of the story, created by ChatGPT for inspiration. The third group was allowed to choose from up to five AI-created story ideas.</p>

<p>The authors found that the work of writers taking the AI's help were over 8-9 per cent more novel, compared to that of writers not relying on the AI. Along with novelty, the microstories were judged for "usefulness" -- were they engaging enough for the audience, and could they be developed and potentially published?</p>

<p>The team also found that the less creative writers 'became' more so, with AI making their stories more novel by 10.7 per cent and more useful by 11.5 per cent, compared to the stories of writers not taking AI's help.</p>

<p>The AI made the work by less creative writers up to 26.6 per cent better, 22.6 per cent more enjoyable and 15.2 per cent less boring, the authors found.</p>

<p>The inherent creativity of the writers was measured using a psychological test -- Divergent Association Task (DAT).</p>

<p>Divergent thinking, which allows one to think of multiple solutions to a problem spontaneously, is known to be important to creativity.</p>

<p>Further, the authors found that among the writers using GenAI's ideas, the stories they produced were 10.7 per cent more similar, compared to the writers not using AI.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/msft5rq8_chatgpt_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study was published in the journal Science Advances]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-officer-officer-trump-supporters-on-seeing-shooter-on-roof-6110513]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video - "Officer! Officer!": Trump Supporters On Seeing Shooter On Roof]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-officer-officer-trump-supporters-on-seeing-shooter-on-roof-6110513]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:23:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Secret Service is under fire over its most stunning failure in decades following the assassination attempt on Trump and witnesses claiming they had flagged the shooter to the officials before he took the shot are only adding to the crisis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Secret Service is under fire over its most stunning failure in decades following the assassination attempt on Donald Trump and several witnesses claiming that they had flagged the shooter to the officials before he took the shot are only adding to the crisis.</p>

<p>The questions facing the authorities are how a 20-year-old lone shooter was able to spot an exposed rooftop barely a football field away from the former president, assume the position, and take the shots, and why did officials not act despite several attendees pointing out the "shooter" on the roof.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One "citizen journalist" Grant Godwin posted a video filmed by supporters at the Trump rally that showed the alleged shooter getting in position.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9bDBZmh29-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9bDBZmh29-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9bDBZmh29-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9bDBZmh29-/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Grant Godwin (@the_typical_liberal)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>"Officer! Officer!" a person is heard calling out to the security officials posted nearby and another saying, "Yeah, someone is on the roof", and pointing to the alleged shooter, 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.</p>

<p>The "shooter" is seen climbing the roof of a shed, approximately just 400 ft, or less than 150 metres, from the stage where Trump was. He tries to stay down, crawling his way forward after getting on the roof.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Someone's on top of the roof... Right there... You see him? He's laying down... Yeah, he is laying down," a person is heard saying. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Yeah, look, there he is..." said another.</p>

<p>Sharing the video on Instagram, Godwin wrote: "HOW DID THIS HAPPEN?! The amount of time the Secret Service and law enforcement had to neutralise this threat is ridiculous. I cannot wrap my head around this. You're telling me rally attendees noticed this guy way ahead of time, informed law enforcement, and still they didn't take this guy out before a shot was taken? Extremely concerning."</p>

<p>Reacting to the video, a user wrote: "I've seen better security at Foot Locker."</p>

<p>"So some random 20-year-old kid just is lucky enough to access the one spot to be able to have a clear shot of Trump? The only place they needed to secure? It makes no sense," said another.</p>

<p>"Walmart security could've taken that dude out," noted a third.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A lone shooter shot at Donald Trump at his campaign rally in Pennsylvania (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/father-daughter-die-at-national-park-in-us-after-running-out-of-water-in-extreme-heat-6110502]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Father, Daughter Die At US National Park After Running Out Of Water]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/father-daughter-die-at-national-park-in-us-after-running-out-of-water-in-extreme-heat-6110502]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:22:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[By the time the pair was found, they were already dead, according to the National Park Service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man, 52, from Wisconsin and his 23-year-old daughter died after getting lost in Utah's Canyonlands National Park and running out of water in extreme heat. They two were hiking at 100-degree Fahrenheit (37.7 degrees Celsius), according to a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/15/us-news/utah-canyonlands-national-park-hikers-die-after-getting-lost-running-out-of-water-in-100-degree-heat/"><em>New York Post.</em></a></p>

<p>National Park Service rangers reported that on Friday afternoon, someone in Canyonlands' Island of the Sky neighbourhood texted 911 to San Juan County dispatchers. After receiving the emergency call, the officials of the Bureau of Land Management's Moab District Helitack searched for the father and daughter.</p>

<p>However, by the time the pair was found, they were already dead, according to the National Park Service.</p>

<p>The tragedy marks the most recent deaths in National Parks this summer. In Arizona's Grand Canyon National Park, several hikers who were unprepared for temperatures in the triple digits died. A motorcyclist in California lost his life in Death Valley when the mercury reached 128 degrees Fahrenheit.</p>

<p>Rangers from the National Park Service encourage people to hike with plenty of water and to avoid hiking in the afternoon when temperatures are at their highest.</p>

<p>A severe heat wave swept central to eastern parts of the United States in June, with several cities recording their highest temperatures in decades, according to the National Weather Service (NWS). Experts warn that this heat wave could turn into a deadly weather event, labelling it the "silent killer."</p>

<p>Kristie Ebi, a public health scientist at the University of Washington who contributed to a United Nations special report on extreme weather, told PBS that in recent years, the heat "seems like it is coming faster and more severe than we expected."</p>

<p>The heat wave sweeping across much of the US is driven by what meteorologists call a "heat dome." This phenomenon involves a high-pressure system in the atmosphere that causes hot air to sink and compress, resulting in soaring temperatures at ground level. Approximately 80 million people across the US are experiencing sweltering conditions, with heat advisories or excessive heat warnings in place. Residents are urged to take precautions, stay hydrated and avoid prolonged exposure to the heat.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/orjqiqco_canyonlands-national-park_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[They two were hiking at 100-degree Fahrenheit (37.7 degrees Celsius).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-joe-biden-ian-bremmer-boost-for-trump-time-for-biden-expert-explains-assassination-bid-impact-6110457]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boost For Trump, Time For Biden: Expert Explains Assassination Bid Impact]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-joe-biden-ian-bremmer-boost-for-trump-time-for-biden-expert-explains-assassination-bid-impact-6110457]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:19:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The assassination attempt on Donald Trump has provided the Republican leader with a unique opportunity to emerge as a taller leader, US political scientist Ian Bremmer told NDTV in an interview.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The assassination attempt on Donald Trump has provided the Republican leader with a unique opportunity to emerge as a taller leader, US political scientist Ian Bremmer told NDTV in an interview.</p>

<p>Mr Bremmer, author and founder of political risk research firm Eurasia Group, explained how the shooting at Trump's rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday will impact the US's political landscape in an election year and in the long-term.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kjndsh5o_ian-bremmer_625x300_15_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>Boost To Trump's Image</strong></p>

<p>"This is a boost for Trump, the fact that he stood up immediately after being shot, with blood on his face, with a fist raised and said, 'fight, fight, fight'. That is an iconic image that will go down in the history of US and will certainly be replayed over and over in the media across the media and by Trump and his supporters in this campaign," Mr Bremmer said, adding that it will increase support for the former President.</p>

<p>"He will appear in Milwaukee on Monday at the Republican National Convention as 'Lazarus risen' and there will be incredible support."&nbsp;Lazarus is a Biblical figure who Jesus brings back to life four days after his death.</p>

<p>This boost in image, he said, also makes it more likely for Trump to win the November election.</p>

<p><strong>What Changes For Biden</strong></p>

<p>On the Democrats side, Mr Bremmer said, Saturday's developments have made it less likely for US President Joe Biden to "stand down". "There has been a lot of pressure since the disastrous debate Biden had against Trump. There was a lot of internal opposition in the party. That is now off... in the most tragic way possible. Biden had not been inclined to step down, but everyone around him was telling him he needed to. Now he has more time to resist that. The story has moved elsewhere," the political scientist said.</p>

<p><strong>Impact On US Politics</strong></p>

<p>Explaining how the assassination attempt is likely to impact the US political landscape, Mr Bremmer said it has created the potential for more violence and social instability "at a time when Americans are highly polarised and are being fed enormous amounts of disinformation". He also said political opposition are now being treated as "enemies".</p>

<p>Asked how the country will respond to Saturday's attack, the political scientist said, "There is a need for a 9/11-type response where the US rallies together and denounces political violence of all sorts. What I fear is going to happen is much more like January 6 (when Trump supporters stormed Capitol Hill).&nbsp;"For a couple of days and weeks, a lot of Americans were denouncing violence, Democrats and Republicans saying this is horrible, but very quickly, January 6 became a threat to democracy for Democrats, but for Republicans, these were patriots who should be lionised and are heroes. I fear that while today, there is outrage across the political spectrum, it will be weaponised."</p>

<p><strong>An Opportunity For Trump</strong></p>

<p>Mr Bremmer said Trump's response to the assassination will be critical to how the narrative around it shapes up.&nbsp;"Joe Biden gave a unifying statement. But it's really about Trump, he was the one who could have been killed. If he wants to stand and be a leader, rally people around a cause greater than him, he is in a unique position to do that. Unfortunately, there is nothing about his history that implies that he will do that," he said.</p>

<p>The Republican leader's political journey, Mr Bremmer said, has been about "dividing the country into us vs them". "That's how he made his billions and how he became President," he said.</p>

<p><strong>US's Image In World</strong></p>

<p>Mr Bremmer said that US is the most powerful country in the world, militarily, economically and technologically. "But America's political system and democracy are in crisis in a way it is not true in India, Europe, Japan or South Korea. Allies around the world are deeply troubled about that. And America's adversaries, particularly Russians, North Koreans and Iranians, see this as great news, an opportunity."</p>

<p>Russians, he said, are "pouring gasoline on fire". "They want US system to collapse," he said.</p>

<p>When he was a student, Mr Bremmer said, the US was "admired politically". "The US won the Cold War because its ideas were better, values were better, political system was better." While the US still has the strongest military, currency and technology, "no one around the world looks at the US political system and thinks I want my political system to work like this".</p>

<p><strong>On Political Extremism In US</strong></p>

<p>The political scientist said that the US, besides being the most dysfunctional of major democracies, also has large gun ownership and this includes military style weapons. "The only country which has more gun ownership than US is Yemen, and Yemen is in the middle of a civil war," he said.</p>

<p>This gun culture has been complimented by unaddressed mental illness, drug use and homelessness that has gone unaddressed, creating a very violent environment. "It has created tinder for an explosive political environment. The reason we haven't seen more political violence is because the US devotes an incredible amount of money and resources to prevent it." He said it is a big question why the Secret Service was "caught unawares yesterday". "This is clearly a major failure of the Secret Service and there will be a lot of investigation. What happened that allowed a shooter to get so close to former President Trump and pop off 6-8 shots, including one that hit him?"</p>

<p><strong>On What's Next</strong></p>

<p>The US, he said, is likely to see more security and surveillance after the assassination attempt on Trump. "Anyone who travels to the White House knows it's very different than it was before 9/11. That's a depressing thing but reality. I suspect we are moving much more towards monitoring of individuals," he said, also underlining privacy and human rights issues that will come with it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/air2iuk8_donald-trump-shooting_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's response after the shooting and the iconic image will go down in history, Ian Bremmer said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ill-be-back-soon-rapper-wiz-khalifa-charged-over-cannabis-possession-in-romania-6110366]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'll Be Back Soon": Wiz Khalifa Charged Over Cannabis Possession In Romania]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ill-be-back-soon-rapper-wiz-khalifa-charged-over-cannabis-possession-in-romania-6110366]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:05:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US rapper Wiz Khalifa has been charged with illegal drug possession after he consumed cannabis on stage while performing at a seaside festival in Romania, prosecutors said Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US rapper Wiz Khalifa has been charged with illegal drug possession after he consumed cannabis on stage while performing at a seaside festival in Romania, prosecutors said Sunday.</p>

<p>The hip-hop star was headlining at the "Beach, Please!" festival in the Romanian village of Costinesti on the shore of the Black Sea, when he got caught with the drug early Sunday, prosecutors say.</p>

<p>Cannabis is considered a "risk drug" in Romania, and possession is punishable by up to ten years in prison.</p>

<p>Videos posted on social media show the rapper being escorted from the venue by Romanian authorities.</p>

<p>"During a performance at a music festival held in Costinesti, the accused was found to have possessed more than 18 grams of cannabis and to have consumed (on stage) another quantity in the form of a handmade cigarette," Romanian anti-organised crime prosecutors (DIICOT) said in a statement.</p>

<p>A source close to the investigation confirmed to AFP that Wiz Khalifa, together with other people, had been taken in for questioning early on Sunday.</p>

<p>Khalifa was subsequently charged, but not kept in custody, the source said.</p>

<p>The investigation into the musician is ongoing, according to prosecutors.</p>

<p>Reacting to the matter, the rapper wrote on X that he "didn't mean any disrespect" to Romania "by lighting up on stage".</p>

<p>"They were very respectful and let me go. I'll be back soon. But without a big ass joint next time," he added.</p>

<p>Khalifa often refers to the delights of marijuana in his lyrics.</p>

<p>Legal cannabis companies in the US have drawn celebrity funding or endorsements from known aficionados of marijuana like Khalifa and rapper Snoop Dogg, but also from actor Seth Rogen and former boxing champ Mike Tyson.</p>

<p>In another recent controversy rocking the music scene in Romania, US rapper Nicki Minaj earlier this month abruptly cancelled her appearance at the Saga Festival in Bucharest, citing safety concerns due to upcoming protests.</p>

<p>Accountants held a protest against changes in fiscal legislation in Romania one day after her scheduled show, but the demonstration passed peacefully.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nfp1jt6g_wiz-khalifa_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wiz Khalifa often refers to the delights of marijuana in his lyrics. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-has-no-plans-to-contact-trump-after-assassination-attempt-kremlin-6110240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Has No Plans To Contact Trump After Assassination Attempt: Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-has-no-plans-to-contact-trump-after-assassination-attempt-kremlin-6110240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:48:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin said on Monday that Russian President Vladimir Putin had not contacted Donald Trump after the assassination attempt on the Republican U.S. presidential candidate over the weekend and had no plans to do so.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin said on Monday that Russian President Vladimir Putin had not contacted Donald Trump after the assassination attempt on the Republican U.S. presidential candidate over the weekend and had no plans to do so.</p>

<p>Asked if security measures around Putin would now be strengthened, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said the Russian leader already enjoyed the appropriate level of protection.</p>

<p>"Security is already strengthened for obvious reasons, regardless of incidents," Peskov told reporters.</p>

<p>"We can only reiterate that the security of the head of state is provided at the appropriate level, everything necessary is being done taking into account the international escalation of tensions in general."</p>

<p>The Kremlin said on Sunday it did not believe the U.S. administration was responsible for Saturday's assassination attempt on Trump, but accused it of creating an atmosphere that provoked the attack.</p>

<p>Trump was shot in the ear during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania after a major security lapse. The attacker was shot dead and law enforcement officials said they had not yet identified a motive.</p>

<p>Putin has not yet commented publicly on the matter.</p>

<p>Peskov's comments echoed those of some of Trump's Republican allies, who immediately pinned the blame on Biden.</p>

<p>"After numerous attempts to remove candidate Trump from the political arena - using first legal tools, the courts, prosecutors, attempts to politically discredit and compromise the candidate - it was obvious to all outside observers that his life was in danger," Peskov said on Sunday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9vnmprvg_putin-trump_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin has not yet commented publicly on the matter. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-iii-writes-to-donald-trump-after-assassination-attempt-6110209]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles III Writes To Donald Trump After Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-iii-writes-to-donald-trump-after-assassination-attempt-6110209]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:42:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's head of state King Charles III has written to former US president Donald Trump after he survived an assassination attempt, Buckingham Palace said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's head of state King Charles III has written to former US president Donald Trump after he survived an assassination attempt, Buckingham Palace said on Monday.</p>

<p>King Charles' message was delivered on Sunday via the UK embassy in Washington, the palace said, adding that the contents would be kept private.</p>

<p>Trump -- set to be confirmed as the Republican Party's candidate in the November presidential election -- was hit in the ear by a gunman at an election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday.</p>

<p>He was left with a bloodied face, but avoided serious injury in the incident in which one bystander died and two others were critically injured.</p>

<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer spoke to Trump on Sunday, expressing his condolences for the other victim and their family, and wishing the former president and the injured a quick recovery.</p>

<p>Starmer said on X, formerly Twitter, that he was "appalled by the shocking scenes" at the rally.</p>

<p>"Political violence in any form has no place in our societies," the premier said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/66hm85so_donald-trump_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was hit in the ear by a gunman at an election rally in Pennsylvania (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-donald-trump-joe-biden-us-presidential-elections-in-donald-trumps-recollection-of-shooting-special-note-for-secret-service-6109873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Trump's Recollection Of Shooting, Special Note For Secret Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-donald-trump-joe-biden-us-presidential-elections-in-donald-trumps-recollection-of-shooting-special-note-for-secret-service-6109873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 14:55:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A day after Donald Trump survived an assassination bid at his last campaign rally, the former US President Donald Trump praised the Secret Service officials for their heroic actions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A day after Donald Trump survived an assassination bid at his last campaign rally, the former US President Donald Trump praised the Secret Service officials for their heroic actions.</p>

<p>"They took him (shooter) out with one shot right between the eyes," he told the New York Post in an interview. "They did a fantastic job," he added.</p>

<p>"It's surreal for all of us," he said.</p>

<p>Donald Trump told the publication that he would have been dead had he not tilted his head slightly to the right to read a chart while addressing the rally.</p>

<p>"I'm not supposed to be here, I'm supposed to be dead," Trump told the New York Post.</p>

<p>Donald Trump told the New York Post that as Secret Service agents led him off stage, he still wanted to continue speaking to supporters.</p>

<p>"I just wanted to keep speaking, but I just got shot," he said.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old had just started his speech during a Saturday campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania when the shots rang out and one of the bullets grazed his ear.</p>

<p>A moment of terrifying political violence at the rally instantly turned into a piece of Donald Trump iconography that's likely to turbocharge his presidential bid.</p>

<p>Images of a defiant Trump - with his fist raised over his head and his bloody right ear, as Secret Service agents surround him and the American flag waving in the background - are blazing across social media and television.</p>

<p>He said that he was glad he didn't have to die for an iconic picture. "A lot of people say it's the most iconic photo they've ever seen. They're right, and I didn't die. Usually, you have to die to have an iconic picture," Trump told the New York Post.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bokt02qg_donald-trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said that he was glad he didn't have to die for an iconic picture.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>