<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 16:44:18 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-and-james-robinson-win-2024-nobel-prize-in-economics-for-work-on-wealth-inequality-6786725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trio Wins 2024 Nobel Prize In Economics For Work On Wealth Inequality]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-and-james-robinson-win-2024-nobel-prize-in-economics-for-work-on-wealth-inequality-6786725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 16:33:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Nobel Prize in Economics was awarded on Monday to Turkish-American Daron Acemoglu and British-Americans Simon Johnson and James Robinson for research into wealth inequality between nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Nobel Prize in Economics was awarded on Monday to Turkish-American Daron Acemoglu and British-Americans Simon Johnson and James Robinson for research into wealth inequality between nations.</p>

<p>By examining the various political and economic systems introduced by European colonisers, the three have been able to demonstrate a relationship between institutions and prosperity, the jury said.</p>

<p>"Reducing the vast differences in income between countries is one of our time's greatest challenges," Jakob Svensson, chair of the Committee for the Prize in Economic Sciences, said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The laureates have demonstrated the importance of societal institutions for achieving this," Svensson added.</p>

<p>Acemoglu, 57, is a professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), as is Johnson, 61.</p>

<p>Robinson, 64, is a professor at the University of Chicago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The jury highlighted the laureates' work illuminating how societal institutions play a role in explaining why some countries prosper, while others do not.</p>

<p>"I am delighted. It's just a real shock and amazing news," Acemoglu told reporters via telephone as the award was announced in Stockholm.</p>

<p>The Economics prize is the only Nobel not among the original five created in the will of Swedish scientist Alfred Nobel, who died in 1896.</p>

<p>It was instead created through a donation from the Swedish central bank in 1968, leading detractors to dub it "a false Nobel".</p>

<p>However, like for the other Nobel science prizes, the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences decides the winner and follows the same selection process.</p>

<p>The Economics Prize wraps up this year's Nobel season, which honoured achievements in artificial intelligence for the physics and chemistry prizes, while the Peace Prize went to Japanese group Nihon Hidankyo, committed to fighting nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>South Korea's Han Kan won the literature prize -- the only woman laureate so far this year -- while the medicine prize lauded discoveries in understanding gene regulation.</p>

<p>The Nobel Prizes consist of a diploma, a gold medal and a one-million-dollar sum.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They will be presented at ceremonies in Stockholm and Oslo on December 10, the anniversary of the 1896 death of scientist and prize creator Alfred Nobel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b93ffs7g_2024-economics-nobel-prize_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Economics prize is the only Nobel not among the original five created in the will of Alfred Nobel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-economics-goes-to-daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-james-robinson-6786223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Economists Get Nobel Prize For Study On Institutions And Prosperity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-economics-goes-to-daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-james-robinson-6786223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 15:23:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson and James Robinson won the 2024 Nobel economics prize "for studies of how institutions are formed and affect prosperity", the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br />
US-based academics Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson and James Robinson won the 2024 Nobel economics prize "for studies of how institutions are formed and affect prosperity", the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences said on Monday.<br />
The prestigious award, formally known as the Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economic Sciences in Memory of Alfred Nobel, is the final prize to be given out this year and is worth 11 million Swedish crowns ($1.1 million).</p>

<p>"Reducing the vast differences in income between countries is one of our time's greatest challenges. The laureates have demonstrated the importance of societal institutions for achieving this," said Jakob Svensson, Chair of the Committee for the Prize in Economic Sciences.</p>

<p>"Societies with a poor rule of law and institutions that exploit the population do not generate growth or change for the better," the award organisers added on their website.</p>

<p>Daron Acemoglu and Simon Johnson work at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, while James Robinson is at the University of Chicago.</p>

<p>Acemoglu and Johnson recently collaborated on a book surveying technology through the ages which demonstrated how some technological advances were better at creating jobs and spreading wealth than others.</p>

<p>The economics award is not one of the original prizes for science, literature and peace created in the will of dynamite inventor and businessman Alfred Nobel and first awarded in 1901, but a later addition established and funded by Sweden's central bank in 1968.</p>

<p>Past winners include a host of influential thinkers such as Milton Friedman, John Nash - played by actor Russell Crowe in the 2001 film "A Beautiful Mind" - and, more recently, former U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Ben Bernanke.</p>

<p>Last year, Harvard economic historian Claudia Goldin won the prize for her work highlighting the causes of wage and labour market inequality between men and women.</p>

<p>The economics prize has been dominated by US academics since its inception, while U.S.-based researchers also tend to account for a large portion of winners in the scientific fields for which 2024 laureates were announced last week.</p>

<p>That crop of prizes began with US scientists Victor Ambros and Gary Ruvkun winning the prize for medicine on Monday and concluded with Japan's Nihon Hidankyo, an organisation of survivors from Hiroshima and Nagasaki who campaigned for the abolition of nuclear weapons landing the award for peace on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/35q9f3_the-nobel-prize-in-economics-2024_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nobel Economics Goes To Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson, James Robinson.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-adds-first-mpox-vaccine-to-its-list-expected-to-speed-up-distribution-6786012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Adds First Mpox Vaccine To Its List, Expected To Speed Up Distribution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-adds-first-mpox-vaccine-to-its-list-expected-to-speed-up-distribution-6786012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:55:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The WHO said Friday it had for the first time prequalified a mpox vaccine -- a move expected to speed up access to the jabs to fight an epidemic raging in Africa.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The WHO said Friday it had for the first time prequalified a mpox vaccine -- a move expected to speed up access to the jabs to fight an epidemic raging in Africa.</p>

<p>The announcement came on the heels of the arrival of the first MVA-BN vaccines to the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), the epicentre of the epidemic.</p>

<p>"This first prequalification of a vaccine against mpox is an important step in our fight against the disease, both in the context of the current outbreaks in Africa and in future," WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We now need urgent scale up in procurement, donations and rollout to ensure equitable access to vaccines where they are needed most... to prevent infections, stop transmission and save lives."</p>

<p>WHO's prequalification listing is used to evaluate the quality, safety and efficacy of medical products like vaccines, paving the way for the United Nations and other international agencies to procure them.</p>

<p>The list is also used by lower-income countries without the means to carry out their evaluations to fast-track procurement approvals.</p>

<p>"The WHO prequalification of the MVA-BN vaccine will help accelerate ongoing procurement of the mpox vaccines by governments and international agencies... on the frontlines of the ongoing emergency in Africa and beyond," said Yukiko Nakatani, WHO's assistant chief in charge of access to medicines and health products.</p>

<p>Mpox, previously known as monkeypox, is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals but can also be passed from human to human through close physical contact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It causes fever, muscular aches and large boil-like skin lesions, and can in some cases be deadly.</p>

<p>The WHO declared an international emergency over <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-approves-first-diagnostic-test-for-mpox-amid-rising-outbreaks-in-africa-6713877">mpox</a> last month, concerned by the surge in cases of the new Clade 1b strain in the DRC that spread to nearby countries.</p>

<p>DRC has recorded nearly 22,000 cases and 716 deaths linked to the virus since January.</p>

<p>So far, some 200,000 vaccine doses have been delivered to the DRC by the European Union, along with about 50,000 from the United States.</p>

<h3><strong>Safe and effective&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>WHO said it had based its prequalification assessment on information submitted by the manufacturer of the MVA-BN vaccine, Bavarian Nordic A/S, and a review by the European Medicines Agency.</p>

<p>"Good safety profile and vaccine performance has been consistently demonstrated in clinical studies, as well as in real-world use," it said.</p>

<p>According to the prequalification, the vaccine can be administered to people over the age of 18 as a two-dose injection given four weeks apart.</p>

<p>With a majority of mpox cases and deaths in the DRC in children, WHO stressed that the vaccine could be used "off-label" in infants, children and adolescents, as well as in pregnant and immunocompromised people.</p>

<p>"This means vaccine use is recommended in outbreak settings where the benefits of vaccination outweigh the potential risks," WHO said.</p>

<p>The agency also recommends single-dose use in outbreak settings where the supply of the vaccine is constrained, although it stressed that more data was needed on vaccine safety and effectiveness in such circumstances.</p>

<p>The currently available data, it said, shows that a single dose of the MVA-BN vaccine given before exposure has an estimated 76 per cent effectiveness in protecting against mpox, while two doses are estimated to be 82 per cent effective. &nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1n5d9p5_mpox-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WHO recommends single-dose use of the vaccine in outbreak settings where the supply. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trudeau Government's Political Agenda": India's Full Statement On Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:22:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has strongly rejected Canada's allegations linking top Indian diplomats to an investigation in their country, calling it a "political agenda of the Trudeau government".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has strongly <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660">rejected Canada's allegations</a> linking top Indian diplomats to an investigation in their country, calling it a "political agenda of the Trudeau government". India-Canada ties have been strained since Prime Minister Justin Trudeau claimed last year that "Indian agents" were involved in terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar's killing. India has rejected the claim multiple times in the past. In a statement today, the central government said Canada has not shared a "shred of evidence" with India and that the charges were centered around the Trudeau government's "vote bank politics".</p>

<p><strong>Read the full statement here:</strong></p>

<p>"India's response to diplomatic communication from Canada</p>

<p>October 14, 2024</p>

<p>We have received a diplomatic communication from Canada yesterday suggesting that the Indian High Commissioner and other diplomats are 'persons of interest' in a matter related to an investigation in that country. The Government of India strongly rejects these preposterous imputations and ascribes them to the political agenda of the Trudeau Government that is centered around vote bank politics.</p>

<p>Since Prime Minister Trudeau made certain allegations in September 2023, the Canadian Government has not shared a shred of evidence with the Government of India, despite many requests from our side. This latest step follows interactions that have again witnessed assertions without any facts. This leaves little doubt that on the pretext of an investigation, there is a deliberate strategy of smearing India for political gains.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence. In 2018, his visit to India, which was aimed at currying favour with a vote bank, rebounded to his discomfort. His Cabinet has included individuals who have openly associated with an extremist and separatist agenda regarding India. His naked interference in Indian internal politics in December 2020 showed how far he was willing to go in this regard. That his Government was dependent on a political party, whose leader openly espouses a separatist ideology vis-a-vis India, only aggravated matters. Under criticism for turning a blind eye to foreign interference in Canadian politics, his Government has deliberately brought in India in an attempt to mitigate the damage. This latest development targeting Indian diplomats is now the next step in that direction. It is no coincidence that it takes place as Prime Minister Trudeau is to depose before a Commission on foreign interference. It also serves the anti-India separatist agenda that the Trudeau Government has constantly pandered to for narrow political gains.</p>

<p>To that end, the Trudeau Government has consciously provided space to violent extremists and terrorists to harass, threaten and intimidate Indian diplomats and community leaders in Canada. This has included death threats to them and to Indian leaders. All these activities have been justified in the name of freedom of speech. Some individuals who have entered Canada illegally have been fast-tracked for citizenship. Multiple extradition requests from the Government of India in respect of terrorists and organized crime leaders living in Canada have been disregarded.</p>

<p>High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma is India's senior most serving diplomat with a distinguished career spanning 36 years. He has been Ambassador in Japan and Sudan, while also serving in Italy, Turkiye, Vietnam and China. The aspersions cast on him by the Government of Canada are ludicrous and deserve to be treated with contempt.</p>

<p>The Government of India has taken cognizance of the activities of the Canadian High Commission in India that serve the political agenda of the current regime. This led to the implementation of the principle of reciprocity in regard to diplomatic representation. India now reserves the right to take further steps in response to these latest efforts of the Canadian Government to concoct allegations against Indian diplomats."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/seuhqis_pm-modi-justin-trudeau-ani_625x300_22_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian government said Justin Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/poorest-countries-face-highest-debt-burden-for-18-years-world-bank-6785781]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Poorest Countries Face Highest Debt Burden For 18 Years: World Bank]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/poorest-countries-face-highest-debt-burden-for-18-years-world-bank-6785781]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:21:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world's 26 poorest economies are facing the most significant debt burden since 2006, the World Bank announced in a new report published Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world's 26 poorest economies are facing the most significant debt burden since 2006, the World Bank announced in a new report published Sunday.</p>

<p>Government debt in these countries, which are home to around 40 percent of the world's population, now stands at an average of 72 percent of GDP -- an 18-year high -- the Washington-based development lender said.</p>

<p>At the same time, the amount of international aid they receive as a share of their economic output has shrunk to a two-decade low.</p>

<p>"There is much that low-income economies can -— and must -— do for themselves," the World Bank's deputy chief economist, Ayhan Kose, said in a statement. "But these economies also need stronger help from abroad."</p>

<p>Low-income economies borrowed heavily during the Covid-19 pandemic, causing primary deficits to triple, the Bank said, adding that many countries had been unable to "fully unwind" these deficits.</p>

<p>Nearly half of the world's 26 poorest economies now find themselves in debt distress or at high risk of it -- double the figure it was in 2015.</p>

<p>The World Bank said its concessional lending arm, the International Development Association (IDA), had provided "nearly half" of all the development aid these economies received in 2022 from multilateral organizations.</p>

<p>"At a time when much of the world simply backed away from the poorest countries, IDA has been their main lifeline," the Bank's chief economist Indermit Gill said.</p>

<p>"But if they are to rise out of a state of chronic emergency and meet key development goals, low-income economies will need to accelerate investment to a pace without precedent," he added.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/poor-people-homeless-people-in-brazil_650x400_51476241928.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nearly half of the world's 26 poorest economies now find themselves in debt distress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Preposterous Imputations": Trudeau's Escalation, India's Strong Rebuttal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:03:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Monday issued a sharp rebuttal to Canada, rejecting allegations of its High Commissioner being a 'person of interest' in a murder investigation, describing them as "preposterous imputations."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Monday issued a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786">sharp rebuttal to Canada</a>, rejecting allegations of its High Commissioner being a 'person of interest' in a murder investigation, describing them as "preposterous imputations."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ties between India and Canada have been thorny ever since Justin Trudeau alleged India's involvement in the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar, a Canadian Khalistani terrorist, in June 2023. India has repeatedly refuted these claims as "absurd" and "motivated," accusing Trudeau's government of indulging in vote-bank politics by pandering to pro-Khalistan elements within Canada.</p>

<p>The diplomatic row took a sharp turn when Canada reportedly named the Indian High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma as a 'person of interest' in its investigation into Nijjar's death. India swiftly hit back, accusing Canada of maligning its officials without evidence and using "preposterous" claims to justify its failure to curb Khalistani extremism on its soil.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786">"Political Agenda Of Trudeau Government": India's Full Statement Slamming Canada</a></p>

<p>In a strongly worded statement, New Delhi condemned Canada's diplomatic communication suggesting that the Indian High Commissioner and other Indian diplomats were implicated in a sensitive investigation. The Ministry of External Affairs issued a sharp rebuttal, stating, "The Government of India strongly rejects these preposterous imputations and ascribes them to the political agenda of the Trudeau Government that is centered around vote bank politics."</p>

<p>"Since Prime Minister Trudeau made certain allegations in September 2023, the Canadian government has not shared a shred of evidence with the Government of India, despite many requests from our side. This latest step follows interactions that have again witnessed assertions without any facts. This leaves little doubt that on the pretext of an investigation, there is a deliberate strategy of smearing India for political gains," the Centre's statement read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma is India's senior most serving diplomat with a distinguished career spanning 36 years. He has been Ambassador in Japan and Sudan, while also serving in Italy, Turkiye, Vietnam and China. The aspersions cast on him by the Government of Canada are ludicrous and deserve to be treated with contempt," it added.</p>

<p>The latest exchange follows a brief encounter between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Justin Trudeau on the sidelines of the ASEAN Summit in Laos recently. While sources in New Delhi described the meeting as inconsequential, Trudeau painted it as a "brief exchange" in which he reiterated his concerns about the safety of Canadians and upholding the rule of law. "I won't go into details about what we talked about... the safety of Canadians is one of the fundamental responsibilities of any Canadian government," Trudeau said at a press conference.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence. In 2018, his visit to India, which was aimed at currying favour with a vote bank, rebounded to his discomfort. His Cabinet has included individuals who have openly associated with an extremist and separatist agenda regarding India. His naked interference in Indian internal politics in December 2020 showed how far he was willing to go in this regard. That his Government was dependent on a political party, whose leader openly espouses a separatist ideology vis-a-vis India, only aggravated matters," Centre's statement read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India has repeatedly highlighted its concerns over the flourishing pro-Khalistan movement in Canada, demanding that Canada take firm and verifiable action against those advocating violence and extremism. Indian officials have warned that the nexus between Khalistani extremists, organised crime, drug syndicates, and human trafficking should be a matter of concern for Canada as well.</p>

<p>"To that end, the Trudeau Government has consciously provided space to violent extremists and terrorists to harass, threaten and intimidate Indian diplomats and community leaders in Canada. This has included death threats to them and to Indian leaders. All these activities have been justified in the name of freedom of speech. Some individuals who have entered Canada illegally have been fast-tracked for citizenship. Multiple extradition requests from the Government of India in respect of terrorists and organized crime leaders living in Canada have been disregarded," the statement read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India has made it clear that repairing relations with Canada hinges on Ottawa's willingness to act against pro-Khalistan elements operating freely within its borders. Despite India's repeated diplomatic overtures, no concrete action has been forthcoming from Canada. In turn, Ottawa has expressed frustration over India's reluctance to participate in its investigation into Nijjar's death.</p>

<p>Canadian Foreign Minister Melanie Joly, in a recent testimony before the Public Inquiry into Foreign Interference, described the current state of relations with India as "tense" and "very difficult," further fueling speculation that ties between the two nations could worsen.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/122o7v0g_modi-trudeau-afp_625x300_23_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has repeatedly highlighted its concerns over the flourishing pro-Khalistan movement in Canada.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-military-encircles-taiwan-us-calls-it-unwarranted-6785647]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Military Encircles Taiwan, US Calls It "Unwarranted"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-military-encircles-taiwan-us-calls-it-unwarranted-6785647]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:00:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States said China's actions were "unwarranted" and risk "escalation" as it called on Beijing to act with restraint.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China deployed fighter jets and warships to encircle Taiwan on Monday in drills Beijing said were aimed at sending a "stern warning" to "separatist" forces on the self-ruled island.</p>

<p>Beijing has not ruled out using force to bring Taiwan under its control and Monday's drills represent its fourth round of large-scale war games in just over two years.</p>

<p>The United States said China's actions were "unwarranted" and risk "escalation" as it called on Beijing to act with restraint.</p>

<p>President Lai Ching-te, who took office in May, has been more outspoken than his predecessor Tsai Ing-wen in defending Taiwan's sovereignty, angering Beijing, which calls him a "separatist".</p>

<p>Lai vowed on Monday to "protect democratic Taiwan and safeguard national security", while the defence ministry said it dispatched "appropriate forces" in response to the drills.</p>

<p>Chinese foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning hit back, saying "Taiwan independence and peace in the Taiwan Strait are irreconcilable".</p>

<p>AFP journalists near the Hsinchu air force base, in the north of Taiwan, saw 12 fighter jets take off on Monday.</p>

<p>Outlying islands administered by Taipei were on "heightened alert" and "aircraft and ships will respond to enemy situations in accordance with the engagement rules", Taiwan's defence ministry said.</p>

<p>Beijing said its exercises served as a "stern warning to the separatist acts of 'Taiwan Independence' forces".</p>

<p>The drills, dubbed Joint Sword-2024B, are testing troops' "joint operations capabilities" according to Captain Li Xi, spokesman for the Chinese military's Eastern Theater Command.</p>

<p>They are taking place in "areas to the north, south and east of Taiwan Island", he said.</p>

<p>The drills are "focusing on subjects of sea-air combat-readiness patrol, blockade on key ports and areas", Li said.</p>

<p>They also practised an "assault on maritime and ground targets".</p>

<p>The Liaoning aircraft carrier group "with its troops of army, navy, air force and rocket force" was also involved, Li said.</p>

<p>The previous large-scale drills held in May, three days after Lai's inauguration, were called "Joint Sword-2024A" and lasted two days.</p>

<p><strong>China coast guard 'inspections'</strong></p>

<p>China's coast guard was also sent to conduct "inspections" around the island.</p>

<p>A diagram released by the coast guard showed four fleets encircling Taiwan and moving in an anti-clockwise direction around the island.</p>

<p>The coast guard of the eastern province of Fujian -- the closest area on the mainland to Taiwan -- also said it was conducting "comprehensive law enforcement patrols" in waters near the Taipei-controlled Matsu islands.</p>

<p>Taiwan said four "formations" of China coast guard ships were patrolling the island, but they had not entered its prohibited or restricted waters.</p>

<p>China has ramped up military activity around Taiwan in recent years, sending warplanes and other military aircraft while its ships maintain a near-constant presence around the island's waters.</p>

<p>"In the face of enemy threats, all officers and soldiers of the country are in full readiness," Taiwan's defence ministry said on Monday.</p>

<p>Lai convened a high-level security meeting over the drills, said Joseph Wu, secretary-general of the National Security Council, who described the exercises as "inconsistent with international law".</p>

<p>In his National Day speech on Thursday, Lai vowed to "resist annexation" and insisted that Beijing and Taipei were "not subordinate to each other".</p>

<p>Lai's Democratic Progressive Party has long defended the sovereignty and democracy of Taiwan, which has its own government, military and currency.</p>

<p>Beijing said on Monday the drills were "a legitimate and necessary operation for safeguarding state sovereignty and national unity".</p>

<p><strong>'Feel a bit numb'</strong></p>

<p>Lieutenant Colonel Fu Zhengnan, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Military Sciences, said in a video shared by state media that the drills could "switch from training to combat at any time".</p>

<p>"If Taiwan separatists provoke once, the PLA's operation around the island will make their first move," Fu said, referring to China's People's Liberation Army.</p>

<p>Taiwan's coast guard said on Monday it had detained a Chinese man on one of its outlying islands after a possible "grey zone intrusion", referring to tactics that fall short of a direct act of war.</p>

<p>In Taipei, people appeared to be largely unperturbed.</p>

<p>"I won't panic too much because they quite often have drills," 34-year-old engineer Benjamin Hsiao told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's not the first time in recent years anyway, so I feel a bit numb."</p>

<p>AFP journalists on Monday afternoon saw about five military jeeps mounted with machine guns patrolling around Taipei Songshan Airport, which is also a military air base.</p>

<p>The dispute between China and Taiwan dates back to a civil war in which the nationalist forces of Chiang Kai-shek were defeated by Mao Zedong's communist fighters and fled to the island in 1949.</p>

<p>China and Taiwan have been ruled separately since then.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pkjtugtg_china-military-drill-in-taiwan_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China deployed fighter jets and warships to encircle Taiwan on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-unacceptable-eu-slams-israel-attacks-on-lebanon-peacekeepers-6785537]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Completely Unacceptable": EU Slams Israel Attacks On Lebanon Peacekeepers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-unacceptable-eu-slams-israel-attacks-on-lebanon-peacekeepers-6785537]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:44:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A series of Israeli attacks have injured United Nations peacekeepers in southern Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The European Union's foreign policy chief Josep Borrell Monday denounced as "completely unacceptable" a series of Israeli attacks that have injured United Nations peacekeepers in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The 27 (EU) members agreed on asking (the) Israelis to stop attacking UNIFIL," Borrell told reporters ahead of a meeting of the bloc's foreign ministers in Luxembourg. "It's completely unacceptable attacking United Nations troops," he said.</p>

<p>At least five peacekeepers have been wounded in recent days as Israel targets Hezbollah in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>UNIFIL, a mission of about 9,500 troops of various nationalities created following Israel's 1978 invasion of Lebanon, has accused the Israeli military of "deliberately" firing on its positions.</p>

<p>"Many European members are participating in this mission," Borrell noted. "Their work is very important."</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called on UN chief Antonio Guterres Sunday to move peacekeepers deployed in south Lebanon out of "harm's way", saying Hezbollah was using them as "human shields".</p>

<p>UNIFIL has refused to leave its positions.</p>

<p><b>Also Read:&nbsp;</b><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/move-lebanon-peacekeepers-out-of-harms-way-right-now-netanyahu-to-un-6783635">"Move Lebanon Peacekeepers Out Of Harm's Way, Right Now": Netanyahu To UN</a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7241fc6g_un-peacekeepers-in-lebanon_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UNIFIL has refused to leave its positions in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-destroys-russian-military-transport-plane-6785471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Destroys Russian Military Transport Plane]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-destroys-russian-military-transport-plane-6785471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:18:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine has stepped up attacks inside Russian territory in recent months, targeting military sites and energy facilities, aiming to upend Russian military logistics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kyiv said Monday its forces had destroyed a Russian military transport plane stationed at an airfield deep inside Russian territory over the weekend, the latest Ukrainian claim of an attack behind Moscow's lines.</p>

<p>Ukraine has stepped up attacks inside Russian territory in recent months, targeting military sites and energy facilities, aiming to upend Russian military logistics.</p>

<p>Kyiv's military intelligence agency said it had destroyed the Tu-134 transport aircraft overnight between Saturday and Sunday at a military airfield in the Orenburg region, which lies around 1,000 kilometres (620 miles) from the border with Ukraine.</p>

<p>"These Soviet-built airplanes are used mainly to transport leadership of the Russian defence ministry," the Defence Intelligence of the Ministry of Defence of Ukraine said on social media.</p>

<p>The agency posted footage of what Ukraine said was an arson attack, showing a blaze burning inside an aircraft, but it did not provide details of how the alleged attack was carried out.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment on the specific claims from Moscow.</p>

<p>Since the start of its invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, Moscow has detained hundreds of people for alleged sabotage and arson attacks on military, railway and other infrastructure sites.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/riijiu7g_plane-generic_625x300_24_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kyiv's military intelligence agency destroyed Tu-134 transport aircraft. (Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-government-looks-at-new-immigration-law-in-2025-6785677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Government Looks At New Immigration Law In 2025]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-government-looks-at-new-immigration-law-in-2025-6785677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:07:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The French authorities want to adopt a new immigration law next year, a spokeswoman said, as the new right-wing government seeks to crack down on immigration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The French authorities want to adopt a new immigration law next year, a spokeswoman said, as the new right-wing government seeks to crack down on immigration.</p>

<p>"There will be a need for a new law," government spokeswoman Maud Bregeon told broadcaster BFMTV on Sunday.</p>

<p>The government's plan to tighten immigration policies and border controls is emblematic of the rightward shift in French politics following this summer's legislative elections that resulted in a hung parliament.</p>

<p>Michel Barnier's government hopes the bill will be submitted to parliament at the beginning of 2025.</p>

<p>In September, a Paris student was raped and murdered in a case that has further inflamed a French debate on migration after a Moroccan was named as the suspected attacker.</p>

<p>The government wants to extend the detention period for undocumented migrants deemed to be dangerous in order to better enforce expulsion orders.</p>

<p>One of the options under consideration is to increase the maximum period of detention from 90 to 210 days, which is now only possible for terrorist offences.</p>

<p>"We don't rule out the possibility of considering other provisions", said Bregeon, adding that there should be "no taboos when it comes to protecting the French."</p>

<p>Last December, France already passed an immigration law.</p>

<p>The bill was hardened to gain the support of the far-right and right-wing MPs.</p>

<p>But the country's highest constitutional authority censured most of the new amendments which were dropped before President Emmanuel Macron signed it into law.</p>

<p>The measures struck down by the Constitutional Council "will serve as a basis for the new immigration bill", a government source told AFP. "Some of them could be modified and there will be additions."</p>

<p>The most hardline member of the government, Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau, has vowed to crack down on immigration. He has stirred controversy just days into the job, saying that "the rule of law is neither intangible nor sacred".</p>

<p>Retailleau, who previously headed the Republicans party in the Senate, was seen as the driving force behind the tough legislation last year.</p>

<p>He wants to reinstate the offense of illegal residence, among other measures.</p>

<p>Gabriel Attal, Barnier's predecessor and now leader in parliament of Macron's Renaissance party, said on Monday that a new law on immigration did not seem a "total priority."</p>

<p>"Adopting a law for the sake of a law makes no sense," he told broadcaster France inter.</p>

<p>He said "the priority is to act so that the state can truly control who enters and leaves" France.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jioolhm_france-immigration-law_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[France Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau, has vowed to crack down on immigration.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-in-4-adults-suspect-undiagnosed-adhd-due-to-social-media-influence-study-6785298]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 In 4 Adults Suspect Undiagnosed ADHD Due To Social Media Influence: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-in-4-adults-suspect-undiagnosed-adhd-due-to-social-media-influence-study-6785298]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:04:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder -- also known as ADHD -- is typically thought of as a childhood condition, a new study on Monday showed that one in four or 25 per cent of adults in America suspect they may have it but is undiagnosed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder -- also known as ADHD -- is typically thought of as a childhood condition, a new study on Monday showed that one in four or 25 per cent of adults in America suspect they may have it but is undiagnosed.</p>

<p>The study based on a national survey of 1,000 American adults showed that social media videos helped adults to realise that their struggles with attention, focus, and restlessness could, in fact, be undiagnosed ADHD.</p>

<p>Worryingly, only 13 per cent of survey respondents have shared their suspicions with their doctor.</p>

<p>That's raising concerns about the consequences of self-diagnosis leading to incorrect treatment, said the team</p>

<p>"Anxiety, depression, and ADHD -- all these things can look a lot alike, but the wrong treatment can make things worse instead of helping that person feel better and improving their functioning," said psychologist Justin Barterian, clinical assistant professor in Ohio State University's Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Health.</p>

<p>An estimated 4.4 per cent of people ages 18 to 44 have ADHD, and some people aren't diagnosed until they're older, Barterian said.</p>

<p>"There's definitely more awareness of how it can continue to affect folks into adulthood and a lot of people who are realising, once their kids have been diagnosed, that they fit these symptoms as well, given that it's a genetic disorder," Barterian said.</p>

<p>Further, more than the older generations, younger adults were more likely to believe they have undiagnosed ADHD.</p>

<p>Barterian said while social media videos can help educate and bring awareness, "seek a psychologist or a psychiatrist or a physician" can help in proper diagnosis and further aid in the treatment of the condition.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/eblsc4h_adhd-generic-_625x300_14_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Younger adults were more likely to believe they had undiagnosed ADHD. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-vigilantes-behind-rise-in-online-blasphemy-cases-6784695]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan 'Vigilantes' Behind Rise In Online Blasphemy Cases]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-vigilantes-behind-rise-in-online-blasphemy-cases-6784695]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:36:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of young men are standing trial in Pakistan courts, accused of making blasphemous statements online or in WhatsApp groups, an offence for which arrests have exploded in recent years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Aroosa Khan's son was chatting on WhatsApp but suddenly found himself the target of "vigilante" investigators who accused him of having committed blasphemy online, a crime that carries the death penalty in Pakistan.</p>

<p>The 27-year-old is one in hundreds of young men standing trial in Pakistan courts accused of making blasphemous statements online or in WhatsApp groups, an offence for which arrests have exploded in recent years.</p>

<p>Many of the cases are being brought to trial by private "vigilante groups" led by lawyers and supported by volunteers who scour the internet for offenders, rights groups and police say.</p>

<p>The families of young Pakistanis, including doctors, engineers, lawyers, and accountants, say that their relatives were duped into sharing blasphemous content by strangers online before being arrested.</p>

<p>"Our lives have been turned upside down," Khan told AFP, saying that her son, who has not been named for security reasons, had been tricked into sharing blasphemous content in the messaging app.</p>

<p>One local police report suggests that the vigilantes may be motivated by financial gains.</p>

<p>One such group was responsible for the conviction of 27 people who have been sentenced to life imprisonment or the death penalty over the past three years.</p>

<p>Blasphemy is an incendiary charge in Muslim-majority Pakistan, where even unsubstantiated accusations can incite public outrage and lead to lynchings.</p>

<p>While they date back to colonial times, Pakistan's blasphemy laws were ramped up in the 1980s when dictator Zia ul-Haq campaigned to "Islamicise" society.</p>

<p>AFP has attended multiple court hearings in the capital Islamabad, where young men are being prosecuted by private vigilante groups and the FIA for blasphemous online content.</p>

<p>Among them is Aroosa's son -- who had joined a WhatsApp group for job-seekers and was contacted by a woman.</p>

<p>She sent him an image of women with Quranic verses printed on their bodies, his mother said, adding that the contact then "denied having sent it and asked Ahmed to send it back to her to understand what he was talking about".</p>

<p>He was later arrested and prosecuted by the Federal Investigation Agency (FIA).</p>

<p><strong>'Noble cause'</strong></p>

<p>The most active private investigation group is the Legal Commission on Blasphemy Pakistan (LCBP), which told AFP they are prosecuting more than 300 cases.</p>

<p>Sheraz Ahmad Farooqi, one of the private investigation group's leaders, told AFP that more than a dozen volunteers track online blasphemy, believing that "God has chosen them for this noble cause".</p>

<p>"We are not beheading anyone; we are following a legal course," Farooqi told AFP outside a courtroom that heard 15 blasphemy cases, all filed by his group.</p>

<p>He said that most of the accused were addicted to pornography and were disrespecting revered Islamic figures by using their names and dubbing voices attributed to them over pornographic content.</p>

<p>He acknowledged that women were involved in tracking and arresting the men, but they were not members of his group.</p>

<p>Cases can drag through the courts for years, though death penalties are often commuted to life in prison on appeal at the Supreme Court and Pakistan has never executed anyone for blasphemy.</p>

<p>A special court, attended by AFP, was formed in September to expedite the dozens of pending cases.</p>

<p><strong>'Vested agenda'</strong></p>

<p>The Human Rights Commission of Pakistan (HRCP) reported that multiple vigilante groups were working in a "dedicated manner" to "witch-hunt" people for online expression or to fabricate blasphemy evidence using social media with "vested agendas".</p>

<p>"All such groups are formalised by self-declared defenders of majoritarian Islam," the group said in a report published in 2023.</p>

<p>A 2024 report by police in Punjab province, the country's most populous province, that was leaked to the media said that "a suspicious gang was trapping youth in blasphemy cases".</p>

<p>"The Blasphemy Business" report was sent to the FIA with recommendations to launch a thorough inquiry to determine the source of the vigilante groups' funding.</p>

<p>Two FIA officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, told AFP that they had received the report but denied that their office was acting on the tips of vigilante groups.</p>

<p>The FIA did not respond to requests for official comment.</p>

<p>An official involved in prosecuting the cases told AFP outside the court: "Not a single person arrested was trapped by any manner. They committed the crime."</p>

<p>"The law is very clear about it, and we have to enforce it as long as the law is there."</p>

<p>Arafat Mazhar, the director of Alliance Against Blasphemy Politics, a group advocating against the misuse of blasphemy laws, told AFP that the alarming rise in cases was not because people "are suddenly more blasphemous".</p>

<p>He said the rise in the use of messaging apps and social media and the ease of sharing and forwarding content was a significant factor.</p>

<p><strong>Shunned</strong></p>

<p>The accused struggle to find defence lawyers willing to represent them and the slightest accusation can turn an entire family into pariahs.</p>

<p>Nafeesa Ahmed, whose brother is accused of sharing blasphemous images on WhatsApp and whose names have also been changed, said her family was shunned by close relatives.</p>

<p>"There is a massive cost that families of accused are bearing. First of all, our security or lives are at risk," she told AFP.</p>

<p>She said some of the families have sold thousands of dollars worth of houses and gold, given to brides on their wedding, to fight the cases.</p>

<p>Dozens of families which have formed a support group have protested in the capital calling for an independent commission to investigate the vigilante groups and their role in prosecuting Pakistanis for blasphemy.</p>

<p>"In this society, if someone commits a murder, he can survive because there are thousands of ways to come out of that but if someone is accused of blasphemy he cannot," said Nafeesa.</p>

<p>"When it comes to blasphemy, the public has its own court and even family members will abandon you."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h4om8a6o_pakistan-online-blasphemy-cases_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/seeing-double-in-twins-capital-of-world-almost-every-family-has-them-6784625]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Seeing Double In 'Twins Capital Of World': Almost Every Family Has Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/seeing-double-in-twins-capital-of-world-almost-every-family-has-them-6784625]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:24:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The global average birth rate for twins is around 12 per 1,000 births -- but in Igbo-Ora, it is thought to be closer to 50 per 1,000, according to scientific studies and hospital records.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On a normal day, a visitor might pass Igbo-Ora with little more than a double take, wondering why so many pairs of residents wear matching clothes.</p>

<p>But this weekend left nobody doubting what makes the town in southwest Nigeria special.</p>

<p>With fanfare, pageantry, talent shows and even a royal visit, hundreds of people gathered in the self-proclaimed "twins capital of the world" to celebrate its unusually high rate of multiple births.</p>

<p>"There's hardly a family here in Igbo-Ora that doesn't have a twin," said visiting Yoruba king Oba Kehinde Gbadewole Olugbenle, himself a twin.</p>

<p>Yoruba culture reveres twins and their first names are traditionally fixed -- Taiwo meaning 'one that tastes the world' for the eldest child, and Kehinde meaning 'one that came after' for the second-born.</p>

<p>The town stands out even in the wider Yorubaland region, which boasts an above-average incidence of non-identical twins, according to population experts.</p>

<p>The global average birth rate for twins is around 12 per 1,000 births -- but in Igbo-Ora, it is thought to be closer to 50 per 1,000, according to scientific studies and hospital records.</p>

<p>Explanations for the abundance differ.</p>

<p>Many residents put it down to diet, especially okra leaf or ilasa soup with yam and amala (cassava flour).</p>

<p>Fertility experts -- and several residents -- are sceptical, saying there is no proven link between diet and the high twin rate.</p>

<p>Scientists are looking into genetic factors, and how the twins' special cultural status might make them more likely to find partners and have children.</p>

<p><strong>'Gift from God'</strong></p>

<p>Whatever the reason, everyone in the town agrees the abundance of twins is a blessing -- even more so this year as Nigeria grapples with its worst economic crisis in a generation.</p>

<p>Suliat Mobolaji gave birth to twins eight months ago and said the family had been showered with gifts ever since.</p>

<p>"It's changed my life," the 30-year-old said, clutching a son in each arm.</p>

<p>"You can't give birth to twins and remain down on your luck," she beamed. "It's a gift from God."</p>

<p>Taiwo Ojewale, a research assistant specialising in Yoruba culture at the University of Ibadan, said celebrating twins was "rooted in traditional religious belief."</p>

<p>Twins are seen as a gift from the supreme god Olodumare, he explained, and Igbo-Ora's oral history describes them as a reward following a series of disasters that befell the community.</p>

<p>The town erupted with joy as the event began on Saturday. At the festival ground, staff rolled out a red carpet for scores of twins both young and old.</p>

<p>They paraded in immaculate matching outfits -- from glamorous sunglasses and patterned adire fabric to a pair of toddlers sporting purple dresses and identical handbags.</p>

<p>Dozens more twins watched from the stands or milled side by side around town.</p>

<p>The festival's organisers -- themselves twins -- say they eventually want to attempt a world record for the largest gathering of twins on the planet.</p>

<p>Taiwo and Kehinde Oguntoye, 39, also said they hope to stage a mass wedding of twin couples next year.</p>

<p>"Twins bring favours, fame and wealth," said Taiwo. "That's why we Yoruba celebrate their birth, and maybe that is the reason why God blessed us in Yorubaland with the highest number of twins in the world."</p>

<p>"It's a blessing," the Oguntoye twins nodded, speaking in unison.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dcmrk8t8_nigeria-twin-festival_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-life-possible-on-europa-jupiter-moon-nasa-to-investigate-6784571]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is Life Possible On Europa, Jupiter Moon? NASA To Investigate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-life-possible-on-europa-jupiter-moon-nasa-to-investigate-6784571]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:14:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Europa Clipper mission will allow the US space agency to uncover new details about the moon, which scientists believe could hold an ocean of liquid water beneath its icy surface.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is there anywhere else in our solar system that could support life? An imposing NASA probe is due to lift off on Monday on a five-and-a-half-year journey to Europa, one of Jupiter's many moons, to take the first detailed step toward finding out.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We're going on a 1.8-billion-mile journey to an ocean world – Jupiter moon, Europa!<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/EuropaClipper?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@EuropaClipper</a> is set to launch on Monday, Oct. 14, on a <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SpaceX</a> Falcon Heavy rocket at 12:06pm ET (1606 UTC) from <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAKennedy?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NASAKennedy</a>. Use <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AskNASA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AskNASA</a> to send us your questions. <a href="https://t.co/o3xgleA6Z3">https://t.co/o3xgleA6Z3</a></p>
— NASA (@NASA) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1845656805948506250?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The Europa Clipper mission will allow the US space agency to uncover new details about the moon, which scientists believe could hold an ocean of liquid water beneath its icy surface.</p>

<p>Lift off is scheduled for "no earlier than" Monday, October 14, from Cape Canaveral in Florida aboard a powerful SpaceX Falcon Heavy rocket, NASA said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Europa is one of the most promising places to look for life beyond Earth," said NASA official Gina DiBraccio at a news conference last month.</p>

<p>The mission will not look directly for signs of life but will instead look to answer the question: Does Europa contain the ingredients that would allow life to be present?</p>

<p>If it does, another mission would then have to make the journey to try and detect it.</p>

<p>"It's a chance for us to explore not a world that might have been habitable billions of years ago," like Mars, Europa Clipper program scientist Curt Niebur told reporters last month, "but a world that might be habitable today, right now."</p>

<p>The probe is the largest ever designed by NASA for interplanetary exploration.</p>

<p>It is 30 meters wide when its immense solar panels -- designed to capture the weak light that reaches Jupiter -- are fully extended.</p>

<p><strong>Primitive life?</strong></p>

<p>While Europa's existence has been known since 1610, the first close-up images were taken by the Voyager probes in 1979, which revealed mysterious reddish lines crisscrossing its surface.</p>

<p>The next probe to reach Jupiter's icy moon was NASA's Galileo probe in the 1990s, which found it was highly likely that the moon was home to an ocean.</p>

<p>This time, the Europa Clipper probe will carry a host of sophisticated instruments, including cameras, a spectrograph, radar, and a magnetometer to measure its magnetic forces.</p>

<p>The mission will look to determine the structure and composition of Europa's icy surface, its depth, and even the salinity of its ocean, as well as the way the two interact -- to find out, for example, if water rises to the surface in places.</p>

<p>The aim is to understand whether the three ingredients necessary for life are present: water, energy and certain chemical compounds.</p>

<p>If these conditions exist on Europa, life could be found in the ocean in the form of primitive bacteria, explained Bonnie Buratti, the mission's deputy project scientist.</p>

<p>But the bacteria would likely be too deep for the Europa Clipper to see.</p>

<p>And what if Europa isn't habitable after all? "That also opens up a whole wealth of questions: Why did we think this? And why is it not there?" said Nikki Fox, an associate administrator at NASA.</p>

<p><strong>49 flybys</strong></p>

<p>The probe will cover 2.9 billion kilometers (1.8 billion miles) during its journey to Jupiter, with arrival expected in April 2030.</p>

<p>The main mission will last another four years.</p>

<p>The probe will make 49 close flybys over Europa, coming as close as 25 kilometers (16 miles) above the surface.</p>

<p>It will be subjected to intense radiation -- the equivalent of several million chest x-rays on each pass.</p>

<p>Some 4,000 people have been working on the $5.2 billion mission for around a decade.</p>

<p>NASA says the investment is justified by the importance of the data that will be collected.</p>

<p>If our solar system turns out to be home to two habitable worlds (Europa and Earth), "think of what that means when you extend that result to the billions and billions of other solar systems in this galaxy," said Niebur, the Europa Clipper program scientist.</p>

<p>"Setting aside the 'Is there life?' question on Europa, just the habitability question in and of itself opens up a huge new paradigm for searching for life in the galaxy," he added.</p>

<p>The Europa Clipper will operate at the same time as the European Space Agency's (ESA) Juice probe, which will study two other moons of Jupiter -- Ganymede and Callisto.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ij4kl9t8_europa-jupiter-moon_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Does Europa contain the ingredients that would allow life to be present?]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-do-you-want-me-to-rape-you-afghan-taekwondo-athlete-harassed-for-speaking-against-taliban-6784564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Afghan Taekwondo Champion Faces Death Threats For Criticizing Taliban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-do-you-want-me-to-rape-you-afghan-taekwondo-athlete-harassed-for-speaking-against-taliban-6784564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:12:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 21-year-old Afghan Taekwondo champion has received over 5,000 threat calls and messages for criticising the Taliban's ban on women's sports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 21-year-old Afghan Taekwondo champion has received over 5,000 threat calls and messages for criticising the Taliban's ban on women's sports. Marzieh Hamidi, who now lives in Paris under police protection, was targeted and harassed online after she suggested the Afghan men's cricket team didn't represent women in her country.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
“Taekwondo gives me more identity as a woman,” Ms Hamidi told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/13/sport/marzieh-hamidi-afghanistan-taekwondo-spt-intl/index.html ">CNN</a>. She condemned the Taliban-controlled Afghan men's cricket team as “the Taliban team for me, not the Afghan team,” calling for a ban on all Afghan sports teams from international competitions.</p>

<p>In Afghanistan, women are prohibited from participating in sports, forcing many female athletes to compete as refugees or without official support. This contrast in treatment between male and female athletes points out the ongoing gender apartheid imposed by the Taliban, according to Richard Bennett, UN Special Rapporteur for Human Rights in Afghanistan. “They have created a situation where women and girls are unable to participate as full human beings in society,” he said.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Taliban sympathisers targeted Ms Hamidi for comments on the cricket team.&nbsp; "We have your location. We will share it for the highest bidder," one message read. “Where do you want me to rape you?” read another.<br />
<br />
A user recently warned, “I only have 3 months left until my money is ready, then I can go directly to Paris and there I will cut your head off.” The Paris prosecutor's office has launched an investigation into these threats.<br />
<br />
Ms Hamidi has also faced scrutiny for her Western-style dress and public presence. “They are criticising Marzieh Hamidi for being a woman, for speaking in public,” said her lawyer, Ines Davau.<br />
<br />
“In Afghanistan, women are not allowed to be women,” Ms Hamidi told CNN. “They do not exist.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm launching this hashtag <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LetUsExist?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#LetUsExist</a> to protest against the gender apartheid in Afghanistan and im inviting all of you to support Afghanistani women and to fight for gender equality ! <a href="https://t.co/ZPwv0DD1aL">pic.twitter.com/ZPwv0DD1aL</a></p>
— marzieh hamidi (@MarziehHamidi) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarziehHamidi/status/1828090877493043596?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Despite the dangers she faces, she is determined. “They want to make us invisible in Afghanistan, I want to show them that we are strong,” she said.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Marzieh Hamidi is not alone in her struggle. Fellow Afghan athletes, including breakdancer Manizha Talash, have faced punitive actions for their protests against the Taliban's treatment of women. Ms Talash was disqualified from the Paris Olympics after unveiling a cape inscribed with the words “Free Afghan Women.” Similarly, sprinter Kimia Yousofi carried a message for education and rights during her events.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k3f9e1eg_marzieh-hamidi_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marzieh Hamidi is not alone in her struggle to end gender apartheid in Afghanistan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-journalist-who-went-missing-a-year-ago-dies-in-russian-detention-kyiv-confirms-6784397]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Journalist Dies In Russian Detention, Kyiv Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-journalist-who-went-missing-a-year-ago-dies-in-russian-detention-kyiv-confirms-6784397]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 10:47:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian journalist Victoria Roshchyna disappeared in August 2022 during a reporting mission in Russian-controlled territory, and her whereabouts remained unknown for months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian journalist Victoria Roshchyna, who went missing over a year ago, has died in Russian detention, <a href="http://https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/13/europe/missing-ukrainian-journalist-dies-russia-intl/index.html">CNN</a> reported. The 27-year-old disappeared in August 2022 during a reporting mission from a Russian-controlled territory of Ukraine.</p>

<p>The Office of the Ukrainian Prosecutor General said that Moscow informed Ms Roshchyna's family of her detention in April this year, long after her capture. The family was left in the dark for months about her fate.</p>

<p>“I have official documentation from the Russian side confirming the death of Ukrainian journalist Victoria Roshchyna, who was illegally deprived of her liberty by Russia,” Ukraine's human rights commissioner, Dmytro Lubinets, said in a statement.</p>

<p>According to a statement by the spokesperson of the Delegation of the European Commission to Ukraine, “She is the thirteenth journalist to be killed since the start of Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine.” The statement further noted that Ms Roshchyna, a recipient of the “Courage in Journalism Award,” was “determined to bring the truth about Russia's brutal war of aggression and its illegal occupation of Ukraine to the world.”</p>

<p>Ms Roshchyna's fellow journalists said she travelled to the Russian-occupied region to report on the condition of the people living under the occupation. Her colleagues believe she was killed by Russian officials.</p>

<p>“We have every reason to believe that her death was either the result of a deliberate murder or the result of the cruel treatment and violence to which she was subjected during her time in Russian captivity,” read a statement from Ukrainian media professionals, published across several Ukrainian outlets.</p>

<p>The statement noted that Ms Roshchyna was in good health before her imprisonment over a year ago. The Ukrainian Prosecutor General's Office launched an investigation, treating her death as both a war crime and a premeditated murder.</p>

<p>Evgeniya Motorevskaya, who previously worked with Ms Roshchyna at the Ukrainian media outlet Hromadske, remembered her as a journalist deeply committed to her craft. In a statement published on Hromadske's website, she said using Ms Roshchyna's nickname, “For her, there was nothing more important than journalism. Vika was always where the most important events for the country took place. And she would have continued to do this for many years, but the Russians killed her.”</p>

<p>Petro Yatsenko, spokesperson for the Ukrainian Coordination Center for the Treatment of Prisoners of War, said that Ms Roshchyna was among around 25 Ukrainian journalists currently held in Russian captivity, with several others reported missing.</p>

<p>Russian authorities reportedly told Ukrainian officials that Ms Roshchyna died while being transferred from a detention centre in Taganrog, a city in southern Russia, to Moscow. The transfer was said to be part of preparations for her release in a prisoner exchange.<br />
<br />
The detention facility in Taganrog has gained notoriety for its harsh conditions, according to the CNN report. Tetyana Katrychenko, a representative of the Media Initiative for Human Rights, described it as “hell on earth” in a statement. She confirmed that Victoria Roshchyna was held there from at least May to September 2024 when she was subjected to solitary confinement.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/46boic1o_ukrainian-journalist-victoria-roshchyna_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukrainian journalist Victoria Roshchyna]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-donald-trump-release-your-medical-records-6784346]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trump Should Do The Same": Harris After Releasing Medical Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-donald-trump-release-your-medical-records-6784346]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 10:39:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris urged voters to question Donald Trumps transparency regarding his health and policy plans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat US presidential nominee Kamala Harris today challenged her Republican rival Donald Trump to release his medical records, a day after she was found in "excellent health" and fit for the presidency.</p>

<p>"Yesterday, I released my medical records. Donald Trump should do the same," she wrote on X.<br />
<br />
“I invite the public to watch his rallies and be the decision maker on his acuity,” she said in the video attached to the tweet.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yesterday, I released my medical records. Donald Trump should do the same. <a href="https://t.co/GWXn7CPaTM">pic.twitter.com/GWXn7CPaTM</a></p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1845648263166259347?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>At a rally in North Carolina, she also urged voters to question Trump's transparency regarding his health and policy plans. She claimed that crucial information was needed for making informed choices in the upcoming election.<br />
<br />
“Check this out,” Harris said during the rally. “He refuses to release his medical records. I've done it. Every other presidential candidate in the modern era has done it.”</p>

<p>Harris's comments highlight the age gap between her and Trump, who at 78 is the oldest presidential nominee in US history.<br />
<br />
She also criticised Trump for declining to participate in a second debate and for cancelling an interview with CBS News' “60 Minutes.”<br />
<br />
“He is unwilling to meet for a second debate,” Harris said in the rally. “And here's the thing, it makes you wonder. Why does his staff want him to hide away? One must question, are they afraid that people will see that he is too weak and unstable to lead America?”<br />
<br />
Kamala Harris' medical report, released on Saturday, describes her as a "healthy 59-year-old female" with seasonal allergies and urticaria (hives). In contrast, Donald Trump's medical history remains undisclosed.<br />
<br />
Trump previously indicated he would release his medical records, telling CBS News in August, “Oh sure, I would do that very gladly.”<br />
<br />
However, the Trump campaign released a statement on Saturday, with a letter from his physician confirming he was in “excellent” overall health, with physical exams in the “normal range” and “exceptional” cognitive test results. The Trump campaign also included two letters from Ronny Jackson, Trump's former White House physician, providing updates on Trump's condition following his gunshot wound in July.<br />
<br />
Kamala Harris is keenly focused on North Carolina, a crucial battleground state that hasn't voted for a Democratic presidential nominee since Barack Obama in 2008. Polls indicate that North Carolina is a toss-up, and a Democratic win could complicate Trump's path to the 270 electoral votes required for victory.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a34kj30g_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris's comments highlight the age gap between her and 78-year-old Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-set-to-blow-up-cross-border-roads-with-south-seoul-6784293]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Set To Blow Up Cross-Border Roads With South: Seoul]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-set-to-blow-up-cross-border-roads-with-south-seoul-6784293]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 10:28:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea on Friday accused South Korea of sending drones to scatter a "huge number" of anti-North leaflets over Pyongyang.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea is getting ready to blow up roads that cross the heavily militarised border with South Korea, Seoul said on Monday, amid an escalating war of words after the North accused its rival of sending drones over its capital Pyongyang.</p>

<p>North Korean troops were working under camouflage on the roads on its side of the border near the west and east coasts that are likely preparations to blow up the roads, possibly as early as on Monday, South Korea's military spokesman said.</p>

<p>Last week, North Korea's Army said it would completely cut roads and railways connected to South Korea and fortify the areas on its side of the border, state media KCNA reported.</p>

<p>Separately, North Korea on Friday accused South Korea of sending drones to scatter a "huge number" of anti-North leaflets over Pyongyang, in what it called a political and military provocation that could lead to armed conflict.</p>

<p>Lee Sung-jun, a spokesman for the South's Joint Chiefs of Staff, declined on Monday to answer questions over whether the South Korean military or civilians flew the drones.</p>

<p>In further statements over the weekend, North Korea warned of a "horrible disaster" if South Korean drones were again found to be flying over Pyongyang. On Sunday, it said it has put eight fully armed artillery units at the border "on standby to open fire."</p>

<p>South Korea's military has said its refusal to answer questions on the drones is because addressing what the North has alleged would be to get drawn into a tactic by Pyongyang to fabricate excuses for provocations.</p>

<p>South Korea has sought to boost its anti-drone defences since 2022, Lee said, when five North Korean drones entered its airspace and flew over the capital Seoul for several hours.</p>

<p>Lee Kyoung-haing, an expert in military drone operations at Jungwon University, said civilians would have no trouble getting drones with ranges of 300 km (186 miles), the round trip from the South to Pyongyang, with light payloads such as leaflets.</p>

<p>On Sunday, North Korea's defence ministry said the drones, which it said were detected over Pyongyang on three days earlier this month, were the kind that required a special launcher or a runway and it was impossible a civilian group could launch them.</p>

<p>The two Koreas are still technically at war after their 1950-53 war ended in an armistice, not a peace treaty.</p>

<p>The cross-border links are remnants of periods of rapprochement between the countries including a 2018 summit between the leaders when they declared there would be no more war and a new era of peace had opened.</p>

<p>North Korea has reintroduced heavy weapons into the Demilitarized Zone border buffer and restored guard posts, after the two sides declared a 2018 military agreement aimed at easing tensions no longer valid.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/brql7pc_north-korea-soldiers_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korean soldiers are seen at their guard post inside North Korean territory.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-genetic-study-says-christopher-columbus-may-have-hidden-sephardic-jewish-heritage-6784242]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[DNA Study Shows Christopher Columbus Was A Jew From Spain]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-genetic-study-says-christopher-columbus-may-have-hidden-sephardic-jewish-heritage-6784242]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 10:19:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The research, led by Spanish scientists suggests Christopher Columbus concealed Sephardic Jewish roots to escape persecution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Famed explorer Christopher Columbus was not Italian, as traditionally believed, but possibly a Sephardic Jew from Spain who concealed his true heritage to avoid persecution, a new genetic study suggests.<br />
<br />
The research, led by Spanish scientists, aims to resolve long-standing uncertainty surrounding Columbus' background. For years, historians have debated the birthplace of the 15th-century navigator, said to have hailed from Genoa, a republic on Italy's northwest coast. However, DNA analysis of Columbus' remains, housed in Seville Cathedral, has produced compelling evidence challenging this narrative, according to a report in the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckg2049ezpko">BBC</a>.<br />
<br />
“We have DNA from Christopher Columbus, very partial but sufficient. We have DNA from Hernando Colón, his son. And both in the Y [male] chromosome and in the mitochondrial DNA [from the mother] of Hernando there are traits compatible with Jewish origin,” Forensic expert and investigator Miguel Lorente said in a documentary titled, Columbus DNA: The True Origin, which aired in Spain recently.<br />
<br />
The research began in 2003 when forensic medicine professor José Antonio Lorente from Granada University, alongside historian Marcial Castro, exhumed what were thought to be Columbus' remains from Seville Cathedral. Their findings, supported by historical context, suggest that Columbus may have hidden his Jewish roots or converted to Catholicism to avoid the religious persecution prevalent in Spain at the time.<br />
<br />
Although researchers have yet to pinpoint Columbus' exact birthplace, they believe it is likely somewhere in Western Europe, with Valencia, Spain, as a strong possibility, according to a report in the New York Post.<br />
<br />
The term “Sephardic” derives from Sefarad, the Hebrew word for Spain. The DNA results, described by Lorente as “almost absolutely reliable,” dismiss numerous alternative theories about Columbus' origins, including claims that he may have been born in countries such as Poland, Portugal or even Scandinavia.<br />
<br />
<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/columbus-final-resting-place-revealed-researchers-to-confirm-ethnicity-6774619">Columbus</a> is best known for his expeditions across the Atlantic, backed by the Spanish monarchy, in search of a new route to Asia. Instead, he made landfall in the Caribbean, igniting a wave of European exploration that would eventually lead to the colonisation of the Americas. While his voyages were significant for their historical impact, they have also been the subject of controversy due to the devastating consequences for the native populations of the Americas. His crew reportedly brutally treated indigenous people. According to a report in <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/history/2019/10/14/here-are-indigenous-people-christopher-columbus-his-men-could-not-annihilate/">The Washington Post</a>, Columbus' men were known to have maimed and enslaved local people, including children.<br />
<br />
Columbus died in 1506 in Valladolid, Spain, and his remains were moved multiple times over the centuries before finally resting in Seville.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-05/b5i484v_christopher-columbus-pixabay_625x300_19_May_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The research aims to resolve long-standing uncertainty surrounding Columbus' background.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thaad-explained-the-advanced-missile-defense-system-the-us-is-deploying-to-israel-6784124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is THAAD, The Advanced US Anti-Missile Battery Being Sent To Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thaad-explained-the-advanced-missile-defense-system-the-us-is-deploying-to-israel-6784124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 10:09:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States has deployed one of its most advanced missile defence systems, the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD), along with 100 US troops to Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States has deployed one of its most advanced missile defence systems, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-israel-awaits-thaad-anti-missile-system-from-us-as-hezbollah-ups-strikes-6784117">Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD)</a>, along with 100 US troops to Israel. The move came in response to a recent barrage of Iranian missile strikes on Israel, retaliating for the assassinations of key Iranian and Hezbollah leaders.</p>

<h2><strong>What is THAAD?</strong></h2>

<p>The THAAD is a state-of-the-art missile defence system designed to counter short, medium and intermediate-range ballistic missile threats. It is the only US system capable of intercepting targets inside and outside the atmosphere. THAAD undergoes continuous improvements to enhance its effectiveness against evolving threats.</p>

<h2><strong>Why THAAD?</strong></h2>

<p>The Joe Biden administration came to Israel's rescue to protect the country against ballistic missile attacks from Iran or its proxies. With Israel preparing to respond to Iran, particularly following the death of Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah, the deployment of THAAD bolsters Israel's defences.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-iran-hamas-sought-irans-help-for-israel-attack-planned-9-11-style-bombing-report-6779663">A 9/11-Style Bombing Plan Was Scrapped Before Hamas Launched Israel Attack</a></p>

<p>Iranian authorities, meanwhile, warned that any Israeli aggression, including potential strikes on Tehran's nuclear facilities, would provoke a forceful response. In light of these escalating threats, Israel requested US support for arms and ammunition, something it has solicited over the last year in its war against Gaza, killing nearly 45,000 people and displacing the entire population.</p>

<p>Not too long ago, its attacks on Lebanon also killed nearly 2,500 people and injured 10,000 others.</p>

<h2><strong>How does THAAD work?</strong></h2>

<p>THAAD is designed to intercept incoming ballistic missiles during the "terminal phase" of their flight - the final stage before impact. This system can target missiles both inside and outside the atmosphere (endoatmospheric and exoatmospheric). THAAD defends against short, medium and intermediate-range ballistic missiles, making it highly adaptable to various types of missile threats.</p>

<p>A unique feature of the system is that it does not carry explosive warheads. Instead, it destroys targets using kinetic energy, meaning it hits incoming missiles with force rather than detonating a warhead.</p>

<h2><strong>Components of THAAD</strong></h2>

<p><strong>THAAD is composed of four main elements:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Interceptor: Destroys incoming missiles using impact force.</li>
	<li>Launch vehicle: Mobile trucks that carry and launch the interceptors.</li>
	<li>Radar: Tracks and detects threats from a range of 870 to 3,000 km.</li>
	<li>Fire control system: Coordinates the launching and targeting of interceptors.</li>
</ul>

<p>A standard THAAD battery includes six truck-mounted launchers, each carrying up to eight interceptors, along with radar and radio equipment. Reloading each launcher takes about 30 minutes, and a full battery requires 95 US soldiers to operate.</p>

<h2><strong>US role in THAAD deployment</strong></h2>

<p>One of the critical aspects of THAAD is that it is exclusively operated by US personnel. If deployed in Israel, this would require the presence of US troops on Israeli soil. The US Army currently possesses seven THAAD batteries deployed in various global conflict zones as part of its defensive strategy.</p>

<p>The decision to send THAAD to Israel made just weeks before the US presidential election, marks the first major US military deployment to Israel since the country started bombing Gaza.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8hngd92o_thaad-reuters-_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The THAAD is a state-of-the-art missile defence system.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>