<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:02:26 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/social-media-users-blast-spotify-for-leaning-into-ai-for-2024-wrapped-so-underwhelming-7183436]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Social Media Users Blast Spotify For Leaning Into AI For 2024 'Wrapped']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/social-media-users-blast-spotify-for-leaning-into-ai-for-2024-wrapped-so-underwhelming-7183436]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:58:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Social media users have lashed out at Spotify for leaning into AI and creating something that did not feel like 'Wrapped' of the previous years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spotify dropped its highly-anticipated, yearly 'Wrapped' on Wednesday (Dec 4) but the listeners have been left disappointed at what turned out to be a 'bland' and 'disappointing' effort from the streaming giant. This year's Spotify Wrapped did not provide listeners with their top music genres, or their top albums. Instead, an odd surprise, termed "wrapped AI podcast" was served which used Google's NotebookLM technology to verbally recap users' listening habits. The bizarre addition featured artificial intelligence (AI) voices elaborating on the data points mentioned in the Wrapped.</p>

<p>The users have since taken to social media to lash out at Spotify for heavily leaning into AI and creating something that did not feel like <em>Wrapped </em>of the previous years.</p>

<p>"Spotify wrapped is so underwhelming and reeks of AI…there seems to be real lack of effort this year from the boring visuals to the missing genres and quirks," said one user, while another added: "Hi I'm just here to remind you all that AI is going to ruin the world and spotify wrapped is the perfect dramatic example of that."</p>

<p>A third added: "So apparently spotify fired a lot of workers and used AI to create this year's Wrapped, no wonder it suck."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">spotify wrapped is underwhelming and reeks of ai… there seems to be real lack of effort this year from the boring visuals to the missing genres and quirks</p>
— ali (@twigsalterego) <a href="https://twitter.com/twigsalterego/status/1864307878665896034?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">spotify wrapped is underwhelming and reeks of ai… there seems to be real lack of effort this year from the boring visuals to the missing genres and quirks</p>
— ali (@twigsalterego) <a href="https://twitter.com/twigsalterego/status/1864307878665896034?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">hi i'm just here to remind you all that AI is going to ruin the world and spotify wrapped is the perfect dramatic example of that. AI cannot replace creative individuals.</p>
— bre (@relaxitsbre) <a href="https://twitter.com/relaxitsbre/status/1864847569748418760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Last year, Spotify gave listeners their own custom “Sound Town,” matching their music tastes to real-world locations, which received widespread acclaim. However, this year, users were given a "music Evolution" list that details a selection of bizarrely titled musical micro-genres. From "Coastal Grandmother Fingerstyle Yacht Rock" to "Boujee Football Rap" to "Pink Pilates Princess Roller Skating Pop" - the listeners were left confused as to what the descriptions meant.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">What the hell is this <a href="https://t.co/SAKOYVEhiH">pic.twitter.com/SAKOYVEhiH</a></p>
— j aubrey ? (@jaubreyYT) <a href="https://twitter.com/jaubreyYT/status/1864407833820680632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">yeah no for sure <a href="https://t.co/jgAXZXoKoQ">pic.twitter.com/jgAXZXoKoQ</a></p>
— kurtis conner (@kurtisconner) <a href="https://twitter.com/kurtisconner/status/1864340810998640799?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>While it is not clear if AI was involved in the use of Wrapped, Spotify in a statement said this year's year-ender was intended to make it "more about the users" with the "AI experiences".</p>

<p>"Through the combination of Spotify's powerful personalization technology and generative AI, we've created hyper-personalized Wrapped experiences that connect millions of listeners worldwide with the music and audio they love," Spotify said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasrallahs-dead-sinwars-dead-pt-ii-idf-shares-its-spotify-wrapped-7176225" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | 'Dead', 'Bye Bye Bye': Israel's Joke 'Spotify Wrapped' List Sparks Row</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>What is Spotify Wrapped?</strong></h3>

<p>Spotify Wrapped is a viral marketing campaign by the Swedish company, released annually since 2016 at the end of November or the start of December. It allows users to view a compilation of their listening activity that typically includes five top songs, singers they listened to the most and musical genres that resonated with them.</p>

<p>A colourful pictorial representation of the data across various slides is presented which the users can later post on social media.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/up5t76o_spotify-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/billionaires-wealth-more-than-doubles-in-10-years-swiss-bank-ubs-7183324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Billionaires' Wealth More Than Doubles In 10 Years: Swiss Bank UBS]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/billionaires-wealth-more-than-doubles-in-10-years-swiss-bank-ubs-7183324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:27:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaires have seen their combined wealth shoot up 121 percent over the past decade to $14 trillion, Swiss bank UBS said Thursday, with tech billionaires' coffers filling the fastest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaires have seen their combined wealth shoot up 121 percent over the past decade to $14 trillion, Swiss bank UBS said Thursday, with tech billionaires' coffers filling the fastest.</p>

<p>Switzerland's biggest bank, which is among the world's largest wealth managers, said the number of dollar billionaires increased from 1,757 to 2,682 over the past 10 years, peaking in 2021 with 2,686.</p>

<p>The 10th edition of UBS's annual Billionaire Ambitions report, which tracks the wealth of the world's richest people, found that billionaires have comfortably outperformed global equity markets over the past decade.</p>

<p>The report documents "the growth and investment of great wealth, as well as how it's being preserved for future generations and used to have a positive effect on society", said Benjamin Cavalli, head of strategic clients at UBS global wealth management.</p>

<p>Between 2015 and 2024, total billionaire wealth increased by 121 percent from $6.3 trillion to $14.0 trillion -- while the MSCI AC World Index of global equities rose 73 percent.</p>

<p><strong>Tech wealth</strong></p>

<p>The wealth of tech billionaires increased the fastest, followed by that of industrialists.</p>

<p>Worldwide, tech billionaires' wealth tripled from $788.9 billion in 2015 to $2.4 trillion in 2024.</p>

<p>"In earlier years, the new billionaires commercialised e-commerce, social media and digital payments; more recently they engineered the generative AI boom, while also developing cyber-security, fintech, 3D printing and robotics," UBS said.</p>

<p>The report found that since 2020, the global growth trend had slowed due to declines among China's billionaires.</p>

<p>From 2015 to 2020, billionaire wealth grew globally at an annual rate of 10 percent, but growth has plunged to one percent since 2020.</p>

<p>Chinese billionaire wealth more than doubled from 2015 to 2020, rising from $887.3 billion to $2.1 trillion, but has since fallen back to $1.8 trillion.</p>

<p>However, North American billionaire wealth has risen 58.5 percent to $6.1 trillion since 2020, "led by industrials and tech billionaires".</p>

<p>Meanwhile billionaires are relocating more frequently, with 176 having moved country since 2020, with Switzerland, the United Arab Emirates, Singapore and the United States being popular destinations.</p>

<p><strong>268 new billionaires in 2024</strong></p>

<p>In 2024, some 268 people became billionaires for the first time, with 60 percent of them entrepreneurs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The year's new billionaires were mainly self-made," said UBS.</p>

<p>The report said US billionaires accrued the greatest gains in 2024, reinforcing the country's place as the world's main centre for billionaire entrepreneurs.</p>

<p>Their wealth rose 27.6 percent to $5.8 trillion, or more than 40 percent of billionaire wealth worldwide.</p>

<p>Billionaires' wealth from mainland China and Hong Kong fell 16.8 percent to $1.8 trillion, with the number of billionaires dropping from 588 to 501.</p>

<p>Indian billionaires' wealth increased 42.1 percent to $905.6 billion, while their number grew from 153 to 185.</p>

<p>Western Europe's total billionaire wealth rose 16.0 percent to $2.7 trillion -- partly due to a 24 percent increase in Swiss billionaires.</p>

<p>UAE billionaires' aggregate wealth rose 39.5 percent to $138.7 billion.</p>

<p><strong>Next 10 years</strong></p>

<p>UBS said billionaires faced an "uncertain world" over the next 10 years, due to high geopolitical tensions, trade barriers and governments with mounting spending requirements.</p>

<p>Billionaires will therefore need to rely on their previous distinctive traits: "smart risk-taking, business focus and determination".</p>

<p>"Risk-taking billionaires are likely to be at the forefront of creating two technology-related industries of the future already taking shape: generative AI and renewables/electrification," UBS predicted.</p>

<p>And more flexible wealth planning will be needed as billionaire families move country and spread around the world.</p>

<p>The heirs and philanthropic causes of baby boom billionaires are set to inherit an estimated $6.3 trillion over the next 15 years, UBS said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/d86hesno_swiss-bank-ubs-reuters_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The wealth of tech billionaires increased the fastest, followed by that of industrialists.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-judge-rejects-boeing-737-max-accord-over-diversity-policies-7183321]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Judge Rejects Boeing 737 MAX Accord Over Diversity Policies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-judge-rejects-boeing-737-max-accord-over-diversity-policies-7183321]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:22:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US judge rejected a criminal settlement with Boeing over the 737 MAX crashes on Thursday, slamming diversity policies at the aviation giant and the Justice Department that made him "skeptical" of a fair outcome.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US judge rejected a criminal settlement with Boeing over the 737 MAX crashes on Thursday, slamming diversity policies at the aviation giant and the Justice Department that made him "skeptical" of a fair outcome.</p>

<p>In the ruling, US District Judge Reed O'Connor blocked Boeing's guilty plea under a deferred prosecution agreement in the case which dates back to two fatal crashes in 2018 and 2019 that killed 346 people.</p>

<p>The agreement would have seen the Justice Department choose a monitor to ensure that Boeing complies with the agreement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But O'Connor wrote that diversity, equity and inclusion (DEI) policies at the Justice Department left him "skeptical" of its assurances that it will pick a monitor solely based on skill.</p>

<p>"The court is not convinced ... that the Government will not choose a monitor without race-based considerations," said O'Connor, who gave the parties 30 days to update the court on next steps in the case.</p>

<p>Under the agreement, the Justice Department was to choose six candidates to serve as monitor, and Boeing had the option to strike one of them.</p>

<p>But, O'Connor wrote in the 12-page ruling, he feared Boeing would decide which one to strike "in a discriminatory manner and with racial considerations."</p>

<p>He cited Boeing policies committing to goals such as adequate representation of Black people in company leadership.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His ruling criticized the DEI policies at Boeing and the Justice Department as "against the public interest."</p>

<p>"In a case of this magnitude, it is in the utmost interest of justice that the public is confident this monitor selection is done based solely on competency," O'Connor said.</p>

<p>"The parties' DEI efforts only serve to undermine this confidence in the Government and Boeing's anti-fraud efforts."</p>

<p>Neither Boeing nor the Justice Department had immediate comment on the ruling.</p>

<p><strong>Agreement 'marginalizes' court </strong></p>

<p>The ruling comes as DEI policies face increasing attack in US corporate and government spheres, with backers of the initiatives -- which seek to correct bias in US workplaces -- on the defense even more after Donald Trump's win in the US presidential election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Paul Cassell, a law professor at the University of Utah who represents families of MAX victims cheered O'Connor's ruling, calling the agreement a "cozy deal" between Boeing and the Justice Department.</p>

<p>"This order should lead to a significant renegotiation of the plea deal to reflect the 346 deaths Boeing criminally caused and put in place proper monitoring of Boeing to ensure that it never again commits a crime like this in the future," said Cassell in a statement.</p>

<p>The Justice Department and Boeing reached deferred prosecution agreement in 2021 after the two crashes, but in May Justice Department officials said Boeing had violated it, raising the possibility of a new prosecution.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Over the summer, Boeing and DOJ reached a new agreement in which Boeing agreed to pay an additional $243.6 million in fines. Boeing has faced renewed scrutiny since January when a panel blew out mid-flight on an Alaska Airlines flight of a 737 MAX.</p>

<p>O'Connor cited a second basis for rejecting the agreement, concluding that the Justice Department's process for restricting the court's oversight of the monitor inappropriately "marginalizes" the court in light of the Justice Department's record on the case.</p>

<p>"It is fair to say the Government's attempt to ensure compliance has failed," he wrote. "At this point, the public interest requires the Court to step in."</p>

<p>Shares of Boeing dropped 0.7 percent in afternoon trading.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-08/2o3kvmsk_boeing-737-maxtwitter650_625x300_12_August_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Neither Boeing nor the Justice Department had immediate comment on the ruling.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-who-snuck-on-new-york-to-paris-flight-charged-as-stowaway-7183289]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Who Snuck On New York To Paris Flight Charged As 'Stowaway']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-who-snuck-on-new-york-to-paris-flight-charged-as-stowaway-7183289]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:18:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman accused of evading airport identity and ticket checks and sneaking onto a flight from New York to Paris was charged Thursday with being a stowaway.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman accused of evading airport identity and ticket checks and sneaking onto a flight from New York to Paris was charged Thursday with being a stowaway.</p>

<p>Svetlana Dali, a Russian with US residency, is alleged to have bypassed a checkpoint at New York's JFK airport, before sneaking aboard a Delta Airlines flight to the French capital on November 26.</p>

<p>She was initially turned away at an airport security checkpoint when she could not produce a boarding pass, so instead passed through a screening channel for air crew by mingling with Air Europa flight staff, the federal criminal complaint reads.</p>

<p>The Transportation Security Administration, responsible for US airline safety, said the woman was subject to physical screening even after her documents were overlooked.</p>

<p>It is unclear why Dali, 57, sought to sneak aboard the Delta flight to Paris, with the crime of being a stowaway carrying a prison sentence of up to five years. She could also be stripped of her US residency.</p>

<p>Dali was challenged by flight attendants midflight when it was revealed she did not have a boarding pass, and detained on arrival in Paris.</p>

<p>Delta said the incident was a "deviation from standard procedures," with reports claiming Dali had moved between aircraft lavatories so crew members would not realize she did not have an assigned seat.</p>

<p>Dali was flown back to the United States Wednesday after two failed attempts to return her, with the woman thwarting the first attempt Saturday by screaming, while the airline refused to transport her Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Dali admitted to flying as a stowaway... She also stated that she knew her conduct was illegal," said the FBI complaint.</p>

<p>A federal judge issued a temporary order of detention until Friday afternoon to give Dali time to come up with bail and a verifiable residence, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Dali did not enter a plea, they added.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7u57vkq_svetlana-dali-facebook_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman was initially turned away at an airport security checkpoint.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-rebels-capture-key-city-of-hama-as-army-withdraws-7183285]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syrian Rebels Capture Key City Of Hama As Army Withdraws]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-rebels-capture-key-city-of-hama-as-army-withdraws-7183285]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:13:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Islamist-led rebels captured the central Syrian city of Hama on Thursday in a new blow to President Bashar al-Assad's forces days after they lost the country's commercial hub Aleppo.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Islamist-led rebels captured the central Syrian city of Hama on Thursday in a new blow to President Bashar al-Assad's forces days after they lost the country's commercial hub Aleppo.</p>

<p>The rebels led by Islamist group Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS) launched their offensive little more than a week ago, just as a ceasefire in neighbouring Lebanon took hold between Israel and Assad's ally Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Following overnight clashes, the rebels stormed Hama "from several sides" and engaged in street battles with Assad's forces, Britain-based war monitor, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, said.</p>

<p>The rebels later announced "the complete liberation of the city of Hama", in a message on their Telegram channel.</p>

<p>Rebel fighters kissed the ground and let off volleys of celebratory gunfire as they entered Syria's fourth largest city.</p>

<p>Many residents turned out to welcome the rebel fighters. An AFP photographer saw some residents set fire to a giant poster of Assad on the facade of city hall.</p>

<p>The army admitted losing control of the city, strategically located between Aleppo and Assad's seat of power in Damascus.</p>

<p>Defence Minister Ali Abbas insisted that the army's withdrawal was a "temporary tactical measure".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our forces are still in the vicinity," he said in a statement carried by the official SANA news agency.</p>

<p>- 'Massive blow' -<br />
Aron Lund, a fellow of the Century International think tank, called the loss of Hama "a massive, massive blow to the Syrian government" because the army should have had an advantage there to reverse rebel gains "and they couldn't do it".</p>

<p>He said HTS would now try to push on towards Syria's third largest city, Homs, some 40 kilometres (25 miles) to the south, where many residents were already leaving on Thursday, images on social media showed.</p>

<p>Observatory director Rami Abdel Rahman reported a mass exodus from the city of members of Assad's Alawite minority community.</p>

<p>He said tens of thousands were heading towards areas along Syria's Mediterranean coast, where &nbsp;the Alawites, followers of an offshoot of Shiite Islam, form the majority.</p>

<p>"We are afraid and worried that what happened in Hama will be repeated in Homs," said a civil servant, who gave his name only as Abbas.</p>

<p>"We fear they (the rebels) will take revenge on us," the 33-year-old said.</p>

<p>Until last week, the war in Syria had been mostly dormant for years, but analysts have said it was bound to resume as it was never truly resolved.</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres said the flare-up reflects "the bitter fruits of a chronic collective failure of previous de-escalation arrangements".</p>

<p>In a video posted online, HTS leader Abu Mohammed al-Jolani said his fighters had entered Hama to "cleanse the wound that has endured in Syria for 40 years", referring to a crackdown on the Muslim Brotherhood in 1982, which led to thousands of deaths.</p>

<p>"I ask God almighty that it be a conquest with no revenge," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a later message on Telegram congratulating "the people of Hama on their victory," he used his real name, Ahmed al-Sharaa, instead of his nom de guerre for the first time.</p>

<p>- Fierce fighting -<br />
The Observatory said 826 people, mostly combatants but also including 111 civilians, have been killed in Syria since the violence erupted last week.</p>

<p>It marks the most intense fighting since 2020 in the civil war sparked by the repression of pro-democracy protests in 2011.</p>

<p>Key to the rebels' successes since the start of the offensive last week was the takeover of Aleppo, which in more than a decade of war had never entirely fallen out of government hands.</p>

<p>While the advancing rebels met little resistance earlier in their offensive, the fighting around Hama has been especially fierce.</p>

<p>The Observatory reported 222 people killed in Hama province since Tuesday evening, four of them civilians.</p>

<p>Assad ordered a 50-percent raise in career soldiers' pay, state news agency SANA reported Wednesday, as he seeks to bolster his forces for a counteroffensive.</p>

<p>Rebels drove back the Syrian armed forces despite the government's sending in "large military convoys", the Observatory said.</p>

<p><strong>Risk of 'abuses'</strong></p>

<p>The rebels launched their offensive in northern Syria on November 27, the same day a ceasefire took effect in the war between Israel and Hezbollah in neighbouring Lebanon.</p>

<p>Both Hezbollah and Russia have been crucial backers of Assad's government, but have been mired in their own conflicts in recent years.</p>

<p>Hezbollah leader Naim Qassem said Thursday that his group's fighters "will be by Syria's side in thwarting the goals of this aggression as much as we can".</p>

<p>Human Rights Watch warned the fighting "raises concerns that civilians face a real risk of serious abuses at the hands of opposition armed groups and the Syrian government".</p>

<p>HTS is rooted in Syria's Al-Qaeda branch.</p>

<p>The group has sought to moderate its image in recent years, but experts say it faces a challenge convincing Western governments it has fully renounced hardline jihadism.</p>

<p>The United States maintains hundreds of troops in eastern Syria as part of a coalition formed against Islamic State group jihadists.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mpsqkdmo_hama-afp_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many residents turned out to welcome the rebel fighters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-bans-assault-weapons-it-plans-to-send-to-ukraine-7183283]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Bans Assault Weapons It Plans To Send To Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-bans-assault-weapons-it-plans-to-send-to-ukraine-7183283]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:11:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canada on Thursday announced a ban on 324 models of assault weapons -- granting amnesty in order to collect them from gun shops -- with the aim of shipping them to Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada on Thursday announced a ban on 324 models of assault weapons -- granting amnesty in order to collect them from gun shops -- with the aim of shipping them to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The move came on the eve of the 35th anniversary of an anti-feminist attack that killed 14 women at Ecole Polytechnique in Montreal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The massacre left deep scars on the national psyche.</p>

<p>"To honor the memories of those we lost in mass shootings is to act on gun control and to restrict access to the very weapons used to commit these horrible crimes," Public Safety Minister Dominic LeBlanc told a news conference.</p>

<p>"Our goal is to ensure that no community, no family, is devastated by mass shootings in Canada again," he said.</p>

<p>Nathalie Provost, a survivor of the December 6, 1989 Ecole Polytechnique attack who has long lobbied for gun control, commented: "I'm crying, but I'm also smiling because it's an important step forward."</p>

<p>"This is a strong signal being sent to people wanting these kinds of firearms (that) the government is acting," she said.</p>

<p>Shootings are less common in Canada than in the United States, but crime statistics showed a steady rise in violent gun crimes in the country over the past decade.</p>

<p>According to the most recent data, there were 1,400 shootings in 2022, or 36.7 incidents per 100,000 people.</p>

<p>Canada in 2020 had banned 1,500 models of assault weapons in response to the country's deadliest-ever mass shooting, a rampage that left 22 people dead in Nova Scotia province.</p>

<p>Thursday's announcement bumps up the types of firearms Canadians cannot buy, sell or import to more than 1,800 models.</p>

<p>An estimated 14,500 guns already in circulation may be turned in under an amnesty in place until October 2025 that would provide owners with compensation.</p>

<p>Defense Minister Bill Blair said Ottawa will work with distributors and gun shops that may have them in stock "in order to get these weapons out of Canada and into the hands of the Ukrainians... for use in their fight against Russia."</p>

<p>"Every bit of assistance that we can offer to the Ukrainians is one step towards their victory," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/2i4h18s8_canada-flag-_625x300_22_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canada has banned on 324 models of assault weapons.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inscribed-bullet-shells-photos-of-unitedhealthcare-ceos-killer-emerge-7183280]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inscribed Bullet Shells, Photos Of UnitedHealthcare CEO's Killer Emerge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inscribed-bullet-shells-photos-of-unitedhealthcare-ceos-killer-emerge-7183280]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:10:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The New York Police Department released new photos that showed the face of the man wanted in connection with the fatal shooting of insurance chief Brian Thompson, as the search for his killer entered a second day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New York Police Department released new photos that showed the face of the man wanted in connection with the fatal shooting of insurance chief <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/people/brian-thompson-all-about-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-who-was-shot-dead-in-new-york-7175840">Brian Thompson</a>, as the search for his killer entered a second day.</p>

<p>Police appealed to the public for help in identifying the suspect, offering $10,000 for tips. They executed a search warrant on the HI New York City youth hostel on Manhattan's Upper West Side on Wednesday, according to a person familiar with the situation. The suspect checked into the hostel using a fake New Jersey driver's license and had been there since Nov. 30, the person said.</p>

<p>The hunt didn't lead to any new evidence of the whereabouts of the suspect, but it yielded additional photos of the alleged shooter. A cell phone discovered near the shooting that was believed to be linked to the suspect is a burner phone, according to the person.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?UPDATE: Below are photos of a person of interest wanted for questioning regarding the Midtown Manhattan homicide on Dec. 4. This does not appear to be a random act of violence; all indications are that it was a premediated, targeted attack.<br />
<br />
The full investigative efforts of… <a href="https://t.co/K3kzC4IbtS">pic.twitter.com/K3kzC4IbtS</a></p>
— NYPD NEWS (@NYPDnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/NYPDnews/status/1864706407985221974?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Thompson, 50, was shot in the back and leg around 6:45 am outside of the New York Hilton Midtown hotel, where UnitedHealth Group Inc. was hosting its investor day. Video showed the attacker waiting for Thompson - who was UnitedHealth's insurance chief - upon his arrival at the hotel. The perpetrator approached the executive from behind and shot him multiple times before leaving by foot and then riding an electric bike toward Central Park.</p>

<p>While UnitedHealth had a security team at the hotel for its investor day, it didn't have anyone stationed outside where the executive was shot, according to a person familiar with the matter. The company didn't comment on the security situation.</p>

<p>Shares fell 5.2% Thursday, erasing more than $29 billion in market value. The stock had gained about 1% on Wednesday after news of Thompson's killing broke.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bryan-thompson-unitedhealthcare-quiet-walk-silencer-on-gun-how-unitedhealthcare-ceo-was-murdered-7176331">Quiet Walk, Silencer On Gun: How UnitedHealthcare CEO Bryan Thompson Was Murdered</a></p>

<p>The words "delay" and "depose" were written on a shell casing and a live round recovered in front of the hotel, where Thompson was shot, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The inscriptions loosely echo the book title Delay, Deny, Defend, which describes tactics allegedly used by insurers to deny claims. Law enforcement officials are looking at whether it suggests a potential motive - anger against health insurers.</p>

<p>"That is really unusual," said Joseph Giacalone, a former New York Police Department sergeant who's now a professor at the John Jay College of Criminal Justice. "I have never seen it, and I spent a long time working investigations."</p>

<p>The manhunt involves drones, canines, and extensive use of surveillance technology. Security cameras captured the killing outside the hotel and the movements of the suspect in the immediate aftermath. Facial recognition software and DNA tracing have so far not provided enough direction to aid the investigation, the person with knowledge of the search said.</p>

<h2><strong>Bomb Threats</strong></h2>

<p>Meanwhile, police in suburban Minneapolis are investigating fake bomb threats reported on Wednesday night at Thompson's home, and at another on a nearby street where his wife lives.</p>

<p>The emailed threat was sent to the prosecuting attorney in Maple Grove, Minnesota, who passed it to the city police. Maple Grove police and fire departments went to the houses, as did the Minneapolis bomb squad and the Hennepin County Sheriff's Office.</p>

<p>"No devices or suspicious items were located during the investigation," Maple Grove police said Thursday in a news release. "The case is considered an active investigation, while the incident appears to be a hoax."</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-received-death-threats-before-being-killed-reveals-wife-7174451">UnitedHealthcare CEO Received Death Threats Before Being Killed, Reveals Wife</a></p>

<p>Such prank calls, triggering responses by emergency services, are known as swatting incidents.</p>

<p>UnitedHealth was among a group of companies slammed in a Senate report earlier this year for using automated tools to increase claim denials. While the words could suggest that the shooting might be motivated by some kind of insurance denial, investigators also have to consider the words on the shell casing may be a distraction designed to divert from the true motive, Giacalone said.</p>

<p>"They are going to take everything seriously but have to have an open mind that this could be a potential ruse," he said.</p>

<p>Thompson, who had two sons, went by the nickname "BT." A 20-year veteran of UnitedHealth, he was one of the company's most senior executives and regularly presented at investor events and on earnings calls. The insurance unit he oversaw is expected to bring in $280 billion in revenue this year, and is the country's largest health insurer.</p>

<p>In 2021, he took over as CEO of the UnitedHealthcare insurance division after working in finance positions across the business. A certified public accountant, Thompson graduated from the University of Iowa with a degree in business in 1997. He worked at PwC in the Twin Cities before joining UnitedHealth.</p>

<p>On social media, the reaction to the shooting was harsh. Some users on X, formerly Twitter, applauded the slaying, pointing to insurance claims denials and United's role in America's "broken health-care system." There were similar sentiments on sites like Reddit and TikTok.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/scn21b3o_unitedhealthcare-ceo-killer_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brian Thompson, 50, was shot in the back and leg outside New York Hilton Midtown hotel]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kash-patel-donald-trumps-fbi-pick-is-qanons-name-to-remember-7183246]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kash Patel, Donald Trump's FBI Pick, Is Qanon's 'Name To Remember']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kash-patel-donald-trumps-fbi-pick-is-qanons-name-to-remember-7183246]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:03:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kash Patel, Donald Trump's pick for FBI director, has repeatedly engaged with QAnon -- the sprawling conspiracy theory that the top US law enforcement body currently says is linked to violent domestic extremism.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kash Patel, Donald Trump's pick for FBI director, has repeatedly engaged with QAnon -- the sprawling conspiracy theory that the top US law enforcement body currently says is linked to violent domestic extremism.</p>

<p>Patel, 44, once said QAnon -- based on the fantasy that Trump is waging a secret war against a global cabal of Satan-worshipping pedophiles -- has "a lot of good to a lot of it."</p>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation briefly probed who was behind QAnon years ago and has warned multiple times that the shadowy movement has incited extremist violence. This included after the January 6, 2021 attack by Trump supporters on the US Capitol, when several QAnon adherents took center stage.</p>

<p>Current FBI Director Christopher Wray himself has expressed concern about the group's potential to spark turmoil.</p>

<p>But Patel -- who held several high-level posts during Trump's first term, including as chief of staff to the acting defense secretary -- is hailed as a hero by the conspiracy theory's followers.</p>

<p>"Kash Patel has openly praised Q," one influential QAnon account said on X after his nomination. "Picture an FBI Director who sees the Q movement in a positive light."</p>

<p>Other supporters shared pictures they had taken with Patel, whose rise in Trump's favor includes having written three little-known children's books about "King Donald."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Patel has also made multiple appearances on QAnon-promoting web shows.</p>

<p>During one 2022 interview that AFP reviewed, Patel said he agreed with a host who insisted that "Q," the anonymous persona whose posts on fringe message boards gave rise to the conspiracy theory in 2017, "has been so right on so many things."</p>

<p>Patel told the host he had tried to "incorporate" the mysterious poster "into our overall messaging scheme to capture audiences, because whoever that person is has certainly captured a widespread breath of the MAGA and the America First movement."&nbsp;</p>

<p>In other appearances on QAnon-promoting shows documented by the left-leaning Media Matters for America, Patel has said that "Q" has done both "good" and "bad."</p>

<p>He said that one of the movement's biggest influencers "knows what he's doing" and that he is "blown away at the amount of acumen some of these people have."</p>

<p>In a statement to AFP, Trump transition team spokesman Alex Pfeiffer dismissed what he said were "false smears about Kash Patel," though without substantiating that assertion.</p>

<p>"He's going to restore integrity to the FBI," Pfeiffer said, adding that Patel worked in the Justice Department under the Obama administration.</p>

<p><strong>'Name to remember'</strong></p>

<p>The QAnon community's excitement over Patel appears in part because "Q" said he was a "name to remember" in a 2018 post.</p>

<p>"Kash becoming FBI Director is probably one of the GREATEST Q PROOFS OF ALL TIME," one prominent account wrote on Telegram.</p>

<p>On Truth Social, Patel once posted an image of himself with a flaming "Q" in the background.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He also interacted repeatedly in 2022 with a Truth Social account that used the handle "@Q" as he courted users to the Trump-owned platform, where he is on the parent company's board.</p>

<p>Mike Rothschild, author of "The Storm is Upon Us," a book on the cult of QAnon, said Patel's nomination "is indicative of the degree to which conspiracism and paranoia have consumed the mainstream Republican Party."</p>

<p>The idea that Trump is fighting a shadowy "deep state" of unelected bureaucrats, in particular, is central to QAnon and has also "become orthodoxy in the GOP," Rothschild said.</p>

<p>"All of the conspiracy theories about Covid, the 2020 election, vaccination and trafficking rings stem from that endless battle, and it's something that Q believers think Patel is going to help win as FBI director."</p>

<p>Patel told conservative strategist Steve Bannon last year that law enforcement agencies -- typically seen as independent from politics -- would under his leadership "come after" journalists as well as government officials.</p>

<p>He has also embraced other conspiracy theories popular in QAnon circles.</p>

<p>In multiple posts on Truth Social, he spread false claims about vaccine safety and "shedding" as he hawked "detox" supplements that supposedly "reverse" the Covid-19 shots.</p>

<p>After the 2020 election, Patel called a former Justice Department official to enquire about claims that Italian satellites altered votes, the official testified to Congress.</p>

<p>And in "The Plot Against the King 2000 Mules," the second of Patel's Trump-themed children's books, he parroted far-right commentator Dinesh D'Souza's discredited allegations that ballot-trafficking "mules" smuggled fraudulent votes to sway the result four years ago.</p>

<p>Select copies of the book were signed with a special message: "WWG1WGA," an abbreviation for the QAnon slogan meaning, "Where we go one, we go all."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gjutg2uo_kash-patel_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kash Patel has also made multiple appearances on QAnon-promoting web shows.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/arctic-could-witness-first-ice-free-day-in-3-years-study-reveals-7183214]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Arctic Could Witness First Ice-Free Day In 3 Years, Study Reveals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/arctic-could-witness-first-ice-free-day-in-3-years-study-reveals-7183214]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 06:51:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Arctic sea ice has been melting at an unprecedented rate of more than 12 per cent each decade, according to NASA.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have warned that the Arctic could witness its first ice-free day in just three years in 2027, as per a new study published in the journal,<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54508-3" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em> Nature Communications</em></a>. Climatologists from Colorado University (CU) Boulder and the University of Gothenburg conducting the study stated that "ice free" refers to a sea ice area reduced to 1 million square kilometres or less. Currently, Arctic sea ice has been melting at an unprecedented rate of more than 12 per cent each decade, compared to its average extent during the period from 1981 to 2010, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/arctic-sea-ice/?intent=121" rel="noindex, nofollow">NASA</a>.</p>

<p>Using hundreds of simulations projecting climate change impact between 2023 to 2100, the scientists found that the Arctic will likely go ice-free within nine to 20 years with the most pessimistic prediction projecting that it could happen as soon as in three years' time.</p>

<p>If the Arctic does go ice-free, it would notably enhance the warming of the upper ocean, accelerating sea ice loss year round and therefore further accelerating climate change. Additionally, once a first ice-free day occurs, it may last between one day and 71 days, with a mean length of 25 days and a standard deviation of 17 days.</p>

<p>"The first ice-free day in the Arctic won't change things dramatically. But it will show that we've fundamentally altered one of the defining characteristics of the natural environment in the Arctic Ocean, which is that it is covered by sea ice and snow year-round, through greenhouse gas emissions," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.livescience.com/planet-earth/arctic/ominous-milestone-for-the-planet-arctic-oceans-1st-ice-free-day-could-be-just-3-years-away-alarming-study-finds" rel="noindex, nofollow">said </a>Alexandra Jahn, the co-author of the study.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-discover-deep-sea-volcano-like-structure-in-the-arctic-ocean-near-alaska-7051948" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Scientists Discover Deep Sea Volcano-Like Structure In The Arctic Ocean Near Alaska</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Doomsday near?</strong></h3>

<p>A further reduction of the summer sea ice cover will also negatively impact the already-stressed Arctic ecosystem -- with the polar bear to the crucial zooplankton facing existential crisis. Notably, as the sea ice melts, it exposes the darker waters that absorb more of the sun's rays -- effectively turning the Arctic from a refrigerator to a radiator.</p>

<p>Despite the doomsday prediction, scientists provided a sliver of hope, stating that a drastic cut in carbon dioxide emissions could dramatically push the ice-free day and soften the impact of such a phenomenon on the planet.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/i3q4654o_arctic-land_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Arctic is one course to witness sits first ice-free day in 2027.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-ready-to-defend-through-any-means-7182901]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says Ready To Defend Through "Any Means"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-ready-to-defend-through-any-means-7182901]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 05:17:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov on Thursday said he hopes the West took "seriously" Moscow's recent use of a hypersonic missile in Ukraine, and warned that Russia was ready to use "any means" to defend itself.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov on Thursday said he hopes the West took "seriously" Moscow's recent use of a hypersonic missile in Ukraine, and warned that Russia was ready to use "any means" to defend itself.</p>

<p>The United States and its allies "must understand that we would be ready to use any means not to allow them to succeed in what they call strategic defeat of Russia," Lavrov said in an interview with US media personality Tucker Carlson released Thursday.</p>

<p>Two weeks ago, Russia fired its new Oreshnik hypersonic missile on the Ukrainian city of Dnipro in a major escalation of the almost three-year war.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has since threatened to use the weapon on Kyiv in response to Ukraine's strikes on Russia's territory.</p>

<p>"We are sending signals and we hope that the last one, a couple of weeks ago, the signal with the new weapons system called Oreshnik... was taken seriously," Lavrov said.</p>

<p>While he insisted that Russia doesn't want to escalate the situation and wants to "avoid any misunderstanding" with Washington and its partners, Lavrov warned that "we will send additional messages if they don't draw necessary conclusions."</p>

<p>Putin said the Oreshnik missile flies at 10 times the speed of sound and cannot be intercepted by air defenses.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky has called the strike "the latest bout of Russian madness" and appealed for updated air-defense systems to meet the new threat.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/sergey-lavrov-reuters-650_650x400_71476328610.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lavrov hopes the West took "seriously" Moscow's recent use of a hypersonic missile in Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-delays-crewed-lunar-landing-until-2027-as-trump-prepares-for-office-7182366]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Delays Crewed Lunar Landing Until 2027 As Trump Prepares For Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-delays-crewed-lunar-landing-until-2027-as-trump-prepares-for-office-7182366]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 02:07:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States is pushing back its planned return to the Moon from 2026 to "mid-2027" as it deals with heat shield issues and other troubles plaguing its Orion crew capsule, NASA officials said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States is pushing back its planned return to the Moon from 2026 to "mid-2027" as it deals with heat shield issues and other troubles plaguing its Orion crew capsule, NASA officials said Thursday.</p>

<p>The announcement comes as President-elect Donald Trump is preparing to take office in January and could significantly reshape the direction of the US space agency.</p>

<p>Artemis, named after the sister of Apollo in Greek mythology, was officially announced in 2017 as part of NASA's plans to establish a sustained presence on Earth's nearest space neighbor, and apply lessons learned there for a future mission to Mars.</p>

<p>Its first mission, an uncrewed test flight to the Moon and back called Artemis 1, took place in 2022, after several postponements.</p>

<p>But teams reviewing the data later learned that Orion's heat shield eroded in unexpected ways, and there were also issues with its electrical and life support systems.</p>

<p>"We were able to recreate the problem here on Earth, and now we know the root cause, and this has allowed us to devise a path forward," NASA administrator Bill Nelson told reporters during a press conference.</p>

<p>Artemis 2, involving a crew that will not land on the lunar surface, has been postponed from September 2025 to April 2026, Nelson told reporters.</p>

<p>Artemis 3, in which the first woman and first person of color are to set foot on lunar soil at the Moon's south pole, should now take place in "mid 2027."</p>

<p>"That will be well ahead of the Chinese government's announced intention that they have already publicly stated of 2030," added Nelson.</p>

<p>"The safety of our astronauts is always first in our decisions. It is our North Star. We do not fly until we are ready."</p>

<p>Apart from the troubles plaguing Orion, NASA is waiting for Elon Musk's SpaceX to have a modified version of its Starship prototype rocket to act as a lunar lander.</p>

<p>While the company is making rapid progress, it still has a long way to go in its testing, especially in proving it can carry out a complex refueling procedure in orbit.</p>

<p>The spacesuits, developed by Axiom, are also still awaited.</p>

<p>Trump on Wednesday nominated online payments billionaire and private astronaut Jared Isaacman to lead NASA.</p>

<p>Experts anticipate significant changes could be in the offing -- from potentially cancelling the expensive Space Launch Systems (SLS) rocket used for Artemis, to possibly scrapping the Moon component altogether, and focusing on Mars.</p>

<p>The announcement comes as President-elect Donald Trump is preparing to take office in January and could significantly reshape the direction of the US space agency.</p>

<p>Artemis, named after the sister of Apollo in Greek mythology, was officially announced in 2017 as part of NASA's plans to establish a sustained presence on Earth's nearest space neighbor, and apply lessons learned there for a future mission to Mars.</p>

<p>Its first mission, an uncrewed test flight to the Moon and back called Artemis 1, took place in 2022, after several postponements.</p>

<p>But teams reviewing the data later learned that Orion's heat shield eroded in unexpected ways, and there were also issues with its electrical and life support systems.</p>

<p>"We were able to recreate the problem here on Earth, and now we know the root cause, and this has allowed us to devise a path forward," NASA administrator Bill Nelson told reporters during a press conference.</p>

<p>Artemis 2, involving a crew that will not land on the lunar surface, has been postponed from September 2025 to April 2026, Nelson told reporters.</p>

<p>Artemis 3, in which the first woman and first person of color are to set foot on lunar soil at the Moon's south pole, should now take place in "mid 2027."</p>

<p>"That will be well ahead of the Chinese government's announced intention that they have already publicly stated of 2030," added Nelson.</p>

<p>"The safety of our astronauts is always first in our decisions. It is our North Star. We do not fly until we are ready."</p>

<p>Apart from the troubles plaguing Orion, NASA is waiting for Elon Musk's SpaceX to have a modified version of its Starship prototype rocket to act as a lunar lander.</p>

<p>While the company is making rapid progress, it still has a long way to go in its testing, especially in proving it can carry out a complex refueling procedure in orbit.</p>

<p>The spacesuits, developed by Axiom, are also still awaited.</p>

<p>Trump on Wednesday nominated online payments billionaire and private astronaut Jared Isaacman to lead NASA.</p>

<p>Experts anticipate significant changes could be in the offing -- from potentially cancelling the expensive Space Launch Systems (SLS) rocket used for Artemis, to possibly scrapping the Moon component altogether, and focusing on Mars.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/6jbl6gcg_moon-exploration-moon-landing-generic-nasa-unsplash_625x300_21_December_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States is pushing back its planned return to the Moon from 2026 to "mid-2027".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-president-emmanuel-macron-to-name-new-pm-in-coming-days-7182197]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Macron Says He Won't Resign, Vows To Name New PM In "Coming Days"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-president-emmanuel-macron-to-name-new-pm-in-coming-days-7182197]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 01:11:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron Thursday vowed to name a new prime minister "in the coming days" after the resignation of Michel Barnier, whose government was toppled by a no-confidence vote in parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Emmanuel Macron on Thursday vowed to name a new prime minister in the coming days to prevent France from sliding deeper into political turmoil, rejecting growing pressure from the opposition to resign.</p>

<p>Macron adopted a defiant tone in an address to the nation, seeking to limit an escalating political crisis after Prime Minister Michel Barnier's government was ousted in a historic no-confidence vote.</p>

<p>Contemporary France's shortest-serving premier, Barnier resigned after Wednesday's parliamentary defeat in a standoff over the budget forced his government to step down, the first such toppling of a French administration in over 60 years.</p>

<p>Macron now faces the task for the third time this year of selecting a new prime minister and did not come up with a name in his address.</p>

<p>"I will appoint a prime minister in the coming days," he said, adding this person would be charged with forming a "government of general interest" with a priority of passing a budget.</p>

<p>He also lashed out at the French far right and hard left for uniting in an "anti-republican front" to bring down the government.</p>

<p>He said lawmakers had "knowingly" chosen "to topple the budget and the government just days before the Christmas holidays."</p>

<p>The French presidency said earlier that Barnier and his ministers would remain "in charge of daily business until the appointment of a new government".</p>

<p><strong>- 'Do the impossible' -</strong></p>

<p>Limiting any impression of political chaos is all the more important for Macron given that on Saturday he will host world leaders -- including US President-elect Donald Trump -- for the reopening of the Notre Dame cathedral in Paris after a devastating 2019 fire.</p>

<p>Pointing to how the edifice was rebuilt within the five-year timeline he had set, Macron said: "It's the proof we're able to do great things, that we can do the impossible."</p>

<p>In an unusual move, Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot, France's top diplomat for just two-and-a-half months, urged unity in a message on social media, saying "instability is vulnerability" at a time of international uncertainty.</p>

<p>A majority of lawmakers on Wednesday supported the no-confidence vote proposed by the hard left and backed by the far right headed by Marine Le Pen.</p>

<p>Barnier's ejection in record time came after snap parliamentary elections in June resulted in a hung parliament. No political force was able to form an overall majority and the far right held the key to the government's survival.</p>

<p>The trigger for Barnier's ouster was his 2025 budget plan, including austerity measures unacceptable to a majority in parliament, but which he argued were necessary to stabilise France's finances.</p>

<p>On Monday he forced through a social security financing bill without a vote, but the ousting of the government means France is still without a budget.</p>

<p><strong>- 'To the end' -</strong></p>

<p>New legislative elections cannot be called until a year after the previous ones in summer 2024.</p>

<p>But while Macron has more than two years of his presidential term left, some opponents are calling on him to resign to break the deadlock.</p>

<p>According to a poll by Odoxa-Backbone Consulting for Le Figaro daily, 59 percent of French want the president to step down, while a survey by Harris for RTL put the figure even higher, at 64 percent.</p>

<p>Bur Macron said: "The mandate that you gave to me democratically (in 2022 elections) is a five-year mandate and I will exercise it fully, right up to the end."</p>

<p>"The 30 months we have ahead of us must be 30 months of useful action for the country."</p>

<p>But he admitted his decision to call snap parliamentary elections this summer that resulted in a hung parliament "was not understood".</p>

<p>"Many have blamed me for it and I know, many continue to blame me. It's a fact and it's my responsibility," he said.</p>

<p>Hard-left leader Jean-Luc Melenchon said that Macron was the "cause of the problem" in France "and would go due to the force of events" before his term ends.</p>

<p>Barnier is Macron's fifth prime minister since coming to power in 2017. Each successive premier has served for a shorter period and, given the composition of the National Assembly, there is no guarantee that Barnier's successor would last any longer.</p>

<p>Loyalist Defence Minister Sebastien Lecornu and Macron's centrist ally Francois Bayrou have been touted as possible contenders, as has former Socialist premier and interior minister Bernard Cazeneuve.</p>

<p>Bayrou, who leads the MoDem party, had lunch with the president at the Elysee, a source close to him told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/q5vssffo_emmanuel-macron_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Macron Thursday vowed to name a new prime minister "in the coming days.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rise-of-ai-powered-tools-among-amazon-execs-top-5-predictions-for-2025-7182195]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rise Of AI-Powered Tools Among Amazon Exec's Top 5 Predictions For 2025]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rise-of-ai-powered-tools-among-amazon-execs-top-5-predictions-for-2025-7182195]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 01:11:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A mission-driven workforce of tomorrow, energy efficiency driving innovation, and rise of AI-powered tools that accelerate fact-checking and debunk misinformation are among the top five tech predictions outlined by Amazon CTO Werner Vogels.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mission-driven workforce of tomorrow, energy efficiency driving innovation, and rise of AI-powered tools that accelerate fact-checking and debunk misinformation are among the top five tech predictions outlined by Amazon CTO Werner Vogels.</p>

<p>According to him, in an era of unprecedented societal challenges and rapid technological advancements, harnessing 'technology for good' has become both an ethical imperative and a profitable endeavour.</p>

<p>"From clean energy innovations unlocking new avenues for sustainable development to AI-powered tools tipping the scales in the fight against disinformation, we are witnessing technology augment human ingenuity in inspiring ways," he said.</p>

<p>Emergence of workforce that is mission-driven, an era of energy efficiency driving innovation, and increasingly, technology tipping the scales in the discovery of truth are among his top tech predictions for 2025.</p>

<p>"As disinformation spreads at unprecedented rates, a new wave of AI-powered tools will emerge to empower journalists, researchers, and engaged citizens in their quest for truth," he said.</p>

<p>Vogels asserted this technological revolution will democratise investigative capabilities, accelerate fact-checking, as it closes the gap between the spread of misinformation and its debunking.</p>

<p>He further observed that the rise of intention-driven technologies is reshaping people's relationship with the digital world, promoting focus and well-being over mere attention capture.</p>

<p>"All the while, a mission-driven workforce is emerging, more eager to tackle hard human problems than chase the bottomline. In the coming years, using technology for positive impact will not just be possible — it will redefine the way we think about success," Vogels noted.</p>

<p>As the world confronts urgent challenges around sustainability, social equity, food and economic security, and responsible AI usage, a quiet revolution is sweeping the job market, marking a shift towards "work that benefits humanity".</p>

<p>Across industries and generations, there is a palpable shift in worker values and preferences, with a growing number of people seeking roles that allow them to make a meaningful impact on society and the environment.</p>

<p>He argues that compared to previous generations, who were more concerned about personal freedom and economic growth, millennials and Gen Z typically show greater concern about issues like inequality, mental health, and climate change.</p>

<p>"Organisations that recognise and harness this shift will be the ones that thrive in the decades to come," he said. To remain competitive, businesses across sectors must adapt their strategies to attract and retain purpose-driven employees.</p>

<p>Vogels also sees open data driving decentralised disaster preparedness. By 2025 and beyond, disaster resilience will be fundamentally transformed through the power of hyperlocal, community-sourced data. This shift will redefine disaster management from a top-down, reactive model to one that is proactive, decentralised, and community-driven, he believes.</p>

<p>The top executive of Amazon further sees intention-driven consumer technology taking hold.</p>

<p>"A subtle shift is underway that is redefining our relationship with consumer technology. As more and more people look for a refuge from constant distraction, devices are emerging that prioritise mindfulness, intentionality, and deep thinking over a barrage of fleeting stimuli," says Vogels.</p>

<p>In 2025 and beyond, technology will empower rather than distract, he says adding, "we'll be better for it".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jq569fk8_wemer-vogels_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2025 and beyond, technology will empower rather than distract: Amazon CTO Werner Vogels]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-0-magnitude-earthquake-hits-us-california-tsunami-warning-issued-7182097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[7.0 Magnitude Earthquake Hits US' California, Tsunami Warning Issued]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-0-magnitude-earthquake-hits-us-california-tsunami-warning-issued-7182097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:45:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A powerful earthquake struck Thursday off the coast of California, sparking a tsunami warning, US seismologists said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A powerful earthquake struck Thursday off the coast of California, sparking a tsunami warning, US seismologists said.</p>

<p>The 7.0-magnitude quake was recorded at a depth of just 10 kilometers (six miles),&nbsp; almost 100 kilometers west-southwest of Ferndale, according to the United States Geological Survey.</p>

<p>"Based on preliminary earthquake parameters... hazardous tsunami are possible for coasts located within 300 KM of the earthquake epicenter," said a warning issued by the National Weather Service's Tsunami Warning Center in Honolulu.</p>

<p>The warning noted that no areas had yet experienced any waves, but that anyone near a coastline should be alert to the possibility of danger.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4h4fqblo_earthquake-generic_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[California Earthquake: he 7.0-magnitude quake was recorded at a depth of just 10 kilometers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/contribution-unequal-reponsibility-must-be-too-india-at-landmark-climate-change-hearing-in-international-court-of-justice-7181897]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Contribution Unequal, Responsibility Must Be Too": India At Climate Hearing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/contribution-unequal-reponsibility-must-be-too-india-at-landmark-climate-change-hearing-in-international-court-of-justice-7181897]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 23:58:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India slammed developed countries for causing the climate crisis during a landmark hearing at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) on Thursday, saying they exploited the global carbon budget, failed to honour climate-finance promises.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India slammed developed countries for causing the climate crisis during a landmark hearing at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) on Thursday, saying they exploited the global carbon budget, failed to honour climate-finance promises and are now demanding that developing countries restrict their resource use.</p>

<p>The court is examining what legal obligations countries have to address climate change and the consequences if they fail.</p>

<p>Making submissions on behalf of India, Luther M Rangreji, joint secretary in the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA), said, "If the contribution to degradation is unequal, the responsibility must also be unequal."</p>

<p>India said developing nations are the hardest hit by climate change, despite contributing the least to it.</p>

<p>"The developed world, which historically contributed the most, is ironically the best equipped with the technological and economic means to address this challenge," Rangreji said.</p>

<p>He criticised rich countries for enjoying the benefits of fossil fuels while discouraging developing nations from using their own energy resources.</p>

<p>"Countries which have reaped development benefits from exploiting fossil fuels demand developing countries to not utilise the national energy resources available to them," he said.</p>

<p>India also slammed the lack of action on climate-finance commitments.</p>

<p>"The USD 100 billion pledged at the Copenhagen COP in 2009 by developed country parties and the doubling of the contribution to the Adaptation Fund have not yet been translated into any concrete actions," India noted.</p>

<p>It called the new climate finance package for the Global South agreed at COP29 in Azerbaijan's Baku "too little, too distant" to meet the urgent needs of developing countries.</p>

<p>India stressed the principle of fairness, saying, "If the contribution to global environmental degradation is unequal, the responsibility should also be unequal."</p>

<p>India also reaffirmed its commitment to its climate targets under the Paris Agreement, but warned against overburdening its citizens.</p>

<p>"There is a limit on how much we burden our citizens, even when India is pursuing Sustainable Development Goals for one-sixth of humanity," it said.</p>

<p>The hearing is the result of years of campaigning by Pacific island nations and Vanuatu, which led to a UN resolution asking the ICJ for an advisory opinion. Over the next two weeks, 98 countries, including small island nations and large emitters, will present their views.</p>

<p>Though non-binding, the ICJ's opinion could set a moral and legal benchmark in the global fight against climate change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/99d98mr8_climate-change_650x400_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The hearing is the result of years of campaigning by Pacific island nations and Vanuatu.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-h-1b-visa-quota-full-for-2025-what-applicants-should-do-now-7181455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US H-1B Visa Quota Full For 2025. What Applicants Should Do Now]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-h-1b-visa-quota-full-for-2025-what-applicants-should-do-now-7181455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 22:37:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A congressional cap of 65,000 H-1B visas for regular applicants and an additional 20,000 visas for US advanced degree holders have been mandated by the US government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been announced by the US Citizenship and Immigration Services or USCIS that they have received enough petitions to meet the cap for H-1B visas.</p>

<p>So, can more people apply or will they be rejected?</p>

<p>A congressional cap of 65,000 H-1B visas for regular applicants and an additional 20,000 visas for US advanced degree holders have been mandated by the US government.</p>

<p>The agency has informed that it will send out non-selection notices to registered candidates through their online accounts. The status later will read, "Not Selected: Not selected - not eligible to file an H-1B cap petition based on this registration" once the notifications are complete.</p>

<p>The H-1B cap lottery comes into the picture after the applications exceed the annual cap set by the US government. After that, a lottery system is used to process the petitions.</p>

<p>The deadline for submitting H-1B cap petitions was June 30 2024 but since the date fell on a Sunday, properly registered petitions received on July 1, 2024 would also be considered on time.</p>

<p>However, USCIS will continue to accept and process petitions that have been exempted from the cap.</p>

<p>"We will continue to accept and process petitions filed to extend the amount of time a current H-1B worker may remain in the United States; change the terms of employment for current H-1B workers; allow current H-1B workers to change employers; and allow current H-1B workers to work concurrently in additional H-1B positions," the USCIS said.</p>

<p>The visa lottery is a complex process and should be followed through with detail. It is advisable to keep track of the notifications sent by USCIS and not miss important deadlines or information.</p>

<p>Usually the majority of H-1B visa holders are Indians (72.3% of the total 386,000 H-1B visas issued), however USCIS data shows a decline in sponsorships across major firms such as Google, Amazon, Infosys and IBM.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/40iqstbo_h1b-visa-istock_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[USCIS has announced that they have received enough petitions to meet the cap for H-1B visas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isro-puts-proba-3-in-orbit-a-10-point-guide-about-the-european-satellite-7181437]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[ISRO Puts PROBA-3 In Orbit. A 10-Point Guide About The European Satellite]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isro-puts-proba-3-in-orbit-a-10-point-guide-about-the-european-satellite-7181437]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 22:32:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian space agency ISRO today successfully launched the European Space Agency's PROBA-3 satellite. The launch was on board ISRO's workhorse rocket - the Polar Satellite Launch Vehicle or PSLV in its 61st commercial mission 'C-59'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">PROBA, short for Project for Onboard Anatomy, is a space programme under the European Space Agency or ESA. Under PROBA, there have been a series of satellite launches. Today's was the third in that series, hence the name PROBA-3.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">PROBA-3 is a solar mission. It's aim is to study the Sun's corona at a level of precision never done before. PROBA-3 consists of two independent, three-axis stabilised spacecraft - the Coronagraph Spacecraft or CSC, which is 310 kg and the Occulter Spacecraft or OSC, which is 240 kg. Both spacecraft will have a highly elliptical orbit around Earth whose apogee or distance farthest from the surface of the planet at the equator will be 60,500 km.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">According to the European Space Agency, the mission will demonstrate 'formation flying' within the context of a large-scale scientific experiment. The two spacecraft in orbit will create an approximately 150-metre-long solar coronagraph to study the Sun's faint corona closer to the solar rim than has ever been achieved before.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">By flying in such a close formation - 150 metres - the Occulter Spacecraft will cast a precise shadow onto the Coronagraph's telescope, thereby blocking any direct sunlight. The Coronagraph will then be able to map and image the Sun's corona in the full electromagnetic spectrum - which includes visible light, Ultraviolet radiation (UV rays) and Infra-Red radiation (IR). It will also be able to image the solar corona in polarised light - which is made up of waves that vibrate in a single plane and include linearly, circularly, and elliptically polarised lights. The CSC will be able to do this for many hours at a time.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The scientific objective of the PROBA-3 mission is to observe the Sun's corona at 1.1 solar radius in the visible wavelength range (visible light). Solar radius is a unit of distance used to describe the size of stars in comparison to the size of the Sun. 1 solar radius equals 6.95700 x 10(to the power 8) meters or 695,700 km. This is roughly 109 times the radius of the Earth. This would make PROBA-3 the most precise satellite to map and image the Sun's corona.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">PROBA-3 marks the next step in formation flying. As a world first, its two satellites - the Coronagraph spacecraft and the Occulter spacecraft - will maintain formation to a few millimetres and arc second precision at distances of around 150 metres of each other for six hours at a time per 19-hour, 36-minute orbit. In effect the pair will be forming a virtual giant satellite. And this will be achieved autonomously, without relying on guidance from the ground.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Now that the two satellites have been successfully placed in orbit, there will be a short preparatory period for the two satellites in which some safety tests will be conducted by the European Space Agency. Because these two satellites will be independent yet flying in tandem in close proximity, a collision manoeuvre test will be conducted. Once these tests are complete, the two satellites will be placed into into a safe relative tandem orbit. They can then be left safely in with no risk of collision or running away from each other.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The PROBA-3 satellites will repetitively demonstrate acquisition, rendezvous, proximity operations, formation flying, coronagraph observations, separation and convoy flying in every orbit.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">According to the Europan Space Agency, the PROBA-3 will be a "Laboratory in space" to validate strategies, guidance, navigation and control, and other algorithms, such as relative GPS navigation, previously tried in ground simulators.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The ESA said that this mission includes a rendezvous experiment. It will test sensors and algorithms for satellites to Rendezvous (cooperative and uncooperative) in elliptical orbit. This cutting-edge technology could be used for a future Mars Sample return mission and for de-orbiting satellites from low-Earth orbit - which will also help declutter the Space around Earth.</li>
</ol>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7ha0ehhg_isro-pslv-c59-mission-proba3-pti_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[ISRO today launched the ESA's PROBA-3 satellite on board the PSLV C-59 rocket.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/scientists-reveal-real-face-of-santa-claus-after-1-700-years-see-pics-7181128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Reveal Real Face Of Santa Claus After 1,700 Years. See Pics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/scientists-reveal-real-face-of-santa-claus-after-1-700-years-see-pics-7181128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:41:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have revealed the face of Saint Nicholas of Myra, the real-life bishop who inspired the concept of modern-day Santa Claus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have revealed the face of Saint Nicholas of Myra, the real-life bishop who inspired the concept of modern-day Santa Claus. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, the groundbreaking reconstruction comes 1,700 years after the saint's death and was possible by analysing data from his skull. Using advanced techniques, researchers managed to "forensically recreate" the face of Saint Nicholas of Myra, whose penchant for gift-giving prompted the legend of Father Christmas.</p>

<p>In the images, shared on Instagram by the study's lead author, Cicero Moraes, the saint is depicted with a broad forehead, thin lips and a round nose. The 3D images reveal his face to be both "strong" and "gentle," Mr Moraes said, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/04/world-news/real-face-of-santa-claus-revealed-thanks-to-science/" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the images below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDJvZEaRRbD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDJvZEaRRbD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDJvZEaRRbD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDJvZEaRRbD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Cicero Moraes (@cogitas3d)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Saint Nicholas of Myra died in 343 AD - long before anyone could snap a photo. He was known for only rewarding well-behaved kids with gifts and inspiring the Dutch folk figure of Sinterklaas. Over time, the character merged with English Father Christmas to become the Santa Claus we know today.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite the saint's popularity, there was no accurate depiction of his until now. Mr Moraes said the 3D images match the early descriptions of Santa Claus in literature, such as the 1823 poem "Twas The Night Before Christmas," which describes his "rosy cheeks," a "broad face" and a "nose like a cherry."</p>

<p>"The skull has a very robust appearance, generating a strong face, as its dimensions on the horizontal axis are larger than average," he said. "This characteristic, combined with a thick beard, is very reminiscent of the figure we have in mind when we think of Santa Claus," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/is-tim-cook-ready-to-retire-apple-ceo-says-i-will-do-it-until-the-voice-7180514">Is Tim Cook Ready To Retire? Apple CEO Says "I Will Do It Until The Voice..."</a></strong></p>

<p>According to the <em>Post</em>, scientists used the data collected by Luigi Martino in 1950 to reconstruct the saint's face. Studying his remains revealed that the saint suffered from chronic arthritis in his spine and pelvis and a thick skull that likely caused frequent headaches. The scientists said the saint also likely survived off a mostly plant-based diet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We initially reconstructed the skull in 3D using this data," Mr Moraes said. "We supplemented this with the anatomical deformation technique, in which the tomography of a living person's head is adjusted so that the virtual donor's skull matches that of the saint," he explained.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The final face is an interpolation of all this information, seeking anatomical and statistical coherence," Mr Moraes added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, while Saint Nicholas was initially buried in Myra, or modern-day Turkey, his bones were later moved to Bari, Italy, where they remain today.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/5i9sj8l8_real-face-of-santa-claus-_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Saint Nicholas of Myra died in 343 AD - long before anyone could snap a photo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reflected-on-lessons-learnt-india-on-diplomatic-talks-with-china-7181035]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Reflected On Lessons Learnt": India On Diplomatic Talks With China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reflected-on-lessons-learnt-india-on-diplomatic-talks-with-china-7181035]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:29:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[To prevent recurrence of military standoff along their contested border, India and China on Thursday reflected on the lessons learnt from the eastern Ladakh face-off that ended a few weeks ago following completion of the disengagement process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To prevent the recurrence of military standoffs along their contested border, India and China on Thursday reflected on the lessons learnt from the eastern Ladakh face-off that ended a few weeks ago following completion of the disengagement process in Depsang and Demchok.</p>

<p>In talks held in Delhi under the framework of the Working Mechanism for Consultation and Coordination on India-China Border Affairs (WMCC), the two sides also prepared for the next meeting of the Special Representatives on the boundary question.</p>

<p>It was the first WMCC dialogue after the completion of the disengagement process in eastern Ladakh that effectively ended the standoff which had begun in May 2020.</p>

<p>"The two sides positively affirmed the implementation of the most recent disengagement agreement which completed the resolution of the issues that emerged in 2020," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said.</p>

<p>"They also prepared for the next meeting of the Special Representatives (SR)," it said.</p>

<p>A decision on the resumption of dialogue under the SR mechanism was taken at a meeting between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping in Kazan on the sidelines of the BRICS summit on October 21.</p>

<p>"Both sides reviewed the situation in border areas, and reflected on the lessons learnt from the events of 2020 in order to prevent their recurrence," the MEA said on the WMCC talks.</p>

<p>"In this context, they highlighted the importance of regular exchanges and contacts at diplomatic and military level through established mechanisms," it said.</p>

<p>"They agreed on the need for effective border management and maintenance of peace and tranquillity in accordance with relevant bilateral agreements, protocols and understandings reached between the two governments," it added.</p>

<p>The leader of the Chinese delegation also called on Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/nfd8fqlc_india-china-ladakh-generic-ndtv-fil-photo_625x300_25_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two sides positively affirmed the implementation of the disengagement process.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/fbi-warns-texts-between-android-and-iphone-could-be-targeted-by-chinese-hackers-shares-tips-to-stay-safe-7180878]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Warns Texts Between Android, iPhone Could Be Hacked, Shares Safety Tips]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/fbi-warns-texts-between-android-and-iphone-could-be-targeted-by-chinese-hackers-shares-tips-to-stay-safe-7180878]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:08:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[FBI urged citizens to use encryption to secure their communications amid a massive Chinese cyberattack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FBI has issued a warning highlighting cybersecurity risks associated with texting between Android and Apple devices. This vulnerability stems from differences in how these platforms handle communication protocols, making texts susceptible to interception.&nbsp;When sending texts between iPhones and Android devices, messages are not protected by end-to-end encryption, leaving them vulnerable to hacking.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Apple's iMessage between iPhone users, and Google Messages between Android users, also employ end-to-end encryption using Signal's protocol. However, the texts exchanged between iPhone and Android devices are not fully encrypted, leaving them vulnerable.</p>

<p>According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/chinese-hackers-stole-americans-phone-data-8-telecoms-us-officials-say-rcna182942">NBC News</a></em>, a group of malicious actors, known as "Salt Typhoon" and believed to be based in China, recently infiltrated major US telecommunications companies, including AT&amp;T, T-Mobile, and Verizon, to spy on customers.&nbsp;Deputy National Security Adviser Anne Neuberger revealed that the cyberattack's impact extends far beyond the US, affecting "dozens of countries around the world."</p>

<p>A senior official further revealed that the hackers had accessed a substantial amount of phone data belonging to American citizens. The primary objective of this breach was to identify potential targets for more sophisticated and invasive spying.</p>

<h3><strong>Here's what to do:</strong></h3>

<p>To enhance security, the FBI recommends using encrypted messaging platforms like Signal or WhatsApp, which provide end-to-end encryption, ensuring messages remain private. Notably, encryption is a technology that scrambles a message and requires a "key" to be able to see or hear it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>End-to-end encryption ensures that only the sender and recipient of a message hold the unique decryption key. This means that even the app's corporate owner and operator cannot access the encrypted message, even if compelled by a court order or in the event of a hack.</p>

<p>Google Messages and iMessage also offer end-to-end encryption, but only for messages sent between devices of the same operating system. Additionally, users are advised to avoid relying on default SMS or MMS services, as these lack adequate protection against interception.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our suggestion, what we have told folks internally, is not new here: Encryption is your friend, whether it's on text messaging or if you can use encrypted voice communication. Even if the adversary is able to intercept the data, if it is encrypted, it will make it impossible," Jeff Greene, the executive assistant director for cybersecurity at the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CSIA), told <em>NBC News.</em></p>

<p>An anonymous FBI official recommended that individuals seeking enhanced communication security consider using cellphones that receive timely operating system updates, devices with responsibly managed encryption and accounts protected by phishing-resistant two-factor authentication.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dirbakug_texts_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[To enhance security, the FBI recommends using encrypted messaging platforms]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>