<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:47:33 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weeks-after-blue-screen-of-death-cyberattack-causes-new-microsoft-outage-6238819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Weeks After "Blue Screen Of Death", Microsoft Suffers New Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weeks-after-blue-screen-of-death-cyberattack-causes-new-microsoft-outage-6238819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:44:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The tech giant said it was a DDoS attack that floods a service with traffic in order to bring them to a standstill.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Less than two weeks after global outage, dubbed as "blue screen of death", Microsoft suffered another similar incident, which the company said was triggered by a distributed denial of service (DDoS) cyberattack. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kateoflahertyuk/2024/07/31/microsoft-confirms-new-outage-was-triggered-by-cyberattack/">According to <em>Forbes</em></a>, the latest attack was reported by several users on Tuesday in which users complained of not being able to access several Microsoft services, such as Office, Outlook and Azure. The incident lasted nearly 10 hours. Companies affected by the new outage include UK bank NatWest, as per the <em>BBC</em>.</p>

<p>Other impacted services included Azure App Services, Application Insights, Azure IoT Central, Azure Log Search Alerts, Azure Policy, as well as the Azure portal itself and "a subset of Microsoft 365 and Microsoft Purview services".</p>

<p>The tech giant said it was a DDoS attack that floods a service with traffic in order to bring them to a standstill.</p>

<p>Firms usually put protection in place for DDoS attacks, but an error in the implementation of defences "amplified the impact of the attack rather than mitigating it", said Microsoft.</p>

<p>This is the second major attack in nearly as many weeks. A Microsoft error had crippled Windows computers worldwide on July 19. It was later revealed that an update to the anti-virus program 'Falcon Sensor' by CrowdStrike caused the massive outage.</p>

<p>From airlines to news channels, the glitch led to the crashing of IT systems, disrupting the daily proceedings.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike's products are predominantly used by major organisations needing robust cyber attack protection, which is why the attack caused a global outage.</p>

<p>Reacting to the glitch, Crowdstrike CEO George Kurtz said it was not a security incident or cyberattack. The company identified the issue, isolated it and deployed a fix.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2558qqf_microsoft-outage_625x300_20_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The July 19 outage impacted airlines across the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-military-chief-mohammed-deif-killed-in-gaza-strike-israel-6238816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Military Chief Mohammed Deif Killed In Gaza Strike: Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-military-chief-mohammed-deif-killed-in-gaza-strike-israel-6238816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:44:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military on Thursday announced that Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif had been killed in a strike it carried out last month in Gaza's southern area of Khan Yunis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military on Thursday announced that Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif had been killed in a strike it carried out last month in Gaza's southern area of Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>The military's confirmation it had killed Deif comes a day after the killing of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, which was announced by Iranian Revolutionary Guards and Hamas.</p>

<p>"The IDF (Israeli army) announces that on July 13th, 2024, IDF fighter jets struck in the area of Khan Yunis, and following an intelligence assessment, it can be confirmed that Mohammed Deif was eliminated in the strike," a military statement said.</p>

<p>"Deif initiated, planned, and executed the October 7th massacre," the military said of the Hamas attack on southern Israel that resulted in the death of 1,197 people, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Health authorities in Hamas-run Gaza said at the time of the July 13 strike that it killed more than 90 people but Hamas denied Deif was among them.</p>

<p>The suspected 2,000-pound bomb (900 kilogrammes0 around the house where Deif was said to have taken refuge with one of his deputies had left a giant crater.</p>

<p>The head of the Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, Hamas's armed wing, Deif had been among Israel's most wanted man for nearly three decades and on a US list of "international terrorists" since 2015.</p>

<p>The military said Deif had over the years carried out several attacks against Israel.</p>

<p>Deif operated along with Yahya Sinwar, the head of Hamas in Gaza, the military said.</p>

<p>"During the war, he commanded Hamas's terrorist activity in the Gaza Strip by issuing commands and instructions to senior members of Hamas's military wing," it added.</p>

<p>During the Hamas attack militants also seized 251 people, 111 are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign since then has killed 39,480 people, according to the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza, which does not provide details of civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/pulthnp_mohammed-deif_625x300_11_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kerala-police-has-warned-against-dark-tourism-know-what-it-is-6237006]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kerala Police Has Warned Against 'Dark Tourism'. Know What It Is]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kerala-police-has-warned-against-dark-tourism-know-what-it-is-6237006]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:45:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dark tourism has gained global attention in recent years, partly thanks to TV shows like Chernobyl and The Dark Tourist.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 167 people died in the devastating landslides in Wayanad on Wednesday. In response to the tragedy, Kerala authorities are urging the public to avoid the area, warning against "dark tourism" that may hinder critical rescue efforts.</p>

<p>"Please don't go to disaster areas for sightseeing. It will affect rescue operations. Call 112 for assistance," Kerala Police warned in a message posted on X.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ml">ദയവായി കാഴ്ചകൾ കാണാൻ ദുരന്ത പ്രദേശങ്ങളിലേക്ക് പോകരുത്????????<br />
അത് രക്ഷാപ്രവർത്തനത്തെ ബാധിക്കും<br />
<br />
സഹായങ്ങൾക്ക് 112 എന്ന നമ്പറിൽ വിളിക്കാം <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/keralapolice?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#keralapolice</a> <a href="https://t.co/D6irnQICNJ">pic.twitter.com/D6irnQICNJ</a></p>
— Kerala Police (@TheKeralaPolice) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheKeralaPolice/status/1818165471226826822?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h2><strong>What is 'dark tourism'?</strong></h2>

<p>Dark tourism, a phenomenon gaining significant attention in recent years, has been thrust into the global spotlight by TV shows like Chernobyl and The Dark Tourist. But what is it?&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dark tourism refers to the practice of travelling to and visiting sites associated with death, suffering, tragedy, violence, or the unusual. These destinations can include cemeteries, mausoleums, mortuaries, disaster zones, battlefields, memorials, prisons, execution sites, and crime scenes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dark tourism destinations may include the Chernobyl exclusion zone in Ukraine, the Killing Fields in Cambodia, the Auschwitz camp in Poland, and the 9/11 Memorial in the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other sites might be haunted houses, paranormal activity, or infamous historical events.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Definitions of 'dark tourism'</strong></h2>

<p>One of the earliest definitions of dark tourism was provided by <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0826450644/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=lifeasabutter-21&amp;creative=6738&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0826450644&amp;linkId=ea7f09c74fbeea0c9125d950ed1088ff ">John Lennon and Malcolm Foley</a>, who described it as "the representation of inhuman acts, and how these are interpreted for visitors."</p>

<p>A more recent definition by <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/9781405165518.wbeosd045.pub2">Kevin Fox Gotham</a> expands on this idea, describing dark tourism as "the circulation of people to places characterised by distress, atrocity or sadness and pain."</p>

<p>Mr Gotham also introduced the concept of "disaster tourism", which refers to situations where tourism rises in response to a major disaster or traumatic event.</p>

<h2><strong>Why dark tourism is popular</strong></h2>

<p>For many, the appeal of dark tourism lies in the emotional connection they make with a place of tragedy. Visitors seek to immerse themselves in the history and culture of a location and connect with the emotions of those who experienced the tragedy firsthand.</p>

<p>By visiting these sites, people can tangibly engage with the past, paying respects to those who suffered. Dark tourism allows individuals to process and understand the significance of historical events and reflect on history.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-09/auschwitz-memorial650_650x400_81441163783.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dark tourism is a phenomenon gaining significant attention in recent years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-to-meet-cops-after-protests-chant-save-our-kids-over-southport-knife-killings-6238027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK PM To Meet Cops Over Stabbing Attack As Protesters Chant "Save Our Kids"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-to-meet-cops-after-protests-chant-save-our-kids-over-southport-knife-killings-6238027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:07:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There were angry scenes in London on Wednesday evening as thousands of anti-immigration protesters gathered near Starmer's Downing Street office and residence chanting "save our kids" and "we want our country back".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer will meet senior police leaders on Thursday, his office said, between after a second night of clashes between protesters and police prompted by the deaths of three young girls in a frenzied knife attack at a dance class.</p>

<p>There were angry scenes in London on Wednesday evening as thousands of anti-immigration protesters gathered near Starmer's Downing Street office and residence chanting "save our kids" and "we want our country back".</p>

<p>The previous night more than 50 police officers were injured in violent clashes in the English seaside town of Southport, where Monday's stabbings took place.</p>

<p>A 17-year-old male was in police custody on suspicion of murder and attempted murder after the bloody rampage on Monday at a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-in-shock-taylor-swift-on-uk-mass-stabbings-that-killed-3-girls-6224379" target="_blank">"Taylor Swift</a> yoga and dance workshop", a summer vacation event for children aged 6 to 11.</p>

<p>Starmer's office said he would use Thursday's meeting with police to "offer them the government's full backing following multiple high-profile incidents of extreme violence and public disorder on our streets".</p>

<p>"While the right to peaceful protest must be protected at all costs, he will be clear that criminals who exploit that right in order to sow hatred and carry out violent acts will face the full force of the law," his office added.</p>

<p>The disorder took place after false information was spread on social media that the suspect was a radical Islamist migrant.</p>

<p>Police are legally restricted in the details they can provide about the alleged teenage attacker, but they have said the incident was not terrorism-related and that he was born in Britain, quashing speculation on his origins.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/0ogi588k_keir-starmer_625x300_23_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 50 police officers were injured in violent clashes in the English town of Southport (AFP)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voting-for-kamala-harriss-democratic-nomination-set-to-begin-today-6237769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Voting For Kamala Harris's Democratic Nomination Set To Begin Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voting-for-kamala-harriss-democratic-nomination-set-to-begin-today-6237769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:52:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Less than two weeks after Joe Biden ended his re election bid, his 52-year-old vice president is in full control of the party, having emerged as the only Democrat in the running to challenge Republican Donald Trump in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris will be confirmed as the Democratic US presidential nominee in an electronic vote starting Thursday that replaces the fanfare of in-person balloting that usually kicks off the party's national convention.</p>

<p>Less than two weeks after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/joe-biden-explains-why-he-ended-re-election-bid-818521" target="_blank">Joe Biden ended his re election bid</a>, his 52-year-old vice president is in full control of the party, having emerged as the only Democrat in the running to challenge Republican Donald Trump in November.</p>

<p>Just under 4,000 delegates, the grassroots activists and politicians allocated during the primary process, sent in signatures backing Harris to be on the ballot for the five-day electronic vote.</p>

<p>No other Democrats have stepped forward to challenge her elevation to the top of the ticket, making her confirmation as the first Black and South Asian woman ever to secure a major party's nomination a formality.</p>

<p>She won the support of 99 percent of the delegates who signed petitions, the Democratic National Committee (DNC) said in a statement, while no one else met the qualifying threshold of 300 signatures.</p>

<p>"Our delegates have an important responsibility -- and opportunity -- in the days ahead to cast their history-making ballots for Vice President Harris, ensuring that she will be on the ballot in every state this November," said DNC chair Jaime Harrison.</p>

<p>"Our party has met this unprecedented moment with a transparent, democratic and orderly process to unite behind a nominee with a proven record who will lead us in the fight ahead."</p>

<p>As well as the "pledged" delegates there are around 700 so-called "superdelegates" who get to vote because they hold elected office -- such as state governors or members of the US Congress -- or are party officials.</p>

<p>The roll call launches at 9:00 am (1300 GMT) Thursday and delegates have until 6:00 pm (2000 GMT) on Monday to return their votes via an online platform run by the DNC.</p>

<p>The announcement could come late Monday, as she hits the campaign trail for a swing across seven crucial battleground states with her newly minted running mate, who has not yet been announced.</p>

<p>US media reported that she would kick off the tour in Pennsylvania on Tuesday, although the DNC did not immediately respond to a request for confirmation.</p>

<p>The 2024 nominating system is largely as it was in 2020, when the Covid-19 pandemic prevented a large in-person convention, but it is still unusual.</p>

<p>The DNC swapped to a virtual process because of Ohio's deadline -- Wednesday next week -- for major parties to submit the names of their certified candidates for the November election.</p>

<p>Much remains unclear about the announcement of the results, however.</p>

<p>The DNC has not revealed if the vote will be livestreamed or if a rolling tally will be available to the public, and has not disclosed whether it would make the results public before the end of the voting period if they were available.</p>

<p>The virtual roll-call marks the official beginning of the 2024 convention, although in practice the festivities get going when thousands of the party's grassroots activists descend on Chicago on August 19.</p>

<p>There will be ceremonial votes for Harris and her running mate in Illinois, in what is expected to be a raucous celebration of her rise from state politics to the top of the ticket.</p>

<p>"Think about this: her dad is of Jamaican descent, her mother's of South Asian descent and then she went to the great Howard University, worked in California, worked in the United States Senate," Georgia Senator Raphael Warnock told a raucous, 10,000-strong crowd at Harris's rally in Atlanta on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"That is the American story. She brings all of those strands together. She sees us because in a real sense she is all of us."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/f31c6agc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris won the support of 99 percent of the delegates who signed petitions (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-ismail-haniyeh-hamas-leader-killed-in-iran-6228475]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Was Ismail Haniyeh, Hamas Leader Killed In Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-ismail-haniyeh-hamas-leader-killed-in-iran-6228475]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 11:05:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was assassinated in Tehran, Iran, on July 31, the Palestinian militant group said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas leader <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024 ">Ismail Haniyeh was assassinated</a> in Tehran, Iran, on July 31, the Palestinian militant group said. According to Iranian state media, Haniyeh and one of his bodyguards were killed in a strike on the building they were staying in.</p>

<p>The Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) said that Haniyeh was in Tehran to attend the inauguration ceremony of Iran's President Masoud Pezeshkian when the incident occurred.</p>

<p>Hamas released a statement condemning the attack and saying Haniyeh was killed in "a treacherous Zionist raid on his residence in Tehran". This allegation has not been confirmed by Iranian authorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Here are some facts about the Hamas leader:</strong></p>

<p>1. Ismail Haniyeh was born on January 29, 1962, in the Shati refugee camp in Gaza City, Gaza Strip. His family, Palestinian refugees, fled their home near the present-day Israeli town of Ashkelon during the 1948 Arab-Israeli war. He studied Arabic literature at the Islamic University of Gaza, graduating in 1987.&nbsp;</p>

<p>2. Haniyeh's involvement in politics began in the 1980s as a student leader at the Islamic University. He was a key figure in the founding of Hamas in 1987 and became a close advisor to Hamas founder Sheikh Ahmed Yassin. After Yassin's assassination in 2004, Haniyeh became the deputy chief of Hamas's political bureau. In 2017, he succeeded Khaled Mashal as the political chief of Hamas.</p>

<p>3. In 1988, he was <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyeh-facts-about-the-hamas-leader-that-ordered-attack-on-israel-4467224 ">arrested by Israeli authorities</a> for joining the First Intifada, a mass uprising against Israeli occupation that began in 1987 and lasted until 1993. He spent six months in jail and was arrested again in 1989. In 1992, he was deported to south Lebanon along with 400 other Islamists.</p>

<p>4. Haniyeh became the Prime Minister of the Palestinian Authority in 2006, a position he held until 2007. During this time, Hamas secured a surprising majority in the 2006 Palestinian legislative council elections. However, internal strife with rival Fatah led to the disbandment of the government and the formation of an independent Hamas-led administration in the Gaza Strip, which Haniyeh led from 2007 to 2014.&nbsp;</p>

<p>5. Ismail Haniyeh was married and was father to five children. His three sons, Hazem, Amir and Mohammad, were killed in an Israeli airstrike in Gaza on April 10, 2024.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel vowed to kill Ismail Haniyeh and destroy Hamas after the October 7 attack that killed 1,195 people. Since then, Israel's war on Gaza has killed 39,400 people and caused injuries to 90,923&nbsp;others, according to the Gaza Health Ministry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v49bimrg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ismail Haniyeh was married and was father to five children.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/co-pilot-faints-on-lisbon-bound-flight-rare-red-alert-issued-6236842]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Co-Pilot Faints On Lisbon-Bound Flight, Rare "Red Alert" Issued]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/co-pilot-faints-on-lisbon-bound-flight-rare-red-alert-issued-6236842]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:13:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Airbus A320 aircraft issued a rare "red alert," which is an obligatory stop of operations as a safety precaution, as the medical situation developed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An co-pilot was hospitalised after he fainted on a flight from London to Portugal on July 27. He became ill during the approach to Lisbon Airport on easyJet Flight EZY2459 from Luton. Upon landing, he was attended to by paramedics at the airport. The first officer was then sent to Santa Maria Hospital in Lisbon for medical treatment, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/news-and-advice/pilot-faints-easyjet-flight-lisbon-b2587488.html"><em>Independent</em></a>.</p>

<p>The Airbus A320 aircraft issued a rare "red alert," which is an obligatory stop of operations as a safety precaution, as the medical situation developed. The 193-passenger flight made a safe, "in line with procedures" landing in Portugal.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for easyJet said in a statement: "easyJet can confirm that the flight EZY2459 from Luton to Lisbon was met by the paramedics upon landing due to a pilot member feeling unwell.</p>

<p>"The Captain landed the flight routinely in line with procedures and passengers disembarked normally. At no point was the safety of the flight compromised. The safety and welfare of passengers and crew is easyJet's highest priority," they said.</p>

<p>Notably, passengers leaving for the return trip to London from Luton experienced a three-hour delay.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a few weeks ago, a pilot of a small aircraft experienced a medical emergency when a passenger took over and the aircraft crashed on an island in Massachusetts, US, as per The Washington Post.</p>

<p>The event happened in West Tisbury, Massachusetts, close to Martha's Vineyard Airport. According to Massachusetts State Police, the male pilot, who is aged 79, experienced an emergency during the plane's final approach. "The crash resulted in a hard landing outside the runway that caused the aircraft's left wing to break in half," The Post quoted the state police as saying.</p>

<p>The pilot was then taken to a Boston hospital in critical condition. The female passenger was not hurt and was released from a local hospital, according to The Post, citing authorities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0mus0ih_easyjet_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 193-passenger flight made a safe, "in line with procedures" landing in Portugal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-drug-lord-el-chapos-son-not-involved-in-kidnapping-says-lawyer-6236700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexican Drug Lord El Chapo's Son Didn't Kidnap Fellow Gangster, Says Lawyer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-drug-lord-el-chapos-son-not-involved-in-kidnapping-says-lawyer-6236700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 09:58:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The son of jailed Sinaloa Cartel kingpin Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman did not kidnap drug lord Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada, the Guzman family's lawyer said on Wednesday, following reports Guzman's son had betrayed Zambada to the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The son of jailed Sinaloa Cartel kingpin Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman did not kidnap drug lord Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada, the Guzman family's lawyer said on Wednesday, following reports Guzman's son had betrayed Zambada to the United States.</p>

<p>Joaquin Guzman Lopez and Zambada, one of the most consequential traffickers in Mexican history, were arrested last week by US agents after the plane in which they were travelling landed at a small airfield in New Mexico.</p>

<p>After the arrests, carried out without the knowledge of the Mexican government, speculation abounded as to whether the two had surrendered or Guzman Lopez had lured Zambada into a trap.</p>

<p>"A kidnapping is out of the question," the Guzman family lawyer, Jose Luis Gonzalez, told Radio Formula.</p>

<p>"No, no. Los Chapitos abide by their father's rules and they followed the usual policy," he said when asked whether Guzman Lopez may have betrayed the 76-year-old Zambada, who co-founded the legendary Sinaloa Cartel alongside his father.</p>

<p>El Chapo's four sons, known as "Los Chapitos," inherited their father's faction of the cartel.</p>

<p>Reuters reached out to Gonzalez but was unable to get an immediate comment.</p>

<p>His account contradicts Zambada's lawyer, Frank Perez, who said on Saturday that Guzman Lopez "kidnapped" his client.</p>

<p>Perez said Guzman Lopez and six men in military uniforms ambushed Zambada near the Sinaloa state capital of Culiacan and forced him onto a plane to the United States against his will.</p>

<p>Both Guzman Lopez and Zambada have pleaded not guilty to drug trafficking charges in US courts.</p>

<p>The Guzman family lawyer said the men's surrender was voluntary and followed about four years of negotiations with US authorities.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7vj0hpbo_joaquin-guzman-lopez-_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joaquin Guzman, one of the most consequential traffickers, was arrested last week by US Agents (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-advises-citizens-to-avoid-all-non-essential-travel-to-lebanon-6236419]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Advises Citizens To Avoid All Non-Essential Travel To Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-advises-citizens-to-avoid-all-non-essential-travel-to-lebanon-6236419]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 09:01:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid escalating tensions in the region, Indian Embassy in Lebanon has advised Indians to avoid all non-essential travel to Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid escalating tensions in the region, Indian Embassy in Lebanon has advised Indians to avoid all non-essential travel to Lebanon. They have been advised to exercise caution, restrict movements and remain in contact with Indian Embassy in Beirut.</p>

<p>Taking to X, the Indian Embassy in Lebanon stated, "In view of the recent escalations in the region, Indian nationals are advised to avoid all non-essential travel to Lebanon. All Indian nationals in Lebanon are advised to exercise caution, restrict their movements and remain in contact with Embassy of India in Beirut through their email id: cons.beirut@mea.gov.in or the emergency phone number 96176860128."</p>

<p>Tensions have further escalated after the rocket attack at Golan Heights, allegedly fired by Hezbollah killed 12 children. In response to the attack at Golan Heights, The Israel Defence Forces (IDF) said that top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr was killed in the Israeli strike in southern Lebanon on Tuesday (local time).</p>

<p>Fuad Shukr, the "most senior Hezbollah military commander," was killed in the Israeli strike, the IDF said in a statement. Shukr sat on the Jihad Council, Hezbollah's top military body, and was considered to be the head of its strategic division.</p>

<p>Since the October 7 attack by Hamas, he has been managing Hezbollah's attacks against Israel, including the deadly strike in Majdal Shams over the weekend that killed 12 children, according to the military.The IDF says Shukr was "responsible for the majority of Hezbollah's most advanced weaponry, including precise-guided missiles, cruise missiles, anti-ship missiles, long-range rockets, and UAVs" and for the terror group's "force build-up, planning, and execution of terror attacks against the State of Israel," as reported by The Times of Israel.</p>

<p>"Eliminated: Fuad Shukr "Sayyid Muhsan," Hezbollah's Most Senior Military Commander and Hassan Nasrallah's Right-Hand Man," the IDF said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"Shukr has directed Hezbollah's attacks on the State of Israel since October 8th, and he was the commander responsible for the murder of the 12 children in Majdal Shams in northern Israel on Saturday evening, as well as the killing of numerous Israelis and foreign nationals over the years. He was also responsible for the majority of Hezbollah's most advanced weaponry, including precise-guided missiles, cruise missiles, anti-ship missiles, long-range rockets and UAVs," it added.</p>

<p>Houthis and Hamas have both condemned the Israeli strike in separate statements, CNN reported.</p>

<p>"While we affirm our solidarity with Lebanon and its resistance in the face of Zionist arrogance, we appreciate the great role of Hezbollah in supporting the Palestinian people and triumphing over their oppression, at a time when the Arab regimes have abandoned their role and responsibility in defending the Palestinian people and confronting crimes," a statement read from the Houthi political wing, also known as Ansar Allah.</p>

<p>In another statement, Hamas declared "full solidarity with our brotherly Lebanon and the brothers in Hezbollah."</p>

<p>Hamas also said it considers the Israeli strike a "dangerous escalation."Israel had blamed Hezbollah for the rocket attack at Golan Heights on Sunday. However, Hezbollah has denied responsibility for the attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/heo7ka68_israeli-strike-on-lebanon_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tensions have further escalated after the rocket attack at Golan Heights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/half-of-dementia-cases-could-be-curbed-by-addressing-key-risk-factors-study-6236379]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Half Of Dementia Cases Can Be Curbed By Addressing These Key Risk Factors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/half-of-dementia-cases-could-be-curbed-by-addressing-key-risk-factors-study-6236379]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 08:43:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of cases of dementia could be prevented or delayed by reducing a range of risk factors such as smoking or air pollution, according to a major new study, though outside experts warn that such measures can only go so far.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of cases of dementia could be prevented or delayed by reducing a range of risk factors such as smoking or air pollution, according to a major new study, though outside experts warn that such measures can only go so far.</p>

<p>The debilitating condition, which progressively robs people of their memories, cognitive abilities, language and independence, currently affects more than 55 million people across the world.</p>

<p>Dementia is caused by a range of diseases, the most common of which is Alzheimer's.</p>

<p>A huge review of the available evidence published in The Lancet journal on Wednesday said that the "potential for prevention is high" in the fight against dementia.</p>

<p>The study follows a previous report in 2020 that also emphasised the importance of prevention.</p>

<p>At the time, the international team of researchers estimated that 40 per cent of dementia cases were linked to 12 risk factors.</p>

<p>The factors included people having a lower level of education, hearing problems, high blood pressure, smoking, obesity, depression, physical inactivity, diabetes, excessive drinking, traumatic brain injury, air pollution and social isolation.</p>

<p>The latest update adds two more risk factors: vision loss and high cholesterol.</p>

<p>"Nearly half of dementias could theoretically be prevented by eliminating these 14 risk factors," the study said.</p>

<h3><strong>EU turns down new drug</strong></h3>

<p>Decades of research and billions of dollars have failed to produce a cure or truly effective drug for dementia.</p>

<p>But since the start of last year, two Alzheimer's treatments have been approved in the United States: Biogen's lecanemab and Eli Lilly's donanemab.</p>

<p>They work by targeting the build-up of two proteins -- tau and amyloid beta -- considered to be one of the main ways the disease progresses.</p>

<p>However, the benefits of the drugs remain modest, they have severe side effects, and they are often very expensive.</p>

<p>In contrast to the US, the European Union's medicine watchdog last week refused to approve lecanemab, and it is still considering donanemab.</p>

<p>Some researchers hope the fact that the new drugs work at all means they will pave the way for more effective treatments in the future.</p>

<p>Others prefer to focus on ways to prevent dementia in the first place.</p>

<p>Masud Husain, a neurologist at the UK's University of Oxford, said that focusing on risk factors "would be far more cost-effective than developing high-tech treatments which so far have been disappointing in their impacts on people with established dementia".</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'How much more could we do?'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Lancet study was welcomed by experts in the field, among whom the importance of prevention is hardly debatable.</p>

<p>However, some said the idea that nearly half of all dementia cases could be prevented should be put in perspective.</p>

<p>It has not been proven that the risk factors directly cause dementia, as the authors of the study acknowledged.</p>

<p>For example, could it be dementia that is causing depression, rather than the other way around?</p>

<p>It is also difficult to separate the risk factors from each other, though the researchers tried.</p>

<p>Some could be intrinsically linked, such as depression and isolation, or smoking and high blood pressure.</p>

<p>Above all, many of the risk factors are societal scourges that have long proven near impossible to fully address.</p>

<p>The study lays out different recommendations ranging from the personal -- such as wearing a helmet while cycling -- to governmental, such as improving access to education.</p>

<p>"It is not clear whether we could ever completely eliminate any of these risk factors," Charles Marshall, a neurologist at Queen Mary University of London, told AFP.</p>

<p>"We already have public health programmes to reduce smoking and hypertension (high blood pressure), so how much more could we do?"</p>

<p>Tara Spires-Jones, a neuroscientist at the University of Edinburgh, said it was important that "we do not blame people living with dementia for their brain disease".</p>

<p>That is because "it is clear that a large portion of dementias could not be prevented due to genes and things beyond people's control, like opportunities for education as children", she added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-07/6g03e98o_dementia-_625x300_15_July_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dementia robs people of their memories and cognitive abilities (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-leader-to-lead-funeral-prayers-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6236223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Leader Ayatollah To Lead Funeral Prayers For Hamas Chief Ismail Haniyeh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-leader-to-lead-funeral-prayers-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6236223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 08:02:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran was set to hold funeral processions on Thursday for Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh ahead of his burial in Doha after he was killed in a strike in Tehran blamed on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran was set to hold funeral processions on Thursday for Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh ahead of his burial in Doha after he was killed in a strike in Tehran blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>The Islamic Republic's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei will lead the prayers for Haniyeh, having earlier threatened a "harsh punishment" for his killing.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's death was announced on Wednesday by Iran's Revolutionary Guards, who said he and his bodyguard were killed in a strike on their accommodation in the Iranian capital at 2:00 am (2230 GMT).</p>

<p>It came just hours after Israel targeted and killed top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr in a retaliatory strike on the Lebanese capital of Beirut, sending fears of a wider regional war soaring.</p>

<p>Israel declined to comment on the Tehran strike.</p>

<p>Khamenei, who has the final say in Iran's political affairs, said after Haniyeh's death that it was "our duty to seek revenge for his blood as he was martyred in the territory of the Islamic Republic of Iran".</p>

<p>The Hamas leader was in Tehran for the inauguration ceremony of newly elected President Masoud Pezeshkian on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The Iranian president said on Wednesday that "the Zionists (Israel) will soon see the consequences of their cowardly and terrorist act".</p>

<p>Hamas political bureau member Musa Abu Marzuk also vowed retaliation, saying: "The assassination of leader Ismail Haniyeh is a cowardly act and will not go unanswered."</p>

<p>The international community, however, called for de-escalation and a focus on securing a ceasefire in Gaza.</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said the strikes in Tehran and Beirut represented a "dangerous escalation".</p>

<p>All efforts, he said, should be "leading to a ceasefire" in Gaza and the release of hostages taken during Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken also said Wednesday that a ceasefire in Gaza was still the "imperative".</p>

<h3><strong>Truce talks threatened&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>From the early hours of Wednesday, crowds took to the streets in cities across Iran to condemn Haniyeh's killing, with hundreds gathering in Tehran's Palestine Square to chant "Death to Israel, Death to America".</p>

<p>The Islamic Republic has not yet published any information on the exact location of the strike.</p>

<p>While Iran has blamed the attack on its arch-foe, Israel has declined to comment on Haniyeh's death. It did, however, claim the killing of Shukr, whom it blamed for a deadly weekend rocket strike on the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it "eliminated" Hezbollah's top commander in the strike, and a source close to the group said Wednesday that they had found his body in the rubble. Iran's IRNA news agency said Iranian military adviser Milad Bidi also died.</p>

<p>The killings come with regional tensions already inflamed by the war in Gaza, a conflict that has drawn in Iran-backed militant groups in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Hamas has for months been indirectly negotiating a truce and hostage-prisoner exchange deal with Israel, with Egypt, Qatar and the United States facilitating the talks.</p>

<p>Analysts told AFP that Haniyeh was a moderating influence within the Islamist group and that while he would be replaced, the dynamics within Hamas could change.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has vowed to destroy Hamas in retaliation for the October 7 attack that ignited war in Gaza.</p>

<p>That attack resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign against Hamas has killed at least 39,445 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>The prime minister of key ceasefire broker Qatar said Haniyeh's killing had thrown the whole mediation process into doubt.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/7qhr89n8_haniyeh-reuters-_625x300_19_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Hamas leader was in Tehran for the inauguration ceremony of newly elected President Masoud Pezeshkian]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-had-emergency-surgery-to-remove-lump-as-a-teen-reveals-new-book-6236131]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton Had Emergency Surgery To Remove Lump As A Teen, Says New Book]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-had-emergency-surgery-to-remove-lump-as-a-teen-reveals-new-book-6236131]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:24:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The surgery left a three-inch scar which several people noticed on Ms Middleton's first solo engagement over two decades ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kate Middleton, Princess of Wales, revealed in March that she has been diagnosed with cancer. Amid this, a new royal biography has revealed that she had an emergency surgery as a teenager to remove a lump from her head, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/kate-middleton-cancer-lump-removal-princess-wales-b2588167.html"><em>Independent</em></a>. This was shared by royal author Rob Jobson in his upcoming book, 'Catherine, the Princess of Wales'.</p>

<p>"Apart from debilitating bouts of morning sickness and, of course, stays in the Lindo Wing at St Mary's Hospital to deliver her babies, Catherine has fortunately avoided hospital for most of her life," Mr Jobson explained. "As a teenager, however, when at Marlborough College she discovered a lump on the left side of her head, just under her hairline," he added.</p>

<p>The author added that her mother took her to the hospital where the doctors removed it. "The school notified her parents immediately and her mother Carole took her to hospital, where she had surgery to remove it," he wrote in the book.</p>

<p>However, the operation left a three-inch scar which several people noticed on Ms Middleton's first solo engagement over two decades ago. The Buckingham Palace shared a brief statement that read, "'The scar is related to a childhood operation."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Princess said in June that she was making good progress as she was undergoing preventative chemotherapy. However, she was "not out of the woods".</p>

<p>In a personal written message, Ms Middleton said she had been "blown away" by the thousands of kind messages from across the globe which followed her cancer announcement in March. "I am making good progress, but as anyone going through chemotherapy will know, there are good days and bad days," her statement said.</p>

<p>She added, "On those bad days you feel weak, tired and you have to give in to your body resting. But on the good days, when you feel stronger, you want to make the most of feeling well." She said they had made a world of difference to her and her husband, heir-to-the-throne Prince William.</p>

<p>"My treatment is ongoing and will be for a few more months," she said. "I'm looking forward to attending The King's Birthday Parade this weekend with my family and hope to join a few public engagements over the summer, but equally knowing I am not out of the woods yet," she said on June 14.</p>

<p>The Princess of Wales was recently seen at the Wimbledon Men's final in London as she walked onto the court to present the trophy to winner Carlos Alcaraz. A passionate tennis fan and player herself, Kate was greeted with a thunderous ovation as she entered the Royal Box at Centre Court, accompanied by her daughter Princess Charlotte and sister Pippa Matthews.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/f5dovut8_kate-middleton-reuters_625x300_23_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Princess said in June that she was making good progress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comic-con-undercover-agents-at-comic-con-rescue-10-sex-trafficking-victims-6236130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Undercover Agents Posed As Sex Buyers At Comic Con To Rescue Victims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comic-con-undercover-agents-at-comic-con-rescue-10-sex-trafficking-victims-6236130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:22:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Undercover officers posing as sex buyers at last week's Comic-Con event in California rescued human trafficking victims, including a 16-year-old girl, and made multiple arrests, prosecutors said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Undercover officers posing as sex buyers at last week's Comic-Con event in California rescued human trafficking victims, including a 16-year-old girl, and made multiple arrests, prosecutors said Wednesday.</p>

<p>A task force involving local San Diego police, federal officers and naval intelligence arrested 14 people who were attempting to buy sex at the giant pop culture gathering.</p>

<p>Ten victims were rescued, nine of them adults, said California Attorney General Rob Bonta.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, sex traffickers capitalize on large-scale events such as Comic-Con to exploit their victims for profit," said Bonta, in a statement.</p>

<p>San Diego Comic-Con is one of the world's largest pop culture events.</p>

<p>Around 135,000 people were expected to attend the convention, which lasted from Thursday to Sunday.</p>

<p>"Obviously we find this very disturbing and, while we were not made aware of this operation, it is our understanding that the arrests were made outside of the event," a spokesperson for Comic-Con said in a statement to AFP.</p>

<p>"We work closely with a variety of law enforcement entities throughout the year and stand ready to assist in any way we can."</p>

<p>Originally a grassroots event for comic book fans to meet, Comic-Con has grown exponentially and is today used by giant Hollywood studios and A-list stars to launch their latest blockbuster movies and TV shows.</p>

<p>Christopher Davis, acting special agent in charge of Homeland Security Investigations in San Diego, said "highly attended events" like Comic-Con are often seen by criminals as "an opportunity to prey upon minors."</p>

<p>"Working together, teams identified and arrested more than a dozen individuals participating in these illegal acts in our city over the weekend," said San Diego Police Chief Scott Wahl.</p>

<p>Law enforcement personnel placed undercover advertisements soliciting sex in order to arrest sex buyers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nial63jo_comic-con-afp-_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[San Diego Comic-Con is one of the world's largest pop culture events.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-accepts-dare-to-fight-venezuela-president-whats-at-stake-6236030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If I Win, He Resigns. If He Wins...": Elon Musk Dares Venezuela President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-accepts-dare-to-fight-venezuela-president-whats-at-stake-6236030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 06:50:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has accepted a challenge to fight Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro on national television. The SpaceX and Tesla chief, and the owner of the social network X, took to his platform to respond to Maduro's challenge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has accepted a challenge to fight Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro on national television. The SpaceX and Tesla chief, and the owner of the social network X, took to his platform to respond to Maduro's challenge. "I accept," he tweeted, sparking a flurry of reactions online.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The animosity between Musk and Maduro has been brewing for some time amidst political turmoil in Caracas. Maduro, whose victory in the recent elections has been widely contested, has found a foe in Musk, a staunch ultra-capitalist and supporter of Donald Trump. This ideological clash pits billionaire Musk against Maduro, a socialist leader who rose from humble beginnings as a bus driver to preside over the oil-rich yet economically struggling nation.</p>

<p>Maduro has accused Musk of orchestrating attacks against Venezuela, alleging that the tech mogul is behind a supposed "computer hacking" at the National Electoral Council (CNE). The CNE controversially declared Maduro the winner of the latest vote without providing detailed data, a move that has led to allegations of foul play.</p>

<p>Following Musk's public comments against him, Maduro responded by saying, "Social media creates a virtual reality, and who controls the virtual reality? Our new archenemy, the famous Elon Musk," he began his speech. Do you want to fight? Let's do it. Elon Musk, I'm ready," Maduro said. I'm not afraid of you Elon Musk. Let's fight, wherever you want."</p>

<p>Musk took to X and replied to a lot of people reacting to the development. In one particular post Musk referred to Maduro as a "big guy", while taking a sly dig at Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg by terming him a "little fella".</p>

<p>"Maduro is a big guy himself and probably knows how to fight, so this would be a real fight. Zuck is a little fella, so that would be a short fight lol," he posted.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Maduro is a big guy himself and probably knows how to fight, so this would be a real fight.<br />
<br />
Zuck is a little fella, so that would be a short fight lol.</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1818700101520703898?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 31, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"If I win, he resigns as dictator of Venezuela. If he wins, I give him a free ride to Mars," Musk wagered.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">If I win, he resigns as dictator of Venezuela.<br />
<br />
If he wins, I give him a free ride to Mars.</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1818699112134721953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 31, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Following the Venezuelan election results, Musk expressed his disapproval, calling Maduro a "dictator" and describing the election as a "travesty." He even posted a 2020 announcement from the US Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) about criminal charges against Maduro for drug trafficking, which includes a $15 million reward for information leading to his arrest.</p>

<p>Maduro's response was fiery. "He wants to come here with his guns and an army to invade Venezuela. Elon Musk, good thing you showed your face because we knew you were behind it all! With your money and your satellites," Maduro claimed.</p>

<p>Musk's retort was sharp and in Spanish: "An ass knows more than Maduro." He later apologised, albeit sarcastically, adding, "Sorry to have compared the poor ass to Maduro. That was an insult to the animal kingdom."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5v31kjn8_maduro-musk-_625x300_01_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maduro has accused Musk of orchestrating attacks against Venezuela.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-year-old-male-charged-with-murder-of-3-girls-in-uk-knife-attack-6235857]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[17-Year-Old Male Charged With Murder Of 3 Girls In UK Knife Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-year-old-male-charged-with-murder-of-3-girls-in-uk-knife-attack-6235857]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 05:58:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 17-year-old male was charged on Thursday with the murder of three girls and the attempted murder of 10 more people in a knife attack at a Taylor Swift-themed dance class, UK prosecutors said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 17-year-old male was charged on Thursday with the murder of three girls and the attempted murder of 10 more people in a knife attack at a Taylor Swift-themed dance class, UK prosecutors said.</p>

<p>"The Crown Prosecution Service (CPS) has authorised Merseyside Police to charge a 17-year-old male of Banks, Lancashire, with three counts of murder and ten counts of attempted murder, following the tragic incident that took place in Southport this week," prosecutors said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2hmhj068_uk-police_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 17-year-old male was charged on Thursday with the murder of three girls.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-wants-to-restart-nuclear-talks-if-donald-trump-wins-says-ex-diplomat-6235708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Wants To Restart Nuclear Talks If Trump Wins, Says Ex-Diplomat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-wants-to-restart-nuclear-talks-if-donald-trump-wins-says-ex-diplomat-6235708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 05:06:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea wants to reopen nuclear talks with the United States if Donald Trump is re-elected as president and is working to devise a new negotiating strategy, a senior North Korean diplomat who recently defected to South Korea told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea wants to reopen nuclear talks with the United States if Donald Trump is re-elected as president and is working to devise a new negotiating strategy, a senior North Korean diplomat who recently defected to South Korea told Reuters.</p>

<p>The escape of Ri Il Gyu from Cuba made headlines globally last month. He was the highest-ranking North Korean diplomat to defect to the South since 2016.</p>

<p>In his first interview with international media, Ri said North Korea has set Russia, the U.S. and Japan as its top foreign policy priorities for this year and beyond.</p>

<p>While bolstering relations with Russia, Pyongyang was keen to reopen nuclear negotiations if Trump - who engaged in both fiery brinkmanship and unprecedented diplomacy with North Korea during his previous term - won re-election in November, Ri said.</p>

<p>Pyongyang's diplomats were mapping out a strategy for that scenario, with the goal of lifting of sanctions on its weapons programmes, removing its designation as a state sponsor of terrorism and eliciting economic aid, said Ri.</p>

<p>His comments signal a potential about-face from the North's current stance after recent statements ditching the possibility of dialogue with the U.S. and warning of armed confrontation.</p>

<p>A summit between North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and Trump in Vietnam in 2019 collapsed over sanctions, for which Ri partly blamed Kim's decision to entrust "inexperienced, clueless" military commanders with nuclear diplomacy.</p>

<p>"Kim Jong Un doesn't know much about international relations and diplomacy, or how to make strategic judgment," he said.</p>

<p>"This time, the foreign ministry would definitely gain power and take charge, and it won't be so easy for Trump to tie North Korea's hands and feet again for four years without giving anything."</p>

<p><strong>RUSSIAN TIES, JAPAN AID</strong></p>

<p>By forging closer ties with Russia, North Korea received help with its missile technology and economy. But a bigger benefit could be to block additional sanctions and undercut existing ones, Ri said, adding it would raise Pyongyang's bargaining power against Washington.</p>

<p>"The Russians got their own hands dirty by engaging in illicit transactions and, thanks to that, North Korea no longer needs to rely on the U.S. to lift sanctions, which essentially means they stripped the U.S. of one key bargaining chip," he said.</p>

<p>In Tokyo, Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida has said he wants to meet Kim, but the issue of Japanese nationals abducted by North Korea in the 1970s and 80s has long been a stumbling block.</p>

<p>According to Ri, Kim would seek to hold a summit with Japan, aiming to get economic assistance in return for concessions on the abductee issue.</p>

<p>Tokyo believes 17 of its citizens were abducted, five of whom returned to Japan in 2002. Pyongyang sees the issue as settled, having admitted to kidnapping 13 Japanese nationals and saying those unaccounted for had either died or their whereabouts were unknown.</p>

<p>Ri said Kim would be willing to change that position, established under his father Kim Jong Il, in order to obtain economic support.</p>

<p>"They're saying that the issue was resolved, but that's just to boost negotiating power until he makes concessions at a summit," he said.</p>

<p><strong>RESENTMENT AND DEFECTION</strong></p>

<p>Having studied at a French school in Algeria and lived in Cuba alongside his late father, who was a state media reporter, Ri says he had imagined a life in South Korea since his childhood, but never acted to flee until he was bullied by a diplomatic colleague for refusing his demand for bribes.</p>

<p>Then the defining moment came when Pyongyang instantly refused his request to get medical treatment in Mexico, at his own expense, for a ruptured disc in his neck.</p>

<p>"That exploded all the resentment I had been harbouring towards the regime," he said.</p>

<p>The COVID-19 lockdown deepened hardships at home and for those stationed overseas, with most telephone lines to Pyongyang cut to prevent any information from spreading in the outside world, Ri said.</p>

<p>Financial troubles have also forced North Korea to shut down a dozen of its 54 diplomatic missions.</p>

<p>"When they began reopening and summoning those working abroad in early 2023, they asked to bring everything from used toothbrushes to spoons back home, saying there's nothing there," he said.</p>

<p>Ri had also witnessed - and in his job tried to impede - the launch of diplomatic relations between South Korea and Cuba, a Cold War-era ally of North Korea.</p>

<p>"I had done everything to block that from happening, but establishing relations with Cuba was the best thing South Korea had done since last year," he said. "It was a model example of how the tides of history have turned, and where a normal civilisation of the international community is headed."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/gm98ccao_donald-trump-kim-jong-un-reuters_625x300_12_June_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The historic talk between Donald Trump and Kim Jong Un was held in Singapore in June 2018.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-plea-deal-reached-with-9-11-mastermind-khalid-sheikh-mohammed-6235674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says Plea Deal Reached With 9/11 Mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-plea-deal-reached-with-9-11-mastermind-khalid-sheikh-mohammed-6235674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:52:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US prosecutors have reached a deal with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed, the Pentagon said Wednesday, reportedly involving a guilty plea in exchange for avoiding a death penalty trial.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US prosecutors have reached a deal with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed, the Pentagon said Wednesday, reportedly involving a guilty plea in exchange for avoiding a death penalty trial.</p>

<p>The agreements with Mohammed and two other accused moves their long-running cases toward resolution. These have been bogged down in pre-trial maneuverings for years while the defendants remained held at the Guantanamo Bay military base in Cuba.</p>

<p>A Pentagon statement said no details of the deal would be immediately made public at this time, but the New York Times reported that Mohammed, Walid bin Attash and Mustafa al-Hawsawi had agreed to plead guilty to conspiracy in exchange for a life sentence instead of a trial after they could get the death penalty.</p>

<p>Such a proposal was detailed by prosecutors in a letter last year but divided the families of the nearly 3,000 people killed in the September 11, 2001 attacks, with some still wanting the defendants to face the ultimate penalty.</p>

<p>Much of the legal jousting surrounding the men's cases has focused on whether they could be tried fairly after having undergone methodical torture at the hands of the CIA in the years after 9/11 -- a thorny question that the plea deals help avoid.</p>

<p>Mohammed was regarded as one of Al-Qaeda chief Osama bin Laden's most trusted and intelligent lieutenants before his March 2003 capture in Pakistan. He then spent three years in secret CIA prisons before arriving in Guantanamo in 2006.</p>

<p>The trained engineer -- who has said he masterminded the 9/11 attacks "from A to Z" -- was involved in a string of major plots against the United States, where he had attended university.</p>

<p>In addition to planning the operation to bring down the Twin Towers, Mohammed claims to have personally beheaded US journalist Daniel Pearl in 2002 with his "blessed right hand," and to have helped in the 1993 World Trade Center bombing that killed six people.</p>

<p>- 'War on Terror' prison -<br />
Bin Attash, a Saudi of Yemeni origin, allegedly trained two of the hijackers who carried out the September 11 attacks, and his US interrogators also said he confessed to buying the explosives and recruiting members of the team that killed 17 sailors in an attack on the USS Cole.</p>

<p>He took refuge in neighboring Pakistan after the US invasion of Afghanistan in 2001 and was captured there in 2003, and was then held in a network of secret CIA prisons.</p>

<p>Hawsawi is suspected of managing the finance for the 9/11 attacks. He was arrested in Pakistan on March 1, 2003, was also held in secret prisons before being transferred to Guantanamo in 2006.</p>

<p>The United States used Guantanamo, an isolated naval base, to hold militants captured during the "War on Terror" that followed the September 11 attacks in a bid to keep the defendants from claiming rights under US law.</p>

<p>The facility held 800 prisoners at its peak, but they have since slowly been repatriated to other countries. President Joe Biden pledged before his election to try and shut down Guantanamo, but it &nbsp;remains open.</p>

<p>In another 9/11-related case, the Justice Department denied a request by Zacarias Moussaoui, the so-called "20th hijacker," to serve the remainder of his life sentence in France.</p>

<p>In a hand-written letter to District Judge Leonie Brinkema obtained by the website Legal Insurrection, Moussaoui -- the only person convicted in the United States in connection with the September 11 attacks -- expressed fears he would be executed if Donald Trump regains the presidency in November.</p>

<p>A Justice Department spokeswoman said the department does not discuss prisoner transfer requests but noted that Moussaoui is "serving a life sentence following conviction for terrorism offenses."</p>

<p>"The Department of Justice plans to enforce this life sentence in US custody," the spokeswoman added.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/60bhh5ro_us-guantanamo-naval-base_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US used Guantanamo, an isolated naval base, to hold militants captured during the "War on Terror".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-orders-attack-on-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killing-report-6235614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's Leader Orders Attack On Israel After Hamas Chief's Killing: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-orders-attack-on-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killing-report-6235614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:36:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, has ordered Iran to strike Israel directly, in retaliation for the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, New York Times reported, citing three Iranian officials, briefed on the order.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, has ordered Iran to strike Israel directly, in retaliation for the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, New York Times reported, citing three Iranian officials, briefed on the order, including two members of the Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>Khamenei gave the order at an emergency meeting of Iran's Supreme National Security Council on Wednesday morning, shortly after Iran announced that Haniyeh had been killed.</p>

<p>Iran and Hamas have accused Israel of the assassination. Israel, which is at war with Hamas in the Gaza Strip, has neither acknowledged nor denied killing Haniyeh, who was in Tehran for the inauguration of Iran's new president.</p>

<p>Notably, Israel has a long history of killing enemies abroad, including Iranian nuclear scientists and military commanders, according to the NYT.</p>

<p>Through almost 10 months of war in Gaza, Iran has tried to strike a balance, putting pressure on Israel with sharply increased attacks by its allies and proxy forces in the region, while avoiding an all-out war between the two nations.</p>

<p>In its biggest and most overt attack on Israel, Iran launched hundreds of missiles and drones in April in retaliation for an Israeli strike on its embassy compound that killed several Iranian military commanders in the Syrian capital of Damascus.</p>

<p>"Now it is unclear how forcefully Iran will respond, and whether it will once again calibrate its attack to steer clear of escalation. Iranian military commanders are considering another combination attack of drones and missiles on military targets in the vicinity of Tel Aviv and Haifa, but would make a point of avoiding strikes on civilian targets," the Iranian officials said.</p>

<p>One option under consideration is a coordinated attack from Iran and other fronts where it has allied forces, including Yemen, Syria and Iraq, for maximum effect, they added.</p>

<p>Khamenei, who has the last word on all state matters and is also the commander in chief of the armed forces, instructed military commanders from the Revolutionary Guards and the army to prepare plans for both an attack and a defence in case the war expands and Israel or the US strike Iran, the officials said.</p>

<p>In his public statement about Haniyeh's death, Khamenei signalled that Iran would retaliate directly, saying, "we see avenging his blood our duty," because it happened on the territory of the Islamic Republic. He said Israel had set the stage for receiving "a severe punishment," New York Times reported.</p>

<p>Other Iranian officials, including the newly elected president, Masoud Pezeshkian, the foreign ministry, the Guards and Iran's mission to the UN, also said openly that Iran would retaliate against Israel and that it had a right to defend itself against a transgression on its sovereignty.</p>

<p>Iran and the regional forces it backs -- Hamas, Hezbollah in Lebanon, the Houthis in Yemen and multiple militias in Iraq -- form what they call the "axis of resistance."</p>

<p>Leaders of those groups were in Tehran for the inauguration of Pezeshkian on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was assassinated at about 2 am (local time), after attending the ceremony and meeting with Khamenei. The killing shocked Iranian officials, who described it as crossing red lines.</p>

<p>According to the NYT, it was a humiliating security breach for Iran, which is eager to project strength but has been unable to prevent Israel from carrying out covert operations on its soil. The embarrassment was compounded by Haniyeh's prominence, the presence of other allies, and that he was attacked at a highly secure Revolutionary Guards guesthouse on a day of heightened security in the capital.</p>

<p>It further reported citing analysts that Tehran sees retaliation as necessary for both avenging the killing of Haniyeh but also as deterrence against Israel killing other powerful enemies, like Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah, or General Ismail Qaani, the commander of the Quds Forces who oversees the militant groups outside Iran.</p>

<p>"Iran likely believes it has no choice other than retaliating to deter further Israeli attacks, defend its sovereignty, and preserve its credibility in the eyes of its regional partners," said Ali Vaez, the Iran director of the International Crisis Group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/b3d2u2tg_ayatollah-ali-khamenei_625x300_01_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran's Supreme Leader gave the order to attack on Israel at an emergency meeting on Wednesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-elon-musk-battle-it-out-online-6235466]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Venezuela's Nicolas Maduro, Elon Musk Battle It Out Online]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-elon-musk-battle-it-out-online-6235466]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:46:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, whose claim to victory at the polls has been widely contested, is no friend of billionaire Elon Musk, and the feeling is clearly mutual, with their war of words escalating amid the political crisis in Caracas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, whose claim to victory at the polls has been widely contested, is no friend of billionaire Elon Musk, and the feeling is clearly mutual, with their war of words escalating amid the political crisis in Caracas.</p>

<p>Musk -- who leads SpaceX and Tesla, and owns the social network X -- is an ultra-capitalist who backs Donald Trump, meaning he is everything that the socialist Maduro despises.</p>

<p>But in recent days, the bus driver-turned-leader of oil-rich, cash-poor Venezuela has Musk -- who he calls his "arch-enemy" -- in his sights.</p>

<p>Maduro has accused Musk of being behind "attacks against Venezuela" and possibly the mastermind of an alleged "computer hacking" at the National Electoral Council (CNE), which declared Maduro the winner of Sunday's vote without providing detailed data.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, following a meeting of Maduro's top political and military advisors, he announced the creation of a special committee, aided by Russian and Chinese experts, to evaluate the nation's biosecurity and an attack on the CNE's communications systems.</p>

<p>"The attacks, I am sure, were directed by the power of Elon Musk," he said.</p>

<p>Opposition figures and observers do not believe there was actually a hack, but that authorities self-sabotaged the system so they would not have to provide the real election results.</p>

<p>Before voters cast their ballots, the 61-year-old Maduro was running well behind opposition candidate Edmundo Gonzalez Urrutia in independent opinion polls.</p>

<p>Late Tuesday, Maduro addressed hundreds of supporters from his balcony -- and once again attacked the 53-year-old Musk.</p>

<p>"Venezuela, as I said yesterday and today, is facing domestic and international aggression from world powers, and now it is evident that Elon Musk is obsessed with the idea of taking over Venezuela and ruling it from abroad," Maduro said.</p>

<p>"He is largely responsible for these attacks and acts of aggression," he added, suggesting the existence of a "global alliance of the far right, the fascist far right, drug traffickers, Elon Musk and the imperialist US government."</p>

<p>"All those who come after Venezuela, we will eliminate them."</p>

<p><strong>- 'Shame on Dictator Maduro' -</strong><br />
Musk has regularly slammed Maduro's policies on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When asked about the criticisms, a senior Venezuelan foreign ministry official said on condition of anonymity: "We know who Musk is. He's on the far right and supports (Argentine President Javier) Milei... So we take all these remarks as compliments."</p>

<p>Before Sunday's election, Musk posted: "It is time for the people of Venezuela to have the chance for a better future. Support Maria Corina!"</p>

<p>He was referring to the wildly popular opposition leader Maria Corina Machado, who was barred from running against Maduro.</p>

<p>After the vote, and the announcement of the results, Musk said Sunday: "Shame on Dictator Maduro" and "What a travesty."</p>

<p>He also posted a 2020 announcement from the US Drug Enforcement Administration of criminal charges against Maduro for drug trafficking and a $15 million reward for information leading to his arrest.</p>

<p>The posts sparked outrage from Maduro.</p>

<p>"He wants to come here with his guns and an army to invade Venezuela. Elon Musk, good thing you showed your face because we knew you were behind it all! With your money and your satellites," Maduro said.</p>

<p>"He wants to control the world, he already controls Argentina... You want to fight? Elon Musk, I am ready. I am the son of Bolivar and Chavez, I'm not afraid of you, Elon Musk... The people defeated Elon Musk's bots, we defeated Elon Musk's bots!"</p>

<p>Musk's retort came in Spanish: "An ass knows more than Maduro."</p>

<p>Later on, the billionaire added: "Sorry to have compared the poor ass to Maduro. That was an insult to the animal kingdom."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/do8o3bco_elon-musk-reuters-_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nicolas Maduro has accused Musk of being behind "attacks against Venezuela".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-expresses-concern-over-escalating-middle-east-conflict-risk-6235408]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Expresses Concern Over Escalating Middle East Conflict Risk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-expresses-concern-over-escalating-middle-east-conflict-risk-6235408]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:21:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The White House on Wednesday voiced concern about the increased risk of an escalation into a broader Middle East war after the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran drew threats of retaliation against Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The White House on Wednesday voiced concern about the increased risk of an escalation into a broader Middle East war after the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran drew threats of retaliation against Israel.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters at a daily briefing, White House national security spokesperson John Kirby said, however, that Washington did not see an all-out conflict in the region as imminent or inevitable and that it was working to prevent that from happening.</p>

<p>He said the U.S. still believed there was a "viable" process to reach a ceasefire deal to end more than nine months of fighting between Israel and Hamas in the Gaza Strip, despite concerns that effort had been dealt a serious blow.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Islamist militant group Hamas and Iran's Revolutionary Guards confirmed the death of Haniyeh, who had participated in internationally-brokered indirect talks on reaching a ceasefire in the Palestinian enclave. The Guards said it took place hours after he attended a swearing-in ceremony for Iran's new president.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government made no mention of Haniyeh's killing in a televised statement on Wednesday evening but said Israel had delivered crushing blows to Iran's proxies of late, including Hamas and Hezbollah, and would respond forcefully to any attack.</p>

<p>The assassination occurred less than 24 hours after Israel claimed to have killed Hezbollah's most senior military commander in the Lebanese capital Beirut in retaliation for a deadly rocket strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights.</p>

<p><strong>CONCERNS OF ESCALATION</strong></p>

<p>"We don't want to see an escalation," Kirby told reporters. "Those risks go up and down every day. They are certainly up right now. They don't make the task of de-escalation, deterrence and dissuasion - which is the goal - any less complicated."</p>

<p>Kirby referred, however, to comments by Iran's Ayatollah Ali Khamenei. The Supreme Leader said Israel had provided the grounds for "harsh punishment for itself" and it was Tehran's duty to avenge Haniyeh's death.</p>

<p>Iranian forces had already made strikes directly on Israel earlier in the Gaza war, which was triggered by a Hamas-led cross-border attack on Israel on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>Kirby declined to say whether the U.S. was urging restraint by Israel, except to say: "We have been working hard to keep this war from escalating."</p>

<p>While the latest events appear to set back any prospects for an imminent ceasefire agreement in Gaza, Kirby said: "We haven't seen any indications ... that the process has been completely torpedoed."</p>

<p>"We still believe the deal on the table is worth pursuing," he added.</p>

<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, at an event in Singapore, sidestepped a question on Haniyeh's killing, saying a ceasefire deal in Gaza was key to avoiding wider regional conflict. He told Channel News Asia that the U.S. had neither been aware of nor involved in the killing.</p>

<p>Blinken spoke by phone to Jordanian and Qatari leaders, and the State Department said they discussed regional tensions and efforts to reach a Gaza ceasefire.</p>

<p>The United States will take every possible measure to protect its personnel and interests in the Middle East after recent attacks there, U.S. State Department Deputy spokesperson Vedant Patel told reporters.</p>

<p>The U.S. also urged its citizens to not travel to Lebanon, citing rising tensions between Israel and the Lebanon-based Hezbollah group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/lha87bsg_john-kirby_625x300_16_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The White House official declined to say whether the U.S. was urging restraint by Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>