<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:17:34 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/paris-olympics-tarun-tahiliani-not-a-couture-show-tarun-tahiliani-to-ndtv-amid-olympics-costume-row-6207878]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Not A Couture Show": Tarun Tahiliani To NDTV Amid Olympics Costume Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/paris-olympics-tarun-tahiliani-not-a-couture-show-tarun-tahiliani-to-ndtv-amid-olympics-costume-row-6207878]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:12:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Responding to the criticism of the Indian contingent's costume at Paris Olympics, fashion designer Tarun Tahiliani has said he stands by the design and slammed "armchair critics" for implying that he charged a fee for designing the athletes' attire.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Responding to the criticism of the Indian contingent's costume at Paris Olympics, fashion designer Tarun Tahiliani has said he stands by the design and slammed "armchair critics" for implying that he charged a fee for designing the athletes' attire.</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV, Mr Tahiliani said his team followed guidelines of International Olympic Committee while designing the kits. "Many things changed in the last minute. I stand by our design. This is what we Indians wear, and this is not to be a couture show. I accept people can have their views. I am good with that, but I stand by what we did," he said.</p>

<p>"We wanted the team in the colours of the tricolour as most countries follow their flag and that was visible from afar," he said.</p>

<p>Many in social media have criticised the designer over the Indian athletes' outfits and described them as dull. "It would have been very easy for me to send them in zardozi vests. But it's not appropriate," the designer said in response to such criticism.</p>

<p>Some social media users have pointed out that the outfits have digital prints on them and India, with its rich heritage of handloom and embroidery, should have been represented on this world stage by better attire.</p>

<p>The designer said his team had just three weeks to ready the costumes. "I can't weave handloom for 300 uniforms in that time. The shoes were brocade, brocade from Benares" he said.</p>

<p>He also responded to the charge that the logo of Tasva, an Aditya Birla Group brand of which Mr Tahiliani is chief design officer, was used on the costumes. "A symbol was made into a border, that's all. When you see a photograph, you won't even notice it. We earlier put the Indian flag there, but were told one should not use it. We followed the guidelines," he said.</p>

<p>The designer strongly denied claims that Tasva charged for designing the costumes. "The cheek of these armchair critics. This was paid for by Tasva. It was not done for a fee, it was done to support our athletes. Asking what I was paid for it just shows their mentality," he said.</p>

<p>Tasva had earlier said in a statement that it was honoured to design the outfits for the Indian contingent in collaboration with Tarun Tahiliani. "This prestigious collaboration for Tasva, as the 'Official Ceremonial Dress Partner' for Team India at the Paris Olympics, marks a significant milestone in Tasva's journey as it represents the spirit, culture, and elegance of India on the global stage," it said.</p>

<p>It said the Indian athletes' ceremonial attire for the opening ceremony draws profound inspiration from the Indian flag. "The tricolor palette embodies national pride and unity. The contemporary silhouettes of the Bundi jacket and the pre-pleated saree when combined with the thoughtful choice of fabrics-cotton and viscose crepe-along with practical detail, not just ensures comfort and functionality for the athletes, but also represents a fine balance of tradition with modernity."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g0i162so_indian-olympic_625x300_28_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The costume of the Indian athletes has been criticised on social media]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-us-carries-out-putin-warns-of-cold-war-style-missile-crisis-6207683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If US Carries Out...": Putin Warns Of Cold War-Style Missile Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-us-carries-out-putin-warns-of-cold-war-style-missile-crisis-6207683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:42:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Sunday threatened to relaunch production of intermediate-range nuclear weapons if the United States confirmed its intention to deploy missiles to Germany or elsewhere in Europe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Sunday threatened to relaunch production of intermediate-range nuclear weapons if the United States confirmed its intention to deploy missiles to Germany or elsewhere in Europe.</p>

<p>"If the United States carries out such plans, we will consider ourselves liberated from the unilateral moratorium previously adopted on the deployment of medium- and short-range strike capabilities," Putin said during a naval parade in Saint Petersburg.</p>

<p>Putin added that now in Russia "the development of a number of such systems is in the final stages".</p>

<p>"We will take mirror measures in deploying them, taking into account the actions of the US, its satellites in Europe and in other regions of the world," the Russian president warned.</p>

<p>Such missiles, which can travel between 500 and 5,500 kilometres (300-3,400 miles), were the subject of an arms control treaty signed by the US and the Soviet Union in 1987.</p>

<p>But both Washington and Moscow withdrew from the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty in 2019, each accusing the other of violations.</p>

<p>Russia subsequently said it would not restart production of such missiles as long as the United States did not deploy missiles abroad.</p>

<p>In early July, Washington and Berlin announced that the "episodic deployments" of long-range US missiles, including Tomahawk cruise missiles, to Germany would begin in 2026.</p>

<p>Putin said that "important Russian administrative and military sites" would fall within the range of such missiles that "could in the future be equipped with nuclear warheads, such that our territories would be within around 10 minutes" of a strike being launched.</p>

<p>The Russian president also mentioned that the US has deployed Typhon mid-range missile systems in Denmark and the Philippines in recent exercises.</p>

<h3><strong>'Cold War' reminder&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"This situation reminds us of the events of the Cold War linked to the deployment of American Pershing medium-range missiles in Europe," said Putin.</p>

<p>The US deployed US Pershing ballistic missiles in West Germany in the 1980s at the height of the Cold War.</p>

<p>US missiles continued to be stationed through the reunification of Germany and into the 1990s.</p>

<p>But following the end of the Cold War, the United States significantly reduced the number of missiles stationed in Europe as the threat from Moscow receded.</p>

<p>The Kremlin had already warned in mid-July that the proposed US deployment would mean that European capitals would become a target for Russian missiles.</p>

<p>"We are taking steady steps towards the Cold War. All the attributes of the Cold War with the direct confrontation are returning," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told a state TV reporter.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pqsvmrc_vladimir-putin-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin said that US has used Typhon mid-range missile systems in Denmark and Philippines recently]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/really-sorry-paris-organisers-apologise-for-offence-caused-by-last-supper-sketch-6207640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Paris Organisers Apologise For Offence Caused By 'Last Supper' Sketch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/really-sorry-paris-organisers-apologise-for-offence-caused-by-last-supper-sketch-6207640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:38:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Paris 2024 organisers apologised on Sunday to Catholics and other Christian groups angered by a kitsch tableau in the Olympic Games opening ceremony that parodied Leonardo Da Vinci's famous 'The Last Supper' painting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paris 2024 organisers apologised on Sunday to Catholics and other Christian groups angered by a kitsch tableau in the Olympic Games opening ceremony that parodied Leonardo Da Vinci's famous 'The Last Supper' painting.</p>

<p>The segment, which resembled the biblical scene of Jesus Christ and his apostles sharing a last meal before crucifixion and featured drag queens, a transgender model and a naked singer made up as the Greek god of wine Dionysus, drew dismay from the Catholic Church and the religious right in America.</p>

<p>"Clearly there was never an intention to show disrespect to any religious group. (The opening ceremony) tried to celebrate community tolerance," Paris 2024 spokesperson Anne Descamps told a press conference.</p>

<p>"We believe this ambition was achieved. If people have taken any offence we are really sorry."</p>

<p>France, while proud of its rich Catholic heritage, also has a long tradition of secularism and anti-clericalism. Blasphemy is not only legal, but also considered by many as an essential pillar of freedom of speech.</p>

<p>Supporters of the tableau praised its message of inclusivity and tolerance.</p>

<p>The Catholic church in France said it deplored a ceremony that "included scenes of derision and mockery of Christianity."</p>

<p>In Germany, the Bishop of Passau, Stefan Oster, said: "An impressive opening to hopefully peaceful games. The queer Last Supper was a low point, however, and wholly superfluous in the context."</p>

<p>Some commentators said the controversy was another example of 21st century culture wars turbocharged by a 24-hour news cycle and social media.</p>

<p>Thomas Jolly, the artistic director and mastermind behind the flamboyant opening ceremony, said religious subversion had never been his intention.</p>

<p>"We wanted to talk about diversity. Diversity means being together. We wanted to include everyone, as simple as that," he told reporters on Saturday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h4u60548_drag-parody_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The segment drew dismay from the Catholic Church]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-every-indication-hezbollah-behind-strike-in-israel-annexed-golan-6207613]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Says "Every Indication" Hezbollah Behind Strike In Golan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-every-indication-hezbollah-behind-strike-in-israel-annexed-golan-6207613]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:31:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Sunday that there was "every indication" that Lebanese fighter group Hezbollah was behind a rocket strike in the Israel-annexed Golan Heights that killed 12 young people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Sunday that there was "every indication" that Lebanese fighter group Hezbollah was behind a rocket strike in the Israel-annexed Golan Heights that killed 12 young people.</p>

<p>"Every indication is that indeed the rocket was from Hezbollah. We stand by Israel's right to defend its citizens from terrorist attacks," Blinken told reporters in Japan.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the young people were struck on Saturday by an Iranian-made rocket carrying a 50-kilogram warhead that Iran-backed Hezbollah fired at a football field in the Druze Arab town of Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has denied responsibility for the strike.</p>

<p>"We are determined to bring the Gaza conflict to a close. It's gone on for far too long. It's cost far too many lives. We want to see Israelis, we want to see Palestinians, we want to see Lebanese live free from the threat of conflict and violence," Blinken said.</p>

<p>"We're in conversations with the government of Israel. And again, I emphasise its right to defend its citizens and our determination to make sure that they're able to do that," he said in Tokyo.</p>

<p>"But we also don't want to see the conflict escalating. We don't want to see a spread. That has been one of our goals from day one, from October 7 on, and we'll continue to do that.</p>

<p>"But again, the best way to do that in a sustained way is to get the ceasefire in Gaza that we're working so hard on virtually every minute of the day," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5c05atig_golan-strikes_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has denied responsibility for the strike]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priti-patel-uk-elections-indian-origin-leaders-bid-to-replace-rishi-sunak-as-conservatives-head-6207211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Leader's Bid To Replace Rishi Sunak As Conservatives Head]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priti-patel-uk-elections-indian-origin-leaders-bid-to-replace-rishi-sunak-as-conservatives-head-6207211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:27:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Home Secretary Priti Patel entered the contest to lead the Conservative Party on Saturday, becoming the fifth contender in a fight to determine the direction of the Tories following their worst-ever election defeat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Home Secretary Priti Patel entered the contest to lead the Conservative Party on Saturday, becoming the fifth contender in a fight to determine the direction of the Tories following their worst-ever election defeat.</p>

<p>Patel is focusing her bid on uniting the Conservatives after they were kicked out of government after 14 years in power and cycled through five prime ministers in that time.</p>

<p>"It is time to put unity before personal vendetta, country before party, and delivery before self-interest," Patel said in a statement.</p>

<p>She joins former Work and Pensions Secretary Mel Stride, former Foreign and Home Secretary James Cleverly, former Security Minister Tom Tugendhat and ex-Immigration Minister Robert Jenrick in a race that will run until Nov. 2.</p>

<p>Leadership nominations will close mid-afternoon on Monday. Conservative Members of Parliament will then narrow the candidates by the end of September - in time for the party's annual conference - before shortlisting two for a party member vote. The new leader is set to be announced on Nov. 2.</p>

<p>Patel is trailing in fifth place at UK bookmakers, with odds as long as 10/1. The bookmakers' favorite to win is former Business Secretary Kemi Badenoch, who has yet to declare.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b9k1uga_priti-patel_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Priti Patel is focusing on uniting the Conservatives after they were kicked out of government this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-students-vow-to-resume-protests-unless-this-demand-is-fulfilled-6206398]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Students Vow To Resume Protests Unless This Demand Is Fulfilled]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-students-vow-to-resume-protests-unless-this-demand-is-fulfilled-6206398]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:56:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Bangladeshi student group has vowed to resume protests that sparked a lethal police crackdown and nationwide unrest unless several of their leaders are released from custody on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Bangladeshi student group has vowed to resume protests that sparked a lethal police crackdown and nationwide unrest unless several of their leaders are released from custody on Sunday.</p>

<p>Last week's violence killed at least 205 people, according to an AFP count of police and hospital data, in one of the biggest upheavals of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's 15-year tenure.</p>

<p>Army patrols and a nationwide curfew remain in place more than a week after they were imposed, and a police dragnet has scooped up thousands of protesters including at least half a dozen student leaders.</p>

<p>Members of Students Against Discrimination, whose campaign against civil service job quotas precipitated the unrest, said they would end their weeklong protest moratorium.</p>

<p>The group's chief Nahid Islam and others "should be freed and the cases against them must be withdrawn", Abdul Hannan Masud told reporters in an online briefing late Saturday.</p>

<p>Mr Masud, who did not disclose his location because he was in hiding from authorities, also demanded "visible actions" be taken against government ministers and police officers responsible for the deaths of protesters.</p>

<p>"Otherwise, Students Against Discrimination will be forced to launch tough protests" from Monday, he said.</p>

<p>Mr Islam and two other senior members of the protest group were on Friday forcibly discharged from a hospital in the capital Dhaka and taken away by a group of plainclothes detectives.</p>

<p>Earlier in the week, Mr Islam told AFP he was being treated at the hospital for injuries police inflicted on him during an earlier round of detention and said he was in fear for his life.</p>

<p>Home minister Asaduzzaman Khan told reporters Friday that the trio were taken into custody for their own safety but did not confirm if they had been formally arrested.</p>

<p>Police told AFP on Sunday that detectives had taken two others into custody, while a Students Against Discrimination activist told AFP that a third had been taken on Sunday morning.</p>

<p>At least 9,000 people have been arrested nationwide since the unrest began according to Prothom Alo, Bangladesh's largest daily newspaper.</p>

<p>While a curfew imposed last weekend remains in force, it has been progressively eased through the week, in a sign of the Hasina government's confidence that order was gradually being restored.</p>

<p>Telecommunications minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak told reporters the country's mobile internet network would be restored later on Sunday, 11 days after a nationwide blackout imposed at the height of the unrest.</p>

<p>Fixed line broadband connections had already been restored on Tuesday but the vast majority of Bangladesh's 141 million internet users rely on their mobile devices to connect with the world, according to the national telecoms regulator.</p>

<h2><strong>Jobs crisis&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Protests began this month over the reintroduction of a quota scheme reserving more than half of all government jobs for certain groups. With around 18 million young Bangladeshis out of work, according to government figures, the move deeply upset graduates facing an acute employment crisis.</p>

<p>Critics say the quota is used to stack public jobs with loyalists to the ruling Awami League.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court cut the number of reserved jobs last week but fell short of protesters' demands to scrap the quotas entirely.</p>

<p>Hasina has ruled Bangladesh since 2009 and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p>Her government is accused by rights groups of misusing state institutions to entrench its hold on power and stamp out dissent, including the extrajudicial killing of opposition activists.</p>

<p>Protests had remained largely peaceful until attacks by police and pro-government student groups on demonstrators last week.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hmsa96t_bangladesh-protest-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 9,000 people have been arrested in Bangladesh since the unrest began.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-olivia-coffey-a-private-equity-staffer-eyeing-gold-at-olympics-6207001]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Olivia Coffey, A Private Equity Staffer Eyeing Gold At Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-olivia-coffey-a-private-equity-staffer-eyeing-gold-at-olympics-6207001]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:48:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Private equity staffers regularly frequent the basement gym at 510 Madison Avenue in Manhattan. Among them: an athlete preparing to don the red, white and blue in her second Summer Olympics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Private equity staffers regularly frequent the basement gym at 510 Madison Avenue in Manhattan. Among them: an athlete preparing to don the red, white and blue in her second Summer Olympics.</p>

<p>Meet Olivia Coffey, a senior associate at One Equity Partners, representing Team USA in the women's eight next week. Her personal best time on an ergometer, or indoor rowing machine, over 2 kilometres is 6 minutes and 36 seconds.</p>

<p>Speaking to Bloomberg News from Erba in Northern Italy, where US rowers trained before travelling to Paris earlier this month, 35-year-old Coffey explained how she forged a career in the alternative asset management industry while pursuing her dreams on the water.</p>

<p>After graduating from Harvard in 2011, Coffey was recruited by One Equity Partners in a back-office role. Her parents trained with the firm's founder Dick Cashin - he and her father Cal rowed for the US at the 1976 Montreal Olympics (the elder Coffey won silver in the pair's event.)</p>

<p>Early in her career, Coffey missed out on selection for the London 2012 Olympics and was a spare for the Rio 2016 Games. She worked on the firm's research and valuations team and rowed while obtaining her MBA from the University of Cambridge, graduating in 2018.</p>

<p>That year, after winning the world championships in Plovdiv, Bulgaria, Coffey resumed work at One Equity Partners and targeted a place on the Olympic team - an effort that was rewarded with a berth in the women's eight, which placed fourth at the Covid-postponed Tokyo Olympics.</p>

<h3><strong>'Rowed to Paris'</strong></h3>

<p>"It was a really awful feeling to walk away without getting to my ultimate goal," she said. "I was ready to be done with rowing, but found my life wasn't balanced, it felt like something was missing," Coffey said.</p>

<p>She resumed workouts in the office basement gym, attended CrossFit classes and began training with a group who communicated on an appropriately-named WhatsApp chat: 'Rowed to Paris.'</p>

<p>Coffey, who lives between Princeton, New Jersey, Manhattan's Upper West Side and Watkins Glen in upstate New York, and spent the most recent winter in Sarasota, Florida, logs 14 to 15 exercise sessions per week.</p>

<p>Awake at 5:30 a.m. each morning, she spends about two hours on the water rowing 20 kilometres to 30 kilometres, and during afternoons, she spends about 90 minutes on another cardio or cross-training activity, be it running or cycling - sometimes in Central Park - or on the rowing machine or lifting weights.</p>

<p>"I usually hit 250 kilometres a week, or 40 kilometres to 50 kilometres a day," said Coffey, who rarely drinks alcohol when training. "I eat a ton of carbs - things like cookies and sweet drinks, which are not great for me long-term," she says.</p>

<p>"When I'm not training, I'm recovering or working," adds Coffey, who aims to be asleep by 10 p.m.</p>

<p>As part of her work at One Equity Partners, Coffey sits on the board of Dragonfly Financial Technologies, a digital banking platform, and is a board observer for Montgomery Transport, a flatbed trucking operator, as well as staffing firm Prime Time Healthcare.</p>

<p>One Equity Partners' flexibility enabled Coffey to schedule work around her training. "I'm thankful, the firm couldn't have been more supportive," she said. "I feel really fortunate to have understanding deal teams, and colleagues who can accommodate my schedule."</p>

<p>Due to her rowing commitments, Coffey isn't subject to what she describes as a classic 80-hour work week. "I work as much as I can within the confines of training," explains Coffey, who generally logs on by 9.30 a.m. or 10 a.m. each morning. Through the fall, when she was training intensely ahead of team trials in March, she notched an average work week of 40 hours. In the lead-up to Paris, that number has halved to about 20 hours, as she focuses on portfolio management and opts out of originating new business.</p>

<h3><strong>Olympians Everywhere</strong></h3>

<p>The&nbsp;US Olympic Committee&nbsp;gives rowers a stipend of $1,000 to $2,000 a month in addition to health insurance, which a lot of athletes supplement with full-time work, said Coffey, who on a regular day, can jump from working on a financial model in Microsoft Excel to a board presentation.</p>

<p>In her role, she deals with everything from origination to due diligence to hashing out terms of a credit agreement, and she especially enjoys meeting founders.</p>

<p>"I know what it feels like to be super passionate and the amount of sacrifice and perseverance it takes to put everything you have into something," Coffey said. "They love what they do."</p>

<p>She'll be supported in Paris by her family including husband Michael Blomquist, a managing director at renewable energy project finance brokerage Open Energy Group, who has made blue tops emblazoned with "Go Liv!" for her cheer squad. Blomquist understands Coffey's drive all too well - he quit Morgan Stanley to focus on qualifying for a spot on the London 2012 US Olympic team.</p>

<p>Also, there will be Jamie Koven, a partner at One Equity Partners, a co-chair of the National Rowing Foundation and former Olympic rower himself, having competed at the Olympics in 1996 and 2000 in Atlanta and Sydney, respectively.</p>

<p>Koven and Cashin are not the only co-workers to have competed at the Olympics. Senior adviser Fritz Hobbs, partners Charlie Cole, Matthew Hughes, Ante Kusurin, and associate Jack Lopas, all rowed at prior Summer Olympics, and principal Mario Ancic is a former professional tennis player who won a bronze medal at the Athens 2004 Games.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qc9adf2g_olivia-coffey_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[After graduating from Harvard in 2011, Olivia Coffey was recruited by One Equity Partners.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-kamala-harris-crazy-liberal-she-calls-out-his-wild-lies-6206955]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Calls Kamala Harris "Crazy Liberal", She Calls Out His "Wild Lies"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-kamala-harris-crazy-liberal-she-calls-out-his-wild-lies-6206955]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:39:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump labeled Vice President Kamala Harris a "crazy liberal," while she vowed to prevail over his "wild lies" as both laid out presidential campaign attack lines Saturday with just 100 days left until election day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump labeled Vice President Kamala Harris a "crazy liberal," while she vowed to prevail over his "wild lies" as both laid out presidential campaign attack lines Saturday with just 100 days left until election day.</p>

<p>After earlier addressing a bitcoin conference in Tennessee, Trump rallied supporters Saturday evening in Minnesota, seeking to make the historically Democratic midwest state into a battleground.</p>

<p>"This November, the American people are going to reject Kamala Harris's crazy liberal extremism in a massive landslide," the Republican told the crowd assembled in a hockey arena.</p>

<p>He quickly took aim at several positions Harris took during her 2020 Democratic primary campaign, some of which she has since walked back, such as a desire to ban fracking or majorly overhaul the criminal justice system.</p>

<p>Calling Harris a "radical left lunatic," Trump also hammered her and President Joe Biden's record on illegal immigration, inflation and crime -- all of which saw significant spikes during their term but have returned to historical averages in recent months.</p>

<p>In his 90-minute speech, the populist billionaire also repeated pledges to "have the largest deportation effort" in US history and end taxation of tips, while repeating unfounded allegations that his 2020 election loss had been "rigged."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Harris on Saturday held a fundraising event in Massachusetts with celebrity guests including singer-songwriter James Taylor and cellist Yoyo Ma.</p>

<p>"We are the underdogs in this race, but this is a people-powered campaign," she told the crowd at the event, which her campaign said would net $1.4 million.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump has been resorting to some wild lies about my record. And some of what he and his running mate are saying, well, it's just plain weird," she said.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign has adopted "weird" as a new catch-all for describing Trump's aggressive rhetoric.</p>

<p>His attacks, repeated on Saturday, include allegations that Harris wants to legalize killing newborn babies -- a falsehood stemming from the vice president's fervent support of abortion rights.</p>

<p>Harris has made her advocacy on the issue central to her campaign against Trump, whose three conservative nominees to the Supreme Court helped overturn the national right to the procedure in 2022.</p>

<p>Trump on Saturday thanked all six conservative justices by name "for the wisdom and courage they showed on this long-term, very contentious issue."</p>

<p>Harris, a former California prosecutor, also challenged Trump to a debate, after his campaign said this week he would not agree to keeping a September 10 televised face-off previously scheduled with Biden.</p>

<p>"I hope he reconsiders because we have a lot to talk about," she said.</p>

<h2><strong>'Mined, minted, made'</strong></h2>

<p>Trump, 78, is now the oldest major-party nominee in history and is scrambling to reorient an election against someone two decades his junior, having expected to face an 81-year-old incumbent Biden beset by concerns over infirmity.</p>

<p>On Saturday, he made his pitch to the cryptocurrency industry, one he previously called a "scam."</p>

<p>Saying China or others could seize the reins on the fast-growing field, Trump's appeal has been welcomed by crypto enthusiasts who feel they have been treated harshly by the Biden administration.</p>

<p>"If crypto is going to define the future, I want (it) to be mined, minted and made in the USA," he said to cheers, calling for the United States to be "the crypto capital of the planet."</p>

<p>Trump on Saturday also vowed a return to outdoor rallies two weeks after being wounded in an attempted assassination at a campaign event in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>He has made the shooting a key part of his campaign pitch, telling supporters he "took a bullet for democracy."</p>

<p>Harris, seeking to become the first female president in US history, is tasked with rapidly assembling a campaign against an opponent who has been in near permanent re-election mode since he became president in 2016.</p>

<p>Her late-starting White House bid has enjoyed early momentum. Polls that had shown Biden steadily slipping against Trump now show Harris in a practical tie.</p>

<p>She's garnered support from Democratic heavyweights, including Biden himself and most recently Barack and Michelle Obama.</p>

<p>Torianna Parrish, 34, was among the crowd greeting Harris upon her arrival Saturday afternoon at the airport in Westfield, Massachusetts.</p>

<p>"I wanted to show there's power in numbers. I wanted to show my support," she said.</p>

<p>"We're rooting for her and we want to see her make this country what it needs to be."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has earlier called Kamala Harris "radical left lunatic". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/sunita-williams-paris-olympics-how-sunita-williams-stuck-in-space-wished-all-the-best-to-paris-olympians-6206874]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Sunita Williams, Stuck In Space, Wished Godspeed To Paris Olympians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/sunita-williams-paris-olympics-how-sunita-williams-stuck-in-space-wished-all-the-best-to-paris-olympians-6206874]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:24:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For 52 days and counting, Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is in limbo at the International Space Station, but in a new video, she is seen celebrating the Olympics spirit in the weightless atmosphere, 400 kilometres above Paris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For 52 days and counting, Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is in limbo at the International Space Station, but in a new video, she is seen celebrating the Olympics spirit in the weightless atmosphere, 400 kilometres above Paris.</p>

<p>She can be seen grabbing an electronic version of the Olympic torch, performing gymnastic steps and doing somersaults inside the space station. Other astronauts are seen throwing discus, shot put balls and trying weightlifting manoeuvres in space where gravity is near zero.</p>

<p>"Let the games begin! Athletes from across the world are gathering today to kick off the 2024 #Olympics - pushing boundaries and inspiring generations. If you were an Olympic athlete, which sport would you play?," NASA has tweeted, sharing a video of astronauts inside the space station.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Let the games begin!<br />
<br />
Athletes from across the world are gathering today to kick off the 2024 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Olympics?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Olympics</a> – pushing boundaries and inspiring generations. If you were an Olympic athlete, which sport would you play? <a href="https://t.co/mnFC3vpvly">pic.twitter.com/mnFC3vpvly</a></p>
— NASA (@NASA) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1816862466816496101?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 26, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The astronauts sent their 'Godspeed' wishes to the athletes who will perform in tough competitive sports under actual gravity conditions. The nine astronauts on-board the space station continue their scientific work and are safe, says NASA.</p>

<p>In a separate update, the American space agency officials today said they conducted a 'hot test' on the troubled spacecraft, the Boeing Starliner, where the malfunctioning thrusters or rockets were tested while still being docked to the space station. "The thrusters performed at peak thrust rating values and the helium system remained stable." The world hopes that the Starliner could well return safely and soon.</p>

<p>Astronaut Sunita Williams and her crewmate Butch Wilmore reached the International Space Station on June 6 on a 10-day mission, but have been stuck after the Starliner malfunctioned. They do not know when and how they will return to Earth, though the US space agency asserts she and the eight other astronauts on-board the International Space Station are safe and in "good spirits".</p>

<p>In the new video, Sunita Williams and her fellow astronauts are seen playing sports in the weightless atmosphere to send good wishes to the athletes participating in the Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old Navy test pilot looks fit and in great spirits. She has helped design the Boeing Starliner and flew as its pilot on the maiden crewed test mission.</p>

<p>NASA has suggested that they are close to understanding the root cause of what is wrong with the Boeing Starliner's malfunctioning systems, but has given no clarity on when Williams and her crew mate Butch Wilmore will return.</p>

<p>According to Boeing, the Starliner can remain docked with the space station for a maximum period of ninety days, after which the batteries on board this spacecraft may drain out. This means that the space technologists in the US have less than six weeks to determine if Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore will return on the handicapped Boeing Starliner spacecraft or on SpaceX's Crew Dragon or Russian Soyuz spacecraft. These standby vehicles are already docked to the space station, so Sunita Williams and the other eight astronauts are not really stranded in space.</p>

<p>Boeing has faced several hiccups in the Starliner development. Initially, it was to have completed this with a $4.2 billion contract but has now spent a total of about $5.7 billion and the going is still uphill as the mission remains incomplete.</p>

<p>NASA wanted an alternative to SpaceX's Crew Dragon, and hence Boeing Starliner was being pushed through. Boeing is also going through a bad patch in general, and its aviation and aircraft business has also been stumbling. Recently, Boeing CEO David Calhoun was grilled by US Senators regarding the aviation giant's safety culture and transparency. If the Boeing Starliner fails to bring the two astronauts back to Earth, it would leave the aviation and space tech giant red-faced.</p>

<p>After today's hot test, whose results are still being assessed by Boeing and NASA, there is hope that Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore could return to Earth before the latest crew of four astronauts heads to the space station. The new crew will be onboard SpaceX's Falcon-9 rocket and Crew Dragon and the lift-off is likely after August 18.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dimhhbao_international-space-station_625x300_28_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The astronauts sent their 'godspeed' wishes to athletes competing in Paris Olympics]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disgusting-jd-vance-slams-jennifer-anistons-remarks-on-his-daughter-6206824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Disgusting": JD Vance Slams Jennifer Aniston's Remarks On His Daughter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disgusting-jd-vance-slams-jennifer-anistons-remarks-on-his-daughter-6206824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:15:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance has hit back at Jennifer Aniston after the actress dragged his two-year-old daughter into their ongoing feud.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican vice-presidential candidate JD Vance has hit back at Jennifer Aniston after the actress dragged his two-year-old daughter into their ongoing feud.</p>

<p>The spat has its roots in JD Vance's 2021 comments about "childless cat ladies" running the country, singling out Kamala Harris and others. Jennifer Aniston, who has spoken publicly about her own infertility struggles, shared a screenshot of the clip on Instagram and <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jennifer-aniston-slams-donald-trumps-running-mate-jd-vance-over-childless-cat-ladies-remark-6191543 ">slammed Vance's remarks</a>. In her post, the <em>Friends</em> star mentioned Vance's daughter, saying she hopes the child will be able to have children of her own one day and won't need to rely on IVF.</p>

<p>JD Vance responded to Aniston's comments on the Megyn Kelly Show, calling them "disgusting" and stating that his daughter is just "2 years old". "And second of all, if she had fertility problems, as I said in that speech, I would try everything I could to try to help her because I believe families and babies are a good thing," the Ohio&nbsp;Senator said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yRMWhqX7b5o?si=OmYlCnuZjInuNqhD" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Vance explained on the Megyn Kelly show that his "childless cat lady" remark was sarcastic and he had "nothing against cats." "People are focusing so much on the sarcasm and not on the substance of what I actually said," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He also pushed back against the criticism, arguing that it was a diversion from the core of his argument. "It's not a criticism of people who don't have children," Vance explained. "I explicitly said in my remarks that this is not about criticising people who, for various reasons, don't have kids. This is about criticising the Democratic Party for becoming anti-family and anti-child."</p>

<p>In a 2021 interview with Tucker Carlson, JD Vance criticised Democratic Party leaders, suggesting that their childlessness influences their policies and attitudes toward the country. Vance had described figures like Kamala Harris, Pete Buttigieg and Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez as "miserable" and lacking a "direct stake" in the country's future due to their lack of children. He also said, "It's just a basic fact - you look at Kamala Harris, Pete Buttigieg, AOC - the entire future of the Democrats is controlled by people without children."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ghp3c7s8_jd-vance-kamala-harris-jennifer-aniston_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance responded to Jennifer Aniston's comments on the Megyn Kelly Show]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-korean-war-anniversary-north-korea-vows-total-destruction-of-enemy-6206263]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Korean War Anniversary, North Korea Vows "Total Destruction" Of Enemy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-korean-war-anniversary-north-korea-vows-total-destruction-of-enemy-6206263]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 12:24:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea vowed to "totally destroy" its enemies in case of war when leader Kim Jong Un gives an order, state media KCNA reported on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea vowed to "totally destroy" its enemies in case of war when leader Kim Jong Un gives an order, state media KCNA reported on Sunday.</p>

<p>Senior military officials including Army Colonel Ri Un Ryong and Navy Lieutenant Commander Yu Kyong Song made the comments "out of surging hatred" towards the U.S. and South Korea at a meeting on Saturday attended by Kim to celebrate the 71st Korean War armistice anniversary, according to KCNA.</p>

<p>North Korea and the United States do not have diplomatic ties and talks over reducing tensions and denuclearising North Korea have been stalled since 2019. North Korea's state media recently said it doesn't expect that to change no matter who is next elected in the White House.</p>

<p>While accusing the US and South Korea of "being hell-bent on provoking a nuclear war," the military officials vowed to strengthen war efficiency to stage an "overwhelming attack on the enemy anytime and without delay and totally destroy them once the respected Supreme Commander Kim Jong Un gives an order."</p>

<p>North Korea signed an armistice agreement with the United States and China on July 27, 1953 ending hostilities in the three-year war. US generals signed the agreement representing the United Nations forces that backed South Korea.</p>

<p>North Korea calls July 27 "Victory Day" while South Korea does not mark the day with any major events.</p>

<p>Hostilities ended with a truce, not a treaty, meaning the two sides are still technically at war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ipinafro_kim-jong-un-with-generals-reuters_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea and the United States do not have diplomatic ties.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-kamala-harris-closes-in-how-donald-trump-is-trying-to-stop-her-6206034]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Donald Trump Is Trying To Stop Kamala Harris As She Closes In]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-kamala-harris-closes-in-how-donald-trump-is-trying-to-stop-her-6206034]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 12:07:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After Joe Biden's exit from the Presidential polls, the Republicans are focusing their attacks on Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris has been able to cut down Donald Trump's lead in the last few weeks, suggest recent polls. Harris has been able to unite the Democratic voters before the big fight in November. Trump and his team haven't missed her momentum and are gearing up to target her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump campaign pollster Tony Fabrizio calls it the "Harris Honeymoon".</p>

<p>After Joe Biden's exit from the Presidential polls, the Republicans are focusing their attacks on Kamala Harris.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>"San Francisco Radical"</strong></h2>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C93AkvGBlci/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C93AkvGBlci/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C93AkvGBlci/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C93AkvGBlci/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by President Donald J. Trump (@realdonaldtrump)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Donald Trump's team is bringing focus to Harris' left-leaning stands during her 2020 presidential campaign. In 2019, in an effort to align with Democratic primary voters, she endorsed policies such as scrapping private health insurance, reforming policing, decriminalising undocumented entry and supporting the Green New Deal. Now, these positions are being used against her by opponents like David McCormick and Donald Trump, who released a video titled "Meet San Francisco Radical Kamala Harris."</p>

<h2><strong>Kamala Harris As Prosecutor</strong></h2>

<p>Harris's background as a prosecutor and California attorney general is under attack too. She has previously used this experience to criticise Trump. Now, Trump's campaign, led by Chris LaCivita, is targeting Harris' years as a prosecutor, citing her tough stance on drug crimes affecting black men and instances where she didn't prosecute or paroled offenders who committed crimes again.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>"Border Czar"</strong></h2>

<p>Another approach Republicans are taking is to tie Kamala Harris to the unpopular decisions and policies of the Joe Biden administration. They are linking her to issues like immigration policies and inflation, making her own record as vice-president a liability.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Republicans have labelled her the "border czar" for her past statements on immigration. Taylor Budowich of the Trump campaign has announced a $32 million ad campaign targeting her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tony Fabrizio of the Trump campaign argues that Harris can't escape her past actions and promised that voters will soon see her as Biden's "partner and co-pilot" with a "dangerously liberal record."&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Trump vs Harris: Polls</strong></h2>

<p>The <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-neck-and-neck-with-donald-trump-show-latest-polls-6201284 ">latest polls</a> indicate a tight race between Trump and Harris. A Wall Street Journal poll shows them neck-and-neck at 49% to 47% in a two-person matchup, within the margin of error of plus or minus 3.1 percentage points.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A New York Times/Siena College poll conducted between July 22-24 shows Trump leading Harris 48% to 47% among likely voters in a head-to-head match. According to Bloomberg, an unweighted average of the polls conducted after Biden exited the presidential race shows Harris trailing Trump by 1.6 percentage points.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris is also expected to get 69% of Black registered voters, up from 59% for Biden last month. She has increased her party's share of Hispanic voters from 45% to 57% and under 30 voters from 46% to 56%. These could potentially boost her chances in the election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kqs5e0o4_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Republicans have labelled Kamala Harris the "border czar".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-calls-joe-bidens-shock-us-poll-exit-a-coup-by-democrats-6206072]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Treated Him Horribly": Trump Calls Biden's Poll Exit A "Coup By Democrats"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-calls-joe-bidens-shock-us-poll-exit-a-coup-by-democrats-6206072]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 11:40:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said incumbent US President Joe Biden was forced to exit the presidential race, describing it a "coup" by the Democratic Party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-joe-bidens-speech-after-exiting-us-presidential-polls-barely-understandable-so-bad-6182893">Donald Trump</a> has said incumbent US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-us-is-more-powerful-than-any-dictator-or-tyrant-6182537">Joe Biden</a> was forced to exit the presidential race, describing it a "coup" by the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>The former president's remarks came during an election rally in Minnesota on Saturday.</p>

<p>"This was really a coup of and by the Democrats. This was a coup of a man that had 14 million votes. He wanted to run. They wouldn't let him run. They treated him horribly. They said to him, we can do it the nice way, or we can do it the hard way. To Joe, he's president," Trump claimed.</p>

<p>This was a coup with the presidency, he said.</p>

<p>"They threatened him with the 25th Amendment. They said, Joe, we're going to threaten you with the 25th Amendment. You're cognitively and physically a mess. And if you don't get out, we're going to take you out with the 25th Amendment," Trump, 78, alleged.</p>

<p>The 25th Amendment of the US Constitution was passed by Congress to determine the presidential succession after the assassination of former President John F Kennedy.</p>

<p>It also gives power to the vice president as well as the Cabinet to remove a president from office if they are deemed physically incapable.</p>

<p>"And he said, I'll go. And then the fake news said, oh, he was so brave. He was so brave. No, he was forced to leave," Trump claimed.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, on July 20 announced his decision to withdraw from the 2024 presidential elections and endorsed Kamala Harris as Democratic Presidential nominee.</p>

<p>This followed a series of fast-moving developments after his disastrous debate performance in Atlanta on June 27 and a failed assassination attempt on Trump. Both the developments resulted in a sharp drop in the popularity rating of Biden, which made the Democrats worried and they started feeling a Trump wave sweeping the nation.</p>

<p>After Biden's exit and his Vice President Harris taking over, the Democrats have regained the momentum and are giving a tough fight to Trump.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cp4tp5lg_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said the Democrats treated Joe Biden "horribly".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-the-masked-torchbearer-at-paris-olympics-opening-ceremony-6205762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Was The Masked Torchbearer At Paris Olympics Opening Ceremony?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-the-masked-torchbearer-at-paris-olympics-opening-ceremony-6205762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 10:48:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Paris Olympics ceremony saw two unique figures - a masked torchbearer running across rooftops and a caped rider who rode a metal horse down the Seine, delivering the Olympic flag.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The opening ceremony of the Paris Olympics 2024 was a spectacular event that took place on Friday, July 26, along the River Seine. For the first time in Olympic history, the ceremony was held outside a stadium, with 85 boats carrying nearly 7,000 athletes from 205 countries along a 6-km stretch of the Seine. The ceremony also saw two unique figures - a masked torchbearer running across rooftops and a caped rider who rode a metal horse down the Seine, delivering the Olympic flag.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Who were the two masked figures?</strong></p>

<p>A masked Amazon on a motorised horse participated in the ceremony, galloping down the Seine while wearing a cape with the Olympic rings. She carried the olympic flag&nbsp;from the Pont d'Iena to the Place du Trocadero on the metal horseback. As she passed under bridges, she unfurled dove wings. The rider was <a href="https://olympics.com/en/news/paris-2024-olympic-games-opening-ceremony-flame-cauldron ">Floriane Issert</a>, a non-commissioned officer in the Gendarmerie Nationale. Following her, a group of Games volunteers carried the national flags.</p>

<p>Ms Issert wasn't the only one to make an impact. A mysterious torchbearer also made a splash by leaping across buildings and past monuments with ease. Clad in a black cloak and mask, their identity remained a secret throughout the ceremony. They met Zinedine Zidane at the end of the procession, handing the torch back to the French football legend before disappearing into the night.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/q1q68ht4_masked-torchbearer-getty_625x300_28_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ta50ddb8_masked-torchbearer-getty_625x300_28_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Paris 2024 Olympics opening ceremony began with a performance by Lady Gaga and included a tribute to French culture, history and sport. Athletes from 205 National Olympic Committees (NOC) participated in the parade, which travelled along the Seine and passed by iconic landmarks such as the Eiffel Tower, Notre-Dame and the Grand Palais.</p>

<p>Apart from Zidane, the Olympic torch was also carried by French sporting heroes Teddy Riner and Marie-Jose Perec, as well as Spanish Tennis legend Rafael Nadal. The cauldron, attached to a hot air balloon, rose into the sky as Celine Dion performed <em>L'hymne à l'amour</em>&nbsp;from the Eiffel Tower balcony.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ceremony was attended by 320,000 spectators along the Seine and watched by millions around the world.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/di7t5qp_masked-torchbearer-getty_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vows-to-make-us-crypto-capital-of-planet-bitcoin-superpower-of-world-6205673]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump To Make US "Crypto Capital Of Planet", Bitcoin "Superpower Of World"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vows-to-make-us-crypto-capital-of-planet-bitcoin-superpower-of-world-6205673]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 10:11:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former President Donald Trump has promised to make the US a "Bitcoin superpower" if returned to the White House and said that he will appoint an advisory council to design transparent regulatory guidance for the benefit of the entire industry.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former President Donald Trump has promised to make the US a “Bitcoin superpower" if returned to the White House and said that he will appoint an advisory council to design transparent regulatory guidance for the benefit of the entire industry.</p>

<p>But Trump, the Republican nominee, stopped short of proposing a formal federal reserve of digital currency.</p>

<p>Trump made a series of cryptocurrency-friendly policy commitments during remarks at a Bitcoin convention Saturday, including promising to fire Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler and creating a “strategic national Bitcoin stockpile.” “I'm laying out my plan to ensure that the United States will be the crypto capital of the planet and the Bitcoin superpower of the world,” Trump, 78, said.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is the world's first widely adopted cryptocurrency — it allows for secure and seamless peer-to-peer transactions on the internet.</p>

<p>He also warned that Bitcoin investors in the audience will be “crushed” if Vice President Kamala Harris is elected as president.</p>

<p>“They (Democrats) want to choke you. They want to choke you out of business. We're not going to let that happen. And no longer will your government sit by and watch as Bitcoin jobs and businesses flee to other countries because America's laws are too unclear and too tough and too angry and too stiff. We will keep each and every Bitcoin job in the United States of America,” Trump said in his address to the Bitcoin2024 Conference, the cryptocurrency industry's largest annual gathering, in Nashville's Music City Center.</p>

<p>Trump is the first major party candidate to address the annual cryptocurrency conference.</p>

<p>Trump also promised to “immediately” establish a “Bitcoin and crypto presidential advisory council,” which he said would provide “transparent regulatory guidance” for the cryptocurrency sector. “I am proud to be the first American president to address a Bitcoin event anywhere in the world. If crypto is going to define the future, I want it to be mined, minted and made in the USA,” he said.</p>

<p>“We will have regulations, but from now on, the rules will be written by people who love your industry, not hate your industry. People who want to make it clear and simple, straightforward and fair. People that want to see your industry thrive, not dive,” he said.</p>

<p>Trump also said he would end efforts by the US government to create a central bank digital currency (CBDC), an initiative that cryptocurrency enthusiasts have long been critical of.</p>

<p>“I will immediately order the treasury department and other federal agencies to cease and desist all steps necessary because there's a thing going on in your industry. They want to move the creation of a central bank digital currency. It's over. Forget it. There will never be a CBDC while I'm President of the United States. I will always defend the right to self-custody. You're going to have a great industry, and we're going to be fuel for your industry,” he said.</p>

<p>As president, Trump has declared Bitcoin “not money” and criticised it as “highly volatile and based on thin air.” But Saturday marked the culmination of a total reversal on the issue during the former president's latest White House bid. Indian-American entrepreneur-turned-politician Vivek Ramaswamy is a key advisor to Trump on cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Trump announced that as part of his effort to provide regulatory clarity, his administration will create a framework to enable the safe and responsible expansion of stable coins allowing them to extend the dominance of the US dollar to new frontiers all around the world.</p>

<p>“America will be richer, the world will be better, and there will be billions and billions of people brought into the crypto economy and storing their savings in Bitcoin. Those who say that Bitcoin is a threat to the dollar have the story backwards. Bitcoin is not threatening the dollar. The behaviour of the current US government is really threatening the dollar,” he said.</p>

<p>“The danger to our financial future does not come from crypto. It comes from trillions of dollars in waste, rampant inflation and open borders while giving welfare and free healthcare to all of the illegal aliens that are pouring into our country by the millions and millions and millions. It comes from printing hundreds of billions of dollars to fund endless wars overseas while our cities are like combat zones here at home,” he alleged.</p>

<p>Trump America under him will become the world's undisputed Bitcoin mining powerhouse.</p>

<p>“You'll be a Bitcoin mining powerhouse. You will not have to move your family to China. You will not be moving to China. As we implement these reforms, Bitcoin and crypto will grow our economy, cement American financial dominance and strengthen our entire country long into the future,” he said. PTI LKJ NSA NSA</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0k183qe_donald-trump_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump made a series of cryptocurrency-friendly policy commitments during a Bitcoin convention]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-4-years-you-wont-have-to-vote-again-donald-trump-tells-christians-6205123]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In 4 Years, You Won't Have To Vote Again," Donald Trump Tells Christians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-4-years-you-wont-have-to-vote-again-donald-trump-tells-christians-6205123]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 07:32:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican nominee Donald Trump has told Christians that if they vote for him in the November presidential elections, he will fix everything so well that they won't have to vote again.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican nominee Donald Trump has told Christians that if they vote for him in the November presidential elections, he will fix everything so well that they won't have to vote again.</p>

<p>Trump was speaking at a Florida event organized by the conservative group Turning Point Action.</p>

<p>"Christians, you have to get out and vote. You won't have to do it anymore. Four more years, you know what, it will be fixed, it will be fine. You won't have to vote anymore, my beautiful Christians. I love you, Christians. I'm a Christian. I love you, get out, you gotta get out and vote. In four years, you don't have to vote again, we'll have it fixed so good you're not going to have to vote," Trump said.</p>

<p>It's not clear what the former president, who faces charges of inciting the 2020 Capitol riots and allegedly trying to overturn his 2022 election loss, meant by these remarks.</p>

<p>The Kamala Harris campaign has not addressed the remarks directly, but spokesperson Jason Singer described his overall speech as "bizarre" and "backward-looking".</p>

<p>Trump had earlier said that he would be a dictator for a day to close the southern border with Mexico if returns to power in November. He later played down his remarks as a joke.</p>

<p>The US presidential race has tightened after President Joe Biden was replaced by his deputy Kamala Harris as the Democratic nominee last week. Ms Harris' entry in the race has largely erased Trump's lead, recent opinion polls.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/an6don1o_trump-afp_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump was speaking at a Florida event organized by Turning Point Action.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-underdog-campaign-will-overcome-trumps-wild-lies-6204455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Says "Underdog" Campaign Will Overcome Trump's "Wild Lies"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-underdog-campaign-will-overcome-trumps-wild-lies-6204455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 03:30:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris on Saturday acknowledged the uphill climb to defeating Donald Trump in November, but said her freshly-minted presidential campaign would prevail over the "wild lies" of her Republican rival.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris on Saturday acknowledged the uphill climb to defeating Donald Trump in November, but said her freshly-minted presidential campaign would prevail over the "wild lies" of her Republican rival.</p>

<p>As Trump prepared to address a bitcoin conference in Tennessee, Harris was speaking at a fundraising event in Massachusetts with celebrity guests including singer-songwriter James Taylor and cellist Yoyo Ma.</p>

<p>"We are the underdogs in this race, but this is a people-powered campaign," she told the crowd at the event, which her campaign said would net $1.4 million.</p>

<p>"You may have noticed, Donald Trump has been resorting to some wild lies about my record. And some of what he and his running mate are saying, well, it's just plain weird," she said, the latest quip adopted by Democrats in describing the Republicans' attacks.</p>

<p>The latest among them included Trump's remarks to a religious convention Friday night, where he accused Harris of being an anti-Semite who plans to allow the murder of newborn babies.</p>

<p>"She doesn't like Jewish people. She doesn't like Israel. That's the way it is," he said of the vice president, whose husband is Jewish.</p>

<p>In perhaps his most outrageous statement of the night, he claimed Harris wanted to enshrine in federal law the right to "rip the baby out of the womb in the eighth, ninth month and even after birth -- execute the baby after birth."</p>

<p>Trump, who at age 78 is now the oldest major-party nominee in history, is scrambling to reorient an election against someone two decades his junior, having expected to face an 81-year-old incumbent Joe Biden beset by concerns over infirmity.</p>

<p>Seeking to become the first female president in US history, Harris is tasked with rapidly assembling a campaign against an opponent who has been in near permanent reelection mode since he became president in 2016.</p>

<p>Her late-starting White House bid has enjoyed early momentum. Polls that had shown Biden steadily slipping against Trump now show Harris in a race too close to call.</p>

<p>She's garnered support from Democratic heavyweights, including Biden himself and most recently Barack and Michelle Obama.</p>

<p>Torianna Parrish, 34, was among the crowd greeting Harris upon her arrival Saturday afternoon at the airport in Westfield, Massachusetts.</p>

<p>"I wanted to show there's power in numbers. I wanted to show my support," she said.</p>

<p>"We're rooting for her and we want to see her make this country what it needs to be."</p>

<p>Harris was introduced at the Colonial Theater in Pittsfield by Taylor, who said: "Let us honor the woman and the moment and may our ardent support be the wind in her sails. Our hopes go with her and she stands for us all."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kqs5e0o4_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-11-6204151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Pay Heavy Price": Netanyahu Warns Hezbollah After Air Strike Kills 11]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-11-6204151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:57:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".</p>

<p>The army said Lebanese group Hezbollah fired the deadly rocket that killed the youngsters aged between 10 and 20 years when they were hit on the pitch in the town of Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>Many residents of the town retain Syrian nationality decades after the territory's occupation in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in south Lebanon prompting the Iran-backed militant group to announce a flurry of retaliatory rocket attacks against the Golan and northern Israel.</p>

<p>Military spokesman Daniel Hagari said on X that 11 youngsters were killed in the attack, while the emergency service Magen David Adom said 19 others were wounded when the rocket hit Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>"We will prepare for a response against Hezbollah... we will act," Rear Admiral Hagari said in a video statement, adding the rocket fire was the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7" when Hamas militants attacked southern Israel sparking war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who was returning early from a visit to the United States, vowed that "Israel will not let this murderous attack go unanswered".</p>

<p>"Hezbollah will pay a heavy price for it, a price it has not paid before," he warned in a statement released by his office.</p>

<p>- 'Only crime' playing soccer -</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog charged that Hezbollah had "brutally attacked and murdered children today, whose only crime was going out to play soccer".</p>

<p>Hezbollah denied it was responsible for the deadly strike.</p>

<p>"The Islamic Resistance has no connection to this incident," it said, referring to its military wing.</p>

<p>The police and the army said the rocket fired at Majdal Shams was part of a barrage of rockets fired from Lebanon which struck multiple locations in the Golan.</p>

<p>Ambulances, helicopters and mobile intensive care units were deployed to the scene, the army said.</p>

<p>"We arrived at a football pitch and saw destruction and objects on fire. Injured people were lying on the grass," paramedic Idan Avshalom said in a statement issued by Magen David Adom.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent saw medics carrying away the wounded for treatment.</p>

<p>"Officers and police bomb disposal experts from the northern district police are currently securing the area and searching for additional (rocket) remnants to eliminate any further risk to the public," the police said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after a Lebanese security source said an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in the southern village of Kfar Kila.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has exchanged near-daily cross-border fire with the Israeli army since the Gaza war erupted last October, confirmed the deaths of four of its fighters.</p>

<p>It said it carried out a dozen retaliatory attacks on Israeli targets, nine in the space of two hours.</p>

<p>The violence since October has killed at least 527 people in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally. Most of the dead have been fighters, but they have included at least 104 civilians.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, 18 soldiers and 24 civilians have been killed, according to Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza broke out after Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,258 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-10-6204150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Pay Heavy Price": Netanyahu Warns Hezbollah After Strike Kills 10]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-10-6204150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:57:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".</p>

<p>The army said Lebanese group Hezbollah fired the deadly rocket that killed the youngsters aged between 10 and 20 years when they were hit on the pitch in the town of Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>Many residents of the town retain Syrian nationality decades after the territory's occupation in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in south Lebanon prompting the Iran-backed militant group to announce a flurry of retaliatory rocket attacks against the Golan and northern Israel.</p>

<p>Military spokesman Daniel Hagari said on X that 11 youngsters were killed in the attack, while the emergency service Magen David Adom said 19 others were wounded when the rocket hit Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>"We will prepare for a response against Hezbollah... we will act," Rear Admiral Hagari said in a video statement, adding the rocket fire was the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7" when Hamas militants attacked southern Israel sparking war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who was returning early from a visit to the United States, vowed that "Israel will not let this murderous attack go unanswered".</p>

<p>"Hezbollah will pay a heavy price for it, a price it has not paid before," he warned in a statement released by his office.</p>

<p>- 'Only crime' playing soccer -</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog charged that Hezbollah had "brutally attacked and murdered children today, whose only crime was going out to play soccer".</p>

<p>Hezbollah denied it was responsible for the deadly strike.</p>

<p>"The Islamic Resistance has no connection to this incident," it said, referring to its military wing.</p>

<p>The police and the army said the rocket fired at Majdal Shams was part of a barrage of rockets fired from Lebanon which struck multiple locations in the Golan.</p>

<p>Ambulances, helicopters and mobile intensive care units were deployed to the scene, the army said.</p>

<p>"We arrived at a football pitch and saw destruction and objects on fire. Injured people were lying on the grass," paramedic Idan Avshalom said in a statement issued by Magen David Adom.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent saw medics carrying away the wounded for treatment.</p>

<p>"Officers and police bomb disposal experts from the northern district police are currently securing the area and searching for additional (rocket) remnants to eliminate any further risk to the public," the police said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after a Lebanese security source said an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in the southern village of Kfar Kila.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has exchanged near-daily cross-border fire with the Israeli army since the Gaza war erupted last October, confirmed the deaths of four of its fighters.</p>

<p>It said it carried out a dozen retaliatory attacks on Israeli targets, nine in the space of two hours.</p>

<p>The violence since October has killed at least 527 people in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally. Most of the dead have been fighters, but they have included at least 104 civilians.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, 18 soldiers and 24 civilians have been killed, according to Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza broke out after Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,258 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-british-were-used-to-rain-uk-pm-shrugs-off-paris-olympics-photo-6204149]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["It's British. We're Used To Rain": UK PM Shrugs Off Paris Olympics Photo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-british-were-used-to-rain-uk-pm-shrugs-off-paris-olympics-photo-6204149]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:55:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Keir Starmer Saturday brushed off the fascination with a viral image taken at the Paris Olympic Games opening ceremony showing him as the only dignitary not wearing a protective plastic poncho during driving rain.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer Saturday brushed off the fascination with a viral image taken at the Paris Olympic Games opening ceremony showing him as the only dignitary not wearing a protective plastic poncho during driving rain.</p>

<p>Starmer was pictured as the only person bare-headed as other VIPs opted to encase themselves in plastic hand-out ponchos to protect themselves from the rain that blighted Friday's opening ceremony on the River Seine.</p>

<p>The image was widely shared on social media, with users seeing the picture as a classic example of a very British stiff upper lip in the face of the inclement weather all to familiar to residents of the famously drizzly country.</p>

<p>"It's British! We are used to the rain," Starmer told French channel LCI in an interview.</p>

<p>"But it (the rain) didn't dampen the spirits," he added, describing the opening ceremony as a "spectacular" and "fantastic" event that made "the whole use of the river (and) of Paris."</p>

<p>Starmer, elected earlier this month in a landslide election victory for the centre-left Labour Party that ended 14 years of right-wing Conservative rule, was making his first official visit to Paris as premier.</p>

<p>"Nothing more British than absolutely refusing to wear one of those plastic poncho things," wrote one user on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>Rain has had considerable symbolism in British politics in recent weeks.</p>

<p>When he called the general election, Conservative former prime minister Rishi Sunak was widely mocked for delivering his address outside 10 Downing Street in pouring rain without a coat or an umbrella.</p>

<p>Starmer was however wearing a navy blue Team GB rain-proof jacket and in other images could also be seen using its hood to protect his hair from the rain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Preparation is the key to success," the Labour Party wrote on X as it posted one of these images.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nr0lrb98_keir-starmer-rain_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The image was seen as a classic example of a very British stiff upper lip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>