<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 13:52:01 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-reflects-on-labours-remarkable-journey-to-victory-6039077]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer Reflects On Labour's Remarkable Journey to Victory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-reflects-on-labours-remarkable-journey-to-victory-6039077]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 13:37:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On the eve of polls opening in the UK general election, Keir Starmer allowed himself a moment to reflect on how far he had come since he became leader of the Labour Party four-and-a-half years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the eve of polls opening in the UK general election, Keir Starmer allowed himself a moment to reflect on how far he had come since he became leader of the Labour Party four-and-a-half years ago. Back then, the party was reeling from one of the worst defeats in its 100-year history.</p>

<p>"The optimists said it will take 10 years to fix this party and get it back," he told reporters ahead of a final rally in the East Midlands. "The pessimists said you're never going to fix this party, it's never going to be in government again." adding "Here we are."</p>

<p>He has now led the Labour Party to victory, on track for the biggest majority in Parliament since at least Tony Blair's New Labour landslide in 1997.</p>

<p>The UK's presumptive prime minister has far outperformed the expectations of his chances when he took over from the hard-left Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn in 2020. Bland, boring, "no Tony Blair," as focus groups often describe him, this relative newcomer to the world of politics has, in part, been a beneficiary of circumstances.</p>

<p>Boris Johnson's "partygate" scandal and Liz Truss's "mini-budget" - which tanked the pound - came at the tail-end of years of Conservative austerity that left deep cuts to many public services. All have contributed to the result we have now seen in the British general election. But Starmer has had his part to play too, demonstrating a quiet ruthlessness in changing his party, purging the Corbynites, even expelling Corbyn himself, and bringing it into a position to win and govern again.</p>

<p>"It feels good, I have to be honest," Starmer told Labour supporters in London after the party crossed the crucial 326-seat threshold in the House of Commons, adding that he knew "a mandate like this comes with a great responsibility."</p>

<p>He'll now have to show whether those same skills that got him into 10 Downing St. will help him resolve a staggering list of challenges. Britons are bruised by the impact of Brexit, the pandemic and a historic squeeze on living standards. His government faces a more dangerous world and has little money to spend on improving the situation at home without raising broad-based taxes, something he's said he doesn't want to do.</p>

<p>Despite being known as "Sir Keir" - he was knighted for his legal career before entering politics - the UK's new prime minister had humble beginnings, something he has been at pains to remind voters throughout the election campaign. He grew up, as he often recounts, in a "pebble-dashed" semi-detached house in Oxted, a London commuter town in the Surrey countryside. He was one of four children to a toolmaker father and a mother with a debilitating autoimmune condition, which meant she had to give up her work as a nurse while Starmer was a child.</p>

<p>Starmer's father raised his four children and looked after his sick wife on his own, and money was often tight. "I remember when our phone was cut off because we couldn't pay the bill," Starmer has recalled during the campaign. "How hard it was to make ends meet."</p>

<p>The young Starmer was given a leg-up in life by attending Reigate Grammar, a state school, where he secured the grades to become the first in his family to attend university. He studied law at Leeds, graduating with honors, and got accepted to Oxford University to do a BCL - a prestigious year-long graduate law course. As a young man in London in the late 1980s, he lived in a "party flat" where there was sometimes vomit in the bathtub, hosting friends into the early hours and writing radical treatises for niche left-leaning publications. But by day he was climbing the ranks to become a respected human rights lawyer.</p>

<p>Starmer, who has denied being the inspiration for the dashing human rights lawyer Mark Darcy in the book and film Bridget Jones' Diary, became known for his pro bono work, including defending individuals in the Caribbean against the death penalty. He had a brush with national fame for defending two activists, Helen Steel and David Morris, a gardener and a former postman, who sued for libel by McDonald's for distributing leaflets criticizing the fast food chain, in what became known as the 'McLibel' case. He was appointed Queen's Counsel in 2002, a few months before his 40th birthday.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer as Director of Public Prosecutions, in 2010.</p>

<p>The following year, Starmer took on a role that would rewrite his theory of change: human rights adviser to the Policing Board in Northern Ireland. His job was to ensure that the new police service, formed after the 1998 peace agreement, commanded the trust of all communities. Before this role, Starmer had seen himself as railing against the system from the outside. This was his first experience of going inside an organization to deliver change. He found this new way was far more effective.</p>

<p>He took on a major role leading after that, becoming director of public prosecutions from 2008 to 2013. The role put him in charge of delivering criminal justice in the UK, running a large organization of thousands of staff and lawyers during a period of major budget cuts. He led the organization when it successfully prosecuted senior media figures for phone hacking and politicians for fiddling with their expenses.</p>

<p>No one was surprised when the country's former top prosecutor entered the world of politics. After his time as DPP ended, Starmer stood for election in the safe Labour seat of Holborn and St. Pancras in the May 2015 general election, expecting to be attorney general in Ed Miliband's Cabinet. Instead, he went straight to the opposition benches and joined a Labour parliamentary party tearing itself apart after a shock defeat.</p>

<p>During the Jeremy Corbyn years Starmer, a remainer, rose through the shadow ministerial ranks to become shadow Brexit secretary. While colleagues like Rachel Reeves refused to serve under Corbyn or resigned from the party altogether over antisemitism, Starmer stayed. But by March 2018, Starmer and his allies - frustrated by the antisemitism problem and by Corbyn's foreign policy stances - knew he would stand for party leader when the time came. For nearly two years, they held secret meetings every Monday morning to make sure he was ready for a leadership campaign when the time arose.</p>

<p>The time came in 2020. Starmer ran and won, a leadership campaign centered on 10 pledges to Labour members, essentially to retain the radical spirit of the Corbynite agenda with promises such as renationalizing, rail, mail, energy, and water. He memorably paid tribute to "my friend Jeremy Corbyn."</p>

<p>Since taking over the leadership, Starmer has expelled Corbyn from the party, introduced mandatory antisemitism training, and vigorously vetted, and sometimes imposed, candidates who will be loyal to his leadership. Encouraged by his shadow chancellor Rachel Reeves and other close aides from the party's right-wing, he has instilled a tight fiscal discipline, ditched almost all of his original leadership pledges, and draped his party in the union flag and embraced the language of security, discipline, and patriotism.</p>

<p>It has not all been plain sailing. He lost the Hartlepool by-election - seeing a safe Labour seat fall to Johnson's Conservatives - early into his leadership in 2020, after which he considered resigning. The experience saw him fire some advisers, appoint new people, and hardened his determination to overhaul his party.</p>

<p>More recently, Starmer suffered a protracted and public disagreement among his top team over whether to ditch his party's pledge to spend £28 billion ($36 billion) per year on green infrastructure, culminating in a major reversal. He has faced criticism and lost votes over an LBC radio interview in October in which he said Israel "has the right" to withhold power and water from Gaza, which he later apologized for.</p>

<p>The team of advisers around him has been referred to as a "boys' club," accused of heavy-handedness in their purging of the Corbynite wing of the party and in their wider attitude to the party's elected representatives.</p>

<p>While his dissenters balk at how different he is from the man who stood for leader four and a half years ago, Starmer is proud of that difference. "I changed my party," he says. "Now I want to change the country."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mrjhen9c_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He has now led the Labour Party to victory, on track for the biggest majority in Parliament.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-ends-conservative-era-key-moments-of-conservative-rule-in-uk-6038897]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Labour Party Ends Conservative Era: Key Moments Of Conservative Rule In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-ends-conservative-era-key-moments-of-conservative-rule-in-uk-6038897]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 13:08:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's Labour Party won a parliamentary election on Friday, bringing to an end 14 years of Conservative Party-led government that saw the country weather one of the more turbulent periods in its post-World War Two political history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Labour Party won a parliamentary election on Friday, bringing to an end 14 years of Conservative Party-led government that saw the country weather one of the more turbulent periods in its post-World War Two political history.</p>

<p>Here are some of the defining moments of the Conservatives' four terms in power - under five prime ministers - since 2010:</p>

<h3><strong>2010 ELECTION RESULTS IN HUNG PARLIAMENT</strong></h3>

<p>The Conservative Party led by David Cameron wins the most seats in parliament but not an overall majority, ousting the Labour Party which had been in power since 1997. Britain has its first coalition government since 1945, after Cameron agrees to work with the centrist Liberal Democrats.</p>

<h3><strong>2014 SCOTTISH REFERENDUM</strong></h3>

<p>In a referendum that had threatened to split the United Kingdom, Scotland votes 55%-45% against independence in a victory for Cameron and the main national political parties over the Scottish National Party.</p>

<h3><strong>2015 SURPRISE CONSERVATIVE ELECTION VICTORY</strong></h3>

<p>With polls pointing to a close election, Cameron wins an unexpected majority and a second term as prime minister. He follows through on a 2013 pledge to hold a referendum on leaving the European Union. Cameron wants Britain to remain in the EU.</p>

<h3><strong>2016: UK VOTES FOR BREXIT, CAMERON QUITS</strong></h3>

<p>Britons cause a global shock by voting 52%-48% to leave the EU, ending a more than 40-year union and plunging the country into its biggest political crisis since World War Two. Cameron resigns and the party chooses Theresa May to succeed him.</p>

<h3><strong>2017 SNAP ELECTION GAMBLE BACKFIRES</strong></h3>

<p>Riding high in opinion polls and seeking a bigger majority in parliament to push Brexit legislation through, May calls a snap election. The Conservatives lose their majority and form a government by striking a deal with Northern Ireland's pro-UK Democratic Unionist Party.</p>

<h3><strong>MAY 2019: BREXIT PARALYSIS, MAY RESIGNS, JOHNSON TAKES OVER</strong></h3>

<p>May quits after failing to break a parliamentary deadlock over how Britain should leave the EU. Boris Johnson - one of the main faces of the pro-Brexit campaign - wins the internal Conservative Party contest to succeed her.</p>

<h3><strong>DEC 2019: JOHNSON LEADS CONSERVATIVES TO SWEEPING WIN</strong></h3>

<p>With parliament paralysed over Brexit, Johnson calls a snap election. Campaigning under the slogan "Get Brexit Done" he steers the Conservatives to their biggest election win since Margaret Thatcher's landslide victory in 1987.</p>

<h3><strong>2020 BREXIT GETS DONE</strong></h3>

<p>Johnson used his mandate to drive a Brexit deal through parliament and Brussels, and Britain exited the EU on Jan. 31, 2020, becoming the first state to withdraw from the bloc.</p>

<h3><strong>JULY 2022: JOHNSON OUSTED</strong></h3>

<p>Johnson leads Britain during the COVID-19 pandemic - at one point being hospitalised himself with the disease - but a long list of scandals and missteps prove too much and he steps down after a ministerial revolt.</p>

<h3><strong>SEPT 2022: TRUSS' CHAOTIC PREMIERSHIP</strong></h3>

<p>Liz Truss beats Rishi Sunak in a contest to succeed Johnson. Her "mini-budget" containing unfunded tax cuts spooks financial markets, pushing up borrowing costs sharply and further tarnishing Britain's reputation for political and fiscal stability. She lasts only 44 days before announcing her resignation.</p>

<h3><strong>OCT 2022: SUNAK BECOMES PRIME MINISTER</strong></h3>

<p>Sunak takes over as Britain's third prime minister in as many months, pledging to restore stability to government. He makes five key pledges focused on the economy, stopping illegal immigration and improving the health system. In February 2023, Sunak struck a deal with the EU on trade rules for Northern Ireland, improving ties with the bloc.</p>

<h3><strong>MAY 2024 - SUNAK CALLS ELECTION</strong></h3>

<p>Trailing the Labour Party by around 20 points in the polls, Sunak calls an election for July 4. Labour, led by Keir Starmer, wins the election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9313gia8_conservative-party_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Conservative Party led the country through one of its most turbulent post-World War Two political eras.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-2024-ai-candidate-makes-uk-poll-debut-gets-179-votes-finishes-last-6038704]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Says No To AI. Virtual Candidate Finishes Last In Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-2024-ai-candidate-makes-uk-poll-debut-gets-179-votes-finishes-last-6038704]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:43:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI Steve was designed to engage with voters in real time on various issues and offer policy ideas. It could handle up to 10,000 conversations simultaneously.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) made its debut in the 2024 UK general election as an independent candidate. <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-ai-steve-first-ai-candidate-contesting-in-uk-elections-5923288 ">AI Steve</a>, the brainchild of businessman Steve Endacott, contested the Brighton Pavilion constituency. However, despite the innovative approach, AI Steve failed to impress voters, securing only <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/election/2024/uk/constituencies/E14001130 ">179 votes</a> (0.3% of the total).&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Endacott, frustrated with the country's "standard politics," launched AI Steve as a unique solution. The AI avatar, powered by Neural Voice company, aimed to provide round-the-clock access to constituents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>AI Steve was designed to engage with voters in real time on various issues and offer policy ideas. It could handle up to 10,000 conversations simultaneously.</p>

<p>Earlier, the UK election watchdog issued a clarification on AI Steve's candidature. If AI Steve won the seat, the human candidate, Steve Endacott, and not the AI entity, would take office as a member of Parliament, the poll body said.</p>

<p>Although AI Steve made history as the first such candidate in UK polls, its campaign struggled to gain momentum. The Brighton Pavilion constituency saw a turnout of 70%, with the Green Party's Sian Berry winning the seat.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Keir Starmer's Labour Party emerged victorious in the UK general election, securing a majority government with over 326 seats in the House of Commons. This decisive win marks the end of 14 years of Conservative rule, with Mr Starmer set to become the next Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak, the incumbent Prime Minister, has conceded defeat after multiple cabinet members lost their seats.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/899pbpk8_ai-candidate-_625x300_19_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier, the UK election watchdog issued a clarification on AI Steve's candidature.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/can-uks-new-pm-keir-starmer-fix-labours-fragile-relations-with-india-6038590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: UK Elections: Mending India-Labour Relations Won't Be Easy For Starmer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/can-uks-new-pm-keir-starmer-fix-labours-fragile-relations-with-india-6038590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:15:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The relations between the UK's Labour Party and the Indian government are complex, influenced by historical ties, diaspora politics, and divergent policy priorities. Addressing such challenges will require nuanced diplomacy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gaf9agr8_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>As was widely expected in the UK elections, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-gets-its-future-back-labours-keir-starmer-in-victory-speech-6037737">the Labour Party has registered</a> one of its biggest victories, inflicting a huge defeat on the Conservative Party.</p>

<p>No one had expected this seismic outcome just a few years ago. But Labour leader Sir Keir Starmer, who is going to be the next British Prime Minister, is being hailed by everyone for changing the fortune of the party. He promised to get Britain out of economic stagnation and claimed he would fix the ailing National Health Services. He even reached out to ethnic communities, including the Indian diaspora.</p>

<h2><strong>'Namaste', Starmer</strong></h2>

<p>In the last days of the election campaign, Keir Starmer visited the Shree Swaminarayan Mandir Kingsbury, a prominent Hindu temple in London, and said "namaste" with folded hands. His charm offensive included him wearing a <em>tilak </em>on his forehead and a floral garland around his neck. Starmer may have looked out of place, but it was an attempt to placate angry Indian diaspora voters, the majority of whom were expected to favour the Conservative Party. The temple visit was also intended to send out a strong signal of friendship with India.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-live-rishi-sunak-braces-for-huge-loss-as-early-results-herald-labour-keir-starmer-win-6037190">Also Read |&nbsp;Labour Sweeps UK Polls, Rishi Sunak's Party Ousted For 1st Time In 14 Years</a></strong></p>

<p>Despite his awkwardness, Starmer knew he had to perform this political act, not only because his visit underscored Labour's commitment to embracing and celebrating diversity within the UK, but also because he needed to repair relations with the influential Indian diaspora, and, by extension, India. It had been clear for quite some time that his party was returning to power after a hiatus of 14 years and he was going to be the next UK Prime Minister; that is why he needed to undertake an India outreach before assuming office.</p>

<h2><strong>The Baggage Of The Past</strong></h2>

<p>Starmer's gesture of visiting the temple was particularly significant given the events of September 2019, when during its annual conference in Brighton, the Labour Party under Jeremy Corbyn's leadership had passed a motion addressing the situation in Jammu and Kashmir. The motion declared that there was a humanitarian crisis in the region and asserted that the people of Kashmir should be granted the right to self-determination. Additionally, it had called for the deployment of international monitors to the area to ensure the protection of human rights and the assessment of the situation on the ground.</p>

<p>Needless to say, the Labour Party had gone too far. And despite the clarification issued by Jeremy Corbyn, the damage was done.</p>

<p>The motion was met with significant backlash from the Indian diaspora, who felt that it was one-sided and did not consider the complexities of the Kashmir issue. The event marked a turning point as many members of the Indian community began to shift their allegiances to the Conservative Party.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-a-massacre-conservative-leader-as-labour-heads-for-massive-uk-win-6037516">Also Read |&nbsp;"This Is A Massacre": Conservative Leader As Labour Heads For Massive UK Win</a></strong></p>

<p>The Indian government also responded sharply to the Labour's motion. It was reported that the Indian High Commission in London took the unprecedented step of cancelling a scheduled dinner for Labour leaders, signalling its strong disapproval. The Indian government officially rejected the motion, emphasising its concerns about what it viewed as interference in its internal affairs.</p>

<p>In an effort to mend relations, Starmer attempted to address the situation last year, when he asserted that the Labour Party would strive to maintain strong relations with India, indicating a desire to rebuild trust and cooperation. Despite these efforts, the episode highlighted the fragile nature of Labour's relations with India and underscored the significant political influence of the Indian diaspora in the UK.<br />
Labour's image makeover under Starmer</p>

<h2><strong>A Changed Labour</strong></h2>

<p>Indeed, the Labour Party has now made a triumphant comeback, securing a thumping majority. We should keep in mind that the party is a much-changed one under Starmer. It wants to inject more depth and substance into Britain's strategic partnership with India.</p>

<p>India is most likely to carefully monitor Labour's policy stance on Kashmir, immigration and the proposed Free Trade Agreement (FTA). The Indian government may have apprehensions about Labour's views on its internal matters, but on balance, the India-UK bilateral relations will not change much under Starmer. In fact, Labour supporters in the Indian community believe that under him, the relations are likely to improve. It is being claimed that the number of Indian-origin Labour MPs would double from the current six members in the outgoing Parliament.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Will The Ties Improve?</strong></h2>

<p>Academics in the UK at times tend to romanticise the bilateral ties between the two countries, looking at it chiefly from the prism of colonial nostalgia. We are led to believe that it is in India's interest to have a deeper strategic partnership with Britain. To be honest, however, India sees Britain as a middle power, whose influence on the global stage has been on the wane for long. One can only blame the Conservative Party for it, a beleaguered and divided house which presided over 14 years of stagnation. India under Narendra Modi, who was born after the country's independence, is, whether rightly or wrongly, not in awe of its erstwhile colonial masters.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/uks-labour-party-commits-to-stamping-out-anti-india-sentiments-5997729">Also Read |&nbsp;UK's Labour Party Commits To Stamping Out "Anti-India Sentiments"</a></strong></p>

<p>Yes, the bilateral trade in goods and services is growing steadily, and stood at&nbsp;£39 billion last year, with the balance of trade heavily in India's favour. Yes, we have a vocal, upwardly mobile Indian diaspora, which acts as a bridge between the two countries and it often works to India's advantage. But the oomph factor in bilateral relations has been missing for a long time. For example, India and the US warmed up to each other and became trusted partners only after the Civil Nuclear Agreement between the two countries was brokered under President George W. Bush. It was a pivotal moment that added significant "oomph" to bilateral ties and transformed the dynamics of the relationship, fostering deeper strategic, economic, and technological cooperation. It set the stage for an enduring partnership in the 21st century. Even during the Obama and Trump administrations the bilateral ties never ran out of excitement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One cannot say the same about India-UK relations, which badly need to be injected with energy, excitement and a mega-deal.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>FTA: Starmer's First Challenge In India-UK Ties</strong></h2>

<p>With regards to India, one of the first tasks on Starmer's desk will be to reach a Free Trade Agreement. He has maintained his commitment to completing the FTA, but it is not going to be easy. India's priority appears to be to finalise an agreement with the European Union (EU) first. The bilateral trade in goods and services last year stood at €113&nbsp;billion. The two sides relaunched the negotiations in 2022 and the progress is said to be satisfactory.</p>

<p>According to a group of researchers, another stumbling block in the India-UK FTA is "the opposition in the UK to Indian demands for more visas for intra-company transfers and particularly to demands that social security contributions from Indian workers during such transfers be reimbursed".</p>

<h2><strong>Immigration Policies</strong></h2>

<p>Brexit has led to record levels of Indian immigration. Of the 6.85 lakh immigrants in the UK today, the majority come from India. The Labour Party's stated aim is to reduce legal immigration and curb illegal immigration. Many of the legal Indian immigrants are IT professionals on work permits, contributing to the UK's technology sector. There is a small number of illegal immigrants from India as well.</p>

<p>The party's policy seeks to balance the economic benefits of skilled migrants with the goal of controlling overall immigration numbers, reflecting broader political and economic priorities.<br />
Human Rights and Citizenship Laws</p>

<p>Historically, the Labour Party has been vocal about human rights issues in India, particularly on laws like the Citizenship (Amendment) Act (CAA) and the National Register of Citizens (NRC). The Labour Party's criticism has been viewed by the Indian government as interference and a misrepresentation of India's internal policies aimed at addressing specific security concerns. Starmer will be under pressure from domestic human rights organisations to put forward liberal British perspectives. His diplomatic skills are bound to be tested in the coming months and years.</p>

<p>The relations between the UK's Labour Party and the Indian government are complex, influenced by historical ties, diaspora politics, and divergent policy priorities. Addressing such challenges will require nuanced diplomacy, mutual respect, and an understanding of the sensitivities involved on both sides.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6nbkdt98_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/co-flier-recalls-meeting-indian-origin-woman-who-died-mid-flight-her-innocent-face-6038584]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Co-Flier Recalls "Innocent Face" Of Indian-Origin Woman Who Died Mid-Flight]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/co-flier-recalls-meeting-indian-origin-woman-who-died-mid-flight-her-innocent-face-6038584]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:13:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Manpreet Kaur was studying in Melbourne and wanted to become a chef. Her body cannot leave Australia because she died from tuberculosis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man seated next to an Indian-origin woman, who suddenly collapsed and died moments before her flight from Melbourne to New Delhi took off, said he is "haunted" by the incident. The incident happened on June 20 when 24-year-old <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-woman-24-dies-on-qantas-flight-from-melbourne-to-new-delhi-6009454">Manpreet Kaur</a> boarded a Qantas flight to fly to Delhi. She suffered a medical episode while putting her seatbelt on and died on the spot. Ravinder Arora was sitting next to her and noticed Ms Kaur when he was taking his seat.</p>

<p>"When I boarded the plane, she was already seated in the aisle. I was in the window, so I asked if she could please get up so I could occupy my seat," <a href="https://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/passenger-speaks-after-woman-dies-next-to-him-on-qantas-flight/news-story/24e8396d8eb3a1d35aea4a4291b847ba">he told <em>NewsAU</em></a>.</p>

<p>"I noticed that she began scrolling through photos on her mobile phone and stopped at a photograph of an elderly couple," said Mr Singh. "I asked if they were her parents. She smiled and nodded and kept staring at it."</p>

<p>Ms Kaur was going to India for the first time in four years.</p>

<p>As the plane began moving on the runway, Mr Singh said the woman leaned forward resting her head on the seat in front of her. But a jerk in the plane caused Ms Kaur's head to move towards Mr Singh. He realised something was wrong and and alerted the crew.</p>

<p>The flight attendants did everything to revive her but all the efforts were unsuccessful.</p>

<p>Mr Singh said he remains haunted by the incident.</p>

<p>"The incident has been etched in my memory for life. It is very difficult to digest that a young girl with whom you were just interacting with has passed away in front of your eyes," he told the outlet.</p>

<p>"Her innocent face stills haunts me and I want her parents to know she loved them a lot. She left this world peacefully looking at their photograph. My heart breaks for her family who would have been looking forward to seeing her after a long time," Mr Singh added.</p>

<p>Ms Kaur was studying in Melbourne and wanted to become a chef. Her body cannot leave Australia because she died from tuberculosis, forcing her parents to apply for visas so they can fly to the country and attend their daughter's funeral.</p>

<p>Her family said Ms Kaur's health had been rapidly deteriorating over recent month and she had "difficulty talking" and "no energy to do anything", <a href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/07/05/womans-heartbreaking-last-words-dying-flight-21165451/">as per <em>Metro</em></a>.</p>

<p>Authorities in Australia started the contact tracing the following day, and anyone identified as a potential risk is being notified.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/l831esmo_manpreet-kaur_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Manpreet Kaur wanted to become a chef.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-dominates-scotland-scottish-national-party-suffers-major-setback-6038537]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Labour Dominates Scotland, Scottish National Party Suffers Major Setback]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-dominates-scotland-scottish-national-party-suffers-major-setback-6038537]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:08:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scotland's pro-separatist Scottish National Party was virtually wiped out at the UK general election on Friday, suffering a devastating blow to its withering independence movement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scotland's pro-separatist Scottish National Party was virtually wiped out at the UK general election on Friday, suffering a devastating blow to its withering independence movement.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer's Labour Party overturned more than a decade of SNP domination by winning a majority of Scottish seats as it rode to power in Westminster.</p>

<p>The SNP lost dozens of lawmakers as it headed for its worst result in a British general election since 2010, with senior MP Stephen Flynn, who held his seat, lamenting a "black night" for his party.</p>

<p>Labour sealed its comeback in its former heartland when it passed the 29-seat threshold to become the largest party in the country shortly after 5:30 am (0430 GMT).</p>

<p>A BBC exit poll predicted that the SNP would win only eight constituencies in Scotland, down from the 48 it won at the last election in 2019, when Labour returned just one Scottish MP.</p>

<p>The crushing loss means the SNP will lose its position as Britain's third-biggest party, which brings a high-profile slot during the weekly Prime Minister's Questions session in parliament.</p>

<p>It will also lose out on public funding and key positions on parliamentary select committees.</p>

<p>"There will have to be a lot of soul-searching as a party as a consequence of these results that have come in tonight," SNP leader John Swinney admitted to the BBC.</p>

<p>Ex-SNP leader and former Scottish leader Nicola Sturgeon said the prediction was "at the grimmer end of the expectations" for her party, which had been tipped to endure a chastening performance.</p>

<p>"This is seismic for Labour. There's no getting away from that, it's a massive achievement for Keir Starmer," she said, as Labour was tipped to win 410 seats and secure a majority of 170 in Britain as a whole.</p>

<h3><strong>Finance scandal&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The SNP has dominated in Scotland in the last three UK elections, peaking with the 2015 vote when it won 56 seats out of 59 seats. In 2010, it got only six seats.</p>

<p>But the party has been under pressure from the resurgence of Labour in its former fiefdom north of the English border, as it rides a wave of displeasure against the Tories nationwide.</p>

<p>The SNP was overtaken by the centrist Liberal Democrats in party size and fighting to stop Nigel Farage's right-wing upstarts Reform UK from pushing it down to fifth position at Westminster.</p>

<p>The SNP has been in turmoil for months as voters tire of its 17 years in charge of the devolved Scottish parliament in Edinburgh.</p>

<p>Critics have also accused it of focusing on independence at the expense of key issues such as the cost-of-living crisis, education and health.</p>

<p>Support for the SNP has also slumped amid a finances scandal that saw Sturgeon's husband, Peter Murrell, charged with embezzlement. Murrell is the party's former chief executive.</p>

<p>Sturgeon herself was arrested, but released without charge.</p>

<p>Swinney only took charge in May following the resignation of Humza Yousaf after the collapse of the SNP's power-sharing deal with the Scottish Greens in Edinburgh.</p>

<p>Yousaf was in power for just over a year.</p>

<p>Swinney had pledged to push for fresh talks on another independence referendum if the SNP had won a majority of seats in Thursday's vote.</p>

<p>Labour and the Conservatives insist the issue was dealt with at the 2014 referendum when 55 percent of voters in Scotland opted to remain part of the UK.</p>

<p>Despite the SNP's slump, the number of Scots favouring independence has held at around 40 percent, according to surveys, providing the SNP with some solace.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gl0b8j9g_john-swinney-ndtv-_625x300_04_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The crushing loss means the SNP will lose its position as Britain's third-biggest party.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-leaders-in-uk-polls-suella-braverman-satvir-kaur-among-indian-origin-leaders-who-won-in-uk-poll-6037967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Suella Braverman, Satvir Kaur Among Indian-Origin Leaders Who Won In UK Poll]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-leaders-in-uk-polls-suella-braverman-satvir-kaur-among-indian-origin-leaders-who-won-in-uk-poll-6037967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:08:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The latest trends in the United Kingdom election results show the Labour Party, led by Keir Starmer, is on course for a landslide victory. Of]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The latest trends in the United Kingdom election results show the Labour Party, led by Keir Starmer, is on course for a landslide victory. Of the 388 seats in which results were out, the Labour won 282 seats, while Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's Conservative Party managed to win 53 seats.<br />
<br />
In the 650-member House of Commons, a party needs 326 seats to form the government.<br />
<br />
The election also saw a significant number of Indian-origin candidates. According to British Future, 14 per cent of the new Parliament is expected to have ethnic minority representatives.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>How Indian-origin leaders fared in UK polls</strong><br />
<br />
<strong>Rishi Sunak (CON)</strong><br />
<br />
Although the Conservative party fared poorly, Rishi Sunak has emerged victorious in his constituency, Richmond (Yorks) and Northallerton. He defeated Labour's Tom Wilson by a margin of almost 13,000 votes.<br />
<br />
<strong>Suella Braverman (CON)</strong><br />
<br />
Suella Braverman, from the Conservative party, has retained the Fareham and Waterlooville seat. She has been the MP for Fareham since 2015 and has served as the Home Secretary from October 2022 to November 2023.<br />
<br />
<strong>Priti Patel (CON)</strong><br />
<br />
Priti Patel, a member of the Conservative party and former Home Secretary from 2019 to 2022, has contested the Witham seat once again, with the results still awaited. The Gujarati-origin politician has been the MP for Witham since 2010 and is hoping to retain her seat in the current election.<br />
<br />
<strong>Kanishka Narayan (LAB)</strong><br />
<br />
Kanishka Narayan, an Indian-origin Labour Party member from Bihar, has won the Vale of Glamorgan seat. He wrested the seat from Conservative Alun Cairns who was an MP from 2010 to 2024.<br />
<br />
<strong>Satvir Kaur (LAB)</strong><br />
<br />
Labour Party's Satvir Kaur won her seat in the 2024 general election. She was elected from the Southampton Test by 15,945 votes.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Primesh Patel (LAB)</strong><br />
<br />
Indian-origin Labour candidate Primesh Patel lost the Harrow East seat to Conservative Bob Blackman by over 11,000 votes.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Shivani Raja (CON)</strong><br />
<br />
Conservative candidate Shivani Raja has won the Leicester East seat, defeating Labour's Rajesh Agarwal by over 4,000 votes. The Leicester East constituency saw a highly contested election with several high-profile candidates, including former MPs Claude Webbe and Keith Vaz, who ran as independents.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/ub39skpo_suella-braverman-afp_625x300_13_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The election saw a significant number of Indian-origin candidates.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greece-will-now-work-6-days-a-week-labour-unions-call-it-barbaric-6038414]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greece Will Now Work 6 Days A Week, Labour Unions Call It "Barbaric"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greece-will-now-work-6-days-a-week-labour-unions-call-it-barbaric-6038414]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 11:47:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As more European countries move towards a shorter, 4-day working week, workers in Greece will have to work for six days every week in a new government initiative aimed at boosting productivity and employment across the nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As more European countries move towards a shorter, 4-day working week, workers in Greece will have to work for six days every week in a new government initiative aimed at boosting productivity and employment across the nation.</p>

<p>From July 1, employees of private companies that provide round-the-clock services will have to work 48 hours a week instead of the traditional 40 hours. The rule would not apply to food service and tourism workers.</p>

<p>Workers will have the option of working an additional two hours per day or an extra eight-hour shift every week and be rewarded with a 40% rise in their daily wage.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis has claimed that the measure, a part of a broader set of labour law reforms last year, is “worker-friendly” and “deeply growth-orientated.” “It brings Greece in line with the rest of Europe," he said.</p>

<p>The government has claimed that a longer work week will ensure employees are sufficiently compensated for overtime work and crack down on the problem of undeclared labour.</p>

<p>PM Mitsotakis has also touted the initiative as a solution for Greece's shrinking population and shortage of skilled workers. Since 2009, over 500,000 young educated citizens have moved out of the country amid a decade-long debt crisis.</p>

<p>However, the move has been heavily criticised by labour unions and political observers, with some calling it "barbaric". Unions have argued that the new law will help employers not hire additional staff.</p>

<p>EU's statistics agency, Eurostat, says the Greeks work an average of 41 hours a week --- the longest in Europe and get paid much less. The left-wing opposition has often referred to the phenomenon as “Bulgarian salaries in a country of British prices”.</p>

<p>“It makes no sense whatsoever. When almost every other civilised country is enacting a four-day week, Greece decides to go the other way," Akis Sotiropoulos a member of the civil servants' union told the Guardian.</p>

<p>“In reality, this has been passed by a government ideologically committed to generating ever bigger profits for capital. Better productivity comes with better work conditions, a better quality of life [for employees] and that, we now know, is about less hours not more," he added</p>

<p>Research has shown that four-day week programmes help increase levels of productivity and improve levels of focus. In 2022, Belgium gave its workers the legal right to spread their working week over four days instead of five. Similar four-day week trials have also been carried out in countries like UK, Germany, Japan, South Africa and Canada.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/0fm9ivhg_office-generic_625x300_29_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Workers will have the option of working an additional two hours per day or an extra eight-hour shift]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-suella-braverman-under-fire-for-immigration-remarks-wins-in-uk-polls-6038310]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Suella Braverman, Under Fire For Immigration Remarks, Wins In UK Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-suella-braverman-under-fire-for-immigration-remarks-wins-in-uk-polls-6038310]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 11:32:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Home Secretary Suella Braverman won the newly-created Fareham and Waterlooville constituency in the 2024 UK general election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Home Secretary Suella Braverman won the newly-created Fareham and Waterlooville constituency in the 2024 UK general election. The Conservative Party leader defeated Labour's Gemma Furnivall by a margin of over 6,000 votes.</p>

<p>Following her victory, the right-wing leader issued an apology to the public for the Conservative Party's performance over the past 14 years. “I'm sorry that my party didn't listen to you,” she said in a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cnd0yndw0jeo ">press conference</a>. “The Conservative party has let you down.”</p>

<p>The Indian-origin MP acknowledged that the party had failed to keep its promises and acted entitled to the voters' support without delivering on their commitments. “You, the great British people, voted for us for over 14 years, and we did not keep our promises, despite promising time after time that we would do those things,” she said.</p>

<p>Ms Braverman talked about the need for the party to learn from its mistakes. She stated, “Because if we don't, bad, as tonight has been for my party, we'll have many worse nights to come.”</p>

<p>The former Home Secretary won the Fareham and Waterlooville seat after a challenging re-election bid. She was fired by Prime Minister Rishi Sunak in 2023 for publicly accusing the Metropolitan Police of bias in handling pro-Palestine protests. Ms Braverman, taking a stance against the Gaza rallies, called pro-Palestine demonstrations "hate marches" and suggested waving a Palestinian flag could be a criminal offence. She also accused police of favouritism and ignoring "pro-Palestinian mobs."</p>

<p>After her dismissal from office, she criticised the government's handling of migration. She argued that the pressure on public services is "unsustainable" and demanded stricter measures to reduce migration.</p>

<p>Ms Braverman had also spoken out against the record high migration figures, calling it a "slap in the face" to the British public who have consistently voted to reduce migration. "The pressure on housing, the NHS, schools, wages, and community cohesion, is unsustainable. When do we say: enough is enough?" she had said. She argued that Brexit provided the tools to control migration, and it was “time to use them.” She&nbsp;had also argued that some people were homeless as a "lifestyle choice."&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/4qc5c81_suella-braverman-bloomberg_625x300_30_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-set-to-be-next-uk-pm-changed-labour-party-stance-on-kashmir-6038301]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer, Set To Be Next UK PM, Changed Party's Stance On Kashmir]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-set-to-be-next-uk-pm-changed-labour-party-stance-on-kashmir-6038301]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 11:25:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One of the first challenges for Keir Starmer as the UK Prime Minister will be to restore the Labour Party's ties with India, which has been tumultuous due to their remarks on Kashmir. Starmer led the party to a landslide win.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the first challenges for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-live-rishi-sunak-braces-for-huge-loss-as-early-results-herald-labour-keir-starmer-win-6037190">Keir Starmer</a> as the UK Prime Minister will be to restore the Labour Party's ties with India, which has been tumultuous due to their remarks on Kashmir. Starmer led the party to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-results-2024-live-keir-starmer-labour-party-tipped-for-historic-sweep-rishi-sunak-conservatives-6034921">landslide win in the general elections</a>, a result that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606">spelt doom for Rishi Sunak's Conservative Party</a>. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In the past, the Labour Party has often come under fire for their stand on the Kashmir issue. Their stance has been in stark contrast with the British government's view that Kashmir is a bilateral matter between India and Pakistan.</p>

<p>Under the leadership of Jeremy Corbyn, the party had in September 2019 passed an emergency motion calling for international observers to "enter" Kashmir and demand the right of self-determination for its people. It also called for Mr Corbyn to meet the high commissioners of both India and Pakistan to ensure there is "mediation" and restoration of peace and normality to prevent a potential nuclear conflict.</p>

<p>The resolution was slammed by India as an effort to "pander to vote-bank's interest".</p>

<p>Starmer, realising how important ties with the world's fastest-growing economy are, set out on a mission to fix the missteps made by his party in the past. His manifesto included a commitment to pursue a "new strategic partnership" with India, emphasizing the trade agreement.</p>

<p>During meetings with the Indian diaspora and public addresses, Starmer affirmed that Kashmir is an internal issue and will be resolved by India and Pakistan.</p>

<p>"Any constitutional issues in India are a matter for the Indian Parliament, and Kashmir is a bilateral issue for India and Pakistan to resolve peacefully," he said during a meeting with Labour Friends of India.</p>

<p>During his poll campaign, Starmer embarked on outreach efforts, denouncing Hinduphobia and celebrating cultural festivals like Diwali and Holi.</p>

<p>This policy adjustment aims to rebuild trust with the British-Indian community and foster stronger business ties with India, a critical aspect of Labour's international agenda.</p>

<p>The Labour Party, out of power for over a decade, has also outlined a foreign policy of "progressive realism," emphasizing pragmatic approaches to global challenges such as climate change and international security. Starmer's manifesto includes plans for a new strategic partnership with India, focusing on trade agreements and cooperation in technology, security, education, and environmental issues.</p>

<p>Labour passed the magic number of 326 seats for a House of Commons majority just before 5 am on Friday, confirming a change of government that was predicted for months but is still a remarkable turnaround for Starmer's party in a single electoral cycle. Starmer will now replace Sunak as prime minister on Friday, ending the Tories' 14-year grip on power.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mrjhen9c_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Stermer will be be the next UK Prime Minister.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/count-binface-the-intergalactic-space-warrior-who-took-on-rishi-sunak-6038214]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Count Binface, The "Intergalactic Space Warrior" Who Took On Rishi Sunak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/count-binface-the-intergalactic-space-warrior-who-took-on-rishi-sunak-6038214]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 11:07:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Count Binface, the self-proclaimed "intergalactic space warrior," who contested against Rishi Sunak from the Richmond parliamentary seat in the UK general elections, celebrated his personal best in his fledgling political career: a 6th place finish.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Count Binface, the self-proclaimed "intergalactic space warrior," who contested against Rishi Sunak from the Richmond and Northallerton parliamentary seat in the UK general elections, celebrated his personal best in his fledgling political career: a 6th place finish.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Declaring this moment as "#BindependenceDay", Count Binface wrote, "My highest ever finish. 6th. My highest ever parliamentary vote. 308. My highest height advantage. 2ft 6in #BindependenceDay has come."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My highest ever finish. 6th<br />
My highest ever parliamentary vote. 308<br />
My highest height advantage. 2ft 6in<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BindependenceDay?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BindependenceDay</a> has come. <a href="https://t.co/InPXEyBRd3">pic.twitter.com/InPXEyBRd3</a></p>
— Count Binface (@CountBinface) <a href="https://twitter.com/CountBinface/status/1809087804254695796?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Count Binface, known off-stage as comedian Jon Harvey, faced off against Mr Sunak, donning his signature headgear resembling a rubbish bin. Among his promises were the construction of at least "one affordable home," the institution of national service for all former prime ministers, and even the nationalisation of singer Adele.</p>

<p>Mr Harvey's alter ego has a history of taking on prominent political figures. Count Binface's journey in UK elections began in 2017, when he ran against Prime Minister Theresa May under the guise of Lord Buckethead. In 2019, Binface ran against then-Prime Minister Boris Johnson in the general election, and more recently, he participated in London's mayoral race, where he outperformed the far-right Britain First party by 4,000 votes.</p>

<p>"In the UK, anybody, literally anybody, is free to stand in an election, no matter how idiotic the get-up," Binface told news agency AFP.</p>

<p>In the recent election, Binface's policies continued to capture public imagination. His proposals included capping the price of croissants at 1.10 pounds, mandatory national service for former prime ministers, and a bid to represent the UK in the Eurovision Song Contest.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer will today become Britain's new prime minister, as his centre-left opposition Labour party swept to a landslide general election victory, ending 14 years of right-wing Conservative rule.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d1b3kh8g_count-binface-_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Harvey's alter ego has a history of taking on prominent political figures.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ryanair-airlines-offers-a-seat-to-outgoing-uk-prime-minister-rishi-sunak-6037903]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ryanair Airlines Offers "A Seat" To Outgoing UK Prime Minister Rishi Sunak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ryanair-airlines-offers-a-seat-to-outgoing-uk-prime-minister-rishi-sunak-6037903]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 10:10:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taking a swipe at Rishi Sunak, whose party has lost the UK election, European Airlines Ryanair said in a post on X that they have got a "seat" for the outgoing British Prime Minister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taking a swipe at Rishi Sunak, whose party has lost the UK election, European Airlines Ryanair said in a post on X that they have got a "seat" for the outgoing British Prime Minister.</p>

<p>Labour Party leader Keir Starmer has, however, secured the seat of the next Prime Minister with a landslide victory. Ryanair's tweet came as Rishi Sunak's Conservative Party, trailing badly from the start, secured their first win only three hours after the counting of votes began.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">don't worry <a href="https://twitter.com/RishiSunak?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RishiSunak</a> we've got a seat for you <a href="https://t.co/5JsrTxCqlp">pic.twitter.com/5JsrTxCqlp</a></p>
— Ryanair (@Ryanair) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ryanair/status/1808885241051857103?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Keir Starmer's Labour Party, on the other hand, is on the track for a landslide win after 1997, as predicted by the opinion polls. The Labour Party has dethroned the Conservatives in the UK after 14 years.</p>

<p>Both the Labour Party's leader and deputy leader, Keir Starmer and Angela Rayner have been reelected in Holborn, St Pancras, and Ashton-under-Lyne respectively. Among the other key contenders, Liberal Democrat Ed Davey has been reelected in Kingston and Suburbiton, and Reform UK leader Nigel Farage has won Clacton.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak also won his own seat and conceded defeat, saying: "I am sorry".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qv126qvo_rishi-sunak-1200_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak also won his own seat and conceded defeat, saying: "I am sorry".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-urges-china-to-avoid-escalation-amid-renewed-military-activity-6037867]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taiwan Urges China To Avoid Escalation Amid Renewed Military Activity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-urges-china-to-avoid-escalation-amid-renewed-military-activity-6037867]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 10:03:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwan on Friday reported renewed Chinese military activity nearby with another "combat patrol" as the government called on Beijing not to escalate tensions after the seizure of a Taiwanese fishing boat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan on Friday reported renewed Chinese military activity nearby with another "combat patrol" as the government called on Beijing not to escalate tensions after the seizure of a Taiwanese fishing boat.</p>

<p>China, which views democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory, has stepped up its pressure over the past four years, both militarily and politically.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Chinese officials boarded and detained a Taiwanese fishing boat for illegally operating in the country's waters, in what a senior Taiwan official said may be an act of psychological warfare.</p>

<p>Taiwan's defence ministry said that starting just before 7 a.m. (2300 GMT) on Friday, it had detected 26 Chinese military aircraft, including J-16 fighters, carrying out a "joint combat readiness patrol" with Chinese warships.</p>

<p>The Chinese aircraft flew into airspace to the north, centre and southern part of Taiwan, the ministry said.</p>

<p>Taiwan has detected at least 127 Chinese military aircraft operating near the island since the start of this month.</p>

<p>China's defence ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters earlier on Friday, Taiwan Premier Cho Jung-tai said fishermen should raise their alert level and not do anything that could be considered illegal.</p>

<p>"At the same time, I also want to ask the Chinese side not to escalate with any the use of any excessive measures, because this can easily cause tension and unnecessary confrontation which is extremely unnecessary," he added.</p>

<p>China says the root cause of its problems with Taiwan is what Beijing views as the "separatist" views of new President Lai Ching-te.</p>

<p>China staged war games shortly after Lai took office in May, and has rebuffed his repeated calls for talks.</p>

<p>Lai rejects China's sovereignty claims, saying only Taiwan's people can decide their future.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/u0mfg8h_china-taiwan_625x300_18_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taiwan has detected at least 127 Chinese military aircraft operating near the island]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-gets-its-future-back-labours-keir-starmer-in-victory-speech-6037737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["UK Gets Its Future Back": Labour's Keir Starmer In Victory Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-gets-its-future-back-labours-keir-starmer-in-victory-speech-6037737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:40:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Labour's Sir Keir Starmer delivered a storming victory speech Friday morning after the party swept the UK general election, declaring the country "gets its future back after 14 years (of a Conservative Party government)".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Labour's Sir <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://ww.ndtv.com/topic/keir-starmer" target="_blank">Keir Starmer</a> delivered a storming victory speech Friday morning after the party swept the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world/uk" target="_blank">UK general election</a>, declaring the country "gets its future back after 14 years (of a Conservative Party government)". A relieved-looking Prime Minister-elect said, with a grin and to loud cheers, "We did it. You campaigned for it, fought for it, voted for it, and now it has arrived. And it feels good, to be honest."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/labour-party" target="_blank">Labour</a> crossed the majority mark of 326 - and is on course to match exit poll predictions of over 400 seats, a '<em>400 paar</em>' in the United Kingdom - in the 650-seat House of Commons early this morning, prompting outgoing PM <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/rishi-sunak" target="_blank">Rishi Sunak</a> to concede and promise a "peaceful and orderly" handover.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer thanked party workers for their hard work - including nearly five years of revamping and rebranding Labour in the face of Tory dominance - and urged them to savour the moment, but warned them of challenges ahead and pledged his government would work for "national renewal".</p>

<p>"We did it. Thank you truly... you have changed our country," Mr Starmer told a sea of supporters at a dawn victory rally in central London, "Four-and-a-half years of work changing this party... this is what it is for. A changed Labour... ready to restore Britain to the service of the working people."</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Labour Sweeps UK Polls, Tories Ousted For 1st Time In 14 Years</a></p>

<p>"... across our country people will be waking up to the news... relieved a weight has been lifted (and) a burden finally removed from the shoulders of this great nation. Now, we can look forward (and) walk into the morning. The sunlight of hope, pale at first, but getting stronger through the day..."</p>

<p>"(But) a mandate like this comes with a great responsibility... Today we start the next chapter... begin the work of change, the mission of national renewal, and start to rebuild our country," he said.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-be-uk-pm-what-this-means-for-india-6037593#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Keir Starmer To Be UK PM: What This Means For India</a></p>

<p>"We have to return politics to public service and show out government can be a force for good," he said, even as results trickled in from across the country to add to Labour's already unbeatable lead.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer - who will be sworn in as Prime Minister - won his Holborn and St Pancras seat in despite a sharply reduced majority - from nearly 23,000 votes in 2019 to fewer than 12,000 this time.</p>

<h3><strong>Sunak Says "Sorry"</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier today Rishi Sunak apologised to the Conservative Party and its supporters.</p>

<p>"I am sorry... I take responsibility for the loss," he said.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"I Am Sorry": Rishi Sunak Concedes Defeat In UK Polls</a></p>

<p>Mr Sunak surprised many by calling for an election ahead of schedule - when his party was 20 points behind Labour in opinion polls - believing the gap would reverse, as it has in past elections.</p>

<p>Unfortunately it did not. Mr Sunak did, though, retain his seat of Richmond and Northallerton. He has vowed to continue as an MP even if, as is likely, he will be relieved of party leadership.</p>

<p>"The Labour Party has won this election and I have called Keir Starmer to congratulate him."</p>

<p>Mr Sunak won his seat but big names from the Conservatives, including former Prime Minister Liz Truss and one-time PM-hopeful Jacob Rees-Mogg, fell by the roadside on a chastening night for the party.</p>

<p>Ms Truss lost South West Norfolk by 630 votes and Mr Rees-Mogg lost North East Somerset and Hanham. Penny Mordaunt, another Tory big name and PM-hopeful, lost from Portsmouth North.</p>

<p>Chancellor Jeremy Hunt, however, just about managed to retain his Godalming and Ash seat.</p>

<h3><strong>Wales Votes Out Tories</strong></h3>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-results-2024-live-keir-starmer-labour-party-tipped-for-historic-sweep-rishi-sunak-conservatives-6034921" target="_blank">Conservative suffered defeats in key constituencies</a>, and has been wiped out entirely in Wales - their worst result since 1997 - with Labour making big gains. The party won 27 of Wales' 32 seats, an increase of nine from the last election. Plaid Cymru won four and the Liberal Democrats one.</p>

<h3><strong>Labour's Scotland Triumph</strong></h3>

<p>Labour also made gains in Scotland, where the Scottish National Party - which was defending 48 of 57 seats - has been thumped. First Minister John Swinney called the results "damaging" for his party and ex-SNP leader Nicola Sturgeon said, "This is seismic for Labour... a massive achievement for Starmer."</p>

<p>The SNP lost dozens of lawmakers in its worst result in a British general election since 2010, with Labour sealing a comeback in its former heartland when it passed the 29-seat threshold early morning.</p>

<p>The crushing loss means the SNP will lose its position as Britain's third-biggest party, which brings a high-profile slot during the weekly Prime Minister's Questions session in parliament.</p>

<p>It will also lose out on public funding and key positions on parliamentary select committees.</p>

<h3><strong>Sinn Fein Rules In N Ireland</strong></h3>

<p>Over in Northern Ireland Sinn Fein is the largest party for the first time with seven seats. Two of NI's 18 seats have yet to be declared</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0fukqq6_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Labour leader Sir Keir Starmer will be the new UK Prime Minister (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Am Sorry": UK PM Rishi Sunak Concedes Defeat In UK Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:16:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK Prime Minister Rishi Sunak has conceded defeat in the country's general elections as the trends showed that the Opposition Labour Party had won over 300 seats, while Sunak's Conservative Party is ahead on 61.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Prime Minister Rishi Sunak has conceded defeat in the country's general elections as the trends showed that the Opposition <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-results-2024-live-keir-starmer-labour-party-tipped-for-historic-sweep-rishi-sunak-conservatives-6034921">Labour Party had won over 400 seats</a>, while Sunak's Conservative Party is ahead on 110.</p>

<p>"The Labour Party has won this general election, and I've called Sir Keir Starmer to congratulate him on his victory. Today, power will change hands in a peaceful and orderly manner, with goodwill on all sides. That is something that should give us all confidence in our country's stability and future," Rishi Sunak said while addressing his supporters in Richmond and Northern Allerton.</p>

<p>"I am sorry. I take responsibility for the loss," he added.</p>

<p>Sunak will tender his resignation to head of state King Charles III, with the monarch then asking Starmer, as the leader of the largest party in parliament, to form a government.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-gets-its-future-back-labours-keir-starmer-in-victory-speech-6037737">Keir Starmer's Labour Party</a> will come to power facing a daunting challenge, with a sluggish economy, creaking public services, and falling living standards - all factors which contributed to the Conservatives' demise.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer will be Britain's next prime minister with his centre left Labour Party expected to win a huge majority in a parliamentary election, ending 14 years of often tumultuous Conservative government by trouncing Rishi Sunak's party.</p>

<p>Despite his convincing victory, polls have suggested there is little enthusiasm for Starmer or his party, and he comes to power at a time when the country is facing a series of daunting challenges.</p>

<p>Britain's tax burden is set to hit its highest since just after World War Two, net debt is almost equivalent to annual economic output, living standards have fallen, and public services are creaking, especially the much cherished National Health Service which has been dogged by strikes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/um992j2_rishi-sunak-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-be-uk-pm-what-this-means-for-india-6037593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer To Be Next UK PM: What This Means For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-be-uk-pm-what-this-means-for-india-6037593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:11:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Labour Party chief Keir Starmer is on course to replace Rishi Sunak as the Britain Prime Minister, with early election results pointing at a crushing loss for the Conservatives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Labour Party chief Keir Starmer is on course to replace <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-live-rishi-sunak-braces-for-huge-loss-as-early-results-herald-labour-keir-starmer-win-6037190">Rishi Sunak</a> as the Britain Prime Minister, with election results pointing at a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-results-2024-live-keir-starmer-labour-party-tipped-for-historic-sweep-rishi-sunak-conservatives-6034921">crushing loss for the Conservatives</a>. The first month of a Keir Starmer premiership will be a whirlwind of international diplomacy including meetings with US President Joe Biden and European leaders.</p>

<p>Labour, out of power since 2010, has pledged a foreign policy of "progressive realism", seeing a more volatile world "as it is not as we would want it to be", said David Lammy, who is expected to become foreign secretary.</p>

<p>The party has also pledged to "make Brexit work" and seek "an ambitious" security pact with the European Union.</p>

<p>Another key aspect of Starmer's foreign policy agenda will be strengthening UK-India relations. Acknowledging historical missteps, particularly Labour's stance on issues like <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-set-to-be-next-uk-pm-changed-labour-party-stance-on-kashmir-6038301">Kashmir</a>, Starmer has pledged to forge a new strategic partnership with India. His commitment to a free trade agreement (FTA) and enhanced bilateral cooperation in technology, security, education, and climate change underscores his ambition to elevate relations with one of the world's fastest-growing economies.</p>

<p>His manifesto included a commitment to pursue a "new strategic partnership" with India, emphasizing the trade agreement.</p>

<p>In a bid to repair strained ties with the Indian diaspora in the UK, Starmer during his campaign embarked on domestic outreach efforts, denouncing Hinduphobia and celebrating cultural festivals like Diwali and Holi. These gestures are aimed at fostering greater trust and inclusion within British-Indian communities, a demographic vital to Labour's electoral calculus.</p>

<p>However, challenges loom on the path to realising Starmer's ambitious foreign policy goals, particularly concerning immigration policies and trade agreements. With bipartisan consensus on the need to reduce immigration, negotiations on temporary visas for Indian workers in the UK service industry present a delicate balancing act for Labour.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's last-minute attempt to sway voters appears to have fallen short. The Conservatives warned voters that opting for Labour would lead to higher taxes. Led by Keir Starmer, the Labour Party is currently ahead on 403 seats, while Rishi Sunak's party has won just 109. To secure victory, a party needs to win 326 seats in the 650-member House of Commons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c6g0o5ag_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prospective UK PM Keir Starmer will take oath later today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-a-massacre-conservative-leader-as-labour-heads-for-massive-uk-win-6037516]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["A Massacre": Conservative Leader As Labour Heads For Massive UK Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-a-massacre-conservative-leader-as-labour-heads-for-massive-uk-win-6037516]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 08:56:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scottish Conservative Party leader Ruth Davison described the UK exit poll prediction of a historic defeat for her party as a "massacre". As the votes are being counted, UK PM Rishi Sunak's Conservative party is staring at a massive loss.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scottish Conservative Party leader Ruth Davison described the UK exit poll prediction of a historic defeat for her party as a "massacre". As the votes are being counted, UK PM Rishi Sunak's Conservative party is staring at a massive loss against Keir Starmer's Labour Party which has won over 183 seats so far. The Conservatives or Tories have won 31.</p>

<p>"So actually 131 – while, there is no dressing it up, this is a massacre – they've actually, if this is right, pulled a few back from where they thought they were. But it was not as bad as it might have been," she told Sky News.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The exit poll, published jointly by the BBC, ITV and Sky News, suggested that the Labour Party will win in 410 constituencies will the Conservative numbers will plunge to 131. It also predicts 61 seats for the Liberal Democrats, 13 for Reform UK, four for Plaid Cymru and two for the Green Party. Other parties are expected to win 19 seats.</p>

<p>To secure victory, a party needs to win 326 seats in the 650-member House of Commons.</p>

<p>The results of the sudden elections called by Rishi Sunak in May are hardly surprising as throughout the six-week campaign the UK PM trailed behind 61-year-old Starmer.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Indian-origin PM's term was marred by cost-of-living and migration crisis following years of instability under five different Conservative prime ministers since 2016.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/um992j2_rishi-sunak-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-become-next-uk-pm-wins-home-constituency-6037270]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer, On Course To Become Next UK PM, Wins Home Constituency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-become-next-uk-pm-wins-home-constituency-6037270]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:49:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK Labour Party chief Keir Starmer has emerged victorious from his home seat in London as he inches closer to replace Rishi Sunak as the Prime Minister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Labour Party chief Keir Starmer has emerged victorious from his home seat in London as he inches closer to replace Rishi Sunak as the Prime Minister.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer vowed to serve every person in the constituency after winning from Holborn and St Pancras in the early morning results with 18,884 votes. His winning margin, however, was lower than that of previous elections.</p>

<p>Exit polls had projected a Labour sweep after Thursday's elections, drubbing the Sunak-led Conservatives. However, such projections often go wrong.</p>

<p>In his first remarks after the morning victory, Starmer thanked his voters and said it was a "huge privilege" to be re-elected from Holborn and St Pancras. "You have voted. It's now time for us to deliver," BBC quoted him as saying.</p>

<p>The heart of the UK's democracy beats not in Westminster or Whitehall, but in town halls, community centres and in the hands of people who hold the vote, he said. "Change begins in this community with the people who came together to make life better," the Labour leader added.</p>

<p>He said he would work for everyone in his constituency, irrespective of who voted for him. "I will speak out for you, have your back, fight your corner every single day," he said.</p>

<p>The people are ready for change and the change begins right here because this is your democracy, your community, your future, he told his voters.</p>

<p>Votes being counted for yesterday's elections have put the Labour Party at 133 seats as against the Conservatives' 19, showed data at 8:15 am.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7ufhjkpg_starmer-sunak-afp_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-brazil-president-jair-bolsonaro-accused-in-saudi-jewel-scandal-6037267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Brazil President Jair Bolsonaro Accused In Saudi Jewel Scandal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-brazil-president-jair-bolsonaro-accused-in-saudi-jewel-scandal-6037267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:48:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazil's former president Jair Bolsonaro is facing possible money laundering and other charges related to undeclared diamond jewelry gifted by Saudi Arabia, local media reported Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil's former president Jair Bolsonaro is facing possible money laundering and other charges related to undeclared diamond jewelry gifted by Saudi Arabia, local media reported Thursday.</p>

<p>Federal police accused Bolsonaro, who led South America's largest country from 2019-2022, of money laundering, embezzlement and criminal association, Brazilian news outlet G1 reported.</p>

<p>The case stems from an undeclared set of diamond jewellery worth $3.2 million that was seized by customs inspectors in October 2021.</p>

<p>The jewels were inside a satchel from Bolsonaro's Mining and Energy ministry entourage upon returning from a trip to the Middle East.</p>

<p>Bolsonaro has previously denied any criminal activity in the case.</p>

<p>Eleven other people were facing charges alongside the far-right leader, including his attorney Fabio Wajngarten.</p>

<p>Wajngarten reacted on X, saying he had been accused of crimes "for the bizarre reason of having complied with the law."</p>

<p>Bolsonaro's son, the Brazilian senator Flavio Bolsonaro, also slammed the accusations on X as "open and brazen persecution" against his father.</p>

<p>Despite the moves by the federal police, Brazil's Attorney General Office has yet to issue any formal charges against Bolsonaro before the country's Federal Supreme Court.</p>

<p>The new accusations represent the latest legal trouble for the far-right former leader, who is also under investigation for his role in the January 2023 Brazil Congress attack and faces possible charges for forging Covid-19 vaccination documents to travel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/e1uj056g_bolsonaro-generic_625x300_05_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jair Bolsonaro has previously denied any criminal activity in the case.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openais-internal-system-hacked-ai-tech-details-stolen-in-2023-report-6037225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI's Internal System Hacked, AI Tech Details Stolen In 2023: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openais-internal-system-hacked-ai-tech-details-stolen-in-2023-report-6037225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:38:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A hacker gained access to the internal messaging systems at OpenAI last year and stole details about the design of the company's artificial intelligence technologies, the New York Times reported on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A hacker gained access to the internal messaging systems at OpenAI last year and stole details about the design of the company's artificial intelligence technologies, the New York Times reported on Thursday.</p>

<p>The hacker lifted details from discussions in an online forum where employees talked about OpenAI's latest technologies, the report said, citing two people familiar with the incident.</p>

<p>However, they did not get into the systems where OpenAI, the firm behind chatbot sensation ChatGPT, houses and builds its AI, the report added.</p>

<p>Microsoft Corp-backed OpenAI did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>OpenAI executives informed both employees at an all-hands meeting in April last year and the company's board about the breach, according to the report, but executives decided not to share the news publicly as no information about customers or partners had been stolen.</p>

<p>OpenAI executives did not consider the incident a national security threat, believing the hacker was a private individual with no known ties to a foreign government, the report said. The San Francisco-based company did not inform the federal law enforcement agencies about the breach, it added.</p>

<p>OpenAI in May said it had disrupted five covert influence operations that sought to use its AI models for "deceptive activity" across the internet, the latest to stir safety concerns about the potential misuse of the technology.</p>

<p>The Biden administration was poised to open up a new front in its effort to safeguard the U.S. AI technology from China and Russia with preliminary plans to place guardrails around the most advanced AI Models including ChatGPT, Reuters earlier reported, citing sources.</p>

<p>In May, 16 companies developing AI pledged at a global meeting to develop the technology safely at a time when regulators are scrambling to keep up with rapid innovation and emerging risks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ioh2ev8_open-ai-reuters_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[OpenAI in May said it had disrupted five covert influence operations that sought to use its AI models.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>