<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:06:05 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-king-charles-queen-camilla-plan-visit-to-india-amid-health-concerns-reports-7101229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's King Charles Plans Visit To India Amid Health Concerns: Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-king-charles-queen-camilla-plan-visit-to-india-amid-health-concerns-reports-7101229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 14:58:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's King Charles III is reportedly planning an official visit to India early next year. Queen Camilla will accompany the King on the royal tour to the Indian subcontinent, which is part of a government-led charm offensive.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's King Charles III is reportedly planning an official visit to India early next year. Queen Camilla will accompany the King on the royal tour to the Indian subcontinent, which is part of a government-led charm offensive, and a personal health boost following a cancer diagnosis earlier this year, according to UK media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>King Charles will visit India, Pakistan and Bangladesh during the trip, GB news reported quoting sources.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We're now working on a pretty normal-looking full overseas tour program for next year, which is a high for us to end on, to know that we can be thinking in those terms," the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gbnews.com/royal/king-charles-queen-camilla-india-cancer-recovery-latest-royal-news" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">report </a>quoted a senior palace official as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The British government is reportedly keen on a royal tour of the Commonwealth nations, with the UK trying to establish significant economic links outside of Europe in a post-Brexit world.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The monarch's earlier planned visit to the Indian subcontinent had to be abandoned after the Queen's death in September 2022. However, the King and the Queen visited Bengaluru last month for a private tour, where they reportedly stayed at a sprawling integrative medical facility.&nbsp;</p>

<p>UK newspaper The Mirror reported that the British Foreign Office has authorised officials to begin discussions with India and other potential host nations for royal visits, and proposals are being drafted.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per the report, after their previous visit was cancelled, Prime Minister Narendra Modi expressed his enthusiasm to welcome King Charles and Queen Camilla.</p>

<h2><strong>King Charles' Cancer Diagnosis</strong></h2>

<p>The 76-year-old monarch was diagnosed with an undisclosed form of cancer in January and stepped back from royal duties for around three months. He returned to work in April with a visit to a cancer centre in London where he met with fellow patients.</p>

<p>King Charles, who is still undergoing treatment, successfully completed a tour of Australia and Samoa in October.&nbsp;He reportedly felt lifted by his 11-day trip to the South Pacific, after which Buckingham Palace put in long-term plans for the King to resume a complete international travel programme next year, subject to medical advice.</p>

<p>A source told The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/royals/king-charles-plans-trip-india-34171156" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Mirror</a>: "It's hugely encouraging to be able to make such plans for the King and Queen given the year the monarch has had, but it's very much full steam ahead. A tour of the Indian subcontinent is in the offing, which will be of huge political and cultural significance for Britain on the world stage. The King and Queen are the perfect ambassadors at such a time."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1r21ps28_king-charles-afp-_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[King Charles and Queen Camilla visited Bengaluru last month for a private tour]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/45-years-later-california-murder-mystery-solved-through-dna-evidence-7100733]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[45 Years Later, California Murder Mystery Solved Through DNA Evidence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/45-years-later-california-murder-mystery-solved-through-dna-evidence-7100733]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 13:48:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[17-year-old Esther Gonzalez's body was found in a snowpack near a highway in Riverside County, California, on February 10, 1979.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 45-year-old cold case of a 17-year-old girl brutally raped and murdered has been resolved, bringing closure to the family. On February 9, 1979, Esther Gonzalez walked from her parents' home to her sister's in Banning, California, roughly 137 km east of Los Angeles. She never arrived. The next day, her body was discovered in a snowpack near a highway in Riverside County, California. Authorities determined she had been raped and bludgeoned to death, leading to an investigation that spanned decades.</p>

<p>The lab was able to match the DNA to a man named Lewis Randolph "Randy" Williamson, who died in 2014. Williamson, a US Marine Corps veteran, called authorities on the fateful day to report finding Ms Gonzalez's body. At the time, he claimed he could not identify whether the body was male or female. Described as “argumentative” by deputies, Williamson was asked to take a polygraph test, which he passed, clearing him of suspicion in the pre-DNA era. He had faced assault allegations in the past but was never convicted of any violent crimes, according to the Los Angeles Times.</p>

<p>Despite limited leads, the Riverside County cold case homicide team didn't give up. A semen sample recovered from Ms Gonzalez's body in 1979 was preserved but remained unmatched in the national Combined DNA Index System (CODIS) for decades.</p>

<p>In 2023, forensic technology finally caught up. The homicide team collaborated with a genetic lab in Texas that specialises in forensic genealogy. A sample of Williamson's blood from his 2014 autopsy provided the DNA match needed to confirm him as the 17-year-old's rapist and killer.</p>

<p>The Gonzalez family had mixed emotions—relief at finally having answers and sadness knowing Williamson would not face justice, as he died in Florida ten years ago. Ms Gonzalez, remembered by her family as a shy yet funny and mild-mannered young woman, was the fourth of seven children. Her oldest brother, Eddie Gonzalez, wrote on Facebook, “The Gonzalez family would like to thank the Riverside County Sheriff's Department on a job well done. After 40 years, the Gonzalez family has closure.”</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="208" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fpermalink.php%3Fstory_fbid%3Dpfbid02Cb7C3F3RpjRN5Ev75nnuZXUeztgg5vAmTL6BPrsmSPzWrx67m2GWC34NEr44AJKwl%26id%3D100036076692115&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>"We are very happy that we finally have closure," Ms Gonzalez's sister, Elizabeth, 64, shared with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/24/us/esther-gonzalez-murder-dna/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>. "We are happy about it but, since the guy has died, a little sad that he won't spend any time for her murder."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/o2glfk98_california-murder-mystery_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Esther Gonzalez was brutally raped and murdered.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/excessive-groundwater-extraction-causes-earths-tilt-to-shift-by-31-5-inches-reveals-study-7100584]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earth's Rotation Has Tilted 31.5 Inches And Humans Are To Blame]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/excessive-groundwater-extraction-causes-earths-tilt-to-shift-by-31-5-inches-reveals-study-7100584]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 13:28:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Earth's tilt, or axial precession, is influenced by the distribution of mass (in this case water) across the planet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new research studying the impact of climate change on our planet has revealed a shocking discovery - earth's axis has tilted by 31.5 inches (nearly 80 centimetres). Researchers attribute this change to pumping of Earth's groundwater by humans, which they say can not only change the planet's rotation but also impact sea-level rise. The study has been published in the journal <em>Geophysical Research Letters</em>.</p>

<p>The change in Earth's tilt is equal to .24 inches of sea level rise, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.popularmechanics.com/science/environment/a62995913/why-has-earth-tilted/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Popular Mechanics</em></a>.</p>

<p>"Earth's rotational pole actually changes a lot. Our study shows that among climate-related causes, the redistribution of groundwater actually has the largest impact on the drift of the rotational pole," Ki-Weon Seo, a geophysicist at Seoul National University and study lead, said in a statement.</p>

<p>The authors further said that earth spins a little differently as water is moved around.</p>

<h3><strong>How Does Earth's Tilt Change?</strong></h3>

<p>Earth's tilt, or axial precession, is influenced by the distribution of mass (in this case water) across the planet. The melting of glaciers and polar ice sheets from Greenland and Antarctica contributes significantly to this redistribution. As ice melts, the water flows toward the equator, altering Earth's balance and causing its axis to shift - a process akin to how a figure skater's spin slows when their arms extend outward.</p>

<p>The study takes into account data from 1993 to 2010 that shows the pumping of as much as 2,150 gigatons of groundwater has caused a change in the Earth's tilt of roughly 31.5 inches. The pumping is largely for irrigation and human use, said the study <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023GL103509" rel="noindex,nofollow">first published in 2023</a> and revised now.</p>

<h3><strong>What is groundwater?</strong></h3>

<p>Groundwater is water stored beneath the Earth's surface in soil pores and rock fractures, forming part of the hydrological cycle. It originates from precipitation that infiltrates the ground, replenishing underground aquifers. These aquifers serve as critical freshwater reservoirs, supplying drinking water, irrigation for agriculture, and industrial needs.</p>

<p>Groundwater is often extracted through wells and springs. Its availability and quality depend on factors like recharge rates, geological formations and human activities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It has a variety of utilities, including farming and being used as drinking water.</p>

<h3><strong>Why It Matters?</strong></h3>

<p>Though the tilt might seem insignificant on a human scale, over geological timescales, such shifts can cause notable environmental consequences. For instance, the redistribution of water can affect sea level changes differently across regions. It also impacts the planet's internal systems, including its magnetic field, which shields us from harmful solar radiation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/naoo5i6_earth-generic_625x300_08_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The authors further said that earth spins a little differently as water is moved around.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-house-catches-fire-as-cargo-plane-crashes-in-lithuania-7100458]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Killed, House Catches Fire As Cargo Plane Crashes In Lithuania]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-house-catches-fire-as-cargo-plane-crashes-in-lithuania-7100458]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 13:10:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A DHL cargo plane flying from Germany to Lithuania crashed early Monday near the airport of the capital Vilnius killing one person.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A DHL cargo plane flying from Germany to Lithuania crashed early Monday near the airport of the capital Vilnius killing one person, firefighters said.</p>

<p>"The plane was due to land at Vilnius airport and crashed a few kilometres away," Renatas Pozela, the head of the firefighting and emergency services unit said, adding that one person in the four-member crew died.</p>

<p>A house caught fire during the crash in unclear circumstances.</p>

<p>Vilmantas Vitkauskas, the head of National Crisis Management Centre, said all the people inside the house had been evacuated.</p>

<p>DHL official Ausra Rutkauskien confirmed the plane belonged to the company.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m0qavlg8_cargo_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A house caught fire during the crash in unclear circumstances.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-parent-killing-menendez-brothers-be-freed-court-hearing-from-today-7100368]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Will Parent-Killing Menendez Brothers Be Freed? Court Hearing From Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-parent-killing-menendez-brothers-be-freed-court-hearing-from-today-7100368]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:58:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lyle and Erik Menendez are set to face a judge Monday as the campaign to free them from their life sentences for the shotgun murders of their parents gathers pace.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lyle and Erik Menendez are set to face a judge Monday as the campaign to free them from their life sentences for the shotgun murders of their parents gathers pace.</p>

<p>The pair have been in prison since a blockbuster trial in 1993 that became almost compulsory viewing for millions of Americans.</p>

<p>Television audiences thrilled to the gruesome details of the slayings of Jose and Kitty Menendez at the family's luxury Beverly Hills mansion.</p>

<p>Prosecutors painted it as a cold-hearted bid by the men -- Lyle was 21 and Erik was 18 at the time -- to get their hands on their parents' $14 million fortune.</p>

<p>But their attorneys described the 1989 killings as an act of desperate self-defense by young men subjected to years of sexual abuse and psychological violence at the hands of an abusive father and a complicit mother.</p>

<p>The case saw a huge surge of renewed interest this year with the release of the Netflix hit "Monsters: The Lyle and Erik Menendez Story."</p>

<p>The brothers are set to appear Monday by videolink in a Los Angeles court, their lawyer told local media.</p>

<p>The hearing comes after a campaign to secure their release, supported by Kim Kardashian and other celebrities.</p>

<p>"Set them free before the Holidays!" wrote Tammi Menendez, Erik's wife, on social media last week.</p>

<p>Public interest is such that the court where the case will be heard will hold a lottery for the 16 seats in the public gallery, with competition for the spots expected to be fierce.</p>

<p>'It's really awesome'</p>

<p>The hearing is a starting point for lawyers working on three routes to free Erik Menendez, now 53, and Lyle Menendez, now 56.</p>

<p>Attorney Mark Geragos has filed a writ of habeas corpus, an attempt to effectively vacate the brothers' first-degree murder conviction, which could free the brothers immediately.</p>

<p>Another route is an effort to get the men re-sentenced on the same conviction, which would open the way for them to request parole.</p>

<p>Finally, Geragos has submitted a clemency request to California Governor Gavin Newsom.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With excitement over the case near fever pitch, tourists are regularly making pilgrimages to the swanky Beverly Hills home where the killings took place.</p>

<p>Australian Christian Hannah, who was born almost two decades after the double murders, made sure the home was a stop on his tour of celebrity hotspots, because of his fascination with the Netflix show.</p>

<p>"It's really awesome seeing it in person," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's just because you see it on TV and you see it in person, just feels really cool."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/licm4blo_menendez-brothers_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The brothers are set to appear in a Los Angeles court via video.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-bangladesh-camps-rohingya-refugees-mobilise-to-fight-in-myanmar-7100345]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Bangladesh Camps, Rohingya Refugees Mobilise To Fight In Myanmar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-bangladesh-camps-rohingya-refugees-mobilise-to-fight-in-myanmar-7100345]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:53:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One day in July, Rafiq slipped out of the world's largest refugee settlement in southern Bangladesh and crossed the border into Myanmar on a small boat. His destination: a ruinous civil war in a nation that he had fled in 2017.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One day in July, Rafiq slipped out of the world's largest refugee settlement in southern Bangladesh and crossed the border into Myanmar on a small boat. His destination: a ruinous civil war in a nation that he had fled in 2017.</p>

<p>Thousands of Rohingya insurgents, like 32-year-old Rafiq, have emerged from camps housing over a million refugees in Cox's Bazar, where militant recruitment and violence have surged this year, according to four people familiar with the conflict and two internal aid agency reports seen by Reuters.</p>

<p>"We need to fight to take back our lands," said Rafiq, a lean and bearded man in a Muslim prayer cap who spent weeks fighting in Myanmar before returning after he was shot in the leg.</p>

<p>"There is no other way."</p>

<p>The Rohingya, a mainly Muslim group that is the world's largest stateless population, started fleeing in droves to Bangladesh in 2016 to escape what the United Nations has called a genocide at the hands of Buddhist-majority Myanmar's military.</p>

<p>A long-running rebellion in Myanmar has gained ground since the military staged a coup in 2021. It involves a complex array of armed groups - with Rohingya fighters now entering the fray.</p>

<p>Many have joined groups loosely allied with their former military persecutors to fight the Arakan Army ethnic militia that has seized much of the western Myanmar state of Rakhine, from which many Rohingya fled.</p>

<p>Reuters interviewed 18 people who described the rise of insurgent groups inside Bangladesh's refugee camps and reviewed two internal briefings on the security situation written by aid agencies in recent months.</p>

<p>The news agency is reporting for the first time the scale of recruitment by Rohingya armed groups in the camps, which totals between 3,000 and 5,000 fighters.</p>

<p>Reuters is also revealing specifics about failed negotiations between the Rohingya and the Arakan Army, inducements offered by the junta to Rohingya fighters such as money and citizenship documents, as well as about the cooperation of some Bangladesh officials with the insurgency.</p>

<p>Several of the people - who include Rohingya fighters, humanitarian workers and Bangladesh officials - spoke on condition of anonymity or that only their first name be used.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's government did not respond to Reuters' questions, while the junta denied in a statement to Reuters that it had conscripted any "Muslims."</p>

<p>"Muslim residents requested protection. So, basic military training was provided in order to help them defend their own villages and regions," it said.</p>

<p>The two largest Rohingya militant groups - the Rohingya Solidarity Organisation (RSO) and the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA) - do not appear to have mass support in the camps in Cox's Bazar, said Shahab Enam Khan, an international relations professor at Bangladesh's Jahangirnagar University.</p>

<p>But the emergence of trained Rohingya fighters and weapons in and around the camps is regarded as a ticking time bomb by Bangladesh, one security source said. Some 30,000 children are born each year into deep poverty in the camps, where violence is rife.</p>

<p>Disillusioned refugees could be drawn by non-state actors into militant activities and pushed further into criminal enterprises, said Khan. "This will then suck in regional countries, too."</p>

<h2><strong>FIGHT FOR MAUNGDAW</strong></h2>

<p>After a boat-ride from near the camps to the western Myanmar town of Maungdaw around the midyear monsoon, Rohingya insurgent Abu Afna said he was housed and armed by junta troops.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the seaside town where the military is fighting the Arakan Army for control, Rohingya were sometimes even billeted in the same room with junta soldiers.</p>

<p>"When I'd be with the junta, I would feel that I am standing next to the same people who raped and killed our mothers and sisters," he said.</p>

<p>But the Arakan Army is backed by the majority Buddhist ethnic Rakhine community that includes people who joined the military in purging the Rohingya.</p>

<p>Reuters this year reported that the Arakan Army was responsible for burning down one of the largest remaining settlements of Rohingya in Myanmar and that the RSO had reached a "battlefield understanding" with the Myanmar military to fight alongside each other.</p>

<p>"Our main enemy isn't the Myanmar government, but the Rakhine community," Abu Afna said.</p>

<p>The military provided Rohingya with weapons, training and cash, according to Abu Afna, as well as a Bangladesh source and second Rohingya man who said he was forcibly recruited by the junta.</p>

<p>The junta also offered the Rohingya a card certifying Myanmar citizenship.</p>

<p>For some, it was a powerful lure. Rohingya have long been denied citizenship despite generations in Myanmar and are now confined to refugee camps where Bangladesh bans them from seeking formal employment.</p>

<p>"We didn't go for the money," Abu Afna said. "We wanted the card, nationality."</p>

<p>About 2,000 people were recruited from the refugee camps between March and May through drives employing "ideological, nationalist, and financial inducements, coupled with false promises, threats, and coercion," according to a June aid agency briefing seen by Reuters, which was shared on condition the authors not be named because it was not public.</p>

<p>Many of those brought to fight were taken by force, including children as young as 13, according to a U.N. official and two Rohingya fighters.</p>

<p>Cash-strapped Bangladesh is increasingly reluctant to take in Rohingya refugees and a person familiar with the matter said some Bangladesh officials believed armed struggle was the only way the Rohingya would return to Myanmar. They also believed that backing a rebel group would give Dhaka more sway, the person said.</p>

<p>Bangladesh retired Brig. Gen. Md. Manzur Qader, who has visited the camps, told Reuters his country's government should back the Rohingya in their armed struggle, which he said would push the junta and Arakan Army to negotiate and facilitate the Rohingya's return.</p>

<p>Under the previous Bangladesh government, some intelligence officials supported armed groups but with little coordination because there was no overall directive, Qader said.</p>

<p>Near the camps in Cox's Bazar, where many roads are monitored by security checkpoints, dozens of Rohingya were taken earlier this year by Bangladesh officials to a jetty overlooking Maungdaw and sent across the border by boat, said Abu Afna, who was part of the group.</p>

<p>"It's your country, you go and take it back," he recalled one official telling them.</p>

<p>Reuters was unable to independently verify his account.</p>

<h3><strong>'WE LIVE IN FEAR'</strong></h3>

<p>In Rakhine state, insurgents struggled to push back the heavily-armed and better drilled Arakan Army. But the battle for Maungdaw has stretched on for six months and Rohingya fighters said tactics including ambushes have slowed the rebel offensive.</p>

<p>"The Arakan Army thought they would have a sweeping victory very soon," said a Bangladesh official with knowledge of the situation. "Maungdaw has proven them wrong because of the participation of the Rohingya."</p>

<p>Bangladesh attempted to broker talks between Rohingya and the Arakan Army early this year, but the discussions quickly collapsed, according to Qader and another person familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>Dhaka is increasingly frustrated by the Arakan Army's strategy of attacking Rohingya settlements, the two people said, with the violence complicating efforts to repatriate refugees to Rakhine.</p>

<p>The Arakan Army has denied targeting Rohingya settlements and said it helps civilians without discriminating on the basis of religion.</p>

<p>Back in Cox's Bazar, there is turmoil in the camps, where RSO and ARSA are jostling for influence. Fighting and shootings are common, terrifying residents and disrupting humanitarian efforts.</p>

<p>John Quinley, director at human rights group Fortify Rights, said violence was at the highest levels since the camps were established in 2017. Armed groups have killed at least 60 people this year, while abducting and torturing opponents and using "threats and harassment to try to silence their critics," according to a forthcoming Fortify report.</p>

<p>Wendy McCance, director of the Norwegian Refugee Council in Bangladesh, warned that international funding for the camp would run out within 10 years and called for refugees to be given "livelihood opportunities" to avert a "massive vacuum where people, especially young men, are being drawn into organised groups to have an income."</p>

<p>Sharit Ullah, a Rohingya man who escaped from Maungdaw with his wife and four children in May, described struggling to secure regular food rations.</p>

<p>The one-time rice and shrimp farmer said his biggest worry is the safety of his family amid spiraling violence.</p>

<p>"We have nothing here," he said, over the shrieks of children playing in the squalid alleyways running like filigree through the camps.</p>

<p>"We live in fear."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bvfmrkq_rohingya-camp-reuters_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There is emergence of trained Rohingya fighters in and around camps in Bangladesh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scott-bessent-trumps-us-treasury-pick-fuels-global-relief-rally-vs-dollar-7100344]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scott Bessent, Trump's US Treasury Pick, Fuels Global Relief Rally Vs Dollar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scott-bessent-trumps-us-treasury-pick-fuels-global-relief-rally-vs-dollar-7100344]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:53:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The selection of Scott Bessent as the next Treasury Secretary has fueled a rally in currencies around the world against the dollar, as traders trim bets that the return of Donald Trump will send tremors throughout global markets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The selection of Scott Bessent as the next Treasury Secretary has fueled a rally in currencies around the world against the dollar, as traders trim bets that the return of Donald Trump will send tremors throughout global markets.</p>

<p>A gauge of the US currency fell 0.6% on Monday, its biggest decline in two weeks, with the yen and the euro among the best performing major currencies. The Korean won and Eastern European currencies led emerging peers higher, pulling back some of their losses following Trump's election victory.</p>

<p>The moves underscore the sense of relief among traders at the choice of Bessent, a Wall Street veteran whose cautious approach may take some of the sting out of Trump's 'America First' policies. Bessent has called for a gradual approach to implementing trade restrictions, and has appeared open to negotiating on the exact size of tariffs.</p>

<p>The market view that Bessent is a "safe hands" candidate may see a relief rally in US Treasuries as the risk of a more unorthodox and less qualified candidate is priced out, Stephen Spratt, a strategist at Societe Generale in Hong Kong, wrote in a note to clients. Bessent's view that tariffs should be imposed gradually and that the levies currently being discussed are "maximalist" positions - meaning they could be negotiated lower - should help Asian currencies, Spratt said.</p>

<p>US Treasuries climbed across the curve in early trading with the yield on benchmark 10-year notes falling five basis points to 4.35%, the lowest in a week. That is also helping take the steam out of the dollar's rally. The currency notched its longest stretch of weekly advances in more than a year on Friday, pushing the euro to a two-year low and the Swiss franc to its weakest since July.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Market participants surveyed by Bloomberg following Bessent's appointment see the hedge fund manager taking a more phased approach on tariffs and attempting to rein in the budget deficit. That's a positive sign for the US economy and markets, but it may also ease some concerns over the impact of Trump's return on other countries' economies and currencies. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Bessent, who will need to be confirmed by the US Senate before taking the job, beat out other prominent contenders including former Federal Reserve board member Kevin Warsh and Trump transition co-chair Howard Lutnick, who had the support of Elon Musk. His nomination is at odds with Trump's choices of a series of unorthodox candidates and absolute loyalists for other key positions, including Robert F. Kennedy Jr. as Health Secretary and Matt Gaetz as Attorney General, although the latter subsequently withdrew.</p>

<p>Bessent's nomination "builds on the emerging narrative that the tail risks of a radical Trump policy departure have been overstated," said Richard Franulovich, head of FX strategy at Westpac Banking Corp. "The failure of Trump's AG nominee to get out of the gates along with the selection of John Thune to lead the Senate - not Trump's choice - reinforce the message that checks and balances can moderate Trump's radical policy proposals."</p>

<p>Still, the dollar's gain over the past eight weeks is unlikely to be erased fully. Traders have dialed back expectations for Federal Reserve easing in 2025 amid fears inflation could accelerate in a robust US economy. Speculative traders boosted their bets on dollar gains in the week ending Nov. 19 to the most bullish level since late June, Commodity Futures Trading Commission data show.</p>

<p>"The current reaction may lead to a short term correction in the US dollar should US yields move lower," said Felix Ryan, an analyst at ANZ Banking Group in Sydney. "But ultimately we still see fundamental dynamics - firm US growth, contrasted with weaker EU and global growth as highlighted in Friday's November PMI data - as still supporting the case for a well-supported US dollar."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2n83ud2_scott-bessent_625x300_23_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Treasuries climbed across the curve in early trading.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uruguays-left-returns-to-presidency-as-yamandu-orsi-wins-election-7100335]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Uruguay's Left Returns To Presidency As Yamandu Orsi Wins Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uruguays-left-returns-to-presidency-as-yamandu-orsi-wins-election-7100335]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:51:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Center-leftopposition candidate Yamandu Orsi secured victory inUruguay'spresidential election, official results showed on Sunday, with 99 per cent of votes tallied, in a second-round race that pollsters expected to be closely fought.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Center-left opposition candidate Yamandu Orsi secured victory in Uruguay's presidential election, official results showed on Sunday, with 99 per cent of votes tallied, in a second-round race that pollsters expected to be closely fought.</p>

<p>Yamandu Orsi, the pre-election favorite by a few points, secured a small but comfortable margin of 49.81 per cent of the vote to conservative Alvaro Delgado's 45.90 per cent, official results showed.</p>

<p>"The horizon is brightening," Mr Orsi said as he addressed thousands of his Broad Front party supporters in Montevideo, who had gathered by a stage overlooking the capital city's waterfront to await the results.</p>

<p>"I am going to be the president who calls for national dialogue again and again," he said. "The country of freedom, equality and also fraternity triumphs once again ... Let's continue on that path."</p>

<p>Mr Orsi, a 57-year-old former mayor of Canelones - which has lured in firms such as a Google - has said he would avoid raising taxes that could scare off business and instead focus on attracting investors, spurring growth and skilling workers.</p>

<p>He has also signaled closer cooperation with Europe on fighting drug trafficking and more funding for the prison system.</p>

<p>His victory was celebrated by the regional Organization of American States and fellow Latin American nations across the political aisle.</p>

<p>Both Mr Delgado and Uruguay's president, fellow National Party member Luis Lacalle Pou, conceded the election, swiftly congratulating Mr Orsi and offering to help with the transition after results signaled a victory for the center-left.</p>

<p>The election between two moderates in the small nation of 3.4 million people, known for its beaches, legalized marijuana and stability, marks the closing of a bumper year for global elections - many that suffered from bitter political divides.</p>

<p>Mr Orsi, Mr Delgado and Mr Lacalle Pou all expressed goodwill for their political opposition and pledged to work together to move the country forward.</p>

<p>Unlike sharp right-left divides in recent elections in Argentina, Brazil and Mexico, Uruguay's political arena is relatively tension-free, with significant overlap between the conservative and liberal coalitions vying for office.</p>

<p>High living costs, inequality and violent crime are among Uruguayans' biggest worries, but inflation had been easing in the run-up to the election, and both employment and real salaries are on the rise.</p>

<p>Mr Orsi, who has pledged a "modern left" policy approach, won 43.9 per cent of the first-round October vote for the Broad Front and faced Mr Delgado, who secured 26.8 per cent but also had the backing of the conservative Colorado Party that together with his National Party made up almost 42 per cent of votes.</p>

<p>Mr Orsi had sought to reassure Uruguayans that he does not plan a sharp policy shift in the traditionally moderate and relatively wealthy nation.</p>

<p>Agustin Rubbo, 27, said he felt relieved. "I hope for a country that is fairer, more to the left," he said.</p>

<p>Construction worker Ruben Parada, 44, a resident of Montevideo, said he was voting for Mr Orsi because his Broad Front party "thought less about the rich" and would do more to help working people.</p>

<p>Conservative Mr Delgado had asked voters to "reelect a good government," seeking to capitalize on the popularity of Mr Lacalle Pou.</p>

<h2><strong>ECONOMIC SUCCESSES</strong></h2>

<p>While the ruling coalition is struggling to defend its record on fighting crime and over several corruption scandals, it had hoped economic successes might be enough to convince voters to choose continuity over change.</p>

<p>"They did more in five years than the Broad Front did in 15 years," said 38-year-old Jaqueline Fleitas, who cast her second-round ballot for Mr Delgado, mentioning the construction of a hospital near her home in Montevideo.</p>

<p>Neither coalition has an absolute majority in the lower house following October's elections. But Mr Orsi's Broad Front won 16 of 30 Senate seats. He says his Senate majority puts him in a better position to lead the next government.</p>

<p>Sunday's results confirmed that Uruguay had followed a global trend of incumbent parties losing vote share compared with the previous election, as the biggest year for elections in history comes to an end. Voters hurt by inflation have punished parties in power, including in Britain, Japan and the United States.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fmsmsjdo_uruguay-yamandu-orsi-reuters_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Uruguay's center-left has won the presidential election with Yamandu Orsi securing 49.3% of votes]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/far-right-pro-russian-populist-takes-surprise-lead-in-romania-elections-7100332]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Far-Right Pro-Russian Populist Takes Surprise Lead In Romania Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/far-right-pro-russian-populist-takes-surprise-lead-in-romania-elections-7100332]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:51:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Far-right candidate Calin Georgescu surged unexpectedly in Romania's presidential election, pulling ahead of the pro-European prime minister with more than 98 percent of votes counted Monday and looking all but certain to advance to a runoff.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Far-right candidate Calin Georgescu surged unexpectedly in Romania's presidential election, pulling ahead of the pro-European prime minister with more than 98 per cent of votes counted Monday and looking all but certain to advance to a runoff.</p>

<p>Exit polls had initially showed centre-left Prime Minister Marcel Ciolacu with a comfortable lead and put a centre-right candidate in second, suggesting the far-right would be shut out of the run-off next month.</p>

<p>But with 98.66 per cent of ballots counted, the pro-Russian Mr Georgescu was leading with 22.59 per cent to Mr Ciolacu's 19.55 perc ent in the race to take over from President Klaus Iohannis in the largely ceremonial post.</p>

<p>In the absence of an outright winner in the first round -- scoring more than 50 per cent -- the top two candidates go through to a second round on December 8.</p>

<p>Whatever the outcome, "the far right is by far the big winner of this election", political scientist Cristian Pirvulescu told AFP.</p>

<p>Another nationalist candidate, George Simion, is currently running fourth, putting the far-right on track to take about a third of the vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The result would be a political earthquake in the country of 19 million, a NATO member which has so far resisted nationalist posturing, setting itself apart from Hungary and Slovakia.</p>

<h2><strong>High Stakes</strong></h2>

<p>Mr Ciolacu's Social Democrat party has shaped Romania's politics for more than three decades, and as he voted Sunday he promised stability and a "decent" standard of living.</p>

<p>But with concerns mounting over inflation and the war in neighbouring Ukraine, the far-right appeared to be gaining ground ahead of the vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Georgescu surged in recent days with a viral TikTok campaign calling for an end to aid for Ukraine. He has also sounded a sceptical note on Romania's NATO membership. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Tonight, the Romanian people cried out for peace. And they shouted very loudly, extremely loudly", he said.</p>

<p>Simion had also tapped into voter anger over inflation while promising more affordable housing.</p>

<p>Looking for a new election breakthrough for European far-right parties, he had warned of possible "fraud" and "foreign interference" when voting.</p>

<p>The stakes are high for Romania, which has a 650-kilometre (400-mile) border with Ukraine and has become more important since Russia invaded its neighbour in 2022.</p>

<p>The Black Sea nation now plays a "vital strategic role" for NATO -- as it is a base for more than 5,000 soldiers -- and the transit of Ukrainian grain, the New Strategy Center think tank said.</p>

<h3><strong>Russian 'Spies' Claim</strong></h3>

<p>The campaign was marked by controversy and personal attacks, with Simion facing accusations of meeting with Russian spies -- a claim he has denied.</p>

<p>Mr Ciolacu has been criticised for his use of private jets.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Some observers had tipped Elena Lasconi, mayor of the small town of Campulung and head of a centre-right opposition party, as a surprise package. But she is currently running third.</p>

<p>Pirvulescu, the political scientist, said the far-right's surprise success could have a "contagion effect" in the parliamentary elections slated for December, which could make it difficult to form a coalition.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4djdsscg_romania-calin-georgescu-reuters_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Romanian hard-right leader Calin Georgescu is a NATO critic and Russia supporter.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-who-wanted-escape-from-london-noise-dies-during-drug-retreat-7100174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Woman Who Wanted Escape From 'London Noise' Dies During Drug Retreat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-who-wanted-escape-from-london-noise-dies-during-drug-retreat-7100174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:37:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ms Rainford's body was flown back to the UK after her daughter, Rochel, 32, approached the British consulate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British woman has died during a 'wellness retreat' in the remote Bolivian rainforest of South America. Maureen Rainford, a mother of three, consumed 'ayahuasca' -- a supposed wonder plant-based psychedelic drug but complained of feeling ill, 10 minutes after consuming it. Ms Rainord soon started experiencing breathing troubles and despite attempts to resuscitate her, died an hour later, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/11/24/british-mother-dies-at-ayahuasca-retreat-in-amazon-bolivia/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Telegraph</em>.</a> A spokesperson for the <em>Ayahuasca and San Pedro Pisatahua Retreat</em> said the death was "due to a medical emergency" and that it was not related to Ayahuasca.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/Maureen-Rainford" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>GoFundMe</em></a> page, set up by the family, Ms Rainford had been looking forward to the retreat as she wanted 'detox' from the noise of London and work for 10 days. "Maureen's love of travel and her curiosity took her to the Bolivian Amazon to detox from the noise of London and work for 10 days," the family said.</p>

<p>"It was a trip she was eagerly looking forward to, sharing her excitement with everyone with her usual vibrancy and zest for life and travel…a time for reflection and personal development."</p>

<p>Ms Rainford's body was flown back to the UK after her daughter, Rochel, 32, approached the British consulate. An autopsy confirmed that Ms Rainford died due to a heart attack.</p>

<p>Ms Rochel said after her mother's death, she wanted to raise "awareness about these places" for people who were "tempted by glassy brochures selling a dream".</p>

<p>"There should be a trained medic on standby when hallucinogenic drugs are being handed out in a remote area," she said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/viral-post-claims-8-silicon-valley-ceos-went-on-psychedelic-trips-quit-their-jobs-6639186" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also read | Viral Post Claims 8 Silicon Valley CEOs Went On "Psychedelic Trips", Quit Their Jobs</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>What is ayahuasca?</strong></h3>

<p>Traditionally consumed by shamans and healers in the Amazon River basin that includes countries such as Peru, Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador and Bolivia. The main active chemical in ayahuasca is a substance called dimethyltryptamine (DMT) which has a structure that looks similar to serotonin - an important brain chemical that regulates mood, emotions and digestion.</p>

<p>In the last few years, the use of ayahuasca has gained prominence in popular culture with retreats, similar to one Ms Rainford attended, being thronged by western tourists, looking to expand their consciousness through ego death and heal their inner selves.</p>

<p>However, in many cases, consuming ayahuasca causes bouts of vomiting, sweating and/or diarrhoea. The hallucinogenic effects kick in 20 to 60 minutes after the tea has been consumed.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u7bujr5g_maureen_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maureen Rainford, 54, had gone to Bolivia on a 10-day retreat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/td-jakes-suffers-medical-emergency-while-delivering-sermon-now-stable-7100087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[TD Jakes Suffers Medical Emergency While Delivering Sermon, Now "Stable"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/td-jakes-suffers-medical-emergency-while-delivering-sermon-now-stable-7100087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:23:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to its website, Potter's House church as founded by TD Jakes in 1996. It has 30,000 members and offices around the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pastor and motivational speaker Thomas Dexter Jakes suffered a medical emergency while delivering his sermon on Sunday. Hundreds of thousands of his followers were watching the event <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u77_dmftc3A" rel="noindex,nofollow">live on YouTube</a> when Jakes said, "Oh Lord, my strength, my redeemer, let them go in peace", and dropped his microphone. The 67-year-old then began involuntarily shaking in his seat before those around him rushed toward him to offer support. As the news broke out, users on social media started searching about Jakes' health, taking his name to the top of the search list on Google.</p>

<p>Hours later, an official statement on Jakes' official social media pages said that was "under the care of medical professionals" and is "stable", reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/bishop-td-jakes-suffers-health-incident-onstage-after-sermon-8750876" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>People Magazine</em></a>.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCxB9l0P7p6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCxB9l0P7p6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCxB9l0P7p6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCxB9l0P7p6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by The Potter's House Of Dallas (@tphdallas)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"During today's service, Bishop T.D. Jakes experienced a slight health incident and received immediate medical attention following his powerful hour-long message," Potter's House, a non-denominational American megachurch in Dallas, Texas, wrote in a statement. "Bishop Jakes is stable and under the care of medical professionals."</p>

<p>"The entire Potter's House family is grateful for the outpouring of love, prayers, and support from the community. Thank you for your understanding and continued prayers," it further said in the statement.</p>

<p>According to its website, Potter's House church as founded by Jakes in 1996. It has 30,000 members and offices around the world.</p>

<p>Jakes' sermon event was widely publicised on the church as well as his Instagram pages in which the pastor urged churchgoers to attend it adding that he was "ready to share what God gave me with YOU".</p>

<h3><strong>TD Jakes' Diddy connection</strong></h3>

<p>The renowned television personality was under fire after one of the lawsuits against Sean Combs alleged Jakes of helping out the rapper who was seen assaulting his now-ex girlfriend Cassie Ventura.</p>

<p>In March 2024, a producer accused Combs of using his connection with Jakes to lessen the impact of sexual assault allegations levelled by Ms Ventura.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7cgaous_td-jakes_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[TD Jakes is a renowned television personality and motivational speaker.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-chief-tim-cook-returns-to-china-as-beijing-prepares-to-fete-ceos-7100027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple Chief Tim Cook Returns To China As Beijing Prepares To Fete CEOs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-chief-tim-cook-returns-to-china-as-beijing-prepares-to-fete-ceos-7100027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:14:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple CEO Tim Cook is visiting China for at least the third time this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple Inc. Chief Executive Officer Tim Cook is visiting China for at least the third time this year, showing up at a suppliers' conference on the same day a top Beijing official convened an important meeting with a group of foreign CEOs.</p>

<p>Chinese Premier Li Qiang is expected to meet with top corporate executives on Monday ahead of the event, just as companies worldwide are bracing for President-elect Donald Trump's threat to hike tariffs on Chinese goods. Disruptions to trade are a source of concern especially for Apple, which makes the majority of its iPhones through Foxconn in the country and counts China as its biggest market after the US.</p>

<p>Cook's agenda in the capital is unclear. The CEO made it a point to emphasize the importance of the Chinese supply chain during brief remarks carried by a social media account linked to state broadcaster China Central Television.</p>

<p>"I value them very highly. We could not do what we do without them," Cook said in response to a question about Apple's Chinese partners.</p>

<p>Li is likely to address a gathering of businesspeople and hear from top executives of global firms such as Rio Tinto Plc, Corning Inc. and Charoen Pokphand Group, Bloomberg News has reported. The discussions will likely cover a wide range of supply chain and trade flow issues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Apple CEO was in the capital just last month when he promised to keep investing in the country and also underscored its vital role in the iPhone maker's global operations. Over the weekend, Nvidia Corp. CEO Jensen Huang was in Hong Kong receiving an honorary doctorate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jfa106g_tim-cook_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/podcaster-joe-rogan-accuses-biden-zelensky-of-potentially-triggering-world-war-iii-7099963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Could Start World War III": Joe Rogan Slams Biden, Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/podcaster-joe-rogan-accuses-biden-zelensky-of-potentially-triggering-world-war-iii-7099963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:04:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Rogans comments are not the first from public figures warning the current trajectory of the war could lead to a broader global conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American podcaster Joe Rogan has launched a scathing attack on both US President Joe Biden and his Ukrainian Volodymyr Zelensky, accusing them of escalating the Ukraine-Russia conflict to the point of potentially triggering a global war.<br />
<br />
In his recent podcast, Rogan criticised Biden for green-lighting Zelensky's request to use American-made long-range missiles against Russian forces, a decision he believes could have catastrophic consequences. “How are you allowed to do that when you're on your way out? There should be some sort of pause for significant actions that could potentially start World War III,” Rogan said, according to a report in <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/24/world-news/joe-rogan-rants-against-biden-zelensky-for-trying-to-start-world-war-iii/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Post</a>.<br />
<br />
Biden recently approved the Ukrainian president's request to use US-supplied Army Tactical Missile Systems (ATACMS) in the war against Russia. The approval followed months of Zelensky's appeals to Washington for advanced weapons to strengthen Ukraine's resistance against the Russian invasion, which began in 2022. In response, the UK also authorised the use of its Storm Shadow missiles, a weapon comparable to the ATACMS.<br />
<br />
Moscow reacted to these developments by launching a new hypersonic missile at Ukraine, which can carry nuclear payloads. The Kremlin warned the missile's extensive range could target the US directly, escalating the threat of nuclear conflict.<br />
<br />
Rogan laid the blame for the intensifying conflict squarely on Ukraine, dismissing Zelensky's claims that Russia was struggling due to its faltering invasion and mounting casualties. “Zelensky says Putin is terrified,” Rogan said, adding, “You people are about to start World War III.”<br />
<br />
The UFC commentator also expressed his concerns about the Biden administration's role in the crisis, suggesting their actions could lead to devastating consequences. “Maybe that would be a good thing we would like to avoid from a dying former president,” Rogan remarked, referring to Biden, who is 82 years old.<br />
<br />
Rogan also expressed hope that US President-elect Donald Trump could end the war. Trump has previously hinted at negotiating a diplomatic resolution to the conflict. It could involve Russia retaining the territories it has occupied, a proposition Zelensky and Ukraine have firmly rejected.<br />
<br />
Rogan's comments are not the first from public figures warning the current trajectory of the war could lead to a broader global conflict. Valery Zaluzhny, Ukraine's former military chief, suggested the involvement of North Korean soldiers and Iranian weapons on the frontlines of the conflict signalled the beginning of World War III.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/0sdd0kq8_joe-biden-zelensky-ukraine_625x300_20_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-first-edition-of-machiavelli-s-the-prince-to-be-auctioned-for-up-to-rs-3-18-crore-7099820]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare Edition Of Machiavelli's 'The Prince' To Fetch Rs 3.18 Crore At Auction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-first-edition-of-machiavelli-s-the-prince-to-be-auctioned-for-up-to-rs-3-18-crore-7099820]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 11:43:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rare first edition of Italian Renaissance diplomat Niccolo Machiavelli's political treatise, The Prince,' is set to go under the hammer at an estimated value of up to &#163;300,000 (around Rs 3.18 crore).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rare first edition of Italian Renaissance diplomat Niccolo Machiavelli's political treatise, ‘The Prince,' is set to go under the hammer at an estimated value of up to £300,000 (around Rs 3.18 crore). Machiavelli, widely associated with cunning political manoeuvres, authored the work in the early 16th century, and this particular edition is one of only 11 first copies. While most of these first editions are housed in institutional collections, primarily in Italy, this copy comes from a private collection, making it a unique find, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/22/style/rare-machiavellis-the-prince-auction-intl-scli/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>“We were not aware of any other copies in private hands, and this is the first copy that we are aware of to have come to auction, certainly in recent decades,” CNN quoted Gabriel Heaton, Sotheby's Books &amp; Manuscripts specialist, as saying. Heaton added, “It's a very first edition and unique opportunity for a copy to come to auction.”</p>

<p>The first edition of 'The Prince' will be part of Sotheby's Books &amp; Manuscripts auction in London, which runs from November 28 to December 12. This copy of the treatise, still bound in its early 17th-century Italian cover, is notable not only for its rarity but also for being bound together with a second edition of Machiavelli's Florentine Histories, another important work by the author.</p>

<p>Machiavelli, who served as a diplomat in the Florentine government, wrote 'The Prince' in 1513 after he was imprisoned on charges of conspiracy. Following his release, he retreated to his family's property in San Casciano, where he completed the treatise. Although 'The Prince' circulated in manuscript form during Machiavelli's lifetime, it was only officially published after his death in 1527, with the first editions appearing posthumously.</p>

<p>This particular copy dates from 1532, and its title page has been removed, possibly to avoid confiscation by authorities at the time. Sotheby's has suggested that the removal may have been a strategic move in light of the Catholic Church's 1559 ban on the text, which was placed on the Index of Prohibited Books. The book was not reprinted until 70 years later.</p>

<p>One of the notable features of this copy is the markings by an early reader on chapter 18 with brackets, drawing attention to its remarkably modern insights into the need for a politician to exploit the divide between how things appear and the reality beneath, as described in the auction catalogue.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hfpqu1qg_prince_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Machiavelli was widely associated with cunning political manoeuvres.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-terrifying-footage-shows-passengers-fleeing-runway-as-plane-catches-fire-7099749]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Terrifying Clip Shows Passengers Fleeing Runway As Plane Catches Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-terrifying-footage-shows-passengers-fleeing-runway-as-plane-catches-fire-7099749]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 11:30:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Antalya Governor's Office Deputy Suat Seyitoglu confirmed that the fire occurred during the landing but was swiftly contained by the first responders.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Frightening footage has emerged showing passengers fleeing a Russian aircraft that combusted into flames on the Antalya Airport runway in Turkey on Sunday (Nov 24). The Russsian-made Sukhoi Superjet 100 Passenger plane with 89 passengers and six crew members, operated by Azimuth Airline, was bound for&nbsp;Antalya from Sochi when it caught fire, allegedly due to a hard landing which damaged one of the engines. Although the fire spread quickly, there were no reports of injuries to anyone as authorities opened an investigation into the incident.</p>

<p>Antalya Governor's Office Deputy Suat Seyitoglu confirmed that the fire occurred during the landing but was swiftly contained by the first responders.</p>

<p>"All passengers were evacuated without injury, and thankfully, no one was harmed," Mr Seyitoglu told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.turkiyetoday.com/turkiye/massive-fire-in-russian-plane-carrying-79-passengers-at-antalya-airport-83891/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Turkiye Today</em>.</a></p>

<p>Meanwhile, a ministry statement added: "A fire broke out in the engine of the SU95 type aircraft, registered RA89085, belonging to Azimuth Airlines, travelling from Sochi Airport in Russia to Antalya Airport, during landing. After landing at Antalya Airport at 21:34, an emergency call was made by the aircraft pilots due to the fire."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Russian Sukhoi Superjet in Turkey tonight, which crashed upon landing.<br />
<br />
One of the problems with living in a terrorist state under sanctions: <a href="https://t.co/jpDfQSkqeJ">pic.twitter.com/jpDfQSkqeJ</a></p>
— KT "Special CIA Operation" (@KremlinTrolls) <a href="https://twitter.com/KremlinTrolls/status/1860779674575487019?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<h3><strong>'Leave luggage'</strong></h3>

<p>In one of the videos going viral on social media, users pointed out that passengers were jeopardising their lives by taking their hand baggage while gliding down the emergency slide.</p>

<p>"In case of an evacuation you should leave your bags behind !!!!!!!! Oh lord, after I saw the passengers rolling their bags, I will not think about the chaos in the plane. This behavior kills people," said one user, while another added: "Anyone who takes their hand luggage with them in an emergency evacuation should be banned from flying for life."</p>

<p>A third commented: "And they all took their hand luggage with them. This is ridiculous."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Video close up of the Russian Sukhoi Superjet 100-95LR aircraft on fire at the Antalya airport, Turkiye (being recorded by a Russian woman, who should be running like hell away from the aircraft as a safety measure, in the event of any possible explosion) <a href="https://t.co/UI02Q6Cxy5">https://t.co/UI02Q6Cxy5</a> <a href="https://t.co/htQbUSyIR5">pic.twitter.com/htQbUSyIR5</a></p>
— raging545 (@raging545) <a href="https://twitter.com/raging545/status/1860789365967921608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Another footage showed the emergency units battling the fire with dark smoke and flames visible.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-passengers-fly-off-their-seats-as-miami-bound-flight-faces-severe-turbulence-7030662" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Watch: Passengers Fly Off Their Seats As Miami-Bound Flight Faces Severe Turbulence</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Previous instance</strong></h3>

<p>This is not the first instance when a Superjet has caught fire upon landing. In 2019, Aeroflot flight SU1492 was struck by lightning after taking off from Moscow, forcing the plane to make an emergency landing and erupt in flames at the Sheremetyevo International Airport.</p>

<p>At least 41 passengers were killed in the incident as families of the victims alleged that some of the passengers delayed the evacuation effort by trying to save their luggage.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/me4cf388_plane_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Passengers sauntering off the runway after the incident.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-hezbollah-fires-250-rockets-into-israeli-after-strike-on-beirut-7099711]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Hezbollah Fires 250 Rockets Into Israel After Strike On Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-hezbollah-fires-250-rockets-into-israeli-after-strike-on-beirut-7099711]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 11:25:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel struck Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold, as Lebanese media reported intense fighting in the border area. In response, Iran-backed Hezbollah fired about 250 rockets and other projectiles into Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heavy exchange of fire continues between Israel and Hezbollah on Sunday. Israel struck Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold, as Lebanese media reported intense fighting in the border area. In response, Iran-backed Hezbollah fired about 250 rockets and other projectiles into Israel in one of the militant group's heaviest barrages in months wounding at least seven people.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israeli air defences intercepted some rockets fired by Hezbollah, but others caused damage to houses in central Israel, according to a report by AFP. Some projectiles even reached the Tel Aviv area in the heart of Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hezbollah, in a statement, said that it had "launched, for the first time, an aerial attack using a swarm of attack drones on the Ashdod naval base" in southern Israel. Later, it said it fired "a barrage of advanced missiles and a swarm of attack drones" at a "military target" in Tel Aviv, and had also launched a volley of missiles at the Glilot army intelligence base in the city's suburbs. Hezbollah has previously reported attacks against the Glilot base.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">⚡️Hezb-Allah publish footage of them targeting the military bases belonging to the Israeli enemy army in the city of Tel Aviv (occupied Jaffa) with suicide drones and "Fadi 6" and "Qader 2" missiles <a href="https://t.co/WNs7wQtbR2">pic.twitter.com/WNs7wQtbR2</a></p>
— War Monitor (@WarMonitors) <a href="https://twitter.com/WarMonitors/status/1860762481381323196?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Israeli military confirmed around 250 projectiles were fired in one of the war's highest daily figures. On September 24-- &nbsp;the day after Israel escalated air strikes against Hezbollah-- there were 350 launches from Lebanon, according to the military.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is what Sunday looks like for millions of Israelis under Hezbollah rocket fire.<br />
<br />
On the left: A direct rocket hit on a home in Northern Israel<br />
<br />
On the right: A car on fire following a rocket attack in central Israel.<br />
<br />
Hezbollah must be eliminated. <a href="https://t.co/VelXCS2yDG">pic.twitter.com/VelXCS2yDG</a></p>
— Israel Foreign Ministry (@IsraelMFA) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsraelMFA/status/1860647271316021674?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, in Lebanon, Israel struck the capital's southern suburbs, a Hezbollah stronghold, a day after a wave of Israeli strikes that the health ministry said killed 84 people. Deadly strikes also hit the heart of Beirut over the past week.</p>

<p>On Sunday Lebanon said in-person classes in the capital area would be suspended on Monday for safety reasons.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>War Casualties And Quest For Truce Deal</strong></h2>

<p>The conflict has killed at least 3,754 people in Lebanon since October 2023, according to the health ministry, most of them since September. On the Israeli side, authorities say at least 82 soldiers and 47 civilians have been killed.</p>

<p>The heavy exchanges of fire came despite an immediate Israel-Hezbollah ceasefire call from top EU diplomat Josep Borrell while on a visit to Lebanon on Sunday. In Beirut, Mr Borrell held talks with parliamentary speaker Nabih Berri, who has led mediation efforts on behalf of his ally Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"We see only one possible way ahead: an immediate ceasefire and the full implementation of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1701," Mr Borrell said.</p>

<p>"Lebanon is on the brink of collapse", he warned.</p>

<p>Earlier this week, US special envoy Amos Hochstein also said in Lebanon that a truce deal was "within our grasp", and then headed to Israel for talks with officials there.</p>

<p>Under Resolution 1701, which ended the last Hezbollah-Israel war of 2006, Lebanese troops and UN peacekeepers should be the only armed forces present in the southern border area.</p>

<p>The resolution also called for Israel to withdraw troops from Lebanon, and reiterated earlier calls for "disarmament of all armed groups in Lebanon."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7s7i1ds8_israel-lebanon-afp_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Lebanon, Israel struck the capital's southern suburbs, a Hezbollah stronghold]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-longer-love-of-my-life-elon-musks-ex-girlfriend-grimes-after-bitter-custody-battle-7099654]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Is "Unrecognizable": Grimes Talks About Bitter Custody Battle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-longer-love-of-my-life-elon-musks-ex-girlfriend-grimes-after-bitter-custody-battle-7099654]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 11:18:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She described Musk as "unrecognizable" and revealed that she had spent a year in a "battle" for her rights as a mother.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Musician Grimes, whose real name is Claire Boucher, recently opened up on X about her ongoing custody battle with her former partner and father of her children, Elon Musk. She described Musk as "unrecognizable" and revealed that she had spent a year in a "battle" for her rights as a mother. Grimes also shared that her social media posts were used against her during the legal proceedings.</p>

<p>This comes after reports that the custody dispute over their three children: 4-year-old X AE A-12 (also known as Baby X), 2-year-old Exa, and 2-year-old Tau-has been resolved.</p>

<p>In her post, she discussed her new creative projects, and said that she had "never been better in my life than right now."</p>

<p>"I spent a lot of my time off with babies getting in my ten thousand hours of creative writing and mastering the art which I've never had," she said. "Having babies rips you apart and puts you back together. Babies are ten thousand philosophy classes of s*** you can only learn from that experience.</p>

<p>"Spent a year locked in battle in a state with terrible mothers rights having my instagram posts and modeling used as reasons I shouldn't have my kids and fighting and detaching from the love of my life as he becomes unrecognizable to me, with a fraction of his resources (or iq/ strategy experience), all the while I didn't see one of my babies for 5 months."</p>

<p>She added: "And this is only what can be said publicly, since most of my experience these last years should remain behind closed doors."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My new shit is so elevated beyond that - after everything I've been thru - I am keeping the best of book 1 for the new stuff but I've never been better in my life than right now, and I spent a lot of my time off with babies getting in my ten thousand hours of creative writing and…</p>
— ?????? ⏳ (@Grimezsz) <a href="https://twitter.com/Grimezsz/status/1859148117083304060?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>In another post, Grimes shared that she was "going bankrupt" due to the lawsuit and that the stress of potentially losing her children was making it difficult to focus on her creativity.</p>

<p>The "Oblivion" singer confirmed her split from Elon Musk in March 2022 after about four years together. In September of the same year, Musk filed a custody lawsuit against her, and Grimes countered with her own suit in a San Francisco court.</p>

<p>According to Business Insider, the couple met in court in August, and their legal teams met again in Texas before the case was resolved. The case was sealed in December, with the judge closing the courtroom to the press and public shortly after a hearing began.</p>

<p>In a now-deleted post on X, Grimes hinted that she had custody of her children every other week. "It's my week without my kids, so if you want responses from me, it's now or every second week after this," she told her followers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-05/sfm1fqp8_elon-musk-and-girlfriend-grimes-afp_625x300_05_May_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This comes after reports that the custody dispute over their three children]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-yamandu-orsi-uruguays-newly-elected-modern-left-president-7099474]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Yamandu Orsi, Uruguay's Newly-Elected 'Modern Left' President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-yamandu-orsi-uruguays-newly-elected-modern-left-president-7099474]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 10:44:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Uruguay's new president-elect Yamandu Orsi was the pollsters' narrow favorite to win the second round of the South American nation's presidential election on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Uruguay's new president-elect Yamandu Orsi, whose political ambitions were galvanized by his experience growing up in a dictatorship, was the pollsters' narrow favorite to win the second round of the South American nation's presidential election on Sunday for the center-left.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 57-year-old former history teacher and local mayor managed to unseat the ruling conservative bloc. He placed first with 49.8% of votes for the left-leaning Broad Front coalition in November's second round, against Alvaro Delgado of the governing center-right National Party with 45.9%.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the campaign, Orsi had sought to reassure Uruguayans that he did not plan a sharp political shift in the traditionally moderate and relatively wealthy nation of 3.4 million people that is known for its beaches, legal cannabis and stable economy.</p>

<p>The election concluded in a cordial atmosphere, with both sides vowing to work together to advance the nation. Delgado had said before the results he would invite Orsi over for traditional mate tea should he secure a victory.</p>

<p>Orsi has said he wants to usher in "a modern left", to tackle homelessness, poverty and crime - a key voter concern.</p>

<p>Homicide rates in Uruguay have risen sharply in recent years, fueled by changing cocaine smuggling routes. The poverty rate is one of the lowest in the region and has dropped back down to pre-COVID levels this year, but charities say it continues to affect children disproportionately.</p>

<p>"The destiny and future of this country has to change," Orsi told Reuters in an interview in capital Montevideo in October, saying his Broad Front coalition was the force to push that change by striking a different balance between social welfare and economic growth.</p>

<p>He has backing from leftist icon Jose "Pepe" Mujica, a former rebel-turned-president, but also moderate groups who like his business-friendly tone. Unlike many other countries in the region, Uruguay has rarely had divisive politics.</p>

<p>"I am going to be the president who calls for national dialogue again and again," Orsi said during his Nov. 24 victory speech.</p>

<p>As mayor of Canelones, the country's second largest region, he was credited with helping to lure prospective investors and easing local bureaucracy to attract international firms like Google, with some level of success. He has said he plans to avoid tax hikes despite a growing deficit, and instead focus on spurring faster growth.</p>

<p>Neither coalition in Uruguay has an absolute majority in the lower house following October's elections, but the Broad Front won 16 of 30 Senate seats. Orsi argues that places him in a better position to lead the government.</p>

<h3><strong>Folksy Style</strong></h3>

<p>Some voters Reuters spoke to said they worried Orsi was indecisive and "short on ideas."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other voters, however, liked that he was moderate and "open to dialogue," while supportive political colleagues said he represented a "generational shift" among Latin America's political left, balancing business needs and social welfare.</p>

<p>"He has practical experience," said Mujica, now 89, in an interview with Reuters earlier this year, championing Orsi as a political bridge-builder.</p>

<p>"He has a willingness to endure differences and is going to build a team. That's why we support him."</p>

<p>Orsi employs a casual, folksy style that in part mirrors Mujica - well known for his humble lifestyle that famously included driving an old VW Beetle to work during his 2010-2015 presidency.</p>

<p>Orsi is often photographed carrying traditional mate tea, walking his dog, Ramon, and dressing casually. He has said that, like Mujica, he would not live in the presidential residence if elected.</p>

<p>While he has been guarded on concrete policies - giving little away in discussion with Reuters - he has said he plans to boost funding to the prison system and strengthen cooperation with Europe on tackling drug crime.</p>

<p>Orsi says that politics was never part of his family life, growing up in a rural area of Canelones where his parents ran a small convenience store. But after elections in 1984 that led to the restoration of democracy, he got sucked into that world.</p>

<p>"Politics was a dirty word ... because we were living in a dictatorship," he said, referring to Uruguay's 1973-1985 period of civic-military rule, one of several dictatorships during that time in South America. Orsi was 17 when elections returned.</p>

<p>"That breath of fresh air back then flooded through me, and there it has remained," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hjcbtfi_yamandu-orsi_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Uruguay election concluded in a cordial atmosphere.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tulsi-gabbard-trumps-intelligence-pick-set-to-face-tough-questions-7099454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tulsi Gabbard, Trump's Intelligence Pick, Set To Face Tough Questions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tulsi-gabbard-trumps-intelligence-pick-set-to-face-tough-questions-7099454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 10:41:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump's pick to head the US intelligence community is likely to face tough questions during confirmation hearings, including over her meeting with Syria's leader, Republican Senator James Lankford said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump's pick to head the US intelligence community is likely to face tough questions during confirmation hearings, including over her meeting with Syria's leader, Republican Senator James Lankford said.</p>

<p>Tulsi Gabbard, the nominee for director of national intelligence, is a Trump loyalist and former Democratic representative from Hawaii who switched parties. She's expected to face scrutiny for comments sympathetic to Russia and a 2017 visit to Syria where she met President Bashar al-Assad.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We'll have lots of questions," Lankford said Sunday on CNN's State of the Union. "She met with Bashar Assad. We'll want to know what the purpose was and what the direction for that was as a member of Congress."</p>

<p>Gabbard contradicted US intelligence assessments by questioning whether Assad used chemical weapons on his citizens after a visit to the country in 2017.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2022, she suggested Russia's invasion of Ukraine could have been avoided if President Joe Biden's administration and the NATO alliance had heeded Moscow's "legitimate security concerns."</p>

<p>"We'll want to get a chance to talk about past comments that she's made and get them into full context," Lankford said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Several of president-elect Donald Trump's cabinet nominees have faced scrutiny - notably now-former Representative Matt Gaetz, who dropped out as nominee for attorney general after bipartisan concern over sexual misconduct allegations reached a fever pitch.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Attention has turned to Gabbard and defense secretary nominee Pete Hegseth, who has faced sexual assault allegations he denies. The Fox News host and Army National Guard officer also has said women shouldn't serve in combat.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Senator Eric Schmitt, a Republican from Missouri, said he'll vote to confirm Hegseth and Gabbard. Allegations that Gabbard is a Russian sympathizer - leveled by Democrats as well as some Republican critics of Trump's choice - are insulting, he said.</p>

<p>"It's a slur, quite frankly," Schmitt said on NBC's Meet the Press. "You know, there's no evidence that she's a asset of another country."</p>

<p>Republican senators have also sought to rally behind Hegseth since a newly released police report last week revealed graphic details about a 2017 sexual encounter that Hegseth said was consensual.</p>

<p>Markwayne Mullin, who like Schmitt is on the Senate Armed Services Committee, said Hegseth has the qualifications to be defense secretary and signaled on Sunday he'll support Trump's Pentagon nominee for confirmation.</p>

<p>"It is clear there was nothing there" and "that there was no crime committed," Mullin said on CNN. "And so that doesn't prevent Pete from moving forward in this."</p>

<p>US policy toward Ukraine is expected to shift under Trump, who has at times promised to end the war sparked by Russia's full-scale invasion before he takes office in January.</p>

<p><strong>US Adversaries</strong></p>

<p>Representative Mike Waltz of Florida, who's in line to be Trump's national security adviser at the White House, said the president-elect is "incredibly concerned about the carnage" and the escalation in the war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We need to bring this to a responsible end. We need to restore deterrence, restore peace and get ahead of this escalation ladder, rather than responding to it," Waltz said on Fox News Sunday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He also warned US foes against thinking they could exploit the presidential transition, saying he met with Jake Sullivan, Biden's national security adviser.</p>

<p>"For our adversaries out there that think this is a time of opportunity, that they can play one administration off the other - they're wrong," Waltz said. "We are hand in glove."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/06lqpfng_tulsi-gabbard-bloomberg_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tulsi Gabbard is a nominee for director of national intelligence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-s-mars-dream-faces-reality-check-7099387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Prize-Winning Book Exposes Flaws In Elon Musk's Mars Dream]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-s-mars-dream-faces-reality-check-7099387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 25 Nov 2024 10:33:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The book, published in November 2023 and winner of the 2024 Royal Society Trivedi Science Book Prize, explores the grim realities of living on Mars.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk aims to establish a human settlement on Mars in the next three decades. Experts, however, have questioned its feasibility.</p>

<p>Can humans survive Mars' hostile environment? How will we overcome challenges like toxic soil, weak gravity, and high radiation? In their award-winning book, <em>A City on Mars: Can We Settle Space, Should We Settle Space, and Have We Really Thought This Through?,</em> authors Kelly and Zach Weinersmith explore these critical questions, ultimately concluding the SpaceX CEO's vision is far from realistic.<br />
<br />
The book, published in November 2023 and winner of the 2024 Royal Society Trivedi Science Book Prize, explores the grim realities of living on Mars. “Leaving a 2-degree-C warmer Earth for Mars would be like leaving a messy room to live in a toxic waste dump,” the authors say.<br />
<br />
Kelly Weinersmith, a biologist at Rice University, and her co-author husband, Zach Weinersmith, a cartoonist, highlight major hurdles for human survival on Mars. The planet's thin atmosphere, high radiation levels, and toxic soil laden with perchlorates pose severe threats to human health. Prolonged exposure could lead to hormone disruption and developmental abnormalities, especially in children.<br />
<br />
Moreover, Mars' weak gravity – just 40 per cent of Earth's – could worsen bone loss and muscle degradation, making childbirth and other biological processes potentially catastrophic. “We have very little relevant data for how adults will do, let alone how having babies would work out,” Ms Kelly told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/22/science/mars-human-settlement-elon-musk/index.html " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a> in an interview.<br />
<br />
Mars lacks a strong magnetic field and has a thin atmosphere, offering little protection against cosmic and solar radiation, according to the authors. Prolonged exposure could increase cancer risks and lead to cognitive decline. The planet also experiences global dust storms, extreme temperature fluctuations, and dangerous airborne particles like regolith, which can damage equipment and harm humans. Mars' isolation – an average of 225 million km from Earth – means communication delays of up to 24 minutes each way. This isolation could worsen mental health issues and limit the ability to manage emergencies.<br />
<br />
The authors also stress the lack of a clear legal framework for space settlement. While the 1967 Outer Space Treaty provides vague guidelines, it does not address modern concerns about resource use or territorial claims. With geopolitical tensions between the US and China escalating, the authors foresee a potential space race over Martian resources and territory.<br />
<br />
Elon Musk's vision of a self-sustaining colony for one million people relies on advanced technologies, including closed-loop agricultural systems and sturdy infrastructure to combat Mars' harsh environment.<br />
<br />
However, the Weinersmiths claim these systems are in their infancy. “If you want to do this, it's got to be the slow work of generations to build up to a point where we could be self-sustaining on Mars,” they told the outlet.<br />
<br />
While the authors remain sceptical of Mars colonisation, they support incremental advances in space exploration. “I would love to see, for example, a research station on the moon where we have rodent colonies, and we see how they do when they go through a couple of generations. Maybe in our lifetime, we'll see people land on Mars, do some exploration and come home, that could happen,” Ms Kelly suggested.<br />
<br />
The authors warn against rushing into large-scale settlement plans without fully understanding the risks.<br />
<br />
For now, Mr Musk's Mars dream may remain just a dream.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/04dtmd6g_elon-musk_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>