<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:46:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-begins-closed-door-trial-for-us-reporter-on-spy-charges-5974825]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Begins Closed-Door Trial For US Reporter On Spy Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-begins-closed-door-trial-for-us-reporter-on-spy-charges-5974825]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:44:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A shaven-headed Evan Gershkovich went on trial behind closed doors on Wednesday in a Russian court where the US journalist is facing accusations of espionage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A shaven-headed Evan Gershkovich went on trial behind closed doors on Wednesday in a Russian court where the US journalist is facing accusations of espionage.</p>

<p>Prosecutors say the Wall Street Journal reporter gathered secret information on the orders of the US Central Intelligence Agency about a company that manufactures tanks for Russia's war in Ukraine. If convicted, he faces a sentence of up to 20 years.</p>

<p>Gershkovich, his newspaper and the US government all reject the allegations and say that he was just doing his job as a reporter accredited by Russia's Foreign Ministry to work there.</p>

<p>"His case is not about evidence, procedural norms, or the rule of law. It is about the Kremlin using American citizens to achieve its political objectives," the US embassy in Moscow said in a statement, calling for Gershkovich's immediate release.</p>

<p>After several hours of closed proceedings, the court said the next session would take place on Aug. 13 - an indication the case will drag on for months. The reason for the long interval was not clear.</p>

<p>Journalists were briefly allowed to film the 32-year-old Gershkovich before the start of the trial, from which the media are barred. Wearing an open-necked shirt and standing in a glass box, he smiled faintly and nodded at colleagues he recognised.</p>

<p>Prosecutor Mikael Ozdoyev later summarised the charges for reporters.</p>

<p>"The investigation established and documented that... Gershkovich, on instructions from the CIA, in September 2023, in the Sverdlovsk region, collected secret information about the activities of a defence enterprise regarding the production and repair of military equipment," Ozdoyev said.</p>

<p>"Gershkovich carried out the illegal actions while observing painstaking conspiratorial measures," he added.</p>

<p>Ozdoyev later told reporters he had misspoken, and the alleged offence was actually in March 2023 - the month of the reporter's arrest.</p>

<h2><strong>Closed Hearing</strong></h2>

<p>Closed trials are standard procedure in Russia for cases of alleged treason or espionage involving classified state material, which typically can last several months.</p>

<p>The Kremlin says the case, and the arrangements for it, are a matter for the court, but has stated - without publishing evidence - that Gershkovich was caught "red-handed".</p>

<p>Against the background of the Ukraine war, Gershkovich and other Americans detained in Russia have been caught up in the gravest crisis between Moscow and Washington for more than 60 years.</p>

<p>President Vladimir Putin has said Russia is open to the idea of a prisoner exchange involving Gershkovich and that contacts with the United States have taken place, but they must remain secret.</p>

<p>The US has accused Russia of conducting "hostage diplomacy". It has designated Gershkovich and another jailed American, Paul Whelan, as "wrongfully detained" and says it is committed to bringing them home.</p>

<p>The US embassy statement said Russian authorities had failed to provide evidence supporting the charges against Gershkovich or to explain why his work as a journalist constituted a crime.</p>

<p>The trial is taking place in the city of Yekaterinburg, where officers of the FSB security service arrested Gershkovich on March 29, 2023, while he was eating in a steakhouse. Since then he has spent nearly 16 months in Moscow's Lefortovo prison.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal has declined to comment on the purpose of his reporting trip to Russia's Urals region or on the specific allegation by prosecutors that Gershkovich was trying to gather information on Uralvagonzavod, a supplier of tanks for Russia's war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"He was there as an accredited journalist, doing his job," Wall Street Journal publisher Almar Latour told Reuters in a phone interview before the trial.</p>

<p>Many Western news organisations pulled staff out of Russia after Putin sent his army into Ukraine in February 2022. Russia then passed laws that set long prison terms for "discrediting" the armed forces or spreading "fake news" about them.</p>

<p>Gershkovich was one of a small number of Western reporters, also including journalists from Reuters, who continued to report from inside Russia.</p>

<p>Another journalist, Russian-American Alsu Kurmasheva, was arrested last year and is awaiting trial on charges of violating Russia's "foreign agent" law and spreading false information about the armed forces, which she denies.</p>

<p>Earlier this month a French researcher, Laurent Vinatier, was arrested and accused of failing to register as a foreign agent while gathering information about Russia's military.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nik4i1vo_evan-gershkovich-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If convicted, Evan Gershkovich faces a sentence of up to 20 years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-wife-requests-privacy-he-needs-to-recuperate-5974782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Julian Assange's Wife Requests Privacy: "He Needs To Recuperate"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-wife-requests-privacy-he-needs-to-recuperate-5974782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:39:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Wikileaks founder Julian Assange needs privacy and time to recover after more than five years in a high-security London prison, his wife Stella said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wikileaks founder Julian Assange needs privacy and time to recover after more than five years in a high-security London prison, his wife Stella said Wednesday.</p>

<p>"He needs time, he needs to recuperate, and this is a process," she told a news conference, appearing close to tears. "I ask you please to give us space, to give us privacy, to find our place, to let our family be a family before he can speak again at a time of his choosing."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/22g6nbkg_julian-assange-with-wife_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange spent over five years in a high-security London prison.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-talks-in-us-led-to-julian-assange-deal-says-australia-pm-anthony-albanese-5974505]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secret Talks In US Led To Julian Assange Deal, Says Australia PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-talks-in-us-led-to-julian-assange-deal-says-australia-pm-anthony-albanese-5974505]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:59:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia's Prime Minister said Wednesday a string of recent non-disclosed missions to the United States helped to forge the plea deal that freed Julian Assange.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia's Prime Minister said Wednesday a string of recent non-disclosed missions to the United States helped to forge the plea deal that freed Julian Assange.</p>

<p>The 52-year-old WikiLeaks founder landed in Canberra hours earlier, after earning his liberty by pleading guilty to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate US national defence information.</p>

<p>He was sentenced by a court in the US Pacific territory of Northern Mariana Islands to time already served in London's high-security Belmarsh prison -- five years and two months -- and allowed to walk free.</p>

<p>The US Department of Justice had to make a "range of decisions" for the plea deal to proceed, Anthony Albanese told a news conference in Canberra, stressing that the US department was independent and "not subject to political influence".</p>

<p>A "whole range of people" had visited the United States as the deal was worked out, the Australian leader told reporters.</p>

<p>"I am surprised that some of it was missed by the people in this room -- some of the visits -- but it's not up to me to indicate that," Albanese said.</p>

<p>He advised journalists to "go back and look at some diaries and who has travelled to the United States in recent months".</p>

<p>Albanese said he had exchanged "directly" with Assange's lawyers during the negotiations.</p>

<p>Australia's high commissioner to the United Kingdom, Stephen Smith, also acted as a conduit for communication, visiting Assange in Belmarsh, the prime minister said.</p>

<p>"The details of the plea deal were worked through over a period of time," he said.</p>

<p>"This was the only way that I could see a resolution being achieved -- and the objective here was to conclude these matters."</p>

<p>Albanese said he had never met with Assange but spoke with him the moment his jet touched down in Canberra as part of a mutually agreed plan.</p>

<p>"I had a very warm discussion with him this evening. He was very generous in his praise of the Australian government's efforts," he added.</p>

<p>"The Australian government stands up for Australian citizens. That's what we do."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ajvkrgf8_julian-assange-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anthony Albanese said he had exchanged "directly" with Julian Assange's lawyers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-australias-quiet-diplomacy-led-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-to-freedom-5974456]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Australia's Quiet Diplomacy Led WikiLeaks' Julian Assange To Freedom]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-australias-quiet-diplomacy-led-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-to-freedom-5974456]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:51:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After Julian Assange was released by a court on the remote US Pacific territory of Saipan, ending a 14-year legal battle, the WikiLeaks founder's lawyer first thanked Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese for making the outcome possible.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After Julian Assange was released by a court on the remote US Pacific territory of Saipan on Wednesday, ending a 14-year legal battle, the WikiLeaks founder's lawyer first thanked Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese for making the outcome possible.</p>

<p>Jennifer Robinson, the Australian attorney of Assange, said diplomacy and intense lobbying with the highest authorities in the US played a big role in Assange walking free, after spending five years in a high-security British prison and seven years holed up in the Ecuadorean embassy in London.</p>

<p>"At every opportunity, and when Australian officials were making outreach to the US, they knew that they were acting with the full authority of the prime minister of Australia," Robinson told reporters outside the courtroom in Saipan.</p>

<p>Albanese has claimed Assange's release as a win for the country, which leveraged its security ties with Washington and London to strengthen its case to resolve the plight of an Australian citizen.</p>

<p>"This work has been complex and it has been considered. This is what standing up for Australians around the world looks like," Albanese, leader of a centre-left Labor government, told parliament on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Assange, who landed in Australia on Wednesday evening, had faced a maximum jail sentence of 175 years after being charged with 17 counts of breaching the US Espionage Act and a hacking-related charge. Under a deal revealed on Tuesday, he pled guilty to a single charge of espionage and walked free.</p>

<p>The deal gained momentum as the US faced growing challenges in the UK over the legality of extraditing Assange, while Australian lawmakers and diplomats raised the heat in Washington and London.</p>

<h2><strong>Political Shift</strong></h2>

<p>A decade ago under a conservative government, there was little political will in Canberra to back Assange's case. But things changed in 2023 when dozens of lawmakers across the political spectrum swung in behind the campaign to bring him home, his father, John Shipton, told Reuters.</p>

<p>That swing culminated in the passage of a parliamentary motion in February this year calling for Assange's release.</p>

<p>Shipton told Reuters the Australian government had been "nothing short of magnificent" and praised former prime minister Kevin Rudd and former defence minister Stephen Smith, Australia's top envoys to the US and Britain.</p>

<p>Australian conservative lawmaker Barnaby Joyce, a former deputy prime minister, was among a cross-party group of politicians who travelled to Washington in September to lobby for a resolution.</p>

<p>Joyce said on Wednesday the trip made the case on Capitol Hill that Australian politicians wanted to "get this thing done", because it was a distraction to Australia's security alliance with the United States.</p>

<p>Long-time advisor to the Australian campaign for Assange, lawyer Greg Barns, said US politicians saw on that trip that "this wasn't a party political issue".</p>

<p>One government official who did not want to be identified said the first big break for Assange came in January 2021, when then shadow Attorney General Mark Dreyfus issued a statement calling for the case against Assange to end after a British court found that it would be unjust to extradite him to the US.</p>

<p>"This was the first indication that a major political party in Australia was supporting the cause to free Assange," the official said.</p>

<h2><strong>Enough Is Enough</strong></h2>

<p>When Labor won power in May 2022, Assange finally had state diplomatic support behind him. Later that year Albanese called for his release on the floor of the House of Representatives, the first time a Prime Minister had mentioned Assange in parliament since 2012.</p>

<p>"Enough is enough, it is time for this matter to be brought to a conclusion," he said.</p>

<p>"My position is clear and has been made clear to the US administration that it is time that this matter be brought to a close. This is an Australian citizen."</p>

<p>Behind the scenes, Albanese and senior cabinet colleagues including Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Attorney General Dreyfus used visits to the US to lobby their counterparts, according to the government official.</p>

<p>The appointment of Smith and Rudd to the top diplomatic jobs in London and Washington in late 2022 added two more sympathetic lobbyists for Assange's cause.</p>

<p>Smith visited Assange in Belmarsh prison in April 2023, the first such visit by Australia's top UK diplomat since he was imprisoned four years earlier.</p>

<p>Deeper ties between Australia and the US through the AUKUS security pact helped push diplomatic efforts along, said Mark Kenny, a professor at Australian National University.</p>

<p>"It looks pretty odd if we're getting ever closer to the US and yet we don't have a special relationship with the US such that we can advocate and get concessions for an Australian citizen," Kenny said.</p>

<h2><strong>Final Details</strong></h2>

<p>As recently as last July, US officials appeared determined to prosecute Assange. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said that month Australia needed to understand US concerns over the issue.</p>

<p>However, a month later, US Ambassador to Australia Caroline Kennedy said a deal was possible.</p>

<p>After the cross-party delegation of Australian politicians travelled to Washington in September to speak to Republican and Democrat lawmakers about the Assange case, the Biden administration appeared to be softening its response.</p>

<p>Joe Biden said in April, "We are considering it," when asked by media about Australia's request to end Assange's prosecution.</p>

<p>But it was the UK High Court's decision in May to allow Assange to appeal against his extradition that triggered the breakthrough in negotiations over a plea deal according to his wife Stella.</p>

<p>The court's decision meant the legal battle over extradition would likely be delayed for months more to make time for appeals.</p>

<p>An early plan to have Assange fly to New York or Washington to enter his plea was changed to Saipan because of Assange's opposition to entering the continental United States, according to an Australian government official.</p>

<p>The deal marks the end of a legal saga following WikiLeaks' mass release of secret US documents in 2010 - one of the largest security breaches in US military history.</p>

<p>As Assange was moved from Belmarsh prison to London's Stansted airport in the dead of night on Monday, the secrecy was such that his children weren't told in case they spilled details about his release, according to his wife Stella Assange.</p>

<p>In a global outpouring of support following the news, a crowdfunding campaign to raise the $520,000 owed to the Australian government for the flights had already raised almost 330,000 pounds ($418,000) by Wednesday evening.</p>

<p>"I don't think that would have happened if it hadn't been for the incredible support that there has been for Julian, and which has been building over the years, which is global, which is across all sectors, all politics," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/7d6e6b88_julian-assange-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anthony Albanese has claimed Julian Assange's release as a win for the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-lands-in-australia-as-a-free-man-5973852]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WikiLeaks Founder Julian Assange, A Free Man, Lands In Australia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-lands-in-australia-as-a-free-man-5973852]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 15:32:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange returned home to Australia to start life as a free man Wednesday after admitting he revealed US defence secrets in a deal that unlocked the door to his London prison cell.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/search?searchtext=Julian-Assange">Julian Assange</a> returned home to Australia to start life as a free man Wednesday after admitting he revealed US defence secrets in a deal that unlocked the door to his London prison cell.</p>

<p>Assange landed on a chilly Canberra evening in a private jet, the final act of an international drama that led him from a five-year stretch in the high-security Belmarsh prison in Britain to a courtroom in a US Pacific island territory and, finally, home.</p>

<p>His white hair swept back, the Australian raised a fist as he emerged from the plane door, striding across the tarmac to give a hug to his wife Stella that lifted her off the ground, and then to embrace his father.</p>

<p>Dozens of television journalists, photographers, and reporters peered through the airport fencing to see Assange, who wore a dark suit, white shirt, and brown tie.</p>

<p>WikiLeaks said on X that it would hold a press conference in the Australian capital at 9:15 pm (1115 GMT) on Wednesday, but did not say if Assange would be present.</p>

<p>"He will be able to spend quality time with his wife Stella, and his two children, be able to walk up and down on the beach and feel the sand through his toes in winter -- that lovely chill," said <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-father-awaits-his-arrival-in-australia-says-my-faith-never-ever-ever-died-5973543">Assange's father, John Shipton</a>.</p>

<p>Assange's long battle with US prosecutors came to an unexpected end in the Northern Mariana Islands where a judge accepted his guilty plea on a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate national defence information.</p>

<p>The remote courtroom was chosen because of the 52-year-old's unwillingness to go to the continental United States and because of its proximity to Australia.</p>

<h2><strong>'A free man'</strong>&nbsp;</h2>

<p>As part of a behind-the-scenes legal negotiation with the US Justice Department he was sentenced to the time he had already served in London -- five years and two months -- and given his liberty.</p>

<p>"You will be able to walk out of this courtroom <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-freed-in-us-plea-deal-hearing-5971114">a free man</a>," the judge told him.</p>

<p>Assange had published hundreds of thousands of confidential US documents on the whistleblowing website from 2010.</p>

<p>He became a hero to free speech campaigners but a villain to those who thought he endangered US security and intelligence sources.</p>

<p>"Working as a journalist, I encouraged my source to provide material that was said to be classified," Assange told the court.</p>

<p>Assange's lawyer Jen Robinson told reporters it was a "historic day" that "brings to an end 14 years of legal battles".</p>

<p>"It also brings to an end a case which has been recognised as the greatest threat to the First Amendment in the 21st century," she said.</p>

<h2><strong>'Too long'</strong></h2>

<p>Australian Prime Minster Anthony Albanese said he was "very pleased" by the outcome.</p>

<p>"Regardless of your views about his activities, and they will be varied, Mr Assange's case has dragged on for too long," he told parliament in Canberra.</p>

<p>The United Nations also hailed Assange's release, saying the case had raised human rights concerns.</p>

<p>But former US vice president Mike Pence slammed the plea deal on social media platform X as a "miscarriage of justice" that "dishonors the service and sacrifice of the men and women of our Armed Forces."</p>

<p>The US Justice Department said after the hearing that Assange was banned from returning there without permission.</p>

<p>US authorities had wanted to put Assange on trial for divulging military secrets about the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>He was indicted by a US federal grand jury in 2019 on 18 counts stemming from WikiLeaks' publication of a trove of national security documents.</p>

<p>The material he released through WikiLeaks included videos showing civilians being killed by fire from a US helicopter gunship in Iraq in 2007. The victims included a photographer and a driver from Reuters.</p>

<h2><strong>'Can't stop crying'</strong></h2>

<p>In 2019, he was arrested and held in Belmarsh prison while fighting extradition to the United States.</p>

<p>He had spent seven years in Ecuador's embassy in London to avoid being extradited to Sweden, where he faced accusations of sexual assault that were eventually dropped.</p>

<p>He met his wife Stella Assange while holed up in the embassy, and the pair married in a ceremony in London's Belmarsh prison. They have two young children.</p>

<p>"I can't stop crying," Stella, who was waiting for him in Australia, said on X.</p>

<p>"I am beyond excited," she later told reporters as she left a Canberra hotel together with Assange's father to see her husband at the airport.</p>

<p>The announcement of the plea deal came two weeks before Assange was scheduled to appear in court in Britain to appeal against a ruling that approved his extradition to the United States.</p>

<p>Washington had accused Assange under the 1917 Espionage Act and supporters warned he risked being sentenced to 175 years in prison.</p>

<p>The plea deal was not entirely unexpected. US President Joe Biden had been under growing pressure to drop the long-running case against Assange.</p>

<p>The Australian government made an official request to that effect in February and Biden said he would consider it, raising hopes among Assange supporters that his ordeal might end.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/gdufm4eg_julian-assange-canberra-a_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange has landed in Canberra to start life as a free man.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-father-awaits-his-arrival-in-australia-says-my-faith-never-ever-ever-died-5973543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["My Faith Never, Ever, Ever Died": Julian Assange's Father On His Return]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-father-awaits-his-arrival-in-australia-says-my-faith-never-ever-ever-died-5973543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:50:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Julian Assange's father, John Shipton, could breathe a massive sigh of relief on Wednesday after a decade-long campaign to free his son.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange's father, John Shipton, could breathe a massive sigh of relief on Wednesday after a decade-long campaign to free his son.</p>

<p>The WikiLeaks founder on Wednesday was released by a court on the U.S. Pacific island territory of Saipan after pleading guilty to violating U.S. espionage law.</p>

<p>Assange's family, including his father, children and wife, Stella, gathered in Australia's capital Canberra ahead of his expected evening arrival by private jet, marking the end of a long legal fight tied to WikiLeaks' release of hundreds of thousands of classified U.S. defence documents in 2010.</p>

<p>Shipton said he planned to ask his son in a low-key Australian way when he arrives: "Where have you been?"</p>

<p>"My faith has never, ever, ever died," he told Reuters in an interview at parliament.</p>

<p>"That Julian can come home to Australia and see his family regularly and do the ordinary things of life is a treasure. Life measured amongst the beauty of the ordinary is the essence of life," Shipton said.</p>

<p>He said he was "divided in two" on the deal that saw Assange plead guilty to one charge of espionage, saying his release meant he would have precious time with his sons.</p>

<p>He was nonetheless concerned about the "political and legal circumstances surrounding it".</p>

<p>"I think it is going to be a problem for journalists and publishers anywhere in the world to publish criticism of the United States government," he said.</p>

<p>Assange's release was cause for celebration in Canberra, where politicians who had campaigned for Assange gathered around Shipton in a hall outside the parliament chamber.</p>

<p>"We want to give you a hug," said lawmaker Sophie Scamps.</p>

<p>Assange will need time to recover from his "monastic life" in self-exile in the Ecuadorian embassy in London for seven years, and then prison for five years, Shipton said.</p>

<p>He looked forward to being involved in his son's "practical everyday human life, not the sweep of politics."</p>

<p>"The American Secret Service in 2011 published their review saying we must hound him and his family to the end of the earth and bankrupt them. Its been expensive but I've got no complaints - the results are there for everyone to see," he said.</p>

<p>He said the Australian government had been "nothing short of magnificent".</p>

<p>Assange has previously said he got his "rebel gene" from his father. Shipton said he considers his son to be personally conservative and polite.</p>

<p>"It is his understanding of the capacity of the internet to bring to us information that can be the foundation of knowledge that is revolutionary," he said.</p>

<p>"He is only 52 I imagine he will find something to do. He will be 53 next week. The momentum he has got ... he will conjure forth those things that he can do."</p>

<p>Shipton said the family had devoted the last decade to doing everything in its capacity to see Assange free.</p>

<p>"We Australians managed to turn around a superpower in its attempt to destroy an Australian citizen," he said.</p>

<p>Shipton learned of the plea deal from his son Gabriel.</p>

<p>Gabriel told Reuters on Wednesday he was "feeling extremely relieved that this ordeal is finally over and that Julian can move on with his life."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tn6a32q_assange-father-reuters-_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The WikiLeaks founder on Wednesday was released by a court]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenyas-anti-tax-protests-turn-deadly-13-killed-military-deployed-5973443]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[13 Killed In Kenya's Anti-Tax Protests, Military Deployed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenyas-anti-tax-protests-turn-deadly-13-killed-military-deployed-5973443]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:32:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The death count from protests in Kenya has climbed to 13, an official from the main doctors' association told AFP Wednesday, after anti-tax hike rallies turned violent and police opened fire at demonstrators who ransacked parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The death count from protests in Kenya has climbed to 13, an official from the main doctors' association told AFP Wednesday, after anti-tax hike rallies turned violent and police opened fire at demonstrators who ransacked parliament.</p>

<p>The unprecedented scenes that left parts of parliament ablaze and destroyed and injured scores of people on Tuesday have shocked Kenyans and prompted President William Ruto's government to deploy the military.</p>

<p>The mainly youth-led rallies began mostly peacefully last week, with thousands of demonstrators marching in the capital Nairobi, and across the country against the tax increases.</p>

<p>But tensions flared sharply on Tuesday afternoon, as police officers fired live rounds on crowds that later ransacked the parliament complex.</p>

<p>Hours later, Defence Minister Aden Bare Duale announced that the government had deployed the army to support the police in tackling "the security emergency" in the country.</p>

<p>"So far, we have at least 13 people killed, but this is not the final number," Simon Kigondu, president of the Kenya Medical Association said, adding that he had never seen "such level of violence against unarmed people."</p>

<p>"Deaths, mayhem", read the front-page headline on the Standard newspaper, while the Daily Nation described the situation as "Pandemonium", saying: "The foundations of the country have been shaken to the core."</p>

<p>An official at Kenyatta National Hospital in Nairobi said Wednesday that medics were treating "160 people... some of them with soft tissue injuries, some of them with bullet wounds".</p>

<p>In a late-night press briefing, Ruto warned that his government would take a tough line against "violence and anarchy", likening some of the demonstrators to "criminals".</p>

<p>"It is not in order or even conceivable that criminals pretending to be peaceful protesters can reign terror against the people, their elected representatives, and the institutions established under our constitution and expect to go scot-free," he said.</p>

<p>The government has been taken by surprise by the intensity of opposition to its tax proposals -- mostly led by young, Gen-Z Kenyans -- which culminated in the scenes at parliament that played out live on television.</p>

<p>Images shared on local TV stations after crowds broke through the barricades showed the building ransacked, with burnt furniture and smashed windows.</p>

<p>As police fired at the angry crowds, leaving several bodies strewn on the ground, protest organisers urged people to walk home together and "stay safe".</p>

<h3><strong>'Madness'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>A heavy police presence was deployed around parliament early on Wednesday, according to an AFP reporter, the smell of tear gas still in the air.</p>

<p>A policeman standing in front of the broken barricades to the complex told AFP he had watched the scenes unfold on TV.</p>

<p>"It was madness, we hope it will be calm today," he said.</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, the rallies in various Kenyan cities had been largely peaceful.</p>

<p>However, tensions escalated in Nairobi later in the day, with some protesters hurling stones at police, who deployed tear gas and water cannons before firing live bullets.</p>

<p>AFP journalists saw three people bleeding heavily and lying motionless on the ground near parliament.</p>

<h3><strong>'Brute force'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The unrest has alarmed the international community, with the White House appealing for calm and more than 10 Western nations -- including Canada, Germany, and Britain -- saying they were "especially shocked by the scenes witnessed outside the Kenyan Parliament".</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres and the head of the African Union Commission, Moussa Faki Mahamat, have also expressed deep concern.</p>

<p>Veteran opposition leader Raila Odinga, who heads the Azimio coalition, accused the government of unleashing "brute force on our country's children".</p>

<p>Rights watchdogs have also accused the authorities of abducting protesters.</p>

<p>The police have not responded to any AFP requests for comment.</p>

<h3><strong>Cost of living&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Long-running grievances over the rising cost of living spiraled last week as lawmakers began debating proposed tax hikes in the 2024 finance bill.</p>

<p>The cash-strapped government says the increases are needed to service the country's massive debt of some 10 trillion shillings ($78 billion), equal to roughly 70 percent of Kenya's GDP.</p>

<p>After rolling back some of the more controversial proposals -- which would have affected bread purchases, car ownership, and financial and mobile services -- the government now intends to increase fuel prices and export duties.</p>

<p>Kenya's treasury has warned of a gaping budget shortfall of 200 billion shillings, following Ruto's decision to roll back some of the tax hikes.</p>

<p>While Kenya is among East Africa's most dynamic economies, a third of its 52 million population live in poverty.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/lea5bi88_kenya-protest_625x300_21_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tensions flared sharply on Tuesday afternoon, as police officers fired live rounds on crowds]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-appoints-dutch-pm-mark-rutte-as-new-secretary-general-5973417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NATO Appoints Dutch PM Mark Rutte As New Secretary General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-appoints-dutch-pm-mark-rutte-as-new-secretary-general-5973417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:30:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NATO allies on Wednesday selected Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte as NATO's next boss, as the war in Ukraine rages on its doorstep and uncertainty hangs over the United States' future attitude to the transatlantic alliance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NATO allies on Wednesday selected Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte as NATO's next boss, as the war in Ukraine rages on its doorstep and uncertainty hangs over the United States' future attitude to the transatlantic alliance.</p>

<p>Rutte's appointment became a formality after his only rival for the post, Romanian President Klaus Iohannis, announced last week that he had quit the race, having failed to gain traction.</p>

<p>"The North Atlantic Council decided to appoint Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte as the next Secretary General of NATO, succeeding Jens Stoltenberg," NATO said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Mr Rutte will assume his functions as Secretary General from 1 October 2024, when Mr Stoltenberg's term expires after ten years at the helm of the Alliance," it added.</p>

<p>After declaring his interest in the post last year, Rutte gained early support from key members of the alliance including the United States, Britain, France and Germany.</p>

<p>Others were more reticent, particularly Eastern European countries which argued the post should go to someone from their region for the first time.</p>

<p>But they ultimately rowed in behind Rutte, a fierce critic of Russian President Vladimir Putin and a staunch ally of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Stoltenberg said he warmly welcomed the selection of Rutte as his successor.</p>

<p>"Mark is a true transatlanticist, a strong leader, and a consensus-builder," he said. "I know I am leaving NATO in good hands."</p>

<p>NATO takes decisions by consensus so Rutte, who is bowing out of Dutch politics after nearly 14 years as prime minister, could only be confirmed once all 32 alliance members gave him their backing.</p>

<p>Rutte will face the challenge of sustaining allies' support for Ukraine's fight against Russia's invasion while guarding against NATO's being drawn directly into a war with Moscow.</p>

<p>He will also have to contend with the possibility that NATO-sceptic Donald Trump may return to the White House after November's U.S. presidential election.</p>

<p>Trump's possible return has unnerved NATO leaders as the Republican former president called into question the U.S. willingness to support other members of the alliance if they were attacked.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/vs3p8h9g_dutch-pm-mark-rutte-reuters_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rutte's appointment comes after his only rival for the post, Romanian President Klaus Iohannis, quit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-family-seeks-compensation-from-nasa-after-space-junk-destroys-home-5973158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Family Seeks Compensation From NASA After Space Junk Destroys Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-family-seeks-compensation-from-nasa-after-space-junk-destroys-home-5973158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:53:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US family whose home was hit by space debris earlier this year is seeking compensation from the American space agency NASA for property damage and mental anguish.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US family whose home was hit by space debris earlier this year is seeking compensation from the American space agency NASA for property damage and mental anguish. The metallic cylinder slab punched a hole in the roof through two layers of ceiling in Alejandro Otero's home in Naples in March. Back then, NASA said that the object was part of a 2.9-ton pallet of used batteries jettisoned from the International Space Station in March 2021. Mr Otero said his son was nearly injured by the impact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now, law firm Cranfill Summer said in a press release that it filed a claim on behalf of Mr Otero and his family. It listed damages including non-insured property damage loss, business interruption, emotional/mental anguish and the costs for assistance from third parties.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9www02e49zo"><em>BBC</em></a>, Attorney Mica Nguyen Worthy said <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-confirms-object-that-destroyed-florida-home-was-space-junk-5452204">space debris </a>"is a real serious issue because of the increase in space traffic in recent years". "My clients are seeking adequate compensation to account for the stress and impact that this event had on their lives," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, speaking to <em>CBS</em> affiliate <em>Wink-TV </em>Mr Otero said that the space junk created a tremendous sound" as it blasted into his home. "I was shaking. I was completely in disbelief. What are the chances of something landing on my house with such force to cause so much damage," Mr Otero said.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-shares-stunning-pic-of-rare-gigantic-jets-spotted-over-himalayas-5971658">NASA Shares Stunning Pic Of Rare "Gigantic Jets" Spotted Over Himalayas</a></strong></p>

<p>The US space agency confirmed that the debris was from its flight support equipment. It was a metal support used to hold old batteries on a disposal pallet jettisoned from the station in 2021. While most of the pallet was expected to burn up in the atmosphere, this particular piece survived the fiery re-entry.</p>

<p>&nbsp;"The hardware was expected to fully burn up during entry through Earth's atmosphere on March 8, 2024. However, a piece of hardware survived and impacted a home in Naples, Florida," the agency said. The ISS will "perform a detailed investigation" on how the debris survived burn-up, according to Nasa.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>The BBC</em> reported that the agency now has 6 months to respond to Mr Otero's claims.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/dtgu3318_space-object_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NASA has 6 months to respond to Mr Otero's claims.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-missile-explodes-midair-after-launch-says-s-korea-military-5972990]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Missile Explodes Midair After Launch, Claims S Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-missile-explodes-midair-after-launch-says-s-korea-military-5972990]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:27:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea test-fired what appeared to be a hypersonic missile off its east coast on Wednesday, but it exploded in midair, South Korea's military said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea test-fired what appeared to be a hypersonic missile off its east coast on Wednesday, but it exploded in midair, South Korea's military said.</p>

<p>The missile was launched from near the capital, Pyongyang, South Korea's Joint Chiefs of Staff said. Japan's Defence Ministry said the missile flew to an altitude of about 100 km (62 miles) and a range of more than 200 km.</p>

<p>Senior officials of South Korea, the United States and Japan held a phone call and condemned the launch as a violation of multiple U.N. Security Council resolutions and a serious threat to the peace and stability of the region and beyond.</p>

<p>South Korea's marine corps said its troops staged firing drills near the maritime border with the North for the first time since Seoul scrapped an inter-Korean military pact early this month. The drills were announced earlier in June.</p>

<p>U.S. Indo-Pacific Command also issued a condemnation and called on Pyongyang to refrain from further unlawful and destabilising acts.</p>

<p>"While we have assessed that this event does not pose an immediate threat to U.S. personnel, or territory, or to our allies, we continue to monitor the situation," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>North Korea's last missile launch was on May 30.</p>

<p>North Korea this week criticised the deployment of a U.S. aircraft carrier to joint drills with South Korea and Japan, and warned of an "overwhelming, new demonstration of deterrence".</p>

<p>The missile launch comes a day after the 74-year anniversary of the beginning of the Korean War.</p>

<p>Last week, North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and Russian President Vladimir Putin held a summit and signed a mutual defence pact. Seoul, Washington and Tokyo criticised the two countries' deepening military cooperation, with South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol calling the pact "anachronistic".</p>

<p>North Korean state media KCNA said on Wednesday a mass rally in Pyongyang was held to commemorate the war anniversary, calling it a day of "struggle against U.S. imperialism" and calling the United States the archenemy.</p>

<p>Recently, North Korea has flown hundreds of balloons carrying trash toward the South, including on Tuesday, while Pyongyang deployed a large group of soldiers to build new fortifications within the heavily armed border between the two Koreas, according to the South's military, occasionally drawing warning shots from South Korean counterparts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hnfrjjs_north-korea-hyperonic-missile-launch-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea's hypersonic missile seems to have exploded midair.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hollywood-crew-union-strikes-deal-with-major-studios-pay-hikes-and-ai-safeguards-5972924]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hollywood Crew Union Strikes Deal With Major Studios On Pay Raise, AI Use]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hollywood-crew-union-strikes-deal-with-major-studios-pay-hikes-and-ai-safeguards-5972924]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:17:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A union representing Hollywood film and television crew said on Tuesday it has reached a tentative three-year deal with major studios that includes agreed-on pay hikes and guardrails against the use of artificial intelligence (AI).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A union representing Hollywood film and television crew said on Tuesday it has reached a tentative three-year deal with major studios that includes agreed-on pay hikes and guardrails against the use of artificial intelligence (AI).</p>

<p>The International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) members, which include lighting technicians and costume designers, are to ratify the deal with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers (AMPTP), which represents Disney, Netflix, and others.</p>

<p>The terms of the agreement include scale-rate increases of 7%, 4%, and 3.5% over the three-year term, the union said.</p>

<p>On the AI front, the deal includes "language that ensures no employee is required to provide Al prompts in any manner that would result in the displacement of any covered employee."</p>

<p>In late 2023, the SAG-AFTRA actors union and the studios reached a labor agreement which ended a near six-month dispute that had halted film and TV production.</p>

<p>That contract also provided for pay raises and streaming bonuses that union leaders said amounted to more than $1 billion over three years, and also included protection around the use of AI in filmmaking.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/b217rvgg_hollywood_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[IATSE members are to ratify the deal with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-florida-online-gaming-feud-turns-violent-as-man-attacks-rival-with-hammer-5972791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Jersey Gamer Flies To Florida To Attack Online Rival With Hammer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-florida-online-gaming-feud-turns-violent-as-man-attacks-rival-with-hammer-5972791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 12:55:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Edward Kang faces serious charges, including attempted second-degree murder and armed burglary with a mask.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An online gaming rivalry turned violent when a 20-year-old man travelled from New Jersey to Florida and assaulted another player with a hammer. Despite never having met in person, Edward Kang reached Fernandina Beach on Sunday and allegedly attacked the victim, the police said.</p>

<p>Kang now faces serious charges, including attempted second-degree murder and armed burglary with a mask, according to court records from Nassau County.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a press conference, Nassau County Sheriff Bill Leeper said that Kang and the victim - also around the same age - played ArcheAge, a mediaeval fantasy multiplayer online role-playing game. The Sheriff called the case a weird one.</p>

<p>Some things you just can't make up, he added.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aLf32Et9L1A?si=0q46pQgVxBkQNTjV" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe><br />
<br />
Kang flew from New Jersey to Florida, telling his mom he was visiting a friend he met online, reported authorities. After landing, Kang purchased a hammer from a local hardware store before heading to the victim's house, which was reportedly left unlocked.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Kang confronted the victim inside the home around 2 am and hit him on the head with the hammer. The victim suffered multiple head wounds but managed to call for help. As the victim struggled with Kang, his stepfather intervened and helped restrain the attacker until police arrived at the scene.<br />
<br />
The victim survived the assault and received medical treatment for his injuries, described as serious but not life-threatening, reported ABC News.<br />
<br />
In custody, Kang called the victim a "bad person online". He asked deputies how much jail time he would get for breaking and assault. An official replied, "It's going to be long before you play video games again."<br />
<br />
Kang is being held without bond and does not have an attorney listed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6itt21co_us-gamer_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Edward Kang attacked his opponent after losing in a mediaeval fantasy multiplayer online game]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dramatic-videos-show-raging-water-flowing-around-us-dam-as-it-sweeps-away-building-5972698]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Videos Show Raging Water Flowing Around US Dam As It Sweeps Away Building]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dramatic-videos-show-raging-water-flowing-around-us-dam-as-it-sweeps-away-building-5972698]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 12:42:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Videos showed a tremendous volume of water flowing around the dam, swallowing a building as dead trees and other debris piled up around it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shocking visuals have surfaced online showing how&nbsp;a key dam in southern Minnesota built in the early 1900s, is at risk of failing after&nbsp;severe storms and flooding hit the region. Videos&nbsp;show strong water continuing to rush around the dam that has ''partially failed'' with officials saying the dam is in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=771440118493427&amp;id=100068823386285&amp;ref=embed_post">"imminent failure condition."</a></p>

<p>As per the<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2024/06/24/rapidan-dam-break-minnesota-flooding/"> Washington Post,</a></em> the alarming situation was brought on by days of torrential rains last week, triggering flooding that had killed at least two people.&nbsp;The floods have destroyed homes, swamped farmland, overtopped levees and caused a major railroad bridge to collapse.</p>

<p>One video shows a tremendous volume of water flowing around the dam, as it swallows a building.&nbsp; As the building falls into the fast-flowing river, it breaks into multiple pieces as it is washed away.&nbsp;Large trees are also seen breaking off at the side of the Blue Earth River and falling into the rapids.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the videos here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BREAKING: DAM FAILURE!<br />
Rapidan Dam Near <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Rapidan?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Rapidan</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Minnesota?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Minnesota</a> Complete Failure Imminent!<br />
The Flooded River Has Eroded The Ground Around The Dam &amp; Is Now Uncontrolled!<br />
The Dam Itself Has Not Failed Yet, But Engineers Believe It Can Completely Collapse At Any Time. <a href="https://t.co/EV9FLrTDNw">pic.twitter.com/EV9FLrTDNw</a></p>
 John Basham (@JohnBasham) <a href="https://twitter.com/JohnBasham/status/1805327536341020926?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ICYMI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ICYMI</a><br />
<br />
The <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RapidanDam?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#RapidanDam</a> in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mankato?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Mankato</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Minnesota?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Minnesota</a> is in imminent danger of failing.<br />
<br />
According to officials, it may fail as debris piles up. Residents living downstream have been warned to "be ready" as the situation worsens. <a href="https://t.co/xG8UzQ10Yc">pic.twitter.com/xG8UzQ10Yc</a></p>
 Geovanni Villafae ???? (@RezZureKtedPoeT) <a href="https://twitter.com/RezZureKtedPoeT/status/1805577296700391609?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>An Xcel Energy substation, which supplies power to 600 customers, was also swept downriver during the overflow Monday, according to the company. Mankato Police and Fire posted on Facebook Monday afternoon that the water level at the dam was 28 feet. The levee system is built to withstand a river capacity of up to 39.5 feet.</p>

<p>However, as of Tuesday afternoon, the dam was still intact and there are no plans for a larger evacuation. Nearby residents who are in immediate danger have been notified, officials said.</p>

<p>"The Dam is currently intact and there is not an evacuation order in place for Blue Earth County residents. A portion of the river flow has diverted around the west side of the dam and water continues to flow. The situation is being monitored closely by BEC Public Works, Emergency Management, and the Sheriff's Office,'' officials said.</p>

<p>According to<em> <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/minnesotas-rapidan-dam-risk-failure-amid-severe-flooding/story?id=111399672">ABC News</a></em>, the Rapidan Dam, built in 1910, is located on the Blue Earth River. Owned by the county, the dam is capable of generating 6 million watts of hydroelectric power. It&nbsp;is near the city of Mankato, about 90 minutes from Minneapolis, and home to some 45,000 people.</p>

<p data-analytics-observe="off" data-article-gutter="true" data-component-name="paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="cms.cnn.com/_components/paragraph/instances/clxuajg6v00023b6kcjv9qfxr@published">As per&nbsp;<a href="https://www.fema.gov/sites/default/files/2020-08/fema_dam-safety_aware-community_fact-sheet_2016.pdf" target="_blank">&nbsp;<em>FEMA</em></a>, dams can break for several reasons, including overtopping due to flooding and structural failure.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/71n6cgr8_minnesota-floods_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As of Tuesday afternoon, the dam was still intact]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abraham-lincolns-wax-sculpture-in-us-melts-as-temperatures-soar-5972632]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Abraham Lincoln's Wax Sculpture In US Melts As Temperatures Soar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abraham-lincolns-wax-sculpture-in-us-melts-as-temperatures-soar-5972632]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 12:31:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A six-foot-tall wax statue of former US President Abraham Lincoln in Washington melted as the capital city's temperatures soared over the weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A six-foot-tall wax statue of former US President Abraham Lincoln in Washington melted as the capital city's temperatures soared over the weekend.</p>

<p>The temperatures, which reportedly touched 37 degrees Celsius, disfigured the wax structure at the site of Camp Barker, a Civil War-era refugee camp that housed formerly enslaved and freed African Americans.</p>

<p>The statue's head was the first to surrender to the scorching heat, followed by the legs, BBC reported. Authorities are now repairing the sculpture.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">WE CAN NOT WITH THIS HEAT EITHER, LINCOLN<br />
Our project, 40 ACRES: Camp Barker by Sandy Williams IV has gone viral (for innocent reasons and some not so innocent ones). Read the articles for yourself: <a href="https://t.co/NfRc0CaLQI">https://t.co/NfRc0CaLQI</a><br />
Check out our website for updates. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/waxlincoln?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#waxlincoln</a> <a href="https://t.co/688QcBUAj2">pic.twitter.com/688QcBUAj2</a></p>
 Cultural_DC (@Cultural_DC) <a href="https://twitter.com/Cultural_DC/status/1805713303798161900?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The structure was a candle and a wax structure with a plaque that said, "Please blow out your wick within 1-2 minutes."</p>

<p>The replica, commissioned by the non-profit organisation CulturalDC, was scheduled to be placed at the site till September 2024.</p>

<p>The organisation also commented on the incident and said, "Whether it's the state of the union, the upcoming election, or this record-level heat, we are all over it!</p>

<p>The statue was created by US-based artist Sandy Williams as part of the Wax Monument Series. It was placed at the site of Camp Barker, which now houses an elementary school.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/mhdmenmo_lincoln-wax-statue-melted_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The statue's head was the first to surrender to the scorching heat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-kept-adopted-black-children-as-slaves-locked-them-in-shed-5972391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Couple Kept Adopted Black Children As "Slaves", Locked Them In Shed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-kept-adopted-black-children-as-slaves-locked-them-in-shed-5972391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 11:56:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The indictment alleges that the children were forced to work on the couple's farmland because of their race and treated as slaves.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A wealthy white couple in West Virginia has been charged with human trafficking, forced labour and child neglect. The couple, Donald Ray Lantz (63) and Jeanne Kay Whitefeather (62), allegedly subjected their five adopted black children to forced labour and confinement, <a href="https://www.wvnews.com/news/wvnews/west-virginia-couple-accused-of-forced-labor-and-abuse-of-adopted-children/article_47603a5c-332f-11ef-99e4-37e6c030b9f5.html">WNews</a>&nbsp;reported.<br />
<br />
The children, aged 6-16, were found living in deplorable conditions. Two teens were locked in a filthy shed without basic amenities, while another child was in a loft in the main house.<br />
<br />
The indictment alleges the children were forced to work on the couple's farmland because of their race and treated as slaves. The couple allegedly also prohibited them from entering the main house, reported the outlet.<br />
<br />
The couple faces multiple charges, including human trafficking, forced labour involving minors, and child neglect, creating a substantial risk of severe injury or death. They pleaded not guilty to the charges on Tuesday, <a href="https://m.wchstv.com/news/local/court-to-hold-400000-used-to-post-sissonville-couples-bond-until-case-resolved">WCHSTV</a> reported.<br />
<br />
The investigation began after a neighbour reported concerns about the well-being of children.<br />
<br />
Police found two teenagers, a 14-year-old boy and a 16-year-old girl, locked in a shed on the couple's property. The shed had no lights, running water, or mattresses, only an RV porta-potty. The teens told police they were forced to sleep on the concrete floor and were last fed 12 hours prior.<br />
<br />
The boy had open sores on his bare feet, and both children wore dirty clothes and smelled of body odour. A 9-year-old girl was found inside the residence, while an 11-year-old boy and a 6-year-old girl were brought to the property later by the couple.<br />
<br />
Kanawha County Circuit Judge Maryclaire Akers described the indictment as one of the worst" she has ever seen, citing allegations of human trafficking and racial targeting. It alleges human trafficking, human rights violations, the use of forced labour, Judge Akers said, as per the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/06/25/us-news/wealthy-white-couple-allegedly-kept-their-black-adopted-children-as-slaves-locked-them-in-barn-report/">NY Post</a>. These children were targeted because of their race, and they were used basically as slaves from what the indictment alleges.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Judge Akers increased the couple's bond from $200,000 to $500,000 each, citing the severe nature of the human trafficking and child neglect charges. She stated that the initial bond was insufficient due to the risk of bodily harm or death involved. The case will go to trial on September 9.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/du2bc1bo_west-virginia-couple_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/karachi-on-high-alert-over-mysterious-deaths-22-found-dead-across-city-5972213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Karachi On High Alert Over Mysterious Deaths, 22 Found Dead Across City]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/karachi-on-high-alert-over-mysterious-deaths-22-found-dead-across-city-5972213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 11:33:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The city of Karachi is grappling with a mysterious and concerning trend as the number of unidentified bodies found in various areas of the metropolis has now reached 22, according to a Geo News report on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The city of Karachi is grappling with a mysterious and concerning trend as the number of unidentified bodies found in various areas of the metropolis has now reached 22, according to a Geo News report on Wednesday.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, five new bodies were discovered, adding to the growing list of unexplained deaths.</p>

<p>According to the Chhipa Welfare Association, a non-profit welfare organization in Pakistan, three of the latest victims appear to be drug addicts, as per Geo News.</p>

<p>Despite efforts by the organization's volunteers, none of the 22 bodies have been identified.</p>

<p>A spokesperson of the Chhipa Welfare Association said in a statement on Tuesday, that volunteers found five more bodies in different areas of Karachi on Tuesday. "Three of them were seemingly drug addicts, however, not a single body was identified so far," the spokesperson added.</p>

<p>According to Geo News, the non-government organisation, that runs a network of ambulances in the metropolis, confirmed that the number of unidentified bodies has reached 22 after today's recoveries.</p>

<p>It added that nearly two dozen of those bodies were still unclaimed as no relatives of the dead came to receive them.</p>

<p>The deaths were attributed to an ongoing heatwave in the port city which affected a vast number of citizens as many of them were admitted to different hospitals due to heatstroke.</p>

<p>An official of another humanitarian organisation in Karachi, Edhi Foundation's Azeem Khan told The News yesterday that most of the dead were drug addicts who died due to severe heat while being under the influence of drugs after over a dozen unidentified persons were found dead in different areas of Karachi.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, In Karachi a senior citizen was brutally assaulted by a group of drug users after confronting them about openly using drugs outside his residence, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>According to details, the victim attempted to stop the youths from engaging in drug activity in front of his home, which provoked the youths, resulting in severe violence against the elderly man.</p>

<p>This incident highlights the rising issue of drug abuse in Pakistan, particularly the increasing use of Ice, also known as crystal methamphetamine, in recent years.</p>

<p>Crystal meth is a highly addictive and potent stimulant that can have devastating effects on individuals and society as a whole. The usage of ice in Pakistan has been particularly prevalent among the younger generation.</p>

<p>The drug is often seen as a party drug that can enhance energy, alertness, and confidence, making it appealing to young people looking for a quick high. The ease of access to ice, as well as its relatively low cost compared to other drugs, has contributed to its popularity among young Pakistanis.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-03/3d9746ug_dead-body-generic_625x300_03_March_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/heres-an-idea-what-if-india-and-china-find-common-ground-5972143]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: The Great Asian Reconciliation: Can India-China Find Common Ground?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/heres-an-idea-what-if-india-and-china-find-common-ground-5972143]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 11:24:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It might sound crazy to suggest that India and China should become trusted partners like the US and India, or Russia and China. But, it's not entirely out of the question.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/9f8gj3p8_india-china_625x300_26_June_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>London is known for its open intellectual climate, where no idea is off-limits. But even in this dynamic city - and indeed in Washington too - it's almost blasphemous to suggest that Russia and the West can be partners, or that the US and China can coexist as global powers. Recently, Nigel Farage, the Reform Party leader in the UK, faced a storm for urging the West to negotiate sensibly with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/russia-ukraine-live-updates">Russia over Ukraine</a>, calling the war a 'complete stalemate'. People accused him of "echoing Russian propaganda".</p>

<p>In India, we often hear that we don't cultivate a society where all ideas are welcome. But let's hope that suggesting a new chapter of "<em>Hindi-Cheeni bhai-bhai</em>" (<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/great-positive-progress-made-on-resolving-border-row-with-india-china-5427103">India-China</a> brotherhood) isn't seen as blasphemy. The strong anti-China sentiment after the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/india-china-clash-galwan-valley">Galwan Valley clash in 2020</a> seems to have subsided. We're buying more Chinese goods now than ever. In 2023, our bilateral trade hit over $136 billion. Hopefully, even those who burnt Chinese products in Gujarat and Delhi following the border skirmishes are more open to the idea now.</p>

<p><span>Sure, it might sound crazy to suggest that India and China should become trusted partners like the US and India, or Russia and China. But, it's not entirely out of the question.</span></p>

<h2><strong>Major Geopolitical Shifts</strong></h2>

<p>India's rise to become a global power is unstoppable; even China knows that. Talking to Chinese academics and journalists, you get the sense that they're open to establishing long-term ties based on mutual respect. They like India, they want more people-to-people interactions, and one of them even wondered recently why India does not try to cast its spell over the dragon through its soft power of Bollywood &nbsp;</p>

<p>Both countries have the responsibility to lift millions of their combined 2.8 billion people out of poverty. Prime Minister Narendra Modi has pledged to make India a developed country by 2047, which is a huge task. There are challenges, but if India and China team up and leverage each other's strengths, it could be a major geopolitical shift, with far-reaching implications for global politics.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/modi-hasina-should-worry-about-china-but-not-too-much-5959266">Read | Modi-Hasina Should Worry About China, But Not Too Much</a></strong></p>

<p>The US and its allies might be shocked and deeply concerned by a close India-China partnership. The West has benefited from the rivalry between the two countries as it aligns with their strategy of counterbalancing China's rise. A partnership between these two Asian giants could undermine the West's strategic interests in the region. Kishore Mahbubani, former Singaporean ambassador to the UN, has often said that most of Asia would cheer if this were to happen.</p>

<p>So, can India and China find common ground despite tensions over their disputed border? Prof. Mahbubani believes that while the two may never be best friends, they can have a good working relationship. He even says the 21st century belongs to the CIA (China, India, and ASEAN) countries. With US power on the decline, these countries will drive the world's economic growth.</p>

<h2><strong>A Rollercoaster Ride</strong></h2>

<p>The idea of India and China being close friends isn't new. Historically, they've acted like quarrelsome neighbours who fight and make up repeatedly. They share a long history of cultural and economic exchange dating back over two millennia. The Silk Road facilitated trade, and Buddhism, which started in India, found a significant following in China. These ancient ties laid a foundation of mutual respect and cultural affinity. During the colonial era, both countries faced subjugation by Western powers, fostering a sense of shared struggle.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After gaining independence from the British, India faced border issues with China, and they continue to strain their relationship. In the early 1950s, the relationship was marked by camaraderie, epitomised by the slogan "<em>Hindi-Chini Bhai-Bhai</em>". However, this period of cooperation was short-lived. The border dispute escalated into a full-scale war in 1962, leaving a lasting scar on bilateral relations. The disputed borders, particularly in the Aksai Chin and Arunachal Pradesh regions, remain contentious issues.</p>

<p>Before the Galwan incident, Prime Minister Narendra Modi naturally leaned towards engaging with China. As Gujarat's Chief Minister, he made four trips to the country to attract investment. As Prime Minister, he has visited China twice, and President Xi Jinping reciprocated with two visits to India. Both countries have emerged as major global economic powers, engaging in significant economic competition and areas of cooperation within multilateral frameworks like BRICS and the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO).</p>

<h2><strong>Strategic Rivalry</strong></h2>

<p>Strategically, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/blog/blog-india-china-ties-through-the-eyes-of-a-student-4381793">India and China view each other with suspicion</a>. The latter's close ties with Pakistan, its infrastructure projects in South Asia under the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI), and its military presence in the Indian Ocean have heightened India's security concerns.</p>

<p>Conversely, India's growing partnership with the US and its participation in the Quad (Quadrilateral Security Dialogue) is viewed warily by China. The 2020 Galwan Valley clash exacerbated tensions and highlighted the fragility of the relationship. Despite several rounds of military and diplomatic talks, a comprehensive resolution to the border disputes remains elusive.</p>

<h2><strong>Mumbai's Shanghai Dreams</strong></h2>

<p>Many youth in India might not know that not too long ago, India used to compare itself with Pakistan in all spheres. This attitude changed around the turn of the millennium, when the Maharashtra government launched a mega project to revamp Mumbai in 2004, based on the "Vision Mumbai" report by Bombay First, an organisation comprising some of Mumbai's super-rich stakeholders. The report outlined strategies for transforming Mumbai into "another Shanghai". While the project to transform Mumbai is still a "work in progress", it marked the beginning of India's comparisons with China. Today, China sees India as its great rival, at least in Asia.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/china-is-revamping-its-military-and-india-must-not-take-it-lightly-5571658">Read | China Is Revamping Its Military, And India Must Not Take It Lightly</a></strong></p>

<p>Projections show that the Indian economy will surpass Germany and Japan's to become the world's third-largest one by 2027. Currently, however, India's economy is only 19% the size of China's, even though it feeds nearly the same number of people. According to the International Monetary Fund (IMF), India's nominal GDP in 2023 stood at $3.5 trillion, compared to China's $18.2 trillion. India's per capita income was $2,411, while China's was $12,720. China's exports last year exceeded $3.38 trillion, while India's exports were $778 billion.</p>

<h2><strong>Collaboration Possibilities</strong></h2>

<p>Since China opened its economy in 1978, it has lifted 800 million people out of poverty - a feat that hasn't been matched by any regime in history. India has also succeeded in reducing poverty significantly. Both nations have many more millions to help. Collaborating in economic development, technology, infrastructure, environmental initiatives, healthcare, cultural exchange, and geopolitical stability can benefit both countries and the world. Overcoming historical tensions and building trust through consistent dialogue will be crucial.</p>

<p>The intense rivalry between the US and China will continue, and India will remain under pressure from the US to stay a reliable partner in its effort to manage China. However, India's strategic positioning between the US and China can work to its advantage. Ultimately, New Delhi's strategic interests are best served by a balanced approach that navigates the complex dynamics of US-China relations while advancing its own national objectives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India knows that neighbours with shared borders may fight at times, but they can still continue to believe in the 'love thy neighbour' dictum.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/kv4a2n_india-china_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-tech-mogul-fahim-salehs-assistant-planned-and-murdered-his-ex-boss-5971777]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Tech Firm Employee Planned And Executed Murder Of His Ex-Boss In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-tech-mogul-fahim-salehs-assistant-planned-and-murdered-his-ex-boss-5971777]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:37:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tyrese Haspil's scheme to steal from his former boss, Fahim Saleh, began in 2018, but it wasn't until July 2020 that his plan turned deadly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tyrese Haspil, a former assistant of tech mogul Fahim Saleh, has been convicted of murdering his former boss in his Manhattan apartment back in 2020.&nbsp;Prosecutors said that Tyrese Haspil killed his former boss to cover up his theft of $400,000 from the 33-year-old businessman.</p>

<p>Mr Saleh was a successful tech entrepreneur and the CEO of Gokada, a Nigeria-based scooter startup.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The 25-year-old was found <a href="https://manhattanda.org/d-a-bragg-announces-all-count-trial-conviction-of-tyrese-haspil-in-murder-of-tech-ceo-fahim-saleh/">guilty of multiple charges</a>, including murder in the first degree, grand larceny, burglary, tampering with physical evidence and concealment of a human corpse. He faces up to 25 years to life in prison and will be sentenced on September 10.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Manhattan District Attorney Alvin Bragg said, Tyrese Haspil tragically cut Mr Saleh's life short  a man who came from a close-knit immigrant family and followed his passions to become a successful entrepreneur. I hope the accountability delivered by today's verdict can provide a measure of comfort to Mr Saleh's loved ones as they continue to mourn his loss.<br />
<br />
Mr Saleh was found murdered in his $2.4 million 7th-floor high-rise condo on East Houston Street, reported the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/06/24/us-news/tech-ceo-fahim-salehs-ex-assistant-convicted-in-grisly-dismemberment-murder/">NY Post</a>.<br />
<br />
<strong>Planning the murder</strong><br />
<br />
Tyrese Haspil's scheme to steal from his former boss, Fahim Saleh, began in 2018, but it wasn't until July 2020 that his plan turned deadly.&nbsp;He embezzled money from Mr Saleh's companies to purchase lavish gifts for his girlfriend, The NYT reported.<br />
<br />
Haspil created a bogus corporate entity and bank account to funnel the stolen money. When Mr Saleh discovered the theft in January 2020, Haspil agreed to a repayment plan but continued to steal more money through a fraudulent PayPal account.<br />
<br />
Concerned that Mr Saleh would discover the more lucrative theft, Haspil began plotting to kill him.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Tyrese Haspil's online activity showed that he searched for "Fahim Saleh" and "murder of tech CEO in New York", as well as "dismembered body" and "anatomy of the human neck". He also looked up building plans and searched for contractor-grade trash bags, weapons and cleaning supplies, as per the NYT.<br />
<br />
Haspil also tracked Mr Saleh's whereabouts on social media and purchased clothes to conceal his identity.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Execution of the murder</strong><br />
<br />
On July 13, 2020, Tyrese Haspil entered an elevator with Mr Saleh in the latter's apartment building wearing a dark plastic face shield, a baseball cap and sunglasses. Mr Saleh, unaware of the impending danger, joked with Haspil about taking Covid precautions seriously. However, as soon as the elevator doors opened, Haspil's demeanour turned deadly.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
According to his testimony, Tyrese Haspil tased Fahim Saleh in the back, rendering him immobile, and then pulled out a knife. With a targeted strike, Haspil aimed for Mr Saleh's neck, delivering a fatal blow, reported the NYT.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
He then left the apartment and returned the next day to dismember Mr Saleh's body with an electric saw. He stuffed the body parts in plastic bags, which were later found strewn across the apartment.<br />
<br />
However, before completing the task, he left again to purchase a battery charger, and it was during this time that Fahim Saleh's cousin discovered the scene when he went to check up on him.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Tyrese Haspil was arrested four days later at an Airbnb he booked for his girlfriend's birthday celebration.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
His public defenders argued that he murdered his ex-boss due to extreme emotional disturbance and unconditional love for his girlfriend. He feared she would leave him if she found out he had been embezzling money from his boss, as per <a href="http://https://nypost.com/2024/06/24/us-news/tech-ceo-fahim-salehs-ex-assistant-convicted-in-grisly-dismemberment-murder/">reports</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/rkp9mc48_tyrese-haspil_625x300_25_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tyrese Haspil (left) killed his boss Fahim Saleh in 2020]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-who-killed-3-daughters-jailed-for-18-years-in-new-zealand-5971516]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Who Killed 3 Daughters Jailed For 18 Years In New Zealand]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-who-killed-3-daughters-jailed-for-18-years-in-new-zealand-5971516]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 09:49:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New Zealand judge on Wednesday sentenced a woman to 18 years imprisonment for murdering her three young daughters in 2021.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New Zealand judge on Wednesday sentenced a woman to 18 years imprisonment for murdering her three young daughters in 2021.</p>

<p>Lauren Dickason will begin her sentence at a mental health hospital in the custody of the state, a court official at Christchurch High Court told AFP, for the triple killings.</p>

<p>In a statement to local media after her sentencing, Dickason said she had "failed" her children and her husband, who has since moved back to South Africa.</p>

<p>"I take responsibility for taking our three beautiful girls from this world," she said.</p>

<p>"I would like to take this opportunity to convey the deepest and most sincere remorse for the extreme pain and hurt caused to my children and my family by my actions."</p>

<p>Justice Cameron Mander did not impose a minimum non-parole period in sentencing Dickason, who escaped life imprisonment which is the usual penalty for murder in New Zealand.</p>

<p>Dickason was found guilty last August on three counts of murder having smothered her two-year-old twins Maya and Karla and first daughter Liane, six.</p>

<p>The killings took place in September 2021 at their home in Timaru while her husband was out to dinner with colleagues. He found the bodies of his children when he returned home.</p>

<p>The family had moved to New Zealand from South Africa just weeks before.</p>

<p>During last year's trial, Dickason admitted killing the girls but had argued a defence of insanity and infanticide, triggered by the stress of the move.</p>

<p>Under New Zealand law, infanticide is a defence for a mother who causes the death of her child when, "at the time of the offence, the balance of her mind was disturbed".</p>

<p>Dickason's lawyer had argued that a mental health unit was the most appropriate place for her, according to local media reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/j5rt51b8_lauren-dickason-x_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I take responsibility for taking our three beautiful girls from this world," said Lauren Dickason.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-koreas-incheon-airport-briefly-shuts-due-to-n-koreas-trash-balloons-5971418]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korean Airport Briefly Shuts Due To N Korea's Trash Balloons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-koreas-incheon-airport-briefly-shuts-due-to-n-koreas-trash-balloons-5971418]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 09:23:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Takeoffs and landings at South Korea's Incheon International Airport were disrupted on Wednesday for about three hours before dawn because of balloons launched by North Korea filled with refuse, an airport spokesperson said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Takeoffs and landings at South Korea's Incheon International Airport were disrupted on Wednesday for about three hours before dawn because of balloons launched by North Korea filled with refuse, an airport spokesperson said.</p>

<p>One balloon landed on the tarmac near passenger Terminal 2 and the three runways at Incheon were temporarily shut down, the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>North Korea has flown balloons carrying trash into South Korea since late May, with hundreds landing in South Korea.</p>

<p>Several balloons were spotted in and around the airport boundaries, the spokesperson said, adding that this was not the first time operations at the airport - which is about 40km from the North Korean border - had been disrupted by balloons nearby.</p>

<p>The disruption to domestic and international flights occurred between 1:46 a.m. and 4:44 a.m., and the runways have re-opened since then, Incheon International Airport Corporation said.</p>

<p>Flight volume at that time of day is usually low. FlightRadar24 showed shows eight arriving cargo and passenger flights were diverted to South Korea's Cheongju or Jeju airports during that time, and one China Cargo freighter from Shanghai was diverted to Yantai, China.</p>

<p>Several more landings were delayed, and departures were delayed by several hours.</p>

<p>North Korea has said the balloons are retaliation for a propaganda campaign by North Korean defectors and activists in the South who regularly send over balloons carrying food, medicine, money and leaflets criticising the North's leaders.</p>

<p>Among the items carried by the North Korean balloons have been articles printed with Hello Kitty characters, badly worn clothing, and soil containing traces of human faeces and parasites, South Korea has said.</p>

<p>South Korea's military on Wednesday said about 100 balloons had fallen to the ground between Tuesday and Wednesday, mostly in the capital, Seoul, and the surrounding Gyeonggi province. Most of carried just scraps of paper.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3bthmlo_north-korea-balloon-_625x300_10_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[South Korea's military said about 100 balloons had fallen to the ground between Tuesday and Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>