<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 07:05:55 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/33-palestinians-killed-in-israeli-strike-in-gaza-6822465]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[33 Palestinians Killed In Israeli Strike In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/33-palestinians-killed-in-israeli-strike-in-gaza-6822465]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 05:27:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 33 Palestinians were killed on Friday evening by an Israeli airstrike on the Jabalia camp in the northern Gaza Strip, the Hamas-run Gaza government media office said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 33 Palestinians were killed on Friday evening by an Israeli airstrike on the Jabalia camp in the northern Gaza Strip, the Hamas-run Gaza government media office said.</p>

<p>Among the killed were 21 women, and total fatalities may reach 50 due to many victims trapped under rubble and buildings. The bombing injured over 85 people, some of whom sustained serious injuries, Xinhua news agency reported, citing a statement issued by the media office.</p>

<p>The Israeli army bombed several homes in Jabalia camp, it added.</p>

<p>The Israeli army has not yet commented on the incident.</p>

<p>Israel has been conducting a large-scale offensive against Hamas in the Gaza Strip to retaliate against a Hamas rampage through the southern Israeli border on October 7, 2023, during which about 1,200 people were killed and about 250 taken hostage.</p>

<p>The Palestinian death toll from ongoing Israeli attacks in the Gaza Strip has risen to 42,500, Gaza-based health authorities said in a statement on Friday.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d48qn25o_israel-gaza-war_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli army bombed several homes in Jabalia camp, it added.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-would-impose-tariffs-on-china-if-it-went-into-taiwan-6822358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says He Would Impose Tariffs On China If It Went Into Taiwan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-would-impose-tariffs-on-china-if-it-went-into-taiwan-6822358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 04:45:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told the Wall Street Journal that he would impose additional tariffs on China if China were to "go into Taiwan."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told the Wall Street Journal that he would impose additional tariffs on China if China were to "go into Taiwan."</p>

<p>"I would say: If you go into Taiwan, I'm sorry to do this, I'm going to tax you, at 150% to 200%," Trump was quoted as saying in the WSJ interview published on Friday evening.</p>

<p>Trump, asked if he would use military force against a blockade on Taiwan by China, said it would not come to that because Chinese President Xi Jinping respected him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f41du9is_donald-trump-afp_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump told the Wall Street Journal that he would impose tariffs on China if China were to go into Taiwan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-donald-trump-barnstorm-key-state-michigan-where-polls-say-theyre-tied-6822140]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris, Trump Barnstorm Key State Michigan, Where Polls Say They're Tied]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-donald-trump-barnstorm-key-state-michigan-where-polls-say-theyre-tied-6822140]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 03:23:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump barreled through the battleground state of Michigan on Friday, where opinion polls show the U.S. presidential candidates are essentially tied just 18 days before the Nov. 5 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump barreled through the battleground state of Michigan on Friday, where opinion polls show the U.S. presidential candidates are essentially tied just 18 days before the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>Former President Trump visited a campaign office in Hamtramck, where he heard praise from the Detroit suburb's first Muslim mayor, Amer Ghalib. Trump was seeking support from Arab Americans in Michigan disenchanted with Democrats, Vice President Harris and President Joe Biden over U.S. support for Israel in the Gaza conflict.</p>

<p>"We all ultimately want one thing. We want peace in the Middle East. We're going to get peace in the Middle East. It's going to happen very fast. It can happen with the right leadership in Washington," Trump said, without elaborating.</p>

<p>Later Trump was to speak in Auburn Hills, a city in Oakland County, north of Detroit, which Biden won by a comfortable margin in 2020. Trump will also return to Detroit - Michigan's largest city - for a rally around 7 p.m. (2300 GMT), after saying on Oct. 10 that the rest of the U.S. would turn into Detroit if Harris won.</p>

<p>Harris will speak in Grand Rapids, the heart of more conservative western Michigan, before heading east to Lansing and then Oakland County on Friday night.</p>

<p>The Midwestern state has about 8.4 million voters and would bring the winner 15 Electoral College votes out of the 270 needed to win, which in several scenarios would be a decisive number. Harris and Trump are battling fiercely for the state's Arab American, senior, union and working-class voters.</p>

<p>Both have sharpened their attacks in recent days.</p>

<p>On Friday, Trump falsely told the "Fox &amp; Friends" program that Harris is Marxist and renewed his attacks on her intelligence.</p>

<p>"I don't think she knows where she is. She's a low-IQ person. She's not smart," he said. Harris on Friday said reports that Trump was skipping interviews and another presidential debate because he was exhausted raised questions about his fitness for office.</p>

<p>"It should be a concern. If he can't handle the rigors of the campaign trail, is he fit to do the job?" she told reporters before a rally in Grand Rapids. "That's a legitimate question."</p>

<h2><strong>'I'M NOT EVEN TIRED'</strong></h2>

<p>Trump, talking to reporters as he arrived in Detroit, rejected such talk.</p>

<p>"I've gone 48 days now without a rest," Trump said.</p>

<p>"I'm not even tired. I'm really exhilarated. You know why? We're killing her in the polls, because the American people don't want her."</p>

<p>On Thursday, Harris said Trump was "gaslighting" the American public about the deadly attack by his loyalists on the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021. Trump recently called the assault a "day of love."</p>

<p>In Michigan and other crucial battleground states, either Harris or Trump holds a razor-thin margin over the other , according to public and internal campaign polls. That's worrying Democrats.</p>

<p>Trump won Michigan by 11,000 votes in 2016. In 2020, Biden beat Trump by 155,000 votes.</p>

<p>Harris is shifting the strategy of her whirlwind campaign to win over more Republicans and men of all races. She's also enlisting popular former first lady Michelle Obama, who will campaign for the vice president in Michigan on Oct. 26.</p>

<p>Nationally, Harris' edge has narrowed from a late September lead of 7 percentage points over Trump to just 3 points, Reuters/Ipsos polling shows, with high food and rent prices still worrying Americans and Trump amplifying fears related to migrants crossing the U.S.-Mexico border with increasingly extreme rhetoric.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9jf8rc3_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and Donald Trump barreled through the battleground state of Michigan on Friday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-and-iran-backed-foes-hamas-and-hezbollah-vow-more-war-after-yahya-sinwars-death-6822057]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel And Iran-Backed Foes Hamas And Hezbollah Vow More War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-and-iran-backed-foes-hamas-and-hezbollah-vow-more-war-after-yahya-sinwars-death-6822057]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 02:56:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pledges from Israel and enemies Hamas and Hezbollah to keep fighting in Gaza and Lebanon dashed hopes on Friday that the death of Palestinian militant leader Yahya Sinwar might hasten an end to more than a year of escalating war in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pledges from Israel and its enemies Iran-backed Hamas and Hezbollah to keep fighting in Gaza and Lebanon dashed hopes on Friday that the death of Palestinian militant leader Yahya Sinwar might hasten an end to more than a year of escalating war in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Israel's arch-foe and the militants' main backer Iran also said Sinwar's death would only fuel "the spirit of resistance".</p>

<p>Hamas leader Sinwar, a mastermind of the Oct. 7, 2023, attack that triggered the Gaza war, was killed by Israeli soldiers in the Palestinian enclave on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Video showed him tossing a stick at a drone as he sat dying.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called his killing a milestone but vowed to keep up the war, which in recent weeks expanded from fighting Hamas in Gaza into an invasion and pursuit of Hezbollah of Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The war, my dear ones, is not yet over," Netanyahu told Israelis late on Thursday, saying fighting would continue until hostages held by Hamas are released.</p>

<p>"We have before us a great opportunity to stop the axis of evil," he added, referring to Iran and its militant allies across the region, also in Syria, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Hamas said hostages would only be released with a halt of hostilities in Gaza, an Israeli withdrawal and the release of its prisoners.</p>

<p>"The martyrdom of our brother, the leader Yahya Sinwar ... will only increase the strength and resolve of Hamas and our resistance," it said, confirming his death.</p>

<p>That rhetoric from the warring parties contrasted with Western leaders, including U.S. President Joe Biden, who said Sinwar's death offered a chance for negotiations. Sinwar had been refusing talks, Washington said.</p>

<p>Israel's government has rejected several attempts by the United States, its main ally, at brokering ceasefires in both Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p>One senior diplomat working in Lebanon told Reuters that hopes Sinwar's death would end the war appeared misplaced.</p>

<p>"We had hoped, really throughout this, that getting rid of Sinwar would be the turning point where the wars would end ... where everyone would be ready to put their weapons down. It appears we were once again mistaken," the diplomat said.</p>

<p>Egypt's Foreign Minister Badr Abdelatty said he feared the war was only going to get worse.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, we are on the verge of a comprehensive regional war," he told state-affiliated Al-Qahera News TV channel. "There are parties keen on escalation."</p>

<p>He said international mediators - which included Egypt - had been close to reaching a ceasefire in Gaza but Israel lacked the political will.</p>

<p>Families of Israeli hostages said that while the killing of Sinwar was an achievement, it would not be complete while captives were still in Gaza.</p>

<p>The conflict has caused direct Iranian-Israeli confrontations, including missile attacks on Israel in April and on Oct. 1.</p>

<p>Netanyahu has vowed to respond to the October attack, though Washington has pressed it not to strike Iranian energy facilities or nuclear sites.</p>

<p>Biden, on a visit to Berlin on Friday, said there was a possibility of working towards a ceasefire in Lebanon but it would be harder in Gaza. He also told reporters he had an understanding of how and when Israel would respond to the missile attacks by Iran. He declined to elaborate.</p>

<h2><strong>TRACKED AND KILLED</strong></h2>

<p>Sinwar, Hamas' overall leader following the assassination of political chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran in July, was believed to have been hiding in the warren of tunnels Hamas has built under Gaza.</p>

<p>He was killed during a gun battle on Wednesday by Israeli troops initially unaware they had caught their number one enemy, Israeli officials said.</p>

<p>The military released drone video of what it said was Sinwar, sitting on an armchair and covered in dust inside a destroyed building. He was tracked by the drone as he lay dying, the video showed, desperately throwing a stick.</p>

<p>The Oct. 7, 2023 attacks he masterminded in Israel killed some 1,200 people, according to Israeli authorities. Israel has subsequently killed more than 42,000 people, according to Palestinian officials. Its offensive has made most of Gaza's 2.3 million people homeless, maimed tens of thousands, caused widespread hunger and destroyed hospitals and schools.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which began firing rockets at Israel in support of its Hamas ally on Oct. 8, is the target of Israel's intensifying assault on Lebanon, which has killed more than 2,000 people and displaced 1.2 million.</p>

<p>Israel has now killed several of Hamas' top leaders and in a matter of weeks decapitated the Hezbollah leadership, mainly through air strikes.</p>

<p>The killings have dealt a blow to what anti-Israeli forces call the Axis of Resistance: a group of proxy militant groups that Iran has spent decades supporting across the region.</p>

<p>Experts said the Palestinian militant group was likely to replace Sinwar with a new political leader based outside Gaza while his brother Mohammad Sinwar was expected to assume a bigger role directing the war against Israel in the territory.</p>

<p>Iran showed no sign Sinwar's killing would shift its support.</p>

<p>"The spirit of resistance will be strengthened," its mission to the United Nations said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah was also defiant, announcing "the transition to a new and escalating phase in the confrontation with Israel".</p>

<p>The Israeli military said on Friday it had also killed Muhammad Hassin Ramal, Hezbollah's commander of the Tayibe area in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni, visiting Beirut, called for the U.N. peacekeeping mission to Lebanon, known as UNIFIL, to be strengthened. Italy contributes troops to the force.</p>

<p>"I repeat that I consider targeting UNIFIL is unacceptable," Meloni told a joint news conference with Lebanese Prime Minister Najib Mikati, referring to recent Israeli attacks involving the mission's troops.</p>

<p>She said she planned to hold talks with Netanyahu after her visit to Lebanon and Jordan.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/stg0gkig_israel-hamas-war-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel and its enemies Iran-backed Hamas and Hezbollah vowed to keep fighting.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-launches-ai-that-can-monitor-other-ai-as-human-involvement-diminishes-6821994]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Launches AI That Can Monitor Other AI As Human Involvement Diminishes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-launches-ai-that-can-monitor-other-ai-as-human-involvement-diminishes-6821994]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 02:31:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facebook owner Meta said on Friday it was releasing a batch of new AI models from its research division, including a "Self-Taught Evaluator" that may offer a path toward less human involvement in the AI development process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facebook owner Meta said on Friday it was releasing a batch of new AI models from its research division, including a "Self-Taught Evaluator" that may offer a path toward less human involvement in the AI development process.</p>

<p>The release follows Meta's introduction of the tool in an August paper, which detailed how it relies upon the same "chain of thought" technique used by OpenAI's recently released o1 models to get it to make reliable judgments about models' responses.</p>

<p>That technique involves breaking down complex problems into smaller logical steps and appears to improve the accuracy of responses on challenging problems in subjects like science, coding and math.</p>

<p>Meta's researchers used entirely AI-generated data to train the evaluator model, eliminating human input at that stage as well.</p>

<p>The ability to use AI to evaluate AI reliably offers a glimpse at a possible pathway toward building autonomous AI agents that can learn from their own mistakes, two of the Meta researchers behind the project told Reuters.</p>

<p>Many in the AI field envision such agents as digital assistants intelligent enough to carry out a vast array of tasks without human intervention.</p>

<p>Self-improving models could cut out the need for an often expensive and inefficient process used today called Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback, which requires input from human annotators who must have specialized expertise to label data accurately and verify that answers to complex math and writing queries are correct.</p>

<p>"We hope, as AI becomes more and more super-human, that it will get better and better at checking its work, so that it will actually be better than the average human," said Jason Weston, one of the researchers.</p>

<p>"The idea of being self-taught and able to self-evaluate is basically crucial to the idea of getting to this sort of super-human level of AI," he said.</p>

<p>Other companies including Google and Anthropic have also published research on the concept of RLAIF, or Reinforcement Learning from AI Feedback. Unlike Meta, however, those companies tend not to release their models for public use.</p>

<p>Other AI tools released by Meta on Friday included an update to the company's image-identification Segment Anything model, a tool that speeds up LLM response generation times and datasets that can be used to aid the discovery of new inorganic materials.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k6ml1b5g_ai-generic-server-generic-ai-server-generic-pixabay_625x300_19_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta's researchers used entirely AI-generated data to train the evaluator model. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-intercepts-suspicious-aerial-target-approaching-from-syria-6821968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says Intercepts Suspicious 'Aerial Target' Approaching From Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-intercepts-suspicious-aerial-target-approaching-from-syria-6821968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 02:27:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said it had intercepted a suspicious "aerial target" approaching from Syria on Friday, which a war monitor said was a drone launched by an Iran-backed group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said it had intercepted a suspicious "aerial target" approaching from Syria on Friday, which a war monitor said was a drone launched by an Iran-backed group.</p>

<p>"A short while ago, a suspicious aerial target that approached Israeli territory from Syria was intercepted by the IAF (air force)... before it crossed into Israeli territory," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said the drone was launched by the Iran-backed Islamic Resistance in Iraq group.</p>

<p>"Israeli air defences in the occupied Syrian Golan targeted two drones launched by the Islamic Resistance in Iraq, coming from Iraq through Syrian territory," the war monitor said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Islamic Resistance in Iraq, a network of pro-Iran militias, has regularly claimed launching drones targeting Israel.</p>

<p>Israel is fighting a war on two fronts, one with Hezbollah in southern Lebanon, the other with Hamas in Gaza, while it also faces attacks from Iran-backed militants in Syria, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities rarely comment publicly about individual strikes or operations involving Syria, but have repeatedly said they will not allow Iran to expand its foothold in the region.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e9qjrljg_iran-attacks-on-israel_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Islamic Resistance in Iraq has regularly claimed launching drones targeting Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cuba-plunges-into-darkness-as-national-power-grid-fails-6821948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cuba Plunges Into Countrywide Darkness As National Power Grid Fails]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cuba-plunges-into-darkness-as-national-power-grid-fails-6821948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 02:20:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cuba plunged into a countrywide blackout on Friday after one of the island's major power plants failed and caused the national electrical grid to shut down, its energy ministry said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cuba plunged into a countrywide blackout on Friday after one of the island's major power plants failed and caused the national electrical grid to shut down, its energy ministry said.</p>

<p>The Communist-run government had already closed schools and non-essential industry and sent most state workers home in a last-ditch effort to keep the lights on during severe power shortages.</p>

<p>But shortly before midday, the Antonio Guiteras power plant, the country's largest and most efficient, went offline, prompting a total grid failure and leaving approximately 10 million people without power.</p>

<p>Officials did not say what had caused the plant to fail.</p>

<p>"There will be no rest until (power) is restored," Cuban President Miguel Diaz-Canel said on X.</p>

<p>The blackout marks a new low point on an island where life has become increasingly unbearable, with residents already suffering from shortages of food, fuel, water and medicine.</p>

<p>The electricity shortages had already prompted officials to cancel all non-vital government services on Friday. Schools, including universities, were shuttered through Sunday. Recreational and cultural activities, including night clubs, were also ordered closed.</p>

<p>Officials said in mid-afternoon they had begun taking steps to restore power but that the process would take time.</p>

<p>Virtually all commerce in the capital Havana ground to a halt on Friday. Many residents sat sweating on doorsteps. Tourists hunkered down in frustration.</p>

<p>"We went to a restaurant and they had no food because there was no power, now we are also without internet," said Brazilian tourist Carlos Roberto Julio, who had recently arrived in Havana. "In two days, we have already had several problems."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Manuel Marrero late on Thursday blamed worsening blackouts during the past several weeks on a perfect storm well-known to most Cubans - deteriorating infrastructure, fuel shortages and rising demand.</p>

<p>"The fuel shortage is the biggest factor," Marrero said in a televised message to the nation.</p>

<p>Strong winds that began with Hurricane Milton last week has crippled the island's ability to deliver scarce fuel from boats offshore to its power plants, officials said.</p>

<p>Cuba's government also blames the U.S. trade embargo, as well as new sanctions under former President Donald Trump, for difficulties in acquiring fuel and spare parts to operate its oil-fired plants.</p>

<p>"The complex scenario is caused primarily by the intensification of the economic war and financial and energy persecution of the United States," Diaz-Canel said on X on Thursday.</p>

<p>"The United States is not to blame for today's blackout on the island, or the overall energy situation in Cuba," a spokesperson for the White House National Security Council said.</p>

<h2><strong>REDUCED FUEL</strong></h2>

<p>While demand for electricity has grown alongside Cuba's private sector, fuel supply has evaporated.</p>

<p>Cuba's largest oil supplier, Venezuela, has reduced shipments to the island to an average of 32,600 barrels per day in the first nine months of the year, about half of the 60,000 bpd sent in the same period of 2023, according to vessel-monitoring data and internal shipping documents from Venezuela's state company PDVSA.</p>

<p>PDVSA, whose refining infrastructure is also ailing, has this year tried to avoid a new wave of fuel scarcity at home, leaving smaller volumes available for export to allied countries like Cuba.</p>

<p>Russia and Mexico, which in the past have sent fuel to Cuba, have also greatly reduced shipments to the island.</p>

<p>The shortfalls have left Cuba to fend for itself on the far costlier spot market at a time when its government is near-bankrupt.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1vru07hg_cuba-national-power-grid-fails-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cuba plunged into a countrywide blackout after the national power grid failed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-decades-later-first-brown-dwarf-ever-found-offers-a-surprise-6821778]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Decades Later, First Brown Dwarf Ever Found Offers A Surprise]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-decades-later-first-brown-dwarf-ever-found-offers-a-surprise-6821778]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 01:21:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In 1995, astronomers confirmed the discovery for the first time of a brown dwarf, a body too small to be a star and too big to be a planet - sort of a celestial tweener. But it turns out that was not the full story.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 1995, astronomers confirmed the discovery for the first time of a brown dwarf, a body too small to be a star and too big to be a planet - sort of a celestial tweener. But it turns out that was not the full story.</p>

<p>Researchers now have taken a fresh look at that brown dwarf and learned that it actually is not a single brown dwarf but rather two of them orbiting astonishingly close to each other while circling a small star. This was documented in two new studies using telescopes in Chile and Hawaii.</p>

<p>These two brown dwarfs are gravitationally locked to each other in what is called a binary system, an arrangement commonly observed among stars. So the brown dwarf that three decades ago was named Gliese 229B is now recognized as Gliese 229Ba, with a mass 38 times greater than our solar system's largest planet Jupiter, and Gliese 229Bb, with a mass 34 greater than Jupiter.</p>

<p>They are located 19 light-years from our solar system - rather close in cosmic terms - in the constellation Lepus. A light year is the distance light travels in a year, 5.9 trillion miles (9.5 trillion km).</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="An artist's illustration shows the nearest brown dwarf to Earth. ESO-I. Crossfield-N. Risinger/Handout via REUTERS" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3m7qdc7g_brown-dwarf-research-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpg" title="An artist's illustration shows the nearest brown dwarf to Earth. ESO-I. Crossfield-N. Risinger/Handout via REUTERS" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">An artist's illustration shows the nearest brown dwarf to Earth. ESO-I. Crossfield-N. Risinger/Handout via REUTERS</p>
</div>

<p>Binary brown dwarfs are a rarity. These two orbit each other every 12 days at a distance of only 16 times the separation between Earth and the moon. Only one other pair of brown dwarfs are known to orbit as close to each other as this twosome.</p>

<p>Brown dwarfs are neither a star nor a planet, but something in between. They could be considered wannabe stars that during their formative stages did not reach the mass necessary to ignite nuclear fusion at their core like a star. But they are more massive than the biggest planets.</p>

<p>"A brown dwarf is an object that fills the gap between a planet and a star. They are formally defined as objects that can burn a heavy form of hydrogen, called deuterium, but not the most common basic form of hydrogen," said Sam Whitebook, a graduate student in Caltech's division of physics, mathematics and astronomy and lead author of one of the studies, published in the Astrophysical Journal Letters.</p>

<p>"In practice, this means they range in mass from approximately 13 to 81 times the mass of Jupiter. Because they can't fuse hydrogen, they can't ignite the fusion channels that power most stars. This causes them to just glow dimly as they cool down," Whitebook said.</p>

<p>The year 1995 was big for astronomers, with the discovery of the first planet beyond our solar system - an exoplanet - also being announced. Until Gliese 229B's discovery, the existence of brown dwarfs had only been hypothesized. But there were anomalies about Gliese 229B, particularly after its mass was measured at about 71 times that of Jupiter.</p>

<p>"This didn't make any sense since an object of that mass would be much brighter than Gliese 229B," said Caltech astronomer Jerry Xuan, lead author of one of the studies, published in the journal Nature. "In fact, some models predict that objects with masses above 70 Jupiter masses fuse hydrogen and become stars, which was clearly not happening here."</p>

<p>The new observations were able to discern two separate brown dwarfs. They orbit a common type of star called a red dwarf with a mass about six-tenths that of our sun. While both brown dwarfs are more massive than Jupiter, their diameter is actually smaller than the gas giant planet because they are more dense.</p>

<p>"We still don't really know how different brown dwarfs form, and what the transition between a giant planet and a brown dwarf is. The boundary is fuzzy," Xuan said. "This finding also shows us that brown dwarfs can come in weird configurations that we were not expecting. This goes to show how complex and messy the star formation process is. We should always be open to surprises."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nctff5jc_first-brown-dward-research-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brown dwarfs named Gliese 229Ba and Gliese 229Bb are 19 light years from our solar system.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-have-a-lot-of-interest-in-indian-films-russia-president-vladimir-putin-praises-bollywood-6821574]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Have A Lot Of Interest In Indian Films": Putin Praises Bollywood]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-have-a-lot-of-interest-in-indian-films-russia-president-vladimir-putin-praises-bollywood-6821574]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:21:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Friday praised 'Bollywood' and said that Indian films are most popular in the country in a media briefing ahead of the BRICS Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Friday praised 'Bollywood' and said that Indian films are most popular in the country in a media briefing ahead of the BRICS Summit.</p>

<p>On being asked if Russia will give incentives to BRICS member states for shooting films in the country, Russian President Putin said, "If we look at BRICS member states, I think in this country Indian films are most popular. We have a special TV channel with Indian movies being shown on it round the clock. We have a lot of interest in Indian films. We hold the BRICS film festival. This year Moscow International Film Festival introduces films from BRICS nations. We are positive that if Indian films are interested then we will find some common ground and promote them in Russia. Pharmaceuticals will also be a good undertaking. I am ready to talk to the Prime Minister of India and we will come to terms and there will be no difficulty..."</p>

<p>Putin said that he would talk to his 'friend', Prime Minister Narendra Modi about this proposal and was confident that the two would come to terms.</p>

<p>"I'm ready to talk with our friend, the Prime Minister of India when he arrives in Kazan. I'm sure we will come to terms 100 per cent. No difficulties, I observe there... It would be fascinating to see not only Indian films but those featuring BRICS countries' actors representing their cultures, an Indian actor, a Chinese and Ethiopian actor. Well, you know, we discussed it with the colleagues from BRICS nations that we should organize a festival of theatrical art and we established the cinema academy," he said.</p>

<p>Notably, Bollywood movies are very famous in Russia, as both societies are arguably similar, and their tastes too appeared to match - they loved a rags-to-riches story about the underdog and a clear division between good and evil. The highest-grossing Indian film in the erstwhile Soviet Union was Disco Dancer (1982), written by Rahi Masoom Raza and starring actor Mithun Chakraborty. In terms of footfalls, the only Indian films estimated to have sold 100 million tickets overseas were Awaara and Disco Dancer.</p>

<p>Raj Kapoor was already a known cultural figure in Russia. When his movie Awaara came out in 1951, it immediately became a buzz in Russia. Moreover, The images of distant fabulous India inspired Russian thinkers, poets, composers, and artists. The influence of cultures was mutual -- the enormous spiritual influence that Leo Tolstoy had on the formation of the views of Mahatma Gandhi is well known.</p>

<p>Putin also said that he, alongwith other BRICS nations will create music festivals in the future.</p>

<p>"Jointly, we will pursue this track in future and popular music festivals also need to be created so there is an open field for work and we'll be interested and the media definitely outlets I think will gladly cover and participate," he said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will visit Russia at the invitation of Russian President Vladimir Putin from October 22-23 to attend the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dcvjqtfg_vladimir-putin_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[" We have a special TV channel with Indian movies being shown on it round the clock", Putin said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harriss-witty-reply-stumps-hecklers-backing-trump-crowd-applauds-6821476]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Harris's Witty Reply Stumps Hecklers Backing Trump, Crowd Applauds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harriss-witty-reply-stumps-hecklers-backing-trump-crowd-applauds-6821476]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat nominee Kamala Harris silenced disruptors at her rally in Wisconsin on Thursday by asking Trump supporters to "go to the smaller one down the street", and the video has gone viral.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat presidential nominee Kamala Harris silenced hecklers at her rally in Wisconsin by asking Donald Trump supporters who were disrupting her campaign to "go to the smaller one down the street", earning a big applause from the rest of the crowd gathered there.</p>

<p>On social media however, there were mixed reactions. One X user commented, "That's MY POTUS", while another claimed, "We know she set that up. It was fake. She's not a good actress!"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">That's MY POTUS!</p>
— Billie Nelson (@Mamabenergy2) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mamabenergy2/status/1847028228407566590?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We know she set that up. It was fake. She's not a good actress!</p>
— Lorrie Ann ?????? (@LorrieAnn25) <a href="https://twitter.com/LorrieAnn25/status/1847097920404824403?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 18, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>This took place when Harris slammed Donald Trump for his position on the sensitive topic of abortion and for his selection of Supreme Court appointees who further helped overrule Roe vs Wade.</p>

<p>While she was on the topic, 'Make America Great Again' or 'MAGA' supporters started shouting, "You lie, you lie!". Harris paused for a few seconds before retorting, "Oh you guys are at the wrong rally!", the crowd burst into applause and laughter.</p>

<p>Wisconsin is one of the seven key swing states that will put a nail on the coffin for this year's presidential elections and Harris' rally at La Crosse was her effort to bond with the people of the state while addressing key issues.</p>

<p>At another rally, she appealed to female voters, maintaining that Trump "has no idea" about women's healthcare and that "everybody did not want Roe vs Wade overturned", as Trump has asserted. She added, "Women are dying of sepsis because they did not get the healthcare they need. It just gets more unbelievable sometimes. And now the man calls himself the 'father of IVF'. I mean, what does that even mean?"</p>

<p>Donald Trump has a razor-thin advantage over Kamala Harris in Wisconsin, leading by less than one percentage point, according to the latest average of polls from Decision Desk HQ and The Hill.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dkob4plg_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris told Donald Trump supporters to "go to the smaller rally down the street"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-releases-ai-model-that-can-check-how-other-models-work-6821254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Releases AI Model That Can Check How Other Models Work]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-releases-ai-model-that-can-check-how-other-models-work-6821254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 23:19:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facebook owner Meta said on Friday it was releasing a batch of new AI models from its research division, including a "Self-Taught Evaluator" that may offer a path toward less human involvement in the AI development process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facebook owner Meta said on Friday it was releasing a batch of new AI models from its research division, including a "Self-Taught Evaluator" that may offer a path toward less human involvement in the AI development process.</p>

<p>The release follows Meta's introduction of the tool in an August paper, which detailed how it relies upon the same "chain of thought" technique used by OpenAI's recently released o1 models to get it to make reliable judgments about models' responses.</p>

<p>That technique involves breaking down complex problems into smaller logical steps and appears to improve the accuracy of responses on challenging problems in subjects like science, coding and math.</p>

<p>Meta's researchers used entirely AI-generated data to train the evaluator model, eliminating human input at that stage as well.</p>

<p>The ability to use AI to evaluate AI reliably offers a glimpse at a possible pathway toward building autonomous AI agents that can learn from their own mistakes, two of the Meta researchers behind the project told Reuters.</p>

<p>Many in the AI field envision such agents as digital assistants intelligent enough to carry out a vast array of tasks without human intervention.</p>

<p>Self-improving models could cut out the need for an often expensive and inefficient process used today called Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback, which requires input from human annotators who must have specialized expertise to label data accurately and verify that answers to complex math and writing queries are correct.</p>

<p>"We hope, as AI becomes more and more super-human, that it will get better and better at checking its work, so that it will actually be better than the average human," said Jason Weston, one of the researchers.</p>

<p>"The idea of being self-taught and able to self-evaluate is basically crucial to the idea of getting to this sort of super-human level of AI," he said.</p>

<p>Other companies including Google and Anthropic have also published research on the concept of RLAIF, or Reinforcement Learning from AI Feedback. Unlike Meta, however, those companies tend not to release their models for public use.</p>

<p>Other AI tools released by Meta on Friday included an update to the company's image-identification Segment Anything model, a tool that speeds up LLM response generation times and datasets that can be used to aid the discovery of new inorganic materials.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s6ovor1g_meta-ai_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta's researchers used entirely AI-generated data to train the evaluator model. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-searching-for-yahya-sinwars-replacement-outside-gaza-report-6821136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Searching For Yahya Sinwar's Replacement Outside Gaza: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-searching-for-yahya-sinwars-replacement-outside-gaza-report-6821136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 22:57:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Palestinian militant group Hamas will likely replace Yahya Sinwar with a new political leader based outside Gaza while his brother - Mohammad Sinwar - is expected to assume a bigger role directing the war against Israel in the territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Palestinian operator group Hamas will likely replace Yahya Sinwar with a new political leader based outside Gaza while his brother - Mohammad Sinwar - is expected to assume a bigger role directing the war against Israel in the territory, experts say.</p>

<p>In its leadership deliberations, Hamas must consider not only the preferences of its main backer - Iran - but also the interests of the Gulf Arab state of Qatar, where all the main candidates to take over as politburo chief currently reside.</p>

<p>Sinwar, a mastermind of the October 7, 2023 attack that ignited the devastating Gaza war, was killed by Israeli forces in a gunbattle on Wednesday -- the second time in less than three months that Hamas has lost its top leader.</p>

<p>Its previous chief, Ismail Haniyeh, was assassinated in Iran in July almost certainly by Israel.</p>

<p>When Sinwar replaced him, he fused together both the military and political leadership in Gaza, but that does not appear likely this time around.</p>

<p>After more than a year of ferocious Israeli attacks that have pounded Hamas, killed thousands of its fighters and eliminated senior figures both inside and out of Gaza, it is not clear how the Islamist group will emerge from this latest blow.</p>

<p>Sinwar's deputy Khalil Al-Hayya, who is viewed as a potential successor, struck a defiant note on Friday, saying Israeli hostages would not be returned until Israeli troops withdrew from Gaza and the war ended.</p>

<p>Hamas has a history of quickly and efficiently replacing its fallen leaders, with its top decision-making body, the Shura Council, tasked with naming a new head.</p>

<p>The Shura Council represents all Hamas members in the Gaza Strip, the West Bank, Israeli prisons and the Palestinian community, meaning the new leader should have the authority to enter ceasefire talks even if he is not in Gaza, where Hamas gunmen still hold dozens of Israelis hostage.</p>

<p>Besides Hayya, who is Hamas' chief negotiator, the other main leadership contenders are Khaled Meshaal, Haniyeh's predecessor, and Mohammad Darwish, a little-known figure who chairs the Shura Council, according to analysts and a Hamas source.</p>

<p>Hamas will need to notify Qatar, which has played a major role in rounds of so far fruitless ceasefire talks, and other regional capitals ahead of its decision, the source said.</p>

<p><strong>Dividing Duties</strong></p>

<p>Ashraf Abouelhoul, an expert on Palestinian affairs, expected Sinwar's responsibilities to be split between two roles - one overseeing military affairs and another running the political office, responsible for international contacts and shaping policies.</p>

<p>"Iran is Hamas strongest ally, which supports the group with money and weapons, and their blessing is key to who becomes Sinwar's successor," said Abouelhoul, managing editor of the state-owned newspaper Al-Ahram in Egypt.</p>

<p>He expected Hamas to stick by core demands in future ceasefire talks, chiefly that Israeli forces withdraw from Gaza and stop the war. But it could show more flexibility on some conditions, such as the details of any deal swapping Israeli hostages for Palestinians imprisoned by Israel.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has declared Sinwar's killing a milestone but that the war is not yet over, saying fighting would continue until the hostages are released.</p>

<p>Hamas was founded in 1987 and is a branch of the Sunni Islamist Muslim Brotherhood movement. Its decisions are usually taken through consensus in Hamas institutions.</p>

<p>With Sinwar dead, the Hamas leadership for Gaza has temporarily passed to his Qatar-based deputy, Hayya.</p>

<p>But the ongoing war and communication difficulties might impose limits on just how much day-to-day contact Hayya can have with men on the ground, leaving the armed wing - the Qassam Brigades - in the driving seat, experts say.</p>

<p>A Hamas source said Hayya was expected to encounter no problems exercising his role as "de facto Gaza leader". The source noted that Hayya had maintained good relations with the military wing and had been close to both Sinwar and Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Akram Attallah, a Palestinian political analyst, said he expected the armed wing to respect Hayya's authority - even from afar. He also expected Mohammad Sinwar to emerge as a more significant figure in the armed wing and in Hamas in general.</p>

<p>A veteran commander of the Qassam Brigades, Mohammad Sinwar has seldom appeared in public, has long been on Israel's most-wanted list and has survived several attempts on his life, Hamas sources said.</p>

<p>Hamas-led gunmen killed 1,200 people and abducted another 250 during the Oct. 7 attack, according to Israeli tallies. This prompted an Israeli offensive which, according to Palestinian authorities, has killed more than 42,000 Palestinians, laid waste to Gaza, and driven nearly all its population from their homes.</p>

<p>Sinwar's appointment in August was seen as both a show of defiance and internal unity by Hamas.</p>

<p>His close ties to Iran were seen as a factor supporting his candidacy. Both Darwish and Hayya are also seen as close to Tehran, whose support will be vital for Hamas to recover after the war.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the prospects of the prominent former Hamas leader Khaled Meshaal have been clouded by a record of friction with Tehran after his support for the Sunni Muslim-led revolt in 2011 against Syrian President Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<p>Attallah said Hayya's ties to Iran stood him in better stead than Meshaal. But if Iran softened its opposition to Meshaal, he may have a chance, he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/158kral_yahya-sinwar_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar's deputy Khalil Al-Hayya is viewed as a potential successor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-and-michelle-obama-team-up-with-kamala-harris-in-historic-campaign-appearance-6820643]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Obamas And Kamala Harris Team Up In Historic Campaign Appearance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-and-michelle-obama-team-up-with-kamala-harris-in-historic-campaign-appearance-6820643]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 22:55:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With just three weeks remaining in the presidential campaign, the polls still find it to be an even-steven affair. Harris hopes to tap into some political charisma from the Obamas, especially with her losing ground to Trump as polls suggest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With just three weeks remaining in the presidential campaign, the polls still suggest it to be an even-steven situation. Kamala Harris hopes to tap into some political charisma from the Obamas, especially with her losing ground to Donald Trump as the latest polls suggest.</p>

<h2><strong>HARRIS, TRUMP NECK-AND-NECK</strong></h2>

<p>As per the latest three polls on Sunday, Kamala Harris's lead has gone southward in the final dash to the election in November. According to the latest NBC News poll, the Democratic and Republican nominees are currently deadlocked in national polls, with each holding 48% support, just ahead of the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Harris is currently leading Trump by a narrow margin of 50% to 48% among likely voters, according to the latest ABC News/Ipsos poll, and the latest CBS News/YouGov poll reveals a tight presidential race, with Kamala Harris holding a narrow lead over Donald Trump among likely voters, 51% to 48%.</p>

<p>To support Harris in her political endeavor, the Obamas are set to hit the campaign trail in separate events starting next week as they are still significantly popular with the Democratic base and hope to drive turnout in the swing states.</p>

<p>On 26th October in Michigan, former first lady Michelle Obama will campaign alongside Kamala Harris this election season and former president Barack Obama will also be seen with her next Thursday in Georgia. Apart from this, he is also set to visit other states solo.</p>

<h3><strong>OBAMA FACES FURY</strong></h3>

<p>The polls have been notably concerning for the Democrats, and although Harris is leading among women of all races, she is struggling to get considerable buttress from men, including Hispanics and African Americans. Obama had addressed this quandary for which he drew some backlash.</p>

<p>He had rebuked Black men for not showing as much enthusiasm to Harris as he had received back in 2008 and 2012 and firmly urged them to support the idea of a woman being president.</p>

<p>"You're coming up with all kinds of reasons and excuses, I've got a problem with that," Obama said at a campaign rally in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. "Because part of it makes me think - and I'm speaking to men directly - part of it makes me think that, well, you just aren't feeling the idea of having a woman as president, and you're coming up with other alternatives and other reasons for that."</p>

<p>Obama also posted on X saying, ".@KamalaHarris has spent her life fighting on behalf of people who need a voice and a chance – and she's going to keep fighting for you. That's the kind of person I'm proud to vote for and that's the kind of president that we need."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">.<a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> has spent her life fighting on behalf of people who need a voice and a chance – and she's going to keep fighting for you. That's the kind of person I'm proud to vote for and that's the kind of president that we need. <a href="https://t.co/IGbZfR5TJA">pic.twitter.com/IGbZfR5TJA</a></p>
— Barack Obama (@BarackObama) <a href="https://twitter.com/BarackObama/status/1847025764929015846?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Kamala Harris was a strong supporter of Barack Obama's presidential run back in 2008, and now the tables have turned. As the Democratic Party's standard-bearer for the 2024 election, Harris is receiving behind-the-scenes support from Obama himself.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1pbfhqts_barack-obama-kamala-harris-obama-harris-getty_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama and Michelle Obama will jon Kamala Harris on Campaign in key election push]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-teen-arrested-for-allegedly-planning-isis-inspired-terror-attack-6820858]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore Teen Arrested For Allegedly Planning ISIS-Inspired Terror Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-teen-arrested-for-allegedly-planning-isis-inspired-terror-attack-6820858]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 22:08:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Singapore has arrested a teenage boy who was allegedly planning an ISIS-inspired terror attack on a busy suburb, the interior minister said Friday, adding it was a "very close shave".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singapore has arrested a teenage boy who was allegedly planning an ISIS-inspired terror attack on a busy suburb, the interior minister said Friday, adding it was a "very close shave".</p>

<p>After watching Islamic State propaganda glorifying knife attacks, the 17-year-old visited the suburb to rehearse his attack before he was arrested in August, Home Minister K. Shanmugam said.</p>

<p>"He was quite serious because he actually practised stabbing motions with the scissors. He checked out which place would cause death -- basically the neck area -- so he practised hitting at the neck," Shanmugam told reporters.</p>

<p>"I would say this was a very close shave. It is very fortunate that ISD (Internal Security Department) arrested him in time."</p>

<p>The teenager, detained under the Internal Security Act, had allegedly planned a stabbing spree to coincide with school holidays in September when the area would be teeming with people.</p>

<p>In a statement released on Friday, ISD said the teenager was exposed to the deluge of online extremist materials posted by the Islamic State group after Hamas' attack on Israel on October 7 last year.</p>

<p>"He joined various online groups which provided updates on ISIS's activities and bought into ISIS's rhetoric of promoting the use of violence to establish an Islamic caliphate," ISD said.</p>

<p>By January, "the youth had become a staunch ISIS supporter and aspired to die as a martyr while fighting for the group," it added.</p>

<p>He took a pledge of allegiance to IS and intended to travel to Syria to fight there, according to ISD.</p>

<p>The teenager acted alone as he was unable to radicalise other people, ISD added.</p>

<p>His family noticed him watching videos of radical preachers and advised him to stop, but he continued, using "codewords" when discussing his beliefs online, the department said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-11/singapore-policeman-afp_650x400_71446877230.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The teenager was detained under Internal Security Act. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/timebomb-damaged-ship-carrying-explosive-cargo-stranded-in-north-sea-for-weeks-6820748]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Damaged Ship Carrying Explosive Cargo Stranded In North Sea For Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/timebomb-damaged-ship-carrying-explosive-cargo-stranded-in-north-sea-for-weeks-6820748]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 21:48:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A damaged ship, spurned by European ports because of its potentially explosive cargo, has been stranded in the North Sea for weeks while authorities work out what to do with it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A damaged ship, spurned by European ports because of its potentially explosive cargo, has been stranded in the North Sea for weeks while authorities work out what to do with it.</p>

<p>The Maltese-flagged Ruby is the latest example of an unwanted vessel left in limbo because no-one dares to handle it. Such vessels, sometimes nicknamed "timebombs", remain stuck for weeks, even months.</p>

<p>Ruby, a Handymax bulk carrier, has 20,000 tonnes of ammonium nitrate on board. That is more than seven times the amount of ammonium nitrate -- used in fertilisers as well as in explosives -- that detonated in Lebanon in 2020, devastating the port of Beirut.</p>

<p>After the vessel set off from the Russian port of Kandalaksha on August 22, it ran into a storm in the Barents Sea and limped, damaged, into the Norwegian port of Tromso for damage inspection.</p>

<p>It was subsequently ordered to leave and proceed with the aid of a tug to another port elsewhere for repairs.</p>

<p>It was turned away by Lithuania, which insisted the ship must offload its volatile cargo first, and continued southwards.</p>

<p>Since September 25, it has been anchored off southeastern England near the Dover Strait, which is one of world's busiest shipping lanes.</p>

<p><strong>Combustion agent</strong></p>

<p>British coastguards said the Ruby was seaworthy, stressing: "The vessel has appropriate safety certificates approved by the vessel's flag state and is able to make its own way."</p>

<p>But it has remained stuck in mooring since September, with its mainly Syrian crew still on board.</p>

<p>The Ruby's Dubai-based managers said they hoped to offload the cargo in a UK port so the vessel could be put in dry dock for repairs.</p>

<p>"It has been logistically challenging to find an adequate solution, which partly explains the delay," the managing company told AFP.</p>

<p>Ports willing to accept a potentially hazardous load are few and far between.</p>

<p>"People associate it (the Ruby) with Beirut but I think it's entirely possible to manage this situation," said Eric Slominski, an expert in shipping dangerous goods.</p>

<p>The Ruby's cargo was destined to make fertiliser while the ammonium nitrate in Beirut had been specifically intended to manufacture explosives, he pointed out.</p>

<p>"It's not a product you can mess around with but it isn't explosive," Nicolas Tanic, from French marine pollution organisation Cedre, said of the Ruby's cargo.</p>

<p>"It's a combustion agent for fuelling fires," said Tanic, whose organisation has analysed the ship's load.</p>

<p><strong>Erika disaster</strong></p>

<p>He said the chemical compound's Russian origins and haunting memories of the Beirut port disaster had triggered alarm and a media frenzy.</p>

<p>But the French shipowners' body said ports could have other reasons too for spurning the Ruby.</p>

<p>"If a vessel gets grounded in your channel, it shuts your port. If it grounds at one of your docks, the dock's unusable for a couple of months. It's a big risk to accept a vessel in difficulty," said managing director Laurent Martens.</p>

<p>In addition, unloading a cargo like the Ruby's is a lengthy operation that "costs hundreds of thousands of euros", Martens explained.</p>

<p>In the wake of the Erika disaster in 1999 -- when an oil tanker of that name broke apart off the western coast of France -- the European Union tightened its laws on maritime safety.</p>

<p>The Erika spilled around 20,000 tonnes of heavy fuel oil into the sea, polluting 400 kilometres (250 miles) of coastline and killing between 150,000 and 300,000 seabirds.</p>

<p>EU states are now required to provide places of refuge for ships in distress to avoid environmental pollution.</p>

<p>But the rules are subject to interpretation.</p>

<p>In 2012, France denied access to the MSC Flaminia for a month while it drifted, crewless, off the coast of Brittany after a fire on board the ship, which was carrying 151 containers labelled "dangerous" goods.</p>

<p>The stricken vessel was ultimately towed to the Germany port of Wilhelmshaven.</p>

<p>In 2015, the same North Sea port provided haven to the Purple Beach, which had burst into flames with 5,000 tonnes of fertiliser on board.</p>

<p>The Purple Beach spent nearly two years in Germany while it was inspected and the authorities cast around for somewhere to send the fertiliser.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d7s6fc38_ship-generic-unsplash_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ruby, a Handymax bulk carrier, has 20,000 tonnes of ammonium nitrate on board. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-next-for-hamas-after-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-killing-6820429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Can Hamas Recover After Yahya Sinwar's Killing? What Experts Say]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-next-for-hamas-after-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-killing-6820429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 20:54:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar dealt a huge blow to the Palestinian group, and while it leaves a gaping void at the top of the movement, its militants remain determined to fight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar dealt a huge blow to the Palestinian group, and while it leaves a gaping void at the top of the movement, its militants remain determined to fight.</p>

<p>Sinwar masterminded the October 7, 2023 attack on Israel that sparked the Gaza war, and became the leader of Hamas in August after the death of his predecessor, Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>While Israel has hailed Sinwar's killing as a major win, analysts say Hamas could use his legacy to mobilise a new generation of militants, who grew up suffering the consequences of Israel's retaliatory war.</p>

<p>Here is a look at what could come next for Hamas.</p>

<p><strong>How harsh a blow?</strong></p>

<p>Confirming Sinwar's death in a video statement on Friday, Hamas official Khalil al-Hayya said the group was mourning the loss of its "great leader".</p>

<p>Sinwar's killing was not just "an extremely symbolic event" but created "a leadership vacuum in this very networked organisation", Middle East analyst Andreas Krieg of King's College London said.</p>

<p>His death comes little more than two months after the death in Iran of Hamas's political chief Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Hamas and Iran have blamed Israel for Haniyeh's death, though Israel has not offered comment.</p>

<p>Krieg said differences had emerged between Hamas's political leadership, in exile mostly in Qatar, and the military and operational wings in Gaza.</p>

<p>In July Israel also said it killed Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif in Gaza, which Hamas has denied.</p>

<p>"Different cells of Hamas will continue fighting, but at the core of the movement, there's a vacuum there, and that will make it very difficult to coordinate," Krieg said.</p>

<p>James Dorsey, of the National University of Singapore's Middle East Institute, said Sinwar was an "exceptional" figure in Hamas who enjoyed "broad support within the movement from both the political and the military wing".</p>

<p><strong>Who could replace Sinwar?</strong></p>

<p>Following his predecessor's death, Sinwar emerged from a field of contenders for the Hamas leadership that included relative moderates based outside of Gaza like Musa Abu Marzuk, an adviser and negotiator seen as close to Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Dorsey said other exiled Hamas figures like Qatar-based Hayya, close to Sinwar and lead negotiator in unsuccessful talks for a Gaza truce and hostage exchange, could once again become contenders for the top post.</p>

<p>Other exiled leaders who could take over, he said, include Khaled Meshaal, who served as Hamas chief until he was replaced by Haniyeh in 2017.</p>

<p>Sinwar's selection as leader over members of its political wing in August was widely viewed as a restructuring of the movement around armed struggle, with the focus on the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Krieg said "the next leader is inevitably going to be someone from the operational level".</p>

<p>Should the leadership be handed to a man on the battlefield, one name has emerged as a favourite: that of Sinwar's younger brother Mohammed Sinwar.</p>

<p>Krieg said the brother "doesn't have the charismatic leadership appeal that Yahya had. But he has a good reputation... as a militant and fighter."</p>

<p><strong>Can Hamas recover?</strong></p>

<p>In his defiant statement on Friday, Hayya said Sinwar's death would help strengthen the movement, adding his killing had set him among "the leaders and symbols of the movement who preceded him".</p>

<p>Krieg said that, despite a "tactical, operational defeat" for Hamas with the killing of its leader, Sinwar's death was "not going to change armed resistance against Israel within Gaza".</p>

<p>Dorsey said Hamas was a movement that had "as a matter of principle proven very resilient".</p>

<p>"Hamas's history... is a history of Israel assassinating its leaders. Yahya Sinwar joins the list," he added.</p>

<p>The killed leader's legacy would "obviously" be tied to the legacy of the October 7 attack, said Dorsey.</p>

<p>But whether the war sparked by the attack could continue to swell Hamas's ranks has as much to do with the sheer levels of desperation in Gaza as it does with Sinwar.</p>

<p>"This is a generation that has lost all hope... certainly in Gaza. If you have no hope, you've got nothing and nowhere to go, you've got nothing to lose," Dorsey said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7464fuuo_yahya-sinwar_650x400_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Analysts say Hamas could use Yahya Sinwar's legacy to mobilise a new generation of militants. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australias-northern-territory-to-resume-jailing-10-year-olds-to-reduce-youth-crime-rates-6820198]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia's Northern Territory To Soon Resume Jailing 10-Year-Olds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australias-northern-territory-to-resume-jailing-10-year-olds-to-reduce-youth-crime-rates-6820198]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 20:21:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Australian Northern Territory (NT) will soon allow children as young as 10 to be jailed again, after a reversal of the previous government's decision to raise the age of criminal responsibility to 12.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Northern Territory (NT) will soon allow children as young as 10 to be jailed again, after a reversal of the previous government's decision to raise the age of criminal responsibility to 12. According to the <em>BBC</em>, the new Country Liberal Party (CLP) government, which was elected in August, said a reversal is necessary to reduce youth crime rates. It argued that returning the age to 10 will ultimately protect children, even though doctors, human rights organisations and Indigenous groups have disputed this logic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cpqz8gyp500o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC</em></a>, the Australian Northern Territory already jails children at a rate 11 times higher than any other jurisdiction in the country. Critics have said that this new law will not reduce crime, instead, it will disproportionately affect Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander children.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro said her government had been given a mandate after their landslide election victory, and that the change would allow courts to put young offenders through programmes designed to address the root causes of their crimes - which, according to statistics, are most commonly break-in and assault offences.</p>

<p>"We have this obligation to the child who has been let down in a number of ways, over a long period of time," Ms Finocchiaro told the parliament on Thursday. "And we have [an obligation to] the people who just want to be safe, people who don't want to live in fear anymore," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moreover, the NT has also tightened bail rules and introduced penalties for "posting and boasting" about crime on social media. "We make no apologies for delivering on our commitments to reduce crime for all Territorians," Ms Finocchiaro said.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/company-hacked-after-accidentally-hiring-north-korean-cyber-criminal-for-remote-job-6819772">Company Hacked After Accidentally Hiring North Korean Cyber Criminal For Remote Job</a></strong></p>

<p>Opposition Leader Selena Uibo, however, called it a "dark day" for the territory. "We know - because all of the evidence tells us this - that the earlier a child comes into contact with the criminal justice system, the more prolonged their involvement is likely to be," she said.</p>

<p>"We want to see children held accountable for bad behaviour but then supported to get on a better path," Ms Uibo added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the change will come into effect at a later date that is yet to be confirmed. Only the Australian Capital Territory has raised the age of criminal responsibility above 10. Victoria has passed legislation to do so, which will come into effect next year. The Tasmanian government has also said it will raise the age to 14 by 2029.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/c9cdh8ao_us-prison-generic-us-jail-generic-getty_625x300_24_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The change will come into effect at a later date. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-conflict-india-dispatches-11-tons-of-medical-aid-to-lebanon-amid-tensions-in-ukraine-6819896]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Dispatches 11 Tons Of Medical Aid To Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-conflict-india-dispatches-11-tons-of-medical-aid-to-lebanon-amid-tensions-in-ukraine-6819896]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 19:36:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Friday dispatched the first tranche of 11 tons of medical supplies to Lebanon as part of a humanitarian effort to support the nation amid rising tensions and the ongoing conflict in southern Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Friday dispatched the first tranche of 11 tons of medical supplies to Lebanon as part of a humanitarian effort to support the nation amid rising tensions and the ongoing conflict in southern Lebanon. A total of 33 tons of medical supplies are being sent.</p>

<p>Randhir Jaiswal, the official spokesperson for the MEA, posted on X (formerly Twitter), "India sends humanitarian assistance to Lebanon. A total of 33 tons of medical supplies are being sent. The first tranche of 11 tons of medical supplies was dispatched today. The consignment comprises of a wide range of pharmaceutical products, including cardiovascular medications, NSAIDs (non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs), anti-inflammatory agents, antibiotics and anaesthetics."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?? sends humanitarian assistance to Lebanon.<br />
<br />
A total of 33 tons of medical supplies are being sent. First tranche of 11 tons of medical supplies was dispatched today.<br />
<br />
The consignment comprises of a wide range of pharmaceutical products, including cardiovascular medications,… <a href="https://t.co/h35wcaeFHD">pic.twitter.com/h35wcaeFHD</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1847218544679014872?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to the post, this is the first tranche of the 33-ton consignment, which includes cardiovascular medications, NSAIDs, anti-inflammatory agents, antibiotics, and anaesthetics. The remaining supplies are expected to follow in the coming days, marking a significant step in India's commitment to aiding Lebanon during this crisis.</p>

<p>Amid escalating violence in southern Lebanon, India has reiterated its strong stance on the safety of United Nations peacekeepers, particularly the personnel stationed along the Blue Line, which separates Lebanon from Israel. With multiple attacks reported on UNIFIL premises, Jaiswal emphasised the nation's concern.</p>

<p>"We take the safety of peacekeepers very seriously. We have called for all action to be taken to maintain the safety of the UNIFIL premises," Jaiswal said during a press conference. India has further confirmed that none of its troops are stationed along the Blue Line but continues to monitor the situation closely.</p>

<p>India's response comes amid growing concerns over the safety of peacekeepers, especially following the recent injury of two Indonesian UNIFIL peacekeepers due to Israeli tank fire. The MEA issued a statement saying, "We are concerned at the deteriorating security situation along the Blue Line. We continue to monitor the situation closely."</p>

<p>The statement also reiterated that the "inviolability of UN premises must be respected by all, and appropriate measures taken to ensure the safety of UN peacekeepers and the sanctity of their mandate."</p>

<p>The situation has drawn international attention, with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu calling on UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres to withdraw peacekeeping forces, citing Hezbollah's growing influence in the region.</p>

<p>UNIFIL, which has been operational in the region since 1978, recently renewed its mandate for another year, stressing the importance of protecting its peacekeepers as violence continues to escalate in southern Lebanon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bo69opl_india-aid-ukraine_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the post, this is the first tranche of the 33-ton consignment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/company-hacked-after-accidentally-hiring-north-korean-cyber-criminal-for-remote-job-6819772]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Company Hacked After Accidentally Hiring North Korean Cyber Criminal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/company-hacked-after-accidentally-hiring-north-korean-cyber-criminal-for-remote-job-6819772]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 19:20:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A company recently found itself in a difficult situation after it accidentally hired a North Korean IT worker, who later stole sensitive data and attempted to extort the company after being fired.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A company recently found itself in a difficult situation after it accidentally hired a North Korean IT worker, who later stole sensitive data and attempted to extort the company after being fired. According to the <em>BBC</em>, the unidentified firm, which is based in the UK, US and Australia, hired the North Korean cyber criminal after he faked his employment history and personal details. He was hired in the summers as a contractor and worked for the firm for four months. Once he had access to the company's computer network, he downloaded sensitive company data and sent a ransom demand.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8vedz4yk7o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC </em></a>reported that the man used the firm's remote working tools to log into the corporate network. He then secretly downloaded as much company data as possible as soon as he had gained access to internal systems.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Once the company fired him for poor performance, it reportedly received emails containing some of the stolen data and a demand to be paid a six-figure sum in cryptocurrency. If the company did not pay, the hacker said he would publish or sell the stolen information online.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The company did not wish to be named. It also did not disclose whether they paid the ransom or not. However, the firm allowed cyber responders from Secureworks to report the hack to spread awareness and warn others.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Secureworks reported that this incident is the latest in a string of cases of Western remote workers being unmasked as North Koreans. Once hired, these cyber criminals use their employee access to download sensitive company data. In some cases, they use the data to extort their former employers.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organ-donor-in-us-wakes-up-on-operating-table-as-doctors-prepare-to-remove-his-heart-6819128">Organ Donor In US Wakes Up On Operating Table As Doctors Prepare To Remove His Heart&nbsp;</a></strong></p>

<p>Cybersecurity authorities have been warning about the rise of North Korean infiltrators since 2022. The US and South Korea have also accused North Korea of tasking thousands of staff to take on multiple well-paid Western roles remotely to earn money for the regime and avoid sanctions. However, according to Rafe Pilling, Director of Threat Intelligence at Secureworks, secret IT workers turning on their employers with cyber attacks is rare.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is a serious escalation of the risk from fraudulent North Korean IT worker schemes," Mr Pilling was quoted as saying by the <em>BBC</em>. "No longer are they just after a steady pay check, they are looking for higher sums, more quickly, through data theft and extortion, from inside the company defences."</p>

<p>Authorities warned employers to be vigilant about new hired if they are fully remote.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/7u5267bg_hacker-generic_625x300_20_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It is not clear whether the company paid the demanded ransom. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kyiv-says-bodies-of-501-ukrainian-soldiers-killed-fighting-russia-returned-6819700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kyiv Says Bodies Of 501 Ukrainian Soldiers Killed Fighting Russia Returned]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kyiv-says-bodies-of-501-ukrainian-soldiers-killed-fighting-russia-returned-6819700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 19:11:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kyiv said Friday it had received the bodies of 501 servicemen killed fighting Russian forces, mainly in eastern Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kyiv said Friday it had received the bodies of 501 servicemen killed fighting Russian forces, mainly in eastern Ukraine.</p>

<p>The exchange of prisoners and bodies of killed military personnel remains one of the few areas of cooperation between Moscow and Kyiv since Russia invaded in 2022.</p>

<p>"As a result of repatriation measures, 501 bodies of fallen Ukrainian defenders were returned to Ukraine," the Coordination Headquarters for the Treatment of Prisoners of War said in a statement.</p>

<p>The announcement represents one of the largest repatriations of killed Ukrainian servicemen since the beginning of the war.</p>

<p>Most of the bodies were returned from the eastern Donetsk region, said the agency. Russian forces have been advancing steadily there since their capture of the industrial hub of Avdiivka in February.</p>

<p>Several state bodies had helped coordinate the return including the defence forces, the agency added, acknowledging the help of the International Committee of the Red Cross.</p>

<p>"Representatives of law enforcement agencies and forensic experts will identify the victims," the coordination centre said in its statement.</p>

<p>"After identification, the bodies of our defenders will be handed over to their families for a proper burial."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/0ghrt3i_russia-ukraine-war-afp_625x300_19_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Most of the bodies were returned from the eastern Donetsk region (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>