<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:57:16 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthis-pledge-huge-response-to-israel-strike-as-gaza-violence-spreads-6154876]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Houthis Pledge "Huge" Response to Israel Strike As Gaza Violence Spreads]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthis-pledge-huge-response-to-israel-strike-as-gaza-violence-spreads-6154876]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 17:54:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthi rebels promised a "huge" retaliation against Israel on Sunday following a deadly strike on the port of Hodeida, as violence sparked by the Gaza war gripped the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Houthi rebels promised a "huge" retaliation against Israel on Sunday following a deadly strike on the port of Hodeida, as violence sparked by the Gaza war gripped the region.</p>

<p>Israel bombed the Palestinian territory, Lebanon and Yemen in quick succession this week in response to attacks from Iran-backed militant groups.</p>

<p>Despite Washington asserting that a deal to end more than nine months of devastating war between Israel and Gaza rulers Hamas was near the "goal line", the Israeli military said it intercepted a missile fired from Yemen as it pressed on with its offensive in the besieged Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Dozens have been killed since Saturday across Gaza, the civil defence agency said, including in strikes on homes in the central Nuseirat and Bureij areas and displaced people near southern Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>Residents said a major operation was underway in the Saudi district west of Rafah in the south, reporting heavy artillery and clashes.</p>

<p>The deadly strikes in Gaza came hours after Hezbollah and its ally Hamas said they fired at Israeli positions from south Lebanon, while Yemen's Houthi rebels vowed to respond to Israeli warplanes hitting a key port.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Houthi military spokesperson Yahya Saree said the rebel's &nbsp;"response to the Israeli aggression against our country is inevitably coming and will be huge."</p>

<h2>Fire still raging</h2>

<p>The fire left raging by the strikes on rebel-held Hodeida port "is seen across the Middle East and the significance is clear," Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Saturday.</p>

<p>The Houthis control swathes of Yemen, including much of its Red Sea coast, while the internationally recognised government has withdrawn to Aden on the south coast.</p>

<p>Detailing the first strikes claimed by Israel in Yemen, Gallant warned of further operations if the Houthis "dare to attack us" after a rebel drone strike killed one in Tel Aviv on Friday.</p>

<p>In Hodeida, three people were killed and 87 wounded, health officials said in a statement carried by Houthi media.</p>

<p>Firefighters struggled to contain the massive blaze caused by the strike on Hodeida, with a port employee saying fuel storage tanks and a power plant were still on fire on Sunday.</p>

<p>Following the strikes, the Israeli military said on Sunday it had intercepted a missile fired from Yemen towards the Red Sea resort town of Eilat. Saree said the rebels had fired ballistic missiles towards the port city.</p>

<h2>Netanyahu travels to Washington</h2>

<p>The trio of militant groups has vowed to keep up attacks on Israel until a truce ends the violence in Gaza, which lies in ruins, with most residents forced to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The Gaza war was triggered by Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza, including 42 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's military retaliation to wipe out Hamas has killed at least 38,983 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-ruled Gaza.</p>

<p>The war has also unleashed hunger and health crises in Gaza, with Israel and the United Nations trading blame for vital aid supplies failing to reach those in need.</p>

<p>After the detection of poliovirus in Gaza sewage, though no individual cases, the World Health Organization said there were "monumental" constraints to mounting a timely response.</p>

<p>WHO spokesman Christian Lindmeier said Friday the agency believes many more diseases are "spreading out of control" inside Gaza.</p>

<p>The months-long war has also brought Israelis to the streets, sometimes in their tens of thousands, focused on securing the release of the remaining hostages.</p>

<p>"Bring them home," demonstrator Ofira Azrieli said Saturday in Tel Aviv, appealing to Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>The premier is due to address US lawmakers Wednesday in Washington, where he will be under pressure to reach a ceasefire with Hamas.</p>

<p>His office announced that he will meet US President Joe Biden on Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/6l5ssuro_houthi-rebels-_625x300_30_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-think-he-misses-me-donald-trump-says-kim-jong-un-wants-him-to-win-us-elections-6154579]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["He Misses Me": Donald Trump Says Kim Jong Un Wants Him To Win US Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-think-he-misses-me-donald-trump-says-kim-jong-un-wants-him-to-win-us-elections-6154579]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 17:01:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump also asserted in his speech that although while in office, he "stopped the missile launches from North Korea" but the country is now "acting up again."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former United States President Donald Trump recently said that Kim Jong Un, leader of North Korea, wants him to win the 2024 Presidential race to the White House. He remarked this during the final night of the Republican National Convention (RNC) in Milwaukee. "But when we get back (in the White House), I get along with him," Mr Trump said, as per a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-kim-jong-un-election-north-korea-1927825"><em>Newsweek</em></a>.</p>

<p>"He'd like to see me back, too. I think he misses me if you wanna know the truth," he added. Citing his interactions with North Korean leader and Russia's Vladimir Putin, he positioned himself as the ideal candidate to handle geopolitical problems involving North Korea and Russia and put an end to conflicts.</p>

<p>He also asserted in his speech that although while in office, he "stopped the missile launches from North Korea" but the country is now "acting up again."</p>

<p>During his presidency, Mr Trump made frequent references to Kim Jong Un as "Little Rocket Man," a nickname that highlighted Kim's ambitions for nuclear weapons and missile testing. Even while there was initially hostility and heated confrontations, Mr Trump eventually adopted a more diplomatic stance.</p>

<p>In 2018, following up on his 'Rocket Man' comment, Donald Trump reportedly <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-he-removed-south-korea-sticker-from-cd-he-gave-to-kim-jong-un-3969963">sent a signed CD of Elton John's 'Rocket Man' </a>song with US Secretary of State Mike Pompeo, who was on a visit to North Korea for advancing denuclearisation talks with Kim Jong-un and putting a timeline on the denuclearisation process.</p>

<p>Speaking on the 'Full Send Podcast', Mr Trump stated that the gag gift for Mr Kim worked to steer the relationship between North and South Korea in a positive direction. "I asked him, 'Did you ever hear of the song Rocket Man?' when I was with him. He said, 'No, no, no,'" Mr Trump recalled. "Did you ever hear about Elton John? 'No, no, no.' I actually handed him the song 'Rocket Man,' which is a pretty good song by Elton John." he added.</p>

<p>"I gave him a tape ...I didn't show that it was made in South Korea, frankly. That the record - it said 'South Korea.' I said, 'Take that off.' We had it chiseled off," Mr Trump joked.</p>

<p>The CD then paved the way for his controversial 2019 meeting with the dictator. The meeting made Donald Trump the first sitting US President to cross into North Korea.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in the podcast, Mr Trump also called Kim Jong-un a "smart, cunning and ruthless person". "But I got to know him very well," he said, as per Newsweek. "And I think we would have had a nuclear war, had Obama been able to stay or had crooked Hillary Clinton become president, you would have had a nuclear war with North Korea," Mr Trump added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-06/pkiiuvqk_donald-trump-kim-jong-un-demilitarised-zone_625x300_30_June_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Trump and Mr Kim Jong Un had two meetings in 2019 and one in 2018.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-home-computers-were-unaffected-by-global-microsoft-outage-6154420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Home Computers Were Not Affected By Global Microsoft Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-home-computers-were-unaffected-by-global-microsoft-outage-6154420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 16:33:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft, the US-based tech giant, estimated that 8.5 million computers worldwide were affected due to the outage. The tech glitch happened on July 19 after Crowdstrike, a cybersecurity software company, rolled out its routine update.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft, the US-based tech giant, estimated that 8.5 million computers worldwide were affected due to the outage. The tech glitch happened on July 19 after Crowdstrike, a cybersecurity software company, rolled out its routine update.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From airlines to news channels, the glitch led to the crashing of IT systems, disrupting the daily proceedings.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/07/20/helping-our-customers-through-the-crowdstrike-outage/">blog</a> post, Microsoft stated, "We currently estimate that CrowdStrike's update affected 8.5 million Windows devices. Deploying hundreds of Microsoft engineers and experts to work directly with customers to restore services.”</p>

<p><b>Why the home PCs weren't affected?</b></p>

<p>CrowdStrike's products are predominantly used by major organisations needing robust cyber attack protection and are rarely found on home PCs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.kshb.com/news/local-news/cybersecurity-expert-says-home-computers-should-be-safe-from-crowdstrike-outage">KSHB Kansas City.com</a>, IT manager Nicole Burres said, “As far as I know, it's not something that you would need to be concerned about at home.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Burres, who works with Loquient Technology Services, added, “Now, it could impact your banking, it could impact some emergency services depending on your location.”</p>

<p>Taking about how CrowdStrike works and who are its clients, Ms Burres added, “CrowdStrike is a cybersecurity company that deploys cloud solutions to companies. They have about 1,000-user minimum licencing requirements, so your end user at home wouldn't be using it.”</p>

<p><b>CrowdStrike's first statement after the glitch</b></p>

<p>Addressing the glitch, Crowdstrike CEO George Kurtz <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fix-deployed-ceo-of-firm-behind-global-microsoft-outage-6140433">said</a>, "CrowdStrike is actively working with customers impacted by a defect found in a single content update for Windows hosts. Mac and Linux hosts are not impacted. This is not a security incident or cyberattack. The issue has been identified, isolated and a fix has been deployed. We refer customers to the support portal for the latest updates and will continue to provide complete and continuous updates on our website. We further recommend organizations ensure they're communicating with CrowdStrike representatives through official channels. Our team is fully mobilized to ensure the security and stability of CrowdStrike customers.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/i77nda7g_desktop-windows-generic_625x300_21_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-mamata-banerjee-rally-show-of-strength-a-message-for-bangladesh-6154306]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Mamata Banerjee's Rally, Show Of Strength, A Message For Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-mamata-banerjee-rally-show-of-strength-a-message-for-bangladesh-6154306]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 16:13:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee today said that the state would offer shelter to anyone in distress who knocks on their door.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee today said that the state would offer shelter to anyone in distress who knocks on their door. Her remarks come amid violent protests in Bangladesh that have already resulted in the death of 151 people. What began as a protest against politicised admission quotas for sought-after government jobs snowballed this week into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's tenure.</p>

<p>Ms Banerjee said that though she did not have the power to speak on the affairs of Bangladesh, and even India's official stand would be taken by the Centre, she would help those in distress who seek help from Bengal.</p>

<p>She referred to the United Nations Resolution on refugees as justification for her stand over the possible humanitarian crisis.</p>

<p>"I should not be speaking on the affairs of Bangladesh since it's another country. Whatever needs to be said on the issue is a subject matter of the Centre. But I only can say, if helpless people knock on Bengal's doors, we will shelter them," the Trinamool Congress chief said at the 'Martyrs Day' rally in Kolkata.</p>

<p>"That's because there is a United Nations Resolution to accommodate refugees in regions adjacent to those under turmoil," Ms Banerjee added while drawing an example from Assamese people who were allowed to live in the Alipurduars area of north Bengal for a considerable period during the Bodo strife in the northeastern state.</p>

<p>Mamata Banerjee also expressed her solidarity with the people who have remained at the receiving end of the ongoing violence in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>“We are sad to see blood getting spilt and my heart goes out to those students who were killed,” she said.</p>

<p>With the death count climbing and police unable to contain the violent protests, the Bangladesh government on Friday imposed a national curfew and deployed the military. Soldiers are patrolling cities across Bangladesh after riot police failed to restore order, while a nationwide internet blackout has drastically restricted the flow of information to the outside world.</p>

<p>Nearly 1,000 Indian students have returned to India from Bangladesh through various land transit points or by flight. External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said the Foreign Ministry is fully focused on ensuring the safety and well-being of the Indians in Bangladesh.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ni2drd4s_bangladesh-riots_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-irritated-with-barack-obama-as-pressure-grows-amid-white-house-race-6154296]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden "Irritated" With Barack Obama Amid White House Race Pressure: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-irritated-with-barack-obama-as-pressure-grows-amid-white-house-race-6154296]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 16:11:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Obama believes that Mr Biden's path to victory has diminished and he should "seriously consider the viability of his candidacy," the Washington Post said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States President Joe Biden has become tired of certain Democratic allies pressuring him to withdraw from the 2024 presidential race. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/19/us/politics/biden-drop-out-2024-election.html">The New York Times</a></em>, sources claimed that Mr Biden has become "irritated" with party leaders, particularly former President Barack Obama, who has reportedly been involved in discussions about the 81-year-old's withdrawal as the Democratic nominee.</p>

<p>Numerous lawmakers have come forward since the first presidential debate, pleading with the president to put an end to his campaign. However, Mr Biden's closest supporters, including Mr Obama and former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, have refrained from openly criticising the President, whose campaign has always maintained that he will remain in the White House race.</p>

<p>However, according to the NYT report, Mr Biden views Mr Obama "as a puppet master behind the scenes" regarding conversations on the President's campaign. Sources close to Mr Biden while speaking anonymously, said that the President "has been around politics long enough to assume that the leaks appearing in the media in recent days are being coordinated to raise the pressure on him to step aside."</p>

<p>On July 19, former US president Barack Obama told allies that Joe Biden needs to reconsider his reelection bid, according to a report in the <em>Washington Post</em>. Mr Obama believes that Mr Biden's path to victory has diminished and that the 81-year-old should "seriously consider the viability of his candidacy," the newspaper said, citing people briefed on his thinking.</p>

<p>It said there was no immediate comment from Mr Obama, who was in office while Mr Biden was Vice President from 2009 to 2017 and who remains hugely influential in the Democratic party.</p>

<p>According to a <em>CNN </em>report, Ms Pelosi has also informed Mr Biden that polls indicate he will not be able to defeat Trump and that this might be detrimental to Democrats across the political spectrum. However, in a statement released on Thursday, the former speaker said that the "feeding frenzy" from unidentified sources "misrepresents any conversations" she had with Mr Biden.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5gmsqu1o_obamabiden_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Biden views Mr Obama "as a puppet master behind the scenes" regarding conversations on the campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-outage-why-china-remained-unaffected-6154041]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Country Was Left Untouched By Biggest-Ever IT Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-outage-why-china-remained-unaffected-6154041]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:25:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft's global outage created havoc. From airline to broadcasting, the blue screen error, in a way, brought the daily operations to a standstill on Friday. Now, it has been reported that China remained largely unaffected by the outage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Microsoft's global outage created havoc. From airline to broadcasting, the blue screen error, in a way, brought the daily operations to a standstill on Friday. Now, it has been reported that China remained largely unaffected by the outage.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">As per a report by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3271171/microsoft-outage-leaves-china-largely-untouched-tech-self-sufficiency-campaign-pays">South China Post</a>, the country's airline and banking sectors weren't hit due to the tech glitch.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Citing the reason, the report added China doesn't rely on outside infrastructure to support its daily operations.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">As per news agency <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flights-resume-after-massive-microsoft-outage-disrupts-operations-6150567 ">AFP</a>, the operations at airports in Beijing were not affected due to the glitch, stated Chinese state media.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, a woman, who works for a foreign company in Shanghai, said that people at her office complained about the blue screen error, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3271171/microsoft-outage-leaves-china-largely-untouched-tech-self-sufficiency-campaign-pays">report </a>added. She also highlight the error message on her screen read, “Recovery. It looks like Windows didn't load correctly.”</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Social media reacts&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">People, in China, also stated that they were facing issues exploring some of the international hotels, the report mentioned.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Xiaohongshu, an Instagram-like Chinese social media platform, was filled with messages from uses complaining about the glitch.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Microsoft Outage: what happened?</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">A software update rolled out by&nbsp; CrowdStrike, a US-based cybersecurity firm, led to the disruption of workflow across the globe. The update was meant to make CrowdStrike clients' systems more secure against hacking by updating the threats it defends against.</p>

<p dir="ltr">But due to a glitch in the update, the IT systems faced Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) error which caused the system to suddenly shut down or restart.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Microsoft issued statement</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">In a<a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/07/20/helping-our-customers-through-the-crowdstrike-outage/"> blogpost</a>, the company said, “We recognize the disruption this problem has caused for businesses and in the daily routines of many individuals. Our focus is providing customers with technical guidance and support to safely bring disrupted systems back online.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9nqnuhio_microsoft_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A report added China doesn't rely on outside infrastructure to support its daily operations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/defiant-netanyahu-to-face-us-congress-meet-biden-at-white-house-amid-gaza-tensions-6154029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu To Face US Congress, Meet Biden At White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/defiant-netanyahu-to-face-us-congress-meet-biden-at-white-house-amid-gaza-tensions-6154029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:20:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is to deliver a landmark speech to the US Congress this week as he fights off intense pressure to cut a Gaza war ceasefire deal with Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is to deliver a landmark speech to the US Congress this week as he fights off intense pressure to cut a Gaza war ceasefire deal with Hamas.</p>

<p>Israel's longest-serving premier will on Wednesday become the first foreign leader to address a joint meeting of the two chambers four times -- pulling ahead of Britain's Winston Churchill on three.</p>

<p>But analysts say the Gaza war since the October 7 Hamas attacks has created worrying tensions between Israel and the United States, its main military and diplomatic backer. Netanyauhu's office announced that he will meet US President Joe Biden on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Washington fears a backlash from the mounting civilian toll in the Gaza Strip, while protests in Israel by families of hostages taken by Hamas are also causing headaches for Netanyahu.</p>

<p>Biden and some Israeli ministers say a deal negotiated through Qatar, Egyptian and US mediators is possible. A plan outlined in May proposed a six-week ceasefire when some Israeli hostages would be swapped for Palestinians held in Israeli prisons.&nbsp;</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Friday that negotiators were "inside the 10 yard line and driving toward the goal line".</p>

<p>Hamas has accused Netanyahu of seeking to block a deal however and Blinken said he wants to "bring the agreement over the finish line" when Netanyahu is in Washington.</p>

<h2>Double pressure</h2>

<p>Israel has intensified its attacks on Gaza in recent weeks and Netanyahu has insisted that only piling on military pressure can free the hostages and beat Hamas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This double pressure is not delaying the deal -– it is advancing it," Netanyahu told troops in Gaza on Thursday.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures. Hamas militants also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza, including 42 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed at least 38,919 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in the Hamas-ruled territory.</p>

<p>Publicly, Biden has voiced strong support for Israel. But he expressed concern over an offensive on the southern city of Rafah in May and for a while suspended deliveries of heavy bombs to Israel. Supplies of 2,000-pound bombs remain embargoed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Never before has the atmosphere been so fraught," said Council on Foreign Relations Middle East specialist Steven Cook.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There is clearly tension in the relationship, especially between the White House and the Israeli prime minister," Cook said in a commentary.</p>

<h2>'Political rhetoric'</h2>

<p>While US Republicans pressed to invite Netanyahu to address Congress, he has lost support among Democrats.</p>

<p>One Jewish senator, Democrat Brian Schatz of Hawaii, announced he would boycott Wednesday's speech, saying he would not listen to "political rhetoric that will do nothing to bring peace in the region".</p>

<p>Netanyahu said after being invited to Congress again that he would "present the truth about our just war against those who seek to destroy us".</p>

<p>Cook said that Netanyahu has two aims for his Washington trip.</p>

<p>First, to show that he has not "undermined" Israel's relations with the United States.</p>

<p>Netanyahu also "will endeavour to shift the conversation away from the conflict in Gaza toward the threat that Iran and its proxies pose" to Israel and the United States, Cook added.</p>

<p>Much attention will be focused on whether Netanyahu meets with Donald Trump or a figure close to the Republican presidential candidate.</p>

<p>Despite the tensions, the United States has defended Israeli interests while taking a key role in mediation efforts, and the military relationship remains strong, according to officials.</p>

<p>Washington's support could prove crucial as Israel faces increasing international criticism over the growing humanitarian toll from nearly 300 days of war.</p>

<p>The International Criminal Court's prosecutor in May asked judges to issue arrest warrants for Netanyahu and Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant. Warrants for three Hamas leaders have also been requested.</p>

<p>The Republican majority in the House of Representatives has called for sanctions against the ICC.</p>

<p>The International Court of Justice found Israel's occupation of Palestinian territories illegal on Friday, and in February called for the country to prevent any acts of genocide in its Gaza offensive.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/435p3ito_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-to-import-electricity-from-turkey-6153984]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iraq To Import Electricity From Turkey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-to-import-electricity-from-turkey-6153984]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:13:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iraq said Sunday a new power line will bring electricity from Turkey to its northern provinces as authorities aim to diversify the country's energy sources to ease chronic power outages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iraq said Sunday a new power line will bring electricity from Turkey to its northern provinces as authorities aim to diversify the country's energy sources to ease chronic power outages.</p>

<p>The 115-kilometre line connects to Kisik power plant west of Mosul and will provide 300 megawatts from Turkey to Iraq's northern provinces of Nineveh, Salah al-Din and Kirkuk, according to a statement by the prime minister's office.</p>

<p>PM Mohamed Shia al-Sudani said the new line is a "strategic" step to link Iraq with neighbouring countries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The line started operating today," Ahmed Moussa, spokesperson for the electricity ministry, told AFP.</p>

<p>Decades of war have left Iraq's infrastructure in a pitiful state, with power cuts worsening the blistering summer when temperatures often reach 50 Celsius (122 Fahrenheit).</p>

<p>Many households have just a few hours of mains electricity per day, and those who can afford it use private generators to keep fridges and air conditioners running.</p>

<p>Despite its vast oil reserves, Iraq remains dependent on imports to meet its energy needs, especially from neighbouring Iran, which regularly cuts supplies.</p>

<p>Sudani has repeatedly stressed the need for Iraq to diversify energy sources to ease the chronic outages.</p>

<p>To reduce its dependence on Iranian gas, Baghdad has been exploring several possibilities including imports from Gulf countries.</p>

<p>In March, a 340-kilometre (210-mile) power line started operating to bring electricity from Jordan to Al-Rutbah in Iraq's southwest.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/mnoriu2_power-electricity-generic_625x300_08_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-it-intercepted-us-bomber-planes-over-arctic-6153920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says It Intercepted US Bomber Planes Over Arctic]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-it-intercepted-us-bomber-planes-over-arctic-6153920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:02:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia said Sunday that it scrambled fighter jets to prevent two US strategic bomber planes from crossing its border over the Barents Sea in the Arctic.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia said Sunday that it scrambled fighter jets to prevent two US strategic bomber planes from crossing its border over the Barents Sea in the Arctic.</p>

<p>The US military routinely carries out flights over international waters, operations that it says are conducted in neutral airspace and in accordance with international law.</p>

<p>But Moscow has responded more aggressively to the exercises in recent months, warning in June that US drone flights over the Black Sea risked leading to a "direct" military clash.</p>

<p>The Russian defence ministry said it had scrambled fighter jets to intercept an "air target approaching the state border of the Russian Federation".</p>

<p>"The crews of the Russian fighters identified the aerial target as a pair of US Air Force B-52H strategic bombers," it said.</p>

<p>"As the Russian fighters approached, the American strategic bombers corrected their flight course, moving away and then turning away from Russia's state border," it said.</p>

<p>In June, Moscow accused the United States of using its reconnaissance drone flights over neutral waters in the Black Sea to help Ukraine strike the Russian-annexed Crimean peninsula.</p>

<p>It said that the flights increased the risk of a "direct confrontation" between NATO and Russia, and that its army had been instructed to prepare an "operational response".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-10/us-bombers-south-korean-japanese-aircraft-wp-650_650x400_41509329282.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/twins-fall-in-front-of-sydney-train-heroic-father-2-year-old-killed-6153440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Twins Fall In Front Of Sydney Train, "Heroic" Father, 2-Year-Old Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/twins-fall-in-front-of-sydney-train-heroic-father-2-year-old-killed-6153440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 13:46:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A pram carrying twin two-year-old girls rolled into the path of an oncoming train in Sydney on Sunday, police said, in an accident that killed one of the children and the "heroic" father who dashed to their rescue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A pram carrying twin two-year-old girls rolled into the path of an oncoming train in Sydney on Sunday, police said, in an accident that killed one of the children and the "heroic" father who dashed to their rescue.</p>

<p>One of the little girls survived only "through good luck" after she landed between the rails when the pram fell off a platform at southern Sydney's Carlton railway station, police said.</p>

<p>She was "largely untouched" by the train that apparently passed above her on its way to central Sydney in the early afternoon, police said.</p>

<p>The parents had taken a lift down to the station platform and as they exited, they took "their hands off the pram for a very, very short period of time", New South Wales police superintendent Paul Dunstan said.</p>

<p>"Whether it's a gust of wind or -- we're not quite sure -- but it appears that the pram has instantly started to roll in the direction of the train lines," he told a news conference.</p>

<p>Police and emergency services arrived within a few minutes of being alerted and were able to see the pram under the train, which had slowed on approach but was not scheduled to stop at the station.</p>

<p>"You could hear crying coming from underneath the train," the police superintendent said.</p>

<p>Though one of the children was unharmed, the other girl and her 40-year-old father had been killed.</p>

<p>The father had "just gone into parent mode" and tried to save his daughters, Dunstan said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In doing so it's cost him his life, but it's an incredibly brave and heroic act by the dad."</p>

<p>The mother and her surviving daughter were taken to the local St. George Hospital, and were said to be in a stable condition.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 39-year-old mother was "in a state of shock and struggling with what's happened" while being supported by family and friends in their local Indian community, Dunstan said.</p>

<p>New South Wales Premier Chris Minns said the local community would be pained by the accident.</p>

<p>"I hope over time they can gain some small solace knowing that the father died from an extraordinary, instinctive act of bravery," Minns said.</p>

<p>"In the face of a terrible, terrible accident, he gave his own life to try and save his children."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2i9dn89k_train_625x300_21_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-violence-hit-bangladesh-top-court-urges-students-to-return-to-class-6153390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Top Court Scales Back Jobs Quota That Sparked Deadly Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-violence-hit-bangladesh-top-court-urges-students-to-return-to-class-6153390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 13:39:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh Supreme Court today asked protesting students to "return to class" after issuing its verdict on contentious civil service hiring rules that led to deadly unrest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's top court on Sunday pared back, but fell short of public demands to abolish, contentious civil service hiring rules that sparked nationwide clashes between police and university students that have killed 151 people.</p>

<p>What began as a protest against politicised admission quotas for sought-after government jobs snowballed this week into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's tenure.</p>

<p>Soldiers are patrolling cities across Bangladesh after riot police failed to restore order, while a nationwide internet blackout since Thursday has drastically restricted the flow of information to the outside world.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court was due to decide next month on the legality of the recently reintroduced scheme that reserves more than half of government jobs for select applicants, but brought forward its verdict as the civil strife intensified.</p>

<p>It decided that a lower bench's order last month to reintroduce the scheme was "illegal", Bangladeshi Attorney General A.M. Amin Uddin told AFP.</p>

<p>Shah Monjurul Hoque, a lawyer involved in the case, told AFP that the court had also asked protesting students "to return to class" after issuing its verdict.</p>

<p>The ruling curtailed the number of reserved jobs, from 56 percent of all positions to seven percent, but fell short of meeting protester demands.</p>

<p>It reserved five percent of all government jobs for the children of "freedom fighters" from Bangladesh's 1971 liberation war against Pakistan, down from 30 percent.</p>

<p>One percent were reserved for tribal communities, and another one percent for people with disabilities or identifying as third gender under Bangladeshi law.</p>

<p>The remaining 93 percent of positions would be decided on merit, the court ruled.</p>

<p>The "freedom fighter" category in particular is a point of resentment for young graduates, with critics saying it is used to stack public jobs with loyalists to Hasina's ruling Awami League.</p>

<p>Students had called for the complete abolition of that category, along with other quotas for women and specific districts of the country.</p>

<p><strong>'Our demand is one point'</strong></p>

<p>Opponents accuse Hasina's government of bending the judiciary to its will, and the premier had already hinted to the public this week that the court would issue a ruling favourable to student demands.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, has ruled the country since 2009 and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p>Her government is accused by rights groups of misusing state institutions to entrench its hold on power and stamp out dissent, including by the extrajudicial killing of opposition activists.</p>

<p>But after the mounting crackdown and a rising death toll, it remains to be seen whether the court's verdict would mollify white-hot public anger.</p>

<p>"It's not about the rights of the students anymore," business owner Hasibul Sheikh, 24, told AFP at the scene of a Saturday street protest, held in the capital Dhaka in defiance of a nationwide curfew.</p>

<p>"Our demand is one point now, and that's the resignation of the government.</p>

<p><strong>'Made the situation worse</strong></p>

<p>With some 18 million young people in Bangladesh out of work, according to government figures, the quota scheme's reintroduction deeply upset graduates facing an acute jobs crisis.</p>

<p>Hasina inflamed tensions this month by likening protesters to the Bangladeshis who had collaborated with Pakistan during the country's independence war.</p>

<p>"Rather than try to address the protesters' grievances, the government's actions have made the situation worse," Crisis Group's Asia director Pierre Prakash told AFP.</p>

<p>Since Tuesday, at least 151 people, including several police officers, have been killed in clashes around the country, according to an AFP count of victims reported by police and hospitals.</p>

<p><strong>Curfew extended</strong></p>

<p>Police have arrested several members of the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Students Against Discrimination, the main protest organising group.</p>

<p>Bangladesh home minister Asaduzzaman Khan told AFP that the curfew imposed on Saturday would continue "until the situation improves".</p>

<p>He said that in addition to the torching of government buildings and police posts by protesters, arson attacks had left Dhaka's metro rail network inoperable.</p>

<p>"They are carrying out destructive activities targeting the government," Khan said, blaming the BNP and the Islamist party Jamaat for stoking the violence.</p>

<p>The US State Department warned Americans on Saturday not to travel to Bangladesh and said it would begin removing some diplomats and their families from the country due to the civil unrest.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/oje1tbbg_bangladesh_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malena-galletto-17-gets-acceptance-letters-from-all-8-ivy-league-schools-6152969]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This US Teen Has Been Accepted At 20 Colleges, All 8 Ivy League Schools]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malena-galletto-17-gets-acceptance-letters-from-all-8-ivy-league-schools-6152969]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 12:19:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Malena Galletto, 17, has received acceptance letters from all eight Ivy League Schools. Not just that, the young sensation, from Washington Heights, has also received positive outcomes from the other 20 colleges and universities she applied to.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Malena Galletto, 17, has received acceptance letters from all eight Ivy League Schools. Not just that, the young sensation, from Washington Heights, has also received positive outcomes from the other 20 colleges and universities she applied to, reported the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/20/us-news/bronx-science-hs-graduate-accepted-into-all-28-colleges-she-applies-to-including-the-eight-ivy-leagues/">NY Post.</a></p>

<p dir="ltr">“When I was about to open [an admissions] letter, I would prepare myself for it to be the first rejection letter. And then I would open them and it would always say, ‘Congratulations on being accepted!” Ms Galletto was quoted as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Ms Galletto, who got a 97% GPA, said that she got her first acceptance from the University of Albany.</p>

<p dir="ltr">She added, “For as long as I can remember, school has always been my number one priority. Even in elementary school, I remember always wanting to be at the top of my class,” she said, crediting her parents, both of whom teach tango and immigrated from their native Argentina to Washington Heights in 2000. They instilled in her that “education was the most important thing.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Recalling the moment when she received the letter from Harvard University, Ms Galletto said, “The first one I opened was from Cornell [University], and when that was a ‘Yes,' it was life-changing…But when I opened Harvard [University], I was absolutely screaming. Deep down, it was always Harvard for me.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Ms Galletto's mother Karina Romero also expressed her excitement about her daughter's achievements. “I am so incredibly proud. She's always studying and doing her very best, and I'm so happy she got what she worked so hard to achieve,” she said.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Ms Galletto has also received a shout-out from City Department of Education spokeswoman Nicole Brownstein. As per Ms Brownstein, the result is a “testament to her [Malena Galletto] hard work and dedication.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/856c41lc_malena-galletto_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Malena Galletto, 17, has received acceptance letters from all eight Ivy League Schools.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-as-plane-used-for-skydiving-crashes-in-new-york-6152944]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Dead As Plane Used For Skydiving Crashes In New York]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-as-plane-used-for-skydiving-crashes-in-new-york-6152944]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 12:11:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One person has died after a plane, used for skydiving, crashed in Niagara County, New York on Saturday, reported CNN. Following the incident, New York officials launched an investigation on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One person has died after a plane, used for skydiving, crashed in Niagara County, New York on Saturday, reported CNN. Following the incident, New York officials launched an investigation on Saturday.</p>

<p>The single-engine Cessna 208B, a plane that was used for skydiving, crashed near Lake Road near Youngstown, New York, shortly before 1 pm, the Federal Aviation Administration said in a statement.</p>

<p>The aeroplane from the Skydive the Falls skydiving centre had released all divers and was heading back to land when it crashed, according to a news release from the Niagara County Sheriff's Office on Saturday, as reported by CNN.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the FAA, Tammy L. Jones, said that the pilot, who was the only person on board, was conducting parachute operations prior to the crash.</p>

<p>However, it is still unclear how many divers were on board before the crash, Niagara County Sheriff Michael Filicetti said at a news conference on Saturday.</p>

<p>Later, a brush fire also reportedly began around the crash site, according to the release.</p>

<p>The initial responding crew had to put out "a significant fire at that point," Filicetti said.</p>

<p>The sheriff called the plane crash "an unfortunate incident" and added that local and federal law enforcement partners are working to determine what led to the crash.</p>

<p>"Well, I think this is like any other emergency-type incident...You get here, you want to try to preserve life. Unfortunately, in this case, we couldn't do that," Filicetti said.</p>

<p>A National Transportation Safety Board investigator is expected to be travelling to the crash site on Saturday, NTSB spokesperson Peter Knudson told CNN.</p>

<p>The investigator will further document the aeroplane wreckage, which will then be moved to a secure facility for further evaluation, Knudson mentioned.</p>

<p>The investigation will involve three primary areas, including, the pilot, the aircraft and the operating environment, CNN reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3g1948q8_skydiving_625x300_21_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sends-trash-balloons-south-responds-with-loudspeakers-6152755]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Sends Trash Balloons, South Responds With Loudspeakers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sends-trash-balloons-south-responds-with-loudspeakers-6152755]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 11:32:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea on Sunday floated balloons carrying trash towards South Korea, South Korea's military said, declaring it would respond with "full-scale" loudspeaker broadcasts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea on Sunday floated balloons carrying trash towards South Korea, South Korea's military said, declaring it would respond with "full-scale" loudspeaker broadcasts.</p>

<p>The South Korean military said the North's actions raising tensions near the heavily armed border could have fatal consequences, adding the North Korean regime would be solely responsible.</p>

<p>"As we warned several times, the military will carry out loudspeaker broadcasts in full scale and on all fronts starting 1 p.m. today," the South's Joint Chiefs of Staff said, calling the North's launch of balloons vulgar and shameful.</p>

<p>Activists and defectors in South Korea have for years sent their own balloons carrying propaganda leaflets and other items into North Korea, angering Pyongyang.</p>

<p>Earlier this week, South Korea's military decided to resume its round-the-clock loudspeaker broadcast campaign targeting North Korea in response to what it called the despicable launch of balloons by Pyongyang carrying trash across the border.</p>

<p>Since May, North Korea has been floating thousands of balloons with bags of trash attached to them, which have become a new source of tension between the two Koreas.</p>

<p>Blaring propaganda, world news and K-pop music, South Korea's broadcasts are considered by military officials and activists as an effective form of psychological warfare.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2p0k4l6g_north-korea-trash-balloon_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[South Korea's military decided to resume its round-the-clock loudspeaker broadcast]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-israel-struck-key-port-in-yemen-one-of-world-poorest-countries-6152668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Place We Won't Reach": Israel After Airstrikes 1,800 Km Away In Yemen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-israel-struck-key-port-in-yemen-one-of-world-poorest-countries-6152668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 11:16:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli warplanes today struck targets around the Houthi-held Red Sea port of Yemen's Hudaydah, retaliating for a drone attack on Tel Aviv by the Iran-backed rebels that killed a man and exposed a vulnerability in Israeli air defences.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli warplanes today struck targets around the Houthi-held Red Sea port of Yemen's Hudaydah, retaliating for a drone attack on Tel Aviv by the Iran-backed rebels that killed a man and exposed a vulnerability in Israeli air defences. The rebels claimed that three people had been killed in the strikes, which triggered a raging fire and plumes of black smoke.</p>

<p>Called Operation 'Outstretched Arm', these strikes are the furthest from the Israel territory ever conducted by their Air Force, the country said. This is the first attack claimed by Israel in the Arabian peninsula's poorest country.</p>

<p>"This operation struck targets 1,800 kilometres from our borders," Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in a video statement. "It clarifies to our enemies that there is no place where the long arm of the State of Israel won't reach."</p>

<p>Explaining the strikes, the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) in a statement said that it struck targets around the Yemen port as it serves as an "entryway of Iranian weapons for the Houthi terrorist regime and as a significant economic source for them."</p>

<p>"Over the past few months, the Houthis have been operating in order to destabilise the Middle East. The Houthi terror attacks are funded and directed by Iran, harming the maritime freedom in the area, regional ports, the Suez Canal and global trade as a whole," the IDF added.</p>

<p>The Israeli strikes killed three people and wounded 87, the rebel-run health ministry said in a statement carried by Huthi media. The ministry said earlier that most of the wounded had severe burns.</p>

<p>Footage aired by the rebels' Al-Masirah television showed casualties being treated in hospital, many of them bandaged and lying on stretchers in packed rooms. &nbsp;</p>

<p>A man interviewed by the broadcaster said many of the wounded were port employees. "The city is dark, people are on the streets, petrol stations are closed and seeing long queues," he said.</p>

<p>The Houthis started targeting Israel with drones and missiles shortly after the war between Israeli forces and Hamas in Gaza began in October. None of those attacks are believed to have caused significant damage in Israel until now, with most projectiles being intercepted or failing to reach the country.</p>

<p>Houthi rebels say they're acting in solidarity with Palestinians and will continue the attacks until there's a ceasefire in Gaza.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/m4g5uiqc_israel-yemen-strike_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thomas-matthew-crooks-was-not-part-of-his-school-s-rifle-team-6152411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Shooter Thomas Crooks Was Not Part Of School's "Rifle Team": Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thomas-matthew-crooks-was-not-part-of-his-school-s-rifle-team-6152411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 10:49:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks, who shot at Donald Trump at the Pennsylvania rally, was not a member of his school's rifle team.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Thomas Matthew Crooks — who shot at Donald Trump at the Pennsylvania rally — was not a member of his school's rifle team.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mr Crooks' school Bethel Park School District has also issued a <a href="https://www.bpsd.org/apps/news/article/1942738">statement</a>. It read, “Bethel Park School District can confirm that the alleged shooter in the July 13, 2024, assassination attempt on former President Donald J. Trump is a graduate of Bethel Park High School. Thomas Matthew Crooks graduated from Bethel Park High School with the Class of 2022.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">The statement added, “The school district wishes to express its sincere wishes for a speedy and complete recovery for Mr. Trump and those in attendance at the Saturday event who may have been physically harmed or emotionally impacted by these tragic events. We offer special condolences to the family of Mr. Corey Comperatore, who was killed. Our thoughts and prayers are with you at this difficult time.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">“Our school district will cooperate fully with the active law enforcement investigation surrounding this case, and as such, we are limited in what we can publicly disclose,” the statement added.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“Moving forward, we will work closely with law enforcement investigators and share information as appropriate regarding school district policies, the active investigation, and law enforcement protocols. Otherwise, we would direct all media inquiries to those handling the investigation for more information,” it stated.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Speaking to <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/14/us-news/would-be-trump-assassin-tried-to-join-high-school-shooting-club-was-rejected-for-being-comically-bad-shot/">The NY Post</a>, Mr Crooks' classmate stated, “We noticed a few things Thomas said and how he interacted with other people … He said some things that were kind of concerning.”</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Mr Crooks was shot dead by the Secret Service after he fired a few rounds at the rally.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bv51s1j_thomas-matthew-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Crooks' school Bethel Park School District has also issued a statement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-first-lady-kim-keon-hee-a-rs-1-84-lakh-handbag-at-centre-of-dior-scandal-6152396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea First Lady, A Rs 1.84 Lakh Handbag At Centre Of "Dior Scandal"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-first-lady-kim-keon-hee-a-rs-1-84-lakh-handbag-at-centre-of-dior-scandal-6152396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 10:12:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea's First Lady Kim Keon Hee has been questioned over allegations of stock manipulation and graft involving a $2,200 luxury handbag, the prosecution said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea's First Lady Kim Keon Hee has been questioned over allegations of stock manipulation and graft involving a $2,200 luxury handbag, the prosecution said on Sunday.</p>

<p>The questioning comes as the opposition calls for a special probe into the first lady, who has been under scrutiny for accepting a Dior bag in violation of government ethics rules, and for her alleged role in a stock manipulation scheme.</p>

<p>Prosecutors conducted "face-to-face questioning" of Kim on Saturday, the Seoul Central District Prosecutors' Office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Hidden camera footage released last year appeared to show Kim accepting a $2,200 luxury designer handbag, an act that was later dubbed the "Dior bag scandal" by local papers.</p>

<p>The scandal-hit President Yoon Suk Yeol's already-low approval ratings, contributed to a stinging defeat for his party in general elections in April as it failed to win back a parliamentary majority.</p>

<p>Such a gift would violate South Korean law, which bans public officials and their spouses from accepting anything worth more than $750.</p>

<p>Kim's aide told investigators earlier this month that the first lady told her to return the bag on the same day she had received it, but she had forgotten to, according to Yonhap news agency.</p>

<p>In his first remarks on the bag scandal in February, Yoon dismissed it as a "political scheme" and said his wife had accepted the bag only because it was difficult for her to refuse it.</p>

<p>But he later apologised in a rare press conference in May, describing his wife's acceptance of the bag as "unwise".</p>

<p>It is not the first time Kim has faced public scrutiny. During Yoon's presidential campaign, she was forced to apologise over falsified credentials.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h62h2s4o_south-korea-first-lady-afp-_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kim's aide told investigators earlier this month that the first lady told her to return the bag]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/does-sunscreen-cause-cancer-as-summer-rages-misinformation-scorches-us-6152261]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Does Sunscreen Cause Cancer? As Summer Rages, Misinformation Scorches US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/does-sunscreen-cause-cancer-as-summer-rages-misinformation-scorches-us-6152261]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 09:40:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the midst of a blazing summer, some social media influencers are offering potentially dangerous advice on sun protection, despite stepped-up warnings from health experts about over-exposure amid rising rates of skin cancer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dismissively tossing a tube of sunscreen over his shoulder, a bare-chested TikTok influencer declares that the cream causes cancer. He instead promotes "regular sun exposure" to his 400,000 followers -- contradicting US dermatologists fighting a surge in such dubious misinformation.</p>

<p>In the midst of a blazing summer, some social media influencers are offering potentially dangerous advice on sun protection, despite stepped-up warnings from health experts about over-exposure amid rising rates of skin cancer.</p>

<p>Further undermining public health, videos -- some garnering millions of views -- share "homemade" recipes that use ingredients such as beef tallow, avocado butter and beeswax for what is claimed to provide effective skin protection.</p>

<p>In one viral TikTok video, "transformation coach" Jerome Tan discards a commercial cream and tells his followers that eating natural foods will allow the body to make its "own sunscreen."</p>

<p>He offers no scientific evidence for this.</p>

<p>Such online misinformation is increasingly causing real-world harm, experts say.</p>

<p>One in seven American adults under 35 think daily sunscreen use is more harmful than direct sun exposure, and nearly a quarter believe staying hydrated can prevent a sunburn, according to a survey this year by Ipsos for the Orlando Health Cancer Institute.</p>

<p>"People buy into a lot of really dangerous ideas that put them at added risk," warned Rajesh Nair, an oncology surgeon with the institute.</p>

<h3><strong>'No safe tan'</strong></h3>

<p>As influencers increasingly cast doubt on commercial sunscreen products, another US survey showed a dip in their use, with some 75 percent of Americans using sunscreen regularly, down from 79 percent in 2022.</p>

<p>The findings coincide with other trends showing rising public mistrust of established medical guidance -- including on Covid-19 and other vaccines -- and increasing reliance on influencers with little or no scientific knowledge.</p>

<p>Dermatologists are scrambling to disabuse people of the increasingly popular perception that higher levels of sun exposure are good for the skin.</p>

<p>"There is no safe tan," Daniel Bennett, a dermatologist and professor at the University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, told AFP.</p>

<p>"The evidence that ultraviolet light exposure is the primary preventable driver of skin cancer is overwhelming," he added.</p>

<p>Many of the misleading or false claims come from influencers seeking to monetize their content on social media platforms, an echo chamber where sensational and false claims often drive engagement, experts say.</p>

<p>Some content creators are leveraging "sunscreen skepticism" to "sell their own supplements or endorse alternative all-natural sunscreens," Eric Dahan, founder of the influencer marketing agency Mighty Joy, told AFP.</p>

<h3><strong>'Sun paranoia'</strong></h3>

<p>Dahan pointed out one Instagram post that advised against "wearing sunscreen constantly" while promoting a range of skincare products.</p>

<p>"Say goodbye to sun paranoia," the emoji-laden post said. "Catch some (guilt-free) rays this summer."</p>

<p>Clutching a surfboard on a beach, another bare-chested Instagram influencer says he rejects sunscreen.</p>

<p>"Do I worry about skin cancer? I do not," he posted, while promoting "animal-based sunscreen" made from beef tallow.</p>

<p>Tallow -- essentially rendered, purified beef fat -- alone has no ability to block ultraviolet radiation, said Megan Poynot Couvillion, a dermatologist practicing in Texas.</p>

<p>"I don't see a problem with using it on the skin as an emollient, but absolutely not as a sunscreen," she told AFP.</p>

<p>The US Food and Drug Administration has called for more research into the ingredients in commercial sunscreens, but it does recommend their use, noting that excessive sun exposure is a major contributor to skin cancer.</p>

<p>Homemade sunscreens "lack effective sun protection," leaving users vulnerable to sunburn, premature skin aging and skin cancer, the American Academy of Dermatology warns.</p>

<p>Some influencers' recipes include zinc oxide, a known sun protector. But concocting sunscreen at home that will effectively block UV radiation is unrealistic, said Adam Friedman, professor at the George Washington University School of Medicine and Health Sciences.</p>

<p>"There's no way you're making this in your basement," Friedman told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ee08e6so_sunscreen-afp-_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some social media influencers are offering potentially dangerous advice on sun protection.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-53-years-later-razakar-dictator-shouts-return-to-bangladesh-politics-6152146]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Return Of 'Razakars' To Bangladesh Political Discourse After 53 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-53-years-later-razakar-dictator-shouts-return-to-bangladesh-politics-6152146]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 09:15:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Violence in Bangladesh has left over 130 dead as students demand reforms to a quota system governing the allocation of government jobs in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Violence in Bangladesh has left over 130 dead as students demand reforms to a quota system governing the allocation of government jobs in the country. The protests intensified following Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's controversial remarks, where she labelled the protestors as "Razakars". This term, historically loaded and carrying a negative connotation, harks back to the East Pakistani volunteer force that opposed the creation of Bangladesh as a sovereign nation during its 1971 War of Independence.</p>

<h3><strong>The Spark</strong></h3>

<p>The protests, which began late last month, reached a boiling point earlier this week when student activists at Dhaka University, the largest university in the country, engaged in violent clashes with police and counter-protesters aligned with the ruling Awami League.</p>

<p>The controversial quota system reserves up to 30 per cent of government jobs for family members of veterans who fought in Bangladesh's 1971 war of independence against Pakistan. Protesters argue that this system is discriminatory and disproportionately benefits supporters of Prime Minister Hasina's Awami League party. They advocate for a merit-based system to replace the existing quota. Prime Minister Hasina's fiery remarks at a public gathering ignited further protests.</p>

<p>"If not the grandchildren of the freedom fighters, then who will get quota benefits? The grandchildren of the 'Razakars'?" the Bangladeshi PM asked. "This is my question. I want to ask the people of the nation. If the protesters don't comply, I can do nothing. They can continue their protest. If protesters damage properties or attack cops, the law will take its course. We can't help."</p>

<p>PM Hasina's intent was to highlight the importance of preserving benefits for the descendants of those who fought for Bangladesh's independence. However, the term "Razakar" struck a raw nerve. It is a term that conjures up memories of widespread violence from the 1971 War of Independence, during which the "Razakars" collaborated with the Pakistani army against the Bengali nationalist movement.</p>

<h3><strong>Historical Context Of The Term "Razakar"</strong></h3>

<p>The "Razakars" were a paramilitary force recruited by the Pakistani army during the 1971 Bangladesh Liberation War. Comprised primarily of pro-Pakistani Bengalis and Urdu-speaking Biharis, the "Razakars" were involved in numerous atrocities, including mass killings, rapes, and torture. The 1971 war saw immense suffering, with estimates of civilian deaths ranging from 300,000 to 3 million. The scars of these events are still evident in the national psyche.</p>

<p>In 2010, Prime Minister Hasina's government established the International Crimes Tribunal to prosecute those accused of war crimes during the 1971 conflict. This move was part of her strategy to address historical injustices and was widely seen as a fulfilment of her party's electoral promises. The tribunal has since convicted several individuals, predominantly from the now-banned Jamaat-e-Islami party.</p>

<p>In December 2019, the government published a list of 10,789 individuals identified as "Razakars", marking the first official recognition of these collaborators. This list included prominent figures and was intended to ensure that future generations understand the historical context of their actions.</p>

<h3><strong>The Contentious Quota System</strong></h3>

<p>The current protests are rooted in the quota system for government jobs, which allocates significant portions to descendants of freedom fighters. This system, established in 1972 and abolished briefly in 2018 before being reinstated, has been a source of contention. Critics argue that it disproportionately benefits Awami League supporters and limits opportunities for other qualified candidates.</p>

<p>"They are protesting against the repressive nature of the state," said Mubashar Hasan, a Bangladesh expert at the University of Oslo in Norway, as quoted by news agency AFP. "Protesters are questioning Hasina's leadership, accusing her of clinging onto power by force. The students are in fact calling her a dictator."</p>

<p>Student protests against the quota system have a history in Bangladesh. The latest wave began after the decision to reinstate the system, which was followed by the Supreme Court suspending the order pending a government appeal. This legal limbo has left many students frustrated, feeling that their demands for a merit-based system are being ignored.</p>

<p>The students' grievances extend beyond the quota system. High youth unemployment and a stagnant economy have all contributed to a sense of frustration and despair. Public sector jobs, with their regular wages and benefits, are highly coveted in a country where economic opportunities are limited.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dt6m1368_bangladesh-protests-_625x300_21_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protests, which began late last month, reached a boiling point earlier this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-top-court-verdict-today-on-job-quotas-that-sparked-unrest-6151993]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Top Court's Verdict Today On Job Quotas That Sparked Unrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-top-court-verdict-today-on-job-quotas-that-sparked-unrest-6151993]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 08:37:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[What began as a protest against politicised admission quotas for sought-after government jobs snowballed this week into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's tenure.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's top court was due to rule Sunday on the future of civil service hiring rules that sparked <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-cops-given-shoot-on-sight-orders-amid-curfew-to-quell-student-protests-6151870">nationwide clashes</a> between police and university students, killing 133 people.&nbsp;</p>

<p>What began as a protest against politicised admission quotas for sought-after government jobs snowballed this week into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's tenure.</p>

<p>Soldiers are patrolling cities across Bangladesh after riot police failed to restore order, while a nationwide internet blackout since Thursday has drastically restricted the flow of information to the outside world.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court was meeting later Sunday to issue a verdict on whether to abolish the contentious job quotas.</p>

<p>Hasina, whose opponents accuse her government of bending the judiciary to her will, hinted to the public this week that the scheme would be scrapped.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But after the mounting crackdown and a rising death count, a favourable verdict is unlikely to mollify white-hot public anger.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's not about the rights of the students anymore," business owner Hasibul Sheikh, 24, told AFP at the scene of a Saturday street protest, held in the capital Dhaka in defiance of a nationwide curfew.</p>

<p>"Our demand is one point now, and that's the resignation of the government."</p>

<p>The catalyst for this month's unrest is a system that reserves more than half of civil service posts for specific groups, including children of veterans from the country's 1971 liberation war against Pakistan.</p>

<p>Critics say the scheme benefits families loyal to Hasina, 76, who has ruled the country since 2009 and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p>Hasina's government is accused by rights groups of misusing state institutions to entrench its hold on power and stamp out dissent, including by the extrajudicial killing of opposition activists.</p>

<h3><strong>'Made the situation worse'</strong></h3>

<p>With Bangladesh unable to provide adequate employment opportunities for its 170 million people, the quota scheme is a pronounced source of resentment among young graduates facing an acute jobs crisis.</p>

<p>Hasina inflamed tensions this month by likening protesters to the Bangladeshis who had collaborated with Pakistan during the country's independence war.</p>

<p>"Rather than try to address the protesters' grievances, the government's actions have made the situation worse," Crisis Group's Asia director Pierre Prakash told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina had been due to leave the country on Sunday for a diplomatic tour to Spain and Brazil but abandoned her plans after a week of escalating violence.</p>

<p>Since Tuesday at least 133 people, including several police officers, have been killed in clashes around the country, according to an AFP count of victims reported by police and hospitals.</p>

<p>The US State Department warned Americans on Saturday not to travel to Bangladesh and said it would begin removing some diplomats and their families from the country due to the civil unrest.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3bnqa0pg_bangladesh-protests_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 133 people have died in Bangladesh protests]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>