<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 03:45:11 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-citizen-arrested-in-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-us-official-politician-6279791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Citizen Arrested In Alleged Iran Plot To Kill US Official, Politician]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-citizen-arrested-in-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-us-official-politician-6279791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 01:58:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani man with ties to Iran has been arrested for allegedly plotting to assassinate a US official in retaliation for the US killing of Revolutionary Guards commander Qassem Soleimani, the Justice Department said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani man with ties to Iran has been arrested for allegedly plotting to assassinate a US official in retaliation for the US killing of Revolutionary Guards commander Qassem Soleimani, the Justice Department said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Asif Raza Merchant, 46, allegedly sought to hire a hitman to assassinate a politician or a US government official in the United States, the department said in a statement.</p>

<p>"For years, the Justice Department has been working aggressively to counter Iran's brazen and unrelenting efforts to retaliate against American public officials for the killing of Iranian General Soleimani," Attorney General Merrick Garland said.</p>

<p>Soleimani, the architect of Iran's foreign military operations, was killed in a US drone strike in Baghdad in January 2020. Iranian officials have repeatedly vowed to take "revenge" for the killing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The Justice Department will spare no resource to disrupt and hold accountable those who would seek to carry out Iran's lethal plotting against American citizens," Garland said.</p>

<p>The intended victim was not identified but the attorney general said no evidence has emerged to link Merchant with the July 13 assassination attempt against former president Donald Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>FBI Director Christopher Wary said the Pakistani national had "close ties to Iran" and that the alleged murder-for-hire plot was "straight out of the Iranian playbook."</p>

<p>Another FBI official said the assassins Merchant allegedly tried to hire were in fact undercover FBI agents.</p>

<p>Merchant was arrested on July 12 as he planned to leave the country.</p>

<p>In August 2022, the United States charged a member of the Revolutionary Guards with plotting to assassinate former US National Security Advisor John Bolton.</p>

<p>The Justice Department said Shahram Poursafi, who remains at large, had offered to pay an individual in the United States $300,000 to kill Bolton.</p>

<p>Iran has dismissed the claim that it had plotted to kill Bolton as "fiction."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/op07qhu_-us-department-of-justice-_625x300_30_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Pakistani man with ties to Iran has been arrested for allegedly plotting to assassinate a US official.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-interim-government-6279601]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus To Lead Bangladesh Interim Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-interim-government-6279601]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:56:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus has been tapped to lead an interim government after the ouster of prime minister Sheikh Hasina, the country's presidency announced early Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad&nbsp;Yunus has been tapped to lead an interim government after the ouster of prime minister Sheikh Hasina, the country's presidency announced early Wednesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The decision "to form an interim government with Yunus as its chief" was taken at a meeting of President Mohammed Shahabuddin, military leaders and the heads of the Students Against Discrimination group, Shahabuddin's press office said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nahid Islam, a leader of the student group, confirmed the decision to reporters after three hours of talks at the presidential palace.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The president has asked the people to help ride out the crisis. Quick formation of an interim government is necessary to overcome the crisis," Shahabuddin's office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Shahabuddin also sacked the national police chief in the wake of deadly protests that sparked Hasina's departure and named a replacement, his office said.</p>

<p>Islam called the talks "fruitful" and said that Shahabuddin had agreed that the interim government "will be formed within the shortest time" possible.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8v0rqhuo_muhammad-yunus-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus won the 2006 Nobel Peace Prize for providing tiny loans to the rural poor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/families-of-people-killed-in-bangladesh-protests-place-11-point-demands-6279480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Families Of People Killed In Bangladesh Protests Place 11-Point Demands]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/families-of-people-killed-in-bangladesh-protests-place-11-point-demands-6279480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:25:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Families of the persons killed in Bangladesh's student protests on Tuesday placed 11-point demands, including rehabilitation by providing jobs, before the interim government,]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Families of the persons killed in Bangladesh's student protests on Tuesday placed 11-point demands, including rehabilitation by providing jobs, before the interim government which is set to be formed to replace the ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's regime.</p>

<p>The death count in the massive protests following Hasina-led government's announcement of the quota system in jobs has risen to 440, with more than 200 people killed in the renewed spell of violence towards the weekend as violent clashes erupted between police and mostly student protesters.</p>

<p>A statement, signed by Harun-ur Rashid, the convener of a proposed "Committee on Families of Injured and Killed in Anti-Discriminatory Student Movement", said an initiative has been taken to collect accurate data on the families of the students, children, youth, elderly, men and women who were injured and killed in the violence.</p>

<p>The demands include providing Tk2,000-3,000 per month as a grant for all students from pre-primary to Masters based on age under a "Food-Card" programme, unemployment allowance of Tk3,000 to job aspirants, formation of an inquiry committee consisting of armed forces and students for the treatment of the injured in the anti-discrimination student movement and the speedy rehabilitation of the affected families, the Dhaka Tribune newspaper reported.</p>

<p>The demands also include direct government scholarships to students in private universities, changing the name of the educational institution established after various individuals of the Sheikh Hasina family and naming those after the martyrs Pilkhana Shaheed army officer, and also in memory of the martyrs killed in various movements and anti-discriminatory student protests.</p>

<p>Inclusion of the neutral ex-army and police force members of the peacekeeping mission in the United Nations on an urgent basis to improve the ongoing law and order situation and also the inclusion of Bangladesh National Cadet Corps (BNCC) and Bangladesh Scouts as their partners, the committee demanded.</p>

<p>The demand also included taking a quick initiative to recover all the illegal weapons used in the movement in the past days, consideration of redeployment of all categories of honest and efficient officers-employees who were deprived of promotion/compulsory retirement due to oppression and discrimination during the previous government.</p>

<p>Speedy recovery of money of big defaulters and money smuggled abroad, the speedy trial of big defaulters and money smugglers in military courts, and the inclusion of at least one person in the interim government from the active student families of the anti-quota movement, the injured families and families of those killed, it said.</p>

<p>The committee offered its deepest condolences to the bereaved families of those killed and injured in the movement and congratulated the army officers and soldiers at all levels of the armed forces, including the chief of the Bangladesh Army.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in a video message issued by the police headquarters' media and public relations division on Tuesday, Inspector General of Police Chowdhury Abdullah Al Mamun urged leaders of all political parties and the Students Against Discrimination to make a call for not carrying out attacks on the police members and their establishments.</p>

<p>He said the army men have been assisting the police to ensure their security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jem8luuo_bangladesh-protest-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The demands also include direct government scholarships to students in private universities. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-hamas-chief-named-following-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-6279281]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Names New Chief After Ismail Haniyeh's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-hamas-chief-named-following-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-6279281]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:41:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas named Gaza Strip chief Yahya Sinwar as its new political leader on Tuesday, a week after his predecessor Ismail Haniyeh's killing in Tehran which has sent regional tensions soaring.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas named Gaza Strip chief Yahya Sinwar as its new political leader on Tuesday, after his predecessor Ismail Haniyeh's was killed in Tehran last week, sending regional tensions soaring.</p>

<p>"The Islamic Resistance Movement Hamas announces the selection of leader Yahya Sinwar as the head of the political bureau of the movement," a statement from the group said.</p>

<p>Minutes after the announcement, Hamas's armed wing, the Ezzedine Al-Qassam Brigades, said it fired a barrage of rockets from the Gaza Strip towards Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli military and officials accuse Sinwar of being one of the masterminds of the October 7 attack on Israel, making him one of the country's most wanted operatives.</p>

<p>His appointment as the new chief of Hamas comes less than a week after Haniyeh was killed in Tehran.</p>

<p>Iran and Hamas have blamed Israel for his assassination. Israel has declined to comment on the killing.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the death of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>During the attack, Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has so far killed at least 39,653 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c59v6a28_hamas-leader-yehya-alsinwar_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-academic-convicted-of-acting-as-foreign-agent-in-us-6279223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Academic Convicted Of Acting As Foreign Agent In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-academic-convicted-of-acting-as-foreign-agent-in-us-6279223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:31:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Wang Shujun was a naturalised US citizen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese academic was convicted on Tuesday of illegally acting as a foreign agent in the United States by collecting information about New York-based activists supporting democracy in China and sharing his findings with Beijing.</p>

<p>A jury found Wang Shujun guilty on four counts including acting as a foreign agent without notifying the US attorney general and lying to US authorities, following a week-long trial in Brooklyn federal court.</p>

<p>Federal prosecutors said Wang, a naturalised US citizen, portrayed himself as a fierce opponent of the ruling Chinese Communist Party to gain the trust of Hong Kong pro-democracy activists, advocates for Taiwanese independence and campaigners for Uyghur and Tibetan rights.</p>

<p>Prosecutors said Wang was actually spying on the activists and sharing his findings with four officials in China's Ministry of State Security (MSS), an intelligence service.</p>

<p>"He was living a double life," prosecutor Nina Gupta said in her closing argument on Monday. "That double life has now been revealed."</p>

<p>Wang, who emigrated to the United States in 1994, was arrested in March 2022.</p>

<p>Defense lawyer Zachary Margulis-Ohnuma said Wang spoke to the intelligence officials about the pro-democracy movement to win their support and promote social change, and was not acting as their agent.</p>

<p>"Why would a guy who devoted his life to toppling the Chinese regime try to help the Chinese regime?" Margulis-Ohnuma said in his summation on Monday.</p>

<p>The US Department of Justice has in recent years cracked down on what it calls "transnational repression" by US adversaries such as China and Iran.</p>

<p>That term refers to the surveillance, intimidation and in some cases attempted repatriation or murder of activists against those governments.</p>

<p>Last year, a former New York City police sergeant was convicted of acting as a Chinese agent by intimidating a US-based fugitive to return to his homeland and face charges.</p>

<p>US prosecutors have also charged four Chinese intelligence officers who allegedly acted as Wang's handlers. Those officers are at large and believed to be in China.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/889t6t5_chinese-academic-spy-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Department of Justice has cracked down on what it calls "transnational repression" by US adversaries]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-confirms-death-of-last-missing-person-from-october-7-attack-6279222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Confirms Death Of Last Missing Person From October 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-confirms-death-of-last-missing-person-from-october-7-attack-6279222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:31:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military confirmed on Tuesday that Bilha Yinon, the last person listed as missing from the October 7 Hamas attack, was killed by militants that day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military confirmed on Tuesday that Bilha Yinon, the last person listed as missing from the October 7 Hamas attack, was killed by Hamas that day.</p>

<p>"Today, IDF (Israel army) representatives officially informed the family of Bilha Yinon that she is no longer alive," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Israeli military and investigators had carried out an extensive search for her, the statement said.</p>

<p>"As part of this effort, evidence was discovered in the area of Yinon's house that, after complex testing, enabled the verification of her identity," it said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are devastated to share that Bilha Yinon who is the last person missing since October 7th has been confimed as dead.<br />
<br />
She was murdered alongside her husband Yaakov on October 7.<br />
<br />
May Bilha and Yaakov's memory be a blessing ? <a href="https://t.co/J6UR9OVmLl">pic.twitter.com/J6UR9OVmLl</a></p>
— Israel ישראל (@Israel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel/status/1820879796848791664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Based on forensic evidence, Israeli experts determined that she was killed on October 7, the military added.</p>

<p>Hamas attacked southern Israeli communities on that day, resulting in the death of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has so far killed at least 39,653 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fsqgfopg_bilha-yinon_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military and investigators had carried out an extensive search for her]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovery-of-tiny-arm-bone-sheds-light-on-mysterious-hobbit-humans-6279069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Discovery Of Tiny Arm Bone Sheds Light On Mysterious ''Hobbit'' Humans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovery-of-tiny-arm-bone-sheds-light-on-mysterious-hobbit-humans-6279069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:07:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The discovery of a tiny arm bone suggests that an ancient human dubbed "hobbits" only shrank down to their diminutive size after they arrived on an Indonesian island a million years ago, scientists said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The discovery of a tiny arm bone suggests that an ancient human dubbed "hobbits" only shrank down to their diminutive size after they arrived on an Indonesian island a million years ago, scientists said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Much about the pint-sized Homo floresiensis has been shrouded in mystery since the first fossils suggesting their existence were found on the island of Flores in 2003.</p>

<p>These tool-using hominins are believed to have been living on the island as recently as 50,000 years ago, when our own species homo sapiens was already walking the Earth, including in nearby Australia.</p>

<p>From some 60,000-year-old teeth and a jawbone found in an island cave, scientists had previously estimated the hobbits were around 1.06 metres (3.5 feet) tall.</p>

<p>But the discovery of part of an upper arm bone as well as some teeth at an open-air island site on the island suggests some hobbits stood just one metre tall around 700,000 years ago, according to a study in the journal Nature Communications.</p>

<p>The bone was so small, that at first the international team of researchers thought it must have been from a child.</p>

<p>Study co-author Adam Brumm, an archaeologist at Australia's Griffith University, told AFP that it was the smallest humerus fossil of an adult hominin ever found.</p>

<h3><strong>'Truly epic'</strong></h3>

<p>The discovery could tip the scales in a heated debate among scientists about how H.floresiensis became so small.</p>

<p>One side argues that the hobbits -- nicknamed after the little heroes in JRR Tolkien's fantasy novels -- descended from an already small earlier hominin which arrived on Flores around a million years ago.</p>

<p>Others believe that it was our ancestor Homo erectus, which were roughly our size and had spread throughout Asia, that became trapped on the island, only to then evolve into the smaller H.floresiensis over the next 300,00 years.</p>

<p>The researchers behind the latest discovery believe it strongly supports the latter theory.</p>

<p>These ancient humans "reduced drastically in body size according to a well known evolutionary phenomenon known as island dwarfism," Brumm said.</p>

<p>Under this process, larger animals tend to shrink over time to adapt to their limited surroundings.</p>

<p>The tropical island was home to other smaller-than-normal mammals, including a cow-sized relative of the elephant.</p>

<p>The newly discovered teeth also look like smaller versions of those from Homo erectus, the researchers said.</p>

<p>"If we are correct, it seems that Homo erectus was somehow able to cross formidable deep-sea barriers to reach isolated islands like Flores," Brumm said.</p>

<p>"We don't know how they were doing this," he said, adding that "accidental 'rafting' on tsunami debris" was one possibility.</p>

<p>Once these ancient humans were trapped on the island, they managed to survive for hundreds of thousands of years, evolving into "strange new forms," Brumm said.</p>

<p>Mark Moore, an archaeologist at Australia's University of New England not involved in the study, said the discovery means "we can now confidently say" that the Homo erectus theory is the more likely scenario.</p>

<p>Moore, who has studied the stone tools used by the hobbits, told AFP that this "technology did not shield our cousin species from the forces of biological evolution".</p>

<p>That the hobbits changed so much over just 300,000 years was "a reminder of the power of natural selection," he added.</p>

<p>"The evolutionary story of this group of hominins is truly epic."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kn94i4j8_hobbit-humans_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The newly discovered teeth also look like smaller versions of those from Homo erectus]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-biden-calls-kamala-harris-pick-for-vice-president-tim-walz-a-great-decision-6279068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Powerful Voice For People": Biden On Kamala Harris' Vice President Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-biden-calls-kamala-harris-pick-for-vice-president-tim-walz-a-great-decision-6279068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:07:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Tim Walz would be a "powerful voice for working people and America's great middle class."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Tuesday praised the selection of Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as Kamala Harris's running mate, saying they would be a "powerful voice for working people and America's great middle class."</p>

<p>"The first major decision a party nominee makes is their choice for vice president. And Kamala Harris has made a great decision in choosing Governor Tim Walz to be her running mate," Biden posted on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mi5arts_tim-walz-and-biden-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said Tim Walz would be a "powerful voice for working people and America's great middle class."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regained-freedom-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-bangladeshis-dream-of-better-future-6278690]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Sheikh Hasina's Ouster, Bangladeshis Dream Of Better Future]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regained-freedom-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-bangladeshis-dream-of-better-future-6278690]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 22:04:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One day after the military took control of Bangladesh following the ouster of the prime minister, the parliament in the capital Dhaka was busy with protesters coming to celebrate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One day after the military took control of Bangladesh following the ouster of the prime minister, the parliament in the capital Dhaka was busy with protesters coming to celebrate.</p>

<p>More than a month of deadly protests in which at least 422 people were killed culminated Monday in the deadliest day of violence and the end of the autocratic rule of Sheikh Hasina, who fled by helicopter to India.</p>

<p>"It's the freedom of the young generation," said student Parvez Hossain, 30, among the crowds in front of the building, which was empty of lawmakers after parliament was dissolved.</p>

<p>Protesters stormed the building on Monday, jumping on tables and setting off what appeared to be smoke bombs.</p>

<p>Hossain spoke of his hope for a new start and idealism for a better future.</p>

<p>"Now we have regained the freedom of Bangladesh," he said. "We want to build the country in a new way again."</p>

<p>The unrest began last month with student-led protests against civil service job quotas and escalated into mass demonstrations calling for Hasina, who had been in power since 2009, to quit.</p>

<p>But while busy streets and open shops in Dhaka gave the initial appearance that daily life was nearly back to business as usual, at least 10 people were killed on Tuesday, and security remained a concern.</p>

<p>The charred ruins of offices of the former ruling party and looted houses of those seen loyal to Hasina showed the scale of bitter violence in the chaos at the end of her rule.</p>

<p>That included violence against police who reported revenge attacks by those who blamed officers for trying to crush protests with deadly force.</p>

<h3><strong>'Anger of the people'</strong></h3>

<p>Police unions said their members had gone on strike Tuesday "until the security of every member of the police is secured".</p>

<p>The union also apologised for police actions against the protesters.</p>

<p>With the police on strike, citizens took it upon themselves to direct traffic, with students standing at junctions and bringing some order to the stream of cars.</p>

<p>Nazrul Islam, 60, who works in pharmaceuticals, said students had lit the spark to allow people to protest wider grievances.</p>

<p>"With the students' protest, the anger of the people also burst. It was impossible to stop this wave," he said.</p>

<p>"Everyone had a hidden anger. Now we just want that no dictator can come to power again."</p>

<p>Some businesses and homes owned by Hindus -- a group seen by some in the Muslim-majority nation as close to Hasina -- were also attacked, witnesses said.</p>

<p>Bangladeshi rights groups, as well as US and European Union diplomats, said Tuesday they were "very concerned" about reports of attacks on religious, ethnic and other minority groups.</p>

<p>Curious citizens, meanwhile, picked through the ransacked interior of Hasina's palace in Dhaka, clicking photographs in front of her trashed furniture and marvelling at the opulent luxury.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's new leadership now rests on the powerful army who have said they will form an interim government.</p>

<p>But whatever the future may be, 60-year-old bicycle rickshaw taxi driver Nurul Islam said he was pleased Hasina was gone.</p>

<p>"People didn't have any peace for the last 15 years," he said, pausing to rest in the bustling street.</p>

<p>"She was not elected even by the people's votes; rather, she captured power as a dictator."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/doatd29g_bangladesh-protest_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh's new leadership now rests on the powerful army]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ultra-orthodox-anti-draft-protesters-break-into-israeli-army-base-6278456]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ultra-Orthodox Anti-draft Protesters Break Into Israeli Army Base]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ultra-orthodox-anti-draft-protesters-break-into-israeli-army-base-6278456]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 21:31:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of ultra-Orthodox Jews protesting against compulsory military service for their community broke into an army base near Tel Aviv on Tuesday, the military said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of ultra-Orthodox Jews protesting against compulsory military service for their community broke into an army base near Tel Aviv on Tuesday, the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Over the past few hours, dozens of protestors attempted to break into the Tel Hashomer base during protests that took place outside of the base", a military statement said.</p>

<p>The demonstrators "managed to infiltrate the Adjutant Corps Monument adjacent to the base fence" before being cleared out by police, it said.</p>

<p>Tel Hashomer, located east of Tel Aviv, is the largest base for newly enlisted army recruits in Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it "condemns this violent behaviour and insists that the protestors be brought to justice".</p>

<p>"The enlistment of ultra-orthodox citizens is an operational necessity and is being conducted in accordance with the law", and the military is "determined" to press ahead with it, the statement added</p>

<p>Historically exempt from compulsory military service, ultra-Orthodox seminary students are being called up while Israel's war in Gaza and a potential conflict with Hezbollah on the northern border sap resources and fuel resentment of those who do not have to serve.</p>

<p>The call-ups follow a ruling in June by Israel's top court that exemptions from mandatory service for ultra-Orthodox men were discriminatory and that the state must draft them.</p>

<p>Under longstanding arrangements, ultra-Orthodox Jews, who make up about 13 percent of Israel's 10 million population, had not been subject to the draft.</p>

<p>Members of the largely insular community, where young men of recruitment age typically study in Jewish seminaries, have taken to the streets to protest conscription, leading to clashes with police in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>Ultra-Orthodox men had already clashed with police outside Tal Hashomer on Monday before being dispersed or physically carried away.</p>

<p>In July, one leading ultra-Orthodox rabbi, Dov Lando, urged Yeshiva students to ignore the summons orders, writing in the Yated Neeman daily that it was "war" against religious Jews.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6bqqoldo_israel-flag_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-tim-walz-says-honor-of-a-lifetime-to-be-kamala-harriss-vice-president-pick-6278344]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tim Walz Says "Honor Of A Lifetime" To Be Kamala Harris's Veep Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-tim-walz-says-honor-of-a-lifetime-to-be-kamala-harriss-vice-president-pick-6278344]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 21:18:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["I'm all in. It reminds me a bit of the first day of school. So, let's get this done, folks!" Walz said on X.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris's newly unveiled running mate Tim Walz said Tuesday it was "the honor of a lifetime" to be the Democratic Party's vice presidential candidate for the US election in November.</p>

<p>"I'm all in. It reminds me a bit of the first day of school. So, let's get this done, folks!" Walz said on X.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/phkib1e_tim-walz-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tim Walz said it was "honor of a lifetime" to be the Democratic Party's vice presidential candidate]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-aircraft-fly-at-low-altitude-over-beirut-breaking-sound-barrier-6277717]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Panic In Beirut As Israeli Warplanes Break Sound Barrier Thrice]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-aircraft-fly-at-low-altitude-over-beirut-breaking-sound-barrier-6277717]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 19:48:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli warplanes swooped low over the Lebanese capital Beirut on Tuesday, setting off a series of sonic booms that rattled windows across the city minutes before the head of Lebanon's Hezbollah was set to give an address.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli warplanes swooped low over the Lebanese capital Beirut on Tuesday, setting off a series of sonic booms that rattled windows across the city minutes before the head of Lebanon's Hezbollah was set to give an address.</p>

<p>The loud booms sent residents rushing to open their windows to prevent the glass from shattering, or standing on their balconies to get a glimpse of the planes flying over. There was no comment from the Israeli military.</p>

<p>In the capital's southern suburbs, a Hezbollah stronghold, members and supporters of the Lebanese armed group had gathered to watch a televised speech by its leader to mark the one-week anniversary of Israel's killing of a senior military commander.</p>

<p>As he began, Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah said the sonic booms were intended to provoke those gathered for the memorial.</p>

<p>The strike that killed commander Fuad Shukr was the second time Israel had struck the southern suburbs in 10 months of hostilities between Hezbollah and the Israeli military that are taking place in parallel with the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah earlier on Tuesday said it launched a swarm of attack drones at two military sites near Acre in northern Israel and also attacked an Israeli military vehicle in another location.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said a number of hostile drones were identified crossing from Lebanon and one was intercepted.</p>

<p>Israeli medical officials said seven people were evacuated to hospital, to the south of the coastal city of Nahariya, one in critical condition.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said an initial investigation indicated the injuries were caused by an interceptor that "missed the target and hit the ground, injuring several civilians." It said the incident was still under review.</p>

<p>Reuters journalists saw one impact site near a bus stop on a main road outside Nahariya.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement sirens sounded around Acre, but that turned out to be a false alarm. It said its air force struck two Hezbollah facilities in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>Fears are rising that the Middle East could tip into full-blown war following vows by Hezbollah to avenge Shukr's killing, and by Iran to respond to the assassination in Tehran last week of the head of Palestinian group Hamas.</p>

<p>A Hezbollah source told Reuters that "the response to the assassination of commander Fuad Shukr has not yet come".</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, four Hezbollah fighters were killed in a strike on a home in the Lebanese town of Mayfadoun, nearly 30 km (19 miles) north of the border, medics and a security source said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i0gaa9mo_israel-lebanon_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli warplanes flew low over the Lebanese capital]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-000-specialist-police-ready-to-deal-with-uk-far-right-riots-government-6277659]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6,000 Specialist Police Ready To Deal With UK Far-Right Riots: Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-000-specialist-police-ready-to-deal-with-uk-far-right-riots-government-6277659]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 19:39:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK government said on Tuesday that 6,000 specialist police were ready to deal with far-right rioting after another night of destructive troubles in English cities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK government said on Tuesday that 6,000 specialist police were ready to deal with far-right rioting after another night of destructive troubles in English cities.</p>

<p>There has been a week of nightly riots in various cities since three children were killed in a mass stabbing.</p>

<p>On Monday, six people were arrested and several police officers injured when they were attacked by rioters hurling bricks and fireworks in Plymouth, southern England.</p>

<p>Officers in Belfast, Northern Ireland, were attacked as rioters attempted to set fire to a shop owned by a foreign national. Police said a man in his 30s was seriously assaulted and that they are treating the incident as a racially motivated hate crime.</p>

<p>A group of men who gathered in Birmingham, central England, to counter a rumoured far-right demonstration, forced a Sky News reporter off air shouting: "Free Palestine". She was then followed by a man in a balaclava holding a knife.</p>

<p>Another reporter said he was chased by members of the group "with what looked like a weapon", while police said there had also been incidents of criminal damage to a pub and a car.</p>

<p>Unrest broke out last Tuesday after three children were killed at a Taylor Swift-themed dance class in Southport, northwest England.</p>

<p>There have been hundreds of arrests around riots that have flared up since.</p>

<p>Justice minister Heidi Alexander told BBC Radio 4 &nbsp;that the government had freed up an extra 500 prison places and drafted in 6,000 specialist police officers to deal with the violence.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer again sought to reassure the nation that action was being taken.</p>

<p>He said after a cabinet meeting: "99.9% of people across the country want their streets to be safe and to feel safe in their communities, and we will take all necessary action to bring the disorder to an end."</p>

<h3><strong>False rumours</strong></h3>

<p>Mobs threw bricks and flares, attacked police, burnt and looted shops, smashed the windows of cars and homes and targeted at least two hotels housing asylum seekers at the weekend.</p>

<p>The National Police Chiefs' Council (NPCC) said Monday that 378 people had so far been arrested. </p>

<p>Clashes broke out in Southport the day after three young girls were killed and five more children critically injured during the knife attack there.</p>

<p>False rumours initially spread on social media saying the attacker was a Muslim asylum seeker.</p>

<p>The suspect was later identified as 17-year-old Axel Rudakubana, born in Wales. UK media reported that his parents are from Rwanda.</p>

<p>That has not stopped mosques from being targeted by rioters and the government has offered extra security to Islamic places of worship.</p>

<p>In Burnley, northwest England, a hate crime investigation was underway after gravestones in a Muslim section of a cemetery were vandalised with grey paint.</p>

<p>"What type of evil individual(s) would undertake such outrageous actions, in a sacrosanct place of reflection, where loved ones are buried, solely intended to provoke racial tensions?", local councillor Afrasiab Anwar said.</p>

<p>The government, only one month old, has vowed to take a tough line on the unrest.</p>

<p>The prime minister warned rioters on Sunday that they would "regret" participating in England's worst disorder in 13 years.</p>

<p>Interior minister Yvette Cooper said "there will be a reckoning".</p>

<p>Cooper also said that social media put a "rocket booster" under the violence.</p>

<p>Starmer stressed that "criminal law applies online as well as offline", with arrests already being made in relation to posts made on Facebook and Snapchat.</p>

<p>Police have blamed the violence on people associated with the now-defunct English Defence League, a far-right Islamophobic organisation founded 15 years ago, whose supporters have been linked to football hooliganism.</p>

<p>The rallies have been advertised on far-right social media channels under the banner "Enough is enough".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/iukik21_uk-riots_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-says-ready-to-head-interim-government-in-bangladesh-report-6277527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Winner Yunus Says Ready To Head Interim Government In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-says-ready-to-head-interim-government-in-bangladesh-report-6277527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 19:22:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel winner Muhammad Yunus said on Tuesday he was ready to head an interim government in Bangladesh after mass demonstrations forced longtime ruler Sheikh Hasina to flee the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh Nobel winner Muhammad Yunus said Tuesday he is ready to head a caretaker government, a day after the military took control as mass protests forced longtime ruler Sheikh Hasina to flee.</p>

<p>Microfinance pioneer Yunus, 84, is credited with lifting millions out of poverty -- earning the enmity of ousted Hasina and the wide respect of millions of Bangladeshis.</p>

<p>"If action is needed in Bangladesh, for my country and for the courage of my people, then I will take it," he told AFP in a statement, also calling for "free elections", after student leaders called for him to lead an interim government.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, had been in power since 2009 but was accused of rigging elections in January and then watched millions of people take to the streets over the past month demanding she quit.</p>

<p>Hundreds of people were killed as security forces sought to quell the unrest but the protests grew and Hasina finally fled aboard a helicopter on Monday after the military turned against her.</p>

<p>Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman announced Monday the military would form an interim government, saying it was "time to stop the violence".</p>

<p>The president dissolved parliament on Tuesday, a key demand of the student leaders and the major opposition Bangladesh National Party (BNP), which has demanded elections within three months.</p>

<h3><strong>'In Dr. Yunus we trust'</strong></h3>

<p>"In Dr. Yunus, we trust," Asif Mahmud, a key leader of the Students Against Discrimination (SAD) group, wrote on Facebook.</p>

<p>The military on Tuesday reshuffled several top generals, demoting some seen as close to Hasina, and sacking Ziaul Ahsan, a commander of the feared and US-sanctioned Rapid Action Battalion paramilitary force.</p>

<p>Ex-prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia, 78, was also released from years of house arrest, a presidential statement and her party said.</p>

<p>Streets in the capital were largely peaceful on Tuesday -- with traffic resuming, shops opening and international flights resuming at Dhaka's airport -- but government offices were mainly closed a day after chaotic violence in which at least 122 people were killed.</p>

<p>Millions of Bangladeshis flooded the streets of Dhaka to celebrate after Waker's announcement on Monday -- and jubilant crowds also stormed and looted Hasina's official residence.</p>

<p>"We have been freed from a dictatorship", said Sazid Ahnaf, 21, comparing the events to the independence war that split the nation from Pakistan more than five decades ago.</p>

<h3><strong>Deadliest day</strong></h3>

<p>Police said mobs had launched revenge attacks on Hasina's allies and their own officers, as well as broke into a prison, releasing more than 500 inmates.</p>

<p>Monday was the deadliest day since protests began in early July, with a further 10 people killed on Tuesday, taking the total toll overall to at least 432, according to an AFP tally based on police, government officials and doctors at hospitals.</p>

<p>Protesters broke into parliament and torched TV stations. Others smashed statues of Hasina's father, Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, Bangladesh's independence hero.</p>

<p>Some businesses and homes owned by Hindus -- a group seen by some in the Muslim-majority nation as close to Hasina -- were also attacked, witnesses said.</p>

<p>Bangladeshi rights groups, as well as US and European Union diplomats, said Tuesday they were "very concerned" about reports of attacks on religious, ethnic and other minority groups.</p>

<p>Key police unions said their members had declared a strike "until the security of every member of the police is secured", offering their "apology" for police actions against the protesters.</p>

<p>Key regional allies of Bangladesh, neighbouring India and China, both called for calm on Tuesday.</p>

<p>China hopes that "social stability can be restored in Bangladesh" soon, the foreign ministry in Beijing said on Tuesday, while Indian foreign minister S. Jaishankar said he was "deeply concerned till law and order is visibly restored".</p>

<h3><strong>Political prisoners freed</strong></h3>

<p>The unrest began last month with protests against civil service job quotas and escalated into wider calls for Hasina to stand down.</p>

<p>Her government was accused by rights groups of misusing state institutions to entrench its hold on power and stamp out dissent, including through the extrajudicial killing of opposition activists.</p>

<p>Mothers of some of the hundreds of political prisoners secretly jailed under Hasina's rule waited outside a military intelligence building in Dhaka on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"We need answers," said campaigner Sanjida Islam Tulee.</p>

<p>The fate of Hasina, now in India, is also uncertain.</p>

<p>A source had said she wanted to go to London but calls by the British government for a UN-led investigation into the "unprecedented" violence put that in doubt.</p>

<p>Thomas Kean from the International Crisis Group said the new authorities faced a daunting challenge.</p>

<p>"The interim government that will now assume power... needs to embark on the long task of rebuilding democracy in Bangladesh, which has been so badly eroded in recent years," he said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8v0rqhuo_muhammad-yunus-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-points-on-tim-walz-kamala-harris-veep-pick-who-calls-trump-weird-6277390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Points On Tim Walz, Kamala Harris' Veep Pick Who Calls Trump "Weird"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-points-on-tim-walz-kamala-harris-veep-pick-who-calls-trump-weird-6277390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 19:05:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Making one of the most consequential decisions of her campaign, the US Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris has picked Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as her running mate, reports have said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Born in Nebraska, the 60-year-old Minnesota Governor is a US Army National Guard veteran and has also been a teacher.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>A former member of Congress who was elected from a Republican-leaning district, polls have shown that Tim Walz appeals to rural, white voters. He is also known for advancing progressive policies as the Minnesota governor, including paid worker leave and free meals in schools.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Mr Walz taught in China's Guangdong province around the time of the 1989 unrest in Tiananmen square. He has taught geography, coached a school's football team in Minnesota and, in 1999, was also reportedly the faculty adviser for the school's first gay-straight alliance chapter.</li>
	<li>Ms Harris' vice-presidential pick enlisted in the US Army National Guard at the age of 17 and served for 24 years. He first ran for office in 2006 and won the gubernatorial elections in 2018 and 2022. He is now the chair of the Democratic Governors Association.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The Minnesota Governor is also credited with calling the Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump and his running mate JD Vance "weird". This was picked up by other Democrats and eventually by Ms Harris as well. The label has been used frequently and Mr Trump and the Republicans have not been able to come up with a hard-hitting response. &nbsp;<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/puciias8_tim-walz_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polls have shown that Tim Walz appeals to rural, white voters]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-riots-elon-musk-hits-back-at-keir-starmer-with-family-guy-meme-6277383]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Riots: Elon Musk Hits Back At Keir Starmer With 'Family Guy' Meme]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-riots-elon-musk-hits-back-at-keir-starmer-with-family-guy-meme-6277383]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 19:03:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In his recent tweet, Musk, the billionaire owner of X, slammed the UK government again with a 'Family Guy' meme.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A war of words broke out between Elon Musk and the prime minister Keir Starmer over riots gripping the UK. In his recent tweet, Musk, the billionaire owner of X, slammed the UK government again with a 'Family Guy' meme and wrote, "In 2030 for making a Facebook comment that the UK government didn't like."</p>

<p>The picture shows the main character of Family Guy, Peter Griffin, getting the death penalty for cracking a joke.</p>

<p><strong>See the post here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In 2030 for making a Facebook comment that the UK government didn't like <a href="https://t.co/UhKDLeCPJb">pic.twitter.com/UhKDLeCPJb</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1820799076310352124?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The internet users were quick to react to the meme.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A user wrote, "The UK is quickly becoming Communist China."</p>

<p>Another user commented, "In 2040 just for existing."</p>

<p>"The UK has officially fallen," the third user commented.</p>

<p>Earlier, Mr. Musk sparked a dispute with Downing Street over UK riots, amid concerns that online disinformation is fueling the unrest.</p>

<p>Commenting on his social media site under a video of rioters setting off fireworks at police, Musk stated, "Civil war is inevitable."</p>

<p>The prime minister's spokesperson quickly dismissed Musk's comment, asserting there is "no justification for comments like that" and warning that "anyone who is whipping up violence online will face the full force of the law."</p>

<p>Musk later responded to a social media post from Sir Keir Starmer that condemned violence against Muslims. Mosques and hotels housing asylum seekers have been among the targets of far-right demonstrations.</p>

<p>Sir Keir declared that the unrest "is not protest, it is pure violence," and emphasized, "We will not tolerate attacks on mosques or Muslim communities."</p>

<p>Musk replied: "Shouldn't you be concerned about attacks on all communities?"</p>

<p>The dispute risks undermining government efforts to hold social media companies accountable for removing harmful online content believed to be inciting some of the violence.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8trrs42_elon-musk_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The internet users were quick to react to the meme.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-gets-life-in-prison-for-tying-girlfriend-to-signpost-before-watching-her-die-6277252]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Tied Girlfriend To Signpost In Nevada Desert Before Watching Her Die]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-gets-life-in-prison-for-tying-girlfriend-to-signpost-before-watching-her-die-6277252]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:49:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US man, who convinced his girlfriend to drive to a desert, where he then tied her to a post and watched her die, has been sentenced to life in prison.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US man, who convinced his girlfriend to drive to a desert, where he then tied her to a post and watched her die, has been sentenced to life in prison. According to <em>People</em>, the incident took place in 2019. On Friday, John Matthew Chapman, 44, was convicted on one count of kidnapping resulting in the death of the woman, identified as 33-year-old Jaime Feden. He was arrested in November 2019, following which he admitted to killing his girlfriend for money.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The defendant violated the victim's trust by luring her away from her family and friends in Pennsylvania and out into the Nevada desert where he viciously killed her," said US Attorney Jason M Frierson in a statement. "This sentence should send a clear message to others that kidnapping and killing another person will result in a substantial prison sentence," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Citing a federal criminal complaint, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/man-lured-girlfriend-desert-bondate-photo-shoot-tied-post-watched-die-8690556">outlet </a>reported that the 44-year-old initially told Ms Feden they were driving to Nevada from Pennsylvania to potentially buy a home in Las Vegas in September 2019. While in Nevada, he then convinced Ms Feden to drive into the desert to participate in a "bandage photoshoot".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Once there, prosecutors said that Chapman zip-tied Ms Feden's hands and feet to a signpost before covering her nose and mount with duct tape. He watched Ms Feden suffocate, and then after she had died, he removed the tape, zip ties and her clothes and left her body in the desert.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-us-man-killed-newlywed-wife-21-and-left-head-in-shower-cops-6276590">23-Year-Old US Man Killed Newlywed Wife, 21, And Left Head In Shower: Cops</a></strong></p>

<p>Prosecutors said that Chapman had a plan to kill Ms Feden before they went on the trip. Ms Feden's body was found in the desert in October 2019. According to prosecutors, after committing the crime, Chapman drove back to Pennsylvania, discarding Ms Feden's clothes along the way.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In November 2019, Ms Feden's friend requested a welfare check. Neighbours told the cops they hadn't seen the 33-year-old for months, but they also said that had seen someone they believed to be her boyfriend coming in and out of her home.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Inside the woman's house, cops found Chapman's ID, Ms Feden's cell phone and multiple rolls of duct tape and zip ties.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Following his arrest, prosecutors said Chapman admitted to killing Ms Feden for money.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-11/mj0et6cc_man-in-prison-generic-_625x300_22_November_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chapman has admitted to killing Ms Feden for money. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-key-points-on-mohammed-shahabuddin-the-president-of-bangladesh-6277213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Key Points On Mohammed Shahabuddin, President Of Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-key-points-on-mohammed-shahabuddin-the-president-of-bangladesh-6277213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:41:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, Shahabuddin dissolved parliament and paved the way for the formation of an interim government and new elections, with army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman scheduled to meet student leaders to discuss further steps.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mohammed Shahabuddin, the president of Bangladesh since <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mohammad-shahabuddin-takes-oath-as-bangladeshs-new-president-3974077" target="_blank">April 2023</a>, is the country's sole top constitutional authority since Sheikh Hasina resigned as prime minister and fled to India on Monday.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Shahabuddin dissolved parliament and paved the way for the formation of an interim government and new elections, with army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman scheduled to meet student leaders to discuss further steps.</p>

<h3><strong>Here are five facts about Shahabuddin:</strong></h3>

<p>* Born in 1949 in Pabna in what was East Pakistan before it won independence and Bangladesh was born. As a student, he actively participated in the fight for independence from Pakistan in 1971.</p>

<p>* Independence leader and Sheikh Hasina's father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman made Shahabuddin a district joint secretary in the Bangladesh Krishak Sramik Awami League, a political front of farmers and workers which included the Awami League party, in 1975.</p>

<p>* Shahabuddin spent three years in jail after Rahman's assassination in 1975.</p>

<p>* A former district judge, Shahabuddin headed a investigation panel that probed violence against Awami League members and supporters when the party was in the opposition.</p>

<p>* With Ms Hasina as prime minister, Shahabuddin was elected unopposed as the country's president.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/s8oagk98_mohammed-shahabuddin-facebook_625x300_24_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shahabuddin spent three years in jail after Rahman's assassination in 1975 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-bangladeshs-banker-to-the-poor-6277155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus: Bangladesh's 'Banker To The Poor']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-bangladeshs-banker-to-the-poor-6277155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:34:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus has been asked by Bangladeshi protest leaders to helm an interim government to replace ousted premier Sheikh Hasina, who had hounded him in speeches and through the courts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus has been asked by Bangladeshi protest leaders to helm an interim government to replace ousted premier Sheikh Hasina, who had hounded him in speeches and through the courts.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old, known as the "banker to the poorest of the poor", was awarded the Peace Prize in 2006 for his work loaning small cash sums to rural women, allowing them to invest in farm tools or business equipment and boost their earnings.</p>

<p>Grameen Bank, the microfinance lender he founded, was lauded for helping unleash breakneck economic growth in Bangladesh, and its work has since been copied by scores of developing countries.</p>

<p>"Human beings are not born to suffer the misery of hunger and poverty," Yunus said during his Nobel lecture, daring his audience to imagine a world where deprivation was confined to history museums.</p>

<p>But his public profile in Bangladesh earned him the hostility of Hasina, who once accused him of "sucking blood" from the poor.</p>

<p>Before her hurried resignation and departure from Bangladesh on Monday, Hasina's 15-year tenure was characterised by a growing intolerance of dissent, and Yunus's popularity marked him as a potential rival.</p>

<p>In 2007, Yunus announced plans to set up his own "Citizen Power" party to end Bangladesh's confrontational political culture, which has been punctuated by instability and periods of military rule.</p>

<p>He abandoned those ambitions within months, but the enmity aroused by his challenge to the ruling elite has persisted.</p>

<p>Yunus was hit with more than 100 criminal cases and a smear campaign by a state-led Islamic agency that accused him of promoting homosexuality.</p>

<p>The government unceremoniously forced him out of Grameen Bank in 2011 -- a decision fought by Yunus but upheld by Bangladesh's top court.</p>

<p>In January he and three colleagues from one of the companies he founded were sentenced to jail terms of six months -- but immediately bailed pending appeal -- by a Dhaka labour court which found they had illegally failed to create a workers' welfare fund.</p>

<p>All four had denied the charges and, with courts accused of rubber-stamping decisions by Hasina's government, the case was criticised as politically motivated by watchdogs including Amnesty International.</p>

<p>Student leaders whose protest campaign culminated in Hasina's ouster on Monday were expected to meet with the military to demand Yunus lead a caretaker government.</p>

<p>Yunus has not commented on the call for him to lead but he said in an interview with India's The Print that Bangladesh had been "an occupied country" under Hasina.</p>

<p>"Today all the people of Bangladesh feel liberated," it quoted him as saying.</p>

<h3><strong>'Poverty was all around me'</strong></h3>

<p>Yunus was born into a well-to-do family -- his father was a successful goldsmith -- in the coastal city of Chittagong in 1940.</p>

<p>He credits his mother, who offered help to anyone in need who knocked on their door, as his biggest influence.</p>

<p>Yunus won a Fulbright scholarship to study in the United States and returned soon after Bangladesh won its independence from Pakistan in a brutal 1971 war.</p>

<p>When he returned, he was chosen to head Chittagong University's economics department, but the young country was struggling through a severe famine and he felt compelled to take practical action.</p>

<p>"Poverty was all around me, and I could not turn away from it," he said in 2006.</p>

<p>"I found it difficult to teach elegant theories of economics in the university classroom... I wanted to do something immediate to help people around me."</p>

<p>After years of experimenting with ways to provide credit for people too poor to qualify for traditional bank loans, he founded Grameen Bank in 1983.</p>

<p>The institution now has more than nine million clients on its books, according to its most recent annual report (2020), and more than 97 percent of its borrowers are women.</p>

<p>Yunus has won numerous high honours for his life's work, including a US Presidential Medal of Freedom awarded by Barack Obama.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/po3eube8_muhammad-yunus_625x300_01_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yunus founded his Bank to offer credit for those too poor to qualify for traditional bank loans. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/minnesota-governor-tim-walz-to-be-kamala-harris-running-mate-reports-6277084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Minnesota Governor Tim Walz Is Kamala Harris' Running Mate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/minnesota-governor-tim-walz-to-be-kamala-harris-running-mate-reports-6277084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:29:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris selected Minnesota Governor Tim Walz to be her running mate on Tuesday, choosing a progressive policy champion and a plain speaker from America's heartland to help win over rural, white voters, said peo]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris selected Minnesota Governor Tim Walz to be her running mate on Tuesday, choosing a progressive policy champion and a plain speaker from America's heartland to help win over rural, white voters.</p>

<p>Harris announced the selection in a text message to supporters.</p>

<p>"I'm pleased to share that I've made my decision: Minnesota Governor Tim Walz will join our campaign as my running mate," she said. "Tim is a battle-tested leader who has an incredible track record of getting things done for Minnesota families. I know that he will bring that same principled leadership to our campaign, and to the office of the vice president."</p>

<p>Walz, a 60-year-old U.S. Army National Guard veteran and former teacher, was elected to a Republican-leaning district in the U.S. House of Representatives in 2006 and served 12 years before being elected governor of Minnesota in 2018.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am proud to announce that I've asked <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Tim_Walz</a> to be my running mate.<br />
<br />
As a governor, a coach, a teacher, and a veteran, he's delivered for working families like his.<br />
<br />
It's great to have him on the team.<br />
<br />
Now let's get to work. Join us:<a href="https://t.co/W4AE2WlMTj">https://t.co/W4AE2WlMTj</a></p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1820828396298879294?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>As governor, Walz has pushed a progressive agenda that includes free school meals, goals for tackling climate change, tax cuts for the middle class and expanded paid leave for Minnesota workers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Walz has long advocated for women's reproductive rights but also displayed a conservative bent while representing a rural district in the U.S. House, defending agricultural interests and backing gun rights.</p>

<p>Harris, the daughter of immigrants from Jamaica and India, is adding a popular Midwestern politician whose home state votes reliably for Democrats in presidential elections but is close to Wisconsin and Michigan, two crucial battlegrounds.</p>

<p>Such states are seen as critical in deciding the Nov. 5 election, and Walz is widely seen as skilled at connecting with white, rural voters who in recent years have voted broadly for Republican Donald Trump, Harris' rival for the White House.</p>

<p>Harris chose Walz over Josh Shapiro, the popular governor of Pennsylvania, who had been seen as helpful to delivering his crucial battleground state.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, became the Democratic Party's standard bearer after President Joe Biden, 81, ended his reelection campaign under party pressure last month. Since then, she has raised hundreds of millions of dollars and recast the race against Trump with a boost of energy from her party's base.</p>

<p>Harris was expected to appear with her running mate at an event in Philadelphia on Tuesday evening.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign hopes Walz's extensive National Guard career, coupled with a successful run as a high school football coach, and his Dad joke videos will attract rural voters who are not yet dedicated to a second Trump term in the White House.</p>

<p>Walz was a relative unknown nationally until the Harris "veepstakes" heated up, but his profile has since surged. A popular member of Congress, he reportedly had the backing of powerful former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, who was instrumental in persuading Biden to leave the race. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris and Walz will face Trump and his running mate JD Vance, also a military veteran from the Midwest, in the November election.</p>

<h3><strong>The George Floyd Factor In Walz's Tenure</strong></h3>

<p>Walz's tenure as governor was marked by the May 2020 killing of George Floyd, a Black man, by a white Minneapolis police officer who was convicted of murder. Walz assigned the state's attorney general to lead the prosecution in the case, saying people "don't believe justice can be served."</p>

<p>Rev. Al Sharpton, founder and president of National Action Network, said Walz had heard calls for justice for Floyd by tapping the attorney general.</p>

<p>"I learned then that he was a man who will listen and do what is right by those he represents," Sharpton said in a statement. "We can count on Governor Walz to take that same kind of open approach as Kamala Harris' vice president."</p>

<p>Trump campaign officials and surrogates quickly went to work trying to define Walz as a hardcore leftist whose values are out of touch with most Americans.</p>

<p>They criticized his handling of violent riots in Minneapolis following Floyd's death.</p>

<p>"It's no surprise that San Francisco Liberal Kamala Harris wants West Coast wannabe Tim Walz as her running-mate - Walz has spent his governorship trying to reshape Minnesota in the image of the Golden State," the Trump campaign said in a statement, a reference to California, Harris' home state.</p>

<h3><strong>Walz On The Attack</strong></h3>

<p>Walz has attacked Trump and Vance as "weird," a catchy insult that has been picked up by the Harris campaign, social media and Democratic activists.</p>

<p>Walz gave the nascent Harris campaign the new attack line in a late July interview: "These are weird people on the other side: They want to take books away. They want to be in your exam room," referring to book bans and women's reproductive consultations with doctors.</p>

<p>Walz has also assailed claims by Trump and Vance of having middle class credentials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They keep talking about the middle class. A robber baron real estate guy and a venture capitalist trying to tell us they understand who we are? They don't know who we are," Walz said in an MSNBC interview.</p>

<p>That approach has struck a chord with the young voters Harris needs to reengage. David Hogg, the co-founder of the gun safety group March for Our Lives, described him as a "great communicator."</p>

<p>Walz is "somewhat of a unicorn," said Ryan Dawkins, a political science professor at Minnesota's Carleton College - a man born in a small town in rural Nebraska capable of conveying Harris' message to core Democratic voters, and those that the party has failed to reach in recent years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dawkins praised his ability to connect with rural voters. It is a group the Biden administration has tried to reach with infrastructure spending and other pragmatic policies, but with little show of messaging success so far.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the 2016 election, Trump won 59% of rural voters; in 2020 that number rose to 65% even though Trump lost the election, according to Pew Research. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>In the 2022 governor's race, Walz won with 52.27% to his Republican opponent's 44.61%, although swaths of rural Minnesota voted for the opponent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While Walz has supported Democratic Party orthodoxy on issues ranging from legalized abortion and same-sex marriage to the Affordable Care Act, known as Obamacare, he also racked up a centrist voting record during his congressional career.</p>

<p>He was a staunch defender of government support for farmers and military veterans, as well as gun-owner rights that won praise from the National Rifle Association, according to The Almanac of American Politics.</p>

<p>He subsequently registered a failing grade with the NRA after supporting gun-control measures during his first campaign for governor.</p>

<p>Walz's shift from a centrist representing a single rural district in Congress to a more progressive politician as governor may have been in response to the demands of voters in major cities like Minneapolis-St. Paul. But it leaves him open to Republican attacks, Dawkins said in a telephone interview.</p>

<p>"He runs the risk of reinforcing some of the worst fears people have of Kamala Harris being a San Francisco liberal," Dawkins said.</p>

<p>Walz has a ready counter-attack.</p>

<p>"What a monster. Kids are eating and having full bellies, so they can go learn and women are making their own healthcare decisions," Walz said in a July CNN interview. "So if that's where they want to label me, I'm more than happy to take the label."</p>

<p>As the state's top executive, Walz mandated the use of face coverings during the COVID-19 pandemic and signed a law making marital rape illegal. He presided over several years of budget surpluses in Minnesota on the road to his 2022 reelection.</p>

<p>During that campaign, Walz touted the backing of several influential labor unions, including the state AFL-CIO, firefighters, Service Employees International Union (SEIU), teachers and others.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/45lqspo_tim-walz-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>