<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:05:20 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-man-who-allegedly-killed-42-women-to-be-in-police-custody-for-30-days-6120462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kenya Man Who Allegedly Killed 42 Women To Be In Police Custody For 30 days]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-man-who-allegedly-killed-42-women-to-be-in-police-custody-for-30-days-6120462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:54:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Kenyan court on Tuesday ordered a man who police said has confessed to murdering and dismembering 42 women to be detained for 30 days as they pursue their investigations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Kenyan court on Tuesday ordered a man who police said has confessed to murdering and dismembering 42 women to be detained for 30 days as they pursue their investigations.</p>

<p>Collins Jumaisi Khalusha, 33, described by police as a "vampire, a psychopath", was arrested in the early hours of Monday following the horrific discovery of mutilated bodies in a Nairobi garbage dump.</p>

<p>He appeared in a court in the Kenyan capital where the magistrate approved a police request for him to be held for 30 days to enable them to complete their probe.</p>

<p>Since Friday, 10 butchered female bodies trussed up in plastic bags have been hauled from the site of an abandoned quarry in the Nairobi slum of Mukuru, according to the Kenya National Commission on Human Rights.</p>

<p>The head of the Directorate of Criminal Investigations, Mohamed Amin, said Monday that Kalusha had confessed to murdering 42 women over a two-year period from 2022, and that his wife had been his first victim.</p>

<p>The DCI said in a statement Tuesday that investigators were holding another two "persons of interest", one of whom was allegedly found with the phone of one of the victims.</p>

<p><strong>Caught 'luring another victim'</strong></p>

<p>Kalusha was detained in the early hours of Monday near a bar where he had been watching the Euro 2024 football match, after officers analysed the phone of one of his alleged victims.</p>

<p>As officers swooped in, "he was in the process of luring another victim", Amin told reporters.</p>

<p>"We are dealing with a vampire, a psychopath," Amin said.</p>

<p>The grisly discoveries were made just 100 metres (yards) from a police station and the officers there have been transferred to ensure an unbiased investigation, acting national police chief Douglas Kanja said on Monday.</p>

<p>The area -- including Kalusha's home, also about 100 metres from where the bodies were found -- will remain "active crime scenes", Amin said.</p>

<p>The dumped bodies have thrown a spotlight on Kenyan police and added more pressure on President William Ruto, who is already confronting a crisis over protests that saw dozens of demonstrators killed and officers accused of using excessive force.</p>

<p>The state-funded KNCHR said it was carrying out its own investigations into the Mukuru case because "there is a need to rule out any possibility of extrajudicial killings".</p>

<p>Amnesty International said it had been directly involved in the retrieval of some of the bodies and had sent independent pathologists to attend postmortems of the victims.</p>

<p>"While it is the case that a multiple homicide crime has taken place, only completing these autopsies will confirm the ongoing investigation into the perpetrator of these murders," Irungu Houghton, executive director of Amnesty's Kenya branch, told AFP.</p>

<p>Kenya's police watchdog, the Independent Police Oversight Authority, had also said Friday it was looking into whether there was any police involvement or a "failure to act to prevent" the killings.</p>

<p>Tensions had run high at the crime scene over the weekend, as volunteers combed through the vast piles of rubbish in search of more victims with officers briefly firing tear gas to disperse the crowds.</p>

<p>Kenyan police are often accused by rights groups of carrying out unlawful killings or running hit squads, but few have faced justice.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rsf46q78_kenya-directorate-of-criminal-investigations_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We are dealing with a vampire, a psychopath," Mohamed Amin said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20th-century-airline-pan-am-to-return-to-skies-for-an-exclusive-flight-priced-at-rs-54-lakh-6120334]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pan Am To Return To Skies For An Exclusive Flight Priced At Rs 54 Lakh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20th-century-airline-pan-am-to-return-to-skies-for-an-exclusive-flight-priced-at-rs-54-lakh-6120334]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:35:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The circuit from New York to Bermuda, Lisbon, Portugal, Marseille, France, London, England and Foynes, Ireland, are among the locations on the "Tracing the Transatlantic" itinerary.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pan Am, an airline which is synonymous with glamorous and comfortable travel, is making a comeback in 2025. Even though the airline ceased operations in 1991, the name nevertheless evokes nostalgia and represents a time when the terms "selfie stick" and "overtourism" did not exist.The airline has announced a special, 12-day comeback journey next year from New York and it is priced at $65,500 (approximately Rs 54 lakh) for an individual ticket. A double occupancy ticket is available at a slight discount.</p>

<p>This amount includes a free "swag bag" and covers "most meals and beverages," as stated on the company's <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.criteriontravel.com/panam/index.html">website</a>. There are only 50 seats available and participants can reserve their spots by paying $5000.</p>

<p>The circuit from New York to Bermuda, Lisbon, Portugal, Marseille, France, London, England and Foynes, Ireland, are among the locations on the "Tracing the Transatlantic" itinerary that had special meaning for Pan Am and were once part of the airline's previous routes.</p>

<p>Passengers will board a Boeing 757-200 that has been privately chartered and is designated as "all business class." It will include "upscale catering featuring continental cuisine and an open bar on all flight legs," in addition to dedicated seats designed for "gathering/socializing."</p>

<p>As per a report in the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/15/lifestyle/panam-is-bringing-luxury-back-at-65000-per-ticket/">New York Post</a></em>, the guests would spend their nights in some of the best hotels each destination has to offer, such as the Four Seasons Lisbon and NYC's Waldorf-Astoria, which will be throwing "gala evenings" both before and after the journey. A fancy dinner at Ireland's Flying Boat and Maritime Museum and a night of fado music in Portugal are the next two unique stops on the itinerary. Notably, the sole replica of Pan Am's Boeing 314 Clipper from the 1930s is housed at the museum.</p>

<p>Craig Carter, CEO of Pan American World Airways and host of the flight experience said, "Relaunching Pan Am requires a careful balance of honouring its storied past while innovating for the future." Mr Carter wants to provide an experience that "resonates with both our longtime fans and new customers."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eq2krseg_panam_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A double occupancy ticket is available at a slight discount.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/would-strongly-consider-vivek-ramaswamy-eyes-trump-veep-picks-jd-vance-senate-seat-6120263]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Would Strongly Consider: Vivek Ramaswamy Eyes Trump Veep Pick's Senate Seat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/would-strongly-consider-vivek-ramaswamy-eyes-trump-veep-picks-jd-vance-senate-seat-6120263]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:21:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy, the India-descent biotech entrepreneur, has thrown his hat into the ring for the US Senate seat that will fall vacant if former President Donald Trump wins the presidential polls, taking away its current occupant J.D. Vance, the Repu]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vivek Ramaswamy, the India-descent biotech entrepreneur, has thrown his hat into the ring for the US Senate seat that will fall vacant if former President Donald Trump wins the presidential polls, taking away its current occupant J.D. Vance, the Republican nominee for Vice-President.</p>

<p>"To be frank, I would strongly consider it if I were asked to serve," Mr Ramaswamy told NBC News.</p>

<p>"I have not discussed this with Governor DeWine, but, you know, I look forward to evaluating what the future holds in store. I would strongly consider it if asked," he added.</p>

<p>Under US rules, Ohio Governor Mike DeWin will nominate someone to complete Vance's six-year term that started in January 2023, after which that person will have to run for the seat or leave it for others to fight for it.</p>

<p>Mr DeWine is a Republican like Vance and Ramaswamy is from Ohio state which Vance represents in the US Senate.</p>

<p>Mr DeWine has said "it's much too early" to name a replacement.</p>

<p>If Mr DeWine picks him, Mr Ramaswamy will become the only Indian-descent member of the current Senate and only the second of Indian-descent.</p>

<p>The first Indian American in the US Senate was Vice-President Kamala Harris. But when she was elected as V-P along with President Joe Biden, her Senate seat fell vacant and because she represented California in the Senate, it fell to the state's Governor Gavin Newsom to name her replacement. Newsom picked Alex Padilla.</p>

<p>This practice landed a Governor of Illinois, Rod Blagojevich, in jail when he tried to auction the seat vacated by Senator Barack Obama on his election to the White House in 2008.</p>

<p>Mr Ramaswamy may even land a position in a second Trump administration if the former President wins. He has impressed Trump with his complete embrace of the latter's MAGA agenda and for forcefully defending him from attacks by critics such as former Governors Chris Christie and Nikki Haley during the Republican primaries; Trump had ignored the primaries while staying miles ahead in polls.</p>

<p>Mr Ramaswamy had quit the race endorsing Trump and had been a part of the starting line of contenders who auditioned for the V-P slot on Trump ticket, but did not make it.</p>

<p>But Trump went on to indicate, according to reports, that if elected, he might name Ramaswamy to head the powerful Department of Homeland Security, which runs, among other things, the country's immigration services.</p>

<p>So, even as he eyes Vance's vacated Senate seat, Mr Ramaswamy is keeping his options open.</p>

<p>"I would also want to have a serious conversation with President Trump about the other ways I could have an impact on the country," he said, adding, "My top passion is taking on the regulatory state."</p>

<p>He added, "There are ways to address that from the executive branch. Some things need to be done by Congress and the Senate too. So, I look forward to those conversations after President Trump is successfully reelected with J.D. Vance."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/7t9l89g_vivek-ramaswamy-afp_625x300_20_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy had quit the race endorsing Trump (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-brother-tristan-banned-from-leaving-romania-amid-human-trafficking-trial-court-6120093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Andrew Tate Banned From Leaving Romania Amid Human Trafficking Trial: Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-brother-tristan-banned-from-leaving-romania-amid-human-trafficking-trial-court-6120093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 20:58:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Controversial influencer Andrew Tate and his brother Tristan have to remain within Romania while awaiting trial over human trafficking and rape charges, a Bucharest court ruled on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Controversial influencer Andrew Tate and his brother Tristan have to remain within Romania while awaiting trial over human trafficking and rape charges, a Bucharest court ruled on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The Bucharest Court of Appeal overturned a previous decision from July 5 that eased travel restrictions on the former professional kickboxer, allowing him and his brother to travel within the European Union.</p>

<p>The final ruling came following an appeal lodged by prosecutors.</p>

<p>The court "dismisses as unfounded the request of the defendants to replace the obligation not to leave the territory of Romania with an obligation not to leave the territorial limit of the European Union", according to the decision delivered on Tuesday.</p>

<p>While awaiting trial over human trafficking and rape charges, the Tate brothers are under judicial supervision in Romania, which is reviewed every 60 days.</p>

<p>Their lawyer Eugen Vidineac announced in a press statement Andrew and Tristan "will fully comply" with the court ruling.</p>

<p>US-born Briton Tate and his brother Tristan, who say they are innocent, are accused of having formed an organised criminal network in early 2021 in Romania and in Britain.</p>

<p>Prosecutors allege that 37-year-old Tate, his brother and two women set up a criminal organisation and sexually exploited several victims.</p>

<p>A trial date has not yet been set.</p>

<p>The Tates also face rape and assault allegations in separate cases in Britain, where they have also been accused of tax evasion last week.</p>

<p>Andrew Tate moved to Romania years ago after first starting a webcam business in the UK.</p>

<p>In 2016, Tate appeared on the "Big Brother" reality television show in Britain but was removed after a video emerged showing him attacking a woman.</p>

<p>He then turned to social media platforms to promote his divisive views.</p>

<p>Giving tips on how to be successful, along with misogynistic and sometimes violent maxims, his videos have made him one of the world's best-known influencers.</p>

<p>Andrew Tate made a brief appearance last weekend on a stage of a seaside festival in Romania, as a guest of the US rapper French Montana.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/4j8n47tg_andrew-tate-tristan-tates-afp_625x300_03_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A trial date has not yet been set. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-orders-nationwide-school-closures-after-violent-student-protests-6120031]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Orders Nationwide School Closures After Violent Student Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-orders-nationwide-school-closures-after-violent-student-protests-6120031]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 20:49:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh ordered every high school, Islamic seminary and vocational institute in the country to close indefinitely on Tuesday, an official told AFP on Tuesday, after violent student protests left at least six people dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh ordered every high school, Islamic seminary and vocational institute in the country to close indefinitely on Tuesday, an official told AFP on Tuesday, after violent student protests left at least six people dead.</p>

<p>"All high schools, colleges, Islamic seminaries and polytechnic institutes will be shut down until further order, considering the security of the students," education ministry spokesman M. A. Khair told AFP</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qf89bp_bangladesh-student-protest_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shutdown was ordered "considering the security of the students": Bangladesh Education Ministry (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-killed-in-oman-attack-near-shiite-mosque-6119858]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Killed In Oman Attack Near Shiite Mosque]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-killed-in-oman-attack-near-shiite-mosque-6119858]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 20:22:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian was killed and another injured in a shooting incident near a Shiite mosque in the Omani capital Muscat, the Indian Embassy said in a social media post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian was killed and another injured in a shooting incident near a Shiite mosque in the Omani capital Muscat, the Indian Embassy said in a social media post.</p>

<p>Shiites make up a small minority of Oman's overwhelmingly Muslim population. Most Omanis follow the Sunni or Ibadi branches of the faith.</p>

<p>"Following the shooting incident reported in Muscat city on 15 July, Foreign Ministry of Sultanate of Oman has informed that one Indian national has lost his life &amp; another is injured," said the embassy on X.</p>

<p>Offering condolences,&nbsp; the Embassy underlined that it will offer all assistance to the families.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Following the shooting incident reported in Muscat city on 15 July, Foreign Ministry of Sultanate of Oman has informed that one Indian national has lost his life &amp; another is injured. Embassy offers its sincere condolences &amp; stands ready to offer all assistance to the families.</p>
— India in Oman (Embassy of India, Muscat) (@Indemb_Muscat) <a href="https://twitter.com/Indemb_Muscat/status/1813212451938451933?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Monday's mosque attack, which has yet to be claimed, came as Shiites this week mark Ashura, an annual day of mourning that commemorates the seventh-century death in battle of Imam Hussein, regarded by the sect as the rightful successor to the Prophet Mohammed.</p>

<p>While several mosque attacks have roiled the Gulf in recent years, Monday's shooting is a first for Oman.</p>

<p>Police said "all necessary security measures and procedures have been taken to handle the situation" following the attack.</p>

<p>"The authorities are continuing to gather evidence and conduct investigations to uncover the circumstances surrounding the incident," police added on X.</p>

<p>Oman has a population of over four million, more than 40 percent of whom are expatriate workers, according to government figures.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bh1evn2g_oman-mosque-shooting_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-indonesia-australia-resolve-to-work-towards-free-indo-pacific-6119795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, Indonesia, Australia Resolve To Work Towards Free Indo-Pacific]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-indonesia-australia-resolve-to-work-towards-free-indo-pacific-6119795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 20:15:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India, Indonesia and Australia on Tuesday reaffirmed their commitment to work towards a free, open and rules-based Indo-Pacific.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India, Indonesia and Australia on Tuesday reaffirmed their commitment to work towards a free, open and rules-based Indo-Pacific.</p>

<p>The overall situation in the Indo-Pacific came up for review at a 'focal points' meeting of the India-Indonesia-Australia trilateral dialogue.</p>

<p>"The three sides held discussions to explore opportunities for collaboration including under the framework of Indo-Pacific Oceans Initiative and the Indian Ocean Rim Association (IORA) mechanisms, maritime domain awareness, marine pollution and blue economy cooperation," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said.</p>

<p>It said the three sides noted convergence between India's Indo-Pacific Oceans Initiative (IPOI) and the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific.</p>

<p>India has consistently been supporting ASEAN's centrality in the Indo-Pacific.</p>

<p>The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) is considered one of the most influential groupings in the region.</p>

<p>"India, Indonesia and Australia reaffirmed their commitment to advancing their shared values and working together towards a free, open, inclusive, peaceful, prosperous and rules-based Indo-Pacific," the MEA said in a statement.</p>

<p>At the East Asia Summit in Bangkok in 2019, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had proposed the setting up of the Indo-Pacific Ocean's Initiative (IPOI) to conserve and sustainably use the maritime domain and to make meaningful efforts to create a safe and secure maritime domain.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b0qp8sng_indo-pacific_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has consistently been supporting ASEAN's centrality in the Indo-Pacific]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-dozens-wounded-in-shooting-near-mosque-in-oman-6119449]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Killed, Dozens Wounded In Shooting Near Mosque In Oman]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-dozens-wounded-in-shooting-near-mosque-in-oman-6119449]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 19:29:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Six people including four Pakistanis were killed and nearly 30 wounded in a shooting near a Shiite mosque in the Omani capital Muscat, officials said Tuesday, a rare attack in the otherwise stable Gulf sultanate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Six people including four Pakistanis were killed and nearly 30 wounded in a shooting near a Shiite mosque in the Omani capital Muscat, officials said Tuesday, a rare attack in the otherwise stable Gulf sultanate.</p>

<p>Monday's mosque attack, which has yet to be claimed, came as Shiites this week mark Ashura, an annual day of mourning that commemorates the seventh-century death in battle of Imam Hussein, regarded by the sect as the rightful successor to the Prophet Mohammed.</p>

<p>"The Royal Oman Police have responded to a shooting incident that occurred in the vicinity of a mosque in the Al-Wadi Al-Kabir area" of the capital, a police statement said.</p>

<p>The three gunmen behind the attack were killed and police officers have "concluded the procedures for dealing with the shooting," it said.</p>

<p>It gave a death count of six killed, including a police officer. It said 28 people "from various nationalities" were wounded, including rescuers and paramedics.</p>

<p>The foreign ministry in Islamabad said at least four Pakistanis were killed.</p>

<p>"Four Pakistanis were martyred as a result of gunshots in the dastardly terrorist attack on the Ali bin Abi Talib mosque," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Another 30 Pakistanis are under treatment in hospitals."</p>

<p>Footage verified by AFP shows people fleeing the Imam Ali Mosque, its minaret visible, as gunshots ring out.</p>

<p>A voice can be heard saying "oh God" and repeating "oh Hussein".</p>

<p>Speaking to AFP, Pakistan's ambassador to Oman Imran Ali said the mosque was mostly frequented by south Asian expatriates. Oman is home to at least 400,000 Pakistanis, he said.</p>

<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif said he was "deeply saddened by the terrorist attack".</p>

<p>In a statement on social media platform X, he said: "Pakistan stands in solidarity with the Sultanate of Oman and offers full assistance in the investigation."</p>

<p><strong>Held 'hostage'</strong></p>

<p>Pakistan's ambassador said the attack started with gunfire from a building adjacent to the mosque as hundreds of people gathered for prayers.</p>

<p>The worshippers were held "hostage" by militants before "they were later freed by Omani forces", Ali told AFP.</p>

<p>He said there was little information on the perpetrators of the attack or their possible motive.</p>

<p>"Everyone is being tight-lipped about this," he said, adding that the attack created a "difficult situation".</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, Ali toured hospitals treating the wounded.</p>

<p>In a video message on X, he urged Pakistanis in Oman to cooperate with the authorities and avoid the area around the mosque.</p>

<p>"We are in touch with Omani authorities as well as hospitals. Our officers are on standby for emergency blood donations in the embassy," he said, adding that a hotline has been set up to assist the wounded and their relatives.</p>

<p>The US embassy in Muscat issued a security alert following the shooting and cancelled all visa appointments for Tuesday.</p>

<p>"US citizens should remain vigilant, monitor local news and heed directions of local authorities," it posted on X.</p>

<p><strong>Investigations underway</strong></p>

<p>Police said "all necessary security measures and procedures have been taken to handle the situation" following the attack.</p>

<p>"The authorities are continuing to gather evidence and conduct investigations to uncover the circumstances surrounding the incident," police added on X.</p>

<p>The area remained cordoned off on Tuesday, with journalists unable to access the mosque, an AFP photographer reported.</p>

<p>Oman has a population of more than four million, of whom upwards of 40 percent are expat workers, mostly from south Asia, according to government figures.</p>

<p>Shiites make up a small minority of Oman's overwhelmingly Muslim population. Most Omanis follow the Sunni or Ibadi branches of the faith.</p>

<p>While several attacks on Shiite mosques have roiled the Gulf in recent years, Tuesday's attack is a first for Oman.</p>

<p>A 2015 suicide attack on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait killed at least 27 worshippers and wounded more than 200. It was claimed by the Sunni extremists of the Islamic State group.</p>

<p>The same year, Saudi Arabia saw two attacks on Shiite mosques in the space of a week, with at least 25 people killed. The attacks were again claimed by IS, which regards Shiites as heretics.</p>

<p>In 2005, a former teacher opened fire inside a government building in Muscat, killing two people and wounding several others, before shooting himself.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bh1evn2g_oman-mosque-shooting_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The foreign ministry in Islamabad said at least four Pakistanis were killed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-killed-in-israeli-strikes-on-gaza-school-petrol-station-hamas-6119222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[22 Killed In Israeli Strikes On Gaza School, Petrol Station: Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-killed-in-israeli-strikes-on-gaza-school-petrol-station-hamas-6119222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 18:55:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza and medics said that at least 22 people were killed in Israeli strikes Tuesday on a petrol station and a school in the war-stricken territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza and medics said that at least 22 people were killed in Israeli strikes Tuesday on a petrol station and a school in the war-stricken territory.</p>

<p>The health ministry said an Israeli strike on a fuel station in Al-Mawasi in southern Gaza killed 17 people and wounded at least 26. The Palestinian Red Crescent initially gave a death count of eight dead in a separate strike at almost the same time on the UN-run Al-Razi School in the Nuseirat refugee camp in central Gaza, but this was quickly revised down to five dead.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[26 people were wounded during the strikes, says Gaza health ministry. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/was-donald-trump-sleeping-at-republican-national-convention-heres-the-truth-6119049]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Was Donald Trump Sleeping At Republican Convention? Here's The Truth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/was-donald-trump-sleeping-at-republican-national-convention-heres-the-truth-6119049]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 18:32:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The event marked Donald Trump's first public appearance since the an assassination attempt at a Pennsylvania rally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video circulating on social media appears to show former US President Donald Trump dozing off during the Republican National Convention on Monday. According to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/did-trump-fall-asleep-rnc-convention-1925683"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, the now-viral clip was shot during Harmeet Dhillon's address. Mr Trump can be seen nodding off while JD Vance, his running mate, is seen next to him with his eyes open. Notably, the event marked his first public appearance since the assassination attempt at a Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>The footage was shared by several users on X (formerly Twitter). Since being shared, the post has amassed over 2.5 million views and 34,000 likes.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">???? He Can't Stay Awake At The RNC!! He Sleep Bih!!!!! ??? The Media Give Dude All The Passes!!! <a href="https://t.co/dBK8rwMgng">pic.twitter.com/dBK8rwMgng</a></p>
— Plies (@plies) <a href="https://twitter.com/plies/status/1813046616837767328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Sleepy Don," said a user.</p>

<p>Another commented, "wakey wakey donald!"</p>

<p>A third person said, "Bro really? How much sleep you think this man has gotten in 48 hours?"</p>

<p>An X user stated, "He literally just, by the grace of God, lived through an assassination attempt.. he then flew out to see his doctors and family, met with politicians, flew back for the RNC (let alone everything we don't see in the background he has had to do to ensure another attempt isn't made)"</p>

<p>"He's probably on super strong pain pills. Just a thought," remarked a user.</p>

<p>As per <em>CBS News</em>, Donald Trump's eyes were closed, not because he was asleep, but because the video was apparently taken during Pastor James Roemke's prayer. Mr Trump and JD Vance were among the large number of people in the crowd who had their eyes closed throughout the pastor's prayer. Some individuals uploaded Roemke's prayer video incorrectly, saying that Mr Trump was sleeping at the moment by editing out other audience members whose eyes were also closed.</p>

<p>The event has sparked a debate as Mr Trump frequently mocks US President Joe Biden, referring to him as "Sleepy Joe," to question his fitness for office. Notably, Mr Biden is the oldest president in American history at 81. Donald Trump said that the POTUS "almost fell asleep" on stage after his heavily criticised performance at the first presidential debate in Atlanta.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in April, several journalists stated that the 78-year-old appeared to doze off several times during his criminal trial in New York, prompting Mr Biden to call him "Sleepy Don." However, Mr Trump denied falling asleep in the courtroom. The campaign told the <em>Independent</em>, "This is 100% Fake News coming from 'journalists' who weren't even in the court room."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cvd931go_trump_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The viral clip has amassed over 2.5 million views and 34,000 likes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/so-proud-of-my-friend-classmate-vivek-ramaswamy-on-jd-vance-trumps-veep-pick-6118834]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Proud Of My Classmate": Vivek Ramaswamy On JD Vance, Trump's Veep Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/so-proud-of-my-friend-classmate-vivek-ramaswamy-on-jd-vance-trumps-veep-pick-6118834]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 18:08:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[JD Vance, Donald Trump's vice presidential pick, has the support of former Trump presidential primary rival Vivek Ramaswamy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>JD Vance, Donald Trump's vice presidential pick, has the support of former Trump presidential primary rival Vivek Ramaswamy.</p>

<p>Reminiscing the days of his law school, Mr Ramaswamy, an Indian-American entrepreneur, underscored how impressed he is with his "classmate" JD Vance getting the "strongest presidential ticket."</p>

<p>"So proud of my friend, classmate, and fellow southwest Ohioan today. We used to watch Bengals games at the bar in law school, it's awesome we're now here a decade later with JD joining the strongest presidential ticket in our lifetime," said Mr Ramaswamy.</p>

<p>"He'll be an outstanding Vice President and I look forward to everything ahead for him and for our country," Mr Ramaswamy added, who dropped out of the 2024 Republican presidential race after finishing fourth in the Iowa caucuses earlier.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">So proud of my friend, classmate, and fellow southwest Ohioan today. We used to watch Bengals games at the bar in law school, it's awesome we're now here a decade later with JD joining the strongest presidential ticket in our lifetime. He'll be an outstanding Vice President and I…</p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1812929198433964249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Donald Trump won the formal nomination Monday as the Republican presidential candidate and picked a right-wing loyalist for his running mate, kicking off a triumphalist party convention in the wake of the weekend's failed assassination attempt.</p>

<p>A White House candidate often chooses a vice presidential running mate who can appeal to new categories of voters or compensate for acknowledged weaknesses in terms of image or policy.</p>

<p>Even if his octogenarian rival Joe Biden appears to be suffering more than him from advanced age, Trump knows he is no spring chicken at 78.</p>

<p>By picking Mr Vance, who at 39 is barely half Trump's age -- and the first millennial on a major US party presidential ticket -- he could neutralize what had been the relatively youthful advantage of Biden's vice president, 59-year-old Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Mr Vance, who was once a fierce Trump antagonist, has made a U-turn to establish himself as one of the billionaire's most ardent defenders.</p>

<p>He has deleted earlier tweets critical of Trump and instead passionately embraced his ideas, advocating a radical anti-immigration fight and uncompromising economic protectionism.</p>

<p>Vance's 2016 memoir "Hillbilly Elegy" was extolled by some as a window into the lives and troubles of the white working class -- and their support for Trump.</p>

<p><em>(With agency inputs)</em></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/q1t98ggg_vivek-jd-vance-1200_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-rolls-royce-head-designer-stabbed-to-death-in-3-million-germany-mansion-6118369]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Rolls-Royce Head Designer Stabbed To Death In $3 Million Germany Mansion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-rolls-royce-head-designer-stabbed-to-death-in-3-million-germany-mansion-6118369]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 17:10:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ian Cameron, former Rolls-Royce head designer and vintage car expert, was killed at his $3 million mansion in Germany after getting stabbed by a man during a robbery attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ian Cameron, former Rolls-Royce head designer and vintage car expert, was killed at his $3 million mansion in Germany after getting stabbed by a man during a robbery attempt.</p>

<p>The 74-year-old British national was living with his wife Verena Kloos in Germany's Herrsching at Lake Ammersee during the incident. Ms Kloos escaped the attack by scaling a wall and landing in her neighbour's house, from where she informed the cops.</p>

<p>The power cables to the garage of Ian Cameron's house, where valuables were kept, had been purposefully cut off, according to CCTV evidence.</p>

<p>"The investigation suggests that this was a violent crime," said police officials.</p>

<p>Ian Cameron played a "significant" role in the designing of iconic Rolls-Royce vehicles like the Ghost, Phantom, and 3 Series.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ian Cameron undertook the role of leading the Rolls-Royce design team after BMW acquired Rolls-Royce's automotive business in 1998.</p>

<p>"We are deeply shocked and saddened by the news about our former Rolls-Royce designer. Our thoughts are with his family and friends during these difficult hours," said BMW in a statement to Automotive News. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Ian played a significant role in shaping Rolls-Royce from when it was first acquired by BMW Group and moved to its home at Goodwood, West Sussex. During Ian's tenure, he led the design team for all Phantom family and Ghost models, creating thoroughly contemporary motor cars that remained sympathetic to the marque's design lineage," the automaker added.</p>

<p>The suspect's height is estimated to be between 180 and 190 cm (5 ft 9 in to 6 ft 2 in). He is wearing light-colored pants, a dark-blue sweatshirt, yellow-green gloves, and a red backpack, according to a description by police officials.</p>

<p>A manhunt has been launched to locate the suspect who is currently on the run. Dogs and a helicopter are helping search teams thoroughly examine the area to catch the murderer.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4tj83fe8_ian-cameron-rolls-royce_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A manhunt has been launched to locate the suspect. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/roberta-metsola-re-elected-as-european-parliament-chief-6118274]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Roberta Metsola Re-Elected As European Parliament Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/roberta-metsola-re-elected-as-european-parliament-chief-6118274]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 16:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[EU lawmakers overwhelmingly voted on Tuesday to give conservative Maltese politician Roberta Metsola another term as speaker of the European Parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>EU lawmakers overwhelmingly voted on Tuesday to give conservative Maltese politician Roberta Metsola another term as speaker of the European Parliament.</p>

<p>Metsola won a massive majority with 562 votes as the 720-seat parliament met for its first session in Strasbourg, France, with new MEPs. Metsola, who belongs to the largest political group in the parliament, will be the parliament's president for the next two and a half years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-01/fr8iurqc_roberta-metsola-afp_625x300_18_January_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Roberta Metsola won a massive majority with 562 votes. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/a-message-to-the-oldest-democracy-from-the-largest-stop-gun-violence-6118106]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: A Message To The Oldest Democracy, From The Largest: Stop Gun Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/a-message-to-the-oldest-democracy-from-the-largest-stop-gun-violence-6118106]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 16:33:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As a citizen of India, a friendly democracy, I appeal to the greater conscience of the American people, political leaders, and society at large. It is time to enforce gun control measures that will protect innocent lives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bq88p95_trump-shooting_625x300_16_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The recent visuals of the shooting at a rally for Donald Trump and the injury he suffered have sent shockwaves across the globe, including India. There is no place for this kind of violence in a democratic society. Both India and the US share a deep commitment to democratic values, and it is this shared commitment that brings us closer together. As an Indian, I find it deeply troubling to witness such acts of violence in a country that has long been a beacon of democracy and freedom. The incident at the Trump rally, where shots were fired and chaos ensued, highlighted a grim reality-that gun violence can strike at the very heart of democracy.</p>

<p>India and the US have much in common. Both nations are built on the foundation of democratic principles and have a long history of upholding the rule of law and human rights. Our countries have thrived on the strength of our diverse societies and the resilience of our democratic institutions. India, the world's largest democracy, has faced its own challenges, but we have always strived to maintain peace and order within our borders. The U.S., as the world's oldest democracy, has been a role model for nations around the globe. This deep respect and commonality of democratic values make it all the more essential for us to address issues that threaten these values.</p>

<h2><strong>America's Social Issues</strong></h2>

<p>While it is yet to be fully understood what actually transpired at the rally and why it happened, this incident highlights the urgent need to address underlying societal issues in the US. As someone who believes in the promise of American democracy, I am compelled to speak out. It is high time that America takes decisive action on gun control.</p>

<p>The issue of gun control has been a topic of national debate in the US for decades. Since the assassination of President John F. Kennedy in 1963, there have been numerous calls for stricter gun laws. Despite these calls, little has been done to address the root causes. The tragic incidents at malls, schools, hospitals, and other public places have instilled fear not only in the hearts of Americans but also in the global community. The perception of safety in America has been significantly altered, and this is a matter of grave concern.</p>

<p>According to data from the Gun Violence Archive, there were over 600 mass shootings in the US in 2022 alone. The country has one of the highest rates of gun violence in the world, with more than 45,000 gun-related deaths reported in the same year. These figures are alarming and underscore the urgent need for comprehensive gun control measures. The Second Amendment of the U.S. Constitution, which protects the right to bear arms, has been interpreted in ways that allow for widespread gun ownership. However, it is crucial to balance this right with the need to ensure public safety.</p>

<h2><strong>The Powerful Gun Lobby</strong></h2>

<p>One of the key reasons for the lack of significant gun control legislation in the US is the powerful lobby of arms manufacturers. The National Rifle Association (NRA) and other pro-gun organisations have a significant influence on American politics. Their lobbying efforts have thwarted numerous attempts to pass meaningful gun control laws. It is imperative to question whether the freedom to own guns is genuinely about protecting individual liberties or whether it is driven by the interests of the arms industry.</p>

<p>Many other democracies around the world have implemented strict gun control measures with positive results. Countries like Australia, the UK, and Japan have shown that it is possible to significantly reduce gun violence through sensible legislation. These nations have demonstrated that public safety can be prioritised without infringing on individual freedoms.</p>

<p>The US must acknowledge that the world is changing. There is an increasing number of people dealing with mental health issues and other personal struggles. In the absence of adequate support systems, some individuals may resort to violence as a means of expression. The availability of guns only exacerbates this problem, leading to tragic consequences that leave lasting scars on families and communities.</p>

<h2><strong>For The People And Society</strong></h2>

<p>As a citizen of India, a friendly democracy, I appeal to the greater conscience of the American people, political leaders, and society at large. It is time to enforce gun control measures that will protect innocent lives. The time to act is now. How many more lives must be lost before meaningful change is implemented?</p>

<p>In conclusion, the US stands at a crossroads. The decisions made today will shape the future of the nation. It is imperative to prioritise the safety and well-being of all citizens. By enacting comprehensive gun control measures, America can demonstrate its commitment to democratic values. As a friend and admirer of American democracy, I urge the US to take bold steps towards a safer and more just society.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<em>(Rituraj Sinha is National Secretary, BJP, and an alumni of Harvard University Kennedy School of Government)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o07p60ko_trump-shooting_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-search-for-civil-war-2-american-civil-war-spike-after-donald-trump-rally-shooting-6117955]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spike In Google Search For 'Civil War 2' After Shooting At Trump Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-search-for-civil-war-2-american-civil-war-spike-after-donald-trump-rally-shooting-6117955]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 16:13:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to Google Analytics, on the day when Mr Trump was shot during a rally in Butler, the search term 'American Civil War' reached a 12-month high.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination attempt by a gunman at a campaign rally today in Pennsylvania on Saturday, a shocking incident that will fuel fears of instability ahead of the 2024 US presidential election. Several politicians, tech leaders and followers of Mr Trump condemned the attack, stressing that political violence is intolerable. Amid this, terms such as 'Civil War 2' and 'American Civil War' spiked on Google search, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/15/us-news/panicked-search-terms-spike-online-after-trump-rally-shooting-civil-war-2/"><em>New York Post.</em></a></p>

<p>According to Google Analytics, on the day when Mr Trump was shot during a rally in Butler, the search term 'American Civil War' reached a 12-month high. Additionally, the day also saw the highest increase in interest in the term 'Secret Service' during the previous five years. The day following the incident witnessed new 12-month highs for the terms 'long-distance shooting' and 'gun store near me,' which both had notable interest surges. At the same time, 'How do I move to Canada' also hit a record 12-month high.</p>

<p>Google Analytics tracks the total amount of interest in a word rather than each individual usage- the term with the most searches during a specific time period (100 points) is at the top of the list, while the term with the fewest searches (0 points) is at the bottom. Within moments of the incident, 'Civil War' soon became the most searched phrase on the platform.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the 78-year-old Republican presidential contender, whose team claimed he was "fine," was attacked shortly as he began his speech."I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin," Mr Trump said on his Truth Social account.</p>

<p>He added, "Much bleeding took place, so I realized then what was happening." Earlier in the statement, he stated, "I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the FBI identified the shooter in the assassination attempt on the former president as 20-year-old <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-who-was-thomas-matthew-crooks-man-who-tried-to-assassinate-donald-trump-6102487">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a>. The US Secret Service said in a statement that the shooter "fired multiple shots toward the stage from an elevated position outside the rally" before being "neutralized" by agents. He was registered as a Republican, according to the state's voter records.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8od8vok_donald-trump_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The former President appeared to be bleeding on the right side of the face.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-explains-why-he-asked-about-his-shoes-amid-shooting-chaos-6117844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Explains Why He Asked About His Shoes Amid Shooting Chaos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-explains-why-he-asked-about-his-shoes-amid-shooting-chaos-6117844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 15:59:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump recently shared details about the dramatic moment he was shot at and rushed off stage by Secret Service agents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump recently shared details about the dramatic moment he was shot at and rushed off stage by Secret Service agents. Amid the chaos, the 78-year-old was heard, saying, "Wait, I want to get my shoes."</p>

<p>Describing the experience as "very surreal," the former President clarified the mystery surrounding his shoes in a recent interview. “The agents struck me that my shoes fell off,” Trump revealed, as per the <a href="http://https://nypost.com/2024/07/14/us-news/grateful-defiant-trump-recounts-surreal-assassination-attempt-at-rally-im-supposed-to-be-dead/ ">NY Post</a>. “And my shoes are tight.”</p>

<p>The Republican nominee narrowly escaped an assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania on Sunday.</p>

<p>The former president recounted the incident, saying had he not turned his head slightly to the right to read a chart, he would be dead by now. At that moment, a bullet grazed Trump's ear, tearing off a small piece and splattering blood on his forehead and cheek. Secret Service agents swiftly jumped in, screaming at him to “get down” and tackled him to the ground like “linebackers” before rushing him to a hospital. Trump even showed off a bruise on his arm from where they grabbed him.</p>

<p>This close call has left many shaken. But Trump is grateful to be alive. He said that medical professionals told him he was “supposed to be dead", sharing&nbsp;that the doctor at the hospital described his survival as a "miracle." The doctor also stated that he had never seen anyone survive after being hit by an AR-15 rifle.</p>

<p>Donald Trump praised the Secret Service for quickly taking down the shooter, who was 130 yards away on a roof. He described the agents' actions as “fantastic” and said they did a great job. He even pointed to his nose to show where they hit the shooter.</p>

<p>The former president also talked about the iconic photo of him raising his fist and saying "fight" as the agents tried to get him to safety. He joked that people usually “have to die” to get such an iconic photo.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8od8vok_donald-trump_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump praised the Secret Service for quickly taking down the shooter.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-embassy-thanks-india-for-first-tranche-of-2-5-million-for-refugees-6117451]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Palestine Embassy Thanks India For 1st Tranche Of $2.5 Million For Refugees]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-embassy-thanks-india-for-first-tranche-of-2-5-million-for-refugees-6117451]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 15:01:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Palestinian Embassy on Tuesday thanked India as it released the first tranche of USD 2.5 million to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) as a part of its annual contribution of USD 5 Million for the year 2024-2025.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Palestinian Embassy on Tuesday thanked India as it released the first tranche of USD 2.5 million to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) as a part of its annual contribution at USD 5 Million for the year 2024-2025.</p>

<p>The embassy said we extend our sincere thanks and appreciation to the Indian Government for releasing the first tranche of USD 2.5 million to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East as a part of its annual contribution at USD 5 Million for the year 2024-2025.</p>

<p>We also followed with great interest India's pledge of support to UNRWA during the UNRWA conference held in New York and announced that in addition to financial assistance, New Delhi will provide medicines to UNRWA upon request, it said.</p>

<p>This Indian assistance and this pledge an important step to support and strengthen the role of UNRWA in the face of attempts to target its role and existence by the Israeli government</p>

<p>While we appreciate the Indian contribution to UNRWA, we believe that this assistance, whether financial or medical, constitutes an important part of the assistance provided to the Palestinian people in various fields, which we look forward to increasing during the next stage due to the urgent need due to the Israeli war on Gaza, which has created a new and dangerous reality.</p>

<p>About 2.2 million Palestinians were residing in the Gaza Strip an area of 365 km2, representing about 41% of the population of Palestine. Most of this population (about 66%) are refugees, about 2 million Palestinians left their homes out of about 2.2 million Palestinians who were residing in the Gaza Strip on the eve of the Israeli occupation aggression, the statement said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA) is facing Israeli plans to target the body of the United Nations Foundation, which witnesses the case of more than 6 million Palestinian refugees and provides services to them in its five areas of operation (Gaza Strip, West Bank, Jordan, Syria and Lebanon).</p>

<p>We hope that India, through its bilateral relationship with the pillars of the international community and through its effective position in many important political and economic blocs and groupings around the world, will work to preserve UNRWA and strengthen its status and role, for which it was founded in 1949, and that Israeli attempts to replace it with other institutions will fail.</p>

<p>The importance of UNRWA for Palestinians goes beyond access to vital services, as they see its existence as linked to the preservation of their rights as refugees, especially their hope to return to their homes from which they or their ancestors were expelled during the Nakba.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j71u1lb8_gaza-july-2024-afp_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 2.2 million, or about 41% of the total population, of Palestinians were residing in the Gaza Strip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-reaffirms-continued-support-to-mauritius-in-its-quest-for-progress-6117387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Reaffirms Continued Support To Mauritius In Its Quest For Progress]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-reaffirms-continued-support-to-mauritius-in-its-quest-for-progress-6117387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:54:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Tuesday reaffirmed India's consistent and continued support to Mauritius in its quest for progress and prosperity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Tuesday reaffirmed India's consistent and continued support to Mauritius in its quest for progress and prosperity.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar is in Mauritius for a two-day visit for "productive engagements" with the leadership of Mauritius to take forward the special bilateral ties.</p>

<p>The visit to the Indian Ocean island nation marks one of the first bilateral engagements undertaken by Mr Jaishankar following his re-appointment in the third term of Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government.</p>

<p>"India's ties with Mauritius have blossomed into a robust and multifaceted partnership. The bilateral relation with Mauritius serves as a role model for India's successful development collaboration abroad," Mr Jaishankar said at an event attended by Mauritius Prime Minister Pravind Jugnauth.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Honored to call on PM <a href="https://twitter.com/KumarJugnauth?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KumarJugnauth</a> today in Port Louis. Conveyed the warm greetings of PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a>.<br />
<br />
Took stock of our special and enduring partnership and appreciated its further broadening.<br />
<br />
Looking forward to the continued collaboration and strengthening of ??-??… <a href="https://t.co/P9phPhhM9d">pic.twitter.com/P9phPhhM9d</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1813145870172348601?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The event saw the inauguration of 12 High Impact Community Development Projects that are funded by India, the exchange of MoUs on education, culture, digitisation of Immigration Archives and collaboration in the field of space and innovation.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar and Mr Jugnauth also handed over OCI cards to seventh-generation Indian-origin people in Mauritius.</p>

<p>The visit underscores the importance of the India-Mauritius relationship and is a reflection of India's 'Neighbourhood First Policy', Vision SAGAR, and commitment to the Global South.</p>

<p>According to the Indian High Commission at Mauritius website, India has close, long-standing relations with Mauritius, an island nation in the Western Indian Ocean, owing to historical, demographic and cultural reasons.</p>

<p>A key reason for the special ties is the fact that Indian-origin people comprise nearly 70 per cent of the island's population of 1.2 million, it added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1pm3125g_s-jaishankar-mauritius-president_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar is in Mauritius for a two-day visit for "productive engagements"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/kamala-harris-to-rishi-sunak-indians-must-be-realistic-about-the-rise-of-indian-origin-leaders-6117384]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Kamala Harris To Rishi Sunak, Indians Must Be Realistic About Indian-Origin Leaders Abroad]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/kamala-harris-to-rishi-sunak-indians-must-be-realistic-about-the-rise-of-indian-origin-leaders-6117384]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:54:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In case Biden withdraws from the US presidential race and Kamala Harris replaces him I am sure people in India, more particularly in Tamil Nadu, will feel proud. But do not expect any favours from her if she wins.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/onflnjc_indian-origin_625x300_16_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Donald Trump's defiant act of pumping his fist in the air, moments after his brush with death, could potentially sink President Joe Biden's chances of victory in the November election. Democrats may disagree, but it has certainly relegated Biden's age concerns to the background. At least for now. The 81-year-old President's mental and physical fitness issue is bound to resurface in the coming days and weeks, leading up to the Democratic Party Convention on August 19-22 in Chicago, when the party candidate will officially be announced.</p>

<p>If Biden, who has remained defiant so far, decides to withdraw from the race, a prominent alternative being considered is Vice-President Kamala Harris.</p>

<h2><strong>Harris and Her Indian Heritage</strong></h2>

<p>Harris, half Indian by heritage, has a familial connection to Thulasendrapuram in Tamil Nadu. Her family from her mother's side come from there. Her appointment in 2020 was celebrated with fireworks and prayers in India, with Prime Minister Narendra Modi calling it a "historic occasion" and expressing his eagerness to work with her to strengthen India-US relations.</p>

<p>Despite the initial excitement, it is clear that the strengthening of India-US relations under Biden's administration has been driven by the President's initiatives rather than Harris's Indian heritage. While Harris often speaks about her Indian roots, her policies and actions are primarily shaped by the strategic interests of the United States, not India.</p>

<h2><strong>The Political Strategy of Indian-Origin Politicians</strong></h2>

<p>A few Indian-origin politicians in the US, such as Nikki Haley and Bobby Jindal, tend to downplay their Indian heritage to appeal to broader voter bases, which can be seen as a political strategy.&nbsp;<br />
In the UK, Indian-origin politicians like Priti Patel and Suella Braverman, despite their immigrant backgrounds, have adopted strict anti-immigrant stances, aligning with conservative values to secure support within their parties.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak's appointment as the UK Prime Minister in 2022 sparked significant excitement among Indians. I met jubilant members of the Indian community in Southampton, Sunak's hometown, who felt immense pride. However, their enthusiasm later dampened as they realised that Sunak's policies were driven by the priorities of the UK, not his Indian heritage. He turned out to be just another politician who was co-opted by the establishment, they felt.</p>

<h2><strong>Symbolism vs. Substance</strong></h2>

<p>The celebrations over Indian-origin politicians achieving high office in Western countries often overlook the reality that these leaders primarily serve the interests of their respective countries. For instance, Sunak's policies were guided by national interests rather than ethnic connections, as evidenced by the stalled Free Trade Agreement (FTA) talks between the UK and India.</p>

<p>Similar cases include Antonio Costa and Leo Varadkar, former Prime Ministers of Portugal and Ireland, respectively, whose political actions did not necessarily favour India. Costa, with Goan roots, and Varadkar, with Maharashtrian heritage, focused on their countries' priorities, not their ancestral ties.</p>

<p>For the Indian diaspora, the rise of leaders like Sunak, Harris, Costa, and Varadkar is a source of inspiration and pride, demonstrating that individuals of Indian descent can achieve the highest political offices in foreign lands. However, the tangible benefits for the diaspora are limited. For example, the Indian community in Southampton has become divided over whether Sunak's premiership has provided any real advantages.</p>

<h2><strong>Starmer's Cabinet And Lack Of Diversity&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>In the recent UK elections, a record 26 MPs of Indian origin were elected, with 19 from Labour, including 12 Sikhs and six female Sikh MPs. Despite this representation, the Indian community was disappointed that only one half-Indian MP received a senior ministerial position in Prime Minister Keir Starmer's cabinet. This cabinet appears predominantly white, a stark contrast to Boris Johnson's diverse 2019 cabinet.</p>

<p>The Biden administration has appointed around 130 Indian-Americans to key positions, reflecting the growing influence and integration of Indian-Americans in US politics. While these appointments are a source of pride and potentially facilitate stronger India-US relations, the primary allegiance of these officials is to the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Indian diaspora is indeed an influential group in many countries, which can be leveraged to India's advantage. That explains why diaspora outreach is one of PM Modi's key foreign policy priorities.&nbsp;<br />
The Modi government has also been advocating for more representations for India at influential global institutions, such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the World Bank, and important United Nations (UN) bodies. If we have more Indians or Indian-origin people in key positions in these institutions, it will surely bring more prestige and power to India.</p>

<h2><strong>Indian-Origin CEOs in Global IT Firms</strong></h2>

<p>Apart from politics, Indian-origin CEOs of global IT firms, such as Sundar Pichai of Google and Satya Nadella of Microsoft, bring indirect benefits to India. They foster stronger business ties, create job opportunities, invest in Indian startups, and promote technology and education initiatives. Their success elevates India's global standing in the tech world.</p>

<p>There is no doubt that the achievements of Indian-origin politicians and business leaders in Western countries or anywhere else are commendable and a source of pride, but it is important to maintain a realistic perspective on their impact. Their primary duty is to serve the interests of their respective countries, and their policies are shaped by the political and strategic priorities of those nations. The symbolic importance of their success does not necessarily translate into tangible benefits for India or the Indian diaspora.&nbsp;</p>

<p>So, in case Biden withdraws from the race and Kamala Harris replaces him I am sure people in India, more particularly in Tamil Nadu, will feel proud. But do not expect any favours from her if she wins. If Trump comes back to power we are bound to remember neither President Biden nor Kamala Harris.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qcqmeks_indian-origin_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-dials-down-attacks-on-donald-trump-after-rally-shooting-6117217]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Dials Down Attacks On Donald Trump After Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-dials-down-attacks-on-donald-trump-after-rally-shooting-6117217]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:31:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The assassination attempt on Donald Trump has forced Joe Biden's campaign to dial down its attacks for now, with the US president admitting he was wrong to say his rival should be put in the "bullseye."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The assassination attempt on Donald Trump has forced Joe Biden's campaign to dial down its attacks for now, with the US president admitting he was wrong to say his rival should be put in the "bullseye."</p>

<p>But Biden has more broadly defended his rhetoric describing his Republican predecessor as a threat to democracy, and is signaling he will not hold back for long while criticizing the man he beat in 2020.</p>

<p>When Biden urged Americans to "lower the temperature" in a rare Oval Office speech on Sunday after the Trump shooting, it seemed it could deprive him of his core attack line.</p>

<p>Just last week the 81-year-old had tried to pivot his campaign back on to his Republican rival, following weeks of turmoil in the Democratic Party over his age and health after a disastrous debate performance.</p>

<p>In the light of the Trump attack, Biden told broadcaster NBC on Monday that was a "mistake" to say in a call with donors a week ago that it was "time to put Trump in the bullseye."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Democrat said he had meant that the party should "focus on what he's doing" instead of calling him to quit after the debate.</p>

<p>Republicans have pointed to the bullseye comment in particular as they accuse Biden himself of creating the political conditions that led a shooter to try to kill Trump -- ignoring their own candidate's history of encouraging violence.</p>

<p>But while Biden's campaign has toned down its language in the immediate aftermath of the shooting, Biden himself hinted that he would not hold back.</p>

<p>"How do you talk about the threat to democracy, which is real, when a president says things like he says. Do you just not say anything because it may incite somebody?" he told NBC.</p>

<p>"I have not engaged in that rhetoric. Now my opponent has engaged in that rhetoric, he talks about how there'll be a bloodbath when he loses."</p>

<p>He also slammed Trump for pledging to pardon those involved in the January 6, 2021 Capitol attack by pro-Trump supporters and for joking about former US House speaker Nancy Pelosi's husband being attacked with a hammer.</p>

<h3><strong>'Changes the calculus'</strong></h3>

<p>Facing repeated questions over Biden's comment at a White House briefing, Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said it was "OK to speak to someone's record, speak to someone's character."</p>

<p>Despite canceling a trip to Texas on Monday, Biden is continuing with a planned visit to the battleground state of Nevada, setting up a split-screen with Trump's convention appearances.</p>

<p>In an opinion piece in the Washington Post, political columnist Karen Tumulty wrote that there could "hardly be a worse moment for Biden to be compelled to redraw his strategy against Trump."</p>

<p>The Trump shooting could, however, help Biden as he fights for his own political survival.</p>

<p>"Obviously this changes the calculus for people calling for Biden to stand down," Peter Loge, a political scientist at George Washington University, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It buys Biden some time."</p>

<p>The Democratic meltdown over Biden's age following the debate had dominated the airwaves for weeks, but with the gunshots on Saturday the revolt over his candidacy fell abruptly silent.</p>

<p>Biden has also sought to strike a presidential tone over the shooting, coming out quickly to react on Saturday and addressing the nation Sunday in just the third Oval Office speech of his presidency.</p>

<p>But if the shooting could unify Democrats, it could also doom Biden's reelection bid, with the president already behind in most polls.</p>

<p>Iconic images of a bloodied Trump waving his fist after the shooting are already galvanizing Republican hopes that voters will further rally behind him for a landslide victory in November.</p>

<p>Loge, however, said there may be little effect as "a lot of voters see Trump as too nuts and Biden as too old, and an assassination attempt doesn't change that."</p>

<p>He added that focusing on the immediate impact of the shooting on the campaigns was the "wrong question" and missed the wider need to tackle the threats and violence plaguing US politics.</p>

<p>"If we make political violence part of a campaign strategy we miss the point of political violence, and we end up kind of normalizing it," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/m1g4332_joe-biden-donald-trump_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump rally shooting could, however, help Biden as he fights for his own political survival]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>