<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 05:07:19 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-takes-action-against-france-5-nations-over-budget-rule-violation-6196912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EU Takes Action Against France, 5 Nations Over Budget Rule Violation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-takes-action-against-france-5-nations-over-budget-rule-violation-6196912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 23:10:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France, Italy and five other EU countries were placed in a formal procedure on Friday for violating the bloc's budget rules, a step that could lead to unprecedented penalties unless they take corrective measures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>France, Italy and five other EU countries were placed in a formal procedure on Friday for violating the bloc's budget rules, a step that could lead to unprecedented penalties unless they take corrective measures.</p>

<p>"Today the Council adopted decisions establishing the existence of excessive deficits for Belgium, France, Italy, Hungary, Malta, Poland and Slovakia," the body representing the 27 member states said.</p>

<p>Known as an "excessive deficit procedure", it kickstarts a process forcing a country to negotiate a plan with Brussels to get their debt or deficit levels back on track.</p>

<p>The seven countries had deficits -- the gap between government revenue and spending -- above three percent of gross domestic product, in violation of the bloc's fiscal rules.</p>

<p>France's deficit reached 5.5 percent in 2023, but it appears that bringing it down would be difficult because of political uncertainty following the results of a snap election that was won by a leftwing coalition demanding much higher public spending.</p>

<p>The EU countries with the highest deficit-to-GDP ratios last year were Italy (7.4 percent), Hungary (6.7 percent), Romania (6.6 percent) and Poland (5.1 percent).</p>

<p>The council also said Romania had "not taken effective action" against its excessive deficit, despite having a procedure opened against it in 2020 and would therefore be kept under watch.</p>

<p>As a next step, the countries will have to send medium-term plans by September about how they will rectify the breach.</p>

<p>Then the European Commission in November will deliver assessments of the plans with details on the route they must take to return to fiscal health.</p>

<p>This is the first time Brussels is rebuking EU states since the bloc suspended the rules after the 2020 coronavirus pandemic and the energy crisis triggered by Russia's war on Ukraine, as states propped up businesses and households with public money.</p>

<p>The EU spent two years during the suspension to reform the budget rules to give greater leeway for investment in critical areas like defence.</p>

<p>But two sacred objectives remain: a state's debt must not go higher than 60 percent of national output, with a public deficit of no more than three percent.</p>

<p>Countries failing to remedy the situation can in theory be hit with fines of 0.1 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) per year, until action is taken to address the violation.</p>

<p>In practice, though, the commission has never gone as far as levying fines, fearing it could trigger unintended political consequences and hurt a state's economy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/6op53pqo_european-union-generic_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The EU spent two years during the suspension to reform the budget rules. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-working-hard-to-reverse-terribly-low-birth-rate-says-kremlin-6196861]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Working Hard To Reverse "Terribly Low" Birth Rate, Says Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-working-hard-to-reverse-terribly-low-birth-rate-says-kremlin-6196861]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 23:04:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin said Friday that it was "working hard" to reverse declining birth rates in Russia, warning that "disastrous" demographic trends were putting the country's future at risk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin said Friday that it was "working hard" to reverse declining birth rates in Russia, warning that "disastrous" demographic trends were putting the country's future at risk.</p>

<p>Russia has faced a myriad of demographic challenges since the collapse of the USSR, including an ageing population, an outflow of men due to the conflict in Ukraine and the lowest fertility rate in 17 years.</p>

<p>"It is now at a terribly low level -- 1.4 (births per woman). This is comparable to European countries, Japan and so on. But this is disastrous for the future of the nation," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told a media festival.</p>

<p>"Anyone with many children is a hero. We live in the largest country in the world. And there are fewer of us every year. And the only way to cope with this is to increase the average birth rate," Peskov said.</p>

<p>Russia had a population of about 148 million people at the breakup of the Soviet Union in 1991, a figure that now stands at around 144 million after a protracted period of high deaths and low births in the 1990s.</p>

<p>The country's birth rate has not recovered since Soviet times despite President Vladimir Putin's government offering generous payouts and mortgage subsidies to large families.</p>

<p>Recent problems include large numbers of Covid deaths, hundreds of thousands of men fleeing the country to avoid being mobilised to fight in Ukraine, and migration into Russia hitting a ten-year low in 2023.</p>

<p>Russia's population could drop to 130 million by the 2040s, demographers have forecasted.</p>

<p>When asked whether young families could still have faith in the future, the Kremlin pointed to similar demographics in other countries.</p>

<p>"This is unfortunately a trend," Peskov said.</p>

<p>"The situation will remain difficult for some period of time, but the government is working hard on this issue, and it is one of the top priorities of the President of Russia," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/8206hht8_dmitry-peskov-reuters_625x300_03_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Anyone with many children is a hero," said Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-preparing-for-decisive-offensive-against-hezbollah-6196815]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Preparing For "Decisive Offensive" Against Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-preparing-for-decisive-offensive-against-hezbollah-6196815]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:56:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli military commander said Friday that troops in the country's north were preparing for "a decisive offensive" against Lebanon's Hezbollah after months of deadly cross-border exchanges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli military commander said Friday that troops in the country's north were preparing for "a decisive offensive" against Lebanon's Hezbollah after months of deadly cross-border exchanges.</p>

<p>Israeli forces have traded near-daily fire with Hamas ally Hezbollah since the Palestinian group's October 7 attack on southern Israel started the ongoing war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Major General Ori Gordin, Israel's commanding officer in the north, told troops that "we have already eliminated more than 500 terrorists in Lebanon, the great majority of them from Hezbollah", an army statement said.</p>

<p>According to an AFP tally, more than nine months of violence have killed at least 523 people in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Most of them, 342 people, have been confirmed to be Hezbollah operatives but the tally also includes 104 civilians. Gordin did not mention civilian casualties.</p>

<p>In northern Israel, at least 18 Israeli soldiers and 13 civilians have been killed, according to the military.</p>

<p>The exchanges of fire have been largely restricted to the border areas and displaced tens of thousands of Lebanese as well as Israeli residents.</p>

<p>The Israeli military has "destroyed thousands" of targets across the border, Gordin said.</p>

<p>The statement said troops were now preparing "for the transition to offence".</p>

<p>"When the moment comes and we go on the offensive, it will be a decisive offensive," Gordin added.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah says it is acting in support of Hamas with its attacks on Israel since October 8.</p>

<p>The escalating violence and unsuccessful mediation efforts have raised fears of all-out conflict between Israel and Hezbollah, which last went to war in 2006.</p>

<p>Israel has demanded that parts of southern Lebanon be cleared of Hezbollah operatives in line with a UN Security Council resolution that ended the 2006 war.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2225v5kg_israel-army_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah says it is acting in support of Hamas with its attacks on Israel since October 8. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-national-duped-on-promise-of-job-returns-from-saudi-says-embassy-6196705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Duped On Promise Of Job Returns From Saudi, Says Embassy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-national-duped-on-promise-of-job-returns-from-saudi-says-embassy-6196705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:35:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian Embassy in Saudi Arabia on Friday confirmed the return of an Indian national who was stranded in the Gulf nation after being duped by an agent who had promised getting him a job in Qatar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Embassy in Saudi Arabia on Friday confirmed the return of an Indian national who was stranded in the Gulf nation after being duped by an agent who had promised getting him a job in Qatar.</p>

<p>Mr Kumar, a resident of Andhra Pradesh, was allegedly cheated by a job agent who had promised him a job in Qatar but sent him to Saudi Arabia, Khaleej Times reported.</p>

<p>The Indian Embassy also thanked the community volunteers who worked with the Embassy to ensure Mr Kumar's safe return to India.</p>

<p>"Few days back, plight of an Indian National, Mr Veerendra Kumar was brought to the attention of the Embassy. We are happy to announce that he has safely returned to now. We wish to thank all the community volunteers who worked with the Embassy to ensure his safe return to India," the Indian Embassy stated on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Few days back, plight of an Indian National, Mr Veerendra Kumar was brought to the attention of the Embassy. We are happy to announce that he has safely returned to ?? now. We wish to thank all the community volunteers who worked with the Embassy to ensure his safe return to ??. <a href="https://t.co/pMEJTTXZPq">pic.twitter.com/pMEJTTXZPq</a></p>
— India in Saudi Arabia (@IndianEmbRiyadh) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndianEmbRiyadh/status/1816776727533670566?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Earlier, after the video of Veerandra Kumar pleading for help surfaced, Telugu Desam Party leader Nara Lokesh assured that he would work for his return to India.</p>

<p>"Veerendra, we will bring you back home safely! Don't worry!" he said in a post on X on July 19.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Veerendra, we will bring you back home safely! Don't worry! <a href="https://t.co/GKk9j4n64R">https://t.co/GKk9j4n64R</a></p>
— Lokesh Nara (@naralokesh) <a href="https://twitter.com/naralokesh/status/1814359817592680966?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Veerendra Kumar said he was cheated by a job agent who had promised him a job in Qatar but sent him to Saudi Arabia where he was asked to work as a herder in the desert.</p>

<p>He reached the international airport in Hyderabad on Friday where his family was waiting for him, Khaleej Times reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jj8trt5_indian-national-duped-saudi_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Veerendra Kumar said he was cheated by a job agent who had promised him a job in Qatar]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexican-drug-lord-ismael-el-mayo-zambada-pleads-not-guilty-to-us-charges-6196641]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexican Drug Lord Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada Pleads Not Guilty To US Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexican-drug-lord-ismael-el-mayo-zambada-pleads-not-guilty-to-us-charges-6196641]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:25:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alleged Mexican kingpin Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada has pleaded not guilty to U.S. drug trafficking charges, court records showed on Friday, after he and a son of another drug lord were arrested on Thursday in El Paso, Texas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alleged Mexican kingpin Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada has pleaded not guilty to U.S. drug trafficking charges, court records showed on Friday, after he and a son of another drug lord were arrested on Thursday in El Paso, Texas.</p>

<p>Court records showed that Zambada on Friday waived his right to appear personally in court and directed that a not guilty plea be entered on his behalf.</p>

<p>He was ordered detained without bond and is scheduled to be arraigned before U.S. Magistrate Judge Anne Berton next Wednesday, the records showed. His lawyer did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Both Zambada and Joaquin Guzman Lopez, a son of Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman, face multiple charges in the U.S. for funneling huge quantities of fentanyl and other drugs to U.S. streets.</p>

<p>Their detentions were a dramatic achievement for U.S. law enforcement that could also shake up the Mexican drug landscape.</p>

<p>Mexico's government was informed of the detentions by the U.S. government, but Mexican authorities did not participate in the operation, Mexican Security Minister Rosa Rodriguez said on Friday.</p>

<p>Rodriguez added that it was unclear if Zambada and Guzman Lopez handed themselves over to U.S. authorities voluntarily.</p>

<p>"The Mexican government did not participate in this detention or surrender," Rodriguez said at a press conference.</p>

<p>Zambada, who is believed to be in his 70s, and Guzman Lopez, who is in his 30s, were detained after landing in a private plane in the El Paso area.</p>

<p>Zambada co-founded the Sinaloa Cartel with El Chapo, who was extradited to the U.S. in 2017 and is serving a life sentence in a maximum-security prison.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/uc77cd78_ismael-el-mayo-zambada_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zambada co-founded the Sinaloa Cartel with El Chapo. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-netanyahu-meets-donald-trump-for-talks-seeking-to-ease-tensions-6196582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli PM Netanyahu Meets Donald Trump For Talks Seeking To Ease Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-netanyahu-meets-donald-trump-for-talks-seeking-to-ease-tensions-6196582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 22:16:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu visited former U.S. President Donald Trump at Trump's Florida resort on Friday for a meeting that could ease tensions between two leaders who forged a close alliance during Trump's years in the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu visited former U.S. President Donald Trump at Trump's Florida resort on Friday for a meeting that could ease tensions between two leaders who forged a close alliance during Trump's years in the White House.</p>

<p>Netanyahu met Trump, the Republican nominee in the 2024 U.S. presidential race, a day after Netanyahu met Democratic President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris, who is running against Trump in the Nov. 5 U.S. election.</p>

<p>The longtime Israeli leader rearranged his US travel schedule to meet Trump. He landed in Palm Beach early on Friday.</p>

<p>Opinion polls put Harris and Trump in a close race for the White House, prompting world leaders like Netanyahu, traditionally more aligned with Trump's Republicans than Biden's Democrats, to strike a balance in dealings with the U.S.</p>

<p>Nine months into an Israeli offensive in Gaza, Harris pressed Netanyahu on the suffering of Palestinians in the enclave in talks that were watched for signs of how she might shift American policy if she becomes president.</p>

<p>"I made clear my serious concern about the dire humanitarian situation there," Harris said on Thursday after the meeting. "I will not be silent."</p>

<p>"Israel has a right to defend itself. And how it does so matters," she said.</p>

<p>Israeli officials criticized Harris for saying it was time for the war to end.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News on Thursday, Trump called for a quick end to the war and a return of the hostages Hamas holds in Gaza, adding that Israel has to better manage its "public relations."</p>

<p>"I want him (Netanyahu) to finish up and get it done quickly," Trump said. "They are getting decimated with this publicity."</p>

<p>Trump also criticized those who protested a speech Netanyahu gave to the U.S. Congress on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Dozens of Democrats boycotted the speech, voicing dismay over the thousands of civilian deaths in Gaza and the displacement of most of its 2.3 million people.</p>

<p><strong>NETANYAHU, TRUMP LOOK TO EASE TENSIONS</strong></p>

<p>The meeting between Trump and Netanyahu signaled that both were looking to ease tensions.</p>

<p>The Israeli leader angered Trump when he congratulated Biden on his victory over Trump in the 2020 election. Trump has falsely claimed the election was stolen from him by voter fraud.</p>

<p>Trump more recently criticized Netanyahu for Israeli security failures around the Oct. 7 Hamas attack on Israel that triggered the Israeli offensive in Gaza.</p>

<p>Hamas and its allies killed 1,200 people and took 250 hostage, according to Israeli tallies. Some 120 hostages are still being held though Israel believes one in three are dead.</p>

<p>In defiant remarks to Congress on Wednesday, Netanyahu defended Israel's military and dismissed criticism of a campaign which has devastated Gaza and killed more than 39,000 people, according to health officials in the Hamas-ruled enclave.</p>

<p>Israeli officials estimate that some 14,000 fighters from&nbsp; groups including Hamas and Islamic Jihad have been killed or taken prisoner out of a force they estimated to number more than 25,000 at the start of the war.</p>

<p>In Wednesday's speech, Netanyahu praised Biden's support for Israel.</p>

<p>But to cheers from Republicans, he touched on Trump's pro-Israel record as president. He praised Trump's decision to move the U.S. embassy from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem, a long-held goal of conservatives that infuriated Palestinians.</p>

<p>He also cited the Abraham Accords, landmark U.S.-brokered agreements signed during Trump's White House years that normalized bilateral relations between Israel and both Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p>Palm Beach County Sheriff Ric Bradshaw encouraged peaceful protests but said he did not expect demonstrations on the scale of what happened during Netanyahu's speech in Washington when thousands of activists marched - vandalizing some landmarks and confronting police - to protest the war in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/has938mg_donald-trump-netanyahu_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump recently criticized Netanyahu for Israeli security failures around the Oct. 7 Hamas attack.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/court-convicts-man-after-woman-dies-at-slapping-therapy-workshop-in-uk-6196448]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Court Convicts Man After Woman Dies At "Slapping Therapy" Workshop In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/court-convicts-man-after-woman-dies-at-slapping-therapy-workshop-in-uk-6196448]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 21:53:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An alternative healer was on Friday found guilty of the manslaughter by gross negligence of a diabetic woman who died from medical complications at a "slapping therapy" workshop in the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An alternative healer was on Friday found guilty of the manslaughter by gross negligence of a diabetic woman who died from medical complications at a "slapping therapy" workshop in the UK.</p>

<p>Hongchi Xiao, 60, from Cloudbreak, California, was convicted following a trial at a court in Winchester, southern England.</p>

<p>He was charged in November following the death of Danielle Carr-Gomm, 71, who was taking part in a session at a hotel to help her diabetes in October 2016.</p>

<p>The pensioner died at a "paida lajin" workshop, which involves patients being slapped or slapping themselves repeatedly.</p>

<p>Prosecutors told the court the alternative healer breached his duty of care towards Carr-Gomm by failing to take reasonable steps to ensure medical assistance when she was suffering from a "medical crisis", namely ketoacidosis.</p>

<p>Diabetic ketoacidosis is a serious condition that can happen in people with diabetes due to a lack of insulin and requires urgent medical treatment.</p>

<p>Xiao, who was born in China, was extradited to the UK from Australia.</p>

<p>Carr-Gomm, who was described by her family as an avid follower of holistic medicine and alternative therapies, was born in France and moved to the UK at the age of 21.</p>

<p>She was diagnosed with diabetes in 1999 but struggled to inject insulin because of a fear of needles.</p>

<p>The head of the Crown Prosecution's special crime division, Rosemary Ainslie, said: "Hongchi Xiao knew the consequences of Danielle Carr-Gomm's decision to stop taking insulin could be fatal, he had seen it before.</p>

<p>"Hongchi Xiao was the man in charge, yet he failed to respond to Mrs Carr-Gomm's worsening condition with tragic consequences.</p>

<p>"His failure to take reasonable steps to help Mrs Carr-Gomm substantially contributed to her death and amounted to gross negligence."</p>

<p>Xiao will be sentenced on October 1.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/gs634ql8_hongchi-xiao_625x300_03_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Xiao, who was born in China, was extradited to the UK from Australia. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-charged-after-he-deliberately-forces-train-to-crash-for-a-youtube-video-6195841]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Teen Charged After He Deliberately Forces Train To Crash For A Video]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-charged-after-he-deliberately-forces-train-to-crash-for-a-youtube-video-6195841]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to court documents, the Nebraska teen allegedly caused the train to go off the tracks, recorded the incident, and shared the footage on YouTube.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 17-year-old teenager in the US has been accused of deliberately causing a train derailment to record it and post it on YouTube. According to court documents, the Nebraska teen allegedly caused the train to go off the tracks, recorded the incident, and shared the footage on YouTube, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/07/25/teen-train-crash-derailment-record-youtube-video-nebraska-21299670/">Metro</a></em> reported.</p>

<p>The incident happened in April this year when the teen allegedly tampered with a rail switch, causing two locomotives and five fully loaded coal trains to veer off the tracks and crash into an empty coal car. He then alerted authorities to the derailment and asked the investigator who arrived what caused the crash. He told the investigator he was a train enthusiast and showed him the video he had shot of the derailment.</p>

<p>When authorities said they did not know the cause of the derailment, the boy said, ''Obviously a switch was flipped the wrong way.''</p>

<p>An investigator with BNSF Railway found that a padlock supposed to be attached to the switch was missing, indicating tampering. Three days later,&nbsp;a BNSF investigator obtained CCTV footage showing a 1996 Buick Park Avenue in the vicinity, with the same teenager walking towards the switch at the south end of the tracks. According to the affidavit, the teen was later recorded returning to his vehicle.</p>

<p>A <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q97XRpF6SZA">video of the derailment was posted on a YouTube account</a> believed to be linked to the teen, an investigator said. Authorities also discovered that a tripod had been set up near the accident site just four minutes before the train derailed. The derailment caused $350,000 in damages to BNSF Railway and the Omaha Public Power District, as per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/teen-accused-derailing-train-recording-crash-posting-online-rcna163686">NBC News.&nbsp;</a></em></p>

<p>The 17-year-old was charged in Lancaster County Juvenile Court on Wednesday, but prosecutors have requested that the case be moved to adult court. He faces two felony charges of criminal mischief in connection with a train derailment.</p>

<p>''My office will file a motion to transfer the case to adult court and it will be up to the juvenile court Judge to transfer the case or have it remain in juvenile court,'' Lancaster County Attorney Patrick Condon told <em>McClatchy News.</em></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8tlh7drg_train_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The derailment caused $350,000 in damages to BNSF Railway and the Omaha Public Power District]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-railway-attacks-force-new-uk-pm-to-change-olympics-travel-plan-6195791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Railway Attacks Force New UK PM To Change Olympics Travel Plan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-railway-attacks-force-new-uk-pm-to-change-olympics-travel-plan-6195791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:17:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Keir Starmer changed his travel plans to get to the Olympics on Friday after Eurostar trains were disrupted due to sabotage attacks against French rail networks, Downing Street said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer changed his travel plans to get to the Olympics on Friday after Eurostar trains were disrupted due to sabotage attacks against French rail networks, Downing Street said.</p>

<p>Starmer was meant to be travelling on the cross-Channel rail service from London to Paris for the Olympics opening ceremony, in his first visit to France since being elected earlier this month.</p>

<p>But a spokeswoman said he flew instead due to the delays and cancellations.</p>

<p>France is welcoming dozens of heads of state and government and royalty for the Olympics that begin with a dazzling ceremony on the river Seine on Friday.</p>

<p>Just hours before the ceremony, arson attacks threw France's high-speed rail network into chaos affecting tens of thousands of passengers, in what officials called premeditated acts of "sabotage".</p>

<p>One in four Eurostar trains were cancelled, the company said, with the disruption set to continue over the weekend.</p>

<p>Beyond the cancellations, Eurostar trains departing and arriving in Paris will run on regular lines rather than high-speed routes.</p>

<p>That would add an extra 90 minutes onto a Paris-London trip that usually takes around two hours and 20 minutes, Eurostar said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g6af87ko_keir-starmer-afp-_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[France is welcoming dozens of heads of state and government and royalty for the Olympics. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boop-the-ick-chefs-kiss-new-additions-to-cambridge-dictionary-6195543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Boop', 'The Ick', 'Chef's Kiss' New Additions To Cambridge Dictionary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boop-the-ick-chefs-kiss-new-additions-to-cambridge-dictionary-6195543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:46:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A few other quirky additions include IYKYK, which is the written abbreviation for "if you know you know".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Informal words used as slang, such as 'boop' and 'the ick', are among more than 3,200 new words and phrases added to the Cambridge Dictionary in its latest update this week.</p>

<p>'Boop', which is defined as "a gentle hit or touch on a person's or animal's nose or head, showing that you like them or as a "joke", and 'the ick', which refers to "a sudden feeling that you dislike someone or something or are no longer attracted to someone because of something they do", are among the slangs to make it to the online edition for 2024 so far.</p>

<p>'Chef's kiss', or a movement in which you put your fingers and thumb together, kiss them, then pull your hand away from your lips as a way of showing that you think that something or someone is perfect or excellent, is another such informal phrase that has been recognised formally.</p>

<p>"Language is always changing, and this means that the 'Cambridge Dictionary' team stays busy researching new words and meanings that enter the English language," the dictionary said in a statement on Thursday.</p>

<p>"Many new additions come from the fields of science and technology, including 'scicomm' - the activity of explaining scientific work and information to people who are not scientists, or articles, talks, etc. that do this, and deep-sky - existing in or relating to the part of space outside the solar system," it said.</p>

<p>A few other quirky additions include IYKYK, which is the written abbreviation for "if you know you know". It is used mostly on social media and in text messages to imply a shared joke or shared knowledge with the reader that other people might not understand.</p>

<p>The noun "face journey" has been added to refer to "a series of expressions that appear on someone's face showing different emotions that they are experiencing as a reaction to something".</p>

<p>Cambridge Dictionary said its team records how English is actually used by real people and uses the Cambridge English Corpus, a huge collection of written and spoken English, to gather evidence for how a new word is used by different people and in a variety of situations.</p>

<p>"We also collect evidence of new words that have only appeared in English very recently. We feature three of these on our weekly About Words blog, where readers can vote on which words they think should be added to the dictionary," it explained, with reference the process behind adding on new terms.</p>

<p>Online gaming also inspired several new entries, such as 'backread' - to read through a series of messages or internet posts that you did not see when they were first created, often starting with the most recent, in order to learn what happened or was discussed earlier; 'speedrun' - to complete a computer game, or part of a computer game, as quickly as possible, especially by taking advantage of any glitches; and 'side quest' - a part of a computer game that has its own aim and story but is not part of the main game.</p>

<p>New additions from the world of music include 'soca' or a type of music that is a mixture of soul and calypso, originally from the Caribbean, and 'jug band' which refers to a small group of performers who play jazz, blues, or folk music on very simple musical instruments, especially using objects such as empty jugs as instruments.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-12/dictionary-generic_650x400_61449816760.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Online gaming also inspired several new entries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-should-we-go-gazans-forced-to-shelter-in-former-prison-amid-war-6195540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Where Should We Go": Gazans Forced To Shelter In Former Prison Amid War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-should-we-go-gazans-forced-to-shelter-in-former-prison-amid-war-6195540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:45:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After weeks of Israeli bombardment left them with nowhere else to go, hundreds of Palestinians have ended up in a former Gaza prison built to hold murderers and thieves.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After weeks of Israeli bombardment left them with nowhere else to go, hundreds of Palestinians have ended up in a former Gaza prison built to hold murderers and thieves.</p>

<p>Yasmeen al-Dardasi said she and her family passed wounded people they were unable to help as they evacuated from a district in the southern city of Khan Younis towards its Central Correction and Rehabilitation Facility.</p>

<p>They spent a day under a tree before moving on to the former prison, where they now live in a prayer room. It offers protection from the blistering sun, but not much else.</p>

<p>Dardasi's husband has a damaged kidney and just one lung, but no mattress or blanket.</p>

<p>"We are not settled here either," said Dardasi, who like many Palestinians fears she will be uprooted once again.</p>

<p>Israel has said it goes out of its way to protect civilians in its war with the Palestinian group Hamas, which runs Gaza and led the attack on Israel on Oct. 7 that sparked the latest conflict.</p>

<p>Palestinians, many of whom have been displaced several times, say nowhere is free of Israeli bombardment, which has reduced much of Gaza to rubble.</p>

<p>An Israeli air strike killed at least 90 Palestinians in a designated humanitarian zone in the Al-Mawasi area on July 13, the territory's health ministry said, in an attack that Israel said targeted Hamas' elusive military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Gaza's health ministry said Israeli military strikes on areas in eastern Khan Younis had killed 14 people.</p>

<p>Entire neighbourhoods have been flattened in one of the most densely populated places in the world, where poverty and unemployment have long been widespread.</p>

<p>According to the United Nations, nine in ten people across Gaza are now internally displaced.</p>

<p>Israeli soldiers told Saria Abu Mustafa and her family that they should flee for safety as tanks were on their way, she said. The family had no time to change so they left in their prayer clothes.</p>

<p>After sleeping outside on sandy ground, they too found refuge in the prison, among piles of rubble and gaping holes in buildings from the battles which were fought there. Inmates had been released long before Israel attacked.</p>

<p>"We didn't take anything with us. We came here on foot, with children walking with us," she said, adding that many of the women had five or six children with them and that water was hard to find.</p>

<p>She held her niece, who was born during the conflict, which has killed her father and brothers.</p>

<p>When Hamas-led gunmen burst into southern Israel from Gaza on Oct. 7 they killed 1,200 people and took more than 250 people hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>More than 39,000 Palestinians have been killed in the air and ground offensive Israel launched in response, Palestinian health officials say.</p>

<p>Hana Al-Sayed Abu Mustafa arrived at the prison after being displaced six times.</p>

<p>If Egyptian, U.S. and Qatari mediators fail to secure a ceasefire they have long said is close, she and other Palestinians may be on the move once again. "Where should we go? All the places that we go to are dangerous," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c57jnb5o_gazans-shelter-_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Palestinians say nowhere is free of Israeli bombardment. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ancient-palestine-site-receives-unesco-tag-amid-raging-conflict-in-gaza-6195467]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ancient Palestine Site Receives UNESCO Tag Amid Raging Conflict In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ancient-palestine-site-receives-unesco-tag-amid-raging-conflict-in-gaza-6195467]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:36:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid the ongoing conflict in Gaza, the ancient heritage site of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer in Palestine on Friday received the UNESCO tag and was simultaneously put on the List of World Heritage in Danger after an "emergency nomination".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid the ongoing conflict in Gaza, the ancient heritage site of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer in Palestine on Friday received the UNESCO tag and was simultaneously put on the List of World Heritage in Danger after an "emergency nomination".</p>

<p>The announcement was made during the ongoing 46th session of the World Heritage Committee (WHC) in Delhi. India is hosting the key UNESCO event for the first time.</p>

<p>Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer in Palestine has been inscribed on the World Heritage List and List of World Heritage in Danger, it was announced in the plenary meeting of the session.</p>

<p>Israel has been carrying out a massive military offensive in Gaza following the unprecedented and multi-pronged attacks on Israeli cities by Hamas militants on October 7.</p>

<p>India in November had urged both the sides to eschew violence, de-escalate the situation and create conditions for an early resumption of direct peace negotiations towards a two-state solution to the Palestine issue.</p>

<p>Friday's inscription has raised hopes about protection of such heritage sites.</p>

<p>The UNESCO in a statement later said that "this decision recognises both the site's value and the need to protect it from danger".</p>

<p>"In view of the threats to this heritage site posed by the ongoing conflict in the Gaza Strip, the World Heritage Committee used the emergency inscription procedure provided for in the World Heritage Convention," it said.</p>

<p>In accordance with the terms of the Convention, "its 195 States Parties are committed to avoid taking any deliberate measures likely to cause direct or indirect damage to this site, which is now inscribed on the World Heritage List, and to assist in its protection", the world body said.</p>

<p>The UNESCO said inclusion on the List of World Heritage in Danger automatically opens the door to "enhanced international technical and financial assistance mechanisms to guarantee the protection of the property and, if necessary, to help facilitate its rehabilitation".</p>

<p>The monastery of Saint Hilarion/Tell Umm Amer, one of the oldest sites in the Middle East, was founded by Saint Hilarion and was home to the first monastic community in the Holy Land.</p>

<p>Situated at the crossroads of the main routes of trade and exchange between Asia and Africa, it was a centre for religious, cultural and economic exchanges, illustrating the prosperity of desert monastic sites in the Byzantine period, the statement said.</p>

<p>In December 2023, at its 18th session, the UNESCO's Intergovernmental Committee for the Protection of Cultural Property in the Event of Armed Conflict had already decided to grant "provisional enhanced protection" to the monastery under the 1954 Hague Convention and its Second Protocol.</p>

<p>The Palestinian delegation which included Mounir Anastas, Ambassador and Permanent Delegate of Palestine to UNESCO, thanked UNESCO for this dual inscription which seeks to bring a protective cover and world's attention to the heritage site located in areas facing conflicts.</p>

<p>"I am honoured to have this inscription taking place in the greatest democracy in the world. Thank you, India. I would like to express my deepest gratitude to all Committee members for their valuable support for this inscription," Anastas said in his statement made in the session right after the inscription.</p>

<p>He also thanked ICOMOS, an advisory body of the UNESCO, and the Secretariat of the UNESCO.</p>

<p>Various state parties from Lebanon, Turkiye and Kazakhstan welcomed the UNESCO inscription of the heritage site in Palestine, with some of them underlining the need for cultural heritage preservation in times of armed conflicts.</p>

<p>The nomination for the site of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer was an "emergency nomination".</p>

<p>Paris-based International Council on Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS) also made a presentation on this site.</p>

<p>The nomination dossier was submitted in June 2024 followed by a "desk review".</p>

<p>"Situated on the coastal dunes in Nuseirat Municipality, the ruins of Saint Hilarion Monastery/Tell Umm Amer represent one of the earliest monastic sites in the Middle East, dating back to the 4th century," according to the UNESCO website.</p>

<p>"Founded by Saint Hilarion, the monastery began with solitary hermits and evolved into a coenobitic community. It was the first monastic community in the Holy Land, laying the groundwork for the spread of monastic practices in the region. The monastery occupied a strategic position at the crossroads of major trade and communication routes between Asia and Africa," it said.</p>

<p>This prime location facilitated its role as a hub of religious, cultural, and economic interchange, exemplifying the flourishing of monastic desert centres during the Byzantine period, the world body said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/589mo1v8_saint-hilarion-monastery_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has been carrying out a massive military offensive in Gaza. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-bangladesh-student-protest-leaders-taken-by-police-from-hospital-report-6194846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Bangladesh Student Protest Leaders Taken By Police From Hospital: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-bangladesh-student-protest-leaders-taken-by-police-from-hospital-report-6194846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 18:22:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladeshi police detectives on Friday forced the discharge from hospital of three student protest leaders blamed for deadly unrest, taking them to an unknown location, staff told news agency AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladeshi police detectives on Friday forced the discharge from hospital of three student protest leaders blamed for deadly unrest, taking them to an unknown location, staff told AFP.</p>

<p>Asif Mahmud, Nahid Islam and Abu Baker Majumder are all members of Students Against Discrimination, the group responsible for organising recent street rallies against civil service hiring rules.</p>

<p>At least 193 people were killed in the ensuing police crackdown and clashes, according to an AFP count of victims reported by police and hospitals, in some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's tenure.</p>

<p>The trio were being treated for injuries that they said were caused by torture in earlier police custody at a hospital in the capital Dhaka.</p>

<p>"They took them from us," Gonoshasthaya hospital supervisor Anwara Begum Lucky told AFP. "The men were from the Detective Branch."</p>

<p>She added that she had not wanted to discharge the student leaders but police had pressured the hospital chief to do so.</p>

<p>Islam's elder sister Fatema Tasnim told AFP from the hospital that six plainclothes detectives had taken all three men.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/61s1g2k_bangladesh-students-protest-reuters_625x300_06_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["They took them from us," Gonoshasthaya hospital supervisor Anwara Begum Lucky said (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-slams-un-expert-for-anti-semitism-over-hitler-netanyahu-comparison-6194793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Slams UN Expert For "Anti-Semitism" Over Hitler-Netanyahu Comparison]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-slams-un-expert-for-anti-semitism-over-hitler-netanyahu-comparison-6194793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 18:16:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel on Friday slammed a UN rights expert for "anti-Semitism" after she endorsed a social media post comparing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to Adolf Hitler.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel on Friday slammed a UN rights expert for "anti-Semitism" after she endorsed a social media post comparing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to Adolf Hitler.</p>

<p>Francesca Albanese, the United Nations special rapporteur on the rights situation in the Palestinian territories, has faced harsh criticism from Israel previously, especially after she in March accused the country of committing genocide in the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>On Thursday, she responded to a post on X, formerly Twitter, displaying a picture of Hitler being celebrated by a crowd with Nazi salutes and cheers above a shot of Netanyahu appearing to be greeted by US congressmen this week.</p>

<p>"History is always watching," Craig Mokhiber, a former UN human rights official who resigned late last October accusing the world body of failing to prevent the "genocide" of Palestinian civilians in Gaza, wrote in the post.</p>

<p>"This is precisely what I was thinking today," Albanese, an independent expert appointed by the UN Human Rights Council in 2022 but who does not speak on behalf of the United Nations, said in her response on Thursday.</p>

<p>Israel's foreign ministry was quick to respond, slamming her on X as being "beyond redemption".</p>

<p>"It is inconceivable that (Albanese) is still allowed to use the UN as a shield to spread anti-Semitism," it said.</p>

<p>Israel's mission to the UN in Geneva also chimed in.</p>

<p>"When a current UN 'expert' endorses Holocaust distortion spread by the former (UN rights office) director in New York... the system is rotten to its core," it said.</p>

<p>"It's high time to #UNseatAlbanese!"</p>

<p>Israel's new ambassador in Geneva, Daniel Meron, used the same hashtag, decrying that "Francesca Albanese abuses her (UN) title to spread hatred and inflammatory rhetoric".</p>

<p>Israel's top ally the United States also weighed in.</p>

<p>"UN Special Rapporteur's comparison of Benjamin Netanyahu to Adolf Hitler is reprehensible and antisemitic," US ambassador to the UN Human Rights Council in Geneva Michele Taylor said on X.</p>

<p>"There should be no place for such dehumanising rhetoric. Special rapporteurs should be striving to improve human rights challenges, not inflame them."</p>

<p>Albanese on Friday hit back at the criticism, insisting that "the memory of the Holocaust remains intact".</p>

<p>"Institutional rants and outburst of selective moral outrage will not stop the course of justice, which is finally in motion."</p>

<p>The Hamas attack that started the war on October 7 resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people in Israel, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Out of 251 people taken hostage that day, 111 are still held in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive against Hamas has killed at least 39,175 Palestinians in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory offensive against Hamas has killed 39,175 Palestinians in Gaza: Hamas (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/train-driver-convicted-over-spains-worst-crash-in-decades-that-killed-79-6194723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Train Driver Convicted Over Spain's Worst Crash In Decades That Killed 79]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/train-driver-convicted-over-spains-worst-crash-in-decades-that-killed-79-6194723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 18:07:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Spanish train driver and a former traffic safety chief at national rail infrastructure operator ADIF were sentenced on Friday to two-and-a-half years in prison over a train disaster that killed 79 people 11 years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Spanish train driver and a former traffic safety chief at national rail infrastructure operator ADIF were sentenced on Friday to two-and-a-half years in prison over a train disaster that killed 79 people 11 years ago.</p>

<p>In Spain's worst rail accident in decades, an eight-carriage, high-speed Alvia 04155 train veered off the track on a sharp bend near the northwestern city of Santiago de Compostela, slammed into a concrete wall and burst into flames. Another 143 people were injured in the 2013 crash.</p>

<p>Presiding judge Elena Fernandez Curras said two elements caused the derailment: the driver got distracted when receiving a call, and there was no safety system in place in case the driver did not respect the speed limit.</p>

<p>The defendants and the insurance companies of ADIF and Renfe were sentenced to pay 25 million euros ($27.14 million) in damages to the victims in the civil part of the trial.</p>

<p>After the crash, ADIF identified more than 300 spots on the Spanish railway network where speed changes were needed.</p>

<p>The judicial investigation into the crash was complex and took years, and the trial ran for 10 months. Only two of more than 20 people investigated were eventually put on trial.</p>

<p>Fernandez revised down the official death count to 79 from 80 as she considered one of the passengers, who passed away weeks after the crash, died as a result of a serious illness he was suffering from, and not the injuries. His relatives will still be compensated as he was injured in the crash.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jk5nmcm8_rain-crash-in-santiago-de-compostela_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The judicial investigation into the crash was complex and took years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-sending-over-1-million-polio-vaccines-to-gaza-to-protect-children-6194238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Sending Over 1 Million Polio Vaccines To Gaza To Protect Children]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-sending-over-1-million-polio-vaccines-to-gaza-to-protect-children-6194238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 17:05:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization is sending more than one million polio vaccines to Gaza to be administered over the coming weeks to prevent children being infected after the virus was detected in sewage samples, its chief said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization is sending more than one million polio vaccines to Gaza to be administered over the coming weeks to prevent children being infected after the virus was detected in sewage samples, its chief said on Friday.</p>

<p>"While no cases of polio have been recorded yet, without immediate action, it is just a matter of time before it reaches the thousands of children who have been left unprotected," Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said in an opinion piece in Britain's The Guardian newspaper.</p>

<p>He wrote that children under five were most at risk from the viral disease, and especially infants under two since normal vaccination campaigns have been disrupted by more than nine months of conflict.</p>

<p>Poliomyelitis, which is spread mainly through the fecal-oral route, is a highly infectious virus that can invade the nervous system and cause paralysis. Cases of polio have declined by 99% worldwide since 1988 thanks to mass vaccination campaigns and efforts continue to eradicate it completely.</p>

<p>Israel's military said on Sunday it would start offering the polio vaccine to soldiers serving in the Gaza Strip after remnants of the virus were found in test samples in the enclave.</p>

<p>Besides polio, the U.N. reported last week a widespread increase in cases of Hepatitis A, dysentery and gastroenteritis as sanitary conditions deteriorate in Gaza, with sewage spilling into the streets near some camps for displaced people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ucbia9h8_gaza-war_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cases of polio have declined by 99% worldwide since 1988 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priyanaka-gandhi-vadra-benjamin-netanyahu-israel-gaza-war-genocidal-barbaric-genocidal-actions-priyanka-gandhi-on-netanyahus-us-speech-6193912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Barbaric, Genocidal Actions...": Priyanka Gandhi On Netanyahu's US Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priyanaka-gandhi-vadra-benjamin-netanyahu-israel-gaza-war-genocidal-barbaric-genocidal-actions-priyanka-gandhi-on-netanyahus-us-speech-6193912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:25:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Congress leader Priyanka Gandhi Vadra on Friday ripped into the Israeli government over its war on Gaza - which is now into its 10th month and has killed nearly 40,000 people - and called on the world to condemn Tel Aviv's "genocidal actions".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Congress leader <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/priyanka-gandhi-vadra" target="_blank">Priyanka Gandhi Vadra</a> on Friday ripped into the Israeli government over its war on Gaza - which is now into its 10th month and has killed nearly 40,000 people - and called on the global community to condemn Tel Aviv's "genocidal actions and force them to stop".</p>

<p>"It is the moral responsibility of every right-thinking individual, including Israeli citizens who do not believe in hatred and violence, and every government in the world to condemn the Israeli government... their actions are unacceptable in a world that professes civility and morality."</p>

<p>"It is no longer enough to speak up for civilians, mothers, fathers, doctors, nurses, aid workers, journalists, teachers, writers, poets, senior citizens, and the thousands of innocent children who are being wiped out, day-after-day, by the horrific genocide taking place in Gaza."</p>

<p>Her trenchant criticism of the Israeli government - which she called "barbaric" - followed Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/benjamin-netanyahu" target="_blank">Benjamin Netanyahu</a>'s speech Wednesday in the United States.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It is no longer enough to speak up for the civilians, mothers, fathers, doctors, nurses, aid workers, journalists, teachers, writers, poets, senior citizens and the thousands of innocent children who are being wiped out day after day by the horrific genocide taking place in Gaza.…</p>
— Priyanka Gandhi Vadra (@priyankagandhi) <a href="https://twitter.com/priyankagandhi/status/1816748398910824835?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"... we are subjected to the image of the Israeli Prime Minister being given a standing ovation in the US Congress," she said on X, "He (the Israel leader) calls it 'a clash between barbarism and civilisation'... he is absolutely correct, except it is him and his government that are barbaric."</p>

<p>"...and their barbarism is given unstinted support of most of the western world..."</p>

<p>"It is truly a shame to watch," the Congress leader said.</p>

<h3><strong>Israel Prime Minister's US Speech</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Netanyahu, addressing a divided US Congress on America's continued support - which has included military aid - declared the nations had to unite for "civilisation to triumph".</p>

<p>Hours before his speech there were massive protests in Washington, D.C.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-protest-netanyahu-outside-us-capitol-call-for-gaza-ceasefire-6180789" target="_blank">Protests Against Netanyahu Outside US Capitol, Calls For Gaza Ceasefire</a></p>

<p>Crowds carrying Palestinian flags and placards gathered outside the Capitol calling for a ceasefire and Mr Netanyahu's arrest, even as prosecutors seek an international warrant.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-carries-out-new-raids-in-gaza-ahead-of-netanyahus-address-to-us-congress-6178865" target="_blank">Israel Carries Out New Raids In Gaza Ahead Of Netanyahu's Address</a></p>

<p>Israel has rejected accusations brought by South Africa at the United Nations' top court that its military operation in Gaza is a state-led genocide campaign against Palestinians. It has reacted angrily to a decision by the International Criminal Court's prosecutor to seek a warrant against Mr Netanyahu.</p>

<h3><strong>Israel Attacks On Gaza Strip</strong></h3>

<p>Meanwhile, as those protests were taking place, Israel carried out&nbsp;new raids.&nbsp;The attacks destroyed homes in towns east of Khan Younis in southern Gaza and thousands were displaced, residents said.</p>

<p>Some Palestinians - gathered at a hospital in Khan Younis before funerals for families and loved ones - criticised the United States, Israel's most important international ally, for welcoming Mr Netanyahu.</p>

<p>A day after his speech Mr Netanyahu met Vice President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/kamala-harris" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a>, who is the presumptive Democratic nominee for the 2024 Presidential election. Ms Harris' comments seemed to signal a shift in American foreign policy, at least in the final few days of Joe Biden's administration.</p>

<h3><strong>"Will Not Be Silent": Kamala Harris</strong></h3>

<p>"What has happened in Gaza over the past nine months is devastating..." she said. "We cannot look away in the face of these tragedies. We cannot allow ourselves to become numb. I will not be silent."</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamal-harris-says-will-not-be-silent-in-face-of-gaza-suffering-6190078" target="_blank">"Will Not Be Silent" On Gaza, Says Kamala Harris After Netanyahu Meeting</a></p>

<p>"We cannot look away in the face of these tragedies. We cannot allow ourselves to become numb to the suffering and I will not be silent," Ms Harris declared.</p>

<p>The US this week said negotiations on a ceasefire-for-hostages deal were moving forward, and that Mr Biden and Mr Netanyahu would discuss the agreement during the latter's US visit.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ceasefire-negotiations-appear-to-be-in-closing-stages-us-6182403" target="_blank">Gaza Ceasefire Negotiations Appear To Be In Closing Stages: US</a></p>

<p>India's Position On Israel-Gaza War</p>

<p>The Indian government last week reaffirmed its commitment to a peaceful resolution and its support for a negotiated 'two-state solution', which will lead to "the establishment of a sovereign, independent and viable state of Palestine, living... side by side at peace with Israel".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-simply-unacceptable-india-on-humanitarian-crisis-in-war-torn-gaza-5658361" target="_blank">"Simply Unacceptable": India On Humanitarian Crisis In Gaza</a></p>

<p>In May the government offered a stronger reaction, as it strongly condemned deaths of civilians and called the resulting humanitarian crisis in the region "simply unacceptable."</p>

<h3><strong>Hamas' Oct 7 Attack</strong></h3>

<p>Hamas-led fighters stormed into southern Israel on October 7, killing 1,200 people and taking 250 captives, according to Israeli tallies, triggering a war in which nearly 40,000 people in Gaza have been killed, most of whom are civilians and children, and millions displaced, many more than once.</p>

<p>Hamas and other militants are still holding 120 hostages; Israel believes around a third of them are dead. Months of stop-and-start talks have failed to produce a deal to gain their release.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/h43hvltk_priyanka-gandhi-vadra-ani_625x300_07_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/laugh-handshake-s-jaishankar-meets-russian-counterpart-in-laos-on-sidelines-of-asean-meetings-6193826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Laugh, Handshake: S Jaishankar Meets Russian Counterpart In Laos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/laugh-handshake-s-jaishankar-meets-russian-counterpart-in-laos-on-sidelines-of-asean-meetings-6193826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:17:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar met his Russian counterpart Sergey Lavrov on the sidelines of ASEAN events in Laos' Vientiane on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar met his Russian counterpart Sergey Lavrov on the sidelines of ASEAN events in Laos' Vientiane on Friday.</p>

<p>In a picture shared by the Russian Embassy in India, Mr Jaishankar and Lavrov were seen sharing a laugh as they shook hands.</p>

<p>Russian Embassy in India stated on social media platform X, "#Russia's Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov and #India's External Affairs Minister Dr S.Jaishankar @DrSJaishankar met on the sidelines of #ASEAN events."</p>

<p>Previously, the two leaders had met on the sidelines of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) Heads of State Council meeting in Astana. During his meeting with Lavrov on July 3, Mr Jaishankar raised "strong concern about Indian nationals" currently in the war zone in Russia. The two leaders also discussed the "global strategic landscape" and exchanged assessments and views.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Mr Jaishankar said, "Good to meet Russian FM Sergey Lavrov in Astana today. Wide ranging conversation on our bilateral partnership and contemporary issues. Noted the progress in many areas since our last meeting in December 2023."</p>

<p>"Raised our strong concern on Indian nationals who are currently in the war zone. Pressed for their safe and expeditious return. Also discussed the global strategic landscape and exchanged assessments and views," he added.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Mr Jaishankar, who is on a visit to Vientiane from July 25-28, participated in the ASEAN meeting. In his remarks, Mr Jaishankar said that political, economic and security cooperation with ASEAN is of the utmost priority.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said that for India, ASEAN is the cornerstone of its Act East policy, the Indo-Pacific vision that was built on it and the people-to-people linkages that India is constantly seeking to expand.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar thanked Minister for Foreign Affairs of Singapore Vivian Balakrishnan, for his wishes on the former's reappointment and said he looked forward to working with him in the future. He also appreciated Balakrishnan's role as country coordinator.</p>

<p>As the Philippines will take over as the next country coordinator, Mr Jaishankar said that he looked forward to working closely with the Secretary of Foreign Affairs of the Philippines, Enrique Manalo.</p>

<p>He congratulated Laos for the chairmanship of ASEAN. "I extend our fullest support for the successful chairmanship [to Lao PDR]. I also thank our colleague and Lao PDR for the warm welcome and hospitality."</p>

<p>He welcomed Timor-Leste as an observer in the meeting. "Last year, Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced that we will open an embassy in Delhi. We are proceeding to do so very shortly and in fact, we will be undertaking high-level visits there as well."</p>

<p>"I extend my deepest appreciation to all of you for strengthening ASEAN India relations through substantive and tangible cooperation identified under the ASEAN India Plan of Action," Mr Jaishankar said, adding that he looked forward to further discussions.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/n3qms518_s-jaishankar-and-lavrov_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar is on a visit to Vientiane from July 25-28]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/franco-swiss-airport-evacuated-for-security-reasons-ahead-of-olympics-opening-ceremony-6193823]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Franco-Swiss Airport Briefly Evacuated For "Security Reasons"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/franco-swiss-airport-evacuated-for-security-reasons-ahead-of-olympics-opening-ceremony-6193823]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:16:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Franco-Swiss airport was temporarily evacuated following a bomb threat Friday, hours after arson attacks disrupted the French rail network ahead of the Olympics opening ceremony.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Franco-Swiss airport was temporarily evacuated following a bomb threat Friday, hours after arson attacks disrupted the French rail network ahead of the Olympics opening ceremony.</p>

<p>EuroAirport, located on the French side of the border near Basel, said on its website that it had reopened and that flight operations were gradually restarting.</p>

<p>Earlier, the Basel-Mulhouse airport said it had been evacuated and closed "for safety reasons".</p>

<p>The prefecture of France's Haut-Rhin department told AFP the evacuation had been due to a bomb threat and that bomb-disposal experts were deployed.</p>

<p>Several French airports, including EuroAirport, had to be evacuated late last year due to a series of fake bomb threats.</p>

<p>EuroAirport welcomed eight million passengers in 2023.</p>

<p>The evacuation came as French authorities were hunting for the perpetrators of arson attacks on the high-speed train network, which disrupted travel for hundreds of thousands of people.</p>

<p>The Paris Olympics opening ceremony will be held Friday evening.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rjrg56og_french-police-afp_625x300_24_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Paris Olympics opening ceremony will begin Friday evening. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-stuck-in-space-still-no-clue-on-how-shell-return-6193495]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams Stuck In Space, Still No Clue How She'll Return]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-stuck-in-space-still-no-clue-on-how-shell-return-6193495]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:34:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fifty days and counting, Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams remains in limbo, uncertain of when and how she may return to Earth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fifty days and counting, Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams remains in limbo, uncertain of when and how she may return to Earth. However, the US space agency maintains that she and the eight other astronauts on board the International Space Station are safe and in 'good spirits'.</p>

<p>An Indian space expert, speaking with a touch of humour, likened her situation to being in a state of 'Trishanku'-a state where one is indeterminably but willingly stuck between a rock and a hard place.</p>

<p>Today, NASA provided further updates, indicating that they are closer to identifying the root cause of the Boeing Starliner's malfunctioning systems, such as the failed thrusters and a series of helium leaks during its maiden test flight. However, there was no clarity on when, or if, Astronaut Sunita Williams and her crewmate Butch Wilmore will return, or if they will do so aboard the same Boeing Starliner spacecraft.</p>

<p>According to Boeing, the Starliner can remain docked with the space station for a maximum of ninety days, after which the batteries on board the spacecraft may deplete. As a result, US space technologists have approximately forty days left to determine whether Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore will return to Earth on the impaired Boeing Starliner, or if they will use SpaceX's Crew Dragon or the Russian Soyuz spacecraft. Both these standby vehicles are already docked at the space station, so neither Sunita Williams nor the other eight astronauts are truly stranded in space.</p>

<p>NASA Commercial Crew Program Manager Steve Stich noted that the crew is in good spirits and making the most of their time on the station as part of Expedition 71, given that both Sunita and Butch have previously undertaken long-duration missions. He added that `contingency plans' are in place, but the current effort is focused on bringing both Sunita and Butch back to Earth on the Boeing Starliner itself.</p>

<p>Putting a brave face on the situation, Mark Nappi, Starliner program manager and vice president of Boeing, said, "I'm very confident we have a good vehicle [in Boeing Starliner] to bring the crew back with."</p>

<p>Boeing has encountered several setbacks during the Starliner's development. Originally contracted for $4.2 billion, the company has now spent approximately $5.7 billion, with the mission still incomplete. NASA sought a second alternative to SpaceX's Crew Dragon, which is why Boeing Starliner was being developed. Boeing is also facing broader difficulties, with its aviation and aircraft business stumbling, and recently, Boeing CEO David Calhoun was questioned by US Senators regarding the company's safety culture and transparency during a US Congress appearance. If the Boeing Starliner fails to return the two astronauts to Earth, it would represent a significant setback for this aerospace and space technology giant.</p>

<p>In a statement today, NASA said, 'With ground testing of a Reaction Control System (RCS) thruster complete and disassembly and inspections concluding, the Starliner team is reviewing data that will aid in future missions and pave the way for NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams to return to Earth. A landing date for the Starliner Crew Flight Test (CFT) will be scheduled following the Flight Test Readiness Review planned for later next week, with landing opportunities available throughout August. Testing of the RCS thruster at NASA's White Sands Test Facility in New Mexico yielded meaningful findings for root cause assessments and to finalise flight rationale in support of a nominal undock and landing.</p>

<p>The Starliner team plans to hot-fire 27 of 28 RCS thrusters this weekend while safely docked to the space station. This test aims to verify thruster performance, similar to what would be done during future missions. The team also seeks another data point on helium leaks, which have remained stable since the spacecraft's arrival at the station on June 6. The helium system has been closed for most of the time while docked, so no helium is leaking in that configuration.</p>

<p>Boeing, in a statement, said, 'Additionally, NASA and Boeing will conduct a second docked hot-fire test over the weekend to demonstrate the spacecraft's thruster performance. The first docked hot-fire test occurred on June 15. The upcoming test will allow checks of the helium leaks while also verifying that the thrusters are operating as expected.'</p>

<p>While some glitches were anticipated during this maiden test flight, the extension of a ten-day mission to over five times its expected duration, with no end date in sight, is deeply concerning for the global space community.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/720ksnho_sunita-williams_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>