<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 14:04:49 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/masked-men-break-into-uks-windsor-castle-estate-steal-vehicles-report-7046223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Masked Men Break Into UK's Windsor Castle Estate, Steal Vehicles: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/masked-men-break-into-uks-windsor-castle-estate-steal-vehicles-report-7046223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:57:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two masked men broke into Britain's royal Windsor Castle estate last month and stole two vehicles from a barn, the Sun newspaper reported on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two masked men broke into Britain's royal Windsor Castle estate last month and stole two vehicles from a barn, the Sun newspaper reported on Monday.</p>

<p>King Charles and his wife Camilla were not in the estate at the time of the incident but Prince William and his family were believed to be at Adelaide Cottage, part of the Windsor Castle estate, the Sun reported.</p>

<p>The men used a stolen truck to break through a security gate at night and then scaled a six-foot fence, the paper said.</p>

<p>Local police said officers were called to a report of a burglary on Crown Estate land in Windsor, west of London, just before midnight on Oct. 13.</p>

<p>"Offenders entered a farm building and made off with a black Isuzu pick-up and a red quad bike. They then made off towards the Old Windsor/Datchet area," Thames Valley Police told the newspaper. "No arrests have been made at this stage and an investigation is ongoing."</p>

<p>Windsor Castle previously faced a security scare in 2021 when authorities arrested a man with a crossbow in the grounds of the castle who said he had wanted to kill Queen Elizabeth.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mnucg928_windsor-castle-uk-reuters_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A general view of Windsor Castle with the Royal Standard flying in Windsor, England.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/hana-rawhiti-maipi-clarke-who-is-new-zealands-youngest-mp-whose-traditional-maori-dance-video-went-viral-7045701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is New Zealand's MP Whose Traditional Maori Dance Video Went Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/hana-rawhiti-maipi-clarke-who-is-new-zealands-youngest-mp-whose-traditional-maori-dance-video-went-viral-7045701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:43:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A young New Zealand parliamentarian tore a copy of the controversial Indigenous Treaty Principles Bill on the floor of the house and then performed the traditional Maori war dance, the haka.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A young New Zealand parliamentarian <a href="http://https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-mp-hana-rawhiti-kareariki-maipi-clarke-leads-traditional-dance-rips-up-copy-of-bill-in-parliament-7020108 ">tore a copy of the controversial Indigenous Treaty Principles Bill</a> on the floor of the house and then performed the traditional Maori war dance, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-haka-traditional-maori-dance-performed-by-new-zealand-mp-7033755 ">the haka</a>. A video of Hana-Rawhiti Kareariki Maipi-Clarke soon took social media by storm on Thursday, with many appreciating the 22-year-old Te Pati Maori MP's bold statement.<br />
<br />
Ms Maipi-Clarke was joined by other MPs and spectators in the gallery. Moments later, speaker Gerry Brownlee briefly suspended the session.<br />
<br />
<strong>Who is Hana-Rawhiti Maipi-Clarke?</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>At 22, Hana-Rawhiti Kareariki Maipi-Clarke is the youngest sitting Member of Parliament in New Zealand in nearly two centuries. She represents Te Pati Maori in New Zealand's Parliament.</li>
	<li>Ms Maipi-Clarke studied at Te Wharekura o Rākaumangamanga in Huntly, New Zealand.</li>
	<li>She made headlines after being elected in the 2023 New Zealand elections. She performed the traditional haka during her maiden speech as well.</li>
	<li>Ms Maipi-Clarke gained attention in a local poll, where she was listed among the top five “preferred Prime Minister” candidates after Luxon's popularity dropped due to controversial policies. Both she and her father were considered candidates to represent Te Pati Maori in the 2023 elections. Ms Maipi-Clarke was ultimately chosen for her “youthful perspective.”</li>
	<li>She has been a vocal critic of Prime Minister Christopher Luxon and his conservative government, accusing them of undermining Maori rights.</li>
	<li>At 17, she <a href="http:// https://www.teaonews.co.nz/2020/07/03/17-year-old-launches-book-about-maramataka-maori/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">published a book</a> called <em>Maahina,</em> focusing on maramataka, the Maori lunar calendar. She was inspired to explore this topic after attending a lecture by Rangi Matamua on Matariki.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Last year, she led a training course for the New Zealand Warriors about maramataka and Matariki.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3jsgi91o_new-zealand-mp-haka_625x300_14_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A video of Hana-Rawhiti Kareariki Maipi-Clarke took social media by storm.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/developing-countries-more-vulnerable-to-antimicrobial-resistance-who-7044680]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Developing Countries More Vulnerable To Antimicrobial Resistance: WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/developing-countries-more-vulnerable-to-antimicrobial-resistance-who-7044680]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:29:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Developing countries are more vulnerable to antimicrobial resistance -- a global health concern affecting the effectiveness of life-saving medicines and management of infectious diseases worldwide, said WHO Regional Director for South-East Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Developing countries are more vulnerable to antimicrobial resistance -- a global health concern affecting the effectiveness of life-saving medicines and the management of infectious diseases worldwide, said Saima Wazed, World Health Organization (WHO) Regional Director for South-East Asia on Monday.</p>

<p>World Antimicrobial Awareness Week (WAAW), celebrated every year from November 18-24, aims to increase awareness of global antimicrobial resistance (AMR) and to encourage best practices. This year's theme, “Educate. Advocate. Act now”, reflects the urgency and commitment needed to combat AMR at every level.</p>

<p>As per the WHO, an estimated 1.27 million global deaths in 2019 were directly the result of bacterial AMR, and it also contributed to 4.95 million deaths.</p>

<p>Wazed cited increased population, limited access to healthcare, and misuse of antimicrobials as major risk factors for raising the risks for AMR in developing nations.</p>

<p>“The urgency of addressing AMR is clear. High population density, restricted healthcare access, and the misuse of antimicrobials amplify the risks and impacts of AMR,” the Regional Director said.</p>

<p>She stated that this year, WAAW comes after the landmark approval of the 2024 Political Declaration on AMR at the 79th United Nations General Assembly (UNGA) High-Level Meeting on AMR, and the 4th Global High-Level Ministerial Conference, in Jeddah.</p>

<p>“This significant declaration sets ambitious targets while also establishing sustainable financing for AMR action, including the target of at least 60 per cent of countries implementing funded national action plans by 2030,” Wazed said.</p>

<p>To address the threat of AMR, she urged the global community to take immediate and decisive action “by educating all stakeholders on AMR, advocating for bold political and financial commitments, and ensuring concrete actions are taken”.</p>

<p>“The choices we make today will impact the health of future generations. Your commitment and leadership are key to transforming declarations and commitments into outcomes and impact,” Wazed said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-02/microbiome_650x400_61456572462.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-visitors-get-to-do-at-coffin-cafe-at-japan-funeral-home-7045036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Visitors Get To Do At 'Coffin Cafe' At Japan Funeral Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-visitors-get-to-do-at-coffin-cafe-at-japan-funeral-home-7045036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:23:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A funeral home in Japan has introduced a unique "coffin cafe", allowing visitors to lie in caskets and reflect on life and death.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A funeral home in Japan has introduced a unique "coffin cafe", allowing visitors to lie in caskets and reflect on life and death. The 120-year-old Kajiya Honten funeral home transformed its first floor into a surreal space for this experience. Visitors can step into one of three intricately designed coffins – gold, green, or yellow – each having floral motifs.</p>

<p>It was launched in September by Kajiya Honten in Futtsu, Chiba Prefecture, The South China Morning Post reported.<br />
<iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="709" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fwasoukukankajiya%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0dPHvkHHkQ84wjBetD5uMtmKL6pvFD7HuzHkTcf7nMCc8T8aTBDNFhwGQA5zWF39ql&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe><br />
The “coffin-lying” experience costs 2,200 yen (approximately Rs 2,000) and provides individuals or couples the opportunity to lie in a casket and contemplate their lives. For some, this has even turned into a photo opportunity.</p>

<p>The inspiration for the cafe comes from a deeply personal place for Kajiya Honten's president, Kiyotaka Hirano. He lost his father unexpectedly at the age of 24 – an event that profoundly shaped his views on life and death.</p>

<p>“Some people may want to close the coffin lid for a few minutes to consider how they want to live before their time comes,” Mr Hirano said, as per <a href="https://theindependent.sg/coffin-cafe-japans-funeral-homes-let-young-people-lie-in-death-to-reflect-on-life/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The Independent</a>.</p>

<p>He describes the activity as a symbolic “rebirth.” Mr Hirano added, “Coming out of the coffin can symbolise a reset – a chance to begin anew. We hope people leave feeling revitalised and ready to live their lives more fully.”</p>

<p>Kajiya Honten also offers services such as personalised coffin designs, floral arrangements, and even memorial urns. Mr Hirano sees the cafe as part of this evolution.</p>

<p>Japan's funeral industry has faced declining demand due to demographic and cultural shifts. A 2023 survey by Japan's Ministry of Economy, Trade, and Industry revealed a 16 per cent drop in funeral costs over the past decade. The concept has garnered attention both locally and abroad, including from Chinese social media users.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5e8f2m5g_coffin-cafe-japan_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The coffin cafe was launched in September by Kajiya Honten in Futtsu.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/work-from-home-has-substantial-benefits-but-lacks-effective-communication-report-7045689]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Work From Home Has Substantial Benefits But Lacks Effective Communication: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/work-from-home-has-substantial-benefits-but-lacks-effective-communication-report-7045689]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:11:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Work from Home (WFH) is beneficial in terms of saving on rentals, reduced commuting stress and increased efficiency for employees and but it is detrimental to effective communication and Teamwork says a report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Work from Home (WFH) is beneficial in terms of saving on rentals, reduced commuting stress and increased efficiency for employees and but it is detrimental to effective communication and Teamwork says a report.</p>

<p>The report by the Confederation of Indian Industry (CII) and the Faculty of Management Studies (FMS) reveals that while work-from-home (WFH) has brought substantial benefits, it also presents significant challenges for both employers and employees.</p>

<p>The study highlighted that WFH has led to considerable cost savings for organizations and employees. It said ". In terms of cost savings, remote working has enabled a very significant reduction in employee commuting time and costs and provided them with the flexibility to live in more affordable areas".</p>

<p>This has not only improved their energy levels but also enhanced their flexibility in choosing affordable residential locations.</p>

<p>However, the study also highlights some downsides of remote working. A key concern is the negative impact on effective communication and teamwork. The absence of physical interactions has hindered collaboration among employees, which is essential for building trust and solving complex problems.</p>

<p>For organizations, the report noted that remote and hybrid working models have allowed moderate savings on office rental costs and costs associated with client meetings.</p>

<p>Additionally, the reduction in employee commuting and accommodation costs has enabled limited adjustments in employee compensation structures. These cost savings collectively contribute to better financial efficiency for both employers and employees.</p>

<p>Moreover, the study warns that WFH may pose challenges to developing and sustaining an organization's culture. Over time, this could affect the formation of social, emotional, and human capital, which are vital for long-term organizational success.</p>

<p>The report emphasized that while remote working offers tangible short-term benefits, organizations and employees must remain cautious about the potential intangible losses it may bring in the future.</p>

<p>Balancing flexibility with opportunities for collaboration and interaction could be the way forward to make remote working sustainable in the long run.</p>

<p>It said "These losses may be intangible in nature, relating to the formation and sustenance of social, emotional, and human capital".</p>

<p>The findings provide food for thought for organizations seeking to optimize their work models in a rapidly changing professional environment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/v71d4cl_work-from-home_625x300_01_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study highlighted that WFH has led to considerable cost savings for organizations and employees.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/mystery-surrounds-alligator-found-in-suburban-new-york-waterway-7045549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mystery Surrounds Alligator Found In Suburban New York Waterway]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/mystery-surrounds-alligator-found-in-suburban-new-york-waterway-7045549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An alligator was found in a creek in Rockland County, New York, sparking widespread confusion and curiosity about how it ended up there.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An alligator was found in a creek in Rockland County, New York, sparking widespread confusion and curiosity about how it ended up there. On November 14, the Haverstraw Police Department shared on social media that a juvenile alligator was pulled from the Minisceongo Creek.</p>

<p>In a post on Facebook, the Haverstraw Police Department said their “personnel assisted in successfully removing the alligator from the water,” and added, “the Hudson Valley Humane Society of Pomona responded to the scene to take possession and care of the alligator.”</p>

<p>The discovery immediately caught the attention of locals, many of whom voiced their surprise and confusion online. “Had to be a pet. Illegally I'm sure,” one Facebook user commented, while another suggested, “People need to stop getting them as pets,” speculating that the alligator might have been a pet abandoned in the cold water.<br />
<iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="524" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fhaverstrawpolice.org%2Fposts%2Fpfbid029kxgmWvFvnqfQfxqCS4cdpzgmbvyeJAyFfsWApn7PVz4UVFoYWsrs9CBRN4e7Amdl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe><br />
In response to the situation, the Hudson Valley Humane Society praised the quick actions of the Haverstraw police. “Many thanks to the incredible response from the Haverstraw Police Department today regarding an alligator in the Minisceongo Creek (Garnerville, NY) who needed rescue. Their quick-thinking and professionalism helped to get this juvenile alligator to safety at the Hudson Valley Humane Society. Currently, this gator is warming up from the cold water,” the organisation wrote on Facebook.</p>

<p>The alligator was safely handed over to the Humane Society staff for care. A Bronx Zoo herpetologist later confirmed the alligator was a male and in good health despite its ordeal.</p>

<p>The big question remains — how did the alligator, which is not native to upstate New York, end up in the creek?</p>

<p>By November 15, the Hudson Valley Humane Society shared an update, saying the alligator, named Philippe, had been moved to Reptile Encounters, a reptile rescue centre in Saugerties, New York, run by Mark Perpetua.</p>

<p>It is illegal to own an alligator in New York but authorities have noted that many people purchase young alligators as pets and later abandon them once the animals grow too large.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cig72oq8_alligator-haverstraw-police-department-_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police department shared on social media that a juvenile alligator was pulled from Minisceongo Creek.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai/terrible-ai-has-given-tech-an-existential-headache-activist-7045582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Terrible' AI Has Given Tech An Existential Headache: Activist]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai/terrible-ai-has-given-tech-an-existential-headache-activist-7045582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:39:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["Then the moment they got an opportunity, with AI, to increase shareholder returns... every single one of them slammed the red button," climate activist Sage Lenier said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Technology firms are ceaselessly promoting new AI products, but climate activist Sage Lenier says AI is useless, unsustainable and has given the industry an existential problem.</p>

<p>"AI has no benefit to society," she told AFP on the sidelines of the Web Summit tech conference in Lisbon.</p>

<p>The CEOs who have become enraptured by a "useless" product class have smashed the idea of tech as an essential utility.</p>

<p>"And now they have an existential problem," she said.</p>

<p>Lenier first garnered attention as a 19-year-old student in 2018 when she founded and led a course at the University of California, Berkeley, titled "Solutions for a Sustainable &amp; Just Future".</p>

<p>She has said students like her were sick of the kind of climate education that offered no hope -- she wanted to focus on the solutions not just the problems.</p>

<p>Hundreds joined the course at Berkeley over the years and eventually hundreds more online, and Lenier has since built a nonprofit around it and now hopes to launch a documentary series.</p>

<p>The California native, who now lives in New York, said she was largely positive about tech.</p>

<p>But her climate focus makes her an outsider at the Web Summit -- "I'll keep coming if they want me to shout at them," she said.</p>

<p>Last year, she told the crowd: "Some of you could be considered directly responsible for architecting the ecological crisis."</p>

<p>She implored tech bosses to embrace the circular economy, which relies on reusing and recycling rather than creating products that end up being junked.</p>

<p>But one year on, Microsoft, Google and others have unleashed an endless stream of energy-gobbling AI products.</p>

<p>They have rushed to reopen nuclear plants, pledged to build many more data centres -- and crashed through their climate targets.</p>

<h3><strong>'Waste of emissions'</strong>&nbsp;</h3>

<p>Yet AI, Lenier said, "has a million negatives".</p>

<p>"It is terrible for the planet. It's terrible for every community that you're running data centres in. And it's useless. I think it's just a waste of emissions," she said.</p>

<p>She points out that it was not always this way in the tech sector.</p>

<p>"It was the only industry, at least in America, where for years and years they tried to portray themselves as clean, green and pro-future," she said.</p>

<p>"Bill Gates has written multiple books on climate change."</p>

<p>The CEOs really want the image, and succeeded in dodging the kind of scrutiny put on the fashion and automotive industries.</p>

<p>"Then the moment they got an opportunity, with AI, to increase shareholder returns... every single one of them slammed the red button," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>'So bad so fast'</strong>&nbsp;</h3>

<p>Although Lenier came to prominence by focusing attention on the solutions to the climate crisis, she sees a bleak future coming within a generation.</p>

<p>"Shit is going to get so bad so fast. The food chain is going to break. We will see mass malnourishment if not mass starvation," she said.</p>

<p>The power grid, too, will break down.</p>

<p>Against this background, products like cars and new clothes are superfluous.</p>

<p>"You can't have cars in the long term. It doesn't matter if they're electric or not. They're unsustainable," she said.</p>

<p>"We can't be producing 80 billion garments of clothing a year in a low carbon future."</p>

<p>A year ago, she said she might have argued that tech was something different.</p>

<p>"It's a piece of our infrastructure, we built our societies around it," she said.</p>

<p>But with AI, "they've given themselves their own little fast fashion".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6cs9vl88_trash-ai_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["AI has no benefit to society," Lenier told AFP on the sidelines of the Web Summit tech conference]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-anubis-apollo-the-dog-is-viral-after-climbing-giza-pyramid-7045472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["This Is Anubis": Apollo The Dog Is Viral After Climbing Giza Pyramid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-anubis-apollo-the-dog-is-viral-after-climbing-giza-pyramid-7045472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:21:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The viral footage, captured by American paragliding enthusiast Alex Lang and shared online by his friend Marshall Mosher, showed Apollo - the dog - fearlessly climbing the 136-metre monument.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Beneath the blazing Egyptian sun, crowds at the Giza Pyramids gazed up at the ancient wonders, but some had their eyes peeled for a new attraction.</p>

<p>"There he is," one Polish tourist told his wife as they spotted a scrappy dog perched on one of the stones.</p>

<p>They were talking about Apollo, a stray who became an overnight sensation last month after being filmed scaling the Great Pyramid of Khafre, one of the seven wonders of the world.</p>

<p>The viral footage, captured by American paragliding enthusiast Alex Lang and shared online by his friend Marshall Mosher, showed Apollo fearlessly climbing the 136-metre monument, barking at birds from the summit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He was acting like a king," Lang told AFP.</p>

<p>As news of Apollo's daring climb spread worldwide, interest grew in the dogs who have long made their homes among the ancient stones.</p>

<p>"He is climbing over there," said Arkadiusz Jurys, a tourist from Poland, craning his neck for a better view.</p>

<p>"It is unusual," he added, describing Apollo as surveying the picture-snapping crowd from above.</p>

<p>Another visitor, Diego Vega from Argentina, felt a special bond with the dogs.</p>

<p>"Connecting with them feels like connecting with the pharaohs," he said, while petting a member of Apollo's pack.</p>

<h3><strong>Sales up</strong></h3>

<p>Apollo's newfound fame has even inspired local guides to include him and his pack in their stories for tourists.</p>

<p>"This is Anubis," one tour guide told two American tourists, comparing Apollo, now known as the "pyramid puppy", with the ancient Egyptian god of the dead, often depicted as a man with a jackal's head.</p>

<p>"He and his pack are now part of our tour conversations," said Sobhi Fakhry, another tour guide.</p>

<p>Businesses around the Giza plateau are also seeing a boost.</p>

<p>Umm Basma, a 43-year-old woman selling souvenirs near the Khafre pyramid, reported an increase in sales thanks to the influx of tourists eager to meet the so-called pyramid dogs.</p>

<p>"We've always seen these dogs climbing the pyramids, but we never thought they would become a blessing for us," she said.</p>

<p>One pyramid guard, who preferred to remain anonymous, also said that some celebrities had paid for permits to have their own dogs photographed with Apollo.</p>

<p>Apollo, a three-year-old Baladi dog, is part of a pack of about eight that has made their home among the ancient ruins.</p>

<p>The dogs, a local breed, are known for their resilience, intelligence and ability to survive in Egypt's harsh climate.</p>

<p>Ibrahim el-Bendary, co-founder of the American Cairo Animal Rescue Foundation, which monitors the pyramid dogs, described Apollo as the pack's "alpha male".</p>

<p>"He is the bravest and strongest in his pack," he said.</p>

<p>Apollo was born in a rocky crevice within the Khafre pyramid where his mother, Laika, found shelter. Sadly, some of Apollo's siblings did not survive the site's perilous heights.</p>

<p>A sympathetic guard eventually relocated Laika to a safer spot where Apollo now stands out with his distinctive curled tail and confident nature.</p>

<h3><strong>Dog adoptions</strong></h3>

<p>The initial focus of Lang and Marshall was the daring canine climber, but their visit led to a deeper connection with Cairo's stray dogs.</p>

<p>Intrigued by the challenges they face, Mosher decided to adopt a puppy from the pack: Anubi, who is Apollo's daughter.</p>

<p>Anubi will join Marshall in the US after she receives the dedicated care she needs in Egypt to grow up healthy.</p>

<p>At the pyramids, local animal care groups are now working with the government in order to set up food and water stations for the strays, as well as for other animals including camels and horses.</p>

<p>A permanent veterinary centre will be established at the pyramids with staff set to receive animal care training, said Egypt's tourism minister.</p>

<p>Vicki Michelle Brown, the other co-founder of the American Cairo Animal Rescue Foundation, believes that Apollo's story can make a difference.</p>

<p>"It sheds so much light on the dogs and cats that are here," Brown said.</p>

<p>"I definitely believe him (Apollo) climbing the pyramids can help all of the dogs in Egypt to have a better life."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sm3viuco_apollo_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apollo's newfound fame has inspired local guides to include him in their stories for tourists.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airbus-a321xlr-the-fuel-efficient-single-aisle-long-range-aircraft-7045429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Airbus A321XLR: The Fuel-Efficient, Single-Aisle, Long-Range Aircraft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airbus-a321xlr-the-fuel-efficient-single-aisle-long-range-aircraft-7045429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:15:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The A321XLR, standing for "Xtra Long Range," is the longest-range commercial aircraft in its class, capable of flying up to 8,700 km.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An advanced single-aisle aircraft, designed for long-haul routes, made its inaugural flight on Thursday, flying from Madrid to Boston. The sleek, fuel-efficient Airbus A321XLR, equipped with a third fuel tank for extended range, completed its maiden journey with Iberia Airlines.</p>

<p>The A321XLR, standing for "Xtra Long Range," is the longest-range commercial aircraft in its class, capable of flying up to about 8,700 km. This is slightly more than the distance from New York to Istanbul. Airbus claims the A321XLR uses 30 per cent less fuel per seat compared to previous aircraft models, making it an economical choice for airlines and a more sustainable option for long-distance flights.<br />
<br />
With its impressive range, the A321XLR opens up new possibilities for airlines to operate routes previously considered impractical with larger, less efficient planes. Irish airline Aer Lingus plans to use the aircraft for new long-haul services, including routes from Dublin to Nashville and Indianapolis, next year.<br />
<br />
Aviation expert Miquel Ros, who previewed the A321XLR on the ground, focussed on the cabin's balance between space and efficiency. He described the business class seats as “slightly narrower than the ones on the airline's twin-aisle aircraft, but they still offer a clearly differentiated premium experience as well as the ability to sleep flat,” <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/16/travel/travel-news-airbus-a321xlr-single-aisle/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a>&nbsp;reported.<br />
<br />
Mr Ros also said the “economy class offers a pitch similar to that found on larger aircraft types as well as the same inflight entertainment system.” He praised the two “state-of-the-art” food galleys, designed to accommodate the aircraft's smaller cabin.<br />
<br />
The A321XLR's ability to access lesser-known destinations could help ease the pressure on some of the world's most visited tourist spots, which are struggling with overcrowding.<br />
<br />
The launch of the A321XLR is not the only exciting news in the aviation industry. Singapore Airlines is retrofitting its Airbus A350-900s, which operate the world's longest nonstop flights between Singapore and New York. The retrofit will include first-class seats on select aircraft.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m0093vv_airbus-a321xlr_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Airbus A321XLR is equipped with a third fuel tank for extended range]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-leaders-to-discuss-climate-tax-donald-trumps-comeback-in-brazil-7045416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[G20 Leaders To Discuss Climate, Tax, Donald Trump's Comeback In Brazil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-leaders-to-discuss-climate-tax-donald-trumps-comeback-in-brazil-7045416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:13:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[G20 leaders gather in Brazil on Monday to discuss fighting poverty, boosting climate financing and other multilateral initiatives that could yet be upended by Donald Trump's impending return to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>G20 leaders gather in Brazil on Monday to discuss fighting poverty, boosting climate financing and other multilateral initiatives that could yet be upended by Donald Trump's impending return to the White House.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden will attend his last summit of the world's leading economies but only as a lame duck whom other leaders are already looking beyond.</p>

<p>The main star of the show is expected to be Chinese President Xi Jinping, who has cast himself as a global statesman and protector of free trade in the face of Trump's "America First" agenda.</p>

<p>Brazil's left-wing President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva will be using his hosting duties to highlight his championing of Global South issues and the fight against climate change.</p>

<p>The summit venue is Rio de Janeiro's stunning bayside museum of modern art.</p>

<p>Security is tight for the gathering, which comes days after a failed bomb attack on Brazil's Supreme Court in Brasilia by a suspected far-right extremist, who killed himself in the process.</p>

<p>The summit will cap a farewell diplomatic tour by Biden which took him to Lima for a meeting of Asia-Pacific trading partners, and then to the Amazon in the first such visit for a sitting US president.</p>

<p>Biden, who has looked to burnish his legacy as time runs down on his presidency, has insisted his climate record would survive another Trump mandate.</p>

<h3><strong>Spotlight on climate</strong></h3>

<p>The G20 meet is happening at the same time as the COP29 climate conference in Azerbaijan, which has stalled on the issue of greater climate finance for developing countries.</p>

<p>All eyes have turned to Rio for a breakthrough.</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has called for G20 members, who account for 80 percent of global emissions, to show "leadership and compromise" to facilitate a deal.</p>

<p>A Brazilian diplomatic source said fast-developing nations like China were refusing pressure by rich countries to join them in funding global climate projects but added that he was hopeful of progress at the summit.</p>

<p>The meeting comes in a year marked by another grim litany of extreme weather events, including Brazil's worst wildfire season in over a decade, fuelled by a record drought blamed at least partly on climate change.</p>

<p>At the last G20 in India, leaders called for a tripling of renewable energy sources by the end of the decade, but without explicitly calling for an end to the use of fossil fuels.</p>

<p>One invited leader who declined to come to Rio is Russian President Vladimir Putin, whose arrest is sought by the International Criminal Court and who said his presence would "wreck" the gathering.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lula, 79, told Brazil's GloboNews channel on Sunday that the wars in Ukraine and the Middle East would be kept off the summit agenda to focus on the poor.</p>

<p>"Because if not, we will not discuss other things which are more important for people that are not at war, who are poor people and invisible to the world," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Taxing billionaires</strong></h3>

<p>The summit will open on Monday with Lula, a former steelworker who grew up in poverty, launching a "Global Alliance against Hunger and Poverty."</p>

<p>"What I want to say to the 733 million people who are hungry in the world, children who go to sleep and wake up not being sure if they will have any food to put in their mouths, is: today there isn't any, but tomorrow there will be," Lula said on the weekend.</p>

<p>Brazil is also pushing for higher taxes on billionaires.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lula had faced resistance to parts of his agenda from Argentina but on Sunday a Brazilian diplomatic source said negotiators from all G20 members had agreed on a draft final statement to be put to their respective leaders.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bd3ammqo_g20_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The summit venue is Rio de Janeiro's bayside museum of modern art.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-pm-modi-transformed-india-africa-engagement-7045413]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: How PM Modi Transformed India-Africa Engagement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-pm-modi-transformed-india-africa-engagement-7045413]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:12:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indias relationship with African nations has deep roots, but despite decades of diplomatic rhetoric, these ties often remained lukewarm. To Modis credit, he has revitalised India-Africa relations, making them a priority.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4nh8gds_pm-modi-nigeria_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It was a moment of great pride for India when the President of the Federal Republic of Nigeria, Bola Ahmed Tinubu, conferred Nigeria's highest civilian award, the 'Grand Commander of the Order of Niger', on Prime Minister Narendra Modi. This honour recognised Modi's statesmanship and significant contributions to fostering ties between the two countries through his visionary leadership.</p>

<p>Two aspects of this recognition stand out. Firstly, Modi is the first foreign leader to receive this award since 1969. Secondly, this accolade underscores India's emergence as a global powerhouse, highlighting the trust and recognition Modi has gained for his commitment to the Global South. The only other foreign dignitary to receive this honour was Queen Elizabeth, shortly after Nigeria gained independence.</p>

<h2><strong>The G20 Invitation</strong></h2>

<p>One of the most cherished moments during India's hosting of the G20 summit in September last year was Prime Minister Modi's invitation for the African Union, represented by Chairperson Azali Assoumani, to join the G20 as a permanent member. The African Union, comprising 55 member states, now holds the same status as the European Union—the only other regional bloc with full membership. This move symbolised India's dedication to fostering inclusive global governance and amplifying Africa's voice on the world stage.</p>

<p>India's relationship with African nations has deep roots, but despite decades of diplomatic rhetoric, these ties often remained lukewarm. To Modi's credit, he has revitalised India-Africa relations, making them a priority and pursuing multi-dimensional partnerships. Many view this as India's strategic response to China's growing influence in the region.</p>

<p>Modi has ushered in a new era of multilateralism by bringing the concerns of the Global South into the mainstream international discourse. His approach reflects a commitment to ensuring that developing nations have a say in shaping the global narrative. To an external observer, it appears that Modi has personalised diplomacy while keeping India's national interests paramount.</p>

<h2><strong>An Old Association</strong></h2>

<p>Modi's interest in Africa predates his tenure as Prime Minister. Before 2014, as Chief Minister of Gujarat, Modi initiated efforts to engage with African nations. While the Gujarati community has long-standing ties with Africa, official engagement between Gujarat and African countries had been minimal. In 2009, Modi visited Uganda to invite investors to the Vibrant Gujarat Global Investors Summit. In 2011, he hosted Rwanda's Prime Minister, Bernard Makuza, at the summit, fostering investment alliances that laid the groundwork for deeper bilateral relations. These connections have strengthened further during Modi's time as Prime Minister as his government expanded its foreign policy initiatives.</p>

<p>Consider the following milestones that have bolstered India's relations with Africa under Modi's leadership:</p>

<ul>
	<li>In 2015, India hosted the 3rd India-Africa Forum Summit in New Delhi, which saw participation from African nations increase more than fourfold, signalling a shift towards deeper and more comprehensive engagement.</li>
	<li>During the COVID-19 pandemic, India's unwavering support reinforced its “first responder” philosophy, supplying vaccines and essential medical supplies to at least 25 African nations.</li>
	<li>In 2022, former Kenyan Prime Minister Raila Odinga expressed his gratitude to Modi, sharing how Ayurveda restored his daughter's eyesight. Odinga even encouraged Modi to bring Ayurveda to Africa, suggesting it could harness indigenous plants for therapeutic use and benefit countless people.</li>
	<li>Over the past decade, India has significantly boosted its development partnership with Africa, investing over $12.37 billion in 206 infrastructure projects across 43 African countries.</li>
	<li>Nearly 40,000 Africans have received training in India through the Indian Technical and Economic Cooperation (ITEC) program over the last 10 years.</li>
	<li>India launched the second phase of its tele-education and telemedicine project, and since 2019, more than 15,000 youth from 22 African countries have received scholarships for various technical degree and diploma courses.</li>
</ul>

<p>For many Indians, their understanding of Africa is rooted in its connection with Mahatma Gandhi. While Gandhi laid the philosophical foundation for India-Africa solidarity, some argue that Modi has transformed that vision into actionable, impactful policies, making it a cornerstone of India's global strategy.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Consulting Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4nh8gds_pm-modi-nigeria_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swedish-minister-bans-bananas-on-official-visits-seeks-help-for-rare-phobia-7045411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Swedish Minister Bans Bananas On Official Visits, Seeks Help For Phobia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swedish-minister-bans-bananas-on-official-visits-seeks-help-for-rare-phobia-7045411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:11:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bananaphobia is a rare and intense fear of bananas that can lead to significant discomfort when exposed to the fruit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sweden's Minister for Gender Equality, Paulina Brandberg, is seeking professional help for her rare phobia of bananas, following reports of government staff sweeping rooms before official visits for health reasons, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/11/15/i-need-help-for-my-banana-phobia-admits-swedish-minister/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Telegraph </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a 2020 post on X (formerly Twitter), Ms Brandberg revealed her "world's weirdest phobia of bananas," but the post has since been deleted. The condition, known as banana phobia, is uncommon but can cause severe reactions, such as nausea and anxiety when individuals come into contact with bananas. These symptoms may be triggered by sight or smell and are often linked to childhood experiences, though the specific causes are difficult to pinpoint.</p>

<p>Leaked emails also indicated that Ms Brandberg's team requested banana-free environments for events, including VIP lunches, often framing the condition as an allergy to make it easier for event organizers to understand.</p>

<p>Ms Brandberg is not alone in experiencing this phobia. Teresa Carvalho, a Social Democratic MP and legal policy spokesperson, also suffers from banana phobia and expressed support for Ms Brandberg on X, saying, "While we've had many tough debates on working conditions, on this issue, we stand united against a common enemy."</p>

<p>Bananaphobia is a rare and intense fear of bananas that can lead to significant discomfort when exposed to the fruit. This phobia is typically tied to negative childhood experiences, such as an unpleasant incident with bananas or a strong sensory aversion to their smell, taste, or texture.</p>

<p>Following the controversy surrounding the banana-proof requests, Ms Brandberg received support from fellow politicians. Swedish Prime Minister Ulf Kristersson expressed his "great respect" for individuals living with phobias.</p>

<p>"It bothers me that a hard-working minister is now almost reduced to a phobia. That she is being ridiculed. I think people should rise above that," he told the TT news agency.</p>

<p>Teresa Carvalho, an MP from the opposition Swedish Social Democratic Party and its spokesman for legal policy, said she also suffered from bananaphobia.</p>

<p>"We may have had many tough debates about conditions in working life, but on this issue we stand united against a common enemy," she told Ms Brandberg on X.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k4okgqsg_paulina-brandberg_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Paulina Brandberg, is seeking professional help for her rare phobia of bananas]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-studies-on-soil-sample-from-moons-far-side-have-found-7044833]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Studies On Soil Sample From Moon's Far Side Have Found]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-studies-on-soil-sample-from-moons-far-side-have-found-7044833]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:04:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Volcanic rock in the sample collected by Chang'e-6, the first mission that brought back soil from the far side of the Moon, is about 2.8 billion years old, suggesting the landing site was volcanically active at the time, according to two new studies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Volcanic rock in the sample collected by Chang'e-6, the first mission that brought back soil from the far side of the Moon, is about 2.8 billion years old, suggesting the landing site was volcanically active at the time, according to two new studies.</p>

<p>Chang'e-6 collected 1.9 kg of lunar soil via a robotic probe in June this year before returning to the Earth.&nbsp;In their first detailed analyses of lunar soil and rock from the Moon's far side, scientists said the eruption marked a recent episode of volcanic activity, previously known from samples taken by NASA's Apollo programme and Russia's Luna missions.</p>

<p>The two papers were published Friday in the journals <a href="http://https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adt1093" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Science</a> and <a href="http://https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08382-0" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Nature</a>.</p>

<p>Surprisingly, the basalt rock from the far side is young in comparison to the previously studied lunar near-side samples that aged more than 3 billion years, said Clive Neal, a professor at the University of Notre Dame and co-author on one of the two studies.</p>

<p>The near-side samples that Chang'e-5 of China collected in 2020 were analysed and found to be two billion years old.</p>

<p>The research showed the samples did not carry the signature of radioactive elements found in several Apollo-era samples.</p>

<p>“The relatively young age of the basalts (retrieved by Chang'e-6) is surprising along with the composition being practically devoid of radioactive elements,” <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/15/science/far-side-moon-samples-chang-e-6/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a> quoted Neal as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This “prompts the question ‘how and why were these magmas generated?'” he said. "The same question is still being asked about the Chang'e 5 basalts,” he added.</p>

<p>The co-author of the study said the initial analyses of the lunar soil samples further raise questions that can only be addressed in the time to come along with the study of additional samples.</p>

<p>Scientists from outside China can only apply to study these soil samples two years after the specimens' arrival on the Earth. This follows the precedent that NASA set during the Apollo missions.</p>

<p>Although the Apollo lunar flights ended in 1972, NASA says it continues to get nearly 60 research requests for samples every year. Using the Apollo data, over 2,500 scientific papers have already been published through 2015, the US space agency said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ap4i0m9g_moon-unsplash_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bluesky-how-does-it-work-and-why-are-users-leaving-elon-musks-x-7045292]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Bluesky, How Does It Work And Why Are Users Leaving Elon Musk's X]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bluesky-how-does-it-work-and-why-are-users-leaving-elon-musks-x-7045292]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:57:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A host of journalists, actors, musicians and other prominent people have dumped X in recent days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk-owned X (formerly Twitter) is undergoing a mass exodus (X-odus on social media) as nearly a million users have joined rival social media platform Bluesky after the conclusion of the US presidential elections. A host of journalists, actors, musicians and other prominent people have dumped X with Bluesky stating it had topped the app download charts on Apple's App Store and Google's Play Store in the US. As of the last update, the platform boasts of 19 million users, compared to only 10 million in early September.</p>

<h3><strong>Why are users migrating to Bluesky?</strong></h3>

<p>After Mr Musk announced his complete support for Donald Trump's presidential campaign and even formed a super PAC that spent almost $200 million on the canvassing trail -- a significant number of X users announced that they would leave the platform if the Republican leader came to power.</p>

<p>Two days before the mass migration began, President-elect Trump announced that Mr Musk would be in his cabinet, co-leading the newly formed Department of Government Efficiency alongside Vivek Ramaswamy. The decision did not go down well with a section of users who believe that X might become an echo chamber of right-wing voices.</p>

<p>Some users have taken their business to Bluesky for non-political reasons as well. A recent update to X's terms and conditions policy, which took effect on November 15, allows the platform to use posts, photos and videos, even from private accounts to train Grok -- an AI chatbot model.</p>

<p>"You agree that this license includes the right for us to (i) analyze text and other information you provide...for use with and training of our machine learning and artificial intelligence models, whether generative or another type," the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://privacy.x.com/en/blog/2024/updates-tos-privacy-policy" rel="noindex, nofollow">terms </a>say under the section about users' rights.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cruise-line-introduces-4-year-trip-for-americans-who-want-to-skip-trumps-second-term-7008487" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Cruise Line Introduces 4-Year Trip For Americans Who Want To Skip Trump's Second Term</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>What is Bluesky?</strong></h3>

<p>Bluesky started as an internal project by former X CEO Jack Dorsey in 2019. Initially an invitation-only platform, Bluesky was opened to the public in February of the same year before becoming an independent company with Jay Graber as its CEO in 2021.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">bluesky's user count grew by another million today<br />
<br />
welcome to all 19M of you ?<a href="https://t.co/x6v5YW0WFT">https://t.co/x6v5YW0WFT</a> <a href="https://t.co/FtCvcyyr20">pic.twitter.com/FtCvcyyr20</a></p>
— bluesky (@bluesky) <a href="https://twitter.com/bluesky/status/1858350434320343155?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<h3><strong>Is Bluesky different to X?</strong></h3>

<p>In theory, Bluesky allows users to customise their feed by choosing the algorithm that drives what they see. It allows users to have website addresses as their handles which makes the interactions authentic as opposed to the swarm of bots on X. Additionally, it could act as a verification tool for public figures, athletes and journalists.</p>

<h3><strong>Can Bluesky cope with the deluge?</strong></h3>

<p>Last week, the Bluesky team stated that it had received 42,000 moderation reports in the last 24 hours (versus 360,000 in all of 2023). The Bluesky team said it was working to hire new members and requested users to help by reporting troll, spam, and scam accounts. Bluesky has also implemented email verification for new signups.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sstlqb68_bluesky_625x300_16_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bluesky has seen its user base swell to 19 million.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-executes-over-100-foreigners-in-2024-why-7045277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Saudi Arabia Executed Over 100 Foreigners This Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-executes-over-100-foreigners-in-2024-why-7045277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:51:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 101 foreigners executed so far included nationals from Pakistan, Yemen, Syria, Nigeria, Egypt, and other countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-executes-over-100-foreigners-in-2024-report-7040603 ">executed 101 foreigners</a> in 2024, the largest number of people put to death in a single year in the kingdom's history. The figure represents nearly three times the number of foreigners executed in 2023 and 2022 (34 each year).</p>

<p>Human rights organisations have accused the kingdom of an unprecedented escalation in its use of the death penalty.<br />
<br />
Drug-related offences drove many of these deaths. Of the 92 executions linked to drug crimes this year, 69 involved foreign nationals.<br />
<br />
"Foreigners are the most vulnerable group," Taha al-Hajji, the legal director of the European-Saudi Organisation for Human Rights (ESOHR), was quoted as saying by the news agency AFP. "They are often victims of major drug dealers and subjected to a series of violations from the moment of their arrest until their execution."<br />
<br />
As the number of executions continues to rise, families of those on death row are left in constant fear.</p>

<p>"Families of foreign nationals on death row are understandably terrified that their loved one will be next," said Jeed Basyouni from the anti-death penalty group Reprieve.</p>

<p>He called the situation an "unprecedented execution crisis."</p>

<p>According to AFP, foreigners executed this year included 21 from Pakistan, 20 from Yemen, 14 from Syria, 10 from Nigeria, nine from Egypt, eight from Jordan and seven from Ethiopia. There were also three each from Sudan, India and Afghanistan, and one each from Sri Lanka, Eritrea and the Philippines.</p>

<p>The kingdom has been under increasing scrutiny for its use of the death penalty, with international organisations such as Amnesty International citing Saudi Arabia as the third-largest executor of prisoners worldwide, behind China and Iran.<br />
<br />
The high number of executions this year contradicts claims of Saudi Arabia's de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, who, in a 2022 interview with The Atlantic, said the kingdom had abolished the death penalty, except for cases involving murder or individuals posing a threat to many lives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ag44m6e_saudi-generic-unsplash_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suhas-subramanyam-congressman-elect-opposes-tariffs-on-india-fears-trade-war-7045204]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Congressman-Elect Opposes Tariffs On India, Fears Trade War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suhas-subramanyam-congressman-elect-opposes-tariffs-on-india-fears-trade-war-7045204]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:42:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Subramanyam's comments came amid the likelihood of higher tariffs on Indian exports by the new Trump administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Congressman-elect Suhas Subramanyam has said he is opposed to imposing tariffs on India as it will lead to a trade war between the two countries. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Subramanyam's comments came amid the likelihood of higher tariffs on Indian exports by the new Trump administration.</p>

<p>"I don't support (imposing) tariffs on India. I think that would be really bad. It would lead to a trade war. And I don't think it's good for either country," Subramanyam told PTI in an interview. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ahead of his election as US President, Donald Trump had taken a potshot at India's tariff structure and talked about imposing reciprocal tax on countries like China and India. &nbsp;</p>

<p>With Trump set to assume charge as US president, there is a likelihood of higher tariffs on Indian exports.</p>

<p>"There's a lot of businesses that do really great work in India and a lot of Indian companies are expanding to the US. So the more our countries work together economically, the stronger we'll be," Subramanyam said.</p>

<p>Getting ready to be sworn in as a member of the House of Representatives, which plays a key role in shaping the foreign policy of the United States, Subramanyam said he wants to be someone who promotes democracy around the world.</p>

<p>"India, for instance, is one of the largest democracies, and the US-India relationship is very important to both countries," he said.</p>

<p>Subramanyam, 38, is the sixth Indian-American elected to the US House of Representatives.</p>

<p>He joins Indian Americans Dr Ami Bera, Pramila Jayapal, Raja Krishnamoorthi, Ro Khanna and Shri Thanedar in the so-called Samosa Caucus.</p>

<p>He was declared elected from the 10th Congressional District of Virginia and is the first Indian-American to be elected from the East Coast.</p>

<p>He also advocated an overhaul of the US immigration system.</p>

<p>"I'm hearing a lot about immigration, especially people on H-1B visas trying to get a path to citizenship and a Green Card at least. And at least a change of status," Subramanyam said.</p>

<p>"We need an immigration system overhaul in the United States. We need to focus on legal immigration. There's a lot of talk about undocumented immigrants, and I certainly support securing our border, but we need to do more than just that," he said.</p>

<p>Subramanyam said he would also oppose any move by the incoming Trump administration to cut large-scale federal jobs and is looking to be a champion of the federal workforce.</p>

<p>."I want to make sure as they look at the government overhaul that's being proposed, that doesn't mean firing federal workers or cancelling federal contracts," he said.</p>

<p>He said he looks forward to being a champion for the federal workforce in Virginia.</p>

<p>"I will oppose any efforts (of the incoming administration to cut federal jobs)," he said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-08/gslm504g_trump-modi_625x300_27_August_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[When Trump assumes charge as US president, there is a likelihood of higher tariffs on Indian exports.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-tracker-big-tech-critic-brendan-carr-to-be-trumps-communications-chief-7045142]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Big Tech Critic Brendan Carr To Be Trump's Communications Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-tracker-big-tech-critic-brendan-carr-to-be-trumps-communications-chief-7045142]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:34:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Trump 2.0 cabinet is taking shape, with Donald Trump appointing his top aides to prominent roles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Trump 2.0 cabinet is taking shape, with Donald Trump appointing his top aides to prominent roles. Ahead of his grand return to the White House in January next year, he has appointed Republican Brendan Carr, an Elon Musk-backed critic of big tech, to lead the Federal Communications Commission (FCC).</p>

<p>Moving quickly since his election on November 5, Trump has begun rolling out his administration - some of whom include a TV news anchor at the helm of the Pentagon. Trump swept all seven swing states as he secured his second presidential term after losing to Joe Biden four years ago.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump Tracker: Follow news about Trump 2.0:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c31dbfe8_trump_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has begun rolling out his administration since his reelection as US President]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mother-sentenced-to-life-for-killing-sons-by-placing-them-in-oven-7045023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Sentenced to Life For Killing Sons By "Placing Them In Oven"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mother-sentenced-to-life-for-killing-sons-by-placing-them-in-oven-7045023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:15:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident dates back to 2017 when Ms Willimas called emergency services to report she had found her two sons dead in the home.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mother of three in the US state of Atlanta has been sentenced to life in prison without parole for killing two of her sons by "placing them in an oven and turning it on", according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://lawandcrime.com/crime/it-was-friday-the-13th-mother-who-killed-her-2-toddler-boys-by-placing-them-in-an-oven-and-turning-it-on-will-spend-the-rest-of-her-life-in-prison/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Law &amp; Crime</em>.</a> Lamora Williams, 24, was convicted of the death of Ja'Karter Penn, 1, and Ke'Yaunte Penn, 2, who were killed roughly an hour apart. Ms Willimas has been convicted of 14 counts against her and will serve an additional 35 years in prison on top of the life sentence.</p>

<p>The incident transpired in 2017 when Ms Willimas called emergency services to report she had found her sons dead in the home after leaving them with a caregiver. "When I came in, the stove was laying on my son, on my youngest son's head, and my other son was laid out on the floor with his brains laid out on the floor," she told the 911 dispatchers.</p>

<p>"Can you please help me? Like, can you please tell me, like, I don't want to get locked up because this is not my fault. I had just came home from work," she added.</p>

<p>Around the same time, the children's father, Jameel Penn also called 911 and reported the incident stating he had received a video call from his wife.</p>

<p>“I just received a call from my child's mother that…my…two dead babies, my sons are dead in an apartment. She video-called me and I seen it. I really think they are dead.”</p>

<p>After police officers arrived on the scene, they discovered the toddler and the baby, reporting they both had burn marks. However, a medical examiner disagreed with the preliminary findings, stating that their heads were likely placed inside a tipped-over oven. The autopsy report added that the two boys suffered "thermal changes" due to "dry heat and changes from prolonged exposure to heat".</p>

<p>"It would require an extensive amount of time to get to this degree," it added.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/amethi-murder-teacher-his-wife-and-2-children-shot-dead-at-their-home-in-up-6709534" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also read | Teacher, Wife And 2 Children Shot Dead At Their Home In UP</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Williams indicted</strong></h3>

<p>According to the arrest warrant issued by the Atlanta Police Department, sometime between midnight on October 12, 2017, and 11 pm the next day, Ms Williams "knowingly and intentionally" placed her two little children in the oven and turned it on.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Ms Williams maintained her innocence by pleading not guilty. According to Ms Williams' mother, Brenda, her daughter struggled with mental health issues and she needed to be placed on suicide watch while in jail.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/aue1fj58_lamora-williams_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Williams during the court hearing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/smartphone-catches-fire-on-parked-airplane-in-us-passengers-forced-to-evacuate-7045014]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Fliers Panic As Phone Catches Fire Inside Plane At US Airport]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/smartphone-catches-fire-on-parked-airplane-in-us-passengers-forced-to-evacuate-7045014]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:12:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Boeing 737-700 was preparing for take-off in Denver, Colorado, on Friday, when the incident was reported, forcing all 108 passengers to deboard immediately.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>People aboard a Southwest Airlines flight in the United States were forced to evacuate after a passenger's smartphone battery caught fire and damaged a seat. The Boeing 737-700 was preparing for take-off in Denver, Colorado, on Friday, when the incident was reported, forcing all 108 passengers to deboard immediately.<br />
<br />
Officials at the Federal Aviation Administration and the airline said that passengers in the back seats of the plane fled with the help of rear emergency slides. Those in the front seats had to reportedly use the front door via the jet bridge to get out of the aeroplane.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A passengers cellphone caught on fire after boarding a Southwest Airlines flight <a href="https://t.co/Epit1PGV62">pic.twitter.com/Epit1PGV62</a></p>
— non aesthetic things (@PicturesFoIder) <a href="https://twitter.com/PicturesFoIder/status/1857884761781322003?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
In its statement, the Dallas-based airline said the preliminary reports in the incident stated that one of the passengers onboard suffered a minor injury during the evacuation process. The person, whose phone caught fire, was being treated for the burns.<br />
<br />
Acting swiftly on the matter, the crew members extinguished the seat fire.<br />
<br />
Due to the inconvenience caused to the passengers, the airline said they worked to accommodate them on another flight so that they could reach their destination on time.<br />
<br />
"Southwest's customer care team is working to accommodate the passengers on another aircraft to their original destination of Houston... Nothing is more important to Southwest than the safety of its customers and employees," an airline spokesperson said.<br />
<br />
The airline said the reason behind the incident currently "remains under investigation."<br />
<br />
On the other hand, the Federal Aviation Administration added it was looking into the matter and would investigate how the smartphone caught fire.<br />
<br />
Due to the incident, the flight got delayed for three hours before reaching its destination at William P. Hobby Airport in Houston, data from FlightAware showed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/18h4ao1_us-airport-plane-fire_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The person, whose phone caught fire, was being treated for the burns.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/runaway-dog-scrim-makes-another-dramatic-escape-search-underway-7044742]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Runaway Dog Scrim Makes Another Dramatic Escape, Search Underway]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/runaway-dog-scrim-makes-another-dramatic-escape-search-underway-7044742]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:10:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scrim, the scruffy white terrier mix who captured New Orleans' heart earlier this year with his escapades, is on the run again after a dramatic escape Friday morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scrim, the scruffy white terrier mix who captured New Orleans' heart earlier this year with his escapades, is on the run again after a dramatic escape Friday morning. The notorious canine managed to jump 13 feet from a second-floor window at his owner's home, leaving rescuers scrambling.</p>

<p>Michelle Cheramie, owner of Zeus' Rescues, an animal rescue shelter, explained in a post on Instagram, “He chewed through the screen of an open window and escaped. Surveillance footage shows him leaping from the window to the ground before running off.”</p>

<p>Surveillance footage shows him landing in the yard, barking briefly, and bolting through the fence to vanish down the street.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCb9oyHRnuT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCb9oyHRnuT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCb9oyHRnuT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCb9oyHRnuT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Zeus' Rescues (@zeusrescues)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>“He's wearing a black collar, was recently shaved, and is extremely fast,” Ms Cheramie told <a href="https://www.nola.com/news/scrim-mid-citys-runaway-dog-escapes/article_4ef52bc0-a430-11ef-aa09-0fee607d4048.html#tncms-source=featured-2 " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Nola News</a>. “We've put up flyers and are going door-to-door in Carrollton, where he was last seen.”<br />
<br />
Scrim, originally adopted from Zeus' Rescues, made headlines last month after fleeing his adoptive home, sparking a six-month search involving tranquilliser darts, net guns, and countless social media alerts. He was finally caught in October, thin and injured, and was treated at Metairie Small Animal Hospital.<br />
<br />
On Friday morning, Scrim stunned his new caretakers by escaping again. “I shut every window except one in my daughter's room. Scrim found it,” Ms Cheramie admitted. “He's clever and determined – there's nothing I haven't already blamed myself for.”<br />
<br />
Equipped with a GPS collar that later ran out of battery, Scrim was last seen in the Carrollton neighbourhood. "He was spotted on Spruce Street between Joliet and Dante," Ms Cheramie wrote. Flyers and door-to-door searches are underway as volunteers rally to locate the determined dog.<br />
<br />
Recent sightings have placed Scrim near Blue Cypress Books late Friday night and close to Tchoupitoulas Street by Children's Hospital on Saturday morning. The team is urging Mid-City residents to remain vigilant and report any sightings.<br />
<br />
Social media is abuzz once again with “Scrim sightings,” and Ms Cheramie has asked anyone who sees the dog to call her at (504) 231-7865.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
“We just want him back safely,” Ms Cheramie said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7qkt75fo_runaway-dog-scrim_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Surveillance footage shows him landing in the yard.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>