<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 22:59:30 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pakistan-pm-nawaz-sharif-heads-to-uk-for-medical-treatment-6874417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Pakistan PM Nawaz Sharif Heads To UK For Medical Treatment]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pakistan-pm-nawaz-sharif-heads-to-uk-for-medical-treatment-6874417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 22:59:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's former prime minister Nawaz Sharif left for London on Friday for medical treatments, according to his party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's former prime minister Nawaz Sharif left for London on Friday for medical treatments, according to his party.</p>

<p>The Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz (PML-N) supremo's visit to the UK comes a year after he returned to Pakistan from London following a four-year-old self-imposed exile.</p>

<p>The 74-year-old three-time former premier reached the Lahore Airport from his Jati Umra residence under high security and left for London via Dubai on a foreign airline, according to the PML-N.</p>

<p>"He will stay in Dubai for one day and continue his journey to London. He may also go to the United States later," the party said.</p>

<p>Nawaz&nbsp;Sharif will spend time with his sons in London and undergo medical treatment, it said. According to Samaa TV, he is also expected to hold important meetings there.</p>

<p>His daughter, Punjab Chief Minister Maryam Nawaz, will also likely travel to London in the first week of next month.</p>

<p>Nawaz returned to the country in October 2023 after a four-year self-imposed exile in the UK.</p>

<p>He was tipped to be the prime minister of Pakistan for the fourth consecutive time after the February 2024 general election, but the powerful military establishment put its weight behind his younger brother, Shehbaz Sharif, who has a better equation with it.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/p393ntp_nawaz-sharif-_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["He may also go to the United States later," Nawaz Sharif's party said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-overtakes-apple-as-worlds-most-valuable-company-6874223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Overtakes Apple As World's Most Valuable Company]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-overtakes-apple-as-worlds-most-valuable-company-6874223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 22:24:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nvidia dethroned Apple as the world's most valuable company on Friday, following a record-setting rally in the stock powered by an insatiable demand for its new supercomputing AI chips.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia dethroned Apple as the world's most valuable company on Friday, following a record-setting rally in the stock powered by an insatiable demand for its new supercomputing AI chips.</p>

<p>Nvidia's stock market value briefly touched $3.53 trillion, while that of Apple was $3.52 trillion, according to data from LSEG.</p>

<p>In June, Nvidia briefly became the world's most valuable company, before it was overtaken by Microsoft and Apple. The tech trio's market capitalizations have been neck-and-neck for several months. Microsoft's market value stood at $3.20 trillion.</p>

<p>Nvidia's stock has risen about 18% so far in October, with a string of gains coming after OpenAI, the company behind ChatGPT, announced a funding round of $6.6 billion. Nvidia provides chips used to train so-called foundation models such as OpenAI's GPT-4.</p>

<p>"More companies are now embracing artificial intelligence in their everyday tasks and demand remains strong for Nvidia chips," said Russ Mould, investment director at AJ Bell.</p>

<p>"It is certainly in a sweet spot and so long as we avoid a big economic downturn in the United States, there is a feeling that companies will continue to invest heavily in AI capabilities, creating a healthy tailwind for Nvidia."</p>

<p>Nvidia's shares hit a record high on Tuesday, building on a rally from last week when TSMC, the world's largest contract chipmaker, posted a forecast-beating 54% jump in quarterly profit driven by soaring demand for chips used in AI.</p>

<p>The next big test will be when Nvidia reports third-quarter results in November. Nvidia in August forecast third-quarter revenue of $32.5 billion, plus or minus 2%, compared with the current average analyst expectation of $32.90 billion, according to data compiled by LSEG.</p>

<p>Morgan Stanley analyst Joseph Moore said in a note dated Oct. 10 that he remains "very bullish" about the company longer term, but the recent rally "raises the bar for earnings somewhat".</p>

<p>After a meeting with Nvidia's CEO Jensen Huang, Moore noted the ramp up in production of its next-generation Blackwell chips appeared to be "quite strong" and are booked out for 12 months. The stock came under pressure in August after Nvidia confirmed reports that the production of Blackwell chips was delayed until the fourth quarter.</p>

<p>Shares of Nvidia, Apple and Microsoft have an outsized influence on the richly valued technology sector as well as the broader U.S. stock market, with the trio accounting for about a fifth of the S&amp;P 500 index's weightage.</p>

<p>Frenzy around the prospects of AI, expectations that the U.S. Federal Reserve will considerably bring down interest rates, and most recently, an upbeat start to the earnings season, have pushed the benchmark S&amp;P 500 to an all-time high last week.</p>

<p>Nvidia's massive gains have helped boost the stock's appeal for option traders and the company's options are among the most traded on any given day in recent months, according to data from options analytics provider Trade Alert.</p>

<p>The stock has surged nearly 190% so far this year as a boom in generative AI prompted the company to issue a series of blowout forecasts.</p>

<p>"The question is whether the revenue stream will last for a long time and will be driven by the emotion of investors rather than by any ability to prove or disprove the thesis that AI is overdone," said Rick Meckler, partner at Cherry Lane Investments, a family investment office in New Vernon, New Jersey.</p>

<p>"I think Nvidia knows that near term, their numbers are likely to be quite remarkable."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dan464no_nvidia-apple-ndtv_625x300_25_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nvidia dethroned Apple as the world's most valuable company today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/waymo-driverless-taxi-start-up-from-googles-parent-firm-alphabet-raises-5-6-billion-6874094]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Waymo, Driverless Cab Start-Up From Google's Parent Firm, Gets $5.6 Billion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/waymo-driverless-taxi-start-up-from-googles-parent-firm-alphabet-raises-5-6-billion-6874094]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 22:07:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alphabet's self-driving unit, Waymo, said on Friday it had closed a $5.6 billion funding round led by the Google parent, as it looks to expand its autonomous ride-hailing service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alphabet's self-driving unit, Waymo, said on Friday it had closed a $5.6 billion funding round led by the Google parent, as it looks to expand its autonomous ride-hailing service.</p>

<p>Automakers and technology companies are investing in autonomous ride-hailing services to capitalize on the technology to drive commercial success, even as it faces widespread skepticism and tight regulatory scrutiny.</p>

<p>The investment round also saw participation from existing investors including Andreessen Horowitz, Fidelity, Perry Creek, Silver Lake, Tiger Global, and T. Rowe Price, Waymo said.</p>

<p>"With this latest investment, we will continue to welcome more riders into our Waymo One ride-hailing service in San Francisco, Phoenix, and Los Angeles, and in Austin and Atlanta through our expanded partnership with Uber," the company said.</p>

<p>Alphabet had planned a $5 billion investment in Waymo over a multi-year period, finance chief Ruth Porat said in July.</p>

<p>Waymo, which offers paid rides in autonomous vehicles in the Bay Area and Los Angeles, as well as in Phoenix, Arizona, spent years logging millions of miles of testing before it received its first permit in 2022 from the California Public Utilities Commission, which regulates ride-hailing services.</p>

<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk said on Wednesday that the electric vehicle maker will roll out driverless ride-hailing services to the public in California and Texas next year.</p>

<p>General Motors' Cruise is testing cars with human safety drivers after an accident last year led it to pull all vehicles from the road. Meanwhile, Amazon's Zoox is expanding testing for its vehicles built without steering wheels and pedals.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6il8jnhk_waymo-ride-hailing-service-waymo-cabs-waymo-taxi_625x300_25_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alphabet's Waymo closes $5.6 billion funding to expand autonomous ride-hailing service]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-ukraine-could-join-nato-we-can-decide-too-putin-on-north-korean-troops-6873893]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[If Ukraine Could Join NATO, We Can Decide Too: Putin On North Korean Troops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-ukraine-could-join-nato-we-can-decide-too-putin-on-north-korean-troops-6873893]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 21:35:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin said on Friday that it was Russia's business whether or not it decided to use North Korean troops and said that if Ukraine wanted to join NATO then Moscow could do what it wanted to ensure its own security.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin said on Friday that it was Russia's business whether or not it decided to use North Korean troops and said that if Ukraine wanted to join NATO then Moscow could do what it wanted to ensure its own security.</p>

<p>The United States said on Wednesday that it had seen evidence that North Korea has sent 3,000 troops to Russia for possible deployment in Ukraine, a move that the West is casting as a significant escalation of the Ukraine war.</p>

<p>Ukraine's military intelligence service said that the first North Korean units trained in Russia had been deployed in the Kursk region, a Russian border area where Ukrainian forces took a chunk of Russian land in August.</p>

<p>"When we have to decide something, we will decide... but it is our sovereign decision whether we will apply it, whether we will not, whether we need it," Putin told Russian state television. "This is our business."</p>

<p>Putin said that the West repeatedly said that it was up to Ukraine how it ensured its security - "with or without NATO."</p>

<p>"The sooner they realise the futility of such an approach in relations with Russia, the better it will be for everyone, and perhaps, above all, for themselves," Putin said.</p>

<p>Vladimir Putin and North Korean leader Kim Jong Un signed a comprehensive strategic partnership agreement during Putin's visit to Pyongyang in June.</p>

<p>Article 4 of the agreement says: "If one of the Parties is subjected to an armed attack by any state or several states and thus finds itself in a state of war, the other party will immediately provide military and other assistance with all means at its disposal."</p>

<p>Putin on Thursday did not deny U.S. claims that North Korea had sent troops to Russia but said on Thursday it is up to Moscow how to run its mutual defence clause with Pyongyang and accused the West of escalating the Ukraine war.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n9v97do4_north-korea-army-north-korea-troops-reuters_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin said that it was Russia's business whether or not it decided to use North Korean troops]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-plans-to-arm-itself-against-chinas-hypersonic-weapons-6873762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How US Plans To Arm Itself Against China's Hypersonic Weapons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-plans-to-arm-itself-against-chinas-hypersonic-weapons-6873762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 21:17:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fearing China will deploy hypersonic weapons to sink ships in the Pacific, the U.S. Navy is moving forward with a plan to arm some of its vessels with Patriot interceptor missiles, two senior defense officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fearing China will deploy hypersonic weapons to sink ships in the Pacific, the U.S. Navy is moving forward with a plan to arm some of its vessels with Patriot interceptor missiles, two senior defense officials said.</p>

<p>One industry official said putting the highly agile Patriot Advanced Capability-3 Missile Segment Enhancement (PAC-3 MSE) interceptors, used primarily in the U.S. by the Army, aboard Navy ships anticipates advances in Chinese missile technology, including the use of highly maneuverable hypersonic weapons.</p>

<p>Integrating the Lockheed Martin-made missiles with ships' air defenses comes amid simmering tension in the Indo-Pacific region as China rapidly modernizes its military, and in the wake of successful missile defense efforts in Ukraine and the Middle East.</p>

<p>How many PAC-3 interceptors the Navy will need is uncertain, but overall demand is "through the roof," said Tom Karako, a missile defense expert at the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington.</p>

<p>He said there was strong interest from foreign governments adding that the U.S. Army wants to more than double production in coming years.</p>

<p>The U.S. has tapped Japan, a key ally, as a location for joint production of Patriot missiles, and Lockheed Martin wants to establish a new production line for the missiles' seekers in Florida, industry sources have told Reuters.</p>

<p>That plant would complement Boeing's seeker manufacturing efforts, and Lockheed Martin is pitching the benefits of additional production to the U.S. Army, which must sign off on it.</p>

<p>The PAC-3 has already shot down maneuvering hypersonic missiles in Ukraine. The Navy thinks it could add another high-probability layer to its anti-missile systems, which have not been battle-tested against such weapons.</p>

<p>The Navy told Reuters, "More testing is required in the development roadmap that will include launching PAC-3 MSE from a ship and validating communication with the SPY-1 radar," the main sensor in the Aegis missile system.</p>

<p>That follows efforts by the U.S. military that have already yielded new weapons and new strategies in the Indo-Pacific aimed at deterring Beijing from a conflict, or winning one if it occurs.</p>

<p>Beijing's most sophisticated anti-ship ballistic missile, the DF-27, which uses a hypersonic glide vehicle to maneuver to its target, was tested in 2023. The Pentagon's China military report that year said the weapon was "in development".</p>

<p>The PAC-3 is shorter-ranged than the Navy's SM-6 missiles and cannot reach into space.</p>

<p>But steering rockets near the nose make it more agile, and destruction of the threat is more likely because of its "hit to kill" concept, in which the interceptor strikes the target rather than explode near it, said a missile defense program director with direct knowledge of the Aegis system.</p>

<p>Facing advanced Chinese weapons, including hypersonic glide vehicle warheads, those qualities "supplement the existing missiles on a U.S. ship very well" by being able to more easily hit high-speed, maneuvering ballistic missiles and destroy them, said the program director.</p>

<p>Like the industry and defense officials, he declined to be identified as he was not authorized to speak to the media.</p>

<h2><strong>GROWING THREAT</strong></h2>

<p>A PAC-3 interceptor from a Patriot missile system, primarily used by the U.S. Army and allied nations for land-based air defense, was tested in May on a "virtual Aegis ship" using a Mk. 70 vertical launcher, but has not been deployed on naval vessels.</p>

<p>In the last year, however, it has intercepted numerous ballistic threats and aircraft in the Middle East and Ukraine, including Russia's advanced Khinzal missiles, making it an attractive addition to Navy magazines, the defense officials and people familiar with the matter said.</p>

<p>The PAC-3 round is also much smaller than an SM-6 or SM-3, weighing about 300 kg (660 lbs), compared with 1,500 kg for the SM-6, and is about 9 cm (3.5 inches) smaller in diameter.</p>

<p>Cost per missile varies by the customer and the deal, but both are roughly $4 million each, according to estimates.</p>

<p>China has already developed a formidable arsenal of anti-ship ballistic missiles, including the DF-21D "carrier killer," and anti-ship warheads for its DF-26 intermediate-range ballistic missile (IRBM).</p>

<p>Its DF-27, which the Pentagon says could reach as far as 8,000 km (5,000 miles), appears to use an aerodynamic warhead that can maneuver to evade defences or more easily hit a moving target, said Tim Wright of the missile defense initiative team at the International Institute of Strategic Studies.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2sfldcn_us-patriot-missile-patriot-advanced-capability-3-pac-3-missile-unit-reuters_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Navy is moving forward with a plan to arm some of its vessels with Patriot interceptor missiles]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/controversial-poop-statue-near-us-capitol-stirs-debate-over-january-6-riots-6873518]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Poop Statue Near US Capitol Stirs Debate Over January 6 Riots]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/controversial-poop-statue-near-us-capitol-stirs-debate-over-january-6-riots-6873518]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 20:41:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This striking "poop statue" installation serves as a symbolic critique of the January 6 Capitol riot, depicting a large, soft-serve turd placed on former House Speaker Nancy Pelosis desk]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the last 10 years, powerful symbols have frequently been used around the world to express popular outrage and protests. One of the more unusual memorials, nevertheless, has just surfaced in front of the US Capitol, which houses the US Congress and is the centre of the federal government.</p>

<p>This unusual sculpture, a massive 'poop statue' that represents the events of the Capitol attack on January 6, has drawn a lot of attention and served as a contentious and enduring reminder of the event's importance in American history.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/25/us-news/poop-statue-overlooking-capitol-creating-quite-the-stink/"><em>The New York Post, </em></a>it depicts a large, soft-served turd sitting atop former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi's desk in an apparent dig at former President Donald Trump and the rioters who stormed the seat of Congress on Jan. 6, 2021.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-january-6-rioter-to-breach-us-capitol-jailed-for-more-than-4-years-6433249"><strong>Also Read | First January 6 Rioter To Breach US Capitol Jailed For More Than 4 Years</strong></a></p>

<p>"This memorial honours the brave men and women who broke into the United States Capitol on January 6th, 2021 to loot, urinate, and defecate throughout those hallowed halls in order to overturn an election," a plaque on the base of the statue reads.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-supporter-who-rioted-at-us-capitol-to-get-his-spear-headdress-back-6273898"><strong>Also Read | Trump Supporter Who Rioted At US Capitol To Get His Spear, Headdress Back</strong></a></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2024/10/24/dc-poop-statue-jan-6-insurrection-national-mall/"><em>The Washington Post,</em></a> the National Park Service granted the permit request to Civic Crafted LLC. Julia Jimenez-Pyzik, the person who requested the permit, did not reply to text or phone messages seeking comment. The installation will remain on the Mall through October 30, according to the permit.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5noon87g_poop-statue_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The statue is not only allowed to be there but will remain there for the next week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-solitary-banana-duct-taped-to-a-wall-could-sell-for-over-rs-10-cr-6873235]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Solitary Banana Duct-Taped To A Wall Could Sell For Over Rs 10 Cr]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-solitary-banana-duct-taped-to-a-wall-could-sell-for-over-rs-10-cr-6873235]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 20:05:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maurizio Cattelan's artwork "Comedian," a banana duct-taped to a wall, returns to the spotlight as it heads to auction, with Sotheby's estimating it will fetch between $1 million and $1.5 million.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The controversial piece of art "Comedian," which is known for having a banana duct taped to a wall, is expected to fetch more than Rs 10 crore at its upcoming auction, according to <em>CNN.</em> The artwork, which was created by Italian artist Maurizio Cattelan, caused a stir in the art world in 2019 when it sold for $120,000, igniting discussions about the value and significance of art.</p>

<p>According to Sotheby's auction house, this viral piece of art, one of three original editions, is anticipated to fetch between $1 million and $1.5 million.It will go on sale at Sotheby's Now and Contemporary Evening Auction in New York on November 20.</p>

<p>For their money, the winning bidder will receive a roll of duct tape and one banana, as well as a certificate of authenticity and official instructions for installing the work. Sotheby's confirmed to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/25/style/banana-artwork-maurizio-cattelan-comedian-auction/index.html"><em>CNN</em></a> that neither the tape nor, thankfully, the banana are the originals.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/performance-artist-eats-120-000-piece-of-art-a-banana-taped-to-wall-2145208"><strong>Also Read | Performance Artist Eats $120,000 Piece Of Art - A Banana Taped To Wall</strong></a></p>

<p>Despite being written off as a gimmick at first, "Comedian" has managed to enthral viewers and collectors, demonstrating that contemporary art's tendency to push boundaries frequently makes it a distinctive investment.</p>

<p>"The most influential and radical artworks of the last century have had the power to fundamentally shift perceptions around the nature of art itself," David Galperin, Sotheby's head of contemporary art for the Americas, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/10/25/solitary-banana-duct-taped-a-wall-sell-1-000-000-21865527/?ito=article.app.share.top.whatsapp"><em>The Metro.</em></a></p>

<p>"In this spirit, Comedian is a defiant work of pure genius. Balancing profound critical thought and subversive wit, this is a defining work for the artist and for our generation. With a single brilliant gesture, Cattelan rocked the foundations of the art world and brought art to the centre of mainstream popular culture," he said.</p>

<p>"If, at its core, Comedian questions the very notion of the value of art, then putting the work at auction this November will be the ultimate realisation of its essential conceptual idea-the public will finally have a say in deciding its true value. Whatever your take on it, you won't want to miss the sensation of the season."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/eki5oteo_comedian-by-maurizio-cattelan-was-on-display-in-seouls-leeum-museum-of-art_625x300_01_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The controversial piece sparked debates on the essence of art and its value.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-ripe-to-join-indias-growth-story-pm-narendra-modi-to-german-business-delegation-6870452]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Time Ripe To Join India's Growth Story: PM To German Business Delegation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-ripe-to-join-indias-growth-story-pm-narendra-modi-to-german-business-delegation-6870452]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 16:22:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi today said this is the right time to join India's growth story, as German Chancellor Olaf Scholz met the Prime Minister in the national capital with a business delegation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today said this is the right time to join India's growth story, as German Chancellor Olaf Scholz met the Prime Minister in the national capital with a business delegation.</p>

<p>Addressing the 18th Asia-Pacific Conference of German Business 2024, PM Modi said the time is ripe for foreign investors to participate in India's growth story, and join the 'Make in India' initiative and 'Make for the World'.</p>

<p>"This is the right time to join India's growth story as the country is becoming a global trade and manufacturing hub," PM Modi said, adding that the country stands on strong pillars of democracy, demography, demand, and data.</p>

<p>Germany has expressed that India's skilled manpower is amazing as the European nation has decided to increase visas for the skilled Indian workforce from 20,000 to 90,000.</p>

<p>Chancellor Scholz arrived in Delhi late on Thursday as part of his three-day official visit to India.</p>

<p>The German Chancellor said he wanted to deepen defence ties with India and bring the two countries' militaries closer.</p>

<p>"Our overall message is clear, we need more co-operation, not less. At our inter-governmental consultations with India, we also want to deepen cooperation in defence and agree to bring our militaries together," he said.</p>

<p>The German Chancellor will travel to Goa on Saturday, where the German naval frigate 'Baden-Wuerttemberg' and combat support ship 'Frankfurt am Main' are making a scheduled port call as part of Germany's Indo-Pacific deployment.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Union Commerce and Industry Minister Piyush Goyal emphasised understanding and respecting mutual sensitivities to fast-track India-EU free trade agreement (FTA) talks.</p>

<p>Addressing the Asia-Pacific Conference of German Business, the minister stated that "extraneous" issues like labour and climate change should be discussed at international forums.</p>

<p>"A trade deal could be concluded swiftly if sensitivities were respected on both sides," Goyal told the Asia-Pacific conference of German business in the Indian capital, attended by German Economy Minister Robert Habeck.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5dhp50rk_india-germany-bilateral-talks-pti_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi and German Chancellor Olaf Scholz today held bilateral talks in New Delhi]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shoplifting-hits-record-high-costing-england-and-wales-stores-rs-18-347-crore-last-year-6871327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Shoplifting Hits Record High, Costing UK Stores Rs 18,347 Crore Last Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shoplifting-hits-record-high-costing-england-and-wales-stores-rs-18-347-crore-last-year-6871327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:54:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shoplifting in England and Wales hit record levels last year, with nearly 1,300 incidents reported daily, a 29% rise from the previous year, reaching a total of 469,788 offences.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With almost 1,300 shoplifting incidences reported per day last year, shoplifting has reached a record level in England and Wales, signalling a worrying rise in retail crime, according to <em>The Metro</em>. According to police data, 469,788 shoplifting crimes were reported in the year ending June 2024. Compared to the 365,173 cases reported the year before, this indicates a 29% rise.</p>

<p>These numbers are the highest since current records began in March 2003, according to the Office for National Statistics (ONS), highlighting a steady increase in shoplifting instances that has intensified recently. Retailers refer to the rise as an "epidemic," saying that the industry lost 1.8 billion pounds (Rs 18347.4) last year due to more aggressive methods and bolder thefts that frequently involved the use of weapons, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/10/24/shoplifting-offences-surge-all-time-high-1-300-every-day-21860208/"><em>The Metro</em></a>.</p>

<p>Major shop chains are now more concerned as a result of the increase in crime. In response, the government has promised to combat minor stealing and explore new laws that would make assaulting store employees a distinct crime.</p>

<p>"As these new figures show, we are seeing far too many prolific offenders persistently steal large volumes of products in UK shops every day, and if they are stealing to fund addictions, the situation often becomes volatile and dangerous.," Matt Hood, managing director of Co-op Food, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/10/24/shoplifting-offences-surge-all-time-high-1-300-every-day-21860208/"><em>The Metro.</em></a></p>

<p>"Crime is an occupation for some-it is not petty crime, and it is not victimless. At Co-op, we have invested over 200 million pounds in preventative measures in our shops and believe the collaborative approach between the retail industry, the police, and the government will start to instigate a change, sending out a clear message to all those who commit brazen and often violent acts of retail theft that time is now up on their criminal ways."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bf05oml8_shoplifting_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[469,788 shoplifting cases were logged in the year ending June 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-to-complete-disengagement-process-by-end-of-this-month-sources-6871293]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, China Troops To Disengage At Depsang, Demchok By Month-End: Sources]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-to-complete-disengagement-process-by-end-of-this-month-sources-6871293]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian and Chinese troops will complete disengagement - in the Depsang and Demchok areas of Ladakh - and fall back to pre-April 2020 positions by Tuesday, Army sources said this afternoon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian and Chinese troops will complete disengagement - in the Depsang and Demchok areas of Ladakh - and fall back to pre-April 2020 positions by Tuesday, Army sources said this afternoon.</p>

<p>Troops from both sides will fall back to pre-April 2020 positions and all temporary infrastructure - sheds or tents - will be removed, while ground commanders will continue to hold regular meetings.</p>

<p>Sources said each side will also continue to have surveillance options in the Depsang and Demchok areas, and will inform the other prior to stepping out on patrol "to avoid any miscommunication".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-agree-on-patrolling-agreement-along-lac-leads-to-disengagement-6838489" target="_blank">India and China reached a patrolling agreement last week</a> - for these regions only - that will, hopefully, put an end to over four years of military and diplomatic tension arising from the Line of Actual Control.</p>

<p>That tension was fuelled by a series of military skirmishes in the Pangong Lake area in May 2020 and included the clash in Ladakh's Galwan in June, in which 20 Indian soldiers died for their country.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-india-china-border-patrol-agreement-and-why-it-is-important-6844560" target="_blank">India-China Border Patrol Deal: What Is It, Why Is It Important</a></p>

<p>In the weeks and months following the Galwan violence both countries ramped up military presence along the LAC, the de facto international border; in August last year it was reported that Delhi had airlifted <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-force-airlifted-68-000-soldiers-to-eastern-ladakh-following-galwan-clash-4294934" target="_blank">nearly 70,000 soldiers, over 90 tanks, and hundreds of infantry combat vehicles</a>, as well as deploying Sukhoi and Jaguar fighter jets in eastern Ladakh, for rapid deployment in the region.</p>

<p>Beijing had similarly deployed soldiers "in considerable numbers all across Eastern Ladakh and the Northern Front, right up to (India's) Eastern Command", the Army had said earlier.</p>

<p>On the disengagement and de-escalation process, Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi said this week that the Indian military is "trying to restore trust" in its Chinese counterpart.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-patrolling-agreement-ladakh-galwan-valley-clashes-trying-to-restore-trust-army-chief-on-india-china-patrolling-deal-6845928" target="_blank">"Trying To Restore Trust": Army Chief On India-China Patrolling Deal</a></p>

<p>"This (rebuilding of trust) will happen once we are able to see each other, and convince and reassure each other, that we are not creeping into buffer zones that have been created," the General said.</p>

<p>The patrolling agreement was announced - hours before Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia for the BRICS summit where he would hold a bilateral with China's Xi Jinping.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-summit-brics-summit-russia-india-china-patrolling-agreement-pm-modi-xi-welcome-complete-disengagement-between-soldiers-al-6857182" target="_blank">PM Modi, Xi Welcome "Complete Disengagement" Along LAC</a></p>

<p>Speaking after it was confirmed, Mr Modi&nbsp;told the Chinese leader, "It should be our priority to ensure there is peace and stability along our border", and stressed the need for "mutual trust, mutual respect".</p>

<p>Earlier External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told NDTV the agreement was the result of "patient and persevering diplomacy". Speaking at NDTV's World Summit, he said, "I think it <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-will-be-able-to-go-back-to-2020-patrolling-s-jaishankar-on-lac-border-row-6839082" target="_blank">creates a basis for peace and tranquillity along the border</a>, which was there before 2020..."</p>

<p>De-escalation is still a concern in other areas, including the Gogra-Hot Springs area in Ladakh, after Indian and Chinese forces backed down in September last year. However, intel indicates China continues to hold large swathes of Indian territory to the north, in the Depsang plains area.</p>

<p>Depsang is seen as critical for India since it provides access to the airstrip at Daulat Beg Oldie and prevents Chinese troops from threatening vital logistics centres in the area. Demchok, meanwhile is divided in two by the LAC; India controls the western part, which is claimed by China.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7hk09f44_soldiers-in-ladakh-army-in-ladakh-ians_625x300_25_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/death-of-hezbollah-leader-marked-end-of-an-era-analyst-6871047]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Death Of Hezbollah Leader Marked "End Of An Era": Analyst]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/death-of-hezbollah-leader-marked-end-of-an-era-analyst-6871047]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:17:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The killing of Hezbollah's powerful leader Hassan Nasrallah a month ago has marked a fundamental shift for the Iran-backed Lebanese movement and revived calls for it to surrender its vast weapons arsenal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The killing of Hezbollah's powerful leader Hassan Nasrallah a month ago has marked a fundamental shift for the Iran-backed Lebanese movement and revived calls for it to surrender its vast weapons arsenal.</p>

<p>"The death of Nasrallah marked the end of an era," said analyst Sam Heller of the US-based think tank Century Foundation.</p>

<p>After decades at the helm, Nasrallah's death "will necessarily mark a shift for the organisation", Heller added.</p>

<p>Nasrallah's influence extended far beyond his loyal Shiite Muslim support base in Lebanon.</p>

<p>He was a key pillar in Iran's "axis of resistance" against the United States and Israel, which includes other armed groups in the Middle East as well as Syria.</p>

<p>Israel dealt Hezbollah a seismic blow when it assassinated Nasrallah on September 27 in a huge air strike on Beirut's southern suburbs that has thrust the movement into a new age.</p>

<p>Hezbollah was already mired in a year of cross-border exchanges of fire with Israel, which it began in support of its Palestinian ally Hamas after the October 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p>Last month, Israel ramped up strikes on Hezbollah strongholds and sent in ground forces while killing one member of the group's top leadership after another.</p>

<p>Nasrallah, who had led the group since 1992, spearheaded operations against Israel for decades, and gained cult status among his supporters during the 2006 war.</p>

<p>According to Heller, "he was the foremost decision-maker in the organisation as it rose to prominence in Lebanon and regionally."</p>

<p>The group's governing Shura Council has yet to appoint a successor.</p>

<p>Hashem Safieddine, a cleric tipped for the post, was killed by Israel just days after Nasrallah.</p>

<p><strong>Home turf</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah is now run by a group of leaders, according to its deputy head Naim Qassem.</p>

<p>Lebanese officials, including Prime Minister Najib Mikati, have said that their contact with the group has been cut off for weeks.</p>

<p>Nabih Berri, Lebanon's parliament speaker who heads the Hezbollah-allied Amal Movement, is tasked with speaking on the group's behalf, Qassem said in a recent speech.</p>

<p>Berri is believed to be pushing for a ceasefire, according to local media reports.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had long linked a ceasefire in Lebanon to an end to fighting in Gaza, a position it has yet to formally reverse.</p>

<p>Even with the group appearing on the back foot, its fighters continue to fire dozens of rockets daily into Israel, some reaching major cities like Haifa and Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>This week, Hezbollah claimed a drone strike on Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's home in the coastal town of Caesarea.</p>

<p>The group says Israeli forces have not been able to take full control of any village in Lebanon, weeks into a ground invasion.</p>

<p>Israeli forces operating in Lebanon "face very fierce resistance and are forced to retreat under heavy blows", said a source close to Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"The maximum depth the Israelis have reached is estimated at about two kilometres (1.2 miles)," said the source, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, he said, has the advantage because it is fighting on its own terrain, knowing which "trees and rocks" to hide behind.</p>

<p><strong>'Disarm'</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah is widely believed to be better armed than Lebanon's national military, and remains the only group that did not surrender its weapons after the 1975-1990 civil war.</p>

<p>After years of dominating political life in Lebanon, Hezbollah is facing new calls from its critics within the country to change.</p>

<p>Lebanese computer engineer Elie Jabbour told AFP he believes the only way forward is for Hezbollah to give up its weapons.</p>

<p>"The war cannot end before Hezbollah is disarmed," he said.</p>

<p>"When that happens, it can join state institutions as a political party only," said the 27-year-old.</p>

<p>A ceasefire in Lebanon has been tied to the implementation of a UN resolution that ended the last Israel-Hezbollah war in 2006.</p>

<p>UN Security Council Resolution 1701 states that only the Lebanese army and UN peacekeepers should deploy in areas south of the Litani River -- an area Hezbollah has long operated in.</p>

<p>But Lebanon is grappling with a prolonged crisis, leaving the country rudderless until a president is elected after a two-year void.</p>

<p>Many in Lebanon blame Hezbollah for blocking the vote.</p>

<p>Samir Geagea, leader of the Lebanese Forces party and a longtime Hezbollah opponent, said any new president must not "leave any group or weapon outside the framework of the state".</p>

<p>Prime Minister Najib Mikati said on Thursday that only the state should carry weapons.</p>

<p>But in a country long wracked by division, attempts to "marginalise Hezbollah politically will... invite a violent response" from the group, Heller said.</p>

<p>It "will end in intra-Lebanese conflict," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b3vhpba_hassan-nasrallah_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah's leader Hassan Nasrallah was killed a month ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kursk-residents-get-used-to-life-with-strikes-sirens-6870892]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kursk Residents Get Used To Life With Strikes, Sirens]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kursk-residents-get-used-to-life-with-strikes-sirens-6870892]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:58:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Ukraine launched a ground assault into Russia's Kursk region in August, President Vladimir Putin promised to quickly "dislodge" Kyiv's forces and return normality to local residents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Ukraine launched a ground assault into Russia's Kursk region in August, President Vladimir Putin promised to quickly "dislodge" Kyiv's forces and return normality to local residents.</p>

<p>But nearly three months later, signs of the conflict are still found everywhere in the region's capital, despite Russia claiming it is clawing back ground from Ukrainian troops.</p>

<p>School buildings in Kursk have been fortified with sandbags, while many windows are sealed with tape due to the risk of Ukrainian attacks.</p>

<p>Displaced people fleeing fighting near the border are regularly seen gathering at aid centres and some residents say they live in fear of aerial bombardment.</p>

<p>"You cannot show fear to your children. Because if you are afraid and they realise it... they become scared," said 36-year-old Margarita Kotova.</p>

<p>The mother of three said her daughter's school lessons were often interrupted by air raid sirens, and that state media was glossing over the impact of the conflict.</p>

<p>"If you watch Russian and Kursk news, we are doing well, everything is great, everything is going according to some plan you don't understand," she told AFP.</p>

<p>"We were not told for a long time what was happening on our border," she said, adding that she now used social media to find out "how things really are".</p>

<p>Russia says it is "achieving the goals" of its two-and-a-half-year offensive in Ukraine, but this statement rings hollow for many in a city home to thousands of internally displaced people.</p>

<p><strong>'Everyone is fed up'</strong></p>

<p>At an aid centre in Kursk, Oksana Barsukova appeared glum as she queued for supplies.</p>

<p>The 44-year-old nursing assistant was told she could return to her home near the border within "three days" of fleeing Ukraine's offensive.</p>

<p>But like thousands of others, she remains displaced by fighting, with little idea of when she can go back.&nbsp;"We left everything, and came here in the clothes we were wearing," the mother of three said.</p>

<p>When she and her family tried going back home, they found its windows were shattered and "everything was broken".</p>

<p>They quickly left after hearing shooting.</p>

<p>In the city, many residents go about their day as usual and passers-by give no reaction when an air alert sounds.</p>

<p>Residents said they had adapted to the grim reality of the conflict.&nbsp;"At school during a missile threat, they sit in the corridors, or go down to a shelter if the school has one," Kotova said.</p>

<p>School principal Marina Starikova said pupils had become "used to the sirens".&nbsp;"Everyone is fed up," said 27-year-old gym teacher Vladimir Kuroptev, who was displaced by Kyiv's offensive.</p>

<p>He hopes the conflict will be over soon, but does not know when.&nbsp;"Not this year, of course, but in a year or two, everything will be over."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7vhdnje_kursk_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/race-against-time-to-avoid-lebanon-conflagration-european-union-6870859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Race Against Time" To Avoid Lebanon "Conflagration": European Union]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/race-against-time-to-avoid-lebanon-conflagration-european-union-6870859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:52:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[EU foreign policy chief Josep Borrell on Friday said the international community must speed up efforts for a political solution to end the fighting in Lebanon and prevent a "conflagration".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>EU foreign policy chief Josep Borrell on Friday said the international community must speed up efforts for a political solution to end the fighting in Lebanon and prevent a "conflagration".</p>

<p>In a statement released the day after a conference on aid for Lebanon in France, Borrell said the first step needed was a "ceasefire" between Israel and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"We are currently engaged in a race against time between the possible start of a political process in Lebanon and a generalised conflagration with incalculable consequences," Borrell said.</p>

<p>"Without a suspension of hostilities, nothing will be possible," he said.</p>

<p>Borrell said once fighting was halted, Lebanon needed to organise long-postponed presidential elections "as soon as possible".</p>

<p>He said the Lebanese Armed Forces must become the "only military force present" in the south of the country, where Israel is engaged in ground battles with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>A UN peacekeeping mission in the area must also be strengthened, he said.</p>

<p>International calls for an end to fighting have so far failed to end the fighting in the region.</p>

<p>The Paris conference on aid for conflict-stricken Lebanon raised around $800 million for humanitarian aid but saw little diplomatic progress.</p>

<p>Israel has been at war with Hezbollah in Lebanon since late last month, in a bid to secure its northern border after nearly a year of cross-border fire from the Iran-backed armed group.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began low-intensity strikes on Israel in support of its Palestinian ally Hamas following the October 7, 2023 attack on Israel, the deadliest in its history.</p>

<p>After nearly a year of war in Gaza sparked by the attack, Israel expanded its focus to Lebanon and last month launched a massive bombing campaign targeting mainly Hezbollah strongholds across the country, sending in ground troops on September 30.</p>

<p>The war in Lebanon has killed at least 1,580 people, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gf9scarg_israel-strike-on-lebanon-_625x300_13_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[EU foreign policy chief Josep Borrell called for a "ceasefire" between Israel and Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-looks-at-north-koreas-military-partners-around-the-world-6870795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Looks At North Korea's Military Partners Around The World]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-looks-at-north-koreas-military-partners-around-the-world-6870795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:43:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea has been accused of sending thousands of troops to Russia, potentially to take part in the war in Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea has been accused this week of sending thousands of troops to Russia, potentially to take part in the war in Ukraine, in a step that could bring the isolated country's first large-scale military deployment overseas since the Vietnam War.</p>

<p>Here is what we know about Pyongyang's past military co-operation with other countries:</p>

<p><strong>Vietnam</strong></p>

<p>North Korea sent more than 1,000 soldiers to North Vietnam between 1966 and 1972, including hundreds of pilots who flew MiG-17s in combat, according to a book published in 2017 by the South Korean defence ministry's Institute for Military History.</p>

<p>The North's air force shot down at least 26 U.S. planes and lost 14 of its own personnel from 1967 to 1969, a retired Vietnamese air force official told the country's People's Police newspaper.</p>

<p>Another team of North Korean psychological warfare specialists was also deployed to support North Vietnam's propaganda and abduction operations targeting South Korean troops in South Vietnam, while dozens of Vietnamese guerrillas were trained in North Korea, the South Korean book said.</p>

<p>But relations have cooled since Vietnam began embracing the West, launching political and economic reforms in the late 1980s and establishing diplomatic ties with South Korea in 1992.</p>

<p><strong>Egypt</strong></p>

<p>During the Yom Kippur War in 1973, North Korea sent a group of about 1,500 military advisers and some 40 air force personnel to Egypt, following a military assistance pact between its late leader Kim Il Sung and Egypt's Hosni Mubarak, said Niu Song, a professor at Shanghai International Studies University.</p>

<p><strong>Libya</strong></p>

<p>North Korea fostered military exchanges with Libya under Muammar Gaddafi, clinching a 10-year alliance treaty in 1982, which called for either to render military aid if the other was attacked and threatened by a third country.</p>

<p>A declassified 1982 CIA cable said Pyongyang might have been seeking to turn Libya into an "out-of-country storehouse" for its military, citing past reports about North Korean pilots and training on MiG-23s there, while laying the groundwork to acquire nuclear weapons.</p>

<p><strong>Syria</strong></p>

<p>Syria is a longtime friend of North Korea, working jointly on missiles and chemical weapons. The North also built a plutonium reactor there, destroyed by an Israeli strike in 2007.</p>

<p>In 2013, Israeli media said several North Korean helicopter pilots and artillery officers were operating in Syria, though Pyongyang's state news agency denied providing military aid.</p>

<p>In 2016, Russia's TASS state news agency said two North Korean military units were fighting in Syria's civil war for President Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<p><strong>Iran</strong></p>

<p>Both subject to U.N. sanctions, North Korea and Iran have also been suspected of co-operating on nuclear and ballistic missile programmes, exchanging technical expertise and components.</p>

<p>In 2015, an exiled Iranian dissident group that exposed the country's Natanz nuclear facility in 2002, said a delegation of seven North Korean nuclear and missile experts visited a military site near Tehran, their third such exchange that year.</p>

<p>U.N. monitors in 2021 revealed that the countries had resumed co-operation to develop long-range missiles, transferring critical parts.</p>

<p>North Korea has also been accused of supplying weapons to Iran's proxies, including Hamas, whose fighters were seen using its grenade launchers in their 2023 attack on Israel, which was denied by Pyongyang.</p>

<p><strong>Africa</strong></p>

<p>North Korea has had longstanding ties with authoritarian regimes in Zimbabwe, Uganda and elsewhere in Africa since the Cold War era, engaging in arms sales and military training.</p>

<p>In 2011, a South Korean lawmaker said North Korea had more than 100 rounds of arms sales talks between 1999 and 2008 with countries such as Angola, Congo, Libya, Tanzania and Uganda, citing confidential government data.</p>

<p>The transactions aimed at earning dollars to buy newer weapons and parts from Russia by selling old, cheap conventional ones in Africa, according to the Institute for National Security Strategy of South Korea's national intelligence agency.</p>

<p>But North Korea's relations with many African partners have waned over the past decade since facing tighter U.N. sanctions, with Botswana severing diplomatic ties in 2015 and Uganda and Ethiopia halting security exchanges in 2016.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h1b0ouag_russia-ukraine-war_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea is accused of of dispatching troops to aid Russia in the war in Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-says-germany-has-increase-visas-for-skilled-indians-from-20-000-to-90-000-6870013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany Has Increase Visas For Skilled Indians To 90,000: PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-says-germany-has-increase-visas-for-skilled-indians-from-20-000-to-90-000-6870013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:15:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Friday hailed the strengthening ties between India and Germany, citing recent collaborations as evidence of their deepening friendship.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Friday hailed the strengthening ties between India and Germany, citing recent collaborations as evidence of their deepening friendship.</p>

<p>Speaking at the 18th Asia-Pacific Conference of German Business 2024, PM Modi said, "On one hand, the CEO Forum meeting is being held here, on the other hand, our navies are practising together.&nbsp;</p>

<p>German naval ships are on a port call in Goa. And in a short while from now, the seventh inter-governmental consultations between India and Germany are also to be organized.</p>

<p>"That is, the friendship between India and Germany is deepening at every step, on every front," he added.</p>

<p>PM Modi said that this year marks the completion of 25 years of India-Germany strategic partnership and added that the next 25 years are going to take this partnership to new heights.</p>

<p>"This year is the 25th year of India-Germany Strategic Partnership. The next 25 years are going to take this partnership to new heights. We have prepared a roadmap for a developed India in the coming 25 years," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi welcomed the release of the "Focus on India" document by the German Cabinet, which outlines how two strong democracies and leading economies can cooperate for global good.</p>

<p>"I am happy that at such a crucial time, the German Cabinet has released the Focus on India document. The Focus on India document is a blueprint of how the world's two strong democracies, the world's two leading economies, can together become a force for global good. It clearly reflects the approach and commitment to take the strategic partnership forward in a holistic manner. The trust that Germany has shown in India's skilled manpower is especially amazing," he said.</p>

<p>PM Modi also expressed confidence that Germany's decision to increase visas for skilled Indians will boost its growth.</p>

<p>"Germany has decided to increase the number of visas given to skilled Indians every year from 20 thousand to 90 thousand. I am confident that this will give a new impetus to Germany's growth," he said.</p>

<p>"Our mutual trade has reached a level of more than 30 billion dollars. Today, on one hand, hundreds of German companies are in India, while Indian companies are also rapidly increasing their presence in Germany. Today, India is becoming the biggest centre of diversification and de-risking. India is also becoming a hub of global trade and manufacturing. In such a situation, this is the most appropriate time for you to Make in India, Make for the World," PM Modi said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m1ns1igo_pm-modi-chancellor-scholz-twitter_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indo-german-ties-strong-anchor-in-times-of-conflict-uncertainty-pm-narendra-modi-6870568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indo-German Ties Strong Anchor In Times Of Conflict, Uncertainty: PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indo-german-ties-strong-anchor-in-times-of-conflict-uncertainty-pm-narendra-modi-6870568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:14:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi today said the strategic partnership between India and Germany has emerged as a strong anchor at a time when the world is faced with tensions, conflicts and uncertainty.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today said the strategic partnership between India and Germany has emerged as a strong anchor at a time when the world is faced with tensions, conflicts and uncertainty.</p>

<p>Participating in the Seventh Inter-Governmental Consultations with German Chancellor Olaf Scholz, Prime Minister Modi said India-Germany ties were a transformational partnership of two capable and strong democracies and not a transactional relationship.</p>

<p>"The world is passing through times of tensions, conflicts and uncertainty. In the Indo-Pacific region, there are serious concerns about the rule of law and freedom of navigation. In times like this, the strategic partnership between India and Germany has emerged as a strong anchor," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>The prime minister recalled that this was Chancellor Scholz's third visit to India and marked the "triple celebration" of the friendship between India and Germany.</p>

<p>"In the last IGC in Berlin in 2022, we took important decisions for our bilateral cooperation. In two years, there has been encouraging progress in various sectors of our strategic relations. There has been increasing cooperation in areas such as defence, technology, energy, green and sustainable development that have become symbols of mutual trust," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>The prime minister also welcomed the 'Focus on India' strategy announced by Germany.</p>

<p>"I am delighted that to expand and elevate our partnership, we are taking several new and important initiatives and moving from the 'Whole of Government' to the Whole of Nation approach," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>The IGC framework was launched in 2011 and allows for a comprehensive review of cooperation and identification of new areas of engagement between the two countries across various sectors.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m5vu5teo_narendra-modi-olaf-scholz-german-chancellor-pti_625x300_25_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi said the strategic partnership between India and Germany has emerged as a strong anchor]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sick-and-disgusting-mia-khalifa-slammed-online-for-mocking-us-military-service-members-6870093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mia Khalifa Slammed Online For Mocking US Military Service Members]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sick-and-disgusting-mia-khalifa-slammed-online-for-mocking-us-military-service-members-6870093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 13:14:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mia Khalifa has come under fire on social media for mocking US military service members. In a video posted on X, Ms Khalifa said she hoped that US army members get "their little brains all scrambled up" for fighting war overseas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former adult film actor Mia Khalifa has come under fire on social media for mocking US military service members. In a video posted to her X account, Ms Khalifa said she hoped that US Army members get "their little brains all scrambled up" for fighting war overseas. "Good morning to everyone who is not in the US military," she starts the clip. "Good morning to everyone who is sitting at home and not on soil that doesn't belong to them, fighting a war for a country that doesn't care about them," she adds.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I hope you go over there and get your little brain all scrambled up with PTSD and come back here and see how much the United States cares about you, pookie!" <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/miakhalifa/status/1848707600591778102">Ms Khalifa mockingly says</a> in a baby voice, adding, "See how much they care about you when you come back."</p>

<p>The former film star then adopts a tone of fake crying, adding, "'Oh, I'm so sad, I p****** my pants every time I see a falafel stand in Manhattan.'"</p>

<p>"Let's see how much the VA cares about you. Let's see what they tell you to do with your little broken brain from going over to fight a war that's not yours. They're going to try to tell you to do breathing exercises because the US government does not give a f*** about you, once you cannot die for them. Once you're done, once you're a shell, they don't care about you," she concludes.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ey-fires-staff-in-us-for-taking-multiple-online-training-courses-at-once-6868561">EY Fires Staff In US For Taking Multiple Online Training Courses At Once</a></strong></p>

<p>Ms Khalifa shared the video a few days back. Since then it has amassed more than 1 million views and over 23,000 likes. In the comments section, several users criticised her for mocking the US military service members.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"People don't care about you for what COMES OUT of your mouth," wrote one user. "Like they care about what a former camgirl thinks. They'll be busy watching you embarrass yourself on their spare time. It really sucks that you made those choices, you could've been in advocacy or something that would've stopped this war," commented another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Stick to what you know.. Leave the wartime decisions to the adults," said a third user. "It's fair to have an opinion on any violent conflict in the history of the world. &nbsp;Wishing PTSD upon U.S. soldiers is sick and disgusting," expressed another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, last year, the former adult star came under fire for saying the US army is "worse than OnlyFans". &nbsp;She made the comparison in July 2022 during an appearance on the late-night talk show Ziwe in the US, and then reshared the clip in November last year on Veterans Day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She has also been outspoken on social media defending Palestinians and making jokes about the October 7, 2023 attacks. On that day, as the terrorist attacks against Israel were still unfolding, Khalifa wrote, "Can someone please tell the freedom fighters in Palestine to flip their phones and film horizontal?"&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Khalifa's posts sparked a wave of outrage on social media, resulting in her getting fired from both the adult magazine Playboy and a business deal with Canadian broadcaster and radio host Todd Shapiro.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c7mjsm1_mia-khalifa-_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video has amassed more than 1 million views.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-beyonce-backs-kamala-harris-joe-rogan-to-interview-donald-trump-6870174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Beyonce Backs Kamala Harris, Joe Rogan To Interview Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-beyonce-backs-kamala-harris-joe-rogan-to-interview-donald-trump-6870174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 13:00:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US election takes a detour from the swing state circuit to decamp to Texas on Friday as Kamala Harris rallies with pop superstar Beyonce and Donald Trump sits down with the world's biggest podcaster.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US election takes a detour from the swing state circuit to decamp to Texas on Friday as Kamala Harris rallies with pop superstar Beyonce and Donald Trump sits down with the world's biggest podcaster.</p>

<p>Solidly Republican Texas makes an unorthodox stop just days before November 5, especially for Harris who could be working to revive her momentum in the battleground states set to decide the vote.</p>

<p>But the Democratic team is gambling that its star-studded show -- also featuring country legend Willie Nelson -- will highlight Republican restrictions on abortion, a key part of Harris's platform against Trump.</p>

<p>Beyonce's backing for Harris comes on top of an endorsement from Taylor Swift and campaign appearances from artists including Lizzo, Stevie Wonder, Bruce Springsteen, Eminem and Usher.</p>

<p>The "Crazy in Love" singer will appear alongside Harris in Houston, while Trump will be in Austin, taping an interview with Joe Rogan, who hosts the most listened-to podcast globally.</p>

<p>November's presidential election will be the first held after a 2022 Supreme Court ruling overturned nationwide protection of abortion.</p>

<p>In her campaign, Harris has repeatedly linked Trump -- who took credit for the abortion ruling after reshaping the court -- to shocking stories of women who have been denied vital reproductive health care.</p>

<p>Texas now prohibits all abortions except in rare cases.</p>

<p><strong>READ |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-barack-obamas-appeal-to-the-youth-a-thought-provoking-question-on-voting-6866630">In Obama's Appeal To The Youth, A Thought-Provoking Question On Voting</a></p>

<p><strong>Viral moments</strong></p>

<p>Friday's show will mark Beyonce's first appearance with Harris, although the 32-time Grammy Award-winner has performed for Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>Harris got permission to use the singer's anthem "Freedom" and it has been the leading soundtrack of her push for the White House.</p>

<p>Both election candidates have sought to broaden their support by sidestepping traditional media in favor of podcasts and YouTube shows consumed by uncommitted young voters who could make all the difference in a tight vote.</p>

<p>Trump will woo Rogan's massive audience, seeking viral moments that tap into his everyman appeal similar to his recent photo-op at a Pennsylvania McDonald's.</p>

<p>"The Joe Rogan Experience" was the world's most listened-to podcast on streaming giant Spotify in 2023, for the fourth year running. It has 17.5 million subscribers on YouTube, and the most popular episode has been viewed 61 million times.</p>

<p>The final night of the Republican National Convention -- featuring Trump's keynote speech -- was televised by 14 networks and yet didn't get close to half that figure, notching 25 million viewers.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign said he would also deliver remarks to the press in Austin on border security and migrant crime before heading to a rally back in the swing states, in closely watched Michigan.</p>

<p><strong>READ |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-kamala-harris-barack-obama-rally-with-rock-legend-bruce-springsteen-in-georgia-6865662">Kamala Harris, Barack Obama Rally With Rock Legend Bruce Springsteen In Georgia</a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qnq9s648_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Elections 2024: A neck-and-neck battle between Donald Trump and Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-2-0-haunts-world-economy-chiefs-gathering-in-washington-before-vote-6869856]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump 2.0 Haunts World Economy Chiefs Gathering in Washington Before Vote]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-2-0-haunts-world-economy-chiefs-gathering-in-washington-before-vote-6869856]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 12:38:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The worlds financial leaders are gathered in Washington, ostensibly to discuss technical stuff: debt, inflation, interest rates. Whats really on their minds is Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world's financial leaders are gathered in Washington, ostensibly to discuss technical stuff: debt, inflation, interest rates. What's really on their minds is Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The ex-president's potential return to the White House has loomed large over this week's annual meetings of the International Monetary Fund and World Bank. At public seminars and panels, or behind closed doors at steak-house dinners, discussion kept turning to the vote that's less than two weeks away.</p>

<p>Everybody is talking about the US election and waiting with bated breath, Malaysia's second finance minister Amir Hamzah Azizan said in an interview.</p>

<p>That's because of the starkly different visions the two candidates are offering for the world's biggest economic power, which some officials speak of alongside top risks to global stability such as wars in Ukraine and the Middle East.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is a modal window.</p>

<p>Vice President Kamala Harris mostly represents continuity, while Trump is threatening to upend global trade even more than he did in his first term, by slapping tariffs of 60% on China and as much as 20% on everyone else.</p>

<p>The outcomes for policy are far enough apart as to be a source of high uncertainty, in the words of one top IMF official, at a time when the world economy is otherwise on track for a soft landing and investors are generally upbeat.</p>

<p>Markets hate uncertainty, and the biggest uncertainty of them all is hanging over these meetings: Who will be the next president of the United States? said Josh Lipsky, director of the Washington-based Atlantic Council's GeoEconomics Center. It matters for everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Kamala Harris, Donald Trump</strong></p>

<p>On the meeting's sidelines, there were plenty of events for attendees absorbed by the election guessing game.</p>

<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. hosted a client dinner keynoted by star pollster Nate Silver. The Institute of International Finance had Mike Pompeo, who served as Trump's secretary of state, among its dinner guests. At a JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. investor seminar, with one session titled Is a Trump Win Inevitable?, speakers on the agenda included Jim Messina, deputy chief of staff in the Obama administration, and senior Trump adviser Scott Bessent.</p>

<p>Financial diplomats were generally careful not to sound like they favored one candidate over the other. And most tried to avoid even mentioning Trump by name.</p>

<p>Still, some sought to paint a sanguine picture regardless of who's elected  highlighting the resilience of the US economy and the fact that Trump's first term already offered guidance about how to negotiate with him.</p>

<p><strong>Pakistan's Muhammad Aurangzeb</strong></p>

<p>Pakistan Finance Minister Muhammad Aurangzeb said his nation will ensure the US remains a major trade partner regardless of happens with policy.</p>

<p>That's been the case under various administrations which have come in, he said in an interview. So all hands on deck from our side to ensure that it remains so.</p>

<p>The Washington-based IMF and World Bank symbolize an era of barely-contested American supremacy in the world economy. That faces new challenges now, including from the BRICS group of emerging markets. Its leaders met in Russia this week, where host Vladimir Putin hailed a new multipolar world.</p>

<p>Although Trump has been skeptical of Western-led multilateral institutions in the past, World Bank President Ajay Banga expressed optimism that the GOP candidate  if elected  would see the value of the lender's ability to leverage resources, rather than opting for the US to go it alone.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Let's wait to see what comes out of the elections, said Banga, who was nominated by President Joe Biden. Let's engage with the presidency with the respect it deserves.</p>

<p><strong>ECB's Christine Lagarde</strong></p>

<p>European Central Bank Chief Christine Lagarde said whoever wins the election should tread carefully with trading partners.</p>

<p>Periods of restrictions and barriers have not been periods of prosperity and strong leadership around the world, she said at an event in the US capital. Whoever becomes the next US president should at least bear that in mind.</p>

<p>Across town at a Morton's steakhouse on Wednesday night, Gavekal Research  a China-focused advisory firm  hosted a discussion that revolved around trade policy and tariffs if Trump wins. The vibe among speakers, and an audience largely made up of finance-industry executives, was that he's in pole position right now.&nbsp;</p>

<p>People have told us that he's still really mad because of Covid and Xi Jinping costing him the last election, said the firm's head of research, Arthur Kroeber. So he's going to come in with a very negative view.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2ne2rg5_trump_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is threatening to upend global trade even more than he did in his first term]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-to-apologise-for-abuse-of-native-american-children-6869916]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden To Apologise For Abuse Of Native American Children]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-to-apologise-for-abuse-of-native-american-children-6869916]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 25 Oct 2024 12:29:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden said Thursday he will issue a formal apology for the treatment of Native American children who were forcibly removed from their families by the US government and put into an abusive boarding school system.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden said Thursday he will issue a formal apology for the treatment of Native American children who were forcibly removed from their families by the US government and put into an abusive boarding school system.</p>

<p>For over 150 years, the schools sought to forcibly assimilate Native Americans, with a recent government report detailing numerous cases of physical, mental and sexual abuse, as well as the deaths of over 950 children.</p>

<p>"I'm heading to do something that should have been done a long time ago," the president said as he left the White House. "To make a formal apology to the Indian nations for the way we treated their children for so many years."</p>

<p>Biden is scheduled to make the official apology Friday on a visit to the Gila River Indian Reservation in Arizona, one of the states with the highest Native American populations in the country and a key battleground in the US election.</p>

<p>The boarding schools, which were run by the US government, were in operation from the early 19th century until the 1970s.</p>

<p>The report found at least 973 children died at these schools, many of which were far from their original homes.</p>

<p>Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland, the first Native American cabinet secretary in US history, was a major force behind the investigation that produced the report.</p>

<p>"For more than a century, tens of thousands of Indigenous children as young as four years old, were taken from their families and communities and forced into boarding schools," Haaland told reporters. "This includes my own family."</p>

<p>"For decades, this terrible chapter was hidden from our history books," she continued. "But now our administration's work will ensure that no one will ever forget."</p>

<p>The apology follows formal declarations in Canada, where thousands of children died at similar boarding schools, and other countries around the world where historic abuses of Indigenous populations are increasingly being recognized.</p>

<p>In a statement, the White House said the apology was being issued in order to "remember and teach our full history, even when it is painful."</p>

<p>"That the president is taking that step tomorrow is so historic, I'm not sure I could adequately put its impact into words," Haaland said.</p>

<p>Biden's visit to Arizona, a state he narrowly won in 2020, comes in the midst of an extremely close presidential campaign between Vice President Kamala Harris and Republican former president Donald Trump.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o30es1hg_joe-biden-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US government run boarding schools were in operation from the early 19th century until the 1970s.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>