<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 22:27:47 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-doctor-injects-girlfriend-with-anaesthesia-20-times-in-6-hours-to-treat-insomnia-she-dies-7041910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Doctor Injects Partner With Anaesthesia To Treat Insomnia, She Dies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-doctor-injects-girlfriend-with-anaesthesia-20-times-in-6-hours-to-treat-insomnia-she-dies-7041910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 21:35:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He caused his girlfriend's death by attempting to treat her insomnia with repeated anaesthetic injections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident in southwestern China's Sichuan province, an anesthesiologist, identified by his surname Qu, has been implicated in a tragic case involving his partner, Chen, a pharmaceutical sales representative. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3286714/china-doctor-kills-insomniac-girlfriend-injecting-anaesthetics-20-times-6-hours">South China Morning Post</a></em>, he caused his girlfriend's death by attempting to treat her insomnia with repeated anaesthetic injections. He administered the anaesthesia more than 20 times&nbsp;in six hours,&nbsp;leading to her death. This incident has sparked significant online outrage in China, with many slamming the doctor's actions despite his claims of trying to help.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the two met through an online dating platform in the summer of 2022. Qu, who works at a hospital in Jinjiang County, Leshan, allegedly administered propofol, a powerful anaesthesia, to Chen in hotel rooms on multiple occasions between September 2023 and March 2024. Chen had requested the medication to alleviate her insomnia.</p>

<p>On March 6, Qu administered approximately 1,300 mg of propofol to Chen, through her ankle over six hours, from 11 pm to 5 am. He provided 20+ doses, followed by an additional 100 mg for her to use later. Upon returning to the hotel, Qu discovered Chen had died.&nbsp;A medical examination confirmed that the cause of her death was acute propofol intoxication.</p>

<p>Qu promptly reported the incident to authorities, confessed to his actions, and later provided financial compensation of 400,000 yuan (US$55,000) to Chen's relatives, who forgave him.</p>

<p>A Shanghai-based representative from a leading propofol manufacturer told The Post that propofol is not intended for treating insomnia and that the dosages used in this case drastically exceeded safe limits.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">"Propofol is a short-acting general anaesthetic used primarily for inducing and maintaining general anaesthesia and sedation. Typically, clinical doses for anaesthesia induction are 1.5-2.5 mg per kilogram of body weight. For maintenance of anaesthesia, the doses usually range from 4-12 mg per kilogram, while sedation doses vary from 1.5-4.5 mg per kilogram, adjusted according to the procedure and patient's age," the employee explained.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">She added, "An injection dose of 1,300 mg is significantly higher than standard treatment protocols. Fatalities from excessive use of anaesthetics like this are not uncommon. Besides, drug abuse, apart from safety issues, can lead to addiction."</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">On November 1, the People's Court of Renshou County in Sichuan Province delivered a verdict, sentencing anesthesiologist Qu to two and a half years in prison for negligent homicide.</p>

<p>The court took into account mitigating factors, including, Qu's voluntary surrender to authorities, his full confession, financial compensation to the victim's family and the family's forgiveness.&nbsp;These factors contributed to a relatively lenient sentence.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7gd9kmo8_china-doctor_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was sentenced to two and a half years in prison for negligent homicide.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sudha-murty-praises-son-in-law-rishi-sunaks-good-indian-cultural-values-7041811]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sudha Murty Praises Son-In-Law Rishi Sunak's "Good Indian Cultural Values"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sudha-murty-praises-son-in-law-rishi-sunaks-good-indian-cultural-values-7041811]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 21:12:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Well-known author and Rajya Sabha MP Sudha Murty has spoken of her pride in son-in-law Rishi Sunak, a British citizen with "good Indian cultural values" imbibed from his parents' upbringing in the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well-known author and Rajya Sabha MP Sudha Murty has spoken of her pride in son-in-law Rishi Sunak, a British citizen with "good Indian cultural values" imbibed from his parents' upbringing in the UK.</p>

<p>Sudha Murty joined Rishi Sunak and her daughter Akshata Murty as the guest of honour at Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan's annual Diwali gala in London on Saturday evening.</p>

<p>The parents of the British Indian former prime minister, Usha and Yashvir Sunak, were also in the audience as Bhavan UK students showcased a variety of Indian classical music and dance forms.</p>

<p>"I always believe when you are abroad, your parents must do two things: one is good education, which gives you wings in return and you can fly anywhere and settle; the second is great culture, your origin which is Indian origin or roots which you can get at Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan along with your parents," said Sudha Murty, delivering her keynote address.</p>

<p>"I want to congratulate Ushaji, my sambandhi and a good friend of mine, who gave her son Rishi Sunak, former prime minister, a great route to identify with the culture, making him a proud British citizen as well as [having] good Indian cultural values," she said.</p>

<p>The philanthropist went on to appeal to the British Indian community to enable the work of Bhavan UK's cultural activities, "mentally, physically and financially".</p>

<p>"You must send your children here to understand Indian culture because when you grow old you go towards your roots... that gap is addressed by Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan, so you have to help them in every way to survive," said the staunch supporter of the cultural centre over the years.</p>

<p>Indian High Commissioner to the UK, Vikram Doraiswami, reflected upon Murty's writings which inspire readers to be true to themselves because our "origin story matters" as he went on to trace the pan-Indian message of Diwali.</p>

<p>"The Krishna story is relevant to Diwali in the south, just as the 'Ramayana' story and the return of Lord Ram to Ayodhya from Lanka is connected to the Diwali story of the north and the story of Kali Puja is connected with the story of Diwali in the east," he said.</p>

<p>"Diwali connects up with the Sikh tradition, with the Jain and Buddhist traditions too. It tells us that light also means there is no such thing as a single certainty because in the light you recognise the diversity of the human condition, the diversity of everything we live with. So, in a world in which we spend our time fighting about certainties, it is a really good idea to look at Diwali as an opportunity to consider how so many things look differently in the light." Subhanu Saxena, chairman of The Bhavan UK, and Executive Director Dr M.N. Nandakumara opened the event with Vedic chants as they highlighted the cultural centre's many achievements over the years as a centre of excellence in Indian arts, music, dance, Yoga and languages, offering over 120 classes across 23 different subject areas.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak and Akshata Murty presented mementoes to the team behind the centre's many activities since the 1970s.</p>

<p>Its students and teachers showcased their Kuchipudi, Kathak and Bharatanatyam skills at the annual Diwali celebration as they appealed for donations from the British Indian community to enhance their summer school and scholarship offerings.</p>

<p>"The Bhavan UK is a great organisation promoting Indian culture and deserves our full support," said NRI industrialist Lord Swraj Paul, one of the many supporters of the centre.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k076u0vg_rishi-sunak_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sudha Murty congratulated Rishi's mother saying she gave him a great route to identify with the culture.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senators-demand-investigation-into-elon-musks-alleged-russian-involvement-7041296]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Senators Demand Investigation Into Elon Musk's Alleged Russian Involvement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senators-demand-investigation-into-elon-musks-alleged-russian-involvement-7041296]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 19:42:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The lawmakers want the Pentagon and Justice Department to probe whether Musk's relationships with a US adversary compromise national security, especially given his major government contracts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Top Senate Democrats - Rhode Island Senator Jack Reed and New Hampshire Senator Jeanne Shaheen are calling for an investigation into Elon Musk's alleged ties with Russian President Vladimir Putin and his top officials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They sent a letter to Attorney General Merrick Garland and Defence Department Inspector General Robert Storch raising "serious questions regarding Mr Musk's reliability as a government contractor and a [security] clearance holder".</p>

<p>The lawmakers want the Pentagon and Justice Department to probe whether Musk's relationships with a US adversary compromise national security, especially given his major government contracts.</p>

<p>Musk's reported "multiple, high-level conversations" with Putin since 2022 have raised eyebrows, despite the Kremlin's denial, according to The Wall Street Journal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The billionaire's response to the accusations was fiery, vowing to "nuke" those behind the claims on his X platform, "going to find out who's making these accusations and nuke them".</p>

<p>Reed and Shaheen question Musk's reliability as a government contractor and security clearance holder, citing his alleged communications with Putin's deputy chief of staff, Sergei Kiriyenko.</p>

<p>The senators highlight Russia's space ambitions as a direct threat to US national security. They're concerned that Musk, with his top-secret level clearance, doesn't report his foreign government contacts, unlike others with similar clearances. SpaceX's deep involvement in US defense and intelligence infrastructure adds to the concerns.</p>

<p>Musk's ties to the US government extend beyond contracts; he backed Trump's 2024 election bid and participated in diplomatic efforts, including calls with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky, Turkish President Tayyip Erdogan and meeting Argentinian President Javier Milei in Trump's Florida home.</p>

<p>However, his recent visit to the Iranian UN ambassador's residence in New York has sparked controversy, with Iran's foreign minister denying the meeting took place.</p>

<p>The investigation request underscores growing scrutiny of Musk's foreign connections and their implications for US national security.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eta35gmg_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk's reported "multiple, high-level conversations" with Putin since 2022 have raised eyebrows]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-goes-to-doctor-for-sore-throat-only-to-find-shes-pregnant-with-quadruplets-7040921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Visits Doctor For Sore Throat, Finds She's Pregnant With Quadruplets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-goes-to-doctor-for-sore-throat-only-to-find-shes-pregnant-with-quadruplets-7040921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 18:40:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The odds of conceiving spontaneous quadruplets are less than one in 500,000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Katelyn Yates, a 20-year-old nursing assistant from Illinois, visited a hospital on April 1, expecting to get treatment for her sore throat. Instead, she received life-changing news that she was pregnant with quadruplets. Ms Yates shared her incredible story with <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.today.com/parents/family/mom-goes-hospital-finds-pregnant-quadruplets-rcna179200">Today</a></em>, recounting how her hospital visit started with throat pain that led doctors to recommend an X-ray.&nbsp;As a precautionary measure, doctors also asked Yates to take a pregnancy test before the X-ray, since radiation can be harmful to a fetus. Surprisingly, her pregnancy test came back positive, and her human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) levels were "off the charts," indicating multiple fetuses.</p>

<p>Notably, hCG is a hormone produced by the placenta during pregnancy, detectable by blood tests around 11 days after conception and urine tests about 12-14 days after conception. Typically, hCG levels double every 72 hours, peaking between 8-11 weeks of pregnancy before levelling off.</p>

<p>Ms Yates thought it was an April Fool's Day joke at first, but reality soon set in. His fiance, Julian Bueker, was overjoyed when he heard the news, which helped calm her nerves.&nbsp;As Yates' pregnancy advanced, complications arose, leading to a diagnosis of preeclampsia, a condition characterised by high blood pressure after 20 weeks. She endured debilitating symptoms, including difficulty breathing, liver complications and kidney issues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At 28 weeks and 4 days, Yates underwent an emergency C-section at HSHS St. John's Hospital in Springfield, Illinois, delivering quadruplets on October 17.&nbsp;The smallest baby was Elizabeth, who weighed 1 pound 2 ounces; while Max, the largest of the bunch, weighed 2 pounds, 6 ounces.</p>

<p>However, all four babies are doing remarkably well, gaining weight and growing. "They're doing phenomenal. They are gaining weight and growing. Elizabeth is about six grams away from reaching two pounds," she told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.today.com/parents/family/mom-goes-hospital-finds-pregnant-quadruplets-rcna179200">Today.&nbsp;</a></em></p>

<p>The odds of conceiving spontaneous quadruplets are less than one in 500,000, according to the<a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6571448/#B1" target="_blank">&nbsp;Journal of Family and Reproductive Health</a>.&nbsp;As per the Mayo Clinic, various factors contribute to premature birth. A woman's previous experiences with pregnancy, such as having had a premature birth or abortion, can increase the risk. Additionally, underlying health issues like uterine abnormalities, high blood pressure, and diabetes can also play a role.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/oa4eclp8_pregnancy_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[HCG is a hormone produced by the placenta during pregnancy, detectable by blood tests]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-spokesman-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-beirut-report-7040828]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Spokesman Killed In Israeli Strike On Beirut: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-spokesman-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-beirut-report-7040828]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 18:24:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Lebanese security source said Hezbollah spokesman Mohammed Afif was killed in an Israeli strike Sunday in central Beirut that hit the Lebanese branch of the Syrian Baath party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Lebanese security source said Hezbollah spokesman Mohammed Afif was killed in an Israeli strike Sunday in central Beirut that hit the Lebanese branch of the Syrian Baath party.</p>

<p>"The strike on Ras al-Nabaa killed Hezbollah media relations official Mohammed Afif," the security source said, requesting anonymity as they were not authorised to brief the media.</p>

<p>Ali Hijazi, secretary-general of the Lebanese branch of the Baath party, "confirmed the death of Hezbollah media official" Afif, the official National News Agency reported.</p>

<p>The Israeli army declined to comment, but Afif is the latest in a long line of Hezbollah officials killed since Israel on September 23 began heavily bombarding Hezbollah strongholds after almost a year of cross-border exchanges with the Iran-backed group over the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said the strike killed one person and wounded three others, adding that the toll was provisional and that work was ongoing to remove rubble from the site of the strike.</p>

<p>Afif was part of the inner circle of longtime Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, who was killed in an Israeli strike in September.</p>

<p>For years, Afif had been responsible for Hezbollah's media relations, providing information to local and foreign journalists, often under the cover of anonymity.</p>

<p>The NNA said the strike by "enemy aircraft" caused "great destruction", reporting an unspecified number of people "trapped under the rubble" in Ras al-Nabaa, an area near the French embassy and a university.</p>

<p>It said "one of the residents of a neighbouring building had received a warning call urging evacuation but it was not taken seriously".</p>

<p>Afif joined Hezbollah at a young age and first came to prominence as information director for Hezbollah's television channel Al-Manar when the group and Israel went to war in 2006.</p>

<p>After Nasrallah's assassination, Afif had held several press conferences in Beirut's southern suburbs, including one last month in which he announced Hezbollah had launched a drone targeting the residence of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>That press conference was cut short when the Israeli army warned it would strike a building nearby.</p>

<p>"Bombardments have not scared us, so how would threats?" Afif said defiantly as journalists hurriedly collected their microphones from the table.</p>

<p>Hezbollah officials killed in previous Israeli strikes include not only Nasrallah but also Hashem Safieddine, tipped as the former chief's successor.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5fduuho_beirut-afp_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike targeted Lebanese branch of the Syrian Baath party, said Lebanese security source]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-executes-over-100-foreigners-in-2024-report-7040603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Executes Over 100 Foreigners In 2024: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-executes-over-100-foreigners-in-2024-report-7040603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:45:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia has executed more than 100 foreigners this year, according to an AFP tally indicating a sharp increase which one rights group said was unprecedented.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has executed more than 100 foreigners this year, according to an AFP tally indicating a sharp increase which one rights group said was unprecedented.</p>

<p>The latest execution, on Saturday in the southwestern region of Najran, was of a Yemeni national convicted of smuggling drugs into the Gulf kingdom, the official Saudi Press Agency reported.</p>

<p>That brought to 101 the number of foreigners executed so far in 2024, according to the tally which is compiled from state media reports.</p>

<p>This is almost triple the figures for 2023 and 2022, when Saudi authorities had put to death 34 foreigners each year, according to AFP tallies.</p>

<p>The Berlin-based European-Saudi Organisation for Human Rights (ESOHR) said this year's executions had already broken a record.</p>

<p>"This is the largest number of executions of foreigners in one year. Saudi Arabia has never executed 100 foreigners in a year," said Taha al-Hajji, the group's legal director.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia has faced persistent criticism over its use of the death penalty, which human rights groups have condemned as excessive and out of step with efforts to soften its forbidding image and welcome international tourists and investors.</p>

<p>The oil-rich kingdom executed the third highest number of prisoners in the world after China and Iran in 2023, according to Amnesty International.</p>

<p>In September, AFP reported that Saudi Arabia had carried out its highest number of executions in more than three decades, surpassing its previous highs of 196 in 2022 and 192 in 1995.</p>

<p>Executions have continued at a rapid clip since then and totalled 274 for the year as of Sunday, according to AFP's tally.</p>

<p><strong>'Execution crisis'</strong></p>

<p>Foreigners executed this year have included 21 from Pakistan, 20 from Yemen, 14 from Syria, 10 from Nigeria, nine from Egypt, eight from Jordan and seven from Ethiopia.</p>

<p>There were also three each from Sudan, India and Afghanistan, and one each from Sri Lanka, Eritrea and the Philippines.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia in 2022 ended a three-year moratorium on the execution of drug offenders, and executions for drug-related crimes have boosted this year's numbers.</p>

<p>There have been 92 such executions so far this year, 69 of them of foreigners, according to the AFP tally.</p>

<p>Diplomats and activists say that foreign defendants usually face a higher barrier to fair trials, including the right to access court documents.</p>

<p>Foreigners "are the most vulnerable group", said Hajji of the ESOHR.</p>

<p>Not only are they often "victims of major drug dealers" but also "subjected to a series of violations from the moment of their arrest until their execution," he said.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia is notorious for beheading those convicted of capital crimes, although official statements tend not to mention the method of execution.</p>

<p>The high number of executions undercuts statements by Saudi Arabia's de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, who told The Atlantic in 2022 that the kingdom had eliminated the death penalty with the exception of murder cases or when an individual posed a threat to many lives.</p>

<p>Jeed Basyouni, who heads Middle East anti-death penalty advocacy for the NGO Reprieve, said persistent drug arrests were "perpetuating the cycle of violence".</p>

<p>The overall number of executions was on track to exceed 300 for the year, she noted.</p>

<p>"This is an unprecedented execution crisis in Saudi Arabia," said Basyouni.</p>

<p>"Families of foreign nationals on death row are understandably terrified that their loved one will be next."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ag44m6e_saudi-generic-unsplash_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is almost triple the figures for 2023 and 2022 (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-receives-nigerias-gcon-award-2nd-foreign-dignitary-after-queen-elizabeth-7040499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi 2nd Foreign Guest After Queen Elizabeth To Get Nigeria's GCON Award]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-receives-nigerias-gcon-award-2nd-foreign-dignitary-after-queen-elizabeth-7040499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:25:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This prestigious award is Nigeria's second-highest national honour, and it marks a milestone in the bilateral relations between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant move to strengthen diplomatic ties between Nigeria and India, President Bola Tinubu has conferred the Grand Commander of the Order of the Niger (GCON) upon Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>

<p>This prestigious award is Nigeria's second-highest national honour, and it marks a milestone in the bilateral relations between the two nations.</p>

<p>The award was announced during a bilateral meeting held at the Aso Rock Presidential Villa in Abuja, where Mr. Modi was warmly received by President Tinubu. The Indian leader arrived in Abuja on Saturday evening and was welcomed with the Indian Anthem, followed by a Guard of Honour and a 21-gun salute.</p>

<p>President Tinubu emphasised that the honour is "to signify our appreciation of India as Nigeria's partner."&nbsp;</p>

<p>This gesture underscores the strong strategic partnership between the two countries, which was established in 2007 during Dr. Manmohan Singh's state visit. Mr. Modi's visit is the first by an Indian prime minister since Dr. Manmohan Singh's state visit in 2007.</p>

<p>President Tinubu and Prime Minister Modi will engage in bilateral discussions to further enhance collaboration in critical sectors. The two leaders will exchange signed MOUs to strengthen cooperation in key areas. The visit will feature delegation-level talks, marking a significant step forward in Nigeria-India relations.</p>

<p>This honour is the 17th international award conferred upon Prime Minister Modi, solidifying his reputation as a key player in global diplomacy. The Grand Commander of the Order of the Niger (GCON) has previously been awarded to Queen Elizabeth II in 1969, making Mr. Modi the second foreign dignitary to receive this prestigious honour.</p>

<p>As Nigeria and India continue to foster their strategic partnership, this visit is expected to yield significant outcomes in areas such as economic development, energy, and defence. With over 200 Indian companies investing more than USD 27 billion in critical sectors in Nigeria, the bilateral relationship is poised for further growth and cooperation.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d36aoeto_modi-in-nigeria-pti_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr. Modi is the second foreign dignitary to receive this prestigious honour.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-asian-woman-24-found-murdered-in-car-boot-in-east-london-7040439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Asian Woman, 24, Found Murdered In Car Boot In London]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-asian-woman-24-found-murdered-in-car-boot-in-east-london-7040439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:12:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 24-year-old woman believed to be of South Asian origin has been found murdered in a car boot in east London after a missing person inquiry was launched for her in the East Midlands region of England.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 24-year-old woman believed to be of South Asian origin has been found murdered in a car boot in east London after a missing person inquiry was launched for her in the East Midlands region of England.</p>

<p>Northamptonshire Police named the victim as Harshita Brella on Saturday night as the force launched a murder inquiry and appealed for information in the case.</p>

<p>Police said it had received a call on Wednesday regarding concerns for Harshita's welfare and officers were deployed to her home address at Skegness Walk in Corby, Northamptonshire.</p>

<p>After getting no answer, the police launched a missing person investigation and fast-track enquiries were made which led to the discovery of the victim's body inside the boot of a vehicle on Brisbane Road in the Ilford area of east London in the early hours of Thursday.</p>

<p>A post-mortem was conducted at Leicester Royal Infirmary on Friday which established the murder victim as Harshita Brella, whose name indicates a South Asian heritage, but there is no further confirmation of her family background at this stage of the inquiry.</p>

<p>"First of all, I want to express my heartfelt condolences to everyone who loved Harshita Brella," said Detective Chief Inspector Johnny Campbell, Senior Investigating Officer from the East Midlands Special Operations Major Crime Unit (EMSOU).</p>

<p>"She was a young woman in her early 20s with her whole life ahead of her and it is absolutely tragic that her life has been cut short in this way. Detectives from EMSOU and Northamptonshire Police are working around the clock to establish the circumstances behind her death, including the exact location and timeframe in which it took place," he said.</p>

<p>Investigators believe Harshita was killed in a "targeted incident" as they appealed to anyone who may have information about the incident to come forward.</p>

<p>"Although we believe Harshita was attacked by someone known to her, we are keeping an open mind, and would appeal to anyone who knew her to contact us with any relevant information they may have," Campbell said.</p>

<p>If you saw anything suspicious in the past week or have any information, no matter how small, please contact us. We would always rather receive well-meaning information that turns out to be nothing as opposed to not receiving it all," he said.</p>

<p>The police said officers were satisfied there is no wider risk to the public as a result of this incident, however, extra patrols will be taking place in Corby in the coming days for reassurance purposes.</p>

<p>As is mandatory, Northamptonshire Police has also made a referral to the Independent Office for Police Conduct (IOPC) due to previous contact between the police force and the victim.</p>

<p>"Shortly after midnight on the morning of Thursday, November 14, the Met was contacted by officers from Northamptonshire Police raising concerns for the welfare of a woman who was believed to be in a car in the east London area," a Metropolitan Police spokesperson said.</p>

<p>"The car was located parked in Brisbane Road, Ilford, and the body of a 24-year-old woman was found inside the vehicle," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The police investigators are now working to establish the connection between Harshita going missing from her home in Corby, around 145km north of London, and being found dead in a car in the UK capital days later.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/ima4e49o_uk-police_625x300_14_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The body was found inside the boot of a vehicle on Brisbane Road of east London.(Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/red-skull-masks-swastikas-racial-slurs-neo-nazi-group-marches-in-ohio-7040054]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Red Skull Masks, Swastikas, Racial Slurs: Neo-Nazi Group Marches In Ohio]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/red-skull-masks-swastikas-racial-slurs-neo-nazi-group-marches-in-ohio-7040054]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 16:00:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of masked people dressed in black and carrying black flags with red swastikas marched through the Short North neighbourhood of Columbus in Ohio on Saturday afternoon, drawing swift condemnation from state and city officials.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of masked people dressed in black and carrying black flags with red swastikas marched through the Short North neighbourhood of Columbus in Ohio on Saturday afternoon, drawing swift condemnation from state and city officials. As they paraded, they shouted racial slurs, and their masks featured a red skull design.</p>

<p>Ohio Governor Mike DeWine condemned the demonstration and decried the display of hate on social media. "We will not tolerate hate in Ohio," Mr DeWine said. "Neo-Nazis -- their faces hidden behind red masks -- roamed streets in Columbus today, carrying Nazi flags and spewing vile and racist speech against people of colour and Jews. There were reports that they were also espousing white power sentiments." He added, "There is no place in this State for hate, bigotry, antisemitism, or violence, and we must denounce it wherever we see it."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/pqA4h5L9K7">pic.twitter.com/pqA4h5L9K7</a></p>
— Governor Mike DeWine (@GovMikeDeWine) <a href="https://twitter.com/GovMikeDeWine/status/1857957427783561450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Videos and pictures began circulating on social media showing about a dozen masked individuals walking through the streets.</p>

<p>A user wrote, "Neo-Nazis marched through the streets of Columbus, Ohio today, clamoring for "white power." Masked men dressed in black waved black flags with red swastikas, ranting at all people of colour and shouting antisemitic slurs. You can bet these were emboldened Trump voters."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Neo-Nazis marched through the streets of Columbus, Ohio today, clamoring for “white power.”<br />
<br />
Masked men dressed in black waved black flags with red swastikas, ranting at all people of color and shouting antisemitic slurs.<br />
<br />
You can bet these were emboldened Trump voters. <a href="https://t.co/oENUckX7zT">pic.twitter.com/oENUckX7zT</a></p>
— Stephanie Kennedy (@WordswithSteph) <a href="https://twitter.com/WordswithSteph/status/1857955520759398808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">⚠️ EXPLICIT: Viewers shared video with us of a group of neo-nazis marching through downtown Columbus, yelling racial slurs. Tonight residents and community leaders are denouncing the hate. Video credit to Dwight Holland. <a href="https://twitter.com/10TV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@10TV</a> <a href="https://t.co/g13LH8CWj4">pic.twitter.com/g13LH8CWj4</a></p>
— Carla Rogner (@CarlaRogner) <a href="https://twitter.com/CarlaRogner/status/1857962808027083259?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone wrote on X, “Feds had a Neo-Nazi parade in Columbus, OH today pretending to be MAGA .”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Feds had a Neo-Nazi parade in Columbus, OH today pretending to be MAGA<br />
<br />
Link below in comments.???? <a href="https://t.co/ntx7nURqFl">pic.twitter.com/ntx7nURqFl</a></p>
— Ashtronaut Girl (@AshtronautGirl) <a href="https://twitter.com/AshtronautGirl/status/1857921756813734371?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The City of Columbus also addressed the incident, emphasising the community's values of tolerance and safety. "We will not allow any of our neighbours to be intimidated, threatened, or harmed because of who they are, how they worship, or whom they love," the city said in a statement reported by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/masked-group-marches-ohio-neighborhood-swastikas-flags/story?id=115937210">ABC News</a>. It also called the march a "cowardly display" and assured residents that authorities are working to ensure the city's security.</p>

<p>City Attorney Zach Klein addressed the group directly, urging them to leave the city permanently. "Take your flags and the masks you hide behind and go home and never come back," Mr Klein said in a statement on X. "Your hate isn't welcome in our city."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">To those involved in the neo-Nazi march in the Short North today, take your flags and the masks you hide behind and go home and never come back.<br />
<br />
Your hate isn't welcome in our city. <a href="https://t.co/m9JpOrwxZQ">pic.twitter.com/m9JpOrwxZQ</a></p>
— Columbus City Attorney Zach Klein (@CityAttyKlein) <a href="https://twitter.com/CityAttyKlein/status/1857878822437191920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This demonstration comes just a week after a similar display outside a production of <em>The Diary of Anne Frank</em> in Howell, Michigan, where masked protesters waved Nazi flags. In that instance, no arrests were made, though the individuals were asked to leave.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a63eumtg_neo-nazi-rally-us_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Videos and pictures of the incident are circulating on social media]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-xi-unite-on-nuclear-safety-humans-over-ai-7039906]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden And Xi Unite On Nuclear Safety: Humans Over AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-xi-unite-on-nuclear-safety-humans-over-ai-7039906]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 15:36:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping made a landmark agreement on Saturday, emphasising the importance of human decision-making over artificial intelligence when it comes to nuclear weapons.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping made a landmark agreement on Saturday, emphasising the importance of human decision-making over artificial intelligence when it comes to nuclear weapons.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The two leaders affirmed the need to maintain human control over the decision to use nuclear weapons," said a statement from the White House. "The two leaders also stressed the need to consider carefully the potential risks and develop AI technology in the military field in a prudent and responsible manner."</p>

<p>This breakthrough marks a significant step forward in discussions between the two nations on nuclear arms and artificial intelligence, areas where progress has been challenging.</p>

<p>The US has been pushing China to engage in nuclear arms talks for months, but negotiations stalled after briefly resuming in November, with the US expressing frustration regarding China's responsiveness.</p>

<p>The US Defense Department estimates that China currently possesses around 500 operational nuclear warheads, with projections suggesting this number will exceed 1,000 by 2030.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This rapid buildup has raised concerns, particularly given China's modernised nuclear program, which includes advanced ballistic missile submarines, hypersonic glide vehicles, and regular nuclear-armed sea patrols.</p>

<p>China's nuclear arsenal is dwarfed by those of Russia (1,710 operational warheads) and the US (1,770 operational warheads), but its advancements have sparked worries about a potential arms race. Despite this, China maintains a policy of no first use and advocates for minimal nuclear deterrence.</p>

<p>The Biden administration updated its classified nuclear guidance earlier this year, citing concerns about nuclear arsenals in China, North Korea, and Russia. While this agreement is a positive step, it remains unclear whether it will lead to further talks or concrete actions.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dddn3te_biden-jinping-reuters_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This marks a significant step forward in discussions between the two nations on nuclear arms and AI]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-tells-biden-about-chinas-4-red-lines-that-us-must-not-cross-7039771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Tells Biden About China's 4 "Red Lines" That US Must Not Cross]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-tells-biden-about-chinas-4-red-lines-that-us-must-not-cross-7039771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 15:10:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping warned the United States on Saturday not to cross a "red line" in support for Taiwan, but told his counterpart Joe Biden that Beijing was willing to work with the incoming administration of Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping warned the United States on Saturday not to cross a "red line" in support for Taiwan, but told his counterpart Joe Biden that Beijing was willing to work with the incoming administration of Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Biden and Xi met on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in Peru, two months before Trump takes office and amid concerns of new trade wars and diplomatic upheaval.</p>

<p>China claims Taiwan as its own territory and has refused to rule out using force to seize it, while the United States is the self-ruled island's main security backer even though it does not recognise Taipei diplomatically.</p>

<p>Xi told Biden that the "Taiwan issue, democracy and human rights, pathways and systems, and development interests are China's four red lines that must not be challenged", according to Chinese state broadcaster CCTV.</p>

<p>"These are the most important guardrails and safety net for China-US relations," CCTV reported Xi as saying.</p>

<p>"The separatist actions of 'Taiwan independence' are incompatible with peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait," he added.</p>

<p>Taiwan's foreign ministry said Sunday that "China's ongoing military provocations near Taiwan are the root cause of destroying regional peace and stability and the major threat to global economic prosperity".</p>

<p>Xi also told Biden that Washington "should not intervene in bilateral disputes... and not condone or support provocative impulses" in the South China Sea, according to CCTV.</p>

<p>Beijing has this year pressed its sweeping claims in the contested waterway with greater assertiveness, despite increased frictions with regional neighbours and a longstanding international ruling that its claims have no legal basis.</p>

<p>Xi also said China's position on the war in Ukraine was "open and aboveboard", and that Beijing would not allow tensions on the Korean peninsula to "descend into conflict or chaos", CCTV reported.</p>

<p>He announced during a separate meeting that China would host the next APEC summit in 2026.</p>

<p>State news agency Xinhua said those talks would aim to "unite Asia-Pacific countries to champion open economic and trade cooperation while rejecting protectionist and confrontational trade tactics".</p>

<h2><strong>'Smooth transition'</strong></h2>

<p>But Xi said China would "strive for a smooth transition" in relations with the United States and is ready to work with the incoming Trump government.</p>

<p>"China is ready to work with the new US administration to maintain communication, expand cooperation and manage differences, so as to strive for a smooth transition of the China-US relationship," Xi told Biden through a translator.</p>

<p>In his first White House term, Trump engaged in a bruising trade war with China, imposing tariffs on billions of dollars in Chinese products and drawing retaliation from Beijing.</p>

<p>He embraced a similar stance on the campaign trail this year.</p>

<p>Both sides should "keep exploring the right way for the two major countries to get along well with each other," Xi said.</p>

<p>Xi warned Saturday that bilateral ties could "encounter twists and turns or even regress" if one side regarded the other as an opponent or enemy, according to the official Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>"Major country competition should not be the underlying logic of the times," Xi added, urging against a "small yard, high fences" approach. He added that "a stable China-US relationship is critical" to both parties and the world, noting that Beijing continues to aim for healthy ties.</p>

<p>But he stressed that Beijing's position of "firmly safeguarding its sovereignty, security and development interests has not changed," according to Xinhua.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ovd5tjcg_biden-xi-afp_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden and Xi met on the sidelines of the APEC summit in Peru.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trump-elon-musk-in-front-row-seats-at-ufc-event-7039660]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Donald Trump, Elon Musk In Front-Row Seats At UFC Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trump-elon-musk-in-front-row-seats-at-ufc-event-7039660]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 14:57:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump was greeted by chanting fans as he attended the Ultimate Fighting Championship heavyweight bout at New York's Madison Square Garden on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump was greeted by chanting fans as he attended the Ultimate Fighting Championship heavyweight bout at New York's Madison Square Garden on Saturday. Trump entered the arena shortly before the start of the main card accompanied by UFC chief executive Dana White, who was a prominent backer during his election campaign.</p>

<p>Several political allies of Trump were also in attendance for the mixed-martial arts fights, including entrepreneurs Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy, who have been asked by Trump to lead efforts to cut government inefficiency.</p>

<p>Robert F Kennedy Jr., who Trump has nominated to be health secretary, was also at the fight and a photo posted on X showed the pair flying to the event together on Trump's private plane.</p>

<p>The night had the feel of a post-election night out for the Republicans.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">PRESIDENT DONALD TRUMP AND ELON MUSK ARE WALKING OUT WITH DANA WHITE!!! ??<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UFC309?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UFC309</a> | LIVE on TNT Sports Box Office ➡️ <a href="https://t.co/uXQAMHNTBd">https://t.co/uXQAMHNTBd</a> <a href="https://t.co/VpggsWHtwZ">pic.twitter.com/VpggsWHtwZ</a></p>
— UFC on TNT Sports (@ufcontnt) <a href="https://twitter.com/ufcontnt/status/1857981854684414326?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Tulsi Gabbard, the former Democratic congresswoman tapped for the role of director of national intelligence, was also in the crowd along with Trump's sons Eric and Don Jr and musician Kid Rock -- a regular at Trump rallies.</p>

<p>After waving to the chanting crowd, Trump warmly greeted UFC broadcast analyst Joe Rogan, the popular podcast host who also endorsed Trump after he appeared as a guest on his show.</p>

<p>The venue's "jumbotron" giant screen above the cage where fighters did battle then showed a video featuring highlights of the election campaign with soundbites from Trump.</p>

<p>The film ended with the numbers 45 and 47 on the screen, representing the Republican's previous and upcoming presidency.</p>

<p>Fans chanted "USA, USA," a refrain frequently heard at Trump rallies, including one he held at Madison Square Garden last month.</p>

<p>Trump watched the fights alongside Musk from front-row seats next to the caged octagon.</p>

<p>After Jon Jones defended his heavyweight title with a third-round technical knockout against fellow American Stipe Miocic in the main event, the fighter celebrated with Trump's trademark 'YMCA' dance.</p>

<p>"I want to say a big thank you to President Donald Trump for being here tonight," said Jones, receiving a huge roar of approval from the crowd.</p>

<p>After leading the crowd in another round of "USA, USA" chant, Jones then passed his heavyweight championship belt to Trump and spent some time in conversation with the President-elect.</p>

<p>Trump frequently attends UFC events and attended three fights during his campaign for the White House.</p>

<p>His ties to the fight world run deep. He featured retired WrestleMania star Hulk Hogan at the Republican convention in August and hosted UFC bouts at his casinos in the early days, when the series struggled to gain traction and well before it became today's multi-billion success.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/56dt69vg_trump-elon-musk-ufc-night_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several political allies of Trump were also in attendance for the mixed-martial arts fights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-campaign-spent-12-million-on-private-jets-despite-climate-stance-7039651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ice Cream, Luxury Hotels, Jets: How Kamala Harris' Campaign Cost $12 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-campaign-spent-12-million-on-private-jets-despite-climate-stance-7039651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 14:55:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kamala Harris campaign also funnelled $5.6 million to various left-leaning advocacy groups, including Voto Latino, Make the Road Action Fund, and Al Sharpton's National Action Network.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris' presidential campaign spent $12 million on private jet travel, with $2.6 million shelled out in the final days of her campaign alone, Federal Election Commission (FEC) data revealed. The campaign,&nbsp;between October 1 and October 17,&nbsp;reportedly paid nearly $2.2 million to Private Jet Services Group, a South Florida-based company, and an extra $430,000 to Advanced Aviation Team, a Virginia-based charter flight broker.</p>

<p>Critics were quick to point out the disconnect between Harris' use of private jets – up to 14 times more polluting than commercial flights – and her past statements labelling global warming as an “existential threat.”</p>

<p>“Kamala Harris and a lot of pro-climate leaders have a lot of hypocrisy with the words that they state and the realities they must think are real,” Benji Backer, founder of the American Conservation Coalition told the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/16/us-news/harris-campaign-blew-2-6m-on-private-jets-in-final-weeks-of-campaign/" rel="nofollow,noindex">NY Post</a>. “We need sensible solutions on environment and climate issues, but we're not going to get them when there's so much hypocrisy coming from the elitists.”</p>

<p>Private Jet Services Group claims its flights are carbon-neutral due to a reforestation program, though it remains unclear if the campaign purchased carbon offsets for these flights.</p>

<p>Beyond the millions spent on private air travel, the campaign incurred significant costs on items like $12,097 for food delivery services such as Uber Eats and DoorDash, $12,081 on ice cream, and $62,772 on accommodations and catering at the luxury Hotel Du Pont in Delaware.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other expenditures included $9,600 on food and drinks at Pebble Bar in New York City and $6,000 to rent space at a board game cafe in Arizona.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The campaign also funnelled $5.6 million to various left-leaning advocacy groups, including Voto Latino, Make the Road Action Fund, and Al Sharpton's National Action Network.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite burning through a record-breaking $1.6 billion in combined campaign funds, Harris' campaign ended with $20 million in debt. Critics within the Democratic Party have pointed to the wasteful spending as a major reason for her loss, with some questioning the decision-making process.</p>

<p>“You are looking at these seven-figure luxury costs and thinking, ‘Couldn't that have been deployed to reach guys who listen to podcasts, to Hispanic men, or suburban voters?'” said Democratic strategist Jon Reinish.</p>

<p>While Harris' team spent heavily on ad buys through Media Buying &amp; Analytics LLC – receiving $281 million in campaign funds – Donald Trump gained ground across the US and won the election.</p>

<p>GOP consultant Erin Perrine summarised the fallout: “Instead of getting the message out, they wanted to have a party. That's not how it works.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eksh4fm_kamala-harris_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-targets-ukraine-power-grids-in-biggest-missile-attack-in-3-months-7039612]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Targets Ukraine Power Grids In Biggest Missile Attack In 3 Months]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-targets-ukraine-power-grids-in-biggest-missile-attack-in-3-months-7039612]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 14:50:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Blasts rang out across Ukraine's capital Kyiv and other cities early on Sunday, as Russia staged its biggest missile attack since August and targeted power facilities with the winter setting in, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blasts rang out across Ukraine's capital Kyiv and other cities early on Sunday, as Russia staged its biggest missile attack since August and targeted power facilities with the winter setting in, officials said.</p>

<p>Ukrainians have been bracing for a major attack on the hobbled power system for weeks, fearing crippling damage to the grid that would cause long blackouts and build psychological pressure at a critical moment in the war Russia launched in February 2022.</p>

<p>"Another massive attack on the power system is under way. The enemy is attacking electricity generation and transmission facilities throughout Ukraine," Ukrainian Energy Minister German Galushchenko wrote on Facebook.</p>

<p>Air defences could be heard engaging drones over the capital in the night, and a series of powerful blasts rang out across the city centre as the missile attack was underway in the morning.</p>

<p>The scale of the damage was not immediately clear. Officials cut power supply to numerous city districts, including in Kyiv, the surrounding region and Dnipropetrovsk region, in what they said was a precaution to prevent a surge in case of damage.</p>

<p>Authorities in the Volyn region in northwestern Ukraine said energy infrastructure had sustained damage but did not elaborate. Officials often withhold information on the state of the power system because of the war.</p>

<p>In Mykolaiv in the south, two people were killed in the overnight drone attack, the regional governor said. Blasts shook the southeastern city of Zaporizhzhia and the Black Sea port of Odesa, Reuters witnesses said. More blasts were reported in the regions of Kryvyi Rih in the south and Rivne in the west.</p>

<p>"Russia launched one of the largest air attacks: drones and missiles against peaceful cities, sleeping civilians, critical infrastructure," said Foreign Minister Andrii Sybiha.</p>

<p>He described the strike as Moscow's "true response" to leaders who had interacted with President Vladimir Putin, an apparent swipe at German Chancellor Olaf Scholz, who placed a phone call to the Russian leader on Friday for the first time since late 2022.</p>

<h2><strong>Poland Scrambles Air Force</strong></h2>

<p>NATO member Poland, which borders Ukraine to the west, said it had scrambled its air force within its airspace as a security precaution due to the Russian attack, which it said used cruise missiles, ballistic missiles and drones.</p>

<p>Poland "activated all available forces and resources at his disposal, the on-duty fighter pairs were scrambled, and the ground-based air defence and radar reconnaissance systems reached the highest state of readiness," the operational command of its armed forces posted on X.</p>

<p>Ukraine's air force urged residents to take cover, providing regular updates on the progress of Russian cruise, ballistic and hypersonic missiles it said were hurtling through Ukrainian air space.</p>

<p>In Kyiv, the roof of a residential building caught fire due to falling debris and at least two people were hurt, city officials said on the Telegram messaging app.</p>

<p>"Emergency services were dispatched to the scene," Kyiv's Mayor Vitali Klitschko said.</p>

<p>Russia last conducted a major missile strike on Kyiv on Aug. 26, when officials said it fired a salvo of more than 200 drones and missiles across the country in an attack that attack killed seven people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h8u6it0g_ukraine-afp_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-news-vpn-use-violates-islamic-law-rules-pakistans-top-religious-body-7039254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[VPN Use Violates Islamic Law, Rules Pakistan's Top Religious Body]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-news-vpn-use-violates-islamic-law-rules-pakistans-top-religious-body-7039254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 14:43:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In Pakistan, accessing blocked content via virtual private networks (VPNs) is prohibited under Shariah, or Islamic law, the country's top religious body has declared.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Pakistan, accessing blocked content via virtual private networks (VPNs) is prohibited under Shariah, or Islamic law, the country's top religious body has declared. The announcement by the Council of Islamic Ideology (CII) comes in line with the government's efforts to implement a nationwide firewall and require VPN registration through the Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA).</p>

<p>The government aims to enhance cybersecurity and fight terrorism, according to <a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/pakistani-religious-body-declares-using-vpn-is-against-islamic-law-/7865991.html " rel="nofollow,noindex">VOA News</a>. However, critics argue that these measures lead to increased online surveillance, restrict freedom of expression, and negatively impact e-commerce.</p>

<p>VPNs allow users to conceal their identity and location, offering privacy and security while enabling access to content that might be restricted within a country. In Pakistan, many use VPNs to bypass restrictions on social media platforms and access content that is otherwise blocked.</p>

<p>The religious council said that VPNs were being used to view prohibited content, including "immoral and porn websites or websites that spread anarchy through disinformation." It added that "using VPNs to access blocked or illegal content is against Islamic and social norms, therefore, their use is not acceptable under Islamic law. It falls under ‘abetting in sin,'" quoting the council's chairman, Raghib Naeemi.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Interior responded by sending a letter to the PTA requesting the blocking of "illegal" VPNs, citing concerns that terrorists were exploiting the technology for violent activities and financial transactions. "VPNs are increasingly being exploited by terrorists to facilitate violent activities and financial transactions in Pakistan," the letter read.</p>

<p>The ministry also expressed concern over the use of VPNs to access pornography, noting that Pakistan ranks high in terms of visits to adult sites via VPNs. "These trends warrant prohibition of unauthorized VPNs to address the critical threats," the letter added.</p>

<p>Alongside their use for business and entertainment, many Pakistanis rely on VPNs to access social media platforms like X, which has been largely inaccessible since the controversial February general elections. The government has defended its move to suspend the platform, citing national security and public order concerns.</p>

<p>Opponents of the restrictions argue that they are primarily aimed at stifling political criticism, especially amid growing backlash against the Pakistani military's influence in politics, following the ousting of former Prime Minister Imran Khan in 2022. The military has consistently referred to online criticism as "digital terrorism."</p>

<p>This week, the PTA introduced a system for registering VPNs, asking users to sign up on a new online platform. This follows widespread VPN disruptions, which sources say were part of a government trial to block VPNs using a new firewall. Although officials deny throttling the internet, experts believe the system, purchased from China, gives the government more power to monitor online activity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To register, users must provide personal details like their national identity number and internet service provider's ID, raising concerns about privacy and potential data breaches. The Interior Ministry has given users until the end of the month to comply.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/3l3thuk4_vpn-services-generic-vpn-generic-unsplash_625x300_19_May_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The religious council said VPNs were being used to view prohibited content (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-chris-wright-trumps-pick-for-energy-secretary-and-fossil-fuel-advocate-7039398]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chris Wright: Trump's Energy Secretary Pick Who Is A Climate Change Sceptic]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-chris-wright-trumps-pick-for-energy-secretary-and-fossil-fuel-advocate-7039398]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 14:09:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has selected Chris Wright, a campaign donor and fossil fuel advocate, as the next Secretary of Energy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chris-wright-climate-change-skeptic-to-be-trumps-energy-secretary-7037504 ">selected Chris Wright</a>, a campaign donor and fossil fuel advocate, as the next Secretary of Energy. Announced on Saturday, the nomination positions Mr Wright, a known climate change sceptic, at the helm of the Department of Energy as the administration sets its sights on “cutting red tape” to boost the nation's energy output.</p>

<p>Donald Trump praised Mr Wright's expertise, saying, “As Secretary of Energy, Chris will be a key leader, driving innovation, cutting red tape, and ushering in a new 'Golden Age of American Prosperity and Global Peace.”</p>

<p><strong>Here are some facts on Chris Wright:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li aria-level="1">Chris Wright is the <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-wright-b8370a17b/" rel="nofollow,noindex">founder, CEO and Chairman of Liberty Energy</a>, a major energy service provider, focusing on technology and the energy sector, based in Denver.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">He grew up in Colorado and has had a long career in the energy industry. He holds an undergraduate degree from MIT and completed graduate work in electrical engineering at UC Berkeley and MIT.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Mr Wright is a strong proponent of oil and gas development, including hydraulic fracturing (fracking), which he views as central to achieving US "energy dominance."</li>
	<li aria-level="1">He has publicly said that there is no "climate crisis" and has criticised policies aimed at transitioning away from fossil fuels. He argues that such policies harm economic opportunities and global prosperity. He has also argued that the global climate movement is "collapsing under its own weight," as per the Washington Post.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Chris Wright founded Pinnacle Technologies in 1992, which helped launch commercial shale gas production through fracking. He also served as chairman of Stroud Energy before founding Liberty Resources in 2010.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">He is closely tied to the Republican Party and has been a major donor to pro-Trump super PACs and the Republican National Committee. He also co-hosted a fundraising event for Donald Trump at a resort in Montana.</li>
</ul>

<p>Donald&nbsp;Trump&nbsp;has made a flurry of picks for his&nbsp;cabinet&nbsp;and other high-ranking administration positions following his election victory. The 78-year-old leader will take office in January next year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d2fis89_chris-wright-reuters_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chris Wright has publicly said that there is no "climate crisis".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/three-suspects-arrested-after-flares-near-israel-pms-home-police-7039269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Three Suspects Arrested After Flares Near Israel PM's Home: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/three-suspects-arrested-after-flares-near-israel-pms-home-police-7039269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 13:46:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three suspects were arrested, Israeli police said Sunday morning, after two flares landed near Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's residence in the central town of Caesarea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three suspects were arrested, Israeli police said Sunday morning, after two flares landed near Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's residence in the central town of Caesarea.</p>

<p>"Three suspects were arrested overnight for their involvement in the incident" that took place Saturday evening, the police said in a statement, adding that the suspects would be interrogated jointly with the Shin Bet internal security agency.</p>

<p>The statement added that a court ordered a gag on publishing any details of the investigation or the suspects' identities for 30 days.</p>

<p>Two flares had landed near Netanyahu's residence in Caesarea on Saturday evening in what Shin Bet described as a "serious incident", though the premier was not present there at the time.</p>

<p>The speaker of Israel's parliament, Amir Ohana, accused anti-government protesters of being behind the incident.</p>

<p>"The writing was on the walls, on the streets, in incendiary messages and in demonstrations," he said, referring to regular anti-government protests that erupted in early 2023.</p>

<p>In the nine months leading up to the October 7, 2023 Hamas attack, Israel saw mass protests over a divisive judicial overhaul introduced by Netanyahu's far-right government that opponents called a threat to Israeli democracy.</p>

<p>Though the reforms were suspended when the war broke out, protests against Netanyahu and his government have continued, alongside demonstrations calling for a deal to release hostages held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog condemned Saturday's incident and warned "against an increase in violence in the public sphere.</p>

<p>"I have now spoken with the head of the Shin Bet and expressed the urgent need to investigate and deal with those responsible for the incident as soon as possible," Herzog said in a post on X.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g46qadu_netanyahu-home-flare_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Three suspects were arrested after two flares landed near PM Benjamin Netanyahu's residence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-the-world-watched-tyson-paul-fight-a-return-of-battle-of-baghpat-7039066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Paul-Tyson Fight Streamed Online, 'Battle Of Baghpat' Stole The Show]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-the-world-watched-tyson-paul-fight-a-return-of-battle-of-baghpat-7039066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 13:14:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Battle of Baghpat is a bizarre and chaotic brawl, where two chaat vendors in Uttar Pradesh’s Baghpat clashed over who could attract more customers to their stalls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the world tuned in to Netflix for the highly anticipated Jake Paul vs Mike Tyson fight on Saturday, the internet's focus momentarily shifted to a different kind of “fight” – one that was just as entertaining, if not more, than any professional bout: the Battle of Baghpat.</p>

<p>The much-anticipated showdown between <a href="https://sports.ndtv.com/boxing/was-mike-tyson-vs-jake-paul-fight-fixed-leaked-script-on-social-media-suggests-7038546 ">YouTuber-turned-boxer Jake Paul and boxing legend Mike Tyson</a>, saw the former win by unanimous decision in a professional bout held in the US state of Texas. Some viewers speculated that the fight might have been scripted.</p>

<p>During the event, Netflix experienced a widespread outage, affecting thousands of viewers who struggled to access the livestream of the fight -- marketed as the biggest boxing match ever to be streamed live.</p>

<p>While Netflix viewers were grappling with technical issues, social media users quickly found an unexpected source of entertainment in the form of the <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/on-second-anniversary-of-baghpat-fight-twitter-posts-hilarious-memes-3805989 ">Battle of Baghpat</a>, a viral video from 2021. In this bizarre and chaotic brawl, two chaat vendors in Uttar Pradesh's Baghpat clashed over who could attract more customers to their stalls. What started as a minor dispute spiraled into a 20-minute showdown, leading to eight arrests in the district.</p>

<p>The video, which was possibly recorded by a bystander, soon became an internet sensation, flooding social media and meme pages. The bizarre, yet entertaining, nature of the fight had viewers hooked, and the video became one of those rare viral moments that remained relevant long after the actual event. Even three years later, the internet still can't get enough of it. Amid the excitement over the Paul-Tyson fight, Battle of Baghpat made its way back into the social media spotlight.</p>

<p>As the Jake Paul-Mike Tyson fight gained global attention, the internet began drawing comparisons between the two events.</p>

<p>An X user posted, “No script, nothing—just pure entertainment. My fav fight #PaulTyson #NetflixFight.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">No script nothing just pure entertainment my fav fight <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PaulTyson?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PaulTyson</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NetflixFight?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NetflixFight</a> <a href="https://t.co/nrVyov3KHM">https://t.co/nrVyov3KHM</a></p>
— Raja Babu (@GaurangBhardwa1) <a href="https://twitter.com/GaurangBhardwa1/status/1857662691235471500?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another user shared their thoughts, “Historic, epic, era defining. When legends collided. When kings were dethroned. When the streets knew. When it was personal. Ladies &amp; gentlemen, The Great Battle Of Baghpat.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Historic, epic, era defining.<br />
When legends collided.<br />
When kings were dethroned.<br />
When the streets knew.<br />
When it was personal.<br />
Ladies &amp; gentleman,<br />
The Great Battle Of Baghpat. <a href="https://t.co/9VU5PgP7K6">https://t.co/9VU5PgP7K6</a></p>
— Pankaj (@pankajcgupta) <a href="https://twitter.com/pankajcgupta/status/1857811501605613845?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Others expressed similar sentiments, with some even claiming that the Battle of Baghpat was the real, raw fight of the moment, unlike the highly produced Paul-Tyson clash. "Paul Tyson fight is nothing, this is pure entertainment and real fight," another user posted with the hashtags #TysonVsJake and #MikeTysonvsJakePaul.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Paul Tyson fight is nothing this is pure entertainment and real fight<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PaulTyson?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PaulTyson</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NetflixFight?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NetflixFight</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TysonVsJake?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TysonVsJake</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MikeTysonvsJakePaul?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MikeTysonvsJakePaul</a> <a href="https://t.co/EVsCw5VtPl">pic.twitter.com/EVsCw5VtPl</a></p>
— Abdul Mannan (@Mannan27101993) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mannan27101993/status/1857692213247094884?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“The Greatest War of Modern History. 'The Battle of Baghpat',” a tweet read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Greatest War of Modern History.<br />
<br />
“The Battle of Baghpat”<br />
<a href="https://t.co/S2Az6Odxr8">https://t.co/S2Az6Odxr8</a></p>
— Jai Saini (@JaiSaini3008) <a href="https://twitter.com/JaiSaini3008/status/1857675362190368979?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The fight between Jake Paul, 27, and Mike Tyson, 58, was set for eight rounds, each lasting two minutes, which is shorter than the usual three-minute rounds and 10 to 12 rounds in most professional fights.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m6l2mjc8_baghpat-fight_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dylan-thomas-heir-to-rs-2-500-crore-fortune-accused-of-stabbing-friend-37-times-to-death-7038819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Heir To Rs 2,500 Crore Fortune Accused Of Stabbing Friend 37 Times]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dylan-thomas-heir-to-rs-2-500-crore-fortune-accused-of-stabbing-friend-37-times-to-death-7038819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 13:09:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disturbing details have come to light in thetrial of UK's Dylan Thomas, accused of killing his childhood friend and roommate, William Bush, on Christmas Eve 2023.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disturbing details have come to light in the&nbsp;trial of UK's Dylan Thomas, accused of killing his childhood friend and roommate, William Bush, on Christmas Eve 2023. Thomas, 24, heir to Peter's Food Services, a Rs 2,500 crore&nbsp;food industry giant in the UK, allegedly stabbed Mr Bush 37 times before killing him. Prosecutors revealed Thomas searched online for the "anatomy of the neck" before the attack, as per the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/13/world-news/heir-to-292m-pie-fortune-made-chilling-online-search-before-alleged-frenzied-stabbing-of-roommate-court/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">NY Post</a>.</p>

<p>On the night of the murder, Thomas invited Mr Bush to his room under the pretence of meeting before the holidays. What followed was nothing short of horrifying.&nbsp;The victim was stabbed a total of 37 times, with 13 of those wounds concentrated on his neck. Mr Bush's desperate attempt to flee left a trail of blood through the house. The final blow came on the patio, where Thomas severed an artery in Mr Bush's neck, ending his life. Neighbours reported hearing "screams of horror" during the assault.</p>

<p>Police body cam footage later showed Thomas covered in blood, falsely claiming that he had disarmed an attacker. A significant part of the case also involved testimony from Mr Bush's girlfriend, Ella Jeffries, who revealed the deteriorating dynamics between the two friends.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Thomas allegedly threatened Mr Bush, “I thought and wondered about killing you. I just wanted to see what would happen if I do certain things,” the court was told, as per the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckgz944vz36o " rel="nofollow,noindex">BBC</a>.</p>

<p>Ms Jeffries also described how her boyfriend had started barricading his bedroom door at night out of fear.</p>

<p>Thomas was diagnosed with schizophrenia following his arrest. He had been previously detained for attempting to climb the fence at Buckingham Palace just weeks before the murder. However, psychiatrists have presented conflicting views on his mental state at the time of the crime. While Thomas pleaded guilty to manslaughter, he denies murder. "Everywhere on him, I kept going and stabbed him. I didn't stop,” Thomas said, as per the BBC, adding, “he stabbed me on my hands, my hands to get the knife.”</p>

<p>The prosecution has painted a disturbing picture of the crime's premeditated nature. Gregory Bull KC, prosecuting, said, "This was a planned attack. He deliberately armed himself with knives and attacked him from behind." Thomas, appearing via video link from Ashworth High Secure Hospital in Merseyside, remains under treatment for his schizophrenia as the court deliberates on the shocking details of the case.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1u7i3t3o_dylan-thomas-_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police body cam footage later showed Thomas covered in blood.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-visits-amazon-the-jungle-that-nearly-killed-teddy-roosevelt-7038812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Visits Amazon, The Jungle That Nearly Killed Teddy Roosevelt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-visits-amazon-the-jungle-that-nearly-killed-teddy-roosevelt-7038812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 12:25:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden on Sunday will be the first sitting US president to visit the Amazon -- the vast tropical rainforest that nearly killed a predecessor, Teddy Roosevelt, after he left office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden on Sunday will be the first sitting US president to visit the Amazon -- the vast tropical rainforest that nearly killed a predecessor, Teddy Roosevelt, after he left office. The trip is part of Biden's final swing through South America before he hands the keys of the White House to Donald Trump, who becomes the United States' 47th president in two months.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, will touch down in the biggest city in the Amazon, Manaus, on his way to Rio de Janeiro, where a two-day G20 summit is to be held.</p>

<p>The Amazon jungle was not a fortunate destination for the 26th US president, Roosevelt. He had a near-death experience in it when he went on a canoe expedition there in 1914, four years after his 1901-1909 stint in office.</p>

<p>Roosevelt, a Republican known for his adventurous spirit, had teamed up with a Brazilian explorer, Candido Rondon, to chart the Rio da Duvida (the River of Doubt), a tributary in the wild center-west of Brazil, in the Amazon.</p>

<p>The river, 760 kilometers (470 miles) long, proved a formidable foe. Several members of Roosevelt's expedition died and the ex-president, aged 55 at the time, caught malaria and a leg infection, which incapacitated him in the final arduous stretch.</p>

<p>"T. R. (Teddy Roosevelt) was out of his mind toward the end; Rondon gave him up for dead several times," his great-grandson Tweed Roosevelt said in remarks noted by The New York Times in 1992.</p>

<p>Roosevelt himself, when he was warned of the dangers by friends at the American Museum of Natural History before embarking on his trip, told them he had already lived a full life and was ready for the risk. "I have had my full share, and if it is necessary for me to leave my bones in South America, I am quite ready to do so," he said, according to the Smithsonian Magazine.</p>

<p>In the end, the Roosevelt-Rondon expedition was saved from disaster when they came across Brazilian rubber-tappers in the jungle, who helped them enough so they could make it to cargo boats, and from there back to the safety of the outside world.</p>

<p>Roosevelt never fully recovered his health from his ordeal, though he and Rondon received acclaim for mapping the River of Doubt. The former president died in 1919 at home of a blood clot in his lungs, aged 60. In his honor, the river he navigated was renamed the Roosevelt River.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vf9oh9t8_amazon-forest-unsplash_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Amazon jungle was not a fortunate destination for the 26th US president. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>