<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:16:32 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/body-of-last-missing-person-found-in-uk-tycoon-mike-lynchs-shipwreck-6401371]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Body Of Last Missing Person Found In UK Tycoon Mike Lynch's Shipwreck]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/body-of-last-missing-person-found-in-uk-tycoon-mike-lynchs-shipwreck-6401371]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:01:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Divers searching for the last person missing after a superyacht sank off Sicily found a body Friday, presumed to be the teenage daughter of UK tech tycoon Mike Lynch, who also perished.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Divers searching for the last person missing after a superyacht sank off Sicily found a body Friday, presumed to be the teenage daughter of UK tech tycoon Mike Lynch, who also perished.</p>

<p>The discovery, confirmed to AFP by the Italian coastguard, brings to seven the final death count in the sinking of the "Bayesian", which went down off the Italian island before dawn on Monday.</p>

<p>The bodies of Lynch, a celebrated tech entrepreneur and investor, and four other passengers were found on Wednesday and Thursday, with his 18-year-old daughter Hannah the only one still missing.</p>

<p>Emergency services had found the body of another man, believed to be the yacht's chef, a few hours after it sank in a sudden storm.</p>

<p>Lynch had invited friends and family onto the sailing boat to celebrate his recent acquittal in a massive US fraud case.</p>

<p>But as the 56-metre (185-feet) British-flagged yacht was anchored off Porticello, near Palermo, it was struck by a waterspout -- akin to a mini-tornado.</p>

<p>It sank within minutes.</p>

<p>Italian authorities launched what they called a "delicate" search operation involving specialist divers, boats from several emergency services and helicopters.</p>

<h3><strong>'Heartbroken'</strong></h3>

<p>Fifteen people had been rescued from the ship, including Lynch's wife, who is believed to have been waiting in a Sicily hotel for news of her husband and daughter.</p>

<p>The 18-year-old Hannah had just finished her end of school exams and had a place to study English literature at Oxford University, according to UK media reports.</p>

<p>Friends of the teenager told The Times newspaper that she was kind and clever, as well as a staunch feminist.</p>

<p>The bodies of Lynch's lawyer Christopher Morvillo and his wife Neda, and Jonathan Bloomer, the chair of Morgan Stanley International, and his wife Judy, were recovered on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Morvillo's firm Clifford Chance paid tribute to the lawyer and his wife, saying all were "heartbroken at the tragic passing... and still coming to terms with this terrible loss".</p>

<p>The Bloomer family described their "unimaginable grief", saying Jonathan and Judy had been together for five decades.</p>

<p>"Our only comfort is that they are still together now," the family said.</p>

<p>The Lynch family has yet to comment publicly.</p>

<p>Many questions remain about why the yacht sank, and so quickly, when other boats nearby were unaffected.</p>

<p>On Thursday the head of the company which built the boat said the tragedy could have been avoided.</p>

<p>"Everything that was done reveals a very long summation of errors," said Giovanni Costantino, head of the Italian Sea Group, which includes the Perini Navi company that built Bayesian in 2008.</p>

<h3><strong>Bad weather forecast</strong></h3>

<p>He told Italy's Corriere della Sera newspaper that bad weather was forecast and all the passengers should have been gathered at a pre-arranged assembly point, with all the doors and hatches closed.</p>

<p>"Instead it took on water with the guests still in the cabin. They ended up in a trap, those poor people ended up like mice in a trap," he said.</p>

<p>Lynch, 59, was acquitted on all charges in a San Francisco court in June after he was accused of an $11 billion fraud linked to the sale of his software firm Autonomy to Hewlett-Packard.</p>

<p>The Bayesian, owned by his family, boasted a 75-metre mast, the tallest aluminium sailing mast in the world, according to the Charter World website.</p>

<p>Raising it would likely cost some 15 million euros and take "six to eight weeks", according to the salvage engineer who led the operation to recover the Costa Concordia cruise ship, which sank off Italy in 2012.</p>

<p>To recover the yacht, the mast could be removed on the seabed but the boat would be lifted up whole using a giant crane and a team of 40 specialist divers, South African engineer Nick Sloane told the Repubblica daily.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7ul933j_mike-lynch-reuters_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mike Lynch had invited friends and family onto the sailing boat (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-george-bush-beyonce-at-democratic-convention-after-speculation-grips-social-media-6401087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No George Bush At Democratic Convention After Speculation Grips Social Media]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-george-bush-beyonce-at-democratic-convention-after-speculation-grips-social-media-6401087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 16:25:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Heading into the glitzy final night of the DNC in Chicago, speculation was rife online about who would be the much vaunted special guest, with figures from ex Republican President George W Bush to superstar musician Beyonce in the frame.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heading into the glitzy final night of the Democratic National Convention (DNC) in Chicago, speculation was rife online about who would be the much vaunted special guest, with figures from ex Republican President George W Bush to superstar musician Beyonce and Taylor Swift in the frame.</p>

<p>It proved to be way off the mark.</p>

<p>George W Bush was put forward as a contender for the surprise spot, with "Republicans against Trump" posting a picture of Bush embracing then first lady Michelle Obama to the account's 765,000 followers on X.</p>

<p>George Bush's spokesperson Freddy Ford told John Bachman, veteran TV news anchor with Newsmax, that Bush is "definitely not" in Chicago to speak at the DNC.</p>

<p>Former Republican presidential nominee Mitt Romney, currently a US senator who has criticized former president Donald Trump, also denied it would be him.</p>

<p>"Contrary to fake news posts, I am not the surprise guest at the DNC tonight. My guess is that it will be Beyonce or Taylor Swift," Mr Romney posted on X. "So disappointing, I know!"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Contrary to fake news posts, I am not the surprise guest at the DNC tonight. My guess is that it will be Beyoncé or Taylor Swift. So disappointing, I know!</p>
— Mitt Romney (@MittRomney) <a href="https://twitter.com/MittRomney/status/1826767490137161906?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 22, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>However, many anti-Trump Republicans spoke at this year's DNC throughout the week, taking a stance against the former president and endorsing Kamala Harris and her <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vice-president-tim-walz-pick-set-to-star-on-day-3-of-democratic-convention-6388689">running mate Tim Walz</a> instead.</p>

<p>This list includes former Trump White House press secretary Stephanie Grisham, former homeland security adviser Olivia Troye, former Republican Representative Adam Kinzinger, and even Trump's former lawyer, Michael Cohen.</p>

<p>But Bush is perhaps one of the most prominent Republicans to publicly announce he was not supporting Trump - sparking rumors he may make a surprise appearance on Thursday.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/indian-americans-cheer-kamala-harris-but-can-she-shift-their-votes-6384029">Kamala Harris</a> accepted her party's presidential nomination on the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-key-takeaways-from-the-democratic-national-convention-6399099">final day of the convention</a>, buoyed by a galaxy of stars, that set the stage for the grueling run-in to November 5.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old Californian has edged <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-donald-trump-race-to-us-election-photo-finish-6400682">ahead by razor-thin margins</a> in polling, reversing what had started to look like a likely Trump victory against Biden before he dramatically pulled out and endorsed Harris.</p>

<p>Democratic heavy hitters, from Michelle Obama and Bill Clinton to vice presidential nominee Tim Walz, have warned that the party could still lose to Trump's Republicans if complacency creeps in.</p>

<p>Walz, a former school football coach, used a sporting analogy, saying that Democrats were "down a field goal, but we're on offense and we've got the ball."</p>

<p>Party strategists spent the week in Chicago showcasing a parade of anti-Trump Republicans, including ex-cabinet officials, a small-town mayor and a former statewide office holder.</p>

<p>"If you vote for Kamala Harris in 2024, you're not a Democrat, you're a patriot," former Georgia lieutenant governor Geoff Duncan said.</p>

<p>Ms Harris called Trump an "unserious" person.</p>

<p>"I will be a president who unites us around our highest aspirations," Harris said in her keynote speech, earning uproarious applause.</p>

<p><em>(With inputs from AFP)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-12/george-bush-afp_650x400_61448981768.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[George Bush was not at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-democratic-convention-event-watch-bill-clinton-jabs-trump-over-age-says-i-am-still-younger-than-him-6400976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Clinton Shreds Trump Over Age, Says "I Am Still Younger Than Him"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-democratic-convention-event-watch-bill-clinton-jabs-trump-over-age-says-i-am-still-younger-than-him-6400976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 16:10:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic National Convention: Former US President Bill Clinton took the stage on the third day of the 2024 Democratic National Convention in Chicago, endorsing Kamala Harris as the party's candidate in the upcoming US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Bill Clinton took the stage on the third day of the 2024 Democratic National Convention in Chicago, endorsing Kamala Harris as the party's candidate in the upcoming US presidential election. During his speech, Clinton, the 42nd President of the US, took a swipe at Republican rival Donald Trump, referencing his own age in a lighthearted jab.</p>

<p>"Two days ago, I turned 78, the oldest man in my family for four generations. And the only personal vanity I want to assert is I'm still younger than Donald Trump," Clinton said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Clinton: Two days ago, I turned 78. The oldest man in my family who is still living. And the only personal vanity I want to assert is that I'm still younger than Donald Trump. <a href="https://t.co/mM6W19sJCO">pic.twitter.com/mM6W19sJCO</a></p>
— Acyn (@Acyn) <a href="https://twitter.com/Acyn/status/1826430840458375295?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Clinton turned 78 on August 19 while Donald Trump celebrated his 78th birthday in June. So, technically Bill Clinton is younger than Trump by roughly two months.</p>

<p>For months,<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-biden-bombshell-a-plot-twist-that-roils-trump-too-6156958"> Trump and his allies played on concerns</a> that the 81-year-old Joe Biden may no longer be fit for office. He was frequently a target of Republican mockery and scorn. Last month, Biden made the formal announcement of his exit from the US Presidential race after he faced intense scrutiny following a shaky performance in a debate against Trump.</p>

<h3><strong>Bill Clinton Backs Kamala Harris, Tim Walz</strong></h3>

<p>Clinton offered strong support for Democratic Presidential nominee <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395">Kamala Harris</a> and her running mate Tim Walz, saying that Harris is a capable leader to address the nation's challenges.</p>

<p>A Democratic heavy lifter, Clinton has warned that the party could still lose to Trump's Republicans if complacency creeps in.</p>

<p>"It's just a fact: Democrats know how to create jobs. And if we elect Kamala Harris and Tim Walz, we'll keep building a strong economy that works for everyone and run the score up much higher," he said at the event.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Kamala Harris' Donald Trump Warning As She Accepts Presidential Nomination</a></strong></p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris 'Vows A New Way Forward' For America</strong></h3>

<p>Kamala Harris <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">accepted the Democratic presidential nomination</a> in Chicago on Thursday, pledging a "new way forward". She warned that Donald Trump will take America backward if he wins November's blockbuster election.</p>

<p>"With this election, our nation has a precious, fleeting opportunity to move past the bitterness, cynicism, and divisive battles of the past -- a chance to chart a new way forward," Harris said to huge cheers from tens of thousands of pumped-up supporters.</p>

<p>"And I want you to know: I promise to be a president for all Americans."</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395">"Miss Her Every Day": Kamala Harris Invokes Mother In Her Biggest Speech</a></strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rnsc5se_bill-clinton_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Clinton turned 78 on August 19 while Donald Trump celebrated his 78th birthday in June]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-dead-nearly-three-million-stranded-in-bangladesh-due-to-floods-6400857]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Dead, Nearly 3 Million Stranded In Deadly Bangladesh Floods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-dead-nearly-three-million-stranded-in-bangladesh-due-to-floods-6400857]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 15:51:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Relentless monsoon rains and flooding have stranded nearly three million people in Bangladesh and killed two, submerging vast areas and damaging homes and infrastructure, officials from the country's disaster management ministry said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Relentless monsoon rains and flooding have stranded nearly three million people in Bangladesh and killed two, submerging vast areas and damaging homes and infrastructure, officials from the country's disaster management ministry said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Reuters TV showed Bangladesh residents evacuating with their belongings by boat and other makeshift transportation as knee-deep water entered their homes.</p>

<p>The Flood Forecasting and Warning Centre (FFWC) has warned that with the rains continuing, water levels could rise further over the next 24 hours, raising concern about additional flooding and displacement.</p>

<p>Road connectivity in several regions were severed, isolating communities and hampering relief efforts, disaster management and relief officials said.</p>

<p>The most affected districts in Bangladesh included Feni, Moulvibazar, Habiganj, Comilla and Chittagong, where five major rivers were flowing above danger levels, the FFWC said.</p>

<p>"I haven't seen so much water in the last 20 years. Everything in my house is wrecked because the water has risen to waist level," said Mohammad Masum, a resident of Feni district.</p>

<p>An analysis in 2015 by the World Bank Institute estimated that 3.5 million people in Bangladesh, one of the world's most climate-vulnerable countries, were at risk of annual river flooding. Scientists attribute the exacerbation of such catastrophic events to climate change.</p>

<p>Late on Wednesday, students in Dhaka held protest rallies, alleging that the floods were caused by the opening of dam sluice gates in<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/are-bangladesh-india-ties-in-troubled-waters-floods-devastate-bangladesh-india-india-global-828827" target="_blank">&nbsp;India.</a></p>

<p>India's foreign ministry said it was<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/tripura-floods-gumti-river-bangladesh-not-correct-government-on-reports-india-dam-caused-bangladesh-floods-6391337" target="_blank"> "not correct"</a> that the floods were caused by water released from the Dumbur dam on the Gumti River in the northeastern state of Tripura.</p>

<p>"We would like to point out that the catchment areas of Gumti River that flows through India and Bangladesh have witnessed the heaviest rains of this year over the last few days," the ministry said in a statement on Thursday.</p>

<p>"The flood in Bangladesh is primarily due to waters from these large catchments downstream of the dam."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/tripura-floods-critical-19-dead-17-lakh-people-affected-6396548" target="_blank">In Tripura</a>, 12 people have died due to landslides and floods triggered by the incessant rain of the past three days, Suman Deb, a Indian disaster management official, told Reuters.</p>

<p>"The impact has been devastating and rescue operations are ongoing," Deb said.</p>

<p>India's Home Minister, Amit Shah, said in a post on X that the central government has rushed disaster management teams, apart from boats and helicopters, to Tripura to assist the state government in relief and rescue operations.</p>

<p>"Floods on the common rivers between India and Bangladesh are a shared problem inflicting sufferings to people on both sides, and requires close mutual cooperation towards resolving them," the foreign ministry said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mv8e9gao_bangladesh-floods_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh is one of the world's most climate vulnerable countries with a risk of annual river flooding.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-donald-trump-race-to-us-election-photo-finish-6400682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris, Donald Trump Race To US Election Photo Finish]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-donald-trump-race-to-us-election-photo-finish-6400682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 15:27:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and Donald Trump set out Friday on the final 10-week sprint to election day, with the Democrat surging after an electrifying speech accepting the Democratic Party nomination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris and Donald Trump set out Friday on the final 10-week sprint to election day, with the Democrat surging after an electrifying speech accepting the Democratic Party nomination.</p>

<p>Less than three weeks before the presidential debate between the US vice president and the Republican ex-president -- and only a month before early in-person voting begins - polls show the race for the White House is neck and neck.</p>

<p>The former senator and prosecutor leaves Chicago with the wind in her sails, having outraised Trump and erased the polling leads he was enjoying before she replaced President Joe Biden atop the Democratic ticket last month.</p>

<p>But Dan Kanninen, battleground director of the Harris campaign, cautioned at a Bloomberg event on the sidelines of the convention that the race "is not fundamentally changed" and still "very, very tight."</p>

<p>"We have tremendous enthusiasm -- I think momentum is on our side -- but we now need to do something with it and engage the electorate effectively this fall," he said.</p>

<p>Harris accepted her party's presidential nomination on a glitzy final night in Chicago, buoyed by a galaxy of stars, that set the stage for the gruelling run-in to November 5.</p>

<h3><strong>Razor thin margins</strong></h3>

<p>The 59-year-old Californian has edged ahead by razor-thin margins in polling, reversing what had started to look like a likely Trump victory against Biden before he dramatically pulled out and endorsed Harris.</p>

<p>In just a month, Harris has raised a record-breaking half a billion dollars, enjoying a political honeymoon that shows little sign of ending.</p>

<p>Party leaders have cautioned that headwinds could still buffet the campaign, however.</p>

<p>These include internal protests over US policy on the Israel-Hamas war and possible shifts in polling with the expected withdrawal on Friday of independent candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr, who may endorse Trump.</p>

<p>The controversial scion of America's revered Kennedy clan is planning an announcement in Arizona, while Trump is also campaigning in the state, and promising to showcase a "special guest."</p>

<p>Analysts are mixed on the effect a Kennedy exit would have.</p>

<p>He is polling in the low single digits and his embrace of conspiracy theories has made him a fringe figure.</p>

<p>However, in a very tight race, it is possible that even a few thousand votes in a crucial swing state could ultimately determine who takes the White House.</p>

<p>Democratic heavy hitters, from Michelle Obama and Bill Clinton to vice presidential nominee Tim Walz, have warned that the party could still lose to Trump's Republicans if complacency creeps in.</p>

<p>"If we see a bad poll -- and we will -- we've got to put down that phone and do something," the former first lady told the party faithful in Chicago.</p>

<p>Walz, a former school football coach, used a sporting analogy, saying that Democrats were "down a field goal, but we're on offense and we've got the ball."</p>

<h3><strong>Reaching for the centre</strong></h3>

<p>Trump has largely been singing to the choir, mobilizing his right-wing base with apocalyptic warnings about migrant criminals and painting a dark picture of a country in "decline" that only he can save.</p>

<p>Harris and her Democrats have been reaching toward the centre.</p>

<p>Party strategists spent the week in Chicago showcasing a parade of anti-Trump Republicans, including ex-cabinet officials, a small-town mayor and a former statewide officeholder.</p>

<p>"If you vote for Kamala Harris in 2024, you're not a Democrat, you're a patriot," former Georgia lieutenant governor Geoff Duncan said.</p>

<p>While they previously characterised Trump as a demagogue, Democrats have instead begun making fun of the Republican nominee in a manner designed to belittle him and dent his aura of invincibility.</p>

<p>Harris called him an "unserious" person.</p>

<p>Harris, who has no events announced for the weekend, heads back to Washington with Second Gentleman Doug Emhoff on Friday to begin sketching out a battle plan for the next 70-plus days.</p>

<p>"I will be a president who unites us around our highest aspirations," Harris said in her keynote speech, earning uproarious applause.</p>

<p>"A president who leads and listens, who is realistic, practical and has common sense and always fights for the American people."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/06lu95io_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris accepted her party's presidential nomination on a glitzy final night in Chicago. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worst-volcanic-activity-in-50-years-in-iceland-after-major-volcano-eruption-6400507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Worst Volcanic Activity In 50 Years In Iceland After Major Volcano Eruption]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worst-volcanic-activity-in-50-years-in-iceland-after-major-volcano-eruption-6400507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 15:01:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A volcanic eruption has begun again on a peninsula adjacent to Iceland's capital Reykjavik, the sixth time lava has emerged in the area in the space of a year. The Lava burst to the surface at 9:26 p.m. local time on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A volcanic eruption has begun again on a peninsula adjacent to Iceland's capital Reykjavik, the sixth time lava has emerged in the area in the space of a year.</p>

<p>Lava burst to the surface at 9:26 p.m. local time on Thursday from a fissure that's expanding northward, according to the Met Office. The crack, north of the previously damaged fishing town of Grindavik, was initially about 1.4 kilometers (0.9 miles) long, the authorities said.</p>

<p>The scenario was anticipated, with scientists warning for several weeks of activity in the area after it woke from an 800-year dormancy in 2021. There's likely more to come, with potential for the unrest to continue for the next 300 to 400 years, according to Thor Thordarson, professor in volcanology and petrology at University of Iceland.</p>

<p>"This could be <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iceland-volcano-erupts-for-5th-time-since-december-shoots-lava-over-50-metres-into-air-5776132" target="_blank">repeated over again</a> for the next months or a few years," he said by phone. "We can have many more eruptions in this particular unrest event, which has lasted since 2021."</p>

<p>Iceland is one of the world's volcanic hot spots due to its position on the mid-Atlantic ridge where the North American and Eurasian tectonic plates rift apart.</p>

<p>Reykjavik, which lies about about 40 kilometers away, has been unaffected by the previous outbursts, and air traffic at nearby Keflavik international airport is not expected to be disrupted.</p>

<p>The devastation in Grindavik means the current volcanic activity is the most destructive in half a century and has thrust the north Atlantic island nation into a new era of contending with the fiery outbursts. The town has been severely damaged by the seismic activity, with deadly cracks emerging on its roads. Lava even overtook three houses in one of the five eruptions on its doorstep.</p>

<p>The previous outburst ended in mid-June, having lasted for 25 days.</p>

<p>Even as Iceland - with its 30 volcanic systems and more than 600 hot springs - is one of the most <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-much-damage-could-possible-iceland-volcano-eruption-cause-4579572" target="_blank">geologically active </a>places on earth, most eruptions have tended to happen in the wilderness. The contrast with suddenly witnessing homes burn has left the population shocked.</p>

<p>Most of Grindavik's 3,700 inhabitants have already relocated from the town previously. About 20 homes were occupied when Thursday's eruption started and their occupants are being evacuated, Hjordis Gudmundsdottir, a spokeswoman for the civil protection authority, said by phone.</p>

<p>"There is no panic and no danger," she said. "The inhabitants now know the drill and how to react."</p>

<p>Officials are evaluating how big the eruption is, she said. Lava is currently not flowing toward the town itself.</p>

<p>Iceland's government has built protective barriers around the town. Those have successfully steered lava flows away from most large-scale infrastructure. The state has also offered to buy out home owners in the volcano struck-town.</p>

<p>Still, roads and pipelines have been overrun by lava in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volcano-erupts-again-on-iceland-peninsula-fourth-time-since-december-5253334" target="_blank">previous eruptions</a> and have had to be rebuilt. Last winter, all 30,000 inhabitants of the peninsula were without hot water for several days after molten rock overtook a pipeline.</p>

<p>Other infrastructure in the area include the Svartsengi power plant owned by HS Orka hf and a number of businesses centered around geothermal heat and power as well as Iceland's top tourist attraction, the Blue Lagoon.</p>

<p>Before the events in Reykjanes, Iceland had previously seen an eruption in inhabited areas in 1973, when part of a 5,000-person fishing town was buried under lava in the the Westman Islands, off the country's southeastern coast.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earthquake-swarm-threat-of-volcanic-eruptions-why-iceland-is-on-the-edge-4566804" target="_blank">Fissure eruptions</a> on land, such as the current one, produce little ash and usually wreak no havoc on air travel.</p>

<p>One of the most disruptive eruptions in Iceland's recent history happened in 2010 when volcano Eyjafjallajokull in the southern part of the country released a plume of ash so vast that it grounded air traffic across Europe for weeks, resulting in the cancellation of 100,000 flights and affecting over 10 million people.</p>

<p>"Years or decades in the future, after this has stopped, we will get another unrest event similar to this one with a number of eruptions and number of seismic unrest on all the volcanic lineaments of the Reykjanes peninsula," said Thordarson at the University of Iceland.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2frih1cg_iceland-volcano_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iceland with over 600 hot springs is one of the most geologically active places on earth.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-meets-zelensky-in-ukraine-amid-war-with-russia-6400385]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In PM Modi's Historic Ukraine Visit, A Hug And Handshake With Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-meets-zelensky-in-ukraine-amid-war-with-russia-6400385]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:46:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The two leaders are scheduled to hold both one-on-one and delegation-level talks with a focus on ways to find a negotiated settlement to the Russia-Ukraine conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today met President Volodymyr Zelensky on the first-ever visit to Ukraine by an Indian prime minister. PM Modi and Mr Zelensky hugged and shook hands as they met at the Martyrologist Exposition in Kyiv.</p>

<p>The two leaders are scheduled to hold both one-on-one and delegation-level talks with a focus on ways to find a negotiated settlement to the Russia-Ukraine conflict.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | PM Modi and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy honour the memory of children at the Martyrologist Exposition in Kyiv <a href="https://t.co/oV8bbZ8bQh">pic.twitter.com/oV8bbZ8bQh</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1826906076689662460?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-arrives-in-ukraine-expected-to-discuss-russia-war-with-zelensky-6399104#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">PM Modi arrived in Kyiv</a> from Poland onboard a 'Rail Force One' train that took around 10 hours, in the second and final leg of his two-nation trip.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-arrives-in-ukraine-expected-to-discuss-russia-war-with-zelensky-6399104" target="_blank"><strong>Watch: PM Modi Greeted With Namastes As He Arrives In Ukraine</strong></a></p>

<p>His Ukraine visit comes nearly six weeks after his high-profile trip to Russia during which he held extensive talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin largely with a focus on ending the conflict.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-ukraine-today-meet-president-volodymyr-zelensky-amid-war-with-russia-6398463" target="_blank">PM Modi last met Mr Zelensky</a> in June on the sidelines of the G7 summit in Italy's Apulia. In the meeting, he conveyed to the Ukrainian President that India would continue to do everything within its means to support a peaceful solution to the Ukraine conflict and that the way to peace is through "dialogue and diplomacy".</p>

<p>He also told Mr Zelensky that India believes in a "human-centric" approach to finding a solution to the conflict in Ukraine. In that meeting, the Ukrainian president invited the prime minister to Kyiv.</p>

<p>Earlier Thursday, he held talks with Polish Prime Minister Donald Tusk and said that the ongoing conflicts in Ukraine and West Asia are a matter of "deep concern" and that "dialogue and diplomacy" is the way forward to restore peace.</p>

<p>"This is India's firm belief that no problem can be solved on the battlefield. In any crisis, the loss of lives of innocent people has become the biggest challenge for the whole of humanity," he had said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/edk7qld8_pm-modi-zelensky_625x300_23_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi met Volodymyr Zelensky on the first-ever visit to Ukraine by an Indian prime minister]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-book-reveals-what-queen-elizabeth-ii-thought-about-donald-trump-6400068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Book Reveals What Queen Elizabeth Thought About Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-book-reveals-what-queen-elizabeth-ii-thought-about-donald-trump-6400068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:41:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Late Queen Elizabeth II thought former US President Donald Trump was "very rude", a new biography revealed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Late Queen Elizabeth II thought former US President Donald Trump was "very rude", a new biography revealed. According to Craig Brown's book, <em>A Voyage Around The Queen</em>, not only did she find Trump's behaviour problematic but also allegedly disliked his conduct.</p>

<p>Moreover, the late Queen also questioned the nature of Donald Trump's relationship with his wife, Melania, suggesting she must have had some sort of "arrangement" with him to stay married. The Queen reportedly couldn't fathom why Melania would remain married to Trump, given his behavioural patterns during their meetings.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Late Queen's comments, mentioned in the newly released book, have drawn attention, particularly in the lead-up to the 2024 US Presidential Elections.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-13758993/queen-elizabeth-donald-trump-melania-craig-brown.html">excerpt from the book</a> read, "A few weeks after President Trump's visit, for instance, she confided in one lunch guest that she found him 'very rude': she particularly disliked the way he couldn't stop looking over her shoulder, as though in search of others more interesting."</p>

<p>Donald Trump first met the Queen in 2018 when he was President. The meeting, however, was overshadowed by controversy, as his state visit to the UK was met with widespread protests. Fast-forward to the present, Trump is making another bid for the White House. And the book appears to have dealt a blow to his campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump has swiftly denied these allegations, labelling the book's author, Craig Brown, a "sleaze bag" and dismissing the claims as "totally false."</p>

<p>In an interview with the&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/MailOnline/status/1826576254541221959 ">Daily Mail</a>, he denied claims, saying, "I had a great relationship with the Queen. She liked me and I liked her."</p>

<p>He added, "We spent hours together at a state dinner. She was a fantastic woman. I think it's a shame that a sleaze bag can write an article that's totally false. In fact, I've always heard the opposite."</p>

<p>He went on to claim that he was the Queen's favourite president, saying, "I heard I was her favourite president, and you've heard that too. She would say it to a lot of people."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-06/e67dtsg8_queentrumpuk-visitreuters650_625x300_04_June_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump first met the Queen in 2018 when he was President.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/humpback-whale-freed-from-entanglement-after-22-hour-rescue-in-sydney-6400155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Humpback Whale Freed From Entanglement After 22-Hour Rescue In Sydney]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/humpback-whale-freed-from-entanglement-after-22-hour-rescue-in-sydney-6400155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:12:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A juvenile humpback whale was freed Friday after it was entangled in ropes and buoys in the harbour of Australia's largest city for 22 hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A juvenile humpback whale was freed Friday after it was entangled in ropes and buoys in the harbour of Australia's largest city for 22 hours.</p>

<p>Rescuers in Sydney received a call on Thursday afternoon that the whale had become entangled and raced under fading light to save it.</p>

<p>By dawn, rescuers followed the whale in an inflatable boat and used specialised equipment to hold the whale in place while they cut the debris away.</p>

<p>The whale was freed shortly before midday on Friday, and swam off to the open ocean after its 22-hour ordeal.</p>

<p>Jessica Fox, from the Organisation for the Rescue and Research of Cetaceans in Australia, told AFP that efforts to save the whale were "incredible".</p>

<p>"It is not uncommon for a whale to enter Sydney Heads -- they pop their heads in time to time, but to have one entangled in Sydney Harbour is extremely rare."</p>

<p>For decades, humpback whale populations were hunted to the brink of extinction -- at one stage there were only an estimated 1,500 of the animals left in Australian waters.</p>

<p>But they are a rare conservation success story after global protections were afforded to the whales in 1965.</p>

<p>Humpback whale numbers now exceed 40,000 -- a number close to pre-whaling levels -- and the marine animal has since been removed from Australia's threatened species list.</p>

<p>"With so many more whales in the ocean and more humans in the ocean, there is going to be greater potential for conflict," Fox said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ktst96go_australia-whale_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Humpback whales are a rare conservation success story after global protections were afforded in 1965.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-mother-separated-from-triplets-by-war-fears-will-die-without-them-6399708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Mother Separated From Triplets By War Fears "Will Die Without Them"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-mother-separated-from-triplets-by-war-fears-will-die-without-them-6399708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 13:45:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As their first birthday approaches, the triplets Gaza-native Hanane Bayouk gave birth to in Jerusalem before the war have seen their mother just once, and she fears she will "die without them".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As their first birthday approaches, the triplets Gaza-native Hanane Bayouk gave birth to in Jerusalem before the war have seen their mother just once, and she fears she will "die without them".</p>

<p>The 26-year-old had to return to the Palestinian territory alone after giving birth to Najoua, Nour and Najmeh on August 24, 2023, because her Israeli travel permit had expired.</p>

<p>Bayouk received a permit to exit Gaza and give birth in annexed east Jerusalem's Al-Maqased hospital after seven years of painful IVF procedures.</p>

<p>She caught a glimpse of her children in their incubators, "barely an hour and a half", before driving back to Gaza after her permit "expired and the hospital told me to leave".</p>

<p>Bayouk was supposed to return in early October after her daughters had spent several weeks in incubators, which were in short supply in hospitals in Gaza even before the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-key-moments-in-israel-hamas-war-6240607" target="_blank"> Israel-Hamas war</a> erupted last October.</p>

<h3><strong>Far from the war</strong></h3>

<p>Two days after she applied for a new exit permit on October 5, Hamas commandos blasted through the Erez terminal, the only entry point from Gaza into Israel.</p>

<p>Once in Israel, the operatives carried out an unprecedented attack that left 1,198 people dead, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/gaza-death-count-climbs-to-40-000-as-ceasefire-talks-continue-in-qatar-826405" target="_blank">40,265</a> Palestinians in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and operative deaths. The UN rights office says most of the dead have been women or children.</p>

<p>Like Bayouk, Heba Idriss found herself surrounded by war and unable to return to Jerusalem to get her only daughter, Saida, born prematurely at the Maqased two months earlier.</p>

<p>The 27-year-old had hoped to bring her newborn back to her husband Saleh at their home in Shujaiya, in the northern Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Instead, the couple has been displaced nine times by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrikes-target-gaza-ahead-of-ceasefire-talks-6336678" target="_blank">Israeli air strikes</a> or evacuation orders and her husband Saleh has only seen pictures of Saida.</p>

<p>"I want to see my daughter, I suffer so much from being separated from her", she said in tears.</p>

<p>Hanane Bayouk too has been forced from her home and now lives in a displacement persons' camp in the south, sharing a tent with seven of her in-laws.</p>

<p>"It drives me crazy. It took me so long to get pregnant, and now I'm crying all the time," she told AFP on one of the rare days she was able to get through on Gaza's struggling phone network.</p>

<p>"Sometimes, I think I'd like for my daughters to return to Gaza before I die because I have never kissed them, but then I get a hold of myself and tell myself it's better for them to be safe far from the war," she said.</p>

<p>Back at the Maqased, neonatal intensive care unit director Hatem Khammach says that in normal times, there would not have been space to keep Nour, Najmeh, and Najoua for so long.</p>

<h3><strong>I cry every time</strong></h3>

<p>But the number of births at the hospital has fallen sharply as Israel has stopped issuing travel permits to mothers from Gaza and slashed the number given to mothers from the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>With more checkpoints closed more often, even those with a permit struggle to access specialist treatment in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>"Before the war, we had seven or eight Gaza babies in our department, which can host 30 at a time," Khammach said.</p>

<p>Since October, none have come, "and many sick people from the West Bank can't reach us".</p>

<p>But the hospital's<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-warns-of-unacceptable-rising-violence-against-human-aid-workers-6368664" target="_blank"> health workers </a>keep busy, like those who call Bayouk to let her speak on the phone to her three daughters.</p>

<p>"My husband can't do it. I do it and I cry every time we hang up. I'm afraid my daughters will grow up without knowing me," Bayouk said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0m20cid8_gaza-triplets_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hanane Bayouk had to return to Palestinian territory after giving birth as her Israeli permit had expired]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-placed-under-house-arrest-latest-case-against-him-explained-6399718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Andrew Tate Has Been Placed Under House Arrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-placed-under-house-arrest-latest-case-against-him-explained-6399718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 13:05:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Andrew Tate, who has often courted criticism for his misogynistic views, appeared in court alongside his brother Tristan, who, too, was placed under special judicial control.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Controversial social media influencer Andrew Tate has been once again placed under house arrest in Romania as authorities investigate new allegations of sex trafficking, including exploiting minors. Andrew Tate, who has often courted criticism for his misogynistic views, appeared in court alongside his brother Tristan, who, too, was placed under special judicial control. Prosecutors sought a 30-day custody to investigate the allegations involving 35 victims.</p>

<h3><strong>The Case Against Andrew Tate</strong></h3>

<p>The case against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-case-romanian-prosecutors-ask-court-to-extend-andrew-tates-detention-6395035" target="_blank">Andrew Tate</a> involves new allegations of sex trafficking and grooming, being investigated by Romania's anti-organised crime agency, DIICOT.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations include sex with a minor, with Tate accused of having sexual relations with a 15-year-old girl. Additionally, Tate and his brother Tristan are accused of trafficking underage persons, grooming and exploiting "vulnerable" individuals, including minors, for online pornographic content.</p>

<p>One suspect, who remains unnamed, is accused of forcing a 17-year-old girl to perform sexual acts for online content and keeping the $1.5M profit. The man allegedly had sexual relations with another girl who was 15.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to DIICOT, the brothers made some $2.8M through sexual exploitation. Prosecutors further accuse the brothers of money laundering, alleging they bought luxury cars and registered them in other people's names to hide the proceeds of their alleged illicit activity. The investigators have seized luxury items and cash and impounded 16 cars.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The two brothers have also allegedly attempted to intimidate victims and witnesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>DIICOT revealed that six people, including both Romanians and foreigners, have been detained in total.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>What Andrew Tate Said</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/misogynist-influencer-andrew-tates-romania-house-raided-over-rape-charges-6384609" target="_blank">Andrew Tate</a> has vehemently denied these allegations, calling the case a "stitch-up" and "absolutely disgusting". He claimed that thirty girls have stated that he and his brother have done nothing wrong and that two of the accusers are mothers of his children who have never been to Romania.</p>

<p>When questioned by a reporter about the allegations of sex with a minor and trafficking underage persons, Tate refused to respond and walked away.</p>

<p>The Tate brothers have faced similar allegations in the past, with previous charges of human trafficking and rape. They were released from house arrest a year ago but were told not to leave Romania.</p>

<p>Despite the mounting allegations, the brothers have consistently denied any wrongdoing and deny the formal charges against them. The new allegations are separate from the previous charges, and the investigation is ongoing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4b2pabh8_andrew-tate_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andrew Tate has vehemently denied these allegations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-thai-politician-under-investigation-after-slapping-woman-reporter-for-asking-question-6399652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Thai Politician Slaps Woman Reporter For Asking Question]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-thai-politician-under-investigation-after-slapping-woman-reporter-for-asking-question-6399652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:57:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thailand's parliament has said that it will investigate veteran politician and former army chief Prawit Wongsuwon after he was filmed slapping a journalist as she tried to ask him questions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thailand's parliament has said that it will investigate veteran politician and former army chief Prawit Wongsuwon after he was filmed slapping a journalist as she tried to ask him questions. According to the <em>BBC</em>, Mr Wongsuwon, the Palang Pracharath Party (PPRP) leader, struck a ThaiPBS reporter on the head after she asked him a question about the new prime minister Paetongtarn Shinawatra. The incident took place on Friday and it prompted the reporter to file a formal complaint against the senior politician, following which the Thai parliament said it would investigate the case.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a video shared on X (formerly Twitter), the senior politician, 79, was seen hitting Duangthip Yiamphop several times around the head as he left a building, demanding, "What are you asking? What? What?" Sharing the clip, a user wrote, "A politician is surrounded by journalists while walking down a corridor when one of them asks him a question. Instead of answering it, he raises his hand and slaps her in the head several times before climbing into his vehicle and driving away."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A politician is surrounded by journalists while walking down a corridor when one of them asks him a question.<br />
■ Instead of answering it, he raises his hand and slaps her in the head several times before climbing into his vehicle and driving away.<br />
■ Videos of this interaction in… <a href="https://t.co/WjYw7CZtWa">pic.twitter.com/WjYw7CZtWa</a></p>
— Stephen Mutoro (@smutoro) <a href="https://twitter.com/smutoro/status/1826264745755783513?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Wongsuwon was Thailand's army chief in the early 2000s. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/22/senior-thai-politician-who-slapped-reporter-to-be-investigated" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Guardian</em></a>, he was one of the architects of the 2014 coup that ousted the then PM, Yingluck Shinawatra. He then went on to serve as deputy prime minister under the military-backed government that ruled until last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the incident started gaining traction on social media, a PPRP party spokesman said that the 79-year-old knew the journalist well and had apologised, saying he was "teasing her as someone who he is close to" and that he "did not have any bad intention".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-of-my-life-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-shyamala-gopalan-6398652">"Star Of My Life": All About Kamala Harris' Mother, Shyamala Gopalan</a></strong></p>

<p>However, the Thai parliament said it would investigate the slapping after the reporter made a formal complaint. The Thai Journalists Association also condemned Mr Wongsuwon for using "violence against a journalist". It said it "considers his actions to be threatening and harassing toward the rights and freedom of the press".</p>

<p>Separately, Thai PBS has demanded that Mr Wongsuwon "take responsibility for his alleged attempts to intimidate a reporter". Noppadol Srihatai, the executive editor of ThaiPBS, said that the politician's actions "threaten journalism". "He was seen hurting a reporter and we cannot accept it. As a public organisation, we must protect journalists' rights so that media work won't be affected in the future," Mr Srihatai said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fio4e7s_prawit-wongsuwon_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/right-to-disconnect-act-employees-will-have-right-to-ignore-their-bosses-outside-working-hours-6399565]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In This Country, You Have The Right To Ignore Your Bosses After Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/right-to-disconnect-act-employees-will-have-right-to-ignore-their-bosses-outside-working-hours-6399565]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:42:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australians can ignore their bosses outside of work hours, according to a new law brought to tackle work-related mental health issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australians can ignore their bosses outside of work hours, according to a new law brought to tackle work-related mental health issues. The Fair Work Amendment (Right to Disconnect) Act, which amends the Fair Work Act 2009, moved through parliament earlier this year and will be implemented from August 26.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-these-countries-companies-cant-disturb-staff-after-office-hours-5017694" target="_blank">"Right to Disconnect"&nbsp;</a><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-these-countries-companies-cant-disturb-staff-after-office-hours-5017694" target="_blank">Act</a>&nbsp;protects</span>&nbsp;employees who refuse to monitor, read, or respond to any contact from their employers outside work hours. It, however, allows circumstances where an employee's right to refuse is "unreasonable", depending on their role, the reason for the contact, and how it is made, among other factors.</p>

<p>According to the law, some factors must be considered when determining whether an employee's refusal is unreasonable:</p>

<ul>
	<li>The reason for the contact.</li>
	<li>How the contact is made and how disruptive it is to the employee.</li>
	<li>Whether the employee is compensated or paid extra for being available to be contacted to perform work within a specific period, or working additional hours outside their ordinary hours of work.</li>
	<li>The nature of the employee's role and level of responsibility.</li>
	<li>The employee's personal circumstances, including family or caring responsibilities.</li>
</ul>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-latest-country-to-give-right-to-ignore-calls-emails-after-hours-5016616" target="_blank">law</a>&nbsp;has drawn criticism from employer groups who call it rushed and flawed.</p>

<p>Similar laws giving employees <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/webstories/feature/countries-where-companies-cant-disturb-staff-after-work-hours-13243" target="_blank">a right to switch off their devices</a> are already in place in France, Belgium, Italy, Argentina, Chile, Luxembourg, Mexico, Philippines, Russia, Slovakia, Spain, Ontario, and Ireland. &nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/u010fcrg_office_625x300_23_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-will-sunita-williams-come-back-to-earth-nasa-shares-big-update-6399519]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[When Will Sunita Williams Come Back To Earth? Nasa Shares Big Update]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-will-sunita-williams-come-back-to-earth-nasa-shares-big-update-6399519]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:37:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Astronauts Sunita Williams and Butchwilmore have been stuck in space since June 6 and are hoping to make their way back to Earth soon, but NASA says they may have to spend the next few days in uncertainty too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Astronauts Sunita Williams and Butchwilmore have been stuck in space since June 6 and are hoping to make their way back to Earth soon, but Nasa says they may have to spend the next few days in uncertainty too.</p>

<p>NASA is expected to take a final decision on Saturday to bring Sunita Williams back to Earth on Boeing's Starliner spacecraft or on SpaceX's Dragon capsule, the US space agency said.</p>

<p>"NASA's decision on whether to return Starliner to Earth with astronauts aboard is expected no earlier than August 24 (Saturday) at the conclusion of an agency-level review," the space agency said in a statement.</p>

<p>What began as an eight-day sojourn on the International Space Station (ISS) has extended to more than two months in space for Williams and Willmore -- the duo who became the first to ride the much-delayed Starliner.</p>

<p>As Starliner approached the orbiting lab, the spacecraft experienced a series of technical issues such as the failure of several thrusters and helium leaks in the propulsion system.</p>

<p>While engineers were able to bring four of the five malfunctioning thrusters back online (there are 28 thrusters on Starliner), it still raises a concern about “a successful de-orbit” to Earth.</p>

<p>Although Boeing proclaimed the safety of Starliner, NASA officials have disagreed.</p>

<p>If the US space agency deems Starliner unfit to travel on Saturday, it would undock uncrewed from the orbiting lab.</p>

<p>Williams and Wilmore will return onboard a SpaceX Dragon capsule in February 2025, as NASA has delayed the launch of the SpaceX Crew-9 mission to the ISS to September 24.</p>

<p>After many setbacks for years, Boeing launched its first flight on June 5.</p>

<p>Together with SpaceX, the company signed a contract in 2014 with NASA's Commercial Crew Programme to fly operational missions to and from the space station.</p>

<p>In 2019, its debut uncrewed orbital flight mission did not go as planned. The mission was completed in 2022.</p>

<p>SpaceX's Dragon capsules have been launching astronauts to space on its Falcon 9 rockets since 2020. It has so far aced about 12 flights to the Space Station.</p>

<p>While Boeing has poured over $1.5 billion into its Starliner programme, NASA has paid the aerospace giant about $4.2 billion over the years.</p>

<p>Both Boeing's Starliner and SpaceX's Dragon were aimed to ferry astronauts and cargo for NASA missions to low Earth orbit, the Moon, Mars, and beyond.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gpei299g_sunita-williams_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-maya-harris-the-sister-of-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-6399041]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who is Maya Harris, Sister Of US Vice President Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-maya-harris-the-sister-of-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-6399041]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:03:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maya Harris was the campaign chairperson during Kamala Harris' first presidential campaign in 2020.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris has accepted the Democratic Party nomination for the US Presidential elections. On the fourth and final night of the Democratic National Convention (DNC) in Chicago, her sister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395">Maya Harris</a> addressed the attendees and spoke at length about her relationship with the US Vice-President and their late mother, Shyamala Gopalan Harris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Noting their mother would be proud to see Kamala Harris as the Democratic Party nominee, Maya said that she raised them to "believe that we could be and do anything, and we believed her".</p>

<p>"She knew that we could be the authors of our own story," she said, adding that her elder sister has been "fighting for each of us to have that freedom."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Who is Maya Harris?</strong></p>

<p>Maya, the younger sister of the US vice president, has remained a major part of her life and professional career over the decades.</p>

<p>When Kamala and Maya's parents -- Donald Harris and Shyamala Gopalan -- parted ways, the two sisters decided to live with their mother. At the time, they were just 12 and nine years old.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shyamala-gopalan-harris-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-who-grew-up-in-india-and-moved-to-us-6398700"><strong>Also Read: All About Kamala Harris' Mother, Who Grew Up In India And Moved To US</strong></a></p>

<p>Maya later attended the Stanford Law School before working as a civil litigator. Then she became an adjunct law professor and Dean of Lincoln Law School of San Jose.</p>

<p>In her career, Maya has majorly focused on policy and civil rights, besides racial and gender justice. She was also a visiting scholar at Harvard Law School and a senior fellow at the Center for American Progress.</p>

<p>She was also the vice president of democracy, rights and justice at the Ford Foundation and executive director of the ACLU of Northern California.</p>

<p><strong>Involvement in presidential campaigns</strong></p>

<p>In 2020, Maya was the campaign chairperson during Kamala Harris' first presidential campaign.</p>

<p>Before that, she even worked as the senior policy advisor to Hillary Clinton during her presidential run in 2016. At the time, she used to lead the group of policy experts, besides developing Clinton's domestic policy.</p>

<p><strong>Family</strong></p>

<p>Maya welcomed her only child, daughter Meena, when she was a teenager.</p>

<p>Interestingly when Meena was just four, she played a matchmaker and introduced her mother to Tony West, who later became her husband.</p>

<p>In an interview with Stanford Lawyer in 2010, she said that Meena played a game of hide-and-seek with West on the campus of the university while they were just students. The two started dating after graduation.</p>

<p>Maya has two granddaughters -- Amara and Leela -- and often posts photographs with them on social media.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p6ps02po_maya-harris-afp_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In her career, Maya Harris has majorly focused on policy and civil rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-kamala-harris-speech-trying-to-gaslight-america-6399161]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trying To Gaslight America": Donald Trump On Kamala Harris' Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-kamala-harris-speech-trying-to-gaslight-america-6399161]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:35:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Kamala Harris spoke, Donald Trump posted about 37 times on his Truth Social platform, launching a series of critical comments against her. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump went all guns blazing in his response to Vice President Kamala Harris' Democratic nomination acceptance speech on Thursday.</p>

<p>Harris took the stage on the fourth day of the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, promising to be a president for all Americans.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In her speech, she talked about her commitment to serving all Americans and upholding the country's core principles. "You can always trust me to put country above party and self. To hold sacred America's fundamental principles from the rule of law to free and fair elections, to the peaceful transfer of power," she told supporters.</p>

<p>As she spoke, Trump posted about 37 times on his Truth Social platform, launching into a tirade against her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His first post, as her speech began, read: "WATCH KAMALA TRY TO GASLIGHT AMERICA..." &nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed truthsocial-video" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009224720203152/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>Throughout her address, Harris discussed a range of topics, including her stance on national security, immigration and Trump's influence on the Supreme Court. She also blamed the Republican nominee for the failure of a bipartisan border bill earlier in the year. The Vice-President called it the "strongest border bill in decades," and accused him of playing politics with national security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In response, Trump posted, "Why didn't she do something about the things of which she complains?"</p>

<p>Referring to her vice-presidential tenure, the former president added, "She said, 'Chart a new way forward,' but she's had three and a half years, and has done nothing but HARM!"</p>

<p>Trump accused Harris of incompetence, weakness, and radicalism. He claimed she wanted to grant citizenship to undocumented immigrants, adding she supported violent rioters during the protests in Minnesota.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009066397212800/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>"She stands for Incompetence and Weakness - Our Country is being laughed at all over the World!," Trump wrote on his social media platform.</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009133460070875/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>In another post, the former president called her a "Radical Marxist." "She just called to give all Illegals CITIZENSHIP, SAY GOODBYE TO THE U.S.A.! SHE IS A RADICAL MARXIST!"</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009120925667027/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>He also took issue with her remarks on the rule of law, pointing out her role as "Border Czar" and accusing her of allowing millions of undocumented immigrants into the country, many of whom he described as "criminals".&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009055608083509/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>Kamala Harris also used her speech to address the overturning of Roe v Wade, which ended federal protections for abortion in 2022. She pointed to Trump's role in appointing three conservative justices to the Supreme Court, which she said directly led to the landmark decision's reversal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump responded on Truth Social, arguing both Democrats and Republicans wanted Roe v Wade overturned to return the decision to the states and that the people are now voting on the issue, as it was "supposed to be."</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009103940625194/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Trump claimed Harris "became the Nominee without receiving one Vote, stealing the Nomination from Crooked Joe Biden, who earned it by getting 14 Million Votes."&nbsp;</p>

<p>This comes just weeks before the Trump vs Harris presidential debate on September 10.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/06lu95io_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-kamala-harris-grandnieces-tutorial-on-pronouncing-leaders-name-6399146]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Kamala Harris' Grandnieces' Tutorial On Pronouncing Leader's Name]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-kamala-harris-grandnieces-tutorial-on-pronouncing-leaders-name-6399146]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:31:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ahead of Kamala Harris' historic speech on the final night of the Democratic National Convention, her grandnieces took the stage to give an unusual tutorial to the crowd.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of Kamala Harris' historic speech on the final night of the Democratic National Convention, her grandnieces took the stage to give an unusual tutorial to the crowd. Introduced by actor Kerry Washington, the two girls offered to help the crowd learn how to properly pronounce the US vice president's name.</p>

<p>"It's come to my attention that there are some folks who struggle — or pretend to struggle — with the proper pronunciation of our future president's name. Confusion is understandable. Disrespect is not. So tonight we are going to help everyone get it right," the actor said before the two children walked on to a cheering crowd.</p>

<p>Eight-year-old Amara and six-year-old Leela, daughters of Harris' niece Meena Harris, were wearing a pink pantsuit and a blue dress.</p>

<p>"First you say ‘comma' like the comma in a sentence," Amara said. "Then you say ‘la' like la-la-la-la-la," added Leela.</p>

<p>Then it was the crowd's turn to practice. "Comma! La!, Comma! La!, Kama La" they roared.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Amara and Leela Ajagu — the daughters of Kamala Harris' niece, Meena Harris — joined actress Kerry Washington on stage to teach people — hint, hint — how to pronounce their “auntie's” name, “Kamala.” <a href="https://t.co/MLmaOd2BG4">pic.twitter.com/MLmaOd2BG4</a></p>
— Andreas Sandre (@andreas212nyc) <a href="https://twitter.com/andreas212nyc/status/1826806449634148388?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The girls' mother and Harris' niece also took the stage talking about growing up with her. “I grew up in Oakland, California in a house full of extraordinary women my mom, my grandma and my auntie who showed me the meaning of service, helping her sister, a 17 year old single mom fighting for justice for the American people and still cooking Sunday family dinner. She guided me. Now she's guiding my own children and I know she'll guide our country forward," she said.</p>

<p>In the past, several leaders have stumbled while pronouncing the Indian-origin leader's name.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most prominently, her now rival and Republican candidate Donald Trump has prided himself on mispronouncing her name, often using it as a way to dismiss her as competition. &nbsp;</p>

<p>When asked why, Trump said he had heard Harris' first name said "about seven different ways."</p>

<p>"Don't worry about it, it doesn't matter what I say. I couldn't care less," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5sqqovh8_kamala-harris-grandnieces_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-on-gaza-war-what-kamala-harris-said-on-gaza-war-6399111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Now Is The Time To...": What Kamala Harris Said On Gaza War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-on-gaza-war-what-kamala-harris-said-on-gaza-war-6399111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:29:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris, accepting the Democratic presidential nomination, pledged to broker a ceasefire in the Gaza conflict and solidify support for Ukraine, while criticizing her Republican opponent Donald Trump's stance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris, accepting the Democratic presidential nomination, pledged to broker a ceasefire in the Gaza conflict and solidify support for Ukraine, while criticizing her Republican opponent Donald Trump's stance.</p>

<p>On the final, and most anticipated, night of the four-day Chicago convention, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Harris, 59, promised</a> to chart a "New Way Forward" as she and Trump, 78, enter the final 11 weeks of the razor-close campaign.</p>

<p>"Now is the time to get a hostage deal and a ceasefire deal done," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395">Kamala Harris</a> told her supporters at the Democratic National Convention as she accepted the party's presidential nomination.</p>

<p>"And let me be clear, I will always stand up for Israel's right to defend itself and I will always ensure Israel has the ability to defend itself," she said</p>

<p>"What has happened in Gaza over the past 10 months is devastating. So many innocent lives lost, desperate hungry people fleeing for safety over and over again. The scale of suffering is heartbreaking," she added.</p>

<p>"President Biden and I are working to end this war such that Israel is secure, the hostages are released, the suffering in Gaza ends and the Palestinian people can realize their right to dignity, security, freedom and self-determination."</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Also Read: Kamala Harris' Donald Trump Warning As She Accepts Presidential Nomination</a></strong></p>

<p>The speech laid out some broad policy principles, foreign and domestic, but left unsaid specific details which in weeks to come she could be pressured to provide.</p>

<p>After days of protests from Palestinian supporters who were disappointed at not getting a speaking spot at the convention, Harris delivered a pledge to secure Israel, bring the hostages home from Gaza and end the war in the Palestinian enclave.</p>

<p>Attacking Trump for his frequent denigration of NATO and Ukraine, she said that "as president I will stand strong with Ukraine and our NATO allies."</p>

<p>Ms Harris called out Trump's public praise for Russian President Vladimir Putin and North Korea's Kim Jong Un, saying "I will not cozy up to tyrants and dictators."</p>

<p>Tyrants are "rooting for Trump, because you know, they know he is easy to manipulate with flattery and favors. They know Trump won't hold autocrats accountable because he wants to be an autocrat himself," she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4ph9j3d_gaza-reuters_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential Elections: Kamala Harris pledged to broker a ceasefire in the Gaza conflict.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-key-takeaways-from-the-democratic-national-convention-6399099]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Five Key Takeaways From The Democratic National Convention]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-key-takeaways-from-the-democratic-national-convention-6399099]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:26:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It was Kamala Harris's big night Thursday but she wasn't the only US Democrat to knock it out of the park during a week of rousing speeches, celebrity cameos and lashings of hope and joy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was Kamala Harris's big night Thursday but she wasn't the only US Democrat to knock it out of the park during a week of rousing speeches, celebrity cameos and lashings of hope and joy.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are some takeaways from the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Star-studded convention</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/let-us-choose-joy-oprah-winfrey-urges-us-voters-in-chicago-6396583" target="_blank">Oprah Winfrey </a>stole the show, exhorting voters to "choose joy" and Stevie Wonder took the convention to "Higher Ground."</p>

<p>John Legend lit up the United Center with a tribute to Prince, while comic actress Mindy Kaling shared stories of cooking lessons from the vice president.</p>

<p>And there was comedy with a serious message from Saturday Night Live star Kenan Thompson, who brought a giant book on stage to represent the radical Trump-linked Project 2025 governing agenda.</p>

<p>There was feverish speculation over a potential appearance by global superstar Beyonce, but it didn't pan out.</p>

<h3><strong>Family affair</strong></h3>

<p>On the biggest stage of their careers, political leaders often look to dewy-eyed family moments that, if seen as genuine, can humanize them and make them relatable to voters.</p>

<p>Minnesota Governor Tim Walz's 17-year-old son Gus touched a nation as he wiped away joyous tears, pointed to his father accepting the vice presidential nomination and sobbed: "That's my dad!"</p>

<p>Second Gentleman Doug Emhoff provided another indelible memory, referring to Harris as "my wiiiiife" as he recounted the goofy, endearing story of their romance.</p>

<p>And President Joe Biden's daughter Ashley was a highlight of the opening night as she paid tribute to "the O.G. Girl Dad."</p>

<h3><strong>Obamas sizzle</strong></h3>

<p>Barack and Michelle Obama -- the undisputed power couple of Democratic politics -- partied like it was 2008 as they gave the convention a shot of star power on Day Two.</p>

<p>The 44th president got the night's biggest laugh as he <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-michelle-obama-donald-trump-obamas-back-kamala-harris-as-president-shred-donald-trump-for-his-lies-6382885" target="_blank">goaded Donald Trump </a>over the Republican's "obsession with crowd sizes."</p>

<p>But he was upstaged by the former first lady -- by far the country's most popular Democrat -- who spoke of the "contagious power of hope" in the most cheered speech of the week.</p>

<p>The party made use of a deep bench of luminaries, including former president Bill Clinton, whose raspy speech was more than twice the allotted time but included some memorable applause lines.</p>

<h3><strong>Gaza fizzles</strong></h3>

<p>There were <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-cheer-joe-biden-and-kamala-harris-in-chicago-convention-amid-protester-march-6368883" target="_blank">protests across Chicago</a> against the administration's handling of the Israel-Hamas war, and particularly over the decision not to allow a Palestinian American to speak from the main stage.</p>

<p>The largest protest Thursday featured several thousand marchers, but was still much smaller than the demonstrations of tens of thousands predicted by organizers, and was not the fly in the ointment that the Democrats had feared.</p>

<p>Protests were largely peaceful, although several demonstrators were arrested when they broke through a security fence earlier in the week around the United Center where the main program was staged.</p>

<p>Although the activists were largely pro-Palestinian, they were joined by others marching against a variety of progressive causes, from reproductive rights to migrant welfare.</p>

<h3><strong>Bye bye Biden</strong></h3>

<p>The president gave an emotional keynote speech to open a conference that he thought just weeks ago he would be headlining.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-pass-torch-to-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-10-points-6373095" target="_blank">Biden</a> took to the stage, dabbing his eyes, and spoke at length about his achievements while making a case for Harris that was criticized for lacking the pizzazz of the Obama endorsements.</p>

<p>Flanked by First Lady Jill Biden and Harris, the veteran Democrat's final bow marked at long last the passing of the torch for a politician who has been in the public eye for more than half a century.</p>

<p>"Democracy has prevailed. Democracy has delivered. And now democracy must be preserved," he declared, to one of many standing ovations from the rapt audience.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qp4pb238_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were protests across Chicago against the administration's handling of the Israel-Hamas war (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-is-our-auntie-all-about-us-vice-presidents-nieces-and-nephews-6399047]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Our Auntie": All About Kamala Harris' Nieces And Nephews]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-is-our-auntie-all-about-us-vice-presidents-nieces-and-nephews-6399047]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:20:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris' godson, niece and nephew - Alexander Hudlin, Arden Emhoff and Jasper Emhoff - participated in the Democratic National Convention (DNC) on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris' godson, niece and nephew - &nbsp;Alexander Hudlin, Arden Emhoff and Jasper Emhoff&nbsp;- participated in the Democratic National Convention (DNC) on Wednesday. The three gave a speech about their "auntie", following a speech by former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi at the United Center in Chicago. They shared some stories about their relationship with her growing up. "Kamala Harris is our auntie," Jasper said, while Arden continued, "She'll be a president who cares for all of us."</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/all-about-kamala-harris-nieces-nephews-8700253" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>People</em></a>, Kamala Harris has one sister, Maya Harris, who is the mother of Meena Harris. The vice president is also an aunt to nieces and nephews on her husband Doug Emhoff's side, including his brother Andrew Emhoff's daughter Arden and son Jasper. Mr Emhoff also has a sister, Jackie, who has children as well. In addition to being an aunt, Ms Harris is also a great-aunt to Ms Meena's daughters, Amara and Leela.</p>

<h3><strong>Now, as Kamala Harris' nieces and nephews take centre stage at the DNC, here's everything to know about them</strong></h3>

<h2>Meena Harris&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Meena Harris, daughter of Kamala Harris' sister Maya, has been open about growing up in an all-women household from her mother and aunt to her grandmother, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-of-my-life-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-shyamala-gopalan-6398652">Shyamala Gopalan</a>. According to the outlet, she described what it was like having "incredible women of colour running around" and how they inspired her to be ambitious.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They were all in service and had a purpose. I appreciate that even more as an adult just how informative that was for me and I think about how I'm raising my own children, not only how I can carry that legacy forward but also that my kids in many good ways are growing up in a different environment," Meena Harris said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/kamala-harris-family-tree-dnc-2024-emhoff-1943293" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, the 39-year-old is the founder and CEO of Phenomenal, a consumer and media company. She is also a lawyer and author and has worked on her aunt's 2022 presidential campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Jasper Emhoff</h2>

<p>Jasper Emhoff is the son of Doug Emhoff's brother, Andy. Emhoff has a sister as well. He grew up in Santa Cruz, California. Like is cousin, he is also building an impressive career for himself after graduating from the University of California, Berkeley, in 2023 with a degree in computer science.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since graduating, Jasper started working as a machine learning engineer at Stealth Startup, People reported.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Arden Emhoff&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Arden Emhoff is Jasper's sister. She made a rare public appearance on Wednesday when she spoke in favour of her aunty at the DNC. Arden shared how "even as a kid, Auntie made me feel that I was seen, that my words are important, that I am important and loved".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Kamala Harris' Donald Trump Warning As She Accepts Presidential Nomination</a></strong></p>

<p>"I know she will value others perspectives no matter their age or background," Arden said. "Let's win this thing."</p>

<h2>Kamala Harris' great-nieces</h2>

<p>The vice president is a great-aunt to Ms Meena's daughters, Amara and Leela. The two little girls made headlines for dressing up like the vice president, including donning fur coats to Ms Harris' inauguration in 2021. Leela also twinned with her aunt at this year's DNC as well. She reportedly wore a tan suit inspired by Kamala Harris' bespoke tan wood suit.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kg7basfg_kamala-harris_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meena Harris is daughter of Kamala Harris' sister Maya.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>