<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 05:32:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-attack-us-warships-with-drones-missiles-pentagon-7006088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthis Attack US Warships With Drones, Missiles: Pentagon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-attack-us-warships-with-drones-missiles-pentagon-7006088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 05:32:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Huthi rebels targeted two US destroyers with drones and missiles as they transited the Bab al-Mandab Strait, but the warships defeated the attacks, the Pentagon said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Yemen's Huthi rebels targeted two US destroyers with drones and missiles as they transited the Bab al-Mandab Strait, but the warships defeated the attacks, the Pentagon said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The Huthis began striking ships in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden in November 2023, part of the region-wide fallout from Israel's devastating war in Gaza, which groups in multiple countries have cited as justification for attacks.</p>

<p>The US warships "were attacked by at least eight one-way attack uncrewed aerial systems, five anti-ship ballistic missiles and three anti-ship cruise missiles, which were successfully engaged and defeated," Pentagon spokesman Major General Pat Ryder told journalists.</p>

<p>"The vessels were not damaged, no personnel were hurt," Ryder said of the Monday attacks.</p>

<p>A claim from the Huthis that they also attacked the USS Abraham Lincoln aircraft carrier is not accurate, he said.</p>

<p>"Based on the information I have, it was not attacked, contrary to some of the allegations... by the Huthis," Ryder said, declining to specify the carrier's location.</p>

<p>The Yemeni rebels say their attacks -- a significant international security challenge that threatens a major shipping lane -- are in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza.</p>

<p>Anger over Israel's ongoing military campaign in the small coastal territory, which began after an unprecedented Hamas attack on October 7, has stoked violence involving Iran-backed groups in Lebanon, Iraq, Syria and Yemen.</p>

<p>The United States and other countries have deployed military vessels to help shield shipping from the Huthi strikes, but attacks directly targeting American warships are relatively rare.</p>

<p>Washington's forces have also carried out frequent air strikes on the Huthis in a bid to degrade their ability to target shipping and have sought to seize weapons before they reach the rebels, but their attacks have persisted.</p>

<p>Ryder said Tuesday that US forces carried out multiple air strikes over the weekend against Huthi weapons storage facilities.</p>

<p>"These facilities housed a variety of advanced conventional weapons used by the Iran-backed Huthis to target US and international military and civilian vessels navigating international waters," he said, noting that both US Air Force and Navy assets were involved.</p>

<p>US forces also targeted Iran-backed groups in Syria on Monday in response to drone and rocket attacks on American troops in that country the previous day.</p>

<p>The attacks did not result in any American casualties, according to Ryder, who said he did not have information to provide on whether the subsequent US strikes killed or wounded operatives.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/omrp6b7g_houthis-attacks-us-ship_625x300_19_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Yemeni rebels say their attacks are in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-33-killed-in-israeli-strikes-says-lebanon-7006032]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[33 Killed In Israeli Strikes, Says Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-33-killed-in-israeli-strikes-says-lebanon-7006032]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 05:18:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon said Israeli strikes killed 33 people across the country on Tuesday, among them many who had been displaced by the intensified conflict between Israel and Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon said Israeli strikes killed 33 people across the country on Tuesday, among them many who had been displaced by the intensified conflict between Israel and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The attacks targeted not only known Hezbollah strongholds such as the southern suburbs of Beirut, but also areas where the Iran-backed group has not traditionally had a presence.</p>

<p>The health ministry said a strike on a town in the Chouf region south of Beirut killed at least 15 people, revising a previous toll upwards from 12.</p>

<p>"The Israeli raid on Joun in the Chouf district resulted... in the death of 15 martyrs, including eight women and four children," it said.</p>

<p>Twelve others were wounded in the strike, the ministry added.</p>

<p>The official National News Agency (NNA) said the building had housed displaced people fleeing bombardment by Israel in its war against Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The health ministry said a strike a few kilometres further north in the mountainous Aley region east of the capital killed eight people.</p>

<p>A security source told AFP the attack had hit a house where people displaced in the war had taken refuge.</p>

<p>The ministry also reported one dead in an Israeli strike in the Tyre area in south Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>Two killed in Israel</strong></p>

<p>Elsewhere in the south of the country, the ministry reported strikes on the towns of Tefahta and Roumin killed seven people.</p>

<p>Attacks on the Hermel region in the Bekaa Valley in the east of the country bordering Syria killed another two people.</p>

<p>Nabatiyeh, the largest city in the south, again came under attack. Last month, Israeli strikes razed its historic marketplace and killed the mayor.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, meanwhile, said it fired missiles at an air base near Tel Aviv, following a wave of Israeli air strikes on the group's south Beirut bastion.</p>

<p>Israel reported two people killed in the northern town of Nahariya by rocket fire from Lebanon.</p>

<p>Since September 23, Israel has stepped up its bombing campaign in Lebanon, mainly targeting Hezbollah strongholds in south Beirut and in the east and south of the country. On September 30, it sent in ground troops.</p>

<p>Israeli strikes outside Hezbollah strongholds have often targeted buildings where displaced civilians have sought refuge, with Lebanese security officials telling AFP the targets were Hezbollah operatives.</p>

<p>On Tuesday morning Israel launched more than a dozen air strikes on south Beirut, state media said, shortly after its military warned residents of four districts to evacuate.</p>

<p><strong>Thousands killed in Lebanon</strong></p>

<p>Israel's military said it had hit "Hezbollah terrorist targets" in south Beirut including "command centres, weapons production sites, and additional Hezbollah terrorist infrastructure".</p>

<p>Witnesses told AFP they heard gunfire in the area ahead of the strikes -- warning shots by residents for people to leave following the evacuation call.</p>

<p>The Lebanon war came after nearly a year of cross-border exchanges of fire, launched by Hezbollah in support of Hamas following its Palestinian ally's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel that triggered the Gaza war.</p>

<p>With little sign of an end to the conflict, UN peacekeeping chief Jean-Pierre Lacroix met Prime Minister Najib Mikati in Beirut on Tuesday as part of a visit aimed at boosting calls for a ceasefire.</p>

<p>More than 3,300 people have been killed in Lebanon since the clashes began last year, according to the health ministry, the majority of them since late September.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel reported 2 people killed in Nahariya by rocket fire from Lebanon. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-major-push-for-nuclear-power-india-asks-states-to-set-up-reactors-7005942]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Major Push For Nuclear Power, India Asks States To Set Up Reactors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-major-push-for-nuclear-power-india-asks-states-to-set-up-reactors-7005942]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 04:49:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has ambitious plans to set up nuclear reactors across the country, especially in states where thermal power plants have either completed its life, or where access to coal is a challenge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has ambitious plans to set up nuclear reactors across the country, especially in states where thermal power plants have either completed its life, or where access to coal is a challenge.</p>

<p>With its focus on clean energy, India aims to reduce its dependence fossil fuels, and for this, the central government has now asked states to set up nuclear power plants.</p>

<p>India's Power Minister, Manohar Lal, on Tuesday chaired the Conference of Power Ministers of States &amp; Union Territories where he asked states that are distant from coal resources to set up nuclear-based power plants. The move has also been made keeping in mind the rapidly-growing demand for electricity in the country.</p>

<p>In the Union Budget, the central government had proposed to partner with private investors to set up small-scale nuclear reactors to meet its growing energy demands.</p>

<p>"States should consider setting up nuclear power plants at the sites where coal-based thermal power plants have completed their life," the Union Minister told state governments as per a statement issued by the Centre.</p>

<p>The minister also asked states to identify power utilities and list them on the stock exchange to meet its investment targets in the power sector. Asking states to ramp up its renewable energy capacity, the minister emphasised on the need to improve transmission systems in order to achieve that.</p>

<p>Many foreign power plant builders have stayed away from building atomic and nuclear plants in India because of stringent laws over compensation as well as very strict rules and regulations imposed by New Delhi in the event of an accident, mishap or leak.</p>

<p>India currently has 24 nuclear power plants in operation. All of them are run and maintained by the Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited or NPCIL, which comes under the Department of Atomic Energy. NPCIL is a government-owned public sector undertaking or PSU, headquartered in Mumbai.</p>

<p>India's current power generation from nuclear plants is around 8 gigawatt. New Delhi has ambitious plans to increase this to more than 20 gigawatt by 2032.</p>

<p>Being the only G20 nation to achieve its climate goals ahead of its deadline, India aims to add 500 gigawatt of renewable energy to its grid by 2030. Prime Minister Narendra Modi has also pledged to make India a nation with net-zero carbon emission by 2070.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-03/nuclear-reactor-istock_650x400_51490779852.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has asked states to consider setting up nuclear plants to reduce dependency on fossil fuels]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-the-church-of-england-hit-by-unprecedented-scandal-will-pick-its-next-leader-7005688]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Church Of England, Hit By Unprecedented Scandal, Will Pick A New Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-the-church-of-england-hit-by-unprecedented-scandal-will-pick-its-next-leader-7005688]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 03:17:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The archbishop of Canterbury, Justin Welby, resigned over an abuse cover-up scandal on Tuesday, marking an unprecedented moment for the Church of England.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The archbishop of Canterbury, Justin Welby, resigned over an abuse cover-up scandal on Tuesday, marking an unprecedented moment for the Church of England.</p>

<p>He becomes the first leader of the church, as well as the wider Anglican Communion of 85 million Christians worldwide, to be forced out in this manner, religious experts say.</p>

<p>Announcing he is leaving "in sorrow," Welby said the timing of his departure would be decided once a review of his remaining obligations had been completed.</p>

<p>The 68-year-old had been in the role since 2013, and would have been expected to retire around age 70.</p>

<h2><strong>HOW IS THE LIST OF CANDIDATES WHITTLED DOWN?</strong></h2>

<p>A period of consultation on the needs of the Church of England, as well as the Anglican Communion, will be followed by an appointment of a Crown Nominations Committee.</p>

<p>The committee will consist of 17 voting members, including the archbishop of York who is the second-most-senior bishop in the institution, another bishop elected by the House of Bishops, and representatives from the Anglican Communion, the Diocese of Canterbury, and the church's governing body - the General Synod.</p>

<p>It will be chaired by an Anglican, ideally in public life, chosen by Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</p>

<p>Assembling the committee could take a couple of months, David Thompson, emeritus professor of modern church history at the University of Cambridge, told Reuters, adding that the whole process could take up to six months.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT DOES THE COMMITTEE DO?</strong></h3>

<p>The committee will make a recommendation to Starmer. If the prime minister accepts it, he will put the name forward to King Charles, who is the supreme governor of the Church of England.</p>

<h3><strong>WHO ARE POSSIBLE SUCCESSORS? &nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Three bishops have been tipped to succeed Welby as the 106th archbishop of Canterbury: Martyn Snow, the bishop of Leicester, Graham Usher, the bishop of Norwich, and Guli Francis-Dehqani, the bishop of Chelmsford.</p>

<p>Snow abstained in a church assembly vote on blessing for gay couples, while Usher is in favour of gay rights and has pushed for higher taxes on fossil-fuel companies.</p>

<p>Francis-Dehqani, who was ordained in 2017, just three years after the first woman bishop was appointed, was born in Iran and has spoken about how her brother was murdered in the aftermath of the Iranian Revolution.</p>

<p>She would be the first woman to become archbishop if selected.</p>

<p>Francis-Dehqani and Usher were among 44 bishops who signed a letter last year expressing regret that the authorisation of standalone services to bless same-sex couples had been delayed.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT AWAITS THEM?</strong></h3>

<p>The new archbishop will likely face the same persistent divisions on same-sex relationships that Welby tried to balance during his 11-year tenure.</p>

<p>It has been a matter of contention not just in the wider Anglican Communion, which includes African churches where homosexuality is taboo, but also within the Church of England.</p>

<p>"The principal problem for the archbishop of Canterbury ... is that he combines the role of the primate of all England, with being the head of the Anglican Communion," Thompson said. "This is effectively a relic of empire, because that was the context in which the Anglican Communion developed.</p>

<p>"It increasingly in the late 20th century and the early 21st century has revealed a conflict of role which hasn't been satisfactorily resolved during Archbishop Welby's tenure." &nbsp;</p>

<p>In his resignation, Welby said his decision made it "clear how seriously the Church of England understands the need for change."</p>

<p>"For nearly twelve years I have struggled to introduce improvements," he wrote. "It is for others to judge what has been done."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d8filkdg_justin-welby-archbishop-of-canterbury-resigns-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The archbishop of Canterbury, Justin Welby, resigned over an abuse cover-up scandal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photos-donald-trumps-cabinet-whos-been-picked-whos-in-the-running-7005593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Photos: Donald Trump's Cabinet - Who's Been Picked, Who's In The Running]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photos-donald-trumps-cabinet-whos-been-picked-whos-in-the-running-7005593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 02:40:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has begun the process of choosing a cabinet and selecting other high-ranking administration officials following his presidential election victory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has begun the process of choosing a cabinet and selecting other high-ranking administration officials following his presidential election victory.</p>

<p>Here are the early picks and top contenders for some of the key posts overseeing defense, intelligence, diplomacy, trade, immigration and economic policymaking. Some are in contention for a range of posts.</p>

<h2><strong>SUSIE WILES, Chief Of Staff</strong></h2>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fbdesfik_susie-wiles-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced last week that Wiles, one of his two campaign managers, will be his White House chief of staff.</p>

<p>While the specifics of her political views are somewhat unclear, Wiles, 67, is credited with running a successful and efficient campaign. Supporters hope she will instill a sense of order and discipline that was often lacking during Trump's first four-year term, when he cycled through a number of chiefs of staff.</p>

<h3><strong>TOM HOMAN, 'Border Czar'</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/32u43a4c_tom-homan-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced on Sunday night that Homan, the acting director of Immigration and Customs Enforcement during Trump's first administration, will be in charge of the country's borders.</p>

<p>Trump made cracking down on people in the country illegally a central element of his campaign, promising mass deportations.</p>

<p>Homan, 62, said on Monday he would prioritize deporting immigrants in the U.S. illegally who posed safety and security threats as well as those working at job sites.</p>

<p>Trump, in a post on his Truth Social platform, said Homan will be "in charge of our nation's borders ('The Border Czar'), including, but not limited to, the Southern Border, the Northern Border, all Maritime, and Aviation Security," including the deportation of immigrants in the U.S. illegally.</p>

<h3><strong>ELISE STEFANIK, UN Ambassador</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/b5jg0s2_elise-stefanik-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced on Monday that Stefanik, a Republican congresswoman and staunch Trump supporter, would be his ambassador to the United Nations.</p>

<p>Stefanik, 40, a U.S. representative from New York state and House Republican conference chair, took a leadership position in the House of Representatives in 2021 when she was elected to replace then-Representative Liz Cheney, who was ousted for criticizing Trump's false claims of election fraud.</p>

<p>"I am honored to nominate Chairwoman Elise Stefanik to serve in my Cabinet as U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations," Trump said in a statement. "Elise is an incredibly strong, tough, and smart America First fighter."</p>

<p>Stefanik will arrive at the U.N. after bold promises by Trump to end the Russia-Ukraine war and Israel's war in Gaza.</p>

<h3><strong>LEE ZELDIN, EPA Administrator</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/930bpq3o_lee-zeldin-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced on Monday he had appointed former congressman Lee Zeldin of New York state as administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and Zeldin said he had accepted the role.</p>

<p>Zeldin, 44, a staunch Trump ally, served in Congress from 2015 to 2023. In 2022, he lost the New York governor's race to Democratic incumbent Kathy Hochul.</p>

<p>Trump has promised to overhaul U.S. energy policy, with the aim of maximizing the country's already record-high oil and gas production by rolling back regulations and speeding up permitting.</p>

<p>As head of the EPA, Zeldin will play a key role in implementing those policies.</p>

<h3><strong>MARCO RUBIO, Secretary Of State</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6ophigok_marco-rubio-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump is expected to tap U.S. Senator Marco Rubio to be his secretary of state, sources said on Monday, putting the Florida-born politician on track to be the first Latino to serve as the United States' top diplomat.</p>

<p>Rubio, 53, was arguably the most hawkish option on Trump's shortlist for secretary of state. The senator has in past years advocated for a muscular foreign policy with respect to U.S. geopolitical foes, including China, Iran and Cuba.</p>

<p>Over the last several years he has softened some of his stances to align more closely with Trump's views. The president-elect accuses past U.S. presidents of leading the U.S. into costly and futile wars and has pushed for a more restrained foreign policy.</p>

<h3><strong>MIKE WALTZ, National Security Adviser</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bgettsik_mike-waltz-michael-waltz-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump on Tuesday said he had picked for national security adviser Republican U.S. Representative Mike Waltz, a retired Army Green Beret who has been a leading critic of China.</p>

<p>Waltz, a 50-year-old Trump loyalist who also served in the National Guard as a colonel, has criticized Chinese activity in the Asia-Pacific and has voiced the need for the U.S. to be ready for a potential conflict in the region.</p>

<p>The national security adviser is a powerful role, which does not require Senate confirmation. Waltz will be responsible for briefing Trump on key national security issues and coordinating with different agencies.</p>

<p>While slamming the Biden administration for a disastrous withdrawal from Afghanistan in 2021, Waltz has publicly praised Trump's foreign policy views.</p>

<h3><strong>KRISTI NOEM, Homeland Security Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7tq94hrk_kristi-noem-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump has chosen South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem to serve as the next homeland security secretary, two sources familiar with the decision said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Noem, 52, once seen as a possible running mate for Trump, is currently serving her second four-year term as South Dakota's governor. She rose to national prominence after refusing to impose a statewide mask mandate during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>

<p>The Department of Homeland Security is responsible for everything from border protection and immigration to disaster response and the U.S. Secret Service.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign and Noem's office did not immediately respond to requests for comments.</p>

<h3><strong>SCOTT BESSENT, Potential Treasury Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/971vpc08_scott-bessent-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Bessent, a key economic adviser to Trump, is widely seen as a top candidate for treasury secretary. A longtime hedge fund investor who taught at Yale University for several years, Bessent has a warm relationship with the president-elect.</p>

<p>While Bessent has long favored the laissez-faire policies that were popular in the pre-Trump Republican Party, he has also spoken highly of Trump's use of tariffs as a negotiating tool. He has praised the president-elect's economic philosophy, which rests on a skepticism of both regulations and international trade.</p>

<h3><strong>ROBERT LIGHTHIZER, Potential Treasury Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fti7e77o_robert-lighthizer-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A loyalist who served as Trump's U.S. trade representative for essentially the then-president's entire term, Lighthizer will almost certainly be invited back. Though Bessent likely has a better shot at becoming treasury secretary, Lighthizer has an outside chance, and he might be able to reprise his old role if he's interested.</p>

<p>Like Trump, Lighthizer, 77,&nbsp; is a trade skeptic and a firm believer in tariffs. He was one of the leading figures in Trump's trade war with China and the renegotiation of the North American Free Trade Agreement, or NAFTA, with Mexico and Canada during Trump's first term.</p>

<h3><strong>HOWARD LUTNICK, Potential Treasury Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ripbsl8s_howard-lutnick-twitter_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The co-chair of Trump's transition effort and the longtime chief executive of financial services firm Cantor Fitzgerald, Lutnick is in the running for treasury secretary.</p>

<p>A bombastic New Yorker like Trump, Lutnick, 63, has uniformly praised the president-elect's economic policies, including his use of tariffs.</p>

<p>He has at times given elaborate, unvarnished opinions about what policies will be enacted in Trump's second term. Some Trump allies had privately complained that he too often presented himself as speaking on behalf of the campaign.</p>

<h3><strong>LINDA McMAHON, Potential Commerce Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a5jepvq_linda-mcmahon-twitter_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Professional wrestling magnate and former Small Business Administration director Linda McMahon is seen as the frontrunner to lead Trump's Department of Commerce, three sources briefed on the plans said.</p>

<p>McMahon, 76, is a major donor and was an early supporter of the Republican president-elect when he first ran for the White House almost a decade ago. This time, Trump tapped her to co-lead a transition team formed to help vet personnel and draft policy ahead of the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>McMahon is the co-founder and former CEO of the professional wrestling franchise WWE. She later served as director of the Small Business Administration, resigning in 2019, and went on to lead a pro-Trump political action committee that supported his 2020 reelection bid.</p>

<h3><strong>JOHN RATCLIFFE, Potential CIA Director</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6eaho2m8_john-ratcliffe-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A former congressman and prosecutor who served as director of national intelligence during Trump's last year in office, Ratcliffe, 59, is seen as a leading contender to be director of the CIA, according to two people familiar with the transition process. Ratcliffe is also a potential attorney general pick.</p>

<p>The president-elect's allies view Ratcliffe as a hardcore Trump loyalist who could likely win Senate confirmation. Still, during his time as director of national intelligence, Ratcliffe often contradicted the assessments of career civil servants, drawing criticism from Democrats who said he politicized the role.</p>

<h3><strong>MIKE LEE, Potential Attorney General</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ri5hg36c_mike-lee-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A U.S. senator from Utah, Lee is widely seen as another top candidate for attorney general. Though the former prosecutor declined to vote for Trump during the 2016 election, he later became an unwavering ally, and he has become something of an intellectual hero among some factions of Trumpworld.</p>

<p>Lee, 53, was a key figure in attempts by Trump and his allies to overturn his 2020 election loss to Democrat Joe Biden, and has spread unfounded conspiracy theories about the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the Capitol.</p>

<h3><strong>KASH PATEL, Potential Candidate For National Security Posts</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ej9qilhk_kash-patel-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A former Republican House staffer who served in various high-ranking staff roles in the defense and intelligence communities during Trump's first term, Patel frequently appeared on the campaign trail to rally support for the candidate.</p>

<p>Some Trump allies would like to see Patel, considered the ultimate Trump loyalist, appointed CIA director. Any position requiring Senate confirmation may be a challenge, however.</p>

<p>Patel, 44, has leaned into controversy throughout his career. In an interview with Trump ally Steve Bannon last year, he promised to "come after" politicians and journalists perceived to be enemies of Trump.</p>

<p>During Trump's first term, Patel drew animosity from some more experienced national security officials, who saw him as volatile and too eager to please the then-president.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-04/3nop7tug_donald-trump-white-house-briefing-_625x300_28_April_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is in the process of choosing a Cabinet and selecting high-ranking officials]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inflation-in-argentina-dips-below-200-for-first-time-in-a-year-7005378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inflation In Argentina Dips Below 200% For First Time In A Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inflation-in-argentina-dips-below-200-for-first-time-in-a-year-7005378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:30:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Argentine inflation has dipped to 193%, landing below the 200% threshold for the first time in close to a year, data from statistics agency INDEC showed on Tuesday, as President Javier Milei's dramatic austerity agenda bears fruit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Argentine inflation has dipped to 193%, landing below the 200% threshold for the first time in close to a year, data from statistics agency INDEC showed on Tuesday, as President Javier Milei's dramatic austerity agenda bears fruit.</p>

<p>Slowing inflation, pulled back in part by the government's dramatic public spending adjustments, has however come at the cost of consumption in a battered economy where more than half of the country has fallen into poverty.</p>

<p>Data from INDEC showed that monthly inflation slowed to 2.7% in October from 3.5% the previous month, its lowest since November 2021. The annual rate dipped below 200% for the first time since November last year.</p>

<p>While rent and utility costs drove monthly price rises, up 5.4%, prices in transport, food and non-alcoholic drinks rose just 1.2% from the previous month.</p>

<p>But the good news can be hard to grasp for Argentines who have had to tighten their belts to make it to the end of the month.</p>

<p>The government has slashed subsidies on public services, and increased public sector layoffs. Inflation is still very high by global standards and has contributed to a deep fall in purchasing power.</p>

<p>"Sales have been dropping a lot, perhaps people come more to buy on a daily basis, small quantities, and you can see the difference," said Maria Sunilda Correa, who works in a poultry store.</p>

<p>Consumers are buying less beef in the famously steak-loving country after Milei ended the previous government's freeze on beef prices. Beef consumption fell in the first six months of the year to its lowest level in 13 years, according to a report by industry group Ciccra.</p>

<p>"The price of meat has not gone up these months because there is very little consumption. As consumption goes down, sales also go down. And well, it is a bit complicated," said Gabriel Segovia, a 52-year-old butcher in Buenos Aires.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v0s9vcko_argentina-inflation-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Argentine inflation has dipped to 193%, landing below the 200% threshold.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-the-latest-science-shows-us-about-climate-change-7005286]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What The Latest Science Shows Us About Climate Change]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-the-latest-science-shows-us-about-climate-change-7005286]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:00:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This year's UN climate summit - COP29 - is being held during yet another record-breaking year of higher global temperatures, adding pressure to negotiations aimed at curbing climate change.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year's UN climate summit - COP29 - is being held during yet another record-breaking year of higher global temperatures, adding pressure to negotiations aimed at curbing climate change.</p>

<p>The last global scientific consensus on climate change was released in 2021 through the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, however scientists say that evidence shows global warming and its impacts are unfolding faster than expected.</p>

<h2><strong>Here is some of the latest climate research:</strong></h2>

<h2><strong>1.5C BREACHED?</strong></h2>

<p>The world may already have hit 1.5 degree Celsius (2.7 F) of warming above the average pre-industrial temperature - a critical threshold beyond which it is at risk of irreversible and extreme climate change, scientists say.</p>

<p>A group of researchers made the suggestion in a study released on Monday based on an analysis of 2,000 years of atmospheric gases trapped in Antarctic ice cores that extends the understanding of pre-industrial temperature trends.</p>

<p>Scientists have typically measured today's temperatures against a baseline temperature average for 1850-1900. By that measure, the world is now at nearly 1.3 C (2.4 F) of warming.</p>

<p>But the new data suggests a longer pre-industrial baseline, based on temperature data spanning the year 13 to 1700, the study published in the journal Nature Geoscience said.</p>

<p>Either way, 2024 is certain to be the warmest year on record.</p>

<h3><strong>SUPERCHARGED HURRICANES</strong></h3>

<p>Not only is ocean warming fuelling stronger Atlantic storms, it is also causing them to intensify more rapidly, for example, jumping from a Category 1 to a Category 3 storm in just hours.</p>

<p>Growing evidence shows this is true of other ocean basins.</p>

<p>Hurricane Milton needed only one day in the Gulf of Mexico in October to go from tropical storm to the Gulf's second-most powerful hurricane on record, slamming Florida's west coast.</p>

<p>Warmer air can also hold more moisture, helping storms carry and eventually release more rain. As a result, hurricanes are delivering flooding even in mountain towns like Asheville, North Carolina, inundated in September by Hurricane Helene.</p>

<h3><strong>WILDFIRE DEATHS</strong></h3>

<p>Global warming is drying waterways and sapping moisture from forests, creating conditions for bigger and hotter wildfires from the U.S. West and Canada to southern Europe and Russia's Far East creating more damaging smoke.</p>

<p>Research published last month in Nature Climate Change calculated that about 13% of deaths associated with toxic wildfire smoke, roughly 12,000 deaths, during the 2010s could be attributed to the climate effect on wildfires.</p>

<h3><strong>CORAL BLEACHING</strong></h3>

<p>With the world in the throes of a fourth mass coral bleaching event — the largest on record&nbsp; — scientists fear the world's reefs have passed a point of no return.</p>

<p>Scientists will be studying bleached reefs from Australia to Brazil for signs of recovery over the next few years if temperatures fall.</p>

<h3><strong>AMAZON ALARM</strong></h3>

<p>Brazil's Amazon is in the grips of its worst and most widespread drought since records began in 1950. River levels sank to all-time lows this year, while fires ravaged the rainforest.</p>

<p>This adds concern to scientific findings earlier this year that between 10% and 47% of the Amazon will face combined stresses of heat and drought from climate change, as well as other threats, by 2050.</p>

<p>This could push the Amazon past a tipping point, with the jungle no longer able to produce enough moisture to quench its own trees, at which point the ecosystem could transition to degraded forests or sandy savannas.</p>

<p>Globally, forests appear to be struggling.</p>

<p>A July study found that forests overall last year failed to absorb as much carbon dioxide from the atmosphere as in the past, due largely to the Amazon drought and wildfires in Canada.</p>

<p>That means a record amount of CO2 entered the atmosphere.</p>

<h3><strong>VOLCANIC SURGE</strong></h3>

<p>Scientists fear climate change could even boost volcanic eruptions.</p>

<p>In Iceland, volcanoes appear to be responding to rapid glacier retreat. As ice melts, less pressure is exerted on the Earth's crust and mantle.</p>

<p>Volcanologists worry this could destabilize magma reservoirs and appears to be leading to more magma being created, building up pressure underground.</p>

<p>Some 245 volcanoes across the world lie under or near ice and could be at risk.</p>

<h3><strong>OCEAN SLOWDOWN</strong></h3>

<p>The warming of the Atlantic could hasten the collapse of a key current system, which scientists warn could already be sputtering.</p>

<p>The Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC), which transports warm water from the tropics to the North Atlantic, has helped to keep European winters milder for centuries.</p>

<p>Research in 2018 showed that AMOC has weakened by about 15% since 1950, while research published in February in the journal Science Advances, suggested that it could be closer to a critical slowdown than previously thought.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jb3e9h3g_climate-change-global-warming-greenhouse-gas-emissions-pixabay_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The last global scientific consensus on climate change was released in 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-senate-democrats-rush-to-confirm-judges-before-donald-trump-takes-office-7005228]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Senate Democrats Rush To Confirm Judges Before Trump Takes Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-senate-democrats-rush-to-confirm-judges-before-donald-trump-takes-office-7005228]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:42:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Senate's Democratic majority began a crusade on Tuesday to confirm as many new federal judges nominated by President Joe Biden as possible to avoid leaving vacancies that Republican Donald Trump could fill after taking office on Jan. 20.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Senate's Democratic majority began a crusade on Tuesday to confirm as many new federal judges nominated by President Joe Biden as possible to avoid leaving vacancies that Republican Donald Trump could fill after taking office on Jan. 20.</p>

<p>With Republicans set to take control of the chamber on Jan. 3, the Senate is set on Tuesday to hold a confirmation vote on one of Biden's judicial nominees - former prosecutor April Perry - for the first time since Trump won the Nov. 5 presidential election. Perry was nominated by the Democratic president to serve as a U.S. district court judge in Illinois.</p>

<p>All told, Biden has announced 31 judicial nominees who are awaiting Senate confirmation votes, including Perry. She is one of 17 who already have been reviewed by the Senate Judiciary Committee and are awaiting a final confirmation vote by the full Senate. Another 14 nominees are awaiting committee review.</p>

<p>The U.S. Constitution assigns to the Senate the power to confirm a president's nominees for life-tenured seats on the federal judiciary.</p>

<p>"We are going to get as many done as we can," Democratic Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer said in a statement.</p>

<p>Trump made 234 judicial appointments during his first four years in office, the second most of any president in a single term, and succeeded in moving the judiciary rightward - including building a 6-3 conservative majority on the U.S. Supreme Court with three appointees.</p>

<p>Biden has appointed a host of liberal judges. Since the beginning of his presidency in 2021, the Senate has confirmed 213 Biden judicial nominees, including liberal Supreme Court Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson. About two-thirds were women, and the same share were racial minorities.</p>

<p>Senate Democrats are under pressure to swiftly confirm the remaining nominees, along with any new picks Biden may name in the waning weeks of his presidency.</p>

<p>How many nominees Senate Democrats will be able to confirm remains to be seen. Trump in a social media post on Sunday called on the Senate to halt approving Biden's nominees, saying, "Democrats are looking to ram through their Judges."</p>

<p>Billionaire Trump backer Elon Musk on Tuesday wrote on social media that "activist" judicial nominees are "bad for the country." Mike Davis, a Trump ally at the conservative judicial advocacy group Article III Project, in another post urged Senate Republicans to vote down all judicial appointments until January.</p>

<p>"The American people voted for monumental change," Davis wrote on social media last week. "Grind the Senate to a halt."</p>

<p>Current Senate Republican leader Mitch McConnell's office declined comment. McConnell has consistently opposed Biden's nominees and, as majority leader, was instrumental in getting Trump's previous nominees confirmed.</p>

<p>Trump's judicial appointees have been involved in major decisions welcomed by conservatives including Supreme Court rulings rolling back abortion rights, widening gun rights, rejecting race-conscious collegiate admissions and limiting the power of federal regulatory agencies.</p>

<p>Judicial nominees require a simple majority for confirmation. Democrats currently hold a slim 51-49 majority, meaning that they can ill afford any defections or absences if Republicans show up in force to oppose Biden's nominees during the chamber's post-election "lame duck" session.</p>

<p>West Virginia Senator Joe Manchin, an independent who caucuses with the Democrats, has said he would not vote for any nominee who does not garner at least one Republican vote. Must-pass legislation like a spending bill to avert a government shutdown also may consume precious time during the session.</p>

<h2><strong>'EVERY POSSIBLE NOMINEE'</strong></h2>

<p>Biden's allies have said a concerted push to confirm his remaining nominees would allow him to build on his legacy of helping to diversify a federal bench long dominated by white men.</p>

<p>He is not done nominating judges. On Friday, Biden announced his first post-election nominee, Tali Farhadian Weinstein, who after unsuccessfully running in the 2021 Democratic primary to be Manhattan district attorney was picked for a job as a federal district judge in New York.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Senator Dick Durbin, the No. 2 Senate Democrat and chair of the Judiciary Committee, said in a statement that he "aims to confirm every possible nominee before the end of this Congress."</p>

<p>White House spokesperson Andrew Bates on Monday noted that during Trump's first term, the Republican-controlled Senate confirmed 18 judges after Biden had won the 2020 election but before he took office.</p>

<p>Pending nominees include five to the influential federal appeals courts. Republicans said before the election that they had the votes to block two of them: Adeel Mangi, who would become the first Muslim federal appellate judge, and North Carolina Solicitor General Ryan Park, who unsuccessfully defended the race-conscious admissions policies before the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>There are an additional 26 picked by Biden to serve as trial court judges, including Perry, a former prosecutor now working at Chicago-headquartered GE HealthCare who would join the bench in Illinois. Biden nominated her to a judgeship in April after her prior nomination to become Chicago's top federal prosecutor was blocked by Republican Senator JD Vance.</p>

<p>Vance began placing a hold on Biden's nominees to the U.S. Justice Department in 2023 after Special Counsel Jack Smith secured the first of two federal indictments against Trump, who subsequently picked the senator as his vice presidential running mate.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/peo27eb8_us-capitol-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Senate is set today to hold a confirmation vote on one of Biden's judicial nominees]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-western-liberal-propaganda-of-choosing-not-to-have-children-7005007]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Bans "Western Liberal Propaganda" Of Choosing Not To Have Children]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-western-liberal-propaganda-of-choosing-not-to-have-children-7005007]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:51:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian MPs on Tuesday passed in the final third reading controversial legislation banning "propaganda" of choosing not to have children, the latest measure targeting what Moscow depicts as Western liberal ideas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian MPs on Tuesday passed in the final third reading controversial legislation banning "propaganda" of choosing not to have children, the latest measure targeting what Moscow depicts as Western liberal ideas.</p>

<p>Facing an ageing population and low birth rates, Moscow is seeking to reverse a demographic slump - accentuated by its military offensive on Ukraine - that threatens its economic future.</p>

<p>MPs in the Duma lower house of parliament voted unanimously in favour of the draft bill, which would apply to materials online, in media, advertising and in films that promote "rejection of childbearing".</p>

<p>The bill targets "destructive content" that promotes a "conscious" rejection of having children.</p>

<p>The bill's authors have said it will not be used as punishment for "a personal choice or lifestyle" but only for promoting such a lifestyle, although it is unclear how this would be differentiated in practice.</p>

<p>Violations would be punishable by fines up to 400,000 rubles ($4,000) on individuals and up to five million rubles for businesses. The bill also includes a provision to deport foreigners found guilty of disseminating the banned information.</p>

<p>"This is a fateful law... Without children, there will be no country. This ideology will lead to people stopping giving birth to children," the Duma's speaker Vyacheslav Volodin said ahead of the vote.</p>

<p>He also said the legislation was about "protecting citizens, primarily the generation growing up, from information spread in the media space that negatively affects the development of personality".</p>

<p>This is "so new generations of our citizens grow up orientated towards traditional family values", he said.</p>

<p>Nina Ostanina, a Communist Party MP who heads the Duma committee on family policy, said the bill aims to "guard our youth from unnecessary ideologies".</p>

<p>The legislation will now be considered by the upper house of parliament on November 20, before coming before President Vladimir Putin, who is expected to sign it into law.</p>

<p>It comes on top of existing bans on "propaganda" of LGBTQ relationships or changing gender.</p>

<h2><strong>ADOPTION BAN</strong></h2>

<p>The Duma also unanimously passed legislation in the third reading banning foreigners living in countries that allow gender reassignment from adopting Russian children.</p>

<p>The bill is aimed at stopping Russian children from being able to legally change gender.</p>

<p>Moscow has long portrayed itself as a bulwark against liberal values, but that trend has hugely accelerated since the Kremlin launched its Ukraine offensive, further rupturing ties with the West.</p>

<p>The bill would ban adoption by citizens of countries that authorise "the change of sex by medical intervention, including with the use of medicine", or allow individuals to change their gender on official identity documents.</p>

<p>Since 1993, foreigners have adopted 102,403 children from Russia, Volodin said, warning that "Western policy towards children is destructive."</p>

<p>Russia previously banned all US adoptions in 2012 with a bill named after a Russian toddler who died of heat stroke in 2008 after his adoptive American father forgot him in a car.</p>

<p>Russia has created an inhospitable environment for LBGTQ people for years. In July 2023, it banned the "international LGBT movement" as extremist and made gender reassignment illegal.</p>

<p>Putin himself has repeatedly mocked people who have undergone gender reassignment as well as LGBTQ people.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-12/red-square-afp_650x400_61451303314.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia passed a law banning "propaganda" of childless lifestyles calling it "western liberal ideas"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-nigeria-guyana-and-brazil-for-g20-summit-next-week-7004967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi To Visit Nigeria, Guyana, And Brazil For G20 Summit, Next Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-nigeria-guyana-and-brazil-for-g20-summit-next-week-7004967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:42:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi will travel to Brazil to attend the annual G20 summit and to Nigeria and Guyana as part of a three-nation visit beginning November 16, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will travel to Brazil to attend the annual G20 summit and to Nigeria and Guyana as part of a three-nation visit beginning November 16, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>PM Modi's first destination will be Nigeria and it will be the first visit to the resource-rich African country by an Indian prime minister in 17 years.</p>

<p>From Nigeria, PM Modi will travel to the Brazilian city of Rio De Janeiro on a two-day trip beginning November 18 to participate in the G20 summit. India is part of the G20 troika along with Brazil and South Africa.</p>

<p>The prime minister will put forward India's positions on various issues of global importance and build on the outcomes from the G20 New Delhi Leaders' Declaration and Voice of the Global South Summits, the MEA said.</p>

<p>On the sidelines of the summit, PM Modi is expected to meet several leaders, it said.</p>

<p>Under its G20 presidency that ended on November 30 last year, India focused on a variety of issues like inclusive growth, digital innovation, climate financing and equitable global health access with an aim largely to benefit the Global South or the developing countries.</p>

<p>PM Modi will visit Nigeria from November 16 to 17 at the invitation of Nigerian President Bola Ahmed Tinubu, the MEA said.</p>

<p>"During the visit, the prime minister will hold talks to review the strategic partnership between India and Nigeria and discuss further avenues to enhance the bilateral relationship," it said.</p>

<p>He is also scheduled to address a gathering of the Indian community in Nigeria.</p>

<p>"India and Nigeria have been strategic partners since 2007 with growing economic, energy and defence collaboration. More than 200 Indian companies have invested over USD 27 billion in important sectors in Nigeria," the MEA said.</p>

<p>It said India and Nigeria also share a strong development cooperation partnership.</p>

<p>The prime minister's final destination will be Guyana. He will visit the island nation from November 19 to 21 at the invitation of President Mohamed Irfaan Ali, according to the MEA.</p>

<p>"This visit to Guyana will be the first by an Indian prime minister since 1968," it said.</p>

<p>In 2023, President Ali visited India as the chief guest at the 17th Pravasi Bharatiya Divas in Indore and he was awarded the Pravasi Bharatiya Samman.</p>

<p>"During the visit, the prime minister will hold discussions with President Ali, meet other senior leaders of Guyana, address the Parliament of Guyana and address a gathering of the Indian diaspora," the MEA said.</p>

<p>"In Georgetown, Guyana, the prime minister will also participate in the second CARICOM-India Summit and hold meetings with leaders of CARICOM member countries to further enhance India's long-standing friendship with the region," it said.</p>

<p>The Caribbean Community (CARICOM) is an intergovernmental organisation of 15 member states in the Caribbean region having the primary objective to promote economic integration and cooperation among the members.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/2dr9i44k_narendra-modi-wave-narendra-modi-india-flag-ndtv-file-photo_625x300_15_June_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi's first destination will be Nigeria, and then he will be visiting Rio De Janeiro. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insight-these-countries-offer-assisted-dying-or-are-considering-it-know-the-law-7004789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[These Countries Offer 'Assisted Dying' Or Are Considering It. How It's Done]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insight-these-countries-offer-assisted-dying-or-are-considering-it-know-the-law-7004789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:14:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain is to debate whether to legalise assisted dying for the terminally ill, potentially paving the way for the law to change. Below is a list of countries which allow people to choose to end their lives or are considering doing so.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>SWITZERLAND </strong>- Switzerland legalised assisted dying in 1942 on the condition the motive is not selfish, making it the first country in the world to permit the practice. Doctors can prescribe drugs and administer them or had them over for self-administration. A number of Swiss organisations such as Dignitas offer their services to foreign nationals.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>UNITED STATES</strong> - Medical aid in dying, also known as physician assisted dying is legal in 10 states: California, Colorado, Hawaii, Montana, Maine, New Jersey, New Mexico, Oregon, Vermont and Washington, plus the District of Columbia. Oregon was the first state to legalise it under a law which came into effect in 1997. It allows mentally competent patients who are terminally ill and with less than six months to live to ask for life-ending medication. People from outside Oregon may travel to the state to take advantage of the law.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>NETHERLANDS </strong>- The "Termination of Life on Request and Assisted Suicide (Review Procedures) Act" came into effect in 2002. A doctor is immune from punishment for euthanasia and assisted suicide where patients are experiencing "unbearable suffering with no prospect of improvement". Minors can request euthanasia from the age of 12 but require parental permission before the age of 16.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>BELGIUM </strong>- Belgium legalised medically assisted dying in 2002 for the terminally ill and for people experiencing unbearable suffering, which includes patients with psychiatric conditions. Since 2014, those under the age of 18 who are terminally ill are covered by the law as long as they have parental permission.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>CANADA </strong>- Canada introduced "Medical Assistance in Dying" in 2016 for those whose death was deemed to be "reasonably foreseeable". Five years later, the law was extended to permit people with a "grievous and irremediable" medical condition to request assisted dying. The country has delayed until 2027 a plan to extend medical assistance in dying to include those with a mental illness.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>AUSTRALIA </strong>- Voluntary assisted dying for the terminally ill or those with a condition that is causing intolerable suffering is legal in most Australian states, after being introduced first in Victoria in 2019. Doctors can prescribe medication for self-administration or administer them where required.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>SPAIN </strong>- Spain approved a law in 2021 which allows euthanasia and medically assisted suicide for people with incurable or debilitating diseases who want to end their life.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>GERMANY </strong>- Assisted dying had been legal in Germany until 2015 when the country outlawed its provision on an organised or commercial basis, effectively banning it in many cases. Five years later the country's top court ruled in favour of groups providing terminally ill adults with assisted suicide services, but lawmakers are yet to finalise new rules.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>FRANCE </strong>- Doctors in France have since 2016 been allowed to put a person who is close to death and in great pain into deep sedation, but not to administer life-ending medication. President Emmanuel Macron earlier this year backed new legislation which would allow assisted dying for those with incurable conditions and a bill was introduced in April, but elections in June and July interrupted the proposed law's progress.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>BRITAIN </strong>- A bill to allow terminally ill adults with six months or less left to live the right to end their lives was introduced to parliament earlier in October and will be debated on Nov. 29.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>IRELAND </strong>- A cross-party Irish parliamentary committee recommended this year that the government should legalise assisted dying in certain restricted circumstances. A majority of lawmakers in October voted in favour of "noting" the committee's findings. With a national election due on Nov. 29, it will be up to the next government to decide whether to consider proposing a new law.</li>
</ol>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/glaov5c8_graveyad-generic-grave-generic-grave-flowers-istock_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-disaster-relief-fund-for-vulnerable-countries-ready-to-disburse-7004717]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[COP29: Disaster Relief Fund For Vulnerable Countries "Ready" To Disburse]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-disaster-relief-fund-for-vulnerable-countries-ready-to-disburse-7004717]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:02:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A long-sought disaster relief fund to help vulnerable countries weather the storm of climate change will start handing out aid next year, officials at COP29 in Baku said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A long-sought disaster relief fund to help vulnerable countries weather the storm of climate change will start handing out aid next year, officials at COP29 in Baku said Tuesday.</p>

<p>"The fund for responding to loss and damage is ready to disburse funding," said executive director Ibrahima Cheikh Diong of Senegal as it was officially signed off in the Azerbaijan capital.</p>

<p>Its launch shows progress amid the tussle at COP29 between global North and South over climate finance.</p>

<p>The fund was agreed in a historic first at the last United Nations climate summit in Dubai last year to help developing countries rebuild in the wake of climate disasters.</p>

<p>Human-driven climate change is making floods, hurricanes and extreme weather events more ferocious and more frequent, scientists say. The nations of the South say they are the most impacted by the disasters, yet are the least responsible.</p>

<p>Mainly wealthy countries including Germany, France, the United Arab Emirates and Denmark have pledged to donate $722 million so far. Sweden was the latest nation to chip in, promising $20 million on Tuesday.</p>

<p>But the amount "doesn't come close to righting the wrong inflicted on the vulnerable" and "is roughly the annual earnings of the world's 10 best-paid footballers", said UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres.</p>

<p>"It does not even account for a quarter of the damage in Vietnam caused by Hurricane Yagi in September," he said.</p>

<p>The damage from climate disasters can run into the billions and there is barely enough cash set aside for loss and damage at present to cover just one such event, experts say.</p>

<p>Developing nations had been pushing for a disaster relief fund to recover from climate impacts for the last 30 years, and the agreement struck last year was hailed as a major diplomatic breakthrough.</p>

<p>The fund now has a director and a board -- where developing countries enjoy greater representation than other international funds -- and is headquartered in the Philippines' capital Manila.</p>

<p>It is temporarily under the aegis of the World Bank, a move many poorer countries opposed.</p>

<p>Some estimates suggest developing countries need over $400 billion annually to rebuild after climate-related disasters. One study said the global bill could rise to between $290 billion and $580 billion a year by 2030 and keep rising.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dd11amb4_cop29-climate-summit-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Its launch shows progress amid the tussle between global North and South over climate finance. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-unveils-its-second-5th-generation-fighter-j-35-looks-exactly-like-this-us-jet-7004553]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Unveils Its Second 5th-Gen Fighter, Looks Exactly Like This US Jet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-unveils-its-second-5th-generation-fighter-j-35-looks-exactly-like-this-us-jet-7004553]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:37:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's second fifth-generation stealth fighter jet is making a debut at its largest air show, taking centre stage at the event and becoming the second nation in the world after the US to have more than one fifth-generation fighter jet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's second fifth-generation stealth fighter jet is making a debut at its largest air show, taking centre stage at the event and becoming the second nation in the world after the US to have more than one fifth-generation fighter jet.</p>

<p>The Shenyang J-35 stealth fighter is a twin-engine, single-seater supersonic jet developed for multirole missions. J-35 is the second fifth-generation fighter China has developed after the J-20.&nbsp;</p>

<p>J-35's design is similar to the US Lockheed Martin F-35, the only difference is that the former is twin-engine and the latter has one engine. China is known for copying the design of several aircraft - The J-20 and the US F-22 Raptor are similar in design except for canards that are present in J-20, and the Chengdu J-10 also known as the "Vigorous Dragon" is similar to the US F-16.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="US F-22 Raptor (Left), China J-20 (Right)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9s4re0d_f22-j20_625x300_12_November_24.jpg" title="US F-22 Raptor (Left), China J-20 (Right)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>US F-22 Raptor (Left), China J-20 (Right)</em></p>
</div>

<p>Global Times, the mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party in a report said, "The aircraft could enhance the country's integrated combat capabilities."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"J-35A functions within both stealth and counter-stealth combat frameworks. Its mission focuses on gaining and maintaining air superiority, eliminating hostile fourth/fifth generation fighter jets and ground/surface air defence forces, as well as intercepting aerial hostile targets including fighters, bombers and cruise missiles," it said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i1j8rtds_f35-fighter-jet-f-35-lightning-ii-jet_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">US F-35 Lighting carrying out formation flying</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<h3><strong>'One Aircraft, Multiple Roles'</strong></h3>

<p>China plans to induct the aircraft into the Air Force and the Navy, similar to the US F-35 which has three variants - The F-35A for the Air Force, F-35B for the Marine Corps and F-35C for the US Navy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The F-35A can take off from an Air Force runway, the F-35B can hover and vertically land on amphibious attack ships of the Marine Corps and the F-35C, with a wide wingspan, is used for aircraft carrier landings by the US Navy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier this year, China's largest and heaviest aircraft carrier, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sea-trials-begin-of-chinas-new-aircraft-carrier-fujian-what-it-means-for-india-5599654">Fujian</a>, was out for sea trials. The conventionally powered aircraft carrier weighs over 80,000 tons and has the most potent aircraft launch system - EMALS or Electromagnetic Aircraft Launch System, which currently only the US operates on the USS Gerald R Ford, the world's largest operational aircraft carrier.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/hac7a7ro_fujian-_625x300_10_May_24.jpg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Fujian is China's third aircraft carrier</em></p>
</div>

<p>The US Department of Defence in a report on China's naval modernization and its implications, said "China may be developing a carrier-capable variant of its FC-31/J-31 fifth-generation stealth fighter to complement or succeed the J-15 on catapult-equipped PLA carriers. &nbsp;China reportedly is also developing a carrier-based airborne early warning (NAEW) aircraft, called the KJ-600, that is similar to the U.S. Navy's carrier-based E-2 Hawkeye AEW aircraft,82 and stealth drone aircraft."</p>

<p>The J-35 is reportedly a lighter version of the J-20. However, the combat capabilities of both aircraft remain unknown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The development of the J-35 fighter jet suggests that China is mirroring the US and aims to combat the latter in the Indo-Pacific. The inclusion in the air show suggests that J-35 is ready for deployment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Recently, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-us-new-missile-will-be-a-game-changer-in-indo-pacific-6421399">US deployed its new long-range air-to-air missile</a> that could potentially disrupt the balance of power in the region. &nbsp;The AIM-174B missile, onboard the US Navy's F-18 Super Hornet, as seen in many pictures, is known to have an operational range of approximately 400 km.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j3fpu9q_aim174b-missile_625x300_26_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<h3><strong>Other Attractions At The Air Show&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>At the Zhuhai air show, China also unveiled the world's first twin-seat variant of a stealth aircraft. The J-20s was under development for a few years and has broken the cover at the air show. China says the aircraft is a "heavy-duty radar-evading fighter jet with long-range operation and multifunction capabilities."</p>

<p>The J-20 fighter jets flew in a diamond formation at the air show. The Russian Su-57, also a fifth-generation fighter jet, participated in the event.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Russias Su-57 participated in the air show" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9211cga_su57_625x300_12_November_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Russias Su-57 participated in the air show" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Russia's Su-57 participated in the air show<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>The airshow will feature a dedicated drone zone for the first time. The Russia-Ukraine war has shown the world the growing relevance of drones on the battlefield and how it is being used extensively by Kyiv to counter the asymmetry in terms of military strength with Russia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China unveiled its '<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3285955/china-unveils-killer-whale-stealth-drone-ship" rel="noindex,nofollow">Killer Whale</a>' ship ahead of the largest air show. The dual diesel and electric propulsion ship is unmanned and can carry a range of weapons like rockets, anti-ship missiles and ship-to-air missiles. It can also allow take-off and landing of choppers at its helipad.</p>

<p>China's Killer Whale is not the first unmanned surface vessel developed by a country. Earlier this year, the US Navy completed its first deployment of four unmanned ships which spent over four months in the Pacific for sea trials. The unmanned surface vessels - Sea Hunter, Sea Hawk, Mariner and Ranger - departed Southern California in August 2023 and returned in January 2024.</p>

<p><strong>India's AMCA Program</strong></p>

<p>India is developing its 5.5 generation Advanced Medium Combat Aircraft which will have stealth capabilities and the Defence Research and Development Organization chief said the induction is expected by 2035.&nbsp;Air Force's latest induction, the Rafale fighter jet, is a 4.5 generation multi-role aircraft that is deployed in the north in Ambala, Haryana, and Hashimara in Assam.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While China has deployed the J-20 fighter jets close to the Line of Actual Control, experts have inferred that in the event of a conflict, standalone weapon systems like surface-to-air missiles, air-to-air missiles and air defence systems will play a huge role for the Indian Air Force to combat and outmanoeuvre the Chinese.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Watch:&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/india-to-induct-5-5-gen-stealth-fighter-jet-amca-by-2035-drdo-chairman-825552">'India To Induct 5.5-Gen Stealth Fighter Jet AMCA By 2035: DRDO Chairman</a></p>

<p>In August, DRDO showcased 40 indigenously developed advanced systems and technologies at the International Defence Aviation Exposition IDAX 2024 during the Tarang Shakti exercise at Tamil Nadu's Sulur. On India's first 5.5-generation stealth aircraft, Advanced Medium Combat Aircraft (AMCA), Chairman of the Defence Research and Development Organisation (DRDO), Dr Samir V. Kamat, said that India's first 5.5-generation stealth aircraft will be inducted by 2035. He further said that India is among the very few nations to develop stealth aircraft.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l4s3l568_china-j35_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The J-35 is reportedly a lighter version of the J-20.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-vows-to-cut-greenhouse-gas-emissions-by-81-on-1990-levels-by-2035-7004548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Vows To Cut Greenhouse Gas Emissions By 81% On 1990 Levels By 2035]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-vows-to-cut-greenhouse-gas-emissions-by-81-on-1990-levels-by-2035-7004548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:36:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK will aim to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 81 percent on 1990 levels by 2035, Prime Minister Keir Starmer announced Tuesday, as his government ramps up its ambitions on climate change.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK will aim to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 81 percent on 1990 levels by 2035, Prime Minister Keir Starmer announced Tuesday, as his government ramps up its ambitions on climate change.</p>

<p>The previous government in London committed in 2021 to curb such emissions by 78 percent over the same period compared to 1990.</p>

<p>Starmer unveiled the new target as he attended the beginning of the COP29 climate conference in Baku, Azerbaijan, where he is one of the only G20 leaders to show up.</p>

<p>The summit's start has been overshadowed by the re-election in the US of longtime climate change sceptic Donald Trump, as well as new warnings that 2024 is on track to break temperature records.</p>

<p>UK Labour party leader Starmer, who took power in July, told a press conference that Britain was "building on our reputation as a climate leader".</p>

<p>"I've had a series of meetings here at COP this week because this government recognises that the world stands at a critical juncture in the climate crisis," he said.</p>

<p>"There is no national security, there is no economic security, there is no global security without climate security."</p>

<p>The British leader insisted his government was not going to "start telling people how to live their lives" in order to meet the new emissions reduction target.</p>

<p>"We're not going to start dictating to people what they do," he added.</p>

<p>Starmer touted efforts already put in place by ministers to meet what he called an "ambitious" but "realisable target", including ending an effective ban on new onshore wind projects.</p>

<p>His Labour government has also said it will not issue any new oil and gas exploration licenses in the North Sea, and closed the UK's last coal power plant in September.</p>

<p>Starmer said that meant Britain was the "first G7 economy to phase out coal power", and that it was now prioritising renewable energy projects.</p>

<p>"Make no mistake, the race is on for the clean energy jobs of the future, the economy of tomorrow," he said.</p>

<p>"And I don't want to be in the middle of the pack. I want to get ahead of the game."</p>

<p>Environmental groups cautiously welcomed the new 2035 target.</p>

<p>Friends of the Earth's head of campaigns, Rosie Downes, called it "a step in the right direction but must be seen as a floor to the level of ambition not a ceiling".</p>

<p>"Deeper, faster cuts are needed to help avert the climate collision course we are on," she added.</p>

<p>"Furthermore, if these targets are to be credible, they must be backed by a clear plan to ensure they are met. The UK's existing 2030 commitment is currently way off course."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ertrc5kk_uk-pm-keir-starmer_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK will aim to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 81% on 1990 levels by 2035, PM Starmer said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-may-soon-bring-assisted-dying-law-lawmaker-explains-its-safeguards-7004474]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK May Soon Bring 'Assisted Dying' Law. Lawmaker Explains Its Safeguards]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-may-soon-bring-assisted-dying-law-lawmaker-explains-its-safeguards-7004474]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:23:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A proposed law allowing terminally ill adults in England and Wales to end their lives was published on Tuesday, setting out safeguards such as ensuring the approval of doctors and judges to try to ease concerns in Britain over its possible misuse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A proposed law allowing terminally ill adults in England and Wales to end their lives was published on Tuesday, setting out safeguards such as ensuring the approval of doctors and judges to try to ease concerns in Britain over its possible misuse.</p>

<p>The proposed law has polarised opinion and has split the governing Labour Party. Lawmakers will vote on the proposed law on Nov. 29, almost 10 years since parliament rejected an earlier bid to legalise assisted dying.</p>

<p>The Labour lawmaker who has proposed the new law, Kim Leadbeater, described it as "very robust", saying the legislation offers layers of safeguards to protect vulnerable people, who some critics fear might feel pressured to end their lives if assisted dying becomes legal.</p>

<p>Assisted dying would only be an option for mentally competent, terminally ill adults with six months or less left to live, as expected, under the proposed new law.</p>

<p>The other safeguards include two doctors confirming seven days apart that the person is eligible and has made their decision free from pressure, while a judge would then speak to one of those doctors before a 14-day period of reflection.</p>

<p>"This is just for terminally ill adults. It's not for anybody else. It's for people who are dying, and it is about shortening death rather than ending life," Leadbeater told BBC radio.</p>

<p>The bill would make it illegal to pressure or coerce someone into ending their life by assisted dying. The offence would be punishable by up to 14 years in prison.</p>

<p>Under current laws assisting suicide is punishable by up to 14 years in jail but Leadbeater argues that current rules do not reflect a shift in public opinion over the issue during the last 10 years.</p>

<p>Supporters of assisted dying say Britain is a laggard after Australia, Canada, New Zealand and some U.S. states legalised it under certain circumstances in recent years. It has been legal in Switzerland since 1942 and in the Netherlands since 2002.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said politicians will be able to vote with their consciences on the matter, rather than along party lines. He has supported changing the law in the past while health minister Wes Streeting has said he will oppose it.</p>

<p>Should the proposal, known as the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Members Bill, pass a first vote, it would kick off the formal process for a law change, subjecting it to further scrutiny and requiring approval by both the House of Commons and the House of Lords, the upper house of parliament.</p>

<p>In 2015, British lawmakers voted 330 to 118 against the second reading of proposed legislation to legalise assisted dying.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2ucce8rk_kim-leadbeater-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Labour Lawmaker Kim Leadbeater speaks during an interview about the Assisted Dying Bill in Westminster.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-expected-to-pick-south-dakota-governor-kristi-noem-as-chief-of-homeland-security-7004471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Expected To Pick Kristi Noem As Chief Of Homeland Security]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-expected-to-pick-south-dakota-governor-kristi-noem-as-chief-of-homeland-security-7004471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:22:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump was expected Tuesday to pick South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem to head the US Department of Homeland Security, a powerful post at the center of the incoming president's tough-on-immigration policies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump was expected Tuesday to pick South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem to head the US Department of Homeland Security, a powerful post at the center of the incoming president's tough-on-immigration policies.</p>

<p>Sources in Trump's transition team told US media including CBS News that he has decided on Noem, a longtime Trump loyalist who was once considered a strong contender to be the Republican nominee's running mate.</p>

<p>Joining Trump's cabinet would be a notable political rebound for Noem, who saw her stock plummet earlier this year when she released a memoir in which she recounted having shot dead an "untrainable" pet dog after a hunting excursion gone awry. Noem has said her action showed she was able to make tough choices.</p>

<p>Homeland Security is a sprawling organization with a budget topping $107 billion, about 15 times that of South Dakota, where Noem is in her second term as governor.</p>

<p>If confirmed as its secretary by the US Senate, the 52-year-old would oversee the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) along with protective security operations on the borders with Canada and Mexico, key agencies in any Trump plan for restricting immigration or deporting undocumented migrants.</p>

<p>DHS also controls the Federal Emergency Management Agency, which assists communities in times of natural disasters like hurricanes.</p>

<p>Trump himself has yet to confirm Noem's nomination. If accurate, it would be the latest quick pick as the Republican leader seeks to flesh out his cabinet.</p>

<p>He has already chosen former immigration official Tom Homan as the country's "border czar," tasking him with fulfilling his key domestic promise of mass deportations of undocumented migrants. The DHS secretary would be closely involved in any such operations.</p>

<p>The current homeland security secretary, Alejandro Mayorkas, was impeached in February by the Republican-majority House of Representatives, as Republicans successfully turned immigration and border security into a critical 2024 election issue. The Democratic-held US Senate rejected the effort to convict him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/omv10r7o_kristi-noem_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If confirmed by US Senate, Kristi Noem would oversee the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-startup-firefly-aerospace-valued-at-over-2-billion-in-latest-funding-round-7004371]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Space Startup Firefly Valued At Over $2 Billion In Latest Funding Round]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-startup-firefly-aerospace-valued-at-over-2-billion-in-latest-funding-round-7004371]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:06:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Firefly Aerospace has raised $175 million in a late-stage funding round led by RPM Ventures, valuing the space startup at more than $2 billion, it said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Firefly Aerospace has raised $175 million in a late-stage funding round led by RPM Ventures, valuing the space startup at more than $2 billion, it said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Venture capital firms have been investing strongly in rocket makers and satellite manufacturers, marking a shift in the investment trend for such capital intensive businesses, Seraphim Space said in a report last month.</p>

<p>Texas-based Firefly makes small and medium launch vehicles for commercial launches to the earth's orbit. It also offers on-orbit services through its Elytra line of orbital vehicles, providing hosting, rideshare, delivery and servicing missions.</p>

<p>The startup is preparing for its first mission to the moon, dubbed Blue Ghost, as part of NASA's Commercial Lunar Payload Service initiative later this year.</p>

<p>The Series D funding round at Firefly included existing investors as well as new entities, including GiantLeap Capital and Human Element.</p>

<p>Firefly intends to utilize the fresh capital to enhance the market reach of its Elytra spacecraft, transition to full-scale production of its Alpha rocket, and expedite the hardware qualification for newly developing vehicles.</p>

<p>The company said it was simultaneously preparing for multiple launches of the Alpha rocket under contracts with Lockheed Martin, L3Harris and NASA, among others, while collaborating with Northrop Grumman to develop a medium launch vehicle.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cm02g2v_firefly-aerospace-alpha-rocket-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Firefly Aerospace's Alpha rocket lifts off from the Vandenberg Space Force Base in California, US]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-methane-emissions-threaten-climate-goals-7004322]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Methane Emissions Threaten Climate Goals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-methane-emissions-threaten-climate-goals-7004322]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:56:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fast-rising methane emissions could undermine efforts to limit global warming by mid-century, prompting scientists and policymakers to urge aggressive action to curb output of the potent greenhouse gas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fast-rising methane emissions could undermine efforts to limit global warming by mid-century, prompting scientists and policymakers to urge aggressive action to curb output of the potent greenhouse gas.</p>

<p>Nearly 160 countries have pledged a 30% cut from 2020 methane emissions levels by the end of this decade.</p>

<p>Over the last five years atmospheric methane levels have risen at their fastest rate since record-keeping began in the 1970s, driven in part by natural sources, according to the 2024 Global Methane Budget report. &nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Here is why controlling methane emissions is so important:</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>HEAT-TRAPPING POWER</strong></h3>

<p>Methane molecules are more powerful than carbon dioxide (CO2) in trapping heat, meaning it takes fewer of them to cause the same amount of warming and reducing them can have a more immediate effect than reducing CO2.</p>

<p>Tackling methane also makes financial sense. United Nations analyses have found cutting methane emissions is likely cheaper than CO2 cuts for a comparable climate benefit.</p>

<p>While CO2 remains in the atmosphere for centuries, methane breaks down after about a decade - meaning it has less of a long-term impact on temperatures.</p>

<p>Scientists normally compare the overall warming effects of methane versus CO2 over a century, calculating that methane emissions are about 28 times worse than CO2 for global warming.</p>

<p>Over a shorter timespan of 20 years, however, methane is 80 times worse.</p>

<p>Methane has led to around 0.5 degrees Celsius of warming so far, or about one-third of the roughly 1.3 C of warming experienced to date since pre-industrial times.</p>

<h3><strong>SURGING EMISSIONS</strong></h3>

<p>Methane concentrations are rising faster than any other major greenhouse gas, with human activities driving at least two-thirds of global emissions, according to the 2024 Global Methane Budget.</p>

<p>That includes the agriculture sector, including rice farming and livestock, fossil fuel activities, and landfills and other waste.</p>

<p>The report, published every five years, found methane emissions from these human activities have risen overall by 20% over the last two decades.</p>

<p>Most of the methane mitigation efforts under way, including EU legislation, are focused on the oil and gas sector, where the emissions are easier to tackle than in agriculture, according to the food-focused investor initiative called FAIRR.</p>

<h3><strong>NATURAL SOURCES A CONCERN</strong></h3>

<p>The remaining third of the world's methane emissions comes from natural sources such as thawing permafrost, peat bogs and wetlands - and emissions could rapidly increase as temperatures rise.</p>

<p>Animals, including humans, are also a source of methane.</p>

<p>While it is easy to measure atmospheric methane, understanding where it comes from is crucial for tackling the problem.</p>

<p>By analyzing distinct isotope signatures in methane detected, scientists can investigate whether the the gas comes from biological sources or industry.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ofbtq81g_methane-emissions-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over the last five years atmospheric methane levels have risen at their fastest rate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/judge-delays-decision-in-trumps-new-york-criminal-case-to-november-19-7003958]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Judge Delays Decision In Trump's New York Criminal Case To November 19]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/judge-delays-decision-in-trumps-new-york-criminal-case-to-november-19-7003958]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:05:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The judge in Donald Trump's New York criminal case has delayed to November 19 a decision on potentially throwing out the US president-elect's conviction, the court said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The judge in Donald Trump's New York criminal case has delayed to November 19 a decision on potentially throwing out the US president-elect's conviction, the court said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump was convicted of 34 felony counts in May after a jury found he had fraudulently manipulated business records to cover up an alleged sexual encounter with a porn star ahead of the 2016 election.</p>

<p>Trump, due to be sentenced on November 26, may receive a reprieve if Judge Juan Merchan decides to dismiss the case following the Supreme Court's recent ruling on presidential immunity.</p>

<p>That landmark ruling saw the court, with a 6-3 conservative majority, decide that presidents have sweeping immunity from prosecution for a range of official acts committed while in office.</p>

<p>Ahead of the election, Trump's lawyers moved to have the case thrown out in light of the Supreme Court decision, a move that prosecutors have firmly rejected.</p>

<p>If Merchan throws out the case on that basis, there will be no sentencing of Trump, 78.</p>

<p>If he does not, Trump's legal team would almost certainly seek to oppose or delay any sentencing, insisting it would interfere with Trump's role as commander-in-chief once he is sworn in on January 20.</p>

<p>"The joint application for a stay of the current deadlines... until November 19, is granted," the court wrote in an email to parties in the case, seen by AFP.</p>

<p><strong>'A severe blow'</strong></p>

<p>An editorial in the Kansas City Star newspaper called for the judge in the case to "do what was once unthinkable -- force a president-elect to take the oath of office in a jail cell."</p>

<p>"The surreal scene, while certainly shocking for the rest of the free world to witness, would send an unmistakable message -- the rule of law still applies in America."</p>

<p>But Trump's former attorney general Bill Barr said that both the New York case as well as others around the country had been "plainly brought for political purposes (and) have now been extensively aired and rejected in the court of public opinion."</p>

<p>"Further maneuvering on these cases in the weeks ahead would serve no legitimate purpose and only distract the country and the incoming administration from the task at hand," he wrote.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly derided the case as a witch hunt, saying it "should be rightfully terminated."</p>

<p>Alongside the New York case, brought by state-level prosecutors, Trump faces two active federal cases, one related to his effort to overturn the 2020 election and the other connected to classified documents he allegedly mishandled after leaving office.</p>

<p>However, as president, he would be able to intervene to end those cases, and Jack Smith, the special counsel handling both cases, has reportedly begun to wind them down.</p>

<p>A Trump-appointed federal judge already threw out the documents case, but Smith had sought to appeal that decision.</p>

<p>"Trump's victory means he is unlikely to be held accountable for any of his alleged criminal misconduct," said former prosecutor Randall Eliason in an article on Substack.</p>

<p>"That's a severe blow to the ideal of the rule of law."</p>

<p>The New York conviction, coming just months before an election that Trump won convincingly, was one of several dramatic developments in the race for the White House.</p>

<p>In July, Trump survived an assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania when a bullet grazed his ear.</p>

<p>Later that month, President Joe Biden stepped aside as the Democratic Party's candidate following a disastrous performance against Trump in a televised debate.</p>

<p>That paved the way for Vice President Kamala Harris to become the first woman of color from a major US party to stand for president.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/862i9kmo_donald-trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Following his conviction, Trump was scheduled for sentencing on November 26. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/potential-for-life-found-on-uranus-moons-scientists-reveal-7003800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Potential For Life Found On Uranus' Moons, Scientists Reveal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/potential-for-life-found-on-uranus-moons-scientists-reveal-7003800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 20:45:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent analysis reveals that Voyager's encounter occurred during an intense solar storm, potentially skewing our perception of the Uranian system.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The planet Uranus and its five largest moons may not be the cold, lifeless worlds scientists once believed. Instead, they could have hidden oceans and even the potential to support life, according to new research.</p>

<p>Most of our knowledge of Uranus comes from NASA's Voyager 2 mission, which visited nearly 40 years ago. However, a recent analysis reveals that Voyager's encounter occurred during an intense solar storm, potentially skewing our perception of the Uranian system, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgk1333k0ypo" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>Uranus, an icy, ringed planet at the solar system's edge, is one of the coldest and most unusual planets due to its extreme tilt, making it appear as if it had been tipped over.</p>

<p>The latest findings reveal that Voyager 2's visit coincided with severe solar activity, which may have temporarily disrupted the planet's magnetic field and swept away atmospheric material. For decades, this led scientists to a possibly inaccurate view of Uranus and its moons, explained Dr William Dunn from University College London.</p>

<p>"These results suggest the Uranian system might be far more intriguing than we thought," Dr. Dunn said. "There may be moons there with conditions that could support life, possibly hiding oceans below their surfaces."</p>

<p>Linda Spilker, a young scientist on the Voyager team when the Uranus data arrived, now serves as the project scientist for the Voyager missions. She expressed excitement about the new findings, published in <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-024-02389-3">Nature Astronomy</a></em>. "It's thrilling to think there's potential for life in the Uranian system," she told BBC News. She added, "It's amazing that scientists are still uncovering new insights from data collected in 1986."</p>

<p>Dr Affelia Wibisono of the Dublin Institute of Advanced Studies, who was not involved in the research, described the findings as "very exciting," noting the importance of re-examining old data, as new discoveries may be hidden within them.</p>

<p>NASA is already planning a return mission to Uranus, the Uranus Orbiter and Probe, expected to launch in the next decade. Dr. Jamie Jasinski from NASA, who led the re-analysis of the Voyager data, noted that insights from the recent study will shape the design and instruments of this upcoming mission to ensure it can accurately capture data unaffected by solar interference.</p>

<p>NASA's probe is expected to reach Uranus by 2045 when scientists hope to determine if these remote, icy moons could indeed host life.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/e4dt663o_uranus-moon-miranda_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The latest findings reveal that Voyager 2's visit coincided with severe solar activity]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>