<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 15:38:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-ukraine-launched-missiles-drones-shot-down-over-kursk-region-6282869]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says Ukraine Launched Missiles, Drones Shot Down Over Kursk Region]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-ukraine-launched-missiles-drones-shot-down-over-kursk-region-6282869]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:46:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine lobbed missiles and drones at Russia's southwest region of Kursk overnight, the local governor said Wednesday, a day after pro-Kyiv forces stormed across the border with tanks and armoured vehicles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine lobbed missiles and drones at Russia's southwest region of Kursk overnight, the local governor said Wednesday, a day after pro-Kyiv forces crossed across the border with tanks and armoured vehicles.</p>

<p>"Two Ukrainian missiles were shot down by air defence systems in the Kursk region", regional governor Alexei Smirnov wrote on Telegram social media channel, adding that three drones were also destroyed.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Moscow's defence ministry said it had rushed its troops and aviation units to the border in Kursk after a morning raid by Ukrainian units -- the latest such attack in the conflict.</p>

<p>The incursion was carried out by some 300 troops, 11 tanks and more than 20 armoured vehicles, Russian authorities said.</p>

<p>Five people were killed throughout the day and some 28 wounded, Smirnov and local health authorities said.</p>

<p>Kursk sits just across from Ukraine's northeastern Sumy region.</p>

<p>Ukrainian drones also targeted residential buildings in the border regions of Voronezh and Belgorod, with damage but no casualties reported, local officials said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Combatants from Ukraine have made several brief incursions into Russia since the beginning of the conflict in February 2022, including by units of Russians fighting in support of Kyiv -- the Russian Volunteer Corps and the Freedom of Russia Legion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/f6l5m3t8_russia-shots-down-ukraine-drone_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Five people were killed throughout the day and some 28 wounded]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bangladesh-political-unrest-india-evacuates-embassy-officials-from-bangladesh-amidst-unrest-6282178]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Evacuates Embassy Officials From Bangladesh Amidst Unrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bangladesh-political-unrest-india-evacuates-embassy-officials-from-bangladesh-amidst-unrest-6282178]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:37:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has evacuated all non-essential staff and their families from its embassy and consulates in Bangladesh, sources have confirmed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has evacuated all non-essential staff and their families from its embassy and consulates in Bangladesh, sources have confirmed. The move comes after massive protests over job quotas forced Sheikh Hasina to quit as Bangladesh's prime minister and flee.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The High Commission continues to operate with a skeletal staff, while those who returned to India did so on a voluntary basis, sources said.</p>

<p>Despite the turmoil, principal officers, including the High Commissioner of India to Dhaka, remain at their posts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to sources, the evacuation occurred via commercial flights and the High Commission remains functional, with dedicated personnel maintaining essential operations amid unrest in the region. In addition to the High Commission in the capital, India has assistant high commissions or consulates in several other cities, including Chittagong, Rajshahi, Khulna and Sylhet.</p>

<p>The protests against the country's quota system for families of freedom fighters slowly turned anti-government, with demonstrators demanding Sheikh Hasina resign as Bangladesh's Prime Minister. Nearly 300 people were killed after authorities used force to disperse the crowd and quell the protests that spread across the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, who had been in power since 2009, resigned and fled the country after protestors stormed the Prime Minister's residence on Monday.</p>

<p>Hasina's plane landed at an airbase near Delhi on Monday evening. National Security Adviser Ajit Doval met with the former prime minister, who is expected to leave for the UK, where she may seek political asylum.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's army chief, General Waker-Uz-Zaman, announced Hasina's resignation in a broadcast on state television, stating that the military would form an interim government. The Bangladesh military has taken over the responsibility of guarding Dhaka's diplomatic neighbourhood, previously overseen by police. They are now responsible for securing the residences of ambassadors and foreign missions in the Gulshan and Baridhara zones.</p>

<p>Earlier on Wednesday, a special Air India flight, operated with an A321 Neo aircraft, took off from Delhi without any passengers and <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-indias-special-flight-to-bangladesh-dhaka-brings-back-205-people-to-delhi-6281258 ">returned with 199 adults and six infants</a> from Dhaka.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Air India will commence its scheduled operations to Dhaka, with two daily flights from Delhi. Other airlines, including Vistara and IndiGo, will also operate their services to Dhaka as per schedule.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Indian government has not issued any official statement on the evacuation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d3t8m64g_bangladesh-protests-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The move comes after massive protests over job quotas forced Sheikh Hasina to quit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/blog/the-complex-emotions-bangladesh-and-its-crisis-evoke-in-me-an-indian-6282978]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blog: The Complex Emotions Bangladesh And Its Crisis Evoke In Me, An Indian]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/blog/the-complex-emotions-bangladesh-and-its-crisis-evoke-in-me-an-indian-6282978]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 13:58:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alongside the term 'ghuspaithiye' and the range of emotions it evokes, there is a mix of empathy, pain, shared legacy, and a common love for Rabindra Sangeet - all experienced in varying degrees and at different times.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jaqe0q7_bangladesh_625x300_07_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The visuals from Bangladesh are disturbing, and the anger on the streets is palpable. They are reminiscent of scenes from Colombo just two years ago when the Presidential Palace was ransacked following then-President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's flight from Sri Lanka.</p>

<p>According to an <em>NDTV </em>report, "On Monday, protesters set fire to a temporary shed at the residence of Bangladesh's Prime Minister (now former). They also looted and vandalised Sheikh Hasina's official residence in Dhaka, smashed a statue of her father, Mujibur Rahman, with hammers, and set her party's offices ablaze as they celebrated her departure as Prime Minister."</p>

<p>Such visuals have been widely circulated and analysed by commentators in the last two days. I will refrain from commenting on whether Bangladesh is falling into the hands of radical Islamic groups or whether there was foreign involvement in the regime change on Monday.</p>

<p>My focus here is different. I want to explore the range of emotions that an average Indian has towards a country that has largely been a good neighbour. Alongside the term '<em>ghuspaithiye</em>' (which gained notoriety with the influx of immigrants right after 1947 of migrants from then-undivided Pakistan) and the range of emotions it evokes, there is a mix of empathy, pain, shared legacy, and a common love for Rabindra Sangeet-all experienced in varying degrees and at different times.</p>

<h2><strong>The '<em>Ghuspaithiye</em>' Sentiment</strong></h2>

<p>For people living in parts of Assam, Tripura, and the bordering districts of West Bengal and Bihar, the mass migration from then-East Pakistan (now Bangladesh) between 1948 and 1965 significantly impacted local demographics. The influx surged following the disturbances surrounding Bangladesh's birth in 1971. According to reliable estimates, there are nearly two crore Bangladeshis in India, with half of them settled in Assam and West Bengal alone.</p>

<p>Since then, the term '<em>ghuspaithiye</em>', or 'illegal immigrant', has become ingrained in the Indian psyche, especially in the context of Bangladesh. The attitude towards these immigrants has often been one of contempt, primarily driven by class bias. They are perceived as poor, persecuted, and a drain on scarce resources. Yet, they are not hated, likely due to another powerful sentiment towards Bangladeshis: empathy.</p>

<h2><strong>We Played A Role In Their Liberation</strong></h2>

<p>This sense of empathy arises from India's active role in Bangladesh's liberation from Pakistan after a bloody struggle. The partition of Pakistan was also seen by many Indians as a vindication of the belief that creating a nation-state based on religion was a flawed concept-a belief that had led to the partition of India in 1947. This sentiment has persisted, and occasional anti-India protests in Bangladesh are considered minor deviations from an otherwise well-behaved neighbour and are therefore mostly overlooked.</p>

<h2><strong>Pain Across the Border</strong></h2>

<p>Growing up in the 1980s and 1990s, my generation was frequently exposed to news about nature's fury in Bangladesh and its devastating toll. Reports from the November 1970 cyclone, one of the deadliest on record, indicated that nearly 5,00,000 lives were lost in then-East Pakistan. Another cyclone in 1985 killed 11,000 people, and one in 1991 claimed nearly 1,50,000 lives.<br />
These reports of widespread destruction frequently made us sad, and there was a sense of shared pain. Combined with empathy, this constituted a significant portion of the positive feeling we held towards Bangladesh.</p>

<h2><strong>They, Too, Love Their Rabindra Sangeet</strong></h2>

<p>A strong Bengali identity played a crucial role in East Pakistan's transition to Bangladesh. Following liberation, Rabindranath Tagore's Amar Sonar Bangla, penned in 1905, became the new country's national anthem. Rabindra Sangeet is as popular in West Bengal as it is across the border in Bangladesh. The beautiful Padma River that separates the two geographies has done nothing to diminish this shared legacy.</p>

<p>Since ties between India and Bangladesh have remained warm throughout Bangladesh's journey, the feelings and emotions described above have persisted. Hence the feeling of loss now as we see the widespread vandalism taking place on the streets of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>As the Indian government considers its stance and options amidst the current turmoil in Bangladesh, it must remain mindful of the shared legacy and common sentiments held by people across the border. It should, therefore, strive to ensure that Bangladesh remains a good neighbour for years to come. Not a tall ask given the long history of bonhomie between the two countries.</p>

<p><em>(Mayank Mishra is Consulting Editor at NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/peuc3j4_bangladesh_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tom-cruise-to-perform-deadly-stunts-for-olympics-closing-ceremony-6282445]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tom Cruise To Perform Deadly Stunts For Paris Olympics Closing Ceremony]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tom-cruise-to-perform-deadly-stunts-for-olympics-closing-ceremony-6282445]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:53:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two weeks after the unprecedented complexity of the opening ceremony along the River Seine, there are big expectations for the show to wrap up the Games.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With Tom Cruise widely predicted to engage in a death-defying stunt on the roof of the Stade de France, Sunday's Paris Olympics closing ceremony promises a memorable passing of the five rings flag to Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Two weeks after the unprecedented complexity of the opening ceremony along the River Seine, there are big expectations for the show to wrap up the Games.</p>

<p>The closing ceremony will be a much shorter affair and will take place -- in more traditional fashion -- at France's national stadium.</p>

<p>Artistic director Thomas Jolly has revealed it will combine "wonder" with "dystopia", suggesting some darker elements than the joyful and impertinent tone of the opening ceremony that drew a record audience of more than a billion worldwide.</p>

<p>Offering a sneak peak to journalists recently, Jolly said he saw the Games as a "fragile monument" and wanted to imagine what would happen if they "disappeared and someone was rebuilding them in a distant future".</p>

<p>One sequence features "travellers from another space-time who arrive on Earth and discover vestiges from the history of the Olympics", with acrobats restoring the famous five rings of the Games.</p>

<p>It will reportedly feature more than 100 dancers, circus artists and other performers, with the promise of aerial displays, giant sets and spectacular lighting.</p>

<h3><strong>Destination Hollywood&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The opening ceremony featured some huge stars including <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/paris-olympics-2024-lady-gaga-celine-dion-add-sparkle-to-opening-ceremony-6199213" target="_blank">Lady Gaga, Celine Dion</a> and Aya Nakamura, but some big celebrities are also expected Sunday.</p>

<p>Cruise has been at several Olympic events and the most daredevil of Hollywood stars would be a natural connection between Paris and the 2028 Los Angeles Games.</p>

<p>US media have reported that Cruise has been preparing a spectacular stunt to pick up the Olympic flag and transfer it to LA, with video sequences already filmed on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>

<p>There have been no shortage of Hollywood stars in attendance for the Games who might also play a role, including Snoop Dogg, Eva Mendes, Ryan Gosling and Sharon Stone.</p>

<p>There are unconfirmed rumours that Beyonce -- a fervent supporter of the US team on social media -- may perform.</p>

<p>Two of France's biggest musical exports -- Air and Phoenix -- are already lined up to play, according to Le Parisien newspaper.</p>

<p>Organisers will be anxious to avoid a repeat of the controversy sparked by the opening ceremony, which featured drag queens in a sequence that some Christians and conservatives thought mocked the Biblical story of The Last Supper.</p>

<p>Organisers insisted it was a reference to Greek gods&gt; But Jolly and other members of the team have since been victims of social media harassment, triggering police investigations and condemnation from French President Emmanuel Macron.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/q9mp491g_tom-cruise_625x300_13_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The closing ceremony will be a much shorter affair and will take place in more traditional fashion (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-cities-are-growing-upward-than-outward-says-satellite-study-6282438]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Cities Are Growing Upward Than Outward, Says Satellite Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-cities-are-growing-upward-than-outward-says-satellite-study-6282438]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:44:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cities are increasingly growing upward instead of outward, with Asian cities leading the way. Previously, cities expanded by occupying more territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A city usually starts as a small town and grows in area after new buildings are made and boundaries are extended. However, in recent times, taller buildings are seen as one of the elements of any modern city. Now, a new study has revealed that cities are soaring upward at a greater rate than they are spreading out. This new finding can reshape how we use our resources and the environment.</p>

<p>The satellite study, published in the journal<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44284-024-00100-1"><em> Nature Cities,</em></a> was conducted by a team of Earth scientists, environmental engineers and geomaticists. The team studied two types of satellite data by measuring the footprint and height of buildings or more than 1,500 cities globally from the 1990s to the 2010s. One kind displayed a city's footprint, making it possible to calculate its size in two dimensions. The second kind, which used microwaves, made it possible to estimate city expansion in three dimensions and took skyscraper construction into account for upward growth.</p>

<p>According to the study, cities are increasingly growing upward instead of outward, with Asian cities leading the way. Previously, cities expanded by occupying more territory.</p>

<p>David Wilson, a professor of geography at the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, said that the study is "extremely interesting" and the change from horizontal to vertical growth in urban areas has both pros and cons.</p>

<p>"This trend is very positive for promoting sustainability and resource management. Less blocks, neighbourhoods, and communities will require the hand of government to reach out and expend scarce resources for policing, fire protection, and provision of housing services," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/cities-growth-urban-taller-skyscrapers-wider-population-1933969#:~:text=According%20to%20the%20researchers%2C%20this,land%20prices%20and%20economic%20development."><em>Newsweek</em></a>.</p>

<p>He added, "At the same time, the prognosis for fostering equity in the city is grim. Dramatic increases in vertical development, especially in mega-cities, often signal the realities of downtown gentrification kicking into hyperdrive, a notorious process for displacing and further isolating the poor and the stigmatized."</p>

<p>According to the study, larger cities with a population of more than 10 million people are at the forefront of the vertical transition.</p>

<p>In recent decades, China's urban growth has experienced a remarkable transformation. Wide outward growth was the initial hallmark, but more recently, taller structures are displacing shorter ones as vertical development has taken hold. Nonetheless, Europe's urban growth patterns have not changed much, with outward growth continuing to predominate and vertical development growing at a very slow rate.</p>

<p>Fast upward growth was rare in the 1990s but considerably more typical by the 2010s. Rapid outward development, on the other hand, declined throughout this time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/92r05jtg_worlds-cities-are-growing-upward-than-outward-says-satellite-study_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cities with a population of more than 10 million are at the forefront of this development.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/tiktok-maker-bytedance-launches-text-to-video-ai-app-rivaling-openais-sora-6282300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[TikTok Maker ByteDance Launch Text-To-Video AI App, Rivals OpenAI's Sora]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/tiktok-maker-bytedance-launches-text-to-video-ai-app-rivaling-openais-sora-6282300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:24:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The launch of a text-to-video model by the parent of short video app firm TikTok follows a series of similar model releases in recent months in China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ByteDance has expanded its offering of a software that can generate videos based on text prompts, joining a growing number of Chinese tech firms entering an emerging market also targeted by ChatGPT creator OpenAI.</p>

<p>Since Microsoft-backed OpenAI unveiled in February its text-to-video model Sora, which is not open for public use yet, Chinese companies have rapidly developed similar tools, with several launching models accessible to users.</p>

<p>Jimeng AI, developed by ByteDance-owned Faceu Technology, is now available on the Apple App Store for Chinese users, Reuters' checks showed on Tuesday, following its release on Android on July 31.</p>

<p>The launch of a text-to-video model by the parent of short video app firm TikTok follows a series of similar model releases in recent months in China.</p>

<p>Kuaishou, one of China's largest video apps, opened its Kling AI text-to-video model to a global audience late last month. Its beta version is accessible worldwide, requiring only an email address for registration.</p>

<p>Chinese AI startup Zhipu AI also introduced its video-generating model Ying last month, and days after its launch another startup, Shengshu, officially launched its Vidu app.</p>

<p>Faceu Technology operates under ByteDance's Jianying business, which is best known for its video editing app CapCut.</p>

<p>Jimeng AI offers subscriptions at 69 yuan ($9.65) monthly, 79 yuan for a single month, or 659 yuan annually. Each plan allows users to create about 2,050 images or 168 AI videos per month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ejeqohqo_bytedance_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[TikTok has been banned in India since January 2021]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-becoming-like-syria-sheikh-hasinas-son-to-ndtv-6282297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Attacking Temples, Parliament...": Sheikh Hasina's Son On Bangladesh Turmoil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-becoming-like-syria-sheikh-hasinas-son-to-ndtv-6282297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:23:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina son has expressed concern over the attacks on his mother's party leaders and minorities in the country amid massive political turmoil.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina son has expressed concern over the attacks on his mother's party leaders and minorities in the country amid massive political turmoil.</p>

<p>Twenty bodies of Awami League leaders have been found across Bangladesh after Sheikh Hasina left the nation, following violent protests by students over giving job quota to freedom fighters' children.</p>

<p>"All our MPs and ministers homes have been burnt. I will ask for the Indian government's help in ensuring their safety," Sajeeb Wazed Joy told NDTV in an exclusive conversation.</p>

<p>"This is not a political movement. If this is a political movement why are they killing people," he said.</p>

<p>Right groups and community leaders have claimed that scores of Hindu temples, business establishments and temples in Bangladesh have been vandalised by violent mobs after the fall of Sheikh Hasina government.</p>

<p>"When Jamaat-e-Islami was in power last time, there were attacks on minorities regularly. Those have resumed. Burning, looting, killing people. Vandalising temples and parliament. The images you are seeing is not of democratic protesters, these are images of violent mob," Mr Joy said.</p>

<p>On being asked, what the future of Bangladesh looks like, Sajeeb Wazed Joy said Bangladesh runs the risk of becoming like Syria.&nbsp;"I wanted to say Pakistan, but It looks more like Bangladesh is becoming like Syria."</p>

<p>"They (people of Bangladesh) have made their future. They will have to live with it. It's going to be bleak, economic growth is going to stop, militancy will continue," he said.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus has been named the head of the military-backed interim government after the ouster of Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina - the daughter of Bangladesh's founding father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman - was given a 45-minute ultimatum to step down as the Prime Minister on Monday, it is learnt.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina left state capital Dhaka in a military aircraft for India after resigning. Foreign Minister S Jaishankar yesterday said the government is giving time to Sheikh Hasina to "recover" and let them know about her next move. "At very short notice, she requested approval to come for the moment to India. We simultaneously received a request for flight clearance from the Bangladesh authorities," he said.</p>

<p>Sources had earlier said wanted to go to London to claim sanctuary, but her son Sajeeb Wazed has dismissed the speculation.</p>

<p>Asked about multiple reports about UK's "silence" her request for asylum and revocation of her visa by the US, Mr Joy said, "The reports about her requesting asylum are incorrect. She has not requested asylum anywhere. So the question of UK or US not responding yet is not true".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8c86snag_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina son has expressed concern over the attacks on minorities in Bangladesh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-sues-group-over-illegal-ad-boycott-that-cost-billions-6282278]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X Sues Group Over "Illegal" Ad Boycott That Cost Billions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-sues-group-over-illegal-ad-boycott-that-cost-billions-6282278]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:20:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X Corp. filed a lawsuit accusing an industry group of violating antitrust laws for an advertising boycott that cost the social media company billions of dollars.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X Corp. filed a lawsuit accusing an industry group of violating antitrust laws for an advertising boycott that cost the social media company billions of dollars.</p>

<p>The lawsuit, filed Tuesday in federal court in Texas, claims the Global Alliance for Responsible Media coordinated the boycott by advertisers in 2022 under the guise of concern about whether X, formerly known as Twitter, would adhere to certain "brand safety" standards for content on the platform after Musk acquired it for $44 billion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"To put it simply, people are hurt when the marketplace of ideas is undermined and some viewpoints are not funded over others as part of an illegal boycott," X Chief Executive Officer Linda Yaccarino said in a post on the platform. "This behavior is a stain on a great industry, and cannot be allowed to continue."</p>

<p>Outcry over unchecked antisemitic content and commentary on X - some of it endorsed by Musk - sparked many big advertisers including Apple Inc. and Walt Disney Co. to pull ads from the platform. And Musk has opposed government efforts to control toxic posts on social media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The lawsuit by X comes as House Republicans and conservative media outlets have ramped up scrutiny of GARM, which counts among its more than 100 members advertisers including Procter &amp; Gamble Co. and Unilever Plc.</p>

<p>GOP lawmakers have accused the group of violating antitrust laws, and the lawsuit cites a July report from the House Judiciary Committee accusing GARM of depriving conservative media outlets of ad revenue from its members.<br />
GARM didn't immediately return a request for comment.</p>

<p>In its 2022 annual report, the industry group said it had helped establish common definitions, metrics and tools to aid brands and their advertising partners in ensuring their ads don't appear alongside content they may find problematic.</p>

<p>In its lawsuit, X claimed the group's actions represent a "naked restraint of trade."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Collective action among competing advertisers to dictate brand safety standards to be applied by social media platforms shortcuts the competitive process and allows the collective views of a group of advertisers with market power to override the interest of consumers," X said in its complaint.</p>

<p>Musk, the world's richest person, is a self-proclaimed champion of free speech on his social media platform and has pursued other legal challenges connected to allegations of lax moderation of toxic posts, though with mixed success.</p>

<p>Rumble, a video-sharing platform, said it would file a lawsuit of its own against GARM and the World Federation of Advertisers in Texas federal court that raises the same allegations as X.</p>

<p>The case is X v. World Federation of Advertisers, 7:24-cv-00114, US District Court, Northern District of Texas (Wichita Falls).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2g3ien7o_x_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-delays-spacex-iss-mission-as-boeing-starliner-faces-issues-6282244]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Delays SpaceX ISS Mission As Boeing Starliner Faces Issues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-delays-spacex-iss-mission-as-boeing-starliner-faces-issues-6282244]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:18:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA on Tuesday postponed the departure of astronauts bound for the International Space Station on a SpaceX flight due to ongoing issues with Boeing's Starliner spacecraft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA on Tuesday postponed the departure of astronauts bound for the International Space Station on a SpaceX flight due to ongoing issues with Boeing's Starliner spacecraft.</p>

<p>The Starliner, which brought two NASA astronauts aboard the ISS in early June, has been docked for the past two months due to anomalies detected in its propulsion system during its flight, with the mission's return date increasingly uncertain.</p>

<p>The SpaceX flight was supposed to carry out the next group of four ISS crew members, dubbed Crew-9, in mid-August, to relieve the current foursome known as "Crew-8" currently aboard the space station.</p>

<p>Given the stranding of the two additional astronauts, however, NASA has had to devise a plan to find another way to bring them back to Earth.</p>

<p>The Crew-9 flight, now scheduled to lift off by September 24 at the earliest, could bring back the two stranded astronauts and only two Crew-8 members, giving Boeing more time to fix issues with its spacecraft.</p>

<p>"This adjustment allows more time...to finalize return planning for the agency's Boeing Crew Flight Test currently docked to the orbiting laboratory," the US space agency said in a blog post.</p>

<p>The Starliner, which also had helium leaks detected during its voyage, could also return unmanned if safety issues are not resolved.</p>

<p>"NASA and Boeing continue to evaluate the spacecraft's readiness, and no decisions have been made regarding Starliner's return," the post continued.</p>

<p>NASA was planning a press conference on Wednesday to provide updates on both Crew-9 and the Starliner spacecraft.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/hfvf4i68_boeing-starliner_625x300_25_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The SpaceX flight was supposed to carry out the next group of four ISS crew members (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-dont-stain-dreams-bangladesh-band-after-singer-home-instruments-burnt-6282172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Don't Stain Dreams": Bangladesh Band After Singer Home, Instruments Burnt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-dont-stain-dreams-bangladesh-band-after-singer-home-instruments-burnt-6282172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:09:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rahul Ananda and his family members managed to escape unharmed, but a huge number of musical instruments were reduced to ash as rioters set fire to the house.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"Don't stain dreams"</p>

<p>This was the message by Joler Gaan, a Bangladeshi folk band, after a violent mob attacked its singer Rahul Ananda's home in Dhaka's Dhanmondi Monday. While Rahul Ananda and his family members managed to escape unharmed, a huge number of musical instruments -- 3000 by some estimates -- were reduced to ash as rioters set fire to the house.</p>

<p>The incident of arson comes amid a spate of mob violence in Bangladesh after Sheikh Hasina resigned as Prime Minister and fled the country. With the Awami League government toppled and the new interim dispensation backed by the Army yet to take charge, mob violence is being reported in several areas of the country.</p>

<p>Hindu organisations have said homes, businesses and temples of the minority community have been targeted. Top leaders, including senior BNP leader and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia's son Tarique Rahman, have appealed for peace.</p>

<p>In its Facebook post, Joler Gaan has said Rahul Ananda's home was not just his residence, but a space where numerous songs were composed. "It was Joler Gaan's official studio. Musical discussions, recording, mixing, editing, everything happened there," the group has said in a post in Bengali.</p>

<p>The gates of Rahul Ananda's home, the post said, were always open so that anyone could meet him. It is worth noting that French President Emmanuel Macron visited the musician's home during his Bangladesh trip last year. And this, too, found a mention in the social media post after the attack.</p>

<p>"Do the instruments belong to just Joler Gaan? No. This is an attempt for all young musicians who believe that we can make our own instruments. It is because of these instruments that people of this country can proudly say these sounds are only heard in Bangladesh. It is this glimpse of a dream that draws another musician from far-off France," the post reads.</p>

<p>It said Rahul Ananda and his family members managed to escape in time and are safe. "But all instruments of our band, documents, Rahul da's furniture have turned to ash. Maybe this chilling memory will stay with his 13-year-old son, Lalit for life. A home built bit by bit burning in the fire of some people's rage and revenge!"</p>

<p>The group said they would again build their collection of instruments from scratch. "But how do we put off this fire of revenge? Why can't we win everything over with love? We welcome the dream for the future, but our celebration must not break someone else's dream."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/u8kd3rj_bangladesh-singer_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joler Gaan shared a video of the last song recorded at the now-burnt home]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-leaders-of-sheikh-hasinas-party-found-dead-as-bangladesh-protests-continue-10-points-6282150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[20 Leaders Of Sheikh Hasina's Party Found Dead As Bangladesh Protests Continue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-leaders-of-sheikh-hasinas-party-found-dead-as-bangladesh-protests-continue-10-points-6282150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:01:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Twenty bodies of Awami League leaders have been found across Bangladesh after ex Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina left the nation, following violent protests by students over giving job quota to freedom fighters' children. Hindus have been targetted too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Widespread vandalism and looting of homes and businesses of Awami League leaders and activists have been reported from across Bangladesh, the Dhaka Tribune reported.</li>
	<li>Eyewitnesses said the house of former councillor Md Shah Alam in Comilla city, 100 km from the capital Dhaka, was set on fire by a mob. Four people were killed on Tuesday when a mob set on fire the house of MP Shafiqul Islam Shimul. Their bodies were found in rooms and balconies.</li>
	<li>In Dhaka, parts of the Awami League's main office were set on fire again on Tuesday. It was first burned down at 12.30 pm on Monday.</li>
	<li>Across Bangladesh, Awami League leaders and minorities such as Hindus have become the main targets of the mainly Muslim-majority mobs.</li>
	<li>Rights groups and diplomats in Bangladesh have raised concerns at reports of attacks on minorities, including Hindus. Some businesses and homes owned by Hindus -- a group seen by some in the Muslim-majority nation as having been close to ousted leader Sheikh Hasina -- were attacked.</li>
	<li>"Houses and shops of minority people were attacked, vandalised and looted, at least 97 places on Monday and Tuesday," Rana Dasgupta, general secretary of Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council, said in a statement. The group said at least 10 Hindu temples were attacked by "miscreants" on Monday.</li>
	<li>One Hindu man was beaten to death in Bangladesh's southern Bagerhat district, said a hospital official who requested anonymity due to safety concerns, news agency AFP reported.</li>
	<li>Horror unfolded when 24 people were killed after a mob set fire to the Zabeer International Hotel in Khulna division. The hotel is owned by Shahin Chakladar, the General Secretary of Jashore district Awami League. "The bodies were lying on different floors," said Mamun Mahmud, Deputy Director of Khulna Fire Service.</li>
	<li>Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus will lead an interim government, the presidency announced today.</li>
	<li>The decision was made in a meeting with President Mohammed Shahabuddin, the heads of the army, navy and air force, and student leaders. "(They) decided to form an interim government with Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus as its chief," Mr Shahabuddin's office said in a statement.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>With inputs from IANS</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1323lctg_bangladesh_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smoke billows near burnt Awami League party office as anti-government protestors set fire in Dhaka]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/namal-rajapaksa-announced-as-candidate-for-sri-lankan-presidency-6282026]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Namal Rajapaksa Announced As Candidate For Sri Lankan Presidency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/namal-rajapaksa-announced-as-candidate-for-sri-lankan-presidency-6282026]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:59:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Namal Rajapaksa, the 38-year-old heir to the Rajapaksa dynasty, was on Wednesday named as the SLPP candidate for the presidential election, thus officially ending Rajapaksa family's backing to the incumbent Ranil Wickremesinghe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Namal Rajapaksa, the 38-year-old heir to the Rajapaksa dynasty, was on Wednesday named as the SLPP candidate for the presidential election, thus officially ending Rajapaksa family's backing to the incumbent Ranil Wickremesinghe.</p>

<p>Sagara Kariyawasam, the general secretary of the Sri Lanka People's Front (SLPP, also known locally by its popular Sinhalese name, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna), announced the younger Rajapaksa's candidacy early on Wednesday morning at a ceremony at the party headquarters.</p>

<p>Namal's entry has made the election a four-cornered contest. Besides, President Wickremesinghe, the main opposition leader Sajith Premadasa and the Marxist JVP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake are already in the fray.</p>

<p>The Rajapaksas – Mahinda, Basil and Gotabaya – were instrumental in Wickremesinghe winning the parliamentary vote in July 2022 to take over Gotabaya's remaining term.</p>

<p>It was soon after the unprecedented development of mid-April 2022 when the island nation declared its first-ever sovereign default since gaining independence from Britain in 1948 and almost civil war-like conditions followed as unrest spread amid locals over inflation and other economic stress that had led to Gotabaya's ouster.</p>

<p>Wednesday's development comes days after the SLPP lost nearly 100 of its MPs to Wickremesinghe after he announced his candidature as an independent.</p>

<p>Those MPs have condemned their party's decision to ditch Wickremesinghe but the SLPP, in turn, has vowed disciplinary action against those who back Wickremesinghe, defying the party decision.</p>

<p>Namal was a late decision from the party. The favoured candidate, business tycoon Dhammika Perera, on Tuesday told the party he was unable to contest due to personal reasons, sources said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-11/6fqq615o_namal-rajapaksa-650_650x400_20_November_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Namal Rajapaksa's entry has made the election a four-cornered contest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-people-trapped-as-hotel-collapses-in-germany-on-river-moselle-6282034]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[9 People Trapped As Hotel Collapses In Germany]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-people-trapped-as-hotel-collapses-in-germany-on-river-moselle-6282034]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:52:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rescue efforts have proven to be extremely complex, according to a police statement. According to regional broadcaster SWR, emergency services have been unable to enter the building because of the risk of further collapse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several people have been trapped in a hotel near the banks of the river Moselle in Germany after parts of the building collapsed, local police said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Rescue efforts have proven to be extremely complex, according to a police statement. According to regional broadcaster SWR, emergency services have been unable to enter the building because of the risk of further collapse.</p>

<p>Local media said up to nine people could be trapped.</p>

<p>The Moselle region attracts tourists for its picturesque towns and vineyards on steep river banks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/h19hkd6g_germany-shooting-german-police_625x300_10_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Moselle region attracts tourists for its picturesque towns and vineyards on steep river banks (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-vice-presidential-pick-tim-walzs-long-history-with-china-may-prove-awkward-6282091]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' Vice Presidential Pick's History With China May Prove Awkward]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-vice-presidential-pick-tim-walzs-long-history-with-china-may-prove-awkward-6282091]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:51:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic vice presidential candidate Tim Walz has connections to China dating back decades that could help inform Kamala Harris's approach to the world's second-biggest economy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic vice presidential candidate Tim Walz has connections to China dating back decades that could help inform Kamala Harris's approach to the world's second-biggest economy, but may also spell trouble with leaders in Beijing and Republicans back home.</p>

<p>The little-known Minnesota governor taught English in China's southern Guangdong province in 1989 and 1990, making him the first person on a presidential ticket to have that kind of experience living in the country since George H. W. Bush, who served as US ambassador in Beijing in the 1970s. Walz has often spoken affectionately about China's people.</p>

<p>"If they had the proper leadership, there are no limits on what they could accomplish," he told a local newspaper after returning from China in 1990. "They are such kind, generous, capable people."</p>

<p>Walz got married on the fifth anniversary of the deadly 1989 Tiananmen Square military crackdown, with his wife Gwen telling a local newspaper "he wanted to have a date he'll always remember." He's also posted on social media that he had a "life-changing" lunch with the Dalai Lama, the Tibetan spiritual leader exiled by China.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/tbt?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#tbt</a> to 2 years ago, a life-changing lunch with <a href="https://twitter.com/DalaiLama?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DalaiLama</a>. We talked about humility, patience, and compassion. I try to embody these values every day in my work. <a href="https://t.co/UnaEyy0GOI">pic.twitter.com/UnaEyy0GOI</a></p>
— Tim Walz (@Tim_Walz) <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz/status/974392962833666048?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 15, 2018</a></blockquote>

<p>His interest in the country has also extended to policy-making, with Walz cosponsoring numerous pieces of legislation in the US House, including the Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act of 2017.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Walz also cosponsored numerous resolutions, including those condemning China's censorship of the killings in Tiananmen Square in 1989, and ones expressing concern about the treatment of Falun Gong practitioners.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With Walz appearing prominently on the national political scene for the first time on Tuesday, many on social media began poring over a long record of comments on China, some of them decades old.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">"If [the Chinese people] had the proper leadership, there are no limits on what they could accomplish. They are such kind, generous, capable people. They just gave and gave and gave to me."<br />
<br />
-1990 article on Tim Walz after he returned from teaching in Foshan, China. -Star-Herald <a href="https://t.co/DFcrBYFufX">pic.twitter.com/DFcrBYFufX</a></p>
— Eric Fish (@ericfish85) <a href="https://twitter.com/ericfish85/status/1820825142718501168?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"I don't fall into the category that China necessarily needs to be an adversarial relationship," Walz said in a video interview posted in 2016 that focused mainly on agriculture that is now being reposted on X. "I totally disagree, and I think we need to stand firm, on what they're doing in the South China Sea. But there's many areas of cooperation that we can work on."</p>

<p>At the same time, his views on China have tracked a familiar evolution from hope that an economic opening up would lead to greater political freedoms to frustration about what he's called China's worsening human-rights record. His positions appear largely in sync with the Biden administration approach to China, which aims to compete with Beijing in military and economic spheres, and cooperate where possible on climate or narcotics trafficking.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I think the idea was, with a free market economy, we'd see a more opening of the Chinese grip on - on social life and on human rights," Walz said in a congressional hearing in 2016. "That simply has not occurred."</p>

<p>Walz's stance toward China - and his past meeting with the Dalai Lama - may open him to criticism from Beijing. But a Chinese official, who asked not to be identified, said the choice of Walz is unlikely to impact US policy as American politicians are unified in their hardline views on China. In Beijing's view, every candidate believes untrue and harmful things about China, the official said.</p>

<p>On the other hand, some of the governor's more nuanced takes on the country from his trips could leave him open to Republican attacks during a tight race for the White House at a time when the China relationship is much more confrontational.</p>

<p>While China appears to be a personal issue for Walz, that's only good "to a point" and doesn't reflect the "zero-sum competition" between the US and China, said Michael Sobolik, a senior fellow at the American Foreign Policy Council and author of Countering China's Great Game: A Strategy for American Dominance.</p>

<p>"The Chinese people aren't Americans' enemies, and Walz understands that basic reality - on the other hand, Walz seems overly optimistic, almost Pollyannish, about Washington's struggle with the Chinese Communist Party," Sobolik said. "Like President Biden and Vice President Harris, Walz seems to reject a cold war framing for US-China relations. That's a bad thing."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Spokespeople for Walz didn't immediately respond to a request for comment on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"I lived in China, I've been there about 30 times," Walz said back in 2016. "But if someone tells you they're an expert on China they're probably not telling you the truth, because it's a complex country."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/35t22p6_tim-walz-kamala-harris-bloomberg_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tim Walz has often spoken affectionately about China's people.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ancient-egyptians-may-have-used-hydraulic-lift-to-build-pyramid-new-study-reveals-6281956]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Egyptians May Have Used Hydraulic Lift To Build Pyramid, New Study Reveals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ancient-egyptians-may-have-used-hydraulic-lift-to-build-pyramid-new-study-reveals-6281956]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:32:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new theory suggests that ancient Egyptians may have used a hydraulic lift system to build the Step Pyramid of Djoser, the oldest pyramid in Egypt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The construction of the pyramids of ancient Egypt has been a topic of debate among Egyptologists for years.&nbsp;Despite centuries of scrutiny, the exact methods used to construct these marvels of engineering remain shrouded in mystery.&nbsp;Now, a new theory suggests that ancient Egyptians may have used a hydraulic lift system to build the Step Pyramid of Djoser, the oldest pyramid in Egypt.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a fascinating study published Monday in the journal&nbsp;<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0306690#abstract0" target="_blank"><em>PLOS One</em></a>, researchers&nbsp;suggested that water played a crucial role in the construction process, potentially powering a hydraulic system that lifted massive stones into place from the very heart of the pyramid.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''Ancient Egyptians are famous for their pioneering and mastery of hydraulics through canals for irrigation purposes and barges to transport huge stones. This work opens a new line of research: the use of hydraulic force to erect the massive structures built by Pharaohs,'' the researchers wrote.</p>

<p>According to Smithsonian Magazine, the Step Pyramid of Djoser was constructed circa 2680BC as a majestic burial complex for the revered King Djoser, a pharaoh of the 3rd dynasty. This ancient marvel holds the distinction of being the oldest significant stone building in Egypt, as noted by Encyclopedia Britannica.</p>

<p>The researchers also said they found evidence of a unified water filtration and hydraulic system at the Step Pyramid that purified water from nearby canals and regulated its flow for practical uses.</p>

<p>Dr Xavier Landreau, of CEA Paleotechnic Institute, said, ''A series of compartments dug into the ground outside of the pyramid may have served as a water treatment facility, allowing sediment to settle as water passed through each subsequent compartment. Water may then have been able to flow into the pyramid shafts themselves, where the force of its rise could help carry the building stones.''</p>

<p>The team say further research is still needed to understand how water might have flowed through the shafts, as well as how much water was available on the landscape at that point in Earth's history.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, not all experts are convinced. Dr Judith Bunbury, a geoarchaeologist at the University of Cambridge, remains sceptical. In an interview with <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/did-ancient-egyptians-use-a-hydraulic-lift-to-build-the-pyramid-of-djoser/">Ars Technica,</a></em> Ms Bunbury pointed out that although ancient Egyptians did employ other hydraulic technologies, there's no concrete evidence to support the existence of a hydraulic lift system.</p>

<p>''While information from this period is sparse, it is not absent, and it is surprising when so many other details of daily life and technologies are recorded in the Old Kingdom tomb scenes and texts like the Red Sea Scrolls, that this type of device is omitted if it were in use,'' she told the publication.</p>

<p>Numerous speculative hypotheses have been proposed, including that they used ramps, levers, cranes, winches, hoists, pivots, or any combination thereof.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3d6bvep_egyptian-pyramids_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Researcherssuggested that water played a crucial role in the construction process]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-latest-attack-donald-trumps-son-eric-trump-calls-meghan-markle-spoiled-apple-6281839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Latest Attack, Trump's Son Eric Calls Meghan Markle "Spoiled Apple"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-latest-attack-donald-trumps-son-eric-trump-calls-meghan-markle-spoiled-apple-6281839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:28:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eric Trump, the son of former US President Donald Trump, has expressed his disdain for Prince Harry and Meghan Markle, suggesting his father may deport the couple, should he win the US presidential election come November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eric Trump, the son of former US President Donald Trump, has expressed his disdain for Prince Harry and Meghan Markle, suggesting his father may deport the couple, should he win the US presidential election come November.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You can happily have those two [Meghan and Harry] back. We'll happily send them back from America," Eric Trump said in an interview with <a href="https://www.gbnews.com/royal/meghan-markle-prince-harry-bad-apples-donald-trump-eric ">GB News</a> on Sunday. "You can have them back over here, but I'm not sure if you want them anymore. We might not want them anymore, it feels like they're on an island of their own."</p>

<p>He praised the royal family as a "beautiful" and "sacred Institute" but took a swipe at Meghan Markle's past career as a Hollywood actress, calling her a "spoiled apple" and saying, "You can always have bad actors in everything."</p>

<p>Eric Trump mentioned he held a deep admiration for the late Queen Elizabeth II, adding he and his father "had so much respect" for her. He fondly recalled his father's interactions with Queen Elizabeth during his presidency, from 2017 to 2021.</p>

<p>After her death in 2022, Donald Trump praised her "historic and remarkable reign" on his Truth Social platform. Eric Trump also shared a personal connection to the royal family, revealing that his late mother, Ivana Trump, "had a great relationship" with Princess Diana, Prince Harry's mother.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Eric Trump's recent comments insulting Prince Harry and Meghan Markle are not the first time the Trump family has publicly criticised the couple. His father, Donald Trump, has been vocal about his dislike for the couple, particularly Markle, whom he has accused of being "disrespectful" to the royal family.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March, Trump suggested that the royal couple, who have been living in California since 2020, may need to relocate due to Harry's admission of drug use in the US, as revealed in his memoir 'Spare'. The former US President stated that Harry should not have "special privileges" and that "appropriate action" must be taken if he lied on his US visa application.</p>

<p>Previously, at the CPAC in February, Donald Trump declared that he "wouldn't protect" Harry, calling him an "embarrassment" and stating that he "betrayed the queen". He also predicted that Harry and Meghan Markle's marriage would "end bad" in a 2022 interview with Piers Morgan.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/vbst8spg_eric-trump-meghan-markle_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Eric Trump took a swipe at Meghan Markle's past career as a Hollywood actress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-refused-to-suppress-protest-sealing-sheikh-hasinas-fate-6280790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Army Refused To Suppress Protest, Sealing Sheikh Hasina's Fate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-refused-to-suppress-protest-sealing-sheikh-hasinas-fate-6280790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:17:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The night before long-time leader Sheikh Hasina abruptly fled Bangladesh amid deadly protests, her army chief held a meeting with his generals and decided that troops would not open fire on civilians to enforce a curfew.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The night before long-time leader Sheikh Hasina abruptly fled Bangladesh amid deadly protests, her army chief held a meeting with his generals and decided that troops would not open fire on civilians to enforce a curfew, two serving army officers with knowledge of the discussions told Reuters.</p>

<p>Gen. Waker-Uz-Zaman then reached out to Hasina's office, conveying to the prime minister that his soldiers would be unable to implement the lockdown she had called for, according to an Indian official briefed on the matter.</p>

<p>The message was clear, the official said: Hasina no longer had the army's support.</p>

<p>Details of the online meeting between military top brass and the message to Hasina that she had lost their backing have not previously been reported.</p>

<p>They help to explain how Hasina's 15-year rule, during which she brooked little dissent, came to such a chaotic and sudden end on Monday, when she fled from Bangladesh to India.</p>

<p>The nationwide curfew had been imposed after at least 91 people were killed and hundreds injured in nationwide clashes on Sunday, the deadliest day since student-led protests against Hasina began in July.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Army spokesman Lt. Col. Sami Ud Dowla Chowdhury confirmed the Sunday evening discussions, which he described as a regular meeting to take updates after any disturbance. He did not provide details when presented with additional questions about decision-making at that meeting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina could not be reached and her son and advisor, Sajeeb Wazed, did not respond to repeated requests for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reuters spoke to ten people familiar with the events of the past week, including four serving army officers and two other informed sources in Bangladesh, to piece together the final 48 hours of Hasina's reign. Many of them spoke on condition of anonymity due to the sensitivity of the matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina, who has ruled Bangladesh for 20 of the last 30 years, was elected to a fourth term leading the country of 170 million in January, after arresting thousands of opposition leaders and workers. That election was boycotted by her main rivals.</p>

<p>Her iron-fisted grasp on power has been challenged since summer by protests triggered by a court ruling to reserve government jobs - heavily coveted amid high youth unemployment - for certain segments of the population. The decision was overturned but the demonstrations had quickly morphed into a movement to oust Hasina.</p>

<p>Zaman has not publicly explained his decision to withdraw support from Hasina. But the scale of the protests and a death toll of at least 241 made supporting Hasina at all costs untenable, three former senior Bangladesh army officers told Reuters.</p>

<p>"There was a lot of uneasiness within the troops," said retired Brig. Gen. M. Sakhawat Hossain. "That is what probably (put) pressure on the chief of army staff, because the troops are out and they are seeing what is happening."</p>

<p>Zaman, who is related to Hasina by marriage, had showed signs of wavering in his support for the prime minister on Saturday, when he sat on an ornate wooden chair and addressed hundreds of uniformed officers in a town hall meeting. The military later made some details of that discussion public.</p>

<p>The general declared that lives had to be protected and called on his officers to show patience, said army spokesman Chowdhury.</p>

<p>It was the first indication that Bangladesh's army would not forcefully suppress the violent demonstrations, leaving Hasina vulnerable.</p>

<p>Retired senior soldiers such as Brig. Gen. Mohammad Shahedul Anam Khan were among those who defied the curfew on Monday and took to the streets.</p>

<p>"We were not stopped by the army," said Khan, a former infantry soldier. "The army has done what he had promised the army would do."</p>

<p><strong>'SHORT NOTICE'</strong></p>

<p>On Monday, the first full day of the indefinite nationwide curfew, Hasina was holed up inside the Ganabhaban, or "People's Palace", a heavily-guarded complex in the capital Dhaka that serves as her official residence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Outside, on the streets of the sprawling city, crowds gathered. Tens of thousands of people had answered protest leaders' call for a march to oust the leader, streaming into the heart of the city.</p>

<p>With the situation spiralling out of her control, the 76-year-old leader decided to flee the country on Monday morning, according to the Indian official and two Bangladesh nationals familiar with the matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina and her sister, who lives in London but was in Dhaka at the time, discussed the matter and flew out together, according to a Bangladesh source. They left for India around lunch, local time.</p>

<p>Indian foreign minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar told parliament on Tuesday that New Delhi had urged "various political forces with whom we were in touch" to resolve the situation via dialogue throughout July.</p>

<p>But as crowds gathered in Dhaka on Monday ignoring the curfew, Hasina decided to resign "after a meeting with leaders of the security establishment", he added. "At very short notice, she requested approval to come for the moment to India."</p>

<p>A second Indian official said it was "diplomatically" conveyed to Hasina that her stay had to be temporary for fear of negatively impacting Delhi's ties with the next government in Dhaka. India's Ministry of External Affairs did not immediately return a request for comment.</p>

<p>Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus, whom the protesting students want to lead the interim government after Hasina's ouster, told The New Indian Express newspaper that India had "good ties with the wrong people... Please revisit your foreign policy."</p>

<p>Yunus wasn't immediately available for an interview.</p>

<p>Late in the afternoon on Monday, a Bangladesh Air Force C130 transport aircraft landed at Hindon air base outside Delhi, with Hasina on board.</p>

<p>There, she was met by Ajit Doval, India's powerful national security advisor, according to the Indian security official.</p>

<p>Delhi had fought to carve Bangladesh out of East Pakistan in 1971. After Hasina's father was assassinated in 1975, Hasina took refuge in India for years and built deep links with her neighbour's political elite.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Returning to Bangladesh, she gained power in 1996, and was seen as more sensitive to India's security concerns than her political rivals. The Hindu-majority nation also regarded her secular stance as favourable for the 13 million Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>But back in Bangladesh, resentment still lingered even among retired soldiers that Hasina had been allowed to leave.</p>

<p>"Personally, I feel that she should not have been given a safe passage," said Khan, the veteran. "That was a folly."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d3t8m64g_bangladesh-protests-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The nationwide curfew had been imposed after at least 91 people were killed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-new-hamas-leader-also-referred-as-dead-man-walking-6281845]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar: New Hamas Leader, Also Referred As "Dead Man Walking"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-new-hamas-leader-also-referred-as-dead-man-walking-6281845]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:14:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After a career in the shadows, spent in Israeli prisons and the internal security apparatus of Hamas, Yahya Sinwar has emerged as leader of the Palestinian group in the middle of a full-blown war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a career in the shadows, spent in Israeli prisons and the internal security apparatus of Hamas, Yahya Sinwar has emerged as leader of the Palestinian group in the middle of a full-blown war.</p>

<p>Sinwar, who until now was the movement's Gaza chief, replaces Ismail Haniyeh, whose killing in Tehran last week sent tensions soaring across the Middle East and raised fears of a coordinated attack on Israel by Iran and its regional proxies.</p>

<p>By choosing him as the group's chief Hamas "is sending a strong message to the occupation that Hamas continues its path of resistance", a senior Hamas official told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sinwar stands accused of masterminding the group's October 7 attacks, the worst in Israel's history, which left 1,198 dead and 251 taken hostage according to an AFP tally and Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of that attack, the Israeli military insisted he was a "dead man walking", although Sinwar has not been seen since.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack was probably a year or two in the planning, "took everyone by surprise" and "changed the balance of power on the ground", said Leila Seurat of the Arab Centre for Research and Political Studies (CAREP) in Paris.</p>

<p>The ascetic 61-year-old is a security operator "par excellence", according to Abu Abdallah, a Hamas member who spent years alongside him in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>"He makes decisions in the utmost calm, but is intractable when it comes to defending the interests of Hamas," Abu Abdallah told AFP in 2017, after his former co-detainee was elected Hamas's leader in Gaza.</p>

<p><strong>Punishing collaborators</strong></p>

<p>After October 7, Israeli military spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Richard Hecht called Sinwar the "face of evil" and declared him a "dead man walking".</p>

<p>Born in the Khan Yunis refugee camp in southern Gaza, Sinwar joined Hamas when Sheikh Ahmad Yassin founded the group around the time the first Palestinian intifada began in 1987.</p>

<p>Sinwar set up the group's internal security apparatus the following year and went on to head an intelligence unit dedicated to flushing out and mercilessly punishing -- sometimes killing -- Palestinians accused of providing information to Israel.</p>

<p>According to a transcript of an interrogation with security officials published in Israeli media, Sinwar professed to have strangled an alleged collaborator with a keffiyeh scarf in a Khan Yunis cemetery.</p>

<p>A graduate of the Islamic University in Gaza, he learned perfect Hebrew during his 23 years in Israeli jails and is said to have a deep understanding of Israeli culture and society.</p>

<p>He was serving four life terms for the killing of two Israeli soldiers when he became the most senior of 1,027 Palestinians released in exchange for Israeli soldier Gilad Shalit in 2011.</p>

<p>Sinwar later became a senior commander in the Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, the military wing of Hamas, before taking overall leadership of the movement in Gaza.</p>

<p>While his predecessor, Haniyeh, had encouraged efforts by Hamas to present a moderate face to the world, Sinwar has preferred to force the Palestinian issue to the fore by more violent means.</p>

<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza says Israel's withering aerial and ground assault launched in response to the October 7 attacks has killed at least 39,653 people in the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p><strong>'Radical and pragmatic'</strong></p>

<p>Sinwar dreams of a single Palestinian state bringing together the Gaza Strip, the occupied West Bank -- controlled by Mahmud Abbas's Fatah party -- and annexed east Jerusalem.</p>

<p>According to US think-tank the Council on Foreign Relations, he has vowed to punish anyone obstructing reconciliation with Fatah, the rival political movement with which Hamas engaged in factional fighting after elections in 2006.</p>

<p>That coming together remains elusive, but the prisoner releases resulting from the brief November truce agreement with Israel have seen Hamas's popularity soar in the West Bank.</p>

<p>Sinwar has pursued a path of being "radical in military planning and pragmatic in politics", according to Seurat.</p>

<p>"He doesn't advocate force for force's sake, but to bring about negotiations" with Israel, she said.</p>

<p>The Hamas chief was added to the US list of the most wanted "international terrorists" in 2015.</p>

<p>Security sources outside Gaza say that Sinwar has taken refuge in the network of tunnels built under the territory to withstand Israeli bombs.</p>

<p>Vowing in November to "find and eliminate" Sinwar, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant urged Gazans to turn Sinwar in, adding "if you reach him before us, it will shorten the war".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qbag8ago_yahya-sinwar-afp_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar stands accused of masterminding the group's October 7 attacks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-awami-league-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-hindu-homes-targeted-as-mobs-run-amok-after-sheikh-hasina-exit-6281773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Hindu Homes Targeted As Mobs Run Amok After Sheikh Hasina Exit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-awami-league-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-hindu-homes-targeted-as-mobs-run-amok-after-sheikh-hasina-exit-6281773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:00:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scores of Hindu temples, business establishments and temples in Bangladesh have been attacked by violent mobs after Sheikh Hasina was ousted as Prime Minister, according to a community association.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scores of Hindu temples, business establishments and temples in Bangladesh have been attacked by violent mobs after Sheikh Hasina was ousted as Prime Minister, according to a community association. While leaders of the movement that toppled the Awami League government have appealed to people not to target the Hindu minority, concerns have been raised about their safety. In a silver lining, several voices have come out in support of Hindus and some temples are being guarded by Muslims and Hindus together.</p>

<p>Hindus account for nearly 8 per cent of Bangladesh's 17 crore population, and a large section of this community has traditionally backed Sheikh Hasina's Awami League. This is due to Sheikh Hasina's strong ties with India and Awami League's posturing as a largely secular force as compared to the opposition that comprises hardline forces.</p>

<p>With the government toppled and the new administration yet to take charge, mobs are running amok, targeting police stations, prisons, Awami League leaders' homes and Hindu establishments.</p>

<p>Tarique Rahman, BNP leader and son of former PM Khaleda Zia, is among the key voices that have appealed for calm.</p>

<p>"I call upon the people of Bangladesh to display restraint and calm in the midst of this transitional moment on our democratic path. It is our duty to protect all Bangladeshis, irrespective of religion and politics, from discriminatory violence, and not to harass any particular community, create division, or seek vengeance. Muslims, Hindus, Christians, Buddhists, believers, atheists - no one will be left behind or be prejudiced on our democratic path; together, we are all proudly Bangladeshis," he has said in a post on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Homes Stormed, Looted</strong></p>

<p>The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council has told Reuters that 200-300 homes, mainly those owned by Hindus, and businesses had been targeted since Monday. About 15-20 Hindu temples had been vandalised and 40-odd people injured, though not seriously, the organisation's general secretary Rana Dasgupta said.</p>

<p>"The communal atrocities erupted hours before she resigned. Although there is no killing, there is injury. Houses and businesses of minorities, especially Hindus, as well as temples, have been targeted, looted, damaged," he said.</p>

<p>Dhaka-based development professional Avirup Sarkar has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy77vgmjlzo">told BBC</a> that his cousin lives in Netrokona, about 100 km from Dhaka. Hours after Sheikh Hasina fled the country, she called Mr Sarkar. "She sounded terrified. She said the house had been attacked and plundered by a mob," he has told BBC. Mr Sarkar's cousin told him that 100 people armed with sticks had stormed the house, smashed furniture, TV, bathroom fittings and doors. They had also taken cash and ornaments. They did not assault anyone in the house.</p>

<p>"You people are descendants of Awami League. This country is in a bad shape because of you. You should leave the country," the mob shouted at the residents, according to the BBC report.</p>

<p><strong>Journalists, Artists Targeted</strong></p>

<p>Pradip Kumar Bhowmik, a journalist with Daily Khoborpatra, died after being assaulted during a mob attack on Rayganj Press Club in Sirajganj, local media has reported. Three other journalists were injured. A total of 25 journalists were injured in incidents of assaults across the country, The Daily Star reported. Many of them are Muslims.</p>

<p>In Dhaka's Dhanmondi, a violent mob attacked Bangladeshi singer Rahul Ananda's ancestral house and burned his musical instruments and furniture. His family members managed to escape the attack. Folk band Joler Gaan, which Rahul Ananda sings for, has put up a video of their last recording in the now gutted room, and questioned the "fire of rage and revenge".</p>

<p><strong>Muslims Join Hindus In Guarding Temples</strong></p>

<p>Amid reports of minorities and temples being targeted, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/353914/temples-in-dhaka-being-guarded-by-students-and">Dhaka Tribune sent a correspondent to three temples</a> and found Hindus and Muslims guarding the places of worship. At Dhakeshwari National Temple, local resident Raj Ghosh said, "Both Muslim and Hindu neighbours are guarding to protect the temple. Some individuals have used this temple for their own benefit. We acknowledge their efforts in developing it, but they have forcibly removed us from the temple."</p>

<p>Ranjan Kumar Das, another resident, said, "There is fear that this temple could be targeted. Last night, some students and local Muslims were with us. They provided their contact details for help in case we were attacked. Our Muslim brothers who have stood beside us are setting an example."</p>

<p>At Ramna Kali Temple, Dhaka University student Rafid Azad is on guard. He said groups are taking turns to guard the temple. Asked who is behind the attacks on temples, he said, "We have seen examples of many countries where, when a regime fails, some people spot an opportunity. We can not say clearly who is attacking the temples. Whoever is behind this is doing a horrible thing."</p>

<p>He said the new government should ensure fundamental rights, including religion and freedom of speech. "Obviously, we do not want a bigoted government, we want a government for everyone."</p>

<p>At ISKCON Swamibag temple, there are no guards, but two posters read, "You are our brothers, do not fear" and "Bangladesh is for all of us". ISKCON member Durlav Harinam Das told Dhaka Tribune, "In this area, we have good relations with everyone, so there is no reason for fear."</p>

<p><strong>India Is Concerned</strong></p>

<p>The safety of minorities in Bangladesh is high on New Delhi's list of priorities, the government has said. Addressing the Parliament on the situation in the neighbouring country, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar yesterday said India is "deeply concerned" over the situation in Bangladesh, especially about the minority community. "We are monitoring the situation with regard to the status of minorities. There are reports of initiatives by various groups and organisations to ensure their protection and well-being. We welcome that, but will naturally remain deeply concerned till law and order is visibly restored," he said.</p>

<p>The minister said New Delhi is in "close and continuous" touch with the Indian community in Bangladesh through diplomatic missions.</p>

<p>Also in focus is the safety of Indian nationals currently in Bangladesh. The minister said there are about 19,000 Indian nationals in Bangladesh, 9,000 of them students. Most students have returned after the students protests against Sheikh Hasina gathered steam. Many Indians are now returning. An Air India chartered flight brought back 205 Indians, including six infants, this morning.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/utc6dteg_hasina_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina quit as Bangladesh PM and fled the country amid violent protests]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asif-merchant-who-is-asif-merchant-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-6281531]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Asif Merchant, Pak Man Arrested For Plot To Kill Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asif-merchant-who-is-asif-merchant-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-6281531]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 10:24:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US has charged a Pakistani man, who allegedly has ties to Iran, with attempting to carry out assassinations of American politicians.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US has charged a Pakistani man, who allegedly has ties to Iran, with attempting to carry out <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-had-planned-protests-as-diversion-6280100">assassinations of American politicians</a>.</p>

<p>Federal prosecutors said Asif Merchant, 46, orchestrated a plot to kill an unidentified politician or US government officials on American soil.</p>

<p>This case has led the US government to increase security for former US President Donald Trump and other officials. While the criminal complaint does not mention Trump explicitly, multiple sources have told reporters that one of the intended targets of the alleged plot was Trump.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Asif Merchant</strong></h3>

<p>Asif Merchant, also known as "Asif Raza Merchant", is a 46-year-old Pakistani national. He has two wives, one each in Pakistan and in Iran, as well as children in both countries.</p>

<p>According to his travel records, Asif frequently travels to Iran, Syria and Iraq, the US Justice Department said.</p>

<h3><strong>How Asif plotted</strong></h3>

<p>The court papers said the plot involved multiple elements - stealing documents or USB drives from a target's home; planning protests, and killing a politician or government official.</p>

<p>Asif Merchant made up code names for each element in the plot - "tee-shirt" for protests, "flannel shirt" for stealing documents, "fleece jacket" for the assassination, and "yarn-dye" for their meetings.</p>

<p>To entice the person he contacted first, who informed officials, Merchant told him he had an uncle in the "yarn-dyed" business in Pakistan and he could go into business with them.</p>

<p>For his plans, Asif Merchant hired people he thought were hitmen, but who were actually undercover agents. He asked one government source he believed was an assassin for hire to explain how "the target" would die in different scenarios.</p>

<h3><strong>How his plot failed</strong></h3>

<p>Asif Merchant's plot failed because he tried to recruit FBI agents for the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>He was arrested on July 12 as he was getting ready to catch a flight out of the country.</p>

<p>In mid-June, Merchant met with people he thought were hitmen. They were undercover US law enforcement officers (the UCs) in New York.</p>

<p>He told them he wanted them to steal documents, arrange protests at political rallies, and kill a "political person".</p>

<p>The plot would have to be carried out after he left the country, and they would be told who the target was either in the last week of August or the first week of September, Merchant told the undercover officers.</p>

<p>Merchant arranged to pay USD 5,000 in cash as an advance for the assassination services and successfully delivered this payment on June 21.</p>

<p>Following this transaction, he made plans to leave the country on July 12, 2024, one day before Donald Trump's assassination attempt. However, law enforcement intervened and arrested him before he could leave, the court document said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/urc6du9_asif-merchant_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Asif Merchant, also known as "Asif Raza Merchant", is a 46-year-old Pakistani national.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>