<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:20:17 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-greeces-golden-visa-scheme-popular-among-wealthy-indians-6607859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Greece's Golden Visa Scheme, Popular Among Wealthy Indians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-greeces-golden-visa-scheme-popular-among-wealthy-indians-6607859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 13:34:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian investors snapped up Greek properties at a record pace in July and August to secure permanent residency before the country's Golden Visa Programme underwent significant changes on September 1.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian investors snapped up Greek properties at a record pace in July and August to secure permanent residency before the country's Golden Visa Programme underwent significant changes on September 1. <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-investors-rush-to-buy-greek-properties-ahead-of-golden-visa-rule-changes-6601066">Property purchases by Indian investors</a> in Greece saw a remarkable 37 per cent increase between July and August, data show. The surge was led by buyers seeking to capitalise on the existing minimum investment requirements.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now the changes in the Golden Visa Programme have doubled the minimum investment required to qualify for a visa through real estate purchases. In Tier I cities, including Athens, Thessaloniki, Mykonos, and Santorini, the threshold has increased €800,000 800,000 (approximately Rs 7 crore).&nbsp;</p>

<p>In Tier II regions, covering all other parts of Greece, the minimum investment has risen to €400,000 from €250,000.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Greece Golden Visa Programme</strong></h2>

<p>The Greece Golden Visa programme is a premier residency-by-investment initiative designed to attract non-EU nationals to invest in Greece.</p>

<p>In 2024, the programme was updated to better align with Greece's economic strategies, introducing new investment thresholds and conditions.</p>

<h2><strong>Eligibility criteria</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Non-EU/EEA citizenship</li>
	<li>Age 18+</li>
	<li>Clean criminal record</li>
	<li>Medical insurance</li>
	<li>Good character</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Benefits</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Residency Rights: Right to reside in Greece without mandatory stay requirements.</li>
	<li>Schengen Area Access: Visa-free travel within the Schengen Zone.</li>
	<li>Family Inclusion: Eligibility for family members to obtain residency.</li>
	<li>Pathway to Citizenship: Potential to apply for Greek citizenship after seven years of residency, subject to conditions.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Application Process and legal requirements</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Required Documentation</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Valid Passport: Current and any previous visas.</li>
	<li>Proof of Investment: Property contracts, bank statements, etc.</li>
	<li>Biometric Data: Required for the application.</li>
	<li>Health Insurance: Policy valid in Greece.</li>
	<li>Criminal Record: Clean criminal record from the applicant's country of residence, officially translated into Greek.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Legal Representation</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Mandatory Lawyer: Licensed to practise in Greece.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Role of Lawyer: Facilitates document preparation, and submission, and ensures compliance with Greek immigration laws.</li>
	<li>Power of Attorney: Often required for the lawyer to act on the applicant's behalf.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Renewal and Permanent Residency</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Initial Permit: Issued for five years, renewable as long as the investment is maintained.</li>
	<li>Permanent Residency: Eligible after seven years of continuous residency in Greece.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Dependents</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Spouse and Partner: Including legally recognised cohabitation agreements.</li>
	<li>Children: Under 21, or older if financially dependent and studying.</li>
	<li>Parents: Dependent parents of the primary applicant or spouse.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/i648nt9g_parthenon-temple-greece_625x300_13_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Greece Golden Visa programme is a premier residency-by-investment initiative.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/titanic-ex-oceangate-employee-says-titan-sub-had-to-abort-a-dive-days-before-fatal-implosion-6607726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Employee Says Titan Sub Had To Abort A Dive Days Before Fatal Implosion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/titanic-ex-oceangate-employee-says-titan-sub-had-to-abort-a-dive-days-before-fatal-implosion-6607726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 12:05:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Titan submersible had to abort a dive just days before the implosion that killed its five passengers as they explored the wreck of the Titanic, an ex-employee of the company that operated the vessel testified on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Titan submersible had to abort a dive just days before the implosion that killed its five passengers as they explored the wreck of the Titanic, an ex-employee of the company that operated the vessel testified on Thursday. The testimony from former OceanGate scientific director Steven Ross came as the US Coast Guard began a two-week hearing on Monday into the 2023 catastrophe, which will feature evidence as to what went wrong and whether physical or design failure contributed to the accident, which garnered worldwide attention.</p>

<p>Ross told the hearing that the earlier dive had to be aborted due to a valve malfunction that left at least one passenger hanging upside down and took "considerable time" to correct.</p>

<p>He said that when the privately-owned and operated submersible surfaced during that dive, it tilted so its bow was pointing upwards at a 45-degree angle.</p>

<p>Ross, who was inside along with four other passengers, explained that "there's nothing to hold on to inside this submersible."</p>

<p>The pilot that day -- OceanGate CEO Stockton Rush, who died in the implosion days later -- "crashed into the rear bulkhead," Ross said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The rest of the passengers tumbled about. I ended up standing on the rear bulkhead," he continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"One passenger was hanging upside down, and the other two managed to wedge themselves into the bow end cap."</p>

<p>He said no one was injured in the incident, but that inside the cramped and confined space "it was uncomfortable and unpleasant, and it took considerable time to correct the problem" -- at least an hour, by his reckoning.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Rush, he said, was "upset" by the incident.</p>

<p>Rush and four passengers descended in the submersible on June 18, 2023, to observe the wreck of the Titanic.</p>

<p>But contact was lost less than two hours after their departure. A vast rescue operation was launched in the hope that the passengers had simply lost power and were drifting helplessly in the ocean's depths.</p>

<p>However, within days it became clear that the sub had been destroyed in a cataclysmic implosion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Victims are presumed to have died instantly in the disaster, which occurred under the crushing pressure of the North Atlantic at a depth of more than two miles (nearly four kilometers).</p>

<p>Apart from Rush, the four others on the Titan were British explorer Hamish Harding, French submarine expert Paul-Henri Nargeolet, Pakistani-British tycoon Shahzada Dawood and his son Suleman.</p>

<p>The family of Nargeolet has taken OceanGate to court, claiming $50 million for negligence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A debris field was found 1,600 feet (500 meters) from the bow of the Titanic, which sits 400 miles off the coast of Newfoundland, Canada.</p>

<p>The Titanic hit an iceberg and sank in 1912 during its maiden voyage from England to New York, with 2,224 passengers and crew on board. More than 1,500 people died.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/epo97r78_oceangate-titan-sub_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Five people had descended in the submersible on June 18, 2023, to observe the wreck of the Titanic]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/generous-gesture-maldives-as-india-sends-crucial-budgetary-support-6607501]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Generous Gesture": Maldives As India Sends "Crucial Budgetary Support"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/generous-gesture-maldives-as-india-sends-crucial-budgetary-support-6607501]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:35:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maldives Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer has expressed gratitude to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar as the Indian government extended budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of the USD 50 million Treasury Bill.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maldives Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer has expressed gratitude to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar as the Indian government extended budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of the USD 50 million Treasury Bill. He said the Indian government's announcement demonstrates "enduring bonds of friendship between the Maldives and India."</p>

<p>In a post on X, Mr Zameer stated, "Sincere gratitude to External Affairs Minister @DrSJaishankar and the Government of #India for extending crucial budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of USD 50 million Treasury Bill. This generous gesture reflects the enduring bonds of friendship between #Maldives and #India."</p>

<p>At the request of the Maldivian government, the State Bank of India (SBI) has subscribed the USD 50 million government Treasury Bills (T-bills) issued by the Ministry of Finance of the Maldives for a period of one more year upon the maturity of the previous subscription on September 19, the Indian High Commission in the Maldives said in a press release.</p>

<p>This is the second rollover granted by the Indian government this year, following the first rollover of a USD 50 million Treasury Bill on May 13.</p>

<p>According to the press release, the Maldivian government is "highly appreciative" of the support announced by India following the request made by Moosa Zameer during his meeting with Mr Jaishankar in August.</p>

<p>In a press release, the Maldives Ministry of Foreign Affairs stated, "Government of India's decision to grant this extension came following a request to that effect made by Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer during the discussions held between the two governments at the recent visit of the Minister of External Affairs of India, S Jaishankar, to the Maldives from 9-11 August 2024."</p>

<p>"The Government of the Maldives is highly appreciative of the generous support that the Government of India has been providing to the Maldives in the form of budgetary support. This extension comes at a pivotal moment as the Government of the Maldives is implementing a strong fiscal consolidation program to address the pressing economic challenges," it added.</p>

<p>Maldivian Ministry of Foreign Affairs noted that India has once again showcased the high value it places on the enduring partnership between the two nations.</p>

<p>The press release stated, "The Government of India has once again demonstrated the high value it places on this enduring partnership. The Government of Maldives looks forward to continuing this collaborative partnership for the mutual benefit and prosperity of the people of both nations."</p>

<p>In the press release, the Indian High Commission called the Maldives India's key maritime neighbour and important partner under India's 'Neighbourhood First' policy.</p>

<p>The Indian High Commission in Maldives stated, "Maldives is India's key maritime neighbour and an important partner under India's 'Neighbourhood First' policy and Vision SAGAR i.e. Security and Growth for All in the Region."</p>

<p>"India has assisted the Maldives in times of need, and the current subscription of T-bills along with the Government of India's decision earlier this year, of extending special quota for export of essential commodities for Maldives by one more year reflect India's continued support to the Government and the people of the Maldives," it added.</p>

<p>It noted that SBI had similarly subscribed a USD 50 mn T-bills under the same mechanism in May 2024, at the request of the Maldives government. These subscriptions have been made at the special request of the Maldives government as emergency financial assistance.</p>

<p>India's ties with the Maldives were strained after Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu took office. Shortly after he was sworn in, Mr Muizzu stirred bilateral tensions by demanding the removal of approximately 88 Indian military personnel from the Maldives. These personnel were repatriated from three aviation platforms and replaced by Indian civilians by the May 10 deadline set by President Muizzu.</p>

<p>Recently, Mr Muizzu's government in the Maldives took a reconciliatory tone after ties between the two nations soured, leading to a diplomatic row in January after three Maldivian deputy ministers made derogatory comments against Prime Minister Narendra Modi over his pictures from the visit to Lakshadweep.</p>

<p>Since January, many efforts have been undertaken by the Muizzu-led government in order to restore the relationship, which includes several high-level visits, including the President himself coming to India for the swearing-in ceremony of PM Narendra Modi or the visit of the Maldivian Foreign Minister.</p>

<p>Earlier in August, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar visited Maldives. During his visit to Male, Mr Jaishankar signed MoUs on capacity building and inaugurated six High Impact Community Development Projects (HICDPs), according to a Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) release.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar also called on Mr Muizzu and reviewed bilateral relations with his Maldives counterpart Moosa Zameer.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/726io9h8_s-jaishankar-moosa-zameer_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wrath-of-god-to-the-angel-6-times-mossad-ops-inspired-hollywood-6607430]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Wrath Of God' To 'The Angel': 6 Times Mossad Ops Inspired Hollywood]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wrath-of-god-to-the-angel-6-times-mossad-ops-inspired-hollywood-6607430]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:21:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's spy intelligence agency Mossad has long been synonymous with daring and covert operations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Israel's spy intelligence agency Mossad has long been synonymous with daring and covert operations. The recent explosions in Lebanon – where thousands of pagers and walkie talkies, allegedly triggered remotely by Israel, killed 32 – have once again brought the agency's capabilities to focus.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mossad's real-life missions have inspired filmmakers worldwide, bringing these dramatic and dangerous operations to the screen. Here are some films and series based on actual Mossad operations:</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Munich (2005)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Directed by Steven Spielberg, <em>Munich</em> follows Avner Kaufman (played by Eric Bana), a Mossad agent tasked with leading a secret mission, "Wrath of God," to assassinate Palestinian militants responsible for the 1972 Olympics terror attack. The film explores the moral complexities of revenge and counter-terrorism.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kidon (2011)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Loosely based on the 2010 assassination of Hamas commander Mahmoud Al-Mabhouh in Dubai, Kidon combines spy action and comedy. The film follows a Mossad team as they execute a high-stakes mission.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Operation Finale (2018)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">This film recreates the 1960 Mossad mission to capture Adolf Eichmann, a key architect of the Holocaust, in Argentina. Peter Malkin (played by Oscar Isaac) leads the team of agents who track down Eichmann and bring him to Israel to face justice.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>The Angel (2018)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Based on the book ‘The Angel: The Egyptian Spy Who Saved Israel', this film tells the story of Ashraf Marwan (played by Marwan Kenzari), an Egyptian diplomat who becomes a double agent for Mossad. Marwan provides crucial intelligence to Israel, including a warning about the 1973 Yom Kippur War.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>The Spy (Netflix series, 2019)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Based on true events, <em>The Spy</em> tells the story of Eli Cohen (played by Sacha Baron Cohen), an Israeli Mossad agent who infiltrates Syrian high society in the 1960s. Cohen, posing as Kamel Amin Thaabet, gains the trust of military officials and politicians, becoming a close confidant of future Syrian President Amin al-Hafiz. His mission provides vital intelligence for Israel's victory in the 1967 Six-Day War. However, his daring mission comes at a great personal cost when his cover is blown and he is captured by Syrian forces.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>The Red Sea Diving Resort (2019)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr"><em>The Red Sea Diving Resort</em> is based on one of Mossad's most audacious humanitarian operations, Operation Brothers, in the early 1980s. The mission aimed to rescue Ethiopian Jews fleeing civil war and famine. Thousands had crossed the border into Sudan making it extremely difficult for Mossad to operate. The solution was Israeli agents setting up a fake diving resort on the Sudanese coast as a front for taking refugees to safety. The resort was fully operational, with tourists and diving activities masking the covert mission.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/at93cihs_munich_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/traslados-argentinas-death-flights-when-people-were-thrown-out-of-planes-6607191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Argentina's "Death Flights": When People Were Thrown Out Of Planes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/traslados-argentinas-death-flights-when-people-were-thrown-out-of-planes-6607191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 10:44:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A documentary, "Traslados", explores the grim legacy of Argentina's death flights, where thousands of dissidents were rounded up and thrown out of planes, often alive.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A chilling reminder of Argentina's violent military dictatorship between 1976 and 1983 has resurfaced on the big screen with the documentary ‘Traslados' (Transferred). The film sheds light on the haunting practice of ‘death flights,' where thousands of dissidents were rounded up and thrown out of planes, often alive, into the River Plate and the Atlantic Ocean.<br />
<br />
This week, a packed crowd at a theatre in Buenos Aires, the capital city of Argentina, saw one of the first screenings of the film, which brought both survivors and younger generations face to face with a past many would prefer to forget.</p>

<h3><strong>What were the ‘death flights'?</strong></h3>

<p>The term ‘death flights' refers to brutal executions by Argentina's military dictatorship. Those considered enemies, including activists and intellectuals, of the regime were told they were being “transferred” to another location. Instead, they were tortured and taken aboard military aircraft.<br />
<br />
Mid-flight, they were thrown from the planes, many still alive, into the sea or the River Plate, where they would drown or die due to the impact. The fate of thousands remains a mystery; their bodies were never recovered. What's been described by many as "state-sponsored terrorism" was a key tactic in silencing dissent during Argentina's “Dirty War.”</p>

<h3><strong>‘Traslados' documentary</strong></h3>

<p>Directed by Nicolas Gil Lavedra, ‘Traslados' – the 90-minute documentary – brings together testimonies from survivors, archived material and dramatised reenactments to present the horrors of the death flights. According to Lavedra, ‘Traslados' “puts evidence on the table, brings together all the pieces and everything known...about the death flights.”<br />
<br />
“There are no partisan or subjective opinions, there are facts and there is evidence,” Lavedra told AFP.<br />
<br />
He aimed to present a clear and unbiased account of the atrocities committed during the dictatorship, an era when 30,000 people were killed or disappeared, according to human rights organisations. One of the central stories featured in ‘Traslados' is that of Esther Ballestrino, Azucena Villaflor, and Maria Ponce, founders of the “Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo” — a group that continues to fight for justice for the disappeared. Along with French nuns Alice Domon and Leonie Duquet, and seven other activists, they were abducted and killed in one of the death flights on December 14, 1977.</p>

<p>The documentary comes while Argentina is still grappling with its dark history. Controversy erupted earlier this year when lawmakers from President Javier Milei's party visited former military officers convicted of crimes against humanity, including Alfredo Astiz, the man who infiltrated the ‘Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo' and identified the women who were later killed.<br />
<br />
The documentary's release has reignited calls for justice and remembrance. For Lavedra, this is more than revisiting history — it's about shaping the present. He said, “The only way we have to heal that wound is with justice, truth and memory.”<br />
<br />
His connection to the subject runs deep, as his father presided over post-dictatorship trials, and he has previously directed a film on human rights activist Estela de Carlotto, president of the ‘Mothers' group.</p>

<h3><strong>Argentina's military dictatorship</strong></h3>

<p>Argentina's military dictatorship remains one of the most brutal in Latin American history. Torture, forced disappearances, and state-sanctioned murders were used to suppress any form of dissent. As the military sought to maintain power, the people of Argentina lived in constant fear, unsure of who among them might vanish next.<br />
The ‘death flights' represent one of the most horrific tactics of this regime, and many of the victims were never identified.<br />
<br />
For younger Argentines, many of whom were born long after the dictatorship, ‘Traslados' provides a stark reminder of the country's brutal past.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rp5646s8_traslados_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A packed crowd at a theatre in Buenos Aires saw one of the first screenings of the film]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-us-elections-2024-if-somebody-breaks-into-my-house-theyre-getting-shot-6606918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If Somebody Breaks Into My House, They're Getting Shot": Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-us-elections-2024-if-somebody-breaks-into-my-house-theyre-getting-shot-6606918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 09:58:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' remarks came during a star-studded rally hosted by talk show legend Oprah Winfrey.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris held a star-studded rally hosted by talk show legend Oprah Winfrey on Thursday in a bid to bedazzle voters, as rival Donald Trump criticized Jewish Americans for not voting for him. Hollywood stars including Jennifer Lopez, Meryl Streep, Julia Roberts, Chris Rock, and Ben Stiller beamed in remotely to lavish praise via screens on the Democratic vice president.</p>

<p>Sitting on a chat-show style stage, Winfrey started by asking Harris about what seemed a sudden burst in confidence -- "a veil or something dropped" -- after she replaced President Joe Biden as nominee.</p>

<p>"We each have those moments in our lives when you have to step up," the 59-year-old Harris replied at the livestreamed "Unite for America" event</p>

<p>The pair hugged as Harris arrived on stage at the rally in Michigan, one of the seven crucial battleground states that will decide the knife-edge November 5 election.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It is so good to be with <a href="https://twitter.com/Oprah?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Oprah</a> for a town hall to speak directly with Americans about the issues on their minds in this election.<br />
<br />
Our campaign is about who we are as Americans—and making clear that we stand for freedom, independence, and dignity. <a href="https://t.co/5k8h5Ra7Uk">pic.twitter.com/5k8h5Ra7Uk</a></p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1836934301453099356?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Harris urged Americans to unite against the "powerful forces that would try to divide us", represented by Republican former president Trump.</p>

<p>The Democrat then talked through her key campaign points, ranging from abortion to economy and immigration and gun control, as audience members told stories about their experiences.</p>

<p>Former prosecutor Harris also made a pitch to gun owners, a key part of the electorate in a country with more firearms than people, even as she called for an end to high-powered assault weapons used in a string of school shootings.</p>

<p>"I'm a gun owner too, if somebody breaks in my house they're getting shot," Harris said with a laugh, before adding: &nbsp;"I probably shouldn't have said that... &nbsp;my staff will deal with that later."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Watch Live: Livestream event with Vice President Kamala Harris and Oprah Winfrey <a href="https://t.co/P8Rax1dAGk">https://t.co/P8Rax1dAGk</a></p>
— Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1836914885587828940?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>TV superstar Winfrey, who also spoke at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago in August, said as she introduced Harris that she felt "hope and joy rising."</p>

<p>Groups including "Swifties for Harris" (made up of fans of Harris-backing pop star Taylor Swift) and "Cat Ladies for Kamala" (women mocking comments by Trump's running mate J.D. Vance on childless people) tuned in remotely.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US election is effectively neck-and-neck as Harris and Trump try to eke out every vote with 47 days left until polling day.</p>

<p>Harris got a boost from a New York Times/Siena poll showing her marginally ahead in Pennsylvania, perhaps the most crucial of all the swing states, but the survey also put her and Trump level nationwide.</p>

<p>Her glitzy event contrasted with the darker tone taken by Trump at an anti-Semitism event in the capital, Washington.</p>

<p>Trump spent much of time repeating his grievance over the fact that Jewish voters in the United States have historically leant towards the Democrats.</p>

<p>"If I don't win this election... in my opinion the Jewish people would have a lot to do with a loss," Trump said.</p>

<p>Accusing Harris of failing to back Israel after the October 7 attacks by Hamas, Trump said that "more than any other people on Earth, Israel, I believe, has to defeat her."</p>

<p>Trump added that "any Jewish person that votes for her... should have their head examined."</p>

<p>The Gaza war could be a crucial one in the election.</p>

<p>The US "Uncommitted" movement, which opposes the Biden-Harris administration's military and political support for Israel's war on Gaza, said on Thursday it would not be backing Harris in the election.</p>

<p>It also threatens Harris's narrow margins in Michigan, where there is a large Arab-American community against the war.</p>

<p>Harris's running mate Tim Walz meanwhile on Thursday met with the families of Americans held hostage by Hamas since the attack.</p>

<p>He said after the meeting that Biden and Harris would "continue doing everything possible to bring them home."</p>

<p>Trump and Harris are also battling for support from US unions.</p>

<p>The powerful Teamsters union on Wednesday declined to endorse a presidential candidate, in a blow for Harris as it had a quarter century tradition of endorsing Democrats.</p>

<p>But Harris's campaign said however that local Teamsters branches representing one million people had since said they endorsed her.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mjjmrfoo_kamala-harris_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/want-to-buy-iphone-16-heres-the-number-days-you-need-to-work-to-afford-it-6606865]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Many Days Do People In Various Countries Need To Work To Buy iPhone 16]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/want-to-buy-iphone-16-heres-the-number-days-you-need-to-work-to-afford-it-6606865]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 09:48:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The new iPhone is now officially being sold in India. The brand new iPhone 16 may not completely fit into every budget, and a new study tells us exactly how many days of work will it take to save up for one, in any country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new iPhone is now officially being sold in India. The brand new iPhone 16 may not completely fit into every budget, and a new study tells us exactly how many days of work will it take to save up for one, in any country. The research shows there are countries where people need to work for more than three months in order to afford the iPhone 16.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.picodi.com/us/bargain-hunting/iphone-index-2024">iPhone Index</a>, a person in Switzerland needs to work only 4 days to afford the iPhone 16. In contrast, an average American requires 5.1 days, while Australians and Singaporeans need 5.7 days.</p>

<p>In India, one needs to work 47.6 days to afford the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/iphone-16-pro-max-plus-price-india-sale-date-specifications-features-6526758">new iPhone 16</a>.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hed1bqho_iphone-index-2024_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The iPhone Index, calculated based on the official prices of the iPhone 16 Pro (128 GB), is an annual index of iPhone price-to-wage ratios since 2018.</p>

<p>In India, iPhone 16 pricing starts at Rs 79,900, iPhone 16 Plus at Rs 89,900, iPhone 16 Pro at Rs 119,900, and iPhone 16 Pro Max at Rs 144,900.</p>

<p>The new iPhones are available at Apple retail and online stores in India, including Apple BKC (Mumbai) and Apple Saket (New Delhi), and through authorized sellers.</p>

<p>The company will roll out the US English version of the Apple Intelligence feature on the iPhone 16 series devices next month through a software update. Apple Intelligence will enable users to rewrite, proofread, and summarise text.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6qceprbg_iphone-16-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new iPhones are available at Apple retail and online stores in India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-pagers-walkie-talkies-banned-on-flights-from-lebanon-after-deadly-blasts-6606808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pagers, Walkie-Talkies Banned On Flights From Lebanon After Deadly Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-pagers-walkie-talkies-banned-on-flights-from-lebanon-after-deadly-blasts-6606808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 09:36:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon has banned walkie-talkies and pagers from flights departing Beirut airport. The decision, announced on Thursday, was made after walkie-talkies and pagers, reportedly used by Hezbollah members, detonated in a deadly attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon has banned walkie-talkies and pagers from flights departing Beirut airport. The decision, announced on Thursday, was made after walkie-talkies and pagers, reportedly used by Hezbollah members, detonated in a deadly attack earlier this week, killing at least 37 people and injured thousands</p>

<p>According to Lebanon's National News Agency, the Civil Aviation Directorate instructed airlines operating out of Beirut Rafic Hariri International Airport (BEY) to inform passengers about the new restrictions. Both walkie-talkies and pagers are now prohibited in carry-on and checked luggage, as well as cargo shipments. The ban will remain in place until further notice, the agency reported.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-bombs-targets-in-lebanon-hours-after-hezbollahs-revenge-vow-6606329#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Hours After Hezbollah Chief's "Revenge" Vow, Israel Bombs Lebanon: 10 Facts</a></p>

<p>Two waves of explosions occurred on Tuesday and Wednesday, killing 37 and wounding more than 3,000 people, according to Lebanese health authorities. The explosions involved large caches of walkie-talkies and pagers, which Hezbollah, the Iran-backed militant group, reportedly used in their operations.</p>

<p>Lebanese officials have claimed that Israel was responsible for the attack, although Israel has yet to officially take credit. Hezbollah and Israel have been locked in an ongoing conflict, exchanging fire across the Lebanese-Israeli border for nearly a year.</p>

<p>Qatar Airways responded to the new directive, announcing it would enforce the ban on pagers and walkie-talkies for all flights from Beirut.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884"> Inside Lebanon Politics: Hezbollah, Iran And A Larger Battle For Hegemony</a></p>

<p>"Effective immediately: Following the directive received from the Directorate General of Civil Aviation of the Republic of Lebanon, all passengers flying from Beirut Rafic Hariri International Airport (BEY) are prohibited from carrying pagers and walkie-talkies on board flights," the airline wrote. "The ban applies to both checked and carry-on luggage, as well as cargo, and will be enforced until further notice."</p>

<p>As tensions escalate between Hezbollah and Israel, the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) launched new airstrikes targeting Hezbollah strongholds in Lebanon on Thursday. In a statement posted on X, the IDF said it aimed to degrade Hezbollah's military capabilities and infrastructure. The Israeli military has been focusing on Hezbollah's network of tunnels and civilian homes in southern Lebanon, which the group allegedly uses for military operations.</p>

<p>"The IDF is currently striking Hezbollah targets in Lebanon to degrade Hezbollah's terrorist capabilities and infrastructure," the IDF said in the post. "For decades, Hezbollah has weaponized civilian homes, dug tunnels beneath them, and used civilians as human shields-having turned southern Lebanon into a war zone."</p>

<p>In an address on Thursday, Israeli Defense Minister Yoav Gallant declared the start of a "new phase" in Israel's ongoing conflict with Hezbollah. Gallant said that Israel is shifting resources and attention to the northern arena, aiming to bring security to the region and allow displaced residents to return to their homes.</p>

<p>"We are at the start of a new phase in the war," Gallant said in a social media post. "We are allocating resources and forces to the northern arena, and our mission is clear: ensuring the safe return of Israel's northern communities to their homes. To do so, the security situation must be changed."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8va96iko_beirut-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Qatar Airways responded to the new directive, announcing it would enforce the ban.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mohamed-al-fayed-billionaire-whose-son-died-with-princess-diana-accused-of-multiple-rapes-6606526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mohamed Al-Fayed, Whose Son Died With Princess Diana, Accused Of Rape]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mohamed-al-fayed-billionaire-whose-son-died-with-princess-diana-accused-of-multiple-rapes-6606526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 08:21:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Harrods boss Mohamed Al-Fayed, whose son Emad El-Din "Dodi" Mohamed Fayed was killed in a 1997 Paris car crash alongside Princess Diana, has been accused of multiple rapes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Harrods boss Mohamed Al-Fayed, whose son Emad El-Din "Dodi" Mohamed Fayed was killed in a 1997 Paris car crash alongside Princess Diana, has been accused of multiple rapes. According to <em>The BBC</em>, five women have claimed that they were raped by the billionaire, who died last year aged 94, when they worked at the luxury London department store Harrods, which Al-Fayed owned from 1985 to 2010. The outlet revealed that it had heard testimonies from more than 20 former female staff members who claim the billionaire businessman sexually assaulted them, with the incidents allegedly taking place in London, St. Tropez, Abu Dhabi and Paris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations were laid out in a <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cz6x635wpjxo">BBC </a></em>documentary, titled <em>'Al-Fayed: Predator at Harrods'</em>. The documentary revealed that during Fayed's ownership, Harrods not only failed to intervene but helped cover up abuse allegations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.harrods.com/en-gb/press">statement</a>, Harrods' current owners said they were "utterly appalled" by the allegations and that his victims had been failed - for which the store apologised.</p>

<p>"These were the actions of an individual who was intent on abusing his power wherever he operated and we condemn them in the strongest terms," the statement read. "We also acknowledge that during this time as a business, we failed our employees who were his victims and for this we sincerely apologise," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <em>The BBC</em>, one woman has alleged that the billionaire raped her at his London apartment. "I made it obvious that I didn't want that to happen. I did not give consent. I just wanted it to be over," she told the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another woman claimed that she was raped at the apartment in Mayfair when she was a teenager. "We were all scared. He actively cultivated fear," she said. "If he said 'jump' employees would ask 'how high'."</p>

<p>A woman named Sophia, who worked as Fayed's personal assistant from 1988 to 1991, says the billionaire tried to rape her more than once. "I couldn't leave. I didn't have a [family] home to go back to, I had to pay rent," she said. "I knew I had to go through this and I didn't want to. It was horrible and my head was scrambled," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another of his personal assistants, Gemma, who worked for Fayed from 2007 to 2009, claimed he raped her at Villa Windsor in Paris, a former home of King Edward VIII and his wife Wallis Simpson. She said that as part of the agreement for her leaving the job, she had to shred all evidence and sign a non-disclosure agreement (NDA) in return for a sum of money. Ms Gemma told the outlet that a shredding truck came to her lawyer's office and a member of HR from Harrods was present.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-accepted-132-000-in-gifts-including-taylor-swift-and-football-tickets-6603625">UK PM Accepted $132,000 In Gifts, Including Taylor Swift And Football Tickets</a></strong></p>

<p>Tony Leeming, a former Harrods department manager of 10 years, said that he was aware of the abuse of women on the shop floor, but claimed he did not know about the allegations of assault or rape. Mr Leeming's testimony is backed by former members of Fayed's security team.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We were aware that he had this very strong interest in young girls," said Eamon Coyle, who joined Harrods in 1979 as a store detective, then became deputy director of security from 1989-95.</p>

<p>Many women told the <em>BBC </em>that when they began working directly for Fayed they underwent medicals - including invasive sexual health tests carried out by doctors. The outlet also reported that before his death, the billionaire faced a number of sexual assault claims in 1997, 2008 and 2017.</p>

<p>Of the women the outlet spoke to for the investigation, a total of 14 have brought civil claims against Harrods for damages. The department store's current owners started settling these in July 2023, according to the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Fayed, born in Egypt, moved to the United Kingdom in 1974 and was already a well-known public figure when he took over Harrods in 1985. His son Dodi was killed in a car crash alongside Princess Diana in 1997. He has become known to a new generation through the two most recent Netflix series of 'The Crown'.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/cd3l3p0o_mohamed-alfayed-afp_625x300_02_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The allegations were laid out in a BBC documentary, titled 'Al-Fayed: Predator at Harrods'.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-us-presidential-elections-2024-who-leads-the-race-to-white-house-after-debate-6606478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris vs Trump: Who Leads The Race To White House After Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-us-presidential-elections-2024-who-leads-the-race-to-white-house-after-debate-6606478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 08:11:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is widely perceived as having outperformed Donald Trump in the September 10 presidential debate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat nominee Kamala Harris has extended her lead over Republican Donald Trump in the race to win the November 5 US presidential election, according to various polls conducted after the September 10 televised debate between the two candidates.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-in-pennsylvania-michigan-post-debate-poll-6597070" target="_blank">Harris</a>, widely perceived as having outperformed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fed-rate-cut-shows-economy-very-bad-or-theyre-playing-politics-donald-trump-6598138" target="_blank">Trump</a> in the debate, now leads her Republican rival 47% to 42% in a September 11-19 Reuters/Ipsos poll.</p>

<p>According to the latest Economist/YouGov poll, the 59-year-old leads the White House race by four percentage points among registered US voters. This is reportedly the largest lead any presidential candidate has registered in any weekly Economist/YouGov poll in nearly a year, since US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-alleges-iranian-hackers-sent-stolen-trump-info-to-joe-biden-campaign-6598045" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> led Trump by 45% to 40% in the September 23-26, 2023 poll.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Before the debate, Harris - who replaced her boss, Biden, as Democrat nominee - was leading by two percentage points in the Economist/YouGov poll.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/avmejuug_harris-trump-polls_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Real Clear Politics, which gave Harris a 1.4-point lead over her 78-year-old opponent on September 10, has now increased it to two points (49.3 percent to 47.3) as of September 19.</p>

<p>According to polling aggregator FiveThirtyEight, the Democrat is now ahead by about three percentage points, which was two points before the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-he-will-not-participate-in-another-debate-with-kamala-harris-6552578" target="_blank">debate</a>.</p>

<p>Silver Bulletin also said that Harris is now leading Trump by over three points.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The debate, hosted by ABC News, attracted over 67 million television viewers, according to Nielsen data, topping the roughly 51 million people who watched Trump debate then-candidate Biden in June.</p>

<p>Biden's disastrous performance in that debate had forced the 81-year-old leader to drop his re-election bid, which he did in July.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6ivehmr8_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-bombs-targets-in-lebanon-hours-after-hezbollahs-revenge-vow-6606329]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hours After Hezbollah Chief's "Revenge" Vow, Israel Bombs Lebanon: 10 Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-bombs-targets-in-lebanon-hours-after-hezbollahs-revenge-vow-6606329]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 07:24:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel unleashed a series of airstrikes on southern Lebanon on Thursday in one of the most intense bombardments seen since the start of cross-border hostilities with armed group Hezbollah on October 7.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) announced that over 100 rocket launchers primed for imminent attacks on Israel were destroyed. These launchers, scattered across Hezbollah's positions in southern Lebanon, contained an estimated 1,000 rocket barrels. In addition, several Hezbollah buildings and a weapons depot were also hit.</li>
	<li>The airstrikes come just a day after Hezbollah's leader, Hassan Nasrallah, vowed revenge for what he described as a series of unprecedented and deadly attacks against Hezbollah operatives. Speaking in his first public address since these attacks, Nasrallah accused Israel of detonating communication devices belonging to Hezbollah operatives across Lebanon which resulted in 37 deaths and nearly 3,000 injuries.</li>
	<li>Nasrallah described the attacks as a "massacre" and warned Israel of "tough retribution and just punishment." The Hezbollah chief claimed that Israel would be struck both where it expects and where it does not. During his speech, Israeli fighter jets roared over Beirut, breaking the sound barrier.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Israel's defence minister Yoav Gallant warned that the country was entering a "new phase in the war," indicating that the conflict, previously centred around Gaza, was now expanding to the northern border with Lebanon.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah, backed by Iran, has been a staunch ally of Hamas, the Palestinian group at the heart of the war in Gaza since the October 7 attack that killed over 1,200 people in Israel, mostly civilians. The conflict has now spilt over into a regional confrontation, with Hezbollah launching daily attacks against Israeli communities along the northern border, prompting retaliatory strikes from the IDF.</li>
	<li>The exchanges of fire between Israel and Hezbollah along the border have triggered mass evacuations, forcing tens of thousands of civilians on both sides of the border to flee their homes. Communities along Israel's northern front are now under strict military guidelines, with residents instructed to remain close to bomb shelters, avoid large gatherings, and reduce movement outside.</li>
	<li>"In the new phase of the war, there are significant opportunities but also significant risks," Gallant said, adding that Hezbollah "feels persecuted" and that the group would continue to pay a "heavy price" for its aggression.</li>
	<li>Thursday's airstrikes came after a major Hezbollah rocket barrage targeting Israel's northern communities. In Metula, a town along the Lebanese border, the damage was described as "tremendous," with homes destroyed and fires ignited by the incoming rockets. Israeli emergency services reported that no casualties were caused.</li>
	<li>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken called for restraint from all parties, urging both Israel and Hezbollah to avoid actions that could further escalate the conflict. The Biden administration has been scrambling to mediate a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas in Gaza, and now faces the added challenge of preventing the conflict from spreading further across the Middle East.</li>
	<li>Lebanon's Foreign Minister Abdallah Bou Habib condemned Israel's airstrikes, calling them a "blatant assault on Lebanon's sovereignty and security." He warned that the escalation risked triggering a broader regional conflict. Iran's Revolutionary Guards vowed a "crushing response" to Israel's actions.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k36tbfng_israel-jet-_625x300_20_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The airstrikes come just a day after Hezbollah's leader, Hassan Nasrallah, vowed revenge.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thai-woman-64-rescued-after-being-in-pythons-grip-for-2-hours-6606269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thai Woman, 64, Rescued After Being In Python's Grip For 2 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thai-woman-64-rescued-after-being-in-pythons-grip-for-2-hours-6606269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 07:01:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 64-year-old woman in Thailand has been rescued by police after being strangled by a huge python for two hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 64-year-old woman in Thailand has been rescued by police after being strangled by a huge python for two hours. According to <em>CBS News</em>, the incident took place on Tuesday. The woman, identified as Arom, was doing the dishes at her home outside Bangkok when she felt a sharp pain in her thigh and looked down to see a 13-to16 foot python taking hold of her. "I was about to scoop some water and when I sat down it bit me immediately. When I looked I saw the snake wrapping around me," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The giant python coiled itself around the 64-year-old's torso, squeezing her down on the flood of her kitchen, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/python-squeezes-woman-thailand-2-hours-before-rescue-by-police/" rel="noindex, nofollow">outlet </a>reported. The woman struggled to free herself from the snake's tightening coils for two hours without success, the cops said.</p>

<p>"I grabbed it by the head, but it wouldn't release me," she said. "It only tightened."</p>

<p>The woman cried out for help, but no one answered initially. Later, one of her neighbours heard her distressed calls and sought assistance from the police.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We were shocked to see the lady was tied down on the floor with the python wrapping around (her)," Police Major Sergeant Anusorn Wongmalee of the Phra Samut Chedi Police Station in Samut Prakan, a province south of Bangkok, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/19/asia/thailand-woman-python-strangled-intl-hnk/index.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>CNN</em></a>. "The snake was really big."</p>

<p>Police and animal control officers used a crowbar to hit the snake on the head until it released its grip and slithered away before it could be captured. In all, Ms Arom spent about two hours in the clutches of the python before being freed. She was later treated for several bites, according to the police.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The snake escaped afterwards, cops said, adding: "We couldn't catch it."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-year-old-japanese-schoolboy-stabbed-to-death-in-china-6604881">10-Year-Old Japanese Schoolboy Stabbed To Death In China</a></strong></p>

<p>Notably, pythons are non-venomous constrictors, which kill their prey by gradually squeezing the breath out of it. Thailand is home to 250 snake species, including three varieties of pythons - the reticulated, Burmese and Blood - according to Thai National Parks.</p>

<p>According to Thailand's National Health Security Office, some 12,000 people were treated for venomous snake and animal bites in the country last year. Twenty-six people died from snake bites during that period, official figures show.</p>

<p>Deaths by large constrictors are considered rare, but several people in Indonesia have also been killed by pythons in recent years. Last month, a woman was found dead inside the belly of a snake after it swallowed her whole in Siteba village, in South Sulawesi province. In June a woman was found dead inside the belly of a reticulated python in another district of South Sulawesi.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/9f8vvbuo_python-generic_625x300_29_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The snake escaped afterwards, cops said. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-cop-mickey-stines-arrested-for-shooting-dead-judge-kevin-mullins-inside-his-office-6606238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Cop Shoots Dead Judge Inside His Office After Argument, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-cop-mickey-stines-arrested-for-shooting-dead-judge-kevin-mullins-inside-his-office-6606238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:56:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A spokesperson for police said the shooting occurred after an argument between Letcher County Sheriff Mickey Stines and judge Kevin Mullins.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A county sheriff was charged with murder Thursday after he allegedly shot and killed a district court judge in the southern US state of Kentucky. Letcher County Sheriff Mickey Stines was taken into custody in connection with a shooting at the Letcher County courthouse, the Louisville Courier Journal newspaper reported.</p>

<p>He was charged with one count of murder in the first degree, according to CBS News.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A spokesperson for police told the outlet the shooting occurred after an argument between Stines and judge Kevin Mullins, 54, in the latter's office.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Investigators have not yet announced a motive.</p>

<p>Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear confirmed the shooting in a post on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>"Sadly, I have been informed that a district judge in Letcher County was shot and killed in his chambers this afternoon," Beshear said.</p>

<p>"There is far too much violence in this world, and I pray there is a path to a better tomorrow."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sadly, I have been informed that a district judge in Letcher County was shot and killed in his chambers this afternoon.<br />
<br />
There is far too much violence in this world, and I pray there is a path to a better tomorrow. ^AB</p>
— Governor Andy Beshear (@GovAndyBeshear) <a href="https://twitter.com/GovAndyBeshear/status/1836880370676928513?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Gun violence is common in the United States, a country where there are more firearms than people.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, a man shot and injured five people on a Kentucky highway. The gunman's body was found Wednesday after a 10-day manhunt.</p>

<p>Despite polls showing Americans favor more gun restrictions, a powerful gun rights lobby, constitutional protections and a passionate culture around firearm ownership mean that attempts to clamp down on gun rights are always met with stiff political resistance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/uvpcdhno_mickey-stines_625x300_20_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Investigators have not yet announced a motive.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miss-india-worldwide-2024-dhruvi-patel-from-us-wins-miss-india-worldwide-2024-6606073]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dhruvi Patel From US Wins Miss India Worldwide 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miss-india-worldwide-2024-dhruvi-patel-from-us-wins-miss-india-worldwide-2024-6606073]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:51:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dhruvi Patel, a Computer Information System student from the USA, has been declared the winner of Miss India Worldwide 2024, the longest running Indian pageant outside of India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dhruvi Patel, a Computer Information System student from the USA, has been declared the winner of Miss India Worldwide 2024, the longest running Indian pageant outside of India.</p>

<p>Dhruvi aspires to be a Bollywood actor and UNICEF Ambassador.</p>

<p>"Winning Miss India Worldwide is such an incredible honour. It's more than a crown - it represents my heritage, my values, and the opportunity to inspire others on a global scale," Dhruvi said after her crowning in Edison, New Jersey.</p>

<p>Lisa Abdoelhak from Suriname was declared the first runner-up, while Malvika Sharma from the Netherlands was adjudged the second runner-up in the same race.</p>

<p>In the Mrs category, SuAnn Mouttet from Trinidad and Tobago was the winner, with Sneha Nambiar the first and Pawandip Kaur from the United Kingdom the second-runner up.</p>

<p>In the Teen category, Sierra Suret from Guadeloupe was crowned Miss Teen India Worldwide.</p>

<p>Shreya Singh from the Netherlands and Shradha Tedjoe from Suriname were declared the first and second runners-up.</p>

<p>The beauty pageant is organised by New York-based India Festival Committee and is headed by Indian-Americans Neelam and Dharmatma Saran.</p>

<p>The crown is celebrating its 31st anniversary this year.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kd05chcg_dhruvi-patel-miss-india-worldwide-2024_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dhruvi Patel has been declared the winner of Miss India Worldwide 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/west-cant-confine-india-into-one-narrative-uk-based-sanskrit-scholar-6606163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[West Can't Confine India Into One Narrative: UK Based Sanskrit Scholar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/west-cant-confine-india-into-one-narrative-uk-based-sanskrit-scholar-6606163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:32:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Professor James Hegarty, an academic in Sanskrit and Indian Religions, who currently heads the School of History, Archaeology, and Religion at Cardiff University said that the West cannot confine India into a single narrative.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Professor James Hegarty, an academic in Sanskrit and Indian Religions, who currently heads the School of History, Archaeology, and Religion at Cardiff University said that the West cannot confine India into a single narrative.</p>

<p>Prof. Hegarty shared his journey with IANS and spoke on Indian religious studies, his academic interests, and how engaging with Sanskrit and Hinduism shaped his career and perspective on life.</p>

<p>When asked about the characters that intrigued him the most, Prof. Hegarty spoke with admiration about Krishna: "The description of Krishna as both man and god is fascinating. He is a layered character, and the stories about him in the Mahabharata are compelling. I started studying Sanskrit for academic purposes, but over the years it also influenced me personally."</p>

<p>His growing connection to Indian spirituality deepened during a recent visit to a BAPS Swaminarayan temple. "I was so much at peace there. I look at Sanskrit and Hinduism differently today than when I first started."</p>

<p>Prof. Hegarty studied M.A. in Religions and Theology at the University of Manchester. He later obtained his PhD in Sanskrit Literature, with his graduate studies supported by the British Academy and the Arts and Humanities Research Council.</p>

<p>One of the figures that particularly captivated him was Gandhari, whom he described as a symbol of sacrifice and moral strength.</p>

<p>"Gandhari is a pivotal character in the Mahabharata. She voluntarily blindfolded herself in solidarity with her blind husband, Dhritarashtra, and despite her immense personal losses, she remained morally upright. Her clarity and adherence to dharma in the face of tragedy make her such a complex and revered figure."</p>

<p>On Western biases toward India, Professor Hegarty said, "The West often views India primarily as a spiritual nation, which is true to an extent, but India is far more complex than that. We cannot confine the country to a single category or perspective."</p>

<p>Reflecting on the formative influences in his life, Prof. Hegarty said: "I had very liberal grandparents who encouraged me to engage with global arts and literature and to reach beyond European material, which made all the difference. I watched Peter Brook's Mahabharata and then the one on Doordarshan with subtitles when I was only 14. I would read political comic books criticising the West, and I was deeply interested in exploring non-Western cultures."</p>

<p>Even as a teenager, Prof. Hegarty was drawn to Indian literature and its philosophical nuances, contrasting with the predominantly Western narratives he encountered in his education.</p>

<p>"I also went to a very Christian school. At that point, I remember thinking I was saving the world by leaving behind the grand stories of the West - stories that started with Greece and ended with England with not much in between! This early exposure to Indian mythology and religion sparked a lifelong academic interest, particularly in the stories of the Mahabharata," he said.</p>

<p>Delving deeper into his academic interests, Prof. Hegarty shared: "I am fascinated by the history of religions in South Asia. I have written about the Hindu, Buddhist, Jain, Sikh, and Christian traditions in the region. In particular, I am interested in how South Asians use religious texts, especially religious stories, to negotiate their understanding of themselves and the world around them. This includes what we ordinarily associate with religion - ideas of god or gods or the nature of the good life - and other forms of knowledge, such as how the past is understood or how political life is conceptualised."</p>

<p>Prof. Hegarty's journey into the depths of the Mahabharata started during his second year of university when he studied the text with Professor Jacqueline Suthren Hirst.</p>

<p>"I remember reading the Draupadi disrobing sequence and discussing the stories within stories. We also explored how these narratives were represented across various media - books, television, etc. My parents, who have a global perspective and have always questioned the status quo, found it fascinating. It was a multidimensional exploration of storytelling, and that's when my professor convinced me there was no point in reading the Mahabharata in English. That's how I was led to read it in Sanskrit."</p>

<p>In addition to his teaching and research, Prof. Hegarty is the author of several notable works, including Religion, Narrative and Public Imagination in South Asia (Routledge, 2012), and co-editor of the forthcoming Oxford Handbook of Hindu Literature.</p>

<p>He has published extensively on Sanskrit, Pali, and vernacular sources, covering many South Asian religious traditions, from Hinduism and Buddhism to Jainism and Sikhism.</p>

<p>His research also touches on the history of Christianity in early South Asia and 19th-century missionary history.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jpc8k9og_-prof-james-hegarty-_625x300_20_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Professor JamesHegarty said that the West cannot confine India into a single narrative.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-court-order-elon-musks-x-goes-offline-again-in-brazil-6606039]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Court Order, X Goes Offline Again In Brazil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-court-order-elon-musks-x-goes-offline-again-in-brazil-6606039]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 05:59:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X social media platform went back offline in Brazil Thursday, a day after it resumed service in contravention of a judicial ban, internet providers said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X social media platform went back offline in Brazil Thursday, a day after it resumed service in contravention of a judicial ban, internet providers said.</p>

<p>Brazil's Supreme Court had earlier in the day ordered X to suspend access to the platform, finding the company had "unlawfully, persistently and intentionally" flouted judicial rulings and would risk a daily fine of more than $900,000 for non-compliance.</p>

<p>The former Twitter was banned last month in Latin America's largest nation, but access to the phone app returned Wednesday in what the government slammed as a deliberate violation of the suspension.</p>

<p>X said the return of its service was "inadvertent and temporary."</p>

<p>On Thursday, the ABRINT association of internet providers said the network went offline again "just before 4:00 pm" local time, and was once again "blocked."</p>

<p>Judge Alexandre de Moraes in a court order Thursday called X "recalcitrant" and ordered state telecommunications agency Anatel to take the necessary measures to once again block access to the network.</p>

<p>The high-profile judge has been engaged in a long feud with South African-born billionaire Musk as part of his drive to crack down on disinformation in Brazil.</p>

<p>His suspension of X last month came after Musk refused to remove dozens of right-wing accounts accused of spreading fake news, and then failed to name a new legal representative in the country as ordered.</p>

<p>- Musk assets frozen -</p>

<p>The suspension infuriated Musk and the far-right, and has fueled a fierce debate on freedom of expression and the limits of social networks, both inside and outside the country.</p>

<p>The social media platform had more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<p>Moraes has also frozen the assets of X and Musk's satellite internet operator Starlink -- which has been operating in Brazil since 2022, especially in remote communities in the Amazon -- to ensure payment of fines imposed on the social network for flouting court orders.</p>

<p>Last week, Moraes ordered the transfer of about $3 million from Musk's companies to pay fines incurred by X.</p>

<p>Musk has repeatedly hit out at Moraes in social media posts, calling him an "evil dictator" and dubbing him "Voldemort" after the villain from the "Harry Potter" series.</p>

<p>Internet providers explained that X became accessible again Wednesday after an automatic update to the phone application.</p>

<p>New software allowed the app to use constantly changing identifying IP addresses via a service called Cloudflare, making it harder to block.</p>

<p>ABRINT said Thursday that X had now stopped using Cloudflare.</p>

<p>While X said the restoration of service was unintentional, Anatel said the company had acted with "deliberate intention" to skirt the Supreme Court order.</p>

<p>Anatel said Thursday it had "identified a mechanism which, we hope" will block the service again.</p>

<p>When banning X, Moraes also ruled that those using "technological subterfuges" such as virtual private networks (VPNs) to access the blocked site could be fined up to $9,000.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/ofjn3hr_x-twitter_625x300_17_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[X said the return of its service was "inadvertent and temporary."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-meet-zelensky-next-week-discuss-war-situation-white-house-6606027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden To Meet Zelensky Next Week, Discuss War Situation: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-meet-zelensky-next-week-discuss-war-situation-white-house-6606027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 05:52:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden will meet Ukrainian counterpart Volodymyr Zelenskyy at the White House on September 26, the White House has announced. Zelenskyy will also meet US Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden will meet Ukrainian counterpart Volodymyr Zelenskyy at the White House on September 26, the White House has announced. Zelenskyy will also meet US Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>During the meeting, the leaders will discuss the state of war between Russia and Ukraine, including Kyiv's strategy planning and the US' support for Ukraine's defence against Russia amid the ongoing war.</p>

<p>In a statement, White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said, "On Thursday, September 26, President Biden will meet with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine at the White House. Vice President Harris will also meet separately with President Zelenskyy at the White House."</p>

<p>"The leaders will discuss the state of the war between Russia and Ukraine, including Ukraine's strategic planning and U.S. support for Ukraine in its defense against Russian aggression. The President and Vice President will emphasize their unshakeable commitment to stand with Ukraine until it aprevails in this war," she added.</p>

<p>During his meeting with Biden, Zelenskyy will present Ukraine's Plan for Victory. The Ukrainian President expects to discuss the details of this plan and the US' support for Ukraine in its right to freedom. He will address the United Nations General Assembly and meet world leaders on the sidelines of UNGA.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Ukrainian President's Office stated, "Next week, President of Ukraine Volodymyr Zelenskyy will visit the United States. The President of Ukraine will address the UN General Assembly and meet with representatives of American defense and energy companies, and the Ukrainian community. The Head of State will hold bilateral negotiations with leaders of countries and international organizations on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly."</p>

<p>"Volodymyr Zelenskyy will meet with US President Joe Biden to present the Plan for Victory. The President of Ukraine expects to discuss the details of this plan as well as the United States' support for Ukraine in its fight for freedom," it added.</p>

<p>During his visit, Ukraine's President will meet representatives of the US Congress from both parties and former US President Donald Trump.</p>

<p>It is pertinent to note that the US has been providing assistance to Ukraine since its war with Russia began in 2022. The United States has also imposed sanctions on Russia.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, White House National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan stated that Biden will meet with Volodymyr Zelenskyy, his counterpart from Ukraine, this month, and that Washington is preparing a "substantial" round of further help for Kyiv.</p>

<p>"I do think we need a comprehensive strategy for success in this war, and that is what President Zelenskyy says he is bringing," Sullivan said.</p>

<p>Notably, Sullivan delivered his remarks via videolink at the Yalta European Strategy conference in Kyiv, Al Jazeera reported.</p>

<p>"So we are very much looking forward to sitting down and talking that through, and President Biden is eager for that conversation," he said.</p>

<p>Sullivan said that the recent events in the region are of "unique concern." In addition, the White House advisor stated that Biden is attempting to place Ukraine in the "best possible position to prevail" in his remaining months in office, Al Jazeera reported. Notably, Biden is not running for reelection, and his tenure expires in January.</p>

<p>"President Zelenskyy has said that ultimately this war has to end through negotiations, and we need them to be strong in those negotiations," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pjqn6kqg_joe-biden-zelensky_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Bide will meet his counterpart Volodymyr Zelenskyy at the White House on September 26]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-destroys-1-000-hezbollah-rocket-launcher-barrels-says-military-6605651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Destroys 1,000 Hezbollah Rocket Launcher Barrels, Says Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-destroys-1-000-hezbollah-rocket-launcher-barrels-says-military-6605651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 03:46:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli fighter jets pounded Hezbollah targets in southern Lebanon late on Thursday, striking hundreds of rocket launcher barrels that were set to be used to immediately fire toward Israeli territory, the military said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Israeli fighter jets pounded Hezbollah targets in southern Lebanon late on Thursday, striking hundreds of rocket launcher barrels that were set to be used to immediately fire toward Israeli territory, the military said.</p>

<p>It said that since the afternoon, fighter jets struck some 100 rocket launchers consisting of about 1,000 barrels.</p>

<p>"The IDF (Israel Defense Forces) will continue to operate to degrade the Hezbollah terrorist organization's infrastructure and capabilities in order to defend the State of Israel," the IDF said.</p>

<p>The intense barrage followed attacks earlier in the week attributed by Lebanon and Hezbollah to Israel that blew up Hezbollah radios and pagers, killing 37 people and wounding about 3,000 in Lebanon.</p>

<p>In Thursday's late operation, Israel launched dozens of bombs across southern Lebanon, three Lebanese security sources said. There were no immediate reports of casualties.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said that Israel will keep up military action against Hezbollah.</p>

<p>British Foreign Secretary David Lammy called for an immediate ceasefire between Israel and Lebanon's Hezbollah after a week of escalation. The U.S. has also expressed fears of further escalation.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed to return tens of thousands of residents evacuated from northern border areas to their homes. Hezbollah</p>

<p>In a show of support with Hamas after the Oct. 7 attacks, Iran-backed Hezbollah began firing rockets into northern Israel, forcing many residents to flee to the center of the country. Israel and Hezbollah have been trading fire daily since.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/g7dminco_yoav-gallant-_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said that Israel will keep up military action against Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airlines-suspend-flights-as-middle-east-tensions-rise-6605511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Airlines Suspend Flights As Middle East Tensions Rise]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airlines-suspend-flights-as-middle-east-tensions-rise-6605511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 02:51:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Concerns over a wider conflict in the Middle East have prompted international airlines to suspend flights to the region or to avoid affected air space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Concerns over a wider conflict in the Middle East have prompted international airlines to suspend flights to the region or to avoid affected air space.</p>

<p>Below are some of the airlines that have adjusted services to and from the region:</p>

<p><strong>AIR ALGERIE</strong></p>

<p>The Algerian airline suspended flights to and from Lebanon until further notice.</p>

<p><strong>AIRBALTIC</strong></p>

<p>Latvia's airBaltic plans to resume flights between Riga and Tel Aviv on Sept. 17, it said via email on Sept. 16.</p>

<p><strong>AIR FRANCE-KLM</strong></p>

<p>Air France said on Sept. 17 it was suspending services to Beirut and Tel Aviv up to and including Sept. 19.</p>

<p>KLM cancelled all flights to and from Tel Aviv until Oct. 26. The Franco-Dutch group's low-cost unit Transavia cancelled flights to and from Tel Aviv until March 31, 2025, and flights to Amman and Beirut until Nov. 3.</p>

<p><strong>AIR INDIA</strong></p>

<p>The Indian flag carrier suspended scheduled flights to and from Tel Aviv until further notice.</p>

<p><strong>CATHAY PACIFIC</strong></p>

<p>Hong Kong-based Cathay Pacific cancelled all flights to Tel Aviv until March 27, 2025.</p>

<p><strong>DELTA AIR LINES</strong></p>

<p>The U.S. carrier said it will pause its flights between New York and Tel Aviv through Dec. 31.</p>

<p><strong>EASYJET</strong></p>

<p>The UK budget airline stopped flying to and from Tel Aviv in April and will resume flights on March 30, 2025, a spokesperson said.</p>

<p>IAG</p>

<p>IAG-owned Spanish low-cost carrier Vueling cancelled its operations to Tel Aviv until Jan. 12, 2025, it said in an e-mailed comment. Flights to Amman have been cancelled until further notice, the airline added.</p>

<p>LOT</p>

<p>The Polish flag carrier suspended flights to Lebanon until further notice, while flights to Tel Aviv are now operating regularly, it said in an emailed comment on Sept. 10.</p>

<p><strong>LUFTHANSA GROUP</strong></p>

<p>The German airline group said on Sept. 17 it was suspending all connections to and from Tel Aviv and Tehran up to and including Sept. 19. The airline had resumed flights to Tel Aviv on Sept. 5, while flights to Beirut will remain suspended through Sept. 30.</p>

<p>Swiss International Air Lines, also a part of the Lufthansa Group, separately said it had suspended flights to Beirut until the end of October.</p>

<p><strong>RYANAIR</strong></p>

<p>Europe's biggest budget airline cancelled flights to and from Tel Aviv until Oct. 26, citing "operational restrictions."</p>

<p><strong>SUNDAIR</strong></p>

<p>The German airline cancelled all flights between Bremen and Beirut until Oct. 23.</p>

<p><strong>SUNEXPRESS</strong></p>

<p>SunExpress, a joint venture between Turkish Airlines and Lufthansa, suspended flights to Beirut through Dec. 17.</p>

<p><strong>UNITED AIRLINES</strong></p>

<p>The Chicago-based airline suspended flights to Tel Aviv for the foreseeable future due to security reasons.</p>

<p><strong>LEBANESE AIRSPACE ALERTS</strong></p>

<p>Britain advised UK airlines not to enter Lebanese airspace from Aug. 8 until Nov. 4 citing "potential risk to aviation from military activity".</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/t1hcc7rg_airplane-generic_625x300_21_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Algerian airline suspended flights to and from Lebanon until further notice.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-2024-key-candidates-ranil-wickremesinghe-sajith-premadasa-anura-kumara-dissanayake-namal-rajapaksa-nuwan-bopage-6605432]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Elections: A Look At The 5 Key Candidates And What They Stand For]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-2024-key-candidates-ranil-wickremesinghe-sajith-premadasa-anura-kumara-dissanayake-namal-rajapaksa-nuwan-bopage-6605432]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 02:23:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka, which is slowly recovering from its worst-ever economic crisis, will vote to elect the next President on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka, which is slowly recovering from its worst-ever economic crisis, will vote to elect the next President on Saturday. The cash-strapped island nation is currently being led by President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who is seeking a re-election to continue with bold reforms to help revive the economy.</p>

<p>President Ranil Wickremesinghe, 75, is seeking a fresh mandate after claiming credit for stabilising the economy and bringing an end to months of food, fuel and medicine shortages.</p>

<p>In 2022, when Ranil Wickremesinghe took charge as President, Sri Lanka was dealing with civil unrest spurred by the economic crisis. There were protests across the nation which led to thousands storming the Presidential palace which was then occupied by Mr Wickremesinghe's predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who fled the country. Mr Wickremesinghe took charge and restored calm and helped revived the economy by taking some tough decisions.</p>

<p>The 2024 election is key to deciding the future of reforms in the economically fragile nation.</p>

<p>Speaking with NDTV, Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe said on Thursday that his vision for future ties with India holds a stronger economic relationship. "We want to encourage more investments from India and more tourists from India. We are working together with India on infrastructure projects like the Trincomalee Harbour," he said.</p>

<p>"I took over as President when the country was in utter chaos and no one thought we could stabilise this fast. But I knew from experience that we could go ahead provided we had the support of the International Monetary Fund and our creditors," the President said, adding that "I have ensured we come back to normalcy. Law and order is functioning, democracy is functioning and although we have stabilised the economy, now we have to decide our path. Are we going to get into the same old ways or are we working towards (building) a strong export economy? I have asked for a mandate to go ahead."</p>

<p>However, Mr Wickremesinghe faces a tough electoral battle from two contenders. In total, President Wickremesinghe is among 38 candidates contesting Sri Lanka's presidential election.</p>

<p>This year's election is dominated by two major alliances, the SJB (Samagi Jana Balawegaya) and the NPP (National People's Power), apart from various smaller parties and independent candidates.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the 5 main contenders in the 2024 Sri Lanka Elections:</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>RANIL WICKREMESINGHE</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/092fhub8_ranil-wickremesinghe-afp-650_625x300_13_July_22.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>75-year-old Ranil Wickremesinghe is a lawyer who has served as prime minister for a record six times. His party holds only one seat in parliament and will need to drum up support from key parties to bolster his chances.</p>

<p>As the leader of the United National Party or UNP, he took office in July 2022 after widespread protests unleashed by the debilitating financial crisis forced his predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa to flee Sri Lanka and later resign.</p>

<p>The Sri Lankan Parliament elected Ranil Wickremesinghe to serve out the rest of the five-year term of Mr Rajapaksa, who took office in 2019.</p>

<p>Ranil Wickremesinghe's re-election bid failed to get formal backing from the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), the party with the most seats in the 225-member parliament, but the support of more than 90 lawmakers puts him in strong position. He is contesting as an independent candidate.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>SAJITH PREMADASA</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1vco5cjs_sajith-premadasa_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The 57 year-old Opposition leader and son of former President Ranasinghe Premadasa, he leads the Samagi Jana Balawegaya or SJB that separated from Mr Wickremesinghe's UNP in 2020.</p>

<p>His centrist, more left-leaning party has called for changes to the $2.9 billion bailout programme with the International Monetary Fund and outlined plans to adjust some targets, such as changing taxes to reduce the cost of living.</p>

<p>Premadasa favours a mix of interventionist and free-market economic policies.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>ANURA KUMARA DISSANAYAKE</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vu6mofi4_anura-kumara-dissanayake_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The 55-year-old leader, who holds just three seats in parliament, stands for tough anti-corruption measures and pro-poor policies have given a popular boost to his candidacy.</p>

<p>He will contest under the National People's Power or NPP coalition, which includes his Marxist-leaning party People's Liberation Front or PLF. His party has traditionally backed stronger state intervention and more closed market economic policies.</p>

<p>A pre-election opinion survey showed Mr Dissanayake was leading in voting preferences at 36%, followed by Mr Premadasa and Mr Wickremesinghe at third.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>NAMAL RAJAPAKSA</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o1meeqe8_namal-rajapaksa_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The 38-year-old leader is a scion of the powerful Rajapaksa family that produced two presidents - his father Mahinda and uncle Gotabaya - Namal is a surprise entrant, as the candidate of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna or SLPP, founded by another uncle, Basil.</p>

<p>He faces the daunting task of keeping the party unified to counter Mr Wickremesinghe's chances of winning.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>NUWAN BOPAGE</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k6podgso_nuwan-bopage_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>40-year-old Nuwan Bopage is the presidential candidate of the Peoples' Struggle Alliance or PSA. He hopes to tap into the remnants of the massive people's uprising that deposed Gotabaya Rajapaksa two years ago.</p>

<p>He has taken a strong anti-corruption stance, backs more pro-poor policies and opposes Sri Lanka's alignment with the IMF programme.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sj6lisg4_ranil-wickremesinghe-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Supporters of Sri Lanka's president Ranil Wickremesinghe attend his final election campaign rally.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>