<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:45:05 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/german-man-60-seventh-person-to-be-likely-cured-of-hiv-doctors-6134527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[German Man, 60, Seventh Person To Be Likely "Cured" Of HIV: Doctors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/german-man-60-seventh-person-to-be-likely-cured-of-hiv-doctors-6134527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:45:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 60-year-old German man is likely the seventh person to be effectively cured of HIV after receiving a stem cell transplant, doctors announced on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 60-year-old German man is likely the seventh person to be effectively cured of HIV after receiving a stem cell transplant, doctors announced on Thursday.</p>

<p>The painful and risky procedure is for people who have both HIV and aggressive leukaemia, so is not an option for almost all of the nearly 40 million people living with the deadly virus across the world.</p>

<p>The German man, who wished to remain anonymous, was dubbed the "next Berlin patient".</p>

<p>The original Berlin patient, Timothy Ray Brown, was the first person declared cured of HIV back in 2008. Brown died from cancer in 2020.</p>

<p>The second man from Berlin to achieve long-term HIV remission was announced ahead of the 25th International AIDS Conference being held in the German city of Munich next week.</p>

<p>He was first diagnosed with HIV in 2009, according to the research abstract being presented at the conference.</p>

<p>The man received a bone marrow transplant for his leukaemia in 2015. The procedure, which has a 10 percent risk of death, essentially replaces a person's immune system.</p>

<p>Then he stopped taking anti-retroviral drugs -- which reduce the amount of HIV in the blood -- in late 2018.</p>

<p>Nearly six years later, he appears to be both HIV and cancer-free, the medical researchers said.</p>

<p>Christian Gaebler, a doctor-researcher at Berlin's Charite University Hospital treating the patient, told AFP that the team cannot be "absolutely certain" every last trace of HIV has been eradicated.</p>

<p>But "the patient's case is highly suggestive of an HIV cure," Gaebler added. "He feels well and is enthusiastic about contributing to our research efforts."</p>

<p><strong>"Promising" For Wider Cure</strong></p>

<p>International AIDS Society President Sharon Lewin said researchers hesitate to use the word "cure" because it is not clear how long they need to follow up on such cases.</p>

<p>But more than five years in remission means the man "would be close" to being considered cured, she told a press conference.</p>

<p>There is an important difference between the man's case and the other HIV patients who have reached long-term remission, she said.</p>

<p>All but one of the other patients received stem cells from donors with a rare mutation in which part of their CCR5 gene was missing, blocking HIV from entering their body's cells.</p>

<p>Those donors had inherited two copies of the mutated CCR5 gene -- one from each parent -- making them "essentially immune" to HIV, Lewin said.</p>

<p>But the new Berlin patient is the first to have received stem cells from a donor who had inherited only one copy of the mutated gene.</p>

<p>Around 15 percent of people of European origin have one mutated copy, compared to one percent for both.</p>

<p>Researchers hope the latest success means there will be a much larger potential donor pool in the future.</p>

<p>The new case is also "promising" for the wider search for an HIV cure that works for all patients, Lewin said.</p>

<p>This is "because it suggests that you don't actually have to get rid of every single piece of CCR5 for gene therapy to work," she added.</p>

<p>The Geneva patient, whose case was announced at last year's AIDS conference, is the other exception among the seven. He received a transplant from a donor without any CCR5 mutations -- yet still achieved long-term remission.</p>

<p>This showed that the effectiveness of the procedure was not just down to the CCR5 gene, Lewin said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/j927li4s_hiv-generic_625x300_05_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The success means there will be a much larger potential donor pool, researchers hope (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-cancels-another-1-2-billion-in-student-debt-as-presidential-vote-nears-6134325]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Cancels Another $1.2 Billion In Student Debt As Vote Nears]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-cancels-another-1-2-billion-in-student-debt-as-presidential-vote-nears-6134325]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:17:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Thursday he was extending his student loan forgiveness program by canceling the loans of an additional 35,000 Americans as he seeks reelection.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said Thursday he was extending his student loan forgiveness program by canceling the loans of an additional 35,000 Americans as he seeks reelection.</p>

<p>The latest move - amounting to $1.2 billion in student debt - brings to 4.76 million the number of people "who benefitted from our various debt relief actions", he said in a statement.</p>

<p>The borrowers, who will get an average of $35,000 in debt cancellation, include teachers, nurses, police officials, and first responders.</p>

<p>The announcement came on the final day of the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, where Donald Trump will accept the Republican nomination for the November election.</p>

<p>Biden vowed Thursday to "never stop working to make higher education affordable -- no matter how many times Republican elected officials try to stop us."</p>

<p>Earlier this year Biden unveiled fresh plans to reduce student loan debt for tens of millions of Americans, in his bid to win over young voters.</p>

<p>That was after the conservative-dominated US Supreme Court last year struck down the Democrat's earlier proposals to cancel several hundred billion dollars of debt.</p>

<p>Last month he cancelled debt owed by 160,000 people, while earlier in the year he announced student debt relief for 150,000 others.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6v5grhls_joe-biden_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last month, Joe Biden cancelled debt owed by 160,000 people (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-state-tv-btv-headquarters-set-ablaze-many-trapped-station-6134279]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh State TV Headquarters Set Ablaze, "Many" Trapped: Network]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-state-tv-btv-headquarters-set-ablaze-many-trapped-station-6134279]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:11:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protesters set fire to the headquarters of Bangladesh's main state broadcaster BTV on Thursday with "many people" trapped inside its offices, the network said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protesters set fire to the headquarters of Bangladesh's main state broadcaster BTV on Thursday with "many people" trapped inside its offices, the network said.</p>

<p>An official at the station, speaking to AFP on condition of anonymity, said that hundreds of protesters had stormed the premises, setting alight at least 60 vehicles and an office building.</p>

<p>"They first torched a police post at Rampura after police opened fire at them," he said, referring to a neighbourhood in the capital Dhaka.</p>

<p>"They chased the police officers when they took refuge at the BTV office. Angry protesters then caused mayhem here."</p>

<p>A post on BTV's verified Facebook page said the fire was "catastrophic" and "spreading fast".</p>

<p>"We seek the cooperation of the Fire Service. Many people are trapped inside," the broadcaster said.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's police force has this week stepped up a violent crackdown on weekslong student protests demanding reforms to civil service hiring rules.</p>

<p>At least 22 people have died in the clashes so far this week.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/c590rf94_fire-generic_625x300_17_May_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hundreds of protesters set fire to the reception building, the network said (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-birth-outcome-of-freezing-eggs-as-effective-as-regular-ivf-6131478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Shows Birth Outcome Of Freezing Eggs As Effective As Regular IVF]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-birth-outcome-of-freezing-eggs-as-effective-as-regular-ivf-6131478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:09:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Success rates of freezing eggs are comparable to those obtained by normal in vitro fertilisation (IVF) and are subject to the same variables of female age and embryo quality, according to a study.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Success rates of freezing eggs are comparable to those obtained by normal in vitro fertilisation (IVF) and are subject to the same variables of female age and embryo quality, according to a study.</p>

<p>When compared to other similar large-scale research conducted on egg freezing in other countries, the findings of this 15-year-long study based on nearly 30,000 frozen eggs revealed an overall live birth rate of 26 per cent per embryo transfer, as per the study published in the peer-reviewed journal Reproductive Biomedicine Online.</p>

<p>This varied depending on the age at which the eggs were frozen, with a lower rate in the over-35s and only 5 per cent in the over-40s.</p>

<p>After transferring all embryos developed from thawed eggs, the total live birth rate was 34 per cent, which increased to 45 per cent in women who had frozen their eggs before the age of 36, according to the study.</p>

<p>"These are results comparable with those nationally recorded in routine IVF," said Professor Nick Macklon, senior author of the study and Medical Director of the London Women's Clinic.</p>

<p>The number of women seeking egg-freezing treatment has increased from 150 in 2015 to over 800 in 2022, yet only 14 per cent return to thaw their eggs. Out of 2,171 patients, 299 returned, completing 332 thaw cycles.</p>

<p>The cumulative live birth rate is 36 per cent, rising to 57 per cent for those who froze eggs under age 35. "Freeze-all" cycles had a 30 per cent live birth rate, improving to 40 per cent with chromosomal screening (PGT-A). All live births in women aged 40 were from screened embryos.</p>

<p>Despite some scepticism, these results indicate that egg freezing and thawing offer a viable path to pregnancy, akin to IVF.</p>

<p>The study noted that "egg freezing and thawing can provide a very real opportunity for women to achieve pregnancy and live birth."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/b2bmik7k_pregnancy-generic-pregnant-generic-pixabay_625x300_30_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Results indicate egg freezing and thawing offer a viable path to pregnancy. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ursula-von-der-leyen-wins-second-term-as-top-eu-leader-6133789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ursula Von Der Leyen Wins Second Term As Top EU Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ursula-von-der-leyen-wins-second-term-as-top-eu-leader-6133789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 18:03:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen was elected for a second term on Thursday after pledging to create a continental "defence union" and stay the course on Europe's green transition while cushioning its burden on industry.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen was elected for a second term on Thursday after pledging to create a continental "defence union" and stay the course on Europe's green transition while cushioning its burden on industry.</p>

<p>Members of the European Parliament backed von der Leyen's bid for another five-year term at the helm of the European Union's powerful executive body with 401 votes in her favour and 284 against in a secret ballot in the 720-member chamber.</p>

<p>In an address to the Parliament in Strasbourg earlier in the day, von der Leyen laid out a programme focused on prosperity and security, shaped by the challenges of Russia's war in Ukraine, global economic competition and climate change.</p>

<p>"The next five years will define Europe's place in the world for the next five decades. It will decide whether we shape our own future or let it be shaped by events or by others," von der Leyen said ahead of a secret ballot on her candidacy.</p>

<p>She stressed the need not to backtrack on the "Green Deal" transformation of the EU economy to fight climate change - a key pledge for Green lawmakers, who joined centre-right, centre-left and liberal groups in backing her for the post.</p>

<p>After pledging to support Ukraine for as long as it takes in its fight against Russia, von der Leyen said Europe's liberty was at stake and it must invest more in defence.</p>

<p>Von der Leyen, a centre-right former German defence minister, pledged to create "a true European Defence Union", with flagship projects on air and cyber defence.</p>

<p>The plan sparked criticism from the Kremlin, which said it</p>

<p>reflected an attitude of "militarisation (and) confrontation".</p>

<p>Von der Leyen blasted Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban's recent visit to Russian President Vladimir Putin in Moscow as an "appeasement mission", winning broad applause from lawmakers.</p>

<p>Defence policy in Europe has traditionally been the domain of national governments and NATO.</p>

<p>But following Russia's attack on Ukraine and amid uncertainty over how much Europe will be able to rely on the United States for its protection should Donald Trump win the U.S. presidential election in November, the European Commission is seeking to push more joint European defence projects.</p>

<p>Von der Leyen also promised a raft of climate policies including a legally-binding EU target to cut emissions by 90% by 2040, compared to 1990 levels.</p>

<p>She also pledged new measures to help European industries stay competitive while they invest in curbing emissions.</p>

<p><strong>Green Support</strong></p>

<p>The Greens' decision to join the informal alliance of parties that supports von der Leyen ensured her margin of victory was fairly comfortable. She needed 361 votes to secure a majority in the chamber.</p>

<p>Her own coalition of the centre-right, centre-left and liberals has 401 seats, but some of its members were expected to vote against her in the secret vote.</p>

<p>She might also promise tighter EU border controls and stronger police cooperation against crime.</p>

<p>Von der Leyen's re-election provides continuity in the European Union's key institution at a time of external and internal challenges - including mounting support for far-right and eurosceptic political parties in the 27-nation bloc.</p>

<p>In the coming weeks, she will propose her team of commissioners, who will face individual hearings from lawmakers before a final vote on the whole Commission later in the year.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/ogonc1v_ursula-von-der-leyen_625x300_26_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ursula von der Leyen needed 361 votes to pass and got 401 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/britain-failed-by-flawed-planning-for-coronavirus-pandemic-probe-finds-6133683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Britain Failed By Flawed Planning For Coronavirus Pandemic, Probe Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/britain-failed-by-flawed-planning-for-coronavirus-pandemic-probe-finds-6133683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 17:51:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain let down its citizens by leaving the nation ill-prepared for the COVID-19 pandemic because of significantly flawed planning and failures by ministers and scientific experts, a public inquiry concluded in a scathing report on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain let down its citizens by leaving the nation ill-prepared for the COVID-19 pandemic because of significantly flawed planning and failures by ministers and scientific experts, a public inquiry concluded in a scathing report on Thursday.</p>

<p>Britain recorded one of the world's highest number of fatalities from COVID with more than 230,000 deaths reported by December 2023, while the nation's finances are still suffering from the economic consequences.</p>

<p>Former Prime Minister Boris Johnson ordered an inquiry in May 2021, and its first report, which examined the nation's preparedness for an outbreak, was damning.</p>

<p>"Had the UK been better prepared for and more resilient to the pandemic, some of the financial and human cost may have been avoided," the report by the inquiry chair, former judge Heather Hallett, said in the report.</p>

<p>"The inquiry has no hesitation in concluding that the processes, planning, and policy of the civil contingency structures within the UK government and devolved administrations and civil service failed their citizens."</p>

<p>The inquiry found there had been a "lack of adequate leadership" with "groupthink" clouding expert advice. Ministers had not been given a broad enough range of opinions and then had failed to sufficiently challenge what they did receive.</p>

<p>A flawed 2011 strategy, which had underpinned the nation's preparations for such an emergency, had prepared for only one type of pandemic - influenza.</p>

<p>It was outdated, had focused on dealing with the impact of an outbreak rather than trying to prevent its spread, and had not taken into account the economic and social impact, the report said. That strategy was virtually abandoned on its first encounter with COVID.</p>

<p>"The Secretaries of State for Health ... who adhered to the strategy, the experts and officials who advised them to do so, and the governments of the devolved nations that adopted it, all bear responsibility for failing to have these flaws examined and rectified," the report said.</p>

<p><strong>Radical Reform</strong></p>

<p>Hallett made 10 recommendations, saying preparation for a civil emergency should be treated the same way as a threat from a hostile state.</p>

<p>"There must be radical reform. Never again can a disease be allowed to lead to so many deaths and so much suffering," she said in her introduction to the report.</p>

<p>Her inquiry's first module has only examined Britain's preparedness, and later reports will provide assessments of the more politically charged issues of decision-making during the pandemic against a backdrop of widespread accusations of government incompetence.</p>

<p>Johnson himself was forced from office in July 2022, with revelations of parties during COVID lockdowns among the many scandals that ended his premiership. A parliamentary committee later concluded he had misled lawmakers over the parties.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak, the finance minister during the pandemic who later became prime minister, was also fined for breaking lockdown rules at the time.</p>

<p>"We know that for lives to be saved in the future, lessons must be learnt from the mistakes of the past," Brenda Doherty said on behalf of the campaign group COVID-19 Bereaved Families for Justice UK ahead of the report's release.</p>

<p>"Sadly, nobody knows the true cost of the government's failure to prepare as we do."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tq6gg4g8_national-covid-memorial-uk-reuters_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A woman at the National Covid Memorial Wall for those in the UK who have died from COVID-19 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earliest-evidence-of-biblical-scarlet-dye-found-in-israel-desert-6133547]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earliest Evidence Of Biblical Scarlet Dye Found In Israel Desert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earliest-evidence-of-biblical-scarlet-dye-found-in-israel-desert-6133547]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 17:37:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli archaeologists working in the Judean Desert found the earliest evidence of Biblical scarlet dye, the Israel Antiquities Authority announced on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli archaeologists working in the Judean Desert found the earliest evidence of Biblical scarlet dye, the Israel Antiquities Authority announced on Thursday.</p>

<p>The rare textile, 3,800-years-old and less than two cm in size, was uncovered in the "Cave of Skulls" northeast of Jerusalem during excavations aimed at preserving heritage finds and preventing antiquities theft. The woolen weft threads were dyed red, while the linen warp threads remained uncolored.</p>

<p>Carbon-14 analysis dated the textile to the Middle Bronze Age (1767-1954 BCE).</p>

<p>According to a new joint study of the Israel Antiquities Authority, Bar-Ilan University and the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, the textile's scarlet color was produced from the oak scale insects, which the researchers identify with the Biblical scarlet worm Tola'at Hashani.</p>

<p>The scarlet-red color, mentioned in the Bible alongside royal blue tekheilet and purple argaman, is considered one of the ancient world's most precious and expensive dyes, which were used -- according to the biblical commandment -- to dye the fabrics of the Tabernacle and the priestly garments.</p>

<p>Using advanced analytical methods, including High-Performance Liquid Chromatography to identify the dye's origin, the researchers concluded that the red hue came from the Kermes vermilio species, known for producing kermesic acid, which imparts the distinctive red color.</p>

<p>The findings were recently published in the peer-reviewed Journal of Archaeological Science: Reports.</p>

<p>"In ancient times, the dye was produced from the female scale insect, which lives on the kermes oak tree (Quercus coccifera)," explained Dr. Na'ama Sukenik, Curator of the Organic Material Collection at the Israel Antiquities Authority.</p>

<p>"Collecting these kermes was done in a very short window of time - one month out of the year, in the summer, after the female laid her eggs but before they hatched-- when the amount of dye was greatest. The short period in which the kermes could be collected, the difficulty in finding them due to their small size, between 3-8 mm, and their camouflage colours -- that make it difficult to locate them," Sukenik added.</p>

<p>The amount of dye that could be produced from the eggs was limited, she explained, but "the beautiful scarlet hue that can be produced from them for dyeing textiles made their use highly prestigious."</p>

<p>The discovery also underscores the interconnectedness of ancient societies. Despite the presence of a native species of a scale insect in Israel capable of producing a red-orange colour, the researchers found that the textile's dye came from a species common in the central and eastern Mediterranean region, indicating extensive trade networks, the researchers said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e88n3qro_desert-generic_625x300_18_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The discovery also underscores the interconnectedness of ancient societies. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shot-perfectly-centred-on-head-new-trump-footage-shows-close-shave-6133371]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Shooter Had Trump's Face Right In Middle Of Crosshairs, Shows New Video]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shot-perfectly-centred-on-head-new-trump-footage-shows-close-shave-6133371]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 17:11:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new video with a graphical reticule shows US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump's head in the middle of what would have been the sniper's crosshair.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new video with a graphical reticule shows US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump's head in the middle of what would have been the sniper's crosshair.</p>

<p>The video shows Mr Trump's tilting his head to look at a screen graphic and leaning into the microphone saved his life, according to a post on X by US journalist Mario Nawfal, whose 'The Roundtable Show' is billed as the biggest example of citizen journalism.</p>

<p>"New footage shows Trump dodging a perfectly aimed shot. Close-up footage reveals Thomas Crook's shot was perfectly centred on Trump's head... The footage was captured just seconds before the shot," Mr Nawfal said in the post.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">???NEW FOOTAGE SHOWS TRUMP DODGED PERFECTLY AIMED SHOT<br />
<br />
Close-up footage reveals Thomas Crooks' shot was perfectly centered on Trump's head.<br />
<br />
Trump's 'head tilt' to look at a screen graphic and leaning into the microphone saved his life.<br />
<br />
The footage was captured just seconds... <a href="https://t.co/PDtNxBaAXy">pic.twitter.com/PDtNxBaAXy</a></p>
— Mario Nawfal (@MarioNawfal) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarioNawfal/status/1813626264957440282?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The US Department of Homeland Security is investigating the Secret Service's handling of security at the campaign rally where the gunman tried to assassinate Mr Trump.</p>

<p>The Secret Service has faced intense scrutiny since Saturday's shooting in Butler, Pennsylvania, during which a gunman opened fire on the Republican presidential candidate from an exposed rooftop some 150 metres away from the stage where Mr Trump was speaking.</p>

<p>Mr Trump was wounded in the ear and a rally attendee was killed. The 20-year-old gunman, Thomas Matthew Crooks, was shot dead by Secret Service snipers.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden has ordered an independent review of the Secret Service's handling of the assassination attempt, which is also being investigated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) as a case of potential domestic terrorism.</p>

<p>The Secret Service is responsible for the safety of the US president, vice president and former presidents, and their families, as well as major election candidates and visiting foreign heads of state.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7d259rs8_trump_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Homeland Security is investigating Secret Service's handling of security at Donald Trump rally]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-sentences-ex-us-paratrooper-michael-travis-leake-to-13-years-in-jail-on-drug-charges-6133163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Sentences Ex-US Paratrooper To 13 Years In Jail On Drug Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-sentences-ex-us-paratrooper-michael-travis-leake-to-13-years-in-jail-on-drug-charges-6133163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 16:49:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian court on Thursday sentenced U.S. citizen Michael Travis Leake to 13 years in prison on drug smuggling charges, Moscow's court service said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian court on Thursday sentenced U.S. citizen Michael Travis Leake to 13 years in prison on drug smuggling charges, Moscow's court service said in a statement.</p>

<p>Leake, a musician and former U.S. paratrooper who was arrested in June 2023, was found guilty of selling drugs on a large scale, the court service said.</p>

<p>It was not clear how he pleaded and Reuters was not able to contact his lawyer.</p>

<p>Leake is one of about a dozen Americans currently held in Russian detention. Washington urges its citizens to leave Russia immediately, citing the threat of arrest and harassment amid the highest tensions between the two countries since the Cold War.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the U.S. embassy in Moscow did not immediately reply to a request for comment on his conviction.</p>

<p>Another American, Robert Romanov Woodland, was sentenced by a Russian court to 12-1/2 years for drug smuggling earlier this month.</p>

<p>Leake was convicted alongside another defendant, a woman. The pair were shown standing in a court cage in brief videos published by the court service. Leake listened to the proceedings with a grim expression, at one point shaking his head.</p>

<p>Leake, who is in his early 50's, is a former songwriter in the rock band "Lovi Noch" ("Catch the Night"). He also previously worked as an English teacher in Moscow and helped translate songs for Russian bands.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-12/jail-generic_650x400_51482400613.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Michael Leake is one of about a dozen Americans currently held in Russian detention (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hope-for-siamese-crocodiles-60-hatchlings-in-cambodias-national-park-6132993]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[60 Rare Siamese Crocodiles Hatch In Cambodia In A Conservation Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hope-for-siamese-crocodiles-60-hatchlings-in-cambodias-national-park-6132993]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 16:25:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of 60 rare Siamese crocodiles have hatched in Cambodia, boosting hopes for one of the world's most endangered reptiles, conservationists said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of 60 rare Siamese crocodiles have hatched in Cambodia, boosting hopes for one of the world's most endangered reptiles, conservationists said Thursday.</p>

<p>Five Siamese crocodile nests were discovered in Cambodia's Cardamom National Park in mid-May, the country's environment and agriculture ministry said in a joint statement with conservation group Fauna and Flora.</p>

<p>The nests contained 106 eggs, of which 66 were fertilised, and a total of 60 Siamese crocodile eggs successfully hatched between June 27 and 30, the ministry said.</p>

<p>"This discovery indicates that the area is a key habitat for natural crocodiles, providing hope for the species' recovery," they said in the statement.</p>

<p>Researchers say there are approximately 1,000 Siamese crocodiles worldwide, including around 300 individuals in the wild in Cambodia.</p>

<p>Their survival is threatened by poachers who supply eggs and adult reptiles to crocodile farms around the region, where their skins are turned into luxury belts, shoes, and handbags.</p>

<p>Cambodian environment minister Eang Sophalleth said it was a source of "pride" that the country is home to some of the world's rarest species, pledging continued efforts to "preserve biodiversity."</p>

<p>Deforestation and poaching have devastated many species in Cambodia, one of Asia's poorest and most corrupt nations.</p>

<p>In its haste to develop, the government has been criticised for allowing firms to clear hundreds of thousands of hectares of forest land -- including in protected zones -- for everything from rubber and sugar cane plantations to hydropower dams.</p>

<p>The successful mass hatching shows the vital importance" of protecting the Cardamom National Park, said Pablo Sinovas, country director of the Fauna &amp; Flora Cambodia programme.</p>

<p>"With only a few hundred individuals estimated in the wild, the hatching of 60 new crocodiles is a tremendous boost," Sinovas added.</p>

<p>Siamese crocodiles grow up to three metres in length and the Mekong River basin and wetlands in Cambodia appear to hold the only remaining wild populations, according to conservation group WWF.</p>

<p>They are listed as critically endangered by the International Union for Conservation of Nature</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fq0uh8fg_siamese-crocodile_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are approximately 1,000 Siamese crocodiles worldwide, researchers said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-appears-to-face-difficulty-while-getting-into-car-video-goes-viral-6132915]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Appears To Face Difficulty While Getting Into Car, Video Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-appears-to-face-difficulty-while-getting-into-car-video-goes-viral-6132915]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 16:15:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident occurred after Mr Biden said that he would be "isolating as I recover" after testing positive for coronavirus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>United States President Joe Biden has made numerous verbal stumbles and gaffes over the years. From verbal slip-ups to near-fall incidents, Mr Biden, whose age is often targeted by opposition leaders and remains a concern for voters, has had all. With US elections just around the corner, questions about the US President's fitness to serve four more years - or win November's election - continue to swirl. Amid this, a video of Mr Biden appearing to have difficulty getting into his vehicle after exiting Air Force One on Wednesday is <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/JordanUhl/status/1813784758201332150">going viral on social media</a>.</p>

<p>The incident occurred after Mr Biden said that he would be "isolating as I recover" after testing positive for coronavirus. He previously cancelled a scheduled appearance at the UnidosUS Annual Conference in Las Vegas. The President also gave the media the thumbs up from his limousine and said "I feel good" following the diagnosis.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/07/17/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-3/">White House</a> said he was suffering from a runny nose, cough and "general malaise," was taking Covid medication, and was flying straight to isolation at his beach house in Rehoboth, Delaware. "He is vaccinated and boosted and he is experiencing mild symptoms. He will be returning to Delaware where he will self-isolate and will continue to carry out all of his duties fully during that time," spokesperson Jean-Pierre said.</p>

<p>Further, his doctor also stated that he was suffering from a runny nose and a "non-productive cough" along with "general malaise. "His symptoms remain mild, his respiratory rate is normal at 16, his temperature is normal at 97.8 and his pulse oximetry is normal at 97 per cent," the White House note added.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the 81-year-old said that he would consider dropping his troubled re-election bid if he was diagnosed with a serious medical condition. He told the media outlet BET, "If I had some medical condition that emerged, if somebody, if the doctors came and said 'you've got this problem, that problem'."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The White House said he was suffering from runny nose, cough and "general malaise".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/july-13-will-be-my-premiere-donald-trump-shooter-thomas-matthew-crookss-post-before-assassination-attempt-6132802]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Trump Shooter Posted Before Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/july-13-will-be-my-premiere-donald-trump-shooter-thomas-matthew-crookss-post-before-assassination-attempt-6132802]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 16:07:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks had posted a chilling online message foreshadowing his plans before attacking former President Donald Trump at his rally in Butler, Pennsylvania.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thomas Matthew Crooks had posted a chilling online message foreshadowing his plans before attacking former President Donald Trump at his rally in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"July 13 will be my premiere, watch as it unfolds,"&nbsp;the 20-year-old would-be assassin, allegedly wrote on Steam, a popular online platform for gamers, reported <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/live-news/trump-rally-shooting-fbi-investigation-attempted-assassination-july-17# ">Fox News</a>.</p>

<p>Crooks reportedly also had images of both Donald Trump and President Biden on his phone and had searched the dates for the Democratic National Convention and Trump's Pennsylvania rally, The<a href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/18/us-news/trumps-would-be-assassin-thomas-crooks-wrote-chilling-online-post-foreshadowing-rally-shooting-report/ "> NYPost </a>reported.</p>

<p>Investigators are analysing the shooter's phones and computer to determine the motive behind the assassination attempt. While they have explored the gunman's search history, they have not yet determined his political affiliation, despite his registration as a Republican.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The shooter reportedly had two cell phones, one found near his body and another at his home with only 27 contacts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Law enforcement sources report that snipers spotted Crooks on a roof with a rifle at 5:52 pm, but he didn't start firing until 6:12 pm. This means a 20-minute delay occurred between the time Crooks was first seen and the start of the shooting.</p>

<p>After Crooks fired at Donald Trump, the Secret Service shot him dead within 26 seconds. The former president survived with just a minor injury to his ear.</p>

<p>The gunshots, fired by an AR-style rifle, killed a 50-year-old father of two girls and injured two others.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sources told the NYPost that&nbsp;Crooks was identified as a person of interest a full hour before the shooting occurred. He had driven to&nbsp;Trump's rally on Saturday with a bunch of suspicious items in his car – a remote control transmitter, a detonator and an improvised metal explosive device connected to a receiver in his trunk – which suggested that he may have planned to cause a distraction or a diversion.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the days leading up to the attack, Crooks visited a <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-shooter-went-to-shooting-range-day-before-assassination-attempt-report-6126076 ">shooting</a> range, and also stopped at Home Depot and a gun store, where he purchased 50 rounds of ammunition and a 5-foot ladder.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bv51s1j_thomas-matthew-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The shooter reportedly had two cell phones (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/us-legislation-to-curb-ai-deepfakes-give-control-back-to-creators-6132746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Legislation To Curb AI Deepfakes, Give Control Back To Creators]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/us-legislation-to-curb-ai-deepfakes-give-control-back-to-creators-6132746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 15:55:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The bill, called Content Origin Protection and Integrity from Edited and Deepfaked Media Act (COPIED ACT), has strong support across the US political spectrum.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States has introduced a bill aimed at tackling AI deepfakes and protecting original content from being used for AI training last week.</p>

<p>The bill, called Content Origin Protection and Integrity from Edited and Deepfaked Media Act (COPIED ACT), has strong support across the US political spectrum.</p>

<p>Last Month, another senate bill dubbed "Take It Down Act '' was tabled, advocating the removal of AI deepfakes specific to non-consensual intimate imagery.</p>

<p>Notably, several controversies including Taylor Swift's AI generated deepfake nude images went viral on X (formerly Twitter), Facebook, and Instagram in January, sparking a nationwide debate on the ills of AI technology.</p>

<p>Apart from addressing deepfakes, COPIED Act will also address the concerns of content creators, journalists, artists and musicians that AI has been profiting off of their work, without acknowledgement or paying deserved compensation.</p>

<p>Last month, a report from Forbes accused Perplexity AI - an AI enabled search engine- of stealing its content. This was followed by an investigation by a New York based technology magazine called Wired that found Perplexity was summarising its articles despite the Robot Exclusion Protocol being in place, trespassing into areas of their website designated as off-limits to search bots.</p>

<h3><strong>How will the COPIED Act work?</strong></h3>

<p>The COPIED act will enable a mechanism whereby provisions will be made for a digital document called "content provenance information" that is akin to a logbook for all content- news articles, artistic expressions, images or videos- which will ensure authentication and detection of all AI generated content.</p>

<p>It also seeks provisions for making it illegal to tamper with this information, helping journalists and creative artists to safeguard their work from AI. Additionally, the bill would empower state officials to enforce the bill, creating an avenue to sue AI companies for removing the watermark or using the content without consent and compensation.</p>

<h3><strong>How are other countries regulating AI?</strong></h3>

<p>The European Union (EU) has one of the most comprehensive legislations in place for regulating AI. In contrast to the US approach, the EU Artificial Intelligence Act requires European states to take a proactive role and classify each AI system into four categories based on risk levels- Unacceptable Risk, High-Risk AI, Limited-Risk AI, and Minimal-Risk AI.</p>

<p>AI systems like those used in China for ascribing a social score to each citizen have been identified to be unacceptable risk levels and prohibited under the act.</p>

<p>In India, although a specific AI regulatory law has not been made yet, a Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology directive in March had mandated AI systems labelled as "under-tested" or "unreliable" to seek government approval before deploying. The directive was later overridden by another one, reversing the mandate, in a move that signalled caution to not affect innovation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/lf66ecu_ai-generated-ai-deepfake_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Disclaimer: Representational Image (AI Generated)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cult-boss-accused-of-plotting-with-santa-to-give-poisoned-candy-to-jewish-children-in-us-report-6132347]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Accused Of Plotting With 'Santa' To Poison Jewish Children: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cult-boss-accused-of-plotting-with-santa-to-give-poisoned-candy-to-jewish-children-in-us-report-6132347]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 15:04:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Arrested in Moldova, Chkhikvishvili recruited others for violent acts and disseminated a manifesto promoting terrorism and ethnic cleansing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Michail Chkhikvishvili, a neo-Nazi leader from Georgia, was indicted this week on charges of soliciting hate crimes and planning acts of mass violence in New York City. He intended to carry out a New Year's Eve attack involving Santa Claus distributing poisoned candy to racial minorities and Jewish children in Brooklyn.</p>

<p>As per a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edny/pr/georgian-national-charged-soliciting-hate-crimes-and-mass-casualty-attack-new-york">US government release</a>, Chkhikvishvili was arrested in Chisinau, Moldova, on July 6, 2024, pursuant to an Interpol Wanted Person Diffusion, which was issued based on a criminal complaint. Chkhikvishvili is alleged to be a leader of the Maniac Murder Cult, also known as "Maniacs Murder Cult," "Maniacs: Cult of Killing," "MKY," "MMC," and "MKU," an international racially or ethnically motivated violent extremist group.</p>

<p>Chkhikvishvili allegedly recruited others for violent acts, including planning a mass attack in NYC with an undercover officer posing as a recruit. US Attorney Breon Peace, Assistant AG Matthew Olsen, and FBI's Christie Curtis announced the charges.</p>

<p>"As alleged, the defendant sought to recruit others to commit violent attacks and killings in furtherance of his Neo-Nazi ideologies," stated United States Attorney Peace. "His goal was to spread hatred, fear, and destruction by encouraging bombings, arson, and even poisoning children for the purpose of harming racial minorities, the Jewish community, and homeless individuals. We will not hesitate to find and prosecute those who threaten the safety and freedoms of all members of our community, including members of minority communities, no matter where in the world these criminals might be hiding."</p>

<p>The government report stated Chkhikvishvili led MKY, an international extremist group with a Neo-Nazi ideology promoting violence against minorities. MKY aims to disrupt social order through terrorism, with members in the United States and abroad.</p>

<p>Since September 2021, Chkhikvishvili has distributed the "Hater's Handbook" to MKY members, promoting MKY's principles and urging mass violence. The manifesto includes Chkhikvishvili's claims of killing for the white race and encourages school shootings, using children for suicide bombings, and other attacks against racial minorities. It outlines strategies for terror attacks, such as targeting large events and crowded streets, specifically in the United States.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8gdqjijo_the-brooklyn-federal-courthouse-in-new-york-city-us_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Brooklyn Federal Courthouse in New York City, US.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arizona-toddler-dies-after-father-leaves-her-in-hot-car-for-hours-6131904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Arizona Toddler Dies After Father Leaves Her In Hot Car For Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arizona-toddler-dies-after-father-leaves-her-in-hot-car-for-hours-6131904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:53:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A two-year-old Arizona toddler's life was cut short after she was left in a car for over three hours, while her father got "distracted" playing video games. Parker Scholtes' dad, Christopher Scholtes, 37, is now facing a murder charge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A two-year-old Arizona toddler's life was cut short after she was left in a car for over three hours, while her father got "distracted" playing video games. Parker Scholtes' dad, Christopher Scholtes, 37, is now facing a murder charge.</p>

<p>Christopher, a father of three, claimed he left the kid in the car for only 30 minutes because he did not want to wake her up after they returned from shopping.</p>

<p>However, court documents and surveillance footage tell a different story. He left her inside their 2023 Acura MDX for more than three hours in the Arizona heat while he played video games on his PlayStation inside their home.</p>

<p>Christopher's wife, a doctor, returned home and discovered the little girl's lifeless body in the car, reported <a href="http://https://www.kplctv.com/2024/07/16/father-may-have-been-distracted-by-playstation-when-toddler-died-hot-car/ ">KPLCTV</a>.</p>

<p>Christopher told police he arrived at their home around 2:30 pm and parked outside because the garage was cluttered with exercise equipment. He claimed he forgot Parker was still in her car seat until Erika, his wife, came home at 4 pm and discovered their daughter's body. However, surveillance footage shows he arrived shortly after 12:30 pm, leaving Parker in the car in 109-degree weather for over three hours.</p>

<p>According to the complaint, Christopher "got distracted playing his game and putting his food away." He admitted to leaving the air conditioning on for Parker but knew it would shut off automatically after 30 minutes.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, his other two children told police their dad regularly left all three siblings alone in the car while he was in the house. Text messages between Christopher and his wife also reveal a history of similar incidents. "I told you to stop leaving them in the car," Erika's text to her husband read. "How many times have I told you?"</p>

<p>In court on Friday, when Christopher was charged with murder and child endangerment, Erika pleaded with the judge to release her otherwise "perfect" husband, calling the death of their child "a big mistake."</p>

<p>She requested that her husband be allowed to return home to support their family during a difficult time and said that the recent incident does not define her husband's character. “I just want the girls to see their father – that I don't have to tell them tonight that they're going to have to endure another loss,” she pleaded, as per the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/16/us-news/christopher-scholtes-distracted-by-playstation-while-daughter-2-died-in-hot-car/ ">NY Post.</a></p>

<p>Authorities have since charged Christopher Scholtes with murder and the judge set bail at $25,000, despite the prosecution's request for a $1 million bond.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-08/i5tvppq_car-generic_625x300_22_August_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man has been charged with murder and child endangerment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/academically-excellent-indian-family-of-trump-vice-president-jd-vances-wife-6132120]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Veep Pick JD Vance's Wife And Her "Academically Strong" Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/academically-excellent-indian-family-of-trump-vice-president-jd-vances-wife-6132120]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:38:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Usha Chilukuri Vance, the wife of Donald Trump's vice presidential running mate, has a great-aunt in southern India, aged 96, celebrated in local media as the country's oldest active professor.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Usha Chilukuri Vance, the wife of Donald Trump's vice presidential running mate, has a great-aunt in southern India, aged 96, celebrated in local media as the country's oldest active professor.</p>

<p>Academic achievement marks the family of US-born Vance, notably Shanthamma Chilukuri, who still travels 60 km (40 miles) most weekdays to university to teach physics.</p>

<p>"Most of our family is academically strong and education has been a top priority," Chilukuri told Reuters by phone from the city of Visakhapatnam.</p>

<p>Usha Vance, 38, made her debut on the U.S. national political stage on Wednesday when she introduced her husband, U.S. Senator J.D. Vance of Ohio, at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>"I got to know about Usha's husband being named as a vice president candidate and of course, we are happy as a family," Chilukuri told Reuters by phone from the city of Visakhapatnam.</p>

<p>In his memoir "Hillbilly Elegy", Vance calls his wife a "supersmart daughter of Indian immigrants" whom he met at Yale Law School.</p>

<p>The parents of Usha Vance moved to the U.S. in the late 1970s and now teach engineering and molecular biology in San Diego.</p>

<p>While Usha Vance studied at Yale and Cambridge, her father and grandfather both taught or studied at the Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), India's premier engineering college. Her younger sister is a mechanical engineer with a semiconductor company in San Diego and her aunt a medical professional in the southern Indian city of Chennai.</p>

<p>The family is originally from a village called Vadduru in Andhra Pradesh state but moved to Chennai when Usha Vance's paternal grandfather, Ramasastry Chilukuri, went to teach at the IIT there around the time it was set up in 1959, members of the family said. The IIT now runs a student award in the memory of Ramasastry, who used to teach physics.</p>

<p>The family, which is Hindu, is also deeply religious.</p>

<p>Shanthamma Chilukuri said many in the family were well-versed in ancient texts like Upanishads and Vedas. She has authored a book on verses from the Bhagavad Gita, one of Hinduism's holiest books.</p>

<p>Senator Vance told Fox News in June that his wife had helped him "re-engage" with his Christian faith.</p>

<p>Sitting by him during the interview, Usha Vance said: "I did grow up in a religious household. My parents are Hindu and that is one of the things that made them such good parents, that made them really good people. And so I have seen the power of that."</p>

<p>Usha Vance was a law clerk to U.S. Chief Justice John Roberts and later became an attorney at U.S. law firm Munger, Tolles &amp; Olson LLP. She resigned after J.D. Vance was named as the Republican vice presidential candidate.</p>

<p>A close India-based family member who attended their wedding in Kentucky in 2014 attributed Usha Vance's success to "the mindset that one must accomplish something, have degrees from top institutes".</p>

<p>"Our family WhatsApp group is flooded with messages ever since J.D. Vance's name was announced," said the family member, who did not want to be named to avoid public attention as interest in the family spikes in the media. "I sent her a congratulatory message and conveyed my best wishes. She was also elated."</p>

<p>Usha Vance's parents and her sister in the United States did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Indian media have hailed her as the latest among several Americans with roots in India rising to fame, including U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, Google CEO Sundar Pichai, and former Republican presidential hopefuls Nikki Haley and Vivek Ramaswamy, who was J.D. and Usha Vance's classmate at Yale Law.</p>

<p>In a 2020 Netflix movie based on J.D. Vance's memoir, Usha Vance's character describes how her father started from scratch when he first moved to the United States.</p>

<p>"He came here with nothing," said the character played by Freida Pinto, an Indian actor who rose to fame as the female lead in Oscar-winning "Slumdog Millionaire". "He had to just find his way."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hrtbmc38_usha-chilukuri-vance-jd-vance-afp_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Senator JD Vance said in June that his wife Usha had helped him "re-engage" with his Christian faith.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/a-shot-in-the-arm-for-republicans-donald-trumps-rise-suddenly-seems-inevitable-6131954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: A Shot In The Arm: Trump's Rise Suddenly Seems Inevitable]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/a-shot-in-the-arm-for-republicans-donald-trumps-rise-suddenly-seems-inevitable-6131954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:14:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Even before the assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump, American politics was churning. But after the dramatic developments of last week, it's spinning in a way few could have foreseen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bq88p95_trump-shooting_625x300_16_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Even before the assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump, American politics was churning. But after the dramatic developments of last week, it's spinning in a way few could have foreseen. Even as President Joe Biden is getting weaker by the day, Trump seems to be gaining an unstoppable momentum. As per internal polling of the Democrats, Biden is losing ground to Trump in 14 key states, including the five that Biden won in 2020 - &nbsp;Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin. His numbers are shaky in Colorado, Minnesota, Maine, New Mexico, Virginia and New Hampshire after his disastrous debate performance.</p>

<p>The Democratic Party remains badly divided with growing fears among its rank and file that, in light of the debate, Biden is in no position to defeat Trump and that he will leave other Democrats on the ballot in November vulnerable too. Voices are growing within the Party asking Biden to step aside, with senior party officials like Rep. Adam Schiff of California making an open case that "a second Trump presidency will undermine the very foundation of our democracy, and I have serious concerns about whether the President can defeat Donald Trump in November". Biden is fighting back but is struggling in convincing his own party about his suitability for the top job.</p>

<h2><strong>The GOP Convention</strong></h2>

<p>His opponent, meanwhile, is basking in the glory of a convention where his past critics are now coming together to anoint him as the party's nominee more formally. All those like Nikki Haley, Ron DeSantis and Marco Rubio, who till a few months back were targeting Trump at the Republican primaries, have now ended up endorsing him unequivocally. Trump with a bandage over his ears and his supporters shouting "Fight, fight, fight!" at the Republican National Convention is a powerful imagery for a nation that a few days back was debating the suitability of a candidate who incited the January 6 insurrection at Capitol Hill. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The confusion in the Republican party was apparent when after J.D. Vance, a former Never Trumper who had, in 2016, wondered whether Trump might be "America's Hitler", was confirmed as the Republican Party's vice presidential nominee. He faced racist attacks from far-right commentators because of his wife's Indian heritage. The upholders of the 'Make America Great Again' movement are finding it difficult to reconcile Vance's multicultural family with their core agenda of anti-immigration.</p>

<h2><strong>Fundamental Challenges</strong></h2>

<p>Political polarisation in the US has led to some fundamental challenges being faced by both the Republicans and the Democrats. The demonisation of the other side has led to a situation where even after an assassination attempt, vitriol continues to flow and there is no attempt at reconciliation.</p>

<p>Though the theme of the Republican convention this week is about unity, there is no place in today's Republican rank and file for those who have a different vision for the US than Trump's. Any challenge to Trump is about challenging the party as the former president has ensured that the Republican Party today is more reflective of his views than a broad tent organisation.</p>

<p>After the assassination attempt on Trump, Vance wrote: "Today is not just some isolated incident. The central premise of the Biden campaign is that President Donald Trump is an authoritarian fascist who must be stopped at all costs. That rhetoric led directly to President Trump's attempted assassination." Trump's own role in vitiating the political climate in the US has been conveniently forgotten by his supporters.</p>

<p>Though President Biden called on the Americans last week to rein in the political debate, arguing that "[It] must never be a battlefield and, God forbid, a killing field", and warning that "no matter how strong our convictions, we must never descend into violence", it's not readily evident if anyone is listening. Trump's ability to tap into the sense of grievance and persecution felt by middle America has thwarted any attempt by the Biden administration and the Democrats more generally to craft a political narrative that can shift the momentum in their favour. And now after the attack on Trump, it has become even more difficult as the image of a defiant former President with blood streaked across his face stands in stark contrast to a fumbling feeble Biden unable to articulate a coherent thought.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
November is still far away. Even a day is a long time in politics. The Democratic Party can still regroup and present a serious challenge to Trump. But there is no denying the fact that the last two weeks have upended the US Presidential elections in fundamental ways and will leave a strong mark on American politics whichever way the political winds blow in the coming days.</p>

<p><em>(Harsh V Pant is Vice-President for Studies and Foreign Policy at ORF.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bq88p95_trump-shooting_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-privately-told-by-ex-speaker-nancy-pelosi-he-cannot-win-report-6131929]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Told Privately By Ex-Speaker Nancy Pelosi He Cannot Win: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-privately-told-by-ex-speaker-nancy-pelosi-he-cannot-win-report-6131929]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:10:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden, who has tested positive for Covid for a third time, was reportedly been told by former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi that he could destroy the Democrats' chances of winning elections in November, due to his age.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden, who has tested positive for Covid for a third time, was reportedly been told by former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi that he could destroy the Democrats' chances of winning elections in November, due to his age.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old President has responded to Pelosi that he still has a chance of winning the presidential race, according to a report by CNN. One of their sources has mentioned Biden getting defensive about the upcoming polls in response.</p>

<p>The California Representative had reportedly asked Biden's Senior Advisor Mike Donilon to connect her with the President on a call, which would mark the second conversation between the two since Biden's poor performance in the debate with Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Although Pelosi seems to have stopped fully backing Biden, it is not known yet whether she thinks that he should withdraw from the race altogether. In an interview last week, she said, "It's up to the president to decide if he is going to run. We're all encouraging him to make that decision because time is running short."</p>

<p>On the other hand, she took to social media platform X (formerly Twitter) after the assassination attempt on Trump, writing, "As one whose family has been the victim of political violence, I know first-hand that political violence of any kind has no place in our society. I thank God that former President Trump is safe."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">As one whose family has been the victim of political violence, I know firsthand that political violence of any kind has no place in our society. I thank God that former President Trump is safe.<br />
<br />
As we learn more details about this horrifying incident, let us pray that all those…</p>
— Nancy Pelosi (@SpeakerPelosi) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpeakerPelosi/status/1812268746574020870?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A Pelosi spokesperson has also reportedly told CNN that she has not spoken to Biden since Friday.</p>

<p>One of the Democratic Party's leading fundraisers, actor George Clooney had said last week that Biden cannot win against time. Clooney said, "Top Democrats -- Chuck Schumer, Hakeem Jeffries, Nancy Pelosi -- and senators, representatives and other candidates who face losing in November need to ask this president to voluntarily step aside."</p>

<p>Biden had recently slammed Trump for joking about Pelosi's husband being attacked with a hammer, by a far-right conspiracy theorist in 2022, when she was the House Speaker.</p>

<p>"If I had some medical condition that emerged, if somebody, if the doctors came and said 'you've got this problem, that problem,'" Biden told the Black media outlet BET in an interview on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Biden testing positive for Covid today, amid pressure for him to withdraw from the White House race due to his age and mental acuity, makes the situation all the more tense in an already polarised nation ahead of the elections in November.</p>

<p>The instance of Biden mistakenly referring to Vice President Kamala Harris as Trump at his solo press conference has also added to doubts over his fitness as the US Presidential Candidate due to his age.</p>

<p>The last two weeks, especially after his disastrous performance in the presidential debate with Trump have seen Biden standing at a chance of losing celebrity support and key endorsers such as Teamsters. Meanwhile, Trump has regained the support of some of his key rivals including Nikki Haley, Ron DeSantis, and Vivek Ramaswamy at the Republican Convention following his assassination bid.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1vtf6fvg_joe-biden-nancy-pelosi-afp-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi seems to have stopped fully backing US President Joe Biden.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-sick-of-joe-biden-uses-covid-diagnosis-to-attack-donald-trump-elon-musk-6131909]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm Sick Of...": Biden Uses Covid Diagnosis To Attack Trump, Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-sick-of-joe-biden-uses-covid-diagnosis-to-attack-donald-trump-elon-musk-6131909]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:08:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has tested positive for Covid-19. The diagnosis, which came with mild symptoms, has been leveraged by his campaign team to target his principal political rival Donald Trump and tech billionaire Elon Musk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden has tested positive for Covid-19. The diagnosis, which came with mild symptoms, has been leveraged by his campaign team to target his principal political rival Donald Trump and tech billionaire Elon Musk.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Democrat, who is currently isolated at his beach home in Delaware, took to social media to announce his diagnosis, quipping "I'm sick" before following up with a tongue-in-cheek remark aimed at Musk and his wealthy associates, accusing them of attempting to "buy this election."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm sick</p>
— Joe Biden (@JoeBiden) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden/status/1813715902250017022?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Musk has pledged roughly $45 million each month to a new fund backing Trump for US president.</p>

<p>President Biden's health issues have raised concerns about his fitness for office, particularly among Democrats. A recent poll conducted by the Associated Press and NORC Center for Public Affairs Research indicated that nearly two-thirds of respondents believe Biden should step down.</p>

<p>The president's illness has also sparked a heated debate within the Democratic Party, with prominent figures like Representative Adam Schiff and former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi urging Biden to "pass the torch. Democratic Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer and House Democratic leader Hakeem Jeffries have reportedly expressed concerns to Biden that his candidacy may jeopardise the party's electoral prospects.</p>

<p>Despite these developments, Biden remains adamant in his pursuit of reelection insisting that Democratic voters support him. &nbsp;White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre assured the public that Biden, who is vaccinated and boosted, continues to fulfil his presidential duties while in isolation. Dr Kevin O'Connor, Biden's physician, confirmed that the president's symptoms remain mild.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/fpd88p5s_elon-musk-donald-trump_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US presidential elections are scheduled for November this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-babydog-the-english-bulldog-steals-the-spotlight-at-republican-national-convention-6131880]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Polls: 'Babydog' Steals Spotlight At The Republican National Convention]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-babydog-the-english-bulldog-steals-the-spotlight-at-republican-national-convention-6131880]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:02:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA['Babydog', the chunky English bulldog belonging to Governor Jim Justice was a sensation at the Republican National Convention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Republican National Convention is currently taking place in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, featuring notable appearances from Donald Trump, JD Vance, and other conservative leaders.</p>

<p>However, the unexpected star this year is not a governor, senator, or presidential candidate, but a chubby bulldog.</p>

<p>Babydog, the pet of West Virginia Governor Jim Justice, has gained viral fame online for her calm demeanour during her owner's speech.</p>

<p>Relaxing on a black leather armchair, the English Bulldog appeared content in front of an audience of hundreds of politicians.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">ICYMI: It was an honor to speak at the Republican National Convention with Babydog by my side! President Trump is tough and super smart; he's a business guy; he cares about all of us; and he loves this nation! That is why we must elect Donald J. Trump and JD Vance in November! <a href="https://t.co/krA2OUZsGG">pic.twitter.com/krA2OUZsGG</a></p>
— Jim Justice (@JimJusticeWV) <a href="https://twitter.com/JimJusticeWV/status/1813680880344523140?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Governor Justice, a major speaker at the convention, made sure to mention his four-legged companion in his remarks.</p>

<p>"Babydog has got a prediction for everybody here," the West Virginia governor and US Senate candidate told the crowd in Milwaukee, after an aide brought his pet out to sit panting on a chair beside him.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7ndc8jc8_babydog_625x300_18_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"Babydog says that we will retain the House, the majority in the House, we are going to flip the United States Senate and overwhelmingly we are going to elect Donald J Trump and JD Vance in November."</p>

<p>Babydog, the governor said, was confident in her prediction, "Because we're worth it."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ghcejt4g_babydog_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jim Justice speaks alongside his bulldog, 'Babydog', during the Republican National Convention.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>