<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:48:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-2-magnitude-earthquake-hits-central-peru-coast-tsunami-alert-lifted-5988147]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[7.2 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Central Peru Coast, Tsunami Alert Lifted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-2-magnitude-earthquake-hits-central-peru-coast-tsunami-alert-lifted-5988147]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:15:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A magnitude 7.2 earthquake struck off the coast of central Peru on Friday, the United States Geological Survey said, but a tsunami threat from the tremor has passed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A magnitude 7.2 earthquake struck off the coast of central Peru on Friday, the United States Geological Survey said, but a tsunami threat from the tremor has passed.</p>

<p>The USGS said the tremor hit 8.8 kilometers (5.5 miles) from Atiquipa district, raising an initial magnitude rating soon after the quake was reported.</p>

<p>The USGS said that strong shaking from the quake would have been felt in areas near the epicenter.</p>

<p>The Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre had earlier said "hazardous tsunami waves are forecast for some coasts" but later said the threat had passed.</p>

<p>"There is no longer a tsunami threat from this earthquake," it said.</p>

<p>Peru, with some 33 million inhabitants, lies on the so-called Pacific Ring of Fire, a vast area of intense seismic activity that runs along the west coast of the Americas.</p>

<p>Peru is hit by hundreds of detectable quakes every year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/g3ujd6gg_earthquake-in-rajasthan_625x300_09_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Peru is hit by hundreds of detectable quakes every year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oceangate-co-founder-to-lead-dive-into-portal-to-hell-a-year-after-titan-tragedy-5988029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OceanGate Co-Founder To Dive Into "Portal To Hell" Year After Titan Tragedy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oceangate-co-founder-to-lead-dive-into-portal-to-hell-a-year-after-titan-tragedy-5988029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:54:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dean's Blue Hole is a 664-foot underwater cavern surrounded by a beach on a remote Bahaman island. It formed some 15,000 years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The co-founder of OceanGate, which conducted a fatal excursion to the Titanic last year, is set to embark on a new journey. Guillermo Sohnlein plans to study a "virtually unexplored" sinkhole in the Bahamas, which is dubbed as "portal to hell" by the locals. According to <em>New York Post</em>, Mr Sohnlein plans to descend in a submersible into the Dean's Blue Hole, one of the world's deepest ocean sinkholes. He will be joined by scientist Kenny Broad and chief medical officer and former NASA astronaut Scott Parazynski, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/06/25/us-news/oceangate-co-founder-to-lead-dive-into-deans-blue-hole-in-bahamas/">the outlet further said</a>.</p>

<p>"Dean's Blue Hole remains virtually unexplored, offering an opportunity to discover the hidden secrets of cave-dwelling species, geological climate history and unique ecosystems," according to a page on <a href="https://bluemarbleexploration.com/abyss/">the company's website</a>.</p>

<p>Dean's Blue Hole is a 664-foot underwater cavern surrounded by a beach on a remote Bahaman island, according to Blue Marble. It formed some 15,000 years ago and, due to its extreme depth, very little is known about it.</p>

<p>The sinkhole is shaped like a vase with a narrow opening near the surface that leads to much wider water body below.</p>

<p>Scientists believe the chamber below is connected to the Atlantic Ocean, something that the company says will offer a "certain amount of unpredictability".</p>

<p>One of the biggest challenges will be to manage the pressure on the ocean floor, which will be considerably high as compared to the surface.</p>

<p>"We fully expect to find human remains and prepare to handle those situations with proper respect for the families," the <em>Post</em> quoted the company as saying. However, the date when the expedition will start has not been announced.</p>

<p>Mr Sohnlein founded OceanGate in 2009 with Stockton Rush - who was one of the five killed when the Titan submersible imploded last June - but left and started another deep-sea exploration company, Blue Marble Exploration.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/7llv5d4g_deans-blue-hole_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Scientists believe the chamber in Dean's Blue Hole is connected to the Atlantic Ocean.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-releases-video-debunking-north-koreas-successful-missile-test-claim-5988020]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Releases Video Debunking North Korea's Missile Success Claim]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-releases-video-debunking-north-koreas-successful-missile-test-claim-5988020]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:52:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea's military on Friday released a video that it said showed a North Korean missile abnormally spiralling early in flight and exploding, a rare publicising of surveillance footage to dismiss the North's claim of a successful test.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea's military on Friday released a video that it said showed a North Korean missile abnormally spiralling early in flight and exploding, a rare publicising of surveillance footage to dismiss the North's claim of a successful test.</p>

<p>Footage filmed by a thermal observation device with South Korean frontline units showed a projectile spiralling out of control on an irregular flight path, then disintegrating.</p>

<p>The South Korean military assessed that "instability during flight" led to the missile's explosion, it said in a statement on Friday, calling North Korea's claims of success as "deception and exaggeration to cover up the failure".</p>

<p>North Korean state media had said that Pyongyang successfully conducted an important test on Wednesday aimed at developing missiles able to deploy multiple warheads, a claim rejected by South Korea.</p>

<p>North Korea's missile administration used the first-stage engine of a solid-fuel intermediate-range ballistic missile to test the separation and guidance of multiple warheads, according to the North's official KCNA news agency.</p>

<p>South Korea's military said it had detected signs of missile launch preparations early on Wednesday and was watching as the rocket was launched.</p>

<p>In April, Pyongyang said it had tested a new solid-fuel hypersonic missile with intermediate range, part of an intensifying race for the next generation of long-range rockets hard to track and intercept.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/4uaqkgrg_north-korean-missile-reuters_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The South Korean military assessed that "instability during flight" led to the missile's explosion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-joe-biden-and-donald-trump-face-off-in-atlanta-debate-five-key-takeaways-5987803]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden And Trump Face Off In Atlanta Debate: Five Key Takeaways]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-joe-biden-and-donald-trump-face-off-in-atlanta-debate-five-key-takeaways-5987803]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:17:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden and Republican challenger Donald Trump squared off Thursday in a debate watched by millions, and what voters saw may have sparked more questions than answers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden and Republican challenger Donald Trump squared off Thursday in a debate watched by millions, and what voters saw may have sparked more questions than answers.</p>

<p>Here are five takeaways from the Atlanta showdown.</p>

<h3><strong>Dems, we have a problem&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Biden -- diagnosed with a cold, according to his campaign -- looked all of his 81 years onstage, speaking in a halting, hoarse voice and missing key opportunities to forcefully and coherently push back against Trump.</p>

<p>While the veteran Democrat showed occasional spark, he mostly appeared lackluster. The post-debate analysis came in quickly -- and it was devastating.</p>

<p>"It was an unmitigated disaster," University of Virginia political science professor Larry Sabato told AFP.</p>

<p>"This debate is a problem," added Princeton University professor Julian Zelizer, saying Biden's supporters "are going to be extremely concerned how this unfolded."</p>

<p>Trump at times looked more authoritative and energetic, although he unleashed a barrage of falsehoods about Biden's presidency, election fraud, and abortion policy.</p>

<h3><strong>A more disciplined Trump&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Of the two candidates, it was Trump who may have surprised viewers, by showing a more restrained, civil side to his normal political bulldozing. Host CNN turned the microphones off unless a candidate was asked a question, a move experts say benefited the challenger.</p>

<p>When Biden railed against Trump, for example, for having "encouraged" rioters to storm the US Capitol in early 2021, Trump largely held his tongue, looking down or shaking his head.</p>

<p>And when it was his turn to speak, he pounced.</p>

<p>"Trump's somewhat tempered and authoritative demeanor -- at least for him -- masked a number of mistruths he made throughout the night and helped him appeal to swing voters on top polling issues like the economy and the border," Ashley Koning, director of the Rutgers Eagleton Center for Public Interest Polling, told AFP.</p>

<h3><strong>It's personal&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The debate, which began without a handshake, left no doubt these men did not like one another. From Biden's blasting his rival as "a convicted felon" to Trump musing that "I don't think (Biden) knows what he said," the personal animus was glaring.</p>

<p>"You have the morals of an alley cat," Biden hissed after laying out Trump's various legal challenges and verdicts against him.</p>

<p>"You're the sucker, you're the loser," Biden said.</p>

<p>Trump punched back, saying "Everything he does is a lie."</p>

<p>"He's the worst president in the history of our country," Trump fumed.</p>

<h3><strong>Less chaos, less accountability&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The helter-skelter tumult of their first 2020 debate, in which then-president Trump ran roughshod over Biden and the debate moderators, was but a memory Thursday night, as CNN's strategy to avoid a shouting match worked.</p>

<p>"I think the rules may have aided Trump because they prevented him from yelling over Biden's answers," said Robert Rowland, a communications professor at Kansas University.</p>

<p>With no studio audience cheering or jeering, both candidates had greater opportunities to focus on the issues.</p>

<p>And with CNN moderators failing to offer real-time fact checks during the debate, Trump and to a lesser degree Biden were unrestrained in making misleading or false statements on a variety of topics, from immigration and crime to the economy.</p>

<h3><strong>Ominous tone&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Trump's couched response to a key question near the debate's end offered a concerning look into the post-election future.</p>

<p>Moderators asked Trump three times whether the Republican would accept the results of the vote before he finally addressed the question directly, saying "If it's a fair and legal and good election, absolutely."</p>

<p>But in the same breath, he repeated his baseless claims about 2020 vote rigging or interference, saying "the fraud and everything else was ridiculous."</p>

<p>Biden suggested even Trump's conditional response should not be trusted. "I doubt that you'll accept it because you're such a whiner," Biden said</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/74s0pkgo_biden-trump-afp-_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The debate, which began without a handshake, left no doubt these men did not like one another.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-gifts-kim-jong-un-limousine-made-with-imported-south-korean-parts-5987494]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Gifts Kim Jong Un Limousine Made With Imported South Korean Parts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-gifts-kim-jong-un-limousine-made-with-imported-south-korean-parts-5987494]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 11:36:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Laughing and joking, Russian President Vladimir Putin and North Korean leader Kim Jong-un cruised around Pyongyang last week in a Russian-made Aurus limousine to showcase their strengthened anti-Western alliance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Laughing and joking, Russian President Vladimir Putin and North Korean leader Kim Jong-un cruised around Pyongyang last week in a Russian-made Aurus limousine to showcase their strengthened anti-Western alliance.</p>

<p>The luxury sedan was intended to epitomize Russia's domestic prowess and reduce dependence on imported technology and goods when unveiled in 2018.</p>

<p>But customs records show that the company that builds it uses millions of dollars in imported parts, many arriving in Russia from what Kim has described as his country's "primary foe", South Korea.</p>

<p>The imports point to Russia's ongoing reliance on Western technology as it seeks to navigate Western attempts to cut it off from global supply chains as punishment for its invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>The two leaders took turns driving the armoured limousine during Putin's pomp-filled visit, his first in nearly a quarter of a century to North Korea, in a demonstration of the two nuclear powers' increasingly close ties.</p>

<p>Russia imported equipment and components worth at least $34 million between 2018 and 2023 for assembling Aurus cars and motorcycles, customs records seen by Reuters showed. Reuters does not have access to more recent data.</p>

<p>The imports included car body parts, sensors, programmable controllers, switches, welding equipment, and other components worth almost $15.5 million imported from South Korea. Parts were also imported from China, India, Turkey, Italy, and other EU countries.</p>

<p>Foreign supplies for Aurus kept coming after Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine, with goods worth almost $16 million, including $5 million produced in South Korea, imported since February 2022, the records showed.</p>

<p>Reuters could not determine specifically which imported foreign parts ended up in the car gifted to Kim, and the imports were not in breach of sanctions - Aurus LLC was sanctioned by the United States in February 2024.</p>

<p>The Aurus sedan was developed by Russian state-owned research institute NAMI in partnership with Russian carmaker Sollers, which has since sold its stake.</p>

<p>Aurus Motors and its CEO Andrey Pankov did not respond to Reuters' requests for comment on the use of foreign parts, including from South Korea, in its vehicles.</p>

<p><strong><span style="font-size:11pt"><span style="line-height:107%"><span style="font-family:Calibri,sans-serif">Growing Production</span></span></span></strong></p>

<p>The company launched official production in Russia's Tatarstan region, around 1,000 km (620 miles) from Moscow, in 2021 - before then it was made on a small, experimental scale at NAMI. It will start additional production in St Petersburg later this year at Toyota's former factory.</p>

<p>Toyota is one of many foreign carmakers to exit the Russian market since the invasion, which Russia calls a "special military operation".</p>

<p>The exodus has left a gap that Chinese producers have been quick to fill, rapidly seizing more than half the market share and exposing Russia's limited domestic production capacity.</p>

<p>South Korean firms were among the largest suppliers to Aurus, including industrial equipment producer Kyungki Industrial Co, car body parts manufacturer BYT CO LTD, and batteries supplier Enertech International Inc.</p>

<p>Italian plastic parts producer Industrie Ilpea Spa and Hong Kong company Rain Electronics also supplied goods.</p>

<p>An official at Kyungki Industrial Co confirmed that the company has supplied parts to Aurus LLC and continues to do so. The company is not concerned about any potential sanctions, the official said, declining to give further details.</p>

<p>Rain Electronics could not be reached for comment. When a Reuters correspondent visited the address listed on the internet as the company's office in Hong Kong, there was no trace of Rain Electronics on the floor listed online or in the office building.</p>

<p>BYT CO LTD, Enertech International, and Industrie Ilpea Spa did not respond to Reuters' requests for comment.</p>

<p>The Aurus Senat, retro-styled after the Soviet-era ZIL limousine, is Russia's official presidential car and was used by Putin at his presidential inaugurations in 2018 and 2024.</p>

<p>Putin has now given Kim, believed to be a keen automobile fan, two Aurus cars, first during Kim's visit to Russia in February, and a slightly different model in North Korea in June.</p>

<p>Prices for Aurus cars - there are four models including an SUV and an armoured version - start from 46.625 million roubles ($528,356). Customers include Turkmenistan President Serdar Berdymukhamedov.</p>

<p>Aurus sold 107 cars in Russia in 2023, according to data from Russian analytical agency Autostat. Aurus does not disclose production numbers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/2tt9s7bo_putin-kim-car_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[South Korean firms were among the largest suppliers to Aurus.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-accuses-joe-biden-of-being-a-manchurian-candidate-what-it-means-5987378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Manchurian Candidate, Paid By China": Trump's Big Charge Against Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-accuses-joe-biden-of-being-a-manchurian-candidate-what-it-means-5987378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 11:05:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, the Republican nominee for the US Presidential poll, accused President and Democratic candidate Joe Biden of taking money from China and called him a "Manchurian candidate" during their first presidential debate on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, the Republican nominee for the US Presidential poll, accused President and Democratic candidate Joe Biden of taking money from China and called him a "Manchurian candidate" during their first presidential debate on Thursday. Held at CNN's headquarters in Atlanta, the debate kicked off the 2024 election cycle.</p>

<p>Trump said that the US currently has "the largest deficit in the history" of the country. "We have the largest deficit with China. He gets paid by China. He's a Manchurian candidate. He gets money from China," Trump said during the heated debate.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Trump: "He gets money from China. He's a Manchurian candidate."<br />
<br />
???????? <a href="https://t.co/198JRT5hnG">pic.twitter.com/198JRT5hnG</a></p>
— Greg Price (@greg_price11) <a href="https://twitter.com/greg_price11/status/1806512577046069400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The term "Manchurian candidate" appears to be a reference to Frank Sinatra's 1962 film of the same name. The movie tells the story of Raymond Shaw, an American soldier captured and brainwashed by communist forces to become a sleeper agent and carry out a political assassination.</p>

<p>Frank Sinatra plays Major Bennett Marco, Shaw's commanding officer, who starts uncovering the sinister plot through disturbing nightmares. The film was remade in 2004 with Denzel Washington taking on the role of Major Bennett Marco.</p>

<p>The two presidential candidates clashed on various issues, including the economy, abortion, and immigration, during the high-stakes debate.</p>

<p>President Biden, 81, began with a rapid-fire critique of Trump's presidency, stumbling over his words several times. The Republican nominee, 78, seized on Biden's phrasing, laying the blame for the Ukraine war squarely at his feet.</p>

<p>"If we had a leader, this is a war that never should have started."</p>

<p>He accused Biden of giving "$200 billion or more to Ukraine", claiming that it was a lot of money and that there never has been "anything like it".</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-v-8wJkmwBY?si=V-66GWVtFS4zHlMQ" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe><br />
<br />
Trump also accused Biden of siding with Palestinians in the Gaza conflict, claiming he refused to support Israel against Hamas. “He doesn't want to do it. He's become like a Palestinian - but they don't like him because he's a very bad Palestinian. He's a weak one,” Trump said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/hauu54q8_trump-biden-split-650_650x400_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump and Biden clashed on various issues during the first high-stakes debate ahead of Presidential polls]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-warns-news-block-on-facebook-for-australia-over-licensing-fees-5987259]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Warns News Block On Facebook For Australia Over Licensing Fees]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-warns-news-block-on-facebook-for-australia-over-licensing-fees-5987259]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 10:44:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facebook owner Meta is considering blocking news content from the platform in Australia if the government makes it pay licensing fees, a company representative told a parliamentary hearing on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facebook owner Meta is considering blocking news content from the platform in Australia if the government makes it pay licensing fees, a company representative told a parliamentary hearing on Friday.</p>

<p>Meta's regional policy director Mia Garlick told lawmakers "All options are on the table" when asked if the company would block Australians from sharing news content to avoid paying fees.</p>

<p>"There's a large number of channels that people can get news content from," Garlick told the inquiry.</p>

<p>She said Meta was waiting for Canberra to decide if it would apply an untested 2021 law that gives the government the right to set the fees U.S. tech giants pay media outlets for links.</p>

<p>The comments are the strongest indication so far that Meta would take the same hardline approach in Australia as it took in Canada in 2023 when that country introduced similar laws.</p>

<p>Meta struck deals with Australian media firms including News Corp and the Australian Broadcasting Corp when the law was brought in Australia, but has since said it will not renew those arrangements beyond 2024.</p>

<p>It now falls on Australia's assistant treasurer to decide whether to step in and force Facebook to pay for news content. The assistant treasurer has said he is still collecting advice but that Meta seems to respect the law only when it suits.</p>

<p>Asked if blocking news from Facebook in Australia would amount to sidestepping the law, Garlick said taking that action would be complying with it.</p>

<p>"Every other law - tax laws, safety laws, privacy laws - we work to comply with," she said. "It's just compliance would look slightly different in relation to this law if it's fully enacted."</p>

<p>Garlick defended Meta's processes for Australians to complain if they believed the company was spreading harmful misinformation or scams, although she said its content moderation centres were all in other countries.</p>

<p>Asked about Australian mining billionaire Andrew Forrest, who is suing Meta for showing cryptocurrency scam advertisements featuring his face, Garlick said the company had processes in place to detect and stop scams, but "there are a lot of challenges".</p>

<p>How could Meta call itself an advertising business when "some ads sell lies", asked Greens Senator Sarah Hanson-Young.</p>

<p>"We have policies and systems and tools to do everything we can to prevent those ads," Garlick replied.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3dhipio8_meta-facebook_625x300_09_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta's comments indicate it might take the same approach in Australia, as it did in Canada in 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-joe-biden-vs-donald-trump-round-1-fact-checking-both-presidential-candidates-5987198]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Vs Trump, Round 1: Fact-Checking Both Presidential Candidates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-joe-biden-vs-donald-trump-round-1-fact-checking-both-presidential-candidates-5987198]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 10:30:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and Republican challenger Donald Trump traded barbs Thursday in the first debate of the 2024 election campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and Republican challenger Donald Trump traded barbs Thursday in the first debate of the 2024 election campaign.</p>

<p>AFP fact-checked what the candidates said on key issues.</p>

<p><strong>'Migrant crime'</strong></p>

<p>Trump falsely claimed that under Biden, "we don't have borders anymore."</p>

<p>"Because of his ridiculous, insane and very stupid policies, people are coming in and they're killing our citizens at a level that we've never seen. We call it 'migrant crime.' I call it 'Biden migrant crime.'"</p>

<p>Following criticism over record border crossings and a bipartisan immigration bill that faltered in Congress, Biden signed an executive order early this month to temporarily shut down the border to asylum seekers after certain daily limits are hit.</p>

<p>That has amounted to "increased enforcement at the border," according to Nicole Hallett, director of the University of Chicago Law School's Immigrants' Rights Clinic.</p>

<p>Despite a few high-profile incidents, including the killing of a university student in the state of Georgia, there is "no evidence" of the migrant crime wave Trump described, Hallett told AFP.</p>

<p>"Crime is down across the country, even as migration has increased," she said.</p>

<p>Violent and property crimes are near the lowest levels in decades, according to FBI data from 2022, the most recent year for which figures are available.</p>

<p>"The overwhelming majority of violent crimes are committed by citizens," said Columbia Law School professor Jeffrey Fagan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A June 2023 study found a decline in incarceration rates among immigrants from all regions since 1960.</p>

<p>Other research has also found migrants commit fewer violent crimes than US citizens -- including a Cato Institute report published this week that found migrants are less likely to be convicted of murder in the state of Texas.</p>

<p>Michelle Mittelstadt, director of communications at the Migration Policy Institute, said there is also no evidence to support Trump's claims during the debate that prisoners and people from mental institutions are flooding across the southern US border.</p>

<p><strong>Inflation blame </strong></p>

<p>Both Trump and Biden sought to defer blame for rising prices by criticizing each other's economic policies.</p>

<p>"He causes inflation. I gave him a country with essentially no inflation," Trump said after reciting his favorite -- but false -- line about ushering in the greatest economy in US history.</p>

<p>Biden countered by saying Trump "decimated the economy" and there were "no jobs" when he took office.</p>

<p>Both candidates misled by omitting the impact of Covid-19 on the economy.</p>

<p>When Trump left office, inflation was around 1.4 percent as the country continued to battle the virus.</p>

<p>Unemployment was about 6.4 percent, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, down from its peak of 14.8 percent in April 2020 after the outbreak.</p>

<p>Inflation started to climb in April 2021 as the country opened up. It continued to balloon under Biden's presidency, hitting a peak of around nine percent in June 2022 before falling to its current level of about three percent.</p>

<p>Several pandemic-related factors have contributed to that trend, including emergency spending packages under both Trump and Biden, a supply crunch and the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p><strong>Rewriting January 6 </strong></p>

<p>Trump attempted to deflect blame for the January 6, 2021 attack on the US Capitol, over which he was impeached, by pointing to former House speaker Nancy Pelosi.</p>

<p>"I offered her 10,000 soldiers, or National Guard, and she turned them down," he falsely claimed.</p>

<p>Pelosi's team has denied being made aware of any request for National Guard assistance until the Capitol was under siege by Trump supporters seeking to overturn the 2020 election.</p>

<p>In fact, Pelosi would not have even had the authority to reject the National Guard's activation had Trump authorized it.</p>

<p>The District of Columbia National Guard "reports only to the president," its website says.</p>

<p>Trump's claim traces back to remarks from former acting defense secretary Christopher Miller, who told a reporter that he recalled Trump floating the idea before January 6 of needing 10,000 troops.</p>

<p>But Miller later told lawmakers that "there was no order from the president."</p>

<p>The House committee that investigated the January 6 attack wrote in its final report that Trump "never gave any order to deploy the National Guard."</p>

<p>Trump also insisted again that "the fraud and everything else was ridiculous" in the 2020 election he lost to Biden -- claims officials from both parties have refuted.</p>

<p>Dozens of lawsuits aimed at overturning the election failed, while audits and recounts in battleground states reaffirmed Biden's win.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hf3j8oio_joe-biden-trump_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both candidates misled by omitting the impact of Covid-19 on the economy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-joe-biden-had-slow-start-admits-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-tense-presidential-debate-5987154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Had "Slow Start", Admits Vice President On Tense Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-joe-biden-had-slow-start-admits-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-tense-presidential-debate-5987154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 10:21:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump faced off in the first presidential debate of the 2024 race. Below are reactions from lawmakers, political analysts, strategists and leaders of advocacy groups:]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump faced off in the first presidential debate of the 2024 race. Below are reactions from lawmakers, political analysts, strategists and leaders of advocacy groups:</p>

<p><strong>Kamala Harris, Vice President</strong></p>

<p>"What we saw tonight is the president making a very clear contrast with Donald Trump on all the issues that matter to the American people. Yes it was a slow start but it was a strong finish," Harris told CNN when asked about concerns that Biden should step aside.</p>

<p>"People can debate on style points but ultimately this election ... has to be about substance," she said.</p>

<p>"I'm not going to spend all night with you talking about the last 90 minutes when I've been watching the last three-and-a-half years of performance."</p>

<p><strong>Top Biden Donor, Who Did Not Wish To Be Named</strong></p>

<p>"There is no way to spin this. His performance was disqualifying. There is going to be a call for a brokered convention. Whitmer, Pritzker, Newsom, Beshear. Those could all be the options. It's inevitable."</p>

<p>The donor added that it would likely come down to Jill Biden to convince him. "He (Biden) is a stubborn guy ... It cannot be described how bad this performance was."</p>

<p>The donor said they thought Andy Beshear, the popular Democratic governor of Kentucky, a deeply Republican state at the federal level, would be the likely winner.</p>

<p>"He won red Kentucky. He'll be a great candidate who can still bring this home. I don't think Newsom (Democratic governor of California) will win."</p>

<p>Fundraising will "dry up," the donor predicted. "Money follows enthusiasm. How can anyone with a straight face say donate to elect Joe? ... I will continue to fundraise for him. What else can we all do? There is no option."</p>

<p><strong>Democratic Senator Raphael Warnock</strong></p>

<p>"I would be concerned if the president didn't have a record to run on, but the fact of the matter is this is a man who's passed historic legislation," Warnock said after the debate.</p>

<p>Julian Castro, Former Hud Secretary Under President Barack Obama</p>

<p>"Tonight was completely predictable. Biden had a very low bar going into the debate and failed to clear even that bar," Castro said on social media network X. "He seemed unprepared, lost, and not strong enough to parry effectively with Trump, who lies constantly."</p>

<p><strong>Amy Walter, Editor-In-Chief Of The Cook Political Report And A Prominent Political Analyst</strong></p>

<p>The debate "only served to remind voters of Biden's weaknesses, especially his health and stamina," Walters said. "To be sure, Trump did not 'win' this debate as much as Biden lost it. Trump lobbed multiple falsehoods and lies. He failed to make a positive case for his second term, spending more time litigating Biden's failures. But, Trump is leading in the polls and doesn't need a 'rest' in the way Biden does."</p>

<p>"I don't think that this debate will sway undecided voters, especially those who say they dislike both candidates. If you came into this debate thinking both men were unsatisfactory choices, their debate performances did not disabuse you of this opinion."</p>

<p><strong>Mitch Landrieu, Biden Campaign Co-Chair</strong></p>

<p>"Well, I thought it was a really bare-knuckled brawl. I think they're right, the president started off slow, but then he came back," Landrieu said on NBC News.</p>

<p>Landrieu acknowledged that the physical performance aspect of the debate will be top of people's minds. "But when you get into the substance of what was said, I think the takeaway from this was that Joe Biden was right on the substance. He told the truth."</p>

<p><strong>Matt Grossmann, Political Science Professor At Michigan State University</strong></p>

<p>"Obviously the biggest factor is that Biden still seemed old and raspy and less coherent than when he ran last time, and that's going to be the big story, I think, out of the debate. I don't think Trump really did anything to help himself beyond his existing supporters, but I think it is eclipsed by people's impressions of Biden on his biggest vulnerability."</p>

<p>Grossmann said that from the beginning of the debate Biden had trouble getting his points across "and just seemed a lot softer." He said Biden didn't really start delivering effective answers until 20 minutes into the debate. "It's hard to recover from that."</p>

<p>Grossmann said that debates typically have a small impact on presidential races and that impact dissipates over time. "Debates do not normally have huge influence on election results. But because we're at this 50-50 election where the country is divided, any small change can make a difference."</p>

<p>Grossmann said one problem for Biden is that some of his supporters are expressing their concerns about his performance rather than defending it. "So there's not a message in his favor. And to the extent that it has an influence, the influence will be to make people's concerns about Biden's age even more salient."</p>

<p><strong>Tevi Troy, Bipartisan Policy Center Fellow And Presidential Historian:</strong></p>

<p>Overall the debate "is going to be a problem for Biden," Troy said. Biden had a lot of answers where he looked weak. "There were other answers where he was more solid, but it doesn't matter because the problematic answers are going to live on through Twitter and social media."</p>

<p>Trump on the other hand was "more restrained" than in previous debates, Troy said. The rules of the debate where they shut off the mics "actually helped him (Trump) so he wasn't interrupting and didn't seem quite as rude."</p>

<p>"There's the phenomenon of the double haters, where people like neither candidate ... One guy's crazy, the other guy's too old. They were definitely validated in thinking the one guy is too old, and in terms of the crazy I think Trump did dial it down."</p>

<p><strong>Adrianne Shropshire, Executive Director Of Blackpac, An Organization That Works To Mobilize Black Voters</strong></p>

<p>Shropshire said she wrote down two things in her notepad while watching the debate. "One is that Trump lies," she said. The other was that Biden "was not as forceful as I thought he needed to be."</p>

<p>Shropshire criticized the moderators for allowing Trump to make various false claims without any pushback. "Trump was essentially allowed to do what he does at his rallies, which is say whatever he wants, regardless of the relationship it has to the truth. And that was really unfortunate."</p>

<p>Shropshire said Biden could have pushed back on Trump's false claims more forcefully. "I think he tried to take the high road by talking policy. And I think that has its place. But when we think about where our politics are right now, there really is a need to just assert facts and assert them very clearly. And I think that got muddled a bit in his policy responses."</p>

<p>Shropshire said she was not as worried as others who have said Biden had an unsteady performance that could increase about his age. "He has great performances that people have talked about just in the past few months," she said. "I also think that it just doesn't change the dynamics of the race, because they also saw Trump standing next to Joe Biden, and I don't think that they saw someone who was stronger necessarily. I think they saw the same unhinged Trump that they see at every rally and in clips when they're on social media."</p>

<p>Shropshire said one strong moment for Biden was when he pointed out that Trump was a convicted felon and criticized his morality. She also said that Trump's reference to migrants taking Black jobs had become "a hilarious meme all across Black Twitter right now." She said it showed how Trump was failing to connect with Black voters. "That there are specific Black jobs for Black people that immigrants are coming to take. Utter nonsense."</p>

<p><strong>Waleed Shahid, Senior Democratic Strategist And A Spokesperson For The National Uncommitteed Movement Against Biden</strong></p>

<p>"You can be mad at Biden but honestly the party establishment has been misleading people about Biden's electability. And it's malpractice - political and moral malpractice," Shahid said. "He completely lost the debate and if the strategy is to go into using the same tactics, where they want to recycle the 2016 playbook and make this an election about fact checking, that is not going to win."</p>

<p>Shahid called the debate "a tipping point," adding that "voters aren't stupid."</p>

<p>"I think we'll see what shakes out in a couple of weeks. But if they do end up replacing the candidate, that candidate does need time. So I don't know what will end up happening. I mean, this is unprecedented."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ube5fho_joe-biden-donald-trump-reuters_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-joe-bidens-freeze-moment-in-showdown-over-medicare-with-trump-5987094]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Joe Biden's 'Freeze Moment' In Showdown Over Medicare With Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-joe-bidens-freeze-moment-in-showdown-over-medicare-with-trump-5987094]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 10:10:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden was left fumbling for words during his the first presidential debate against his Republican rival and predecessor Donald Trump. The 81-year-old leader is frequently seen fumbling and freezing during public events.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was left fumbling for words during his first presidential debate against his Republican rival and predecessor Donald Trump. The 81-year-old leader, frequently seen fumbling and freezing during public events, appeared to lose his train of thought while answering a question by a CNN anchor on the economy.</p>

<p>A 30-second video showed the US President failing to make sense as he answered the question. “...making sure that we're able to make every single solitary person eligible for what I've been able to do with the with the COVID, excuse me, dealing with everything we have to do with..." the leader paused before making another gaffe by saying, “We finally beat Medicare".&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">YIKES: Joe Biden starts to freeze <a href="https://t.co/AQ7irpCrDf">pic.twitter.com/AQ7irpCrDf</a></p>
— Wendell Husebø (@WendellHusebo) <a href="https://twitter.com/WendellHusebo/status/1806497206033133810?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>Medicare is a US state health insurance program for people age 65 or older and people with disabilities.</p>

<p>Trump was quick to use the slip-up as an opportunity to hit out at his opponent. “He did beat Medicare. He beat it to death,” he quipped.</p>

<p>The Democrat made yet another mistake while answering a question on voters feeling "worse off" under his presidency</p>

<p>"Unemployment rate rose to 15% [under Trump], it was terrible,” Biden argued. “And so what we had to do is try to put things back together again. That's exactly what we began to do. We created 15,000 new jobs,” he said, instead of “15 million new jobs.”</p>

<p>During the fiery 90-minute debate, the two leaders traded barbs over the economy, democracy, war and the effect of age on their cognitive abilities.</p>

<p>While stopping at a restaurant for a meal after the debate, Biden told reporters he had a sore throat but "I think we did well."&nbsp;His deputy, Vice President Kamala Harris, admitted to CNN that the president had a slow start. "Yes, there was a slow start, but it was a strong finish," she said.</p>

<p>A survey by CNN found that 67 per cent of viewers thought Trump had won the debate.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hf3j8oio_joe-biden-trump_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-president-xi-jinping-urges-global-unity-amid-economic-and-security-disputes-5987055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Xi Jinping Urges Global Unity Amid Economic And Security Disputes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-president-xi-jinping-urges-global-unity-amid-economic-and-security-disputes-5987055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 10:06:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping on Friday called for the building of "bridges" in the global economy, as Beijing grapples with economic and security disputes with its neighbours and trading partners around the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping on Friday called for the building of "bridges" in the global economy, as Beijing grapples with economic and security disputes with its neighbours and trading partners around the world.</p>

<p>China will never leave the road of peaceful development, Xi said at a conference commemorating China's guiding principles for foreign affairs first formulated 70 years ago.</p>

<p>China will also not become a "strong" state that would try to dominate others, Xi told conference attendees that included former Myanmar President Thein Sein and former General Secretary of the Vietnamese Communist Party Nong Duc Manh.</p>

<p>"Facing the history of peace or war, prosperity or unity or confrontation, more than ever before, we need to carry forward the spirit and connotation of the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence," Xi said.</p>

<p>The Five Principles first appeared in a 1952 pact reached with regional rival India over their Himalayan border. Even so, Indian officials were absent from the front row of the audience reserved for guests of honour.</p>

<p>Since the 1950s, China's ruling Communist Party has gone from not being recognised by the United Nations to boasting the biggest diplomatic footprint in the world and presiding over the second-biggest economy.</p>

<p>Beijing now signals a desire that other countries see it as a diplomatic heavyweight, even as other countries accuse it of economic coercion and unfair competition.</p>

<p>After China brokered an unexpected detente between Iran and Saudi Arabia last year, Wang Yi, China's top diplomat, said the country would continue to play a constructive role in handling global hotspot issues.</p>

<p>But Beijing's unwillingness to condemn Russia's invasion of Ukraine and pursuit of a "no-limits partnership" with Moscow present hurdles to that ambition and saw China skip a summit on a peace conference in Switzerland earlier this month.</p>

<p>Rising tensions between China and the Philippines in the South China Sea, where Vietnam also has claims, have also led U.S. officials to remind Beijing that the mutual defence treaty obligations it has with the Philippines are ironclad.</p>

<p>China's trade ties with the European Union have also come under strain as the 27-state bloc plans to impose additional tariffs on Chinese-made electric vehicles, potentially opening up a new front in the West's tariff war with Beijing which began with Washington's initial import duties in 2018.</p>

<p>The EU accuses China of flooding its market with cheap EVs produced by Chinese automakers that have benefited from heavy state subsidies.</p>

<p>"In the era of economic globalisation, what we need is not to create chasms of division, but to build bridges of communication, and not raise the iron curtain of confrontation but to pave the way of cooperation," Xi said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ubd5reao_xi-jinping-reuters_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China now signals a desire that other countries see it as a diplomatic heavyweight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-donald-trump-joe-biden-snipe-about-golf-youre-the-worst-youre-a-whiner-5986997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You're The Worst!"; "You're A Whiner": Trump, Biden Snipe About Golf]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-donald-trump-joe-biden-snipe-about-golf-youre-the-worst-youre-a-whiner-5986997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:53:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A bad tempered and unedifying US presidential debate between the two oldest candidates ever to run for office degenerated into a squabble over golfing prowess on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A bad tempered and unedifying US presidential debate between the two oldest candidates ever to run for office degenerated into a squabble over golfing prowess on Thursday.</p>

<p>The first head-to-head in an already painfully long campaign saw 81-year-old Joe Biden and his 78-year-old challenger Donald Trump trade insults and accusations for 90 minutes on prime time television.</p>

<p>There was name-calling: "You're the worst!" "No, YOU'RE the worst!"</p>

<p>There were accusations: "You're a whiner!"</p>

<p>And then they fought over their golf handicaps.</p>

<p>"He can't hit a ball 50 yards," said Trump, on one of the few occasions the two men directly addressed each other.</p>

<p>"He challenged me to a golf match. He can't hit a ball 50 yards."</p>

<p>Trump's own vitality was never in question, he boasted, insisting "I'm in as good a shape as I was years ago."</p>

<p>Not to be outdone over his putting prowess, Biden insisted he was game on the green.</p>

<p>"I'd be happy to have a driving contest," he said. "I got my handicap when I was the vice president down to a six."</p>

<p>Trump scoffed.</p>

<p>"A six handicap?" he snorted. "I've seen your swing. I know your swing."</p>

<p>The exchange came towards the end of the CNN-hosted debate, which had started without the handshake that is customary on such occasions and gone downhill from there.</p>

<p>The animosity between the two men was palpable, with Biden taking an early swing at a man he said had "the morals of an alley cat."</p>

<p>"How many billions of dollars do you owe in civil penalties for molesting a woman in public... for having sex with a porn star... while your wife was pregnant," he said, in reference to Trump's alleged dalliance with adult film actress Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>The Republican former president again denied adultery, but a New York jury found him guilty of 34 counts of falsifying business records to cover up hush-money payments to her.</p>

<p>Trump wasted few chances to hammer home his claim that Biden was "weak" and not "a leader."</p>

<p>He also took aim at Biden's perceived mental frailties, an issue that polls repeatedly show voters are concerned about.</p>

<p>"I took two tests, cognitive tests. I aced them, both of them, as you know, we made it public," he said.</p>

<p>"He took none. I'd like to see him take one, just one, a real easy one, like go through the first five questions. He couldn't do it."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/gj2f6vr_donald-trump-joe-biden-afp_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential Election: The exchange came towards the end of the debate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-2024-faltering-joe-biden-forceful-donald-trump-clash-in-presidential-debate-5986774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Faltering Biden, Forceful Trump Clash In Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-2024-faltering-joe-biden-forceful-donald-trump-clash-in-presidential-debate-5986774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:06:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A halting Joe Biden struggled Thursday to hold off a forceful offensive from Donald Trump as the two traded personal insults in the fiery first debate of a razor-close presidential race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A halting Joe Biden struggled Thursday to hold off a forceful offensive from Donald Trump as the two traded personal insults in the fiery first debate of a razor-close presidential race.</p>

<p>A bombastic Trump lashed out at his successor, calling him a failure on the economy and the world stage. Biden looked to hit back, but his delivery was hesitant as he spoke rapidly in a soft, trailing-off voice and stumbled on his words several times.</p>

<p>It was the first debate ever between a president and former president -- and each accused each other of being history's worst. Trump and Biden, who were each the oldest president when first elected, even accused each other of being childlike as they argued over their golf swings.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, and Trump, 78, did not shake hands as they walked to their podiums at the CNN headquarters in Atlanta. There was no live audience and their microphones muted as the other spoke -- rules agreed as they open a campaign in a deeply polarized country.</p>

<p>Biden, who was reported to have a cold, hit Trump with clearly rehearsed lines as he sought to remind millions of television viewers that Trump would be the first convicted felon in the White House.</p>

<p>"Think of all the civil penalties you have. How many billions of dollars do you owe in civil penalties for, for molesting a woman in public," Biden said, and "for having sex with a porn star on the night, while your wife was pregnant?"</p>

<p>"You have the morals of an alley cat," Biden said.</p>

<p>Trump, a veteran of rallies and reality television, spoke loudly as he rushed through a long list of complaints about Biden's record.</p>

<p>"It's a shame what's happened to our country in the last four years," Trump said "I'm friends with a lot of people. They cannot believe what happened to the United States of America. We're no longer respected."</p>

<p>Trump sought to seize on Biden's delivery, saying at one point, "I really don't know what he said at the end of that sentence. I don't think he knows what he said either."</p>

<p>Kate Bedingfield, a former Biden communications director, acknowledged that "it was a really disappointing debate performance" from the president.</p>

<p>"I don't think there is any other way to slice it," she told CNN after the debate.</p>

<p><strong>Attack on economic record</strong></p>

<p>Biden immediately attacked Trump when he was asked about stubborn inflation, saying that he inherited an economy in "freefall."</p>

<p>Trump said that he led "the greatest economy in the history of our country."</p>

<p>"We have never done so well. Everybody was amazed by other countries were copying us," he said.</p>

<p>Biden shot back: "Well, look, the greatest economy in the world? He's the only one who thinks that."</p>

<p>In one of the most personal attacks, Biden cited accounts that Trump had described soldiers who died in the Normandy landing as "suckers" and noted his own son Beau, who served in Iraq and later died of cancer.</p>

<p>"My son was not a loser, was not a sucker. You're the sucker. You're the loser," Biden said.</p>

<p>Trump denied the remarks and repeatedly accused Biden of not being coherent.</p>

<p><strong>Clash on world role</strong></p>

<p>On the world stage, Trump accused Biden -- who faces a backlash from parts of his Democratic base over his support for Israel -- of not helping Israel "finish the job" against Hamas.</p>

<p>"He doesn't want to do it. He's become like a Palestinian -- but they don't like him because he's a very bad Palestinian, he's a weak one," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump described Biden's withdrawal from Afghanistan as the "most embarrassing moment in the history of our country" and said it encouraged Russia to invade Ukraine.</p>

<p>Biden, however, noted that he was the first recent president who has not had soldiers at risk overseas.</p>

<p>Trump and Biden also locked horns over abortion and immigration, key issues for their respective bases.</p>

<p>Biden, attacking Trump for appointing justices to the Supreme Court who ended Roe vs. Wade, the decision that allowed abortion rights around the country, said: "It's been a terrible thing, what you've done."</p>

<p>Some Democratic supporters quickly voiced anxiety about Biden's performance.</p>

<p>At a watch party in San Francisco, Hazel Reitz said she would still vote for Biden but added: "I can't understand a word that he says. Isn't it sad?"</p>

<p>Julian Zelizer, a historian at Princeton University, said Biden's supporters will be "extremely concerned."</p>

<p>"Biden fueled the basic perception that has continued to overshadow him," he said.</p>

<p>One candidate not on the stage was Robert F. Kennedy Jr., the member of the storied political dynasty who is running an anti-establishment campaign but failed to meet CNN's standard of reaching 15 percent in four national polls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kennedy instead spent the 90 minutes of the Biden-Trump debate taking questions on a livestream.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tovvvtjg_joe-biden-donald-trump-afp_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential debate 2024: It was the first debate ever between a president and former president]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-vs-trump-live-joe-biden-vs-donald-trump-us-presidential-debate-who-said-what-5986333]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You're The Sucker": Biden vs Trump Presidential Debate - Who Said What]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-vs-trump-live-joe-biden-vs-donald-trump-us-presidential-debate-who-said-what-5986333]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 07:01:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and his Republican challenger, former President Donald Trump, clashed in their first debate of the 2024 presidential election cycle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and his Republican challenger, former President Donald Trump, clashed in their first debate of the 2024 presidential election cycle. With no live audience present, the two candidates did not greet each other with a customary handshake and stood just feet apart at their respective podiums, setting the stage for a night of pointed exchanges.</p>

<h3><strong>On Economy</strong></h3>

<p>President Biden wasted no time in criticising Trump's economic legacy during the latter's tenure in the Oval Office. "Donald Trump left me an economy that was in free fall," Biden stated. He then slammed Trump's handling of the COVID-19 pandemic. "He said things were fine during the pandemic- just inject a little bleach in your arm. I turned our country around," Biden claimed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In another sharp rebuke, Biden highlighted job losses under Trump's administration, stating, "Donald Trump is the only president besides Herbert Hoover who left office with fewer jobs than when he began. Donald Trump had the largest national debt of any US president over a four-year period."</p>

<h3><strong>On Foreign Policy</strong></h3>

<p>The debate took a heated turn when the topic shifted to foreign policy, specifically the withdrawal of US troops from Afghanistan. Trump seized the opportunity to criticise Biden's execution of the withdrawal, calling it "the most embarrassing day in the history of our country's life."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was getting out of Afghanistan, but we were getting out with dignity, with strength, with power" he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden responded by saying, "When he was president they were still killing people in Afghanistan. He didn't do anything about that."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Referring to allegations that Trump had labeled these soldiers as "suckers," Biden invoked the memory of his late son Beau, who served in Iraq and later succumbed to cancer.</p>

<p>"My son was not a loser, was not a sucker. You're the sucker. You're the loser," Biden declared.</p>

<h3><strong>On Immigration</strong></h3>

<p>Immigration was another hot-button issue during the debate. Biden accused Trump of exaggerating and spreading falsehoods about the state of the country's immigration crisis. "The idea that illegal immigrants are being welcomed in the United States is simply not true," Biden said. "There's no data to support what he said. Once again, he's exaggerating. He's lying."</p>

<p>Trump countered by claiming that Biden had failed to secure the southern US border, which he claimed had allowed scores of criminals into the country. "I call it Biden migrant crime," Trump declared.</p>

<h3><strong>On Abortion Rights</strong></h3>

<p>The debate took a heated turn when Biden attacked Trump for being an advocate for abortion ban. He called Trump's actions "a terrible thing" after the Republican boasted of nominating Supreme Court justices that helped overturn Roe v. Wade. "It has been a terrible thing, what you have done," Biden said, in one of his firmer critiques of his presidential predecessor.</p>

<p>Trump defended his position by arguing that returning the issue to the states was the right course of action and accused Biden of not supporting any limits on abortions.</p>

<p>Addressing the plight of women who have been raped and now face greater obstacles in accessing abortion services, Biden added, "It's just ridiculous, and they can do nothing about it. You have the morals of an alley cat."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/d1docuf_biden-trump-afp-_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden wasted no time in criticising Trump's economic legacy during the latter's tenure.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-trump-face-off-in-early-debate-with-age-ability-in-focus-5986145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden And Trump Face Off In Early Debate, With Age, Ability In Focus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-trump-face-off-in-early-debate-with-age-ability-in-focus-5986145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:03:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump take the stage on Thursday night for a debate that will offer voters a rare side-by-side look at the two oldest candidates ever to seek the U.S. presidency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic President Joe Biden and his Republican rival Donald Trump take the stage on Thursday night for a debate that will offer voters a rare side-by-side look at the two oldest candidates ever to seek the U.S. presidency.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, and Trump, 78, will be under pressure to display their command of issues and avoid verbal stumbles as they seek a breakout moment in a race that opinion polls show has been deadlocked for months.</p>

<p>The 90-minute televised debate, the first between a sitting president and a former one, will air at 9 p.m. ET (0100 GMT on Friday) on CNN and takes place far earlier than normal - more than four months before the Nov. 5 Election Day.</p>

<p>It comes at a moment of profound polarization and deep-seated anxiety among voters about the state of American politics. Two-thirds of voters said in a May Reuters/Ipsos poll that they were concerned violence could follow the election, nearly four years after a mob of Trump supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol.</p>

<p>Trump will take the stage as a felon who still faces a trio of criminal cases, including to his efforts to overturn the 2020 election. The former president, who continues to falsely claim that his defeat was the result of fraud and has suggested he will punish his political enemies if returned to power, will need to convince undecided voters that he does not pose a mortal threat to democracy, as Biden asserts.</p>

<p>Biden arrived in Atlanta on Thursday afternoon under intense pressure to deliver a forceful performance after months of Republican assertions his faculties have dulled with age.</p>

<p>Ahead of the debate, the Biden campaign released a video featuring former Trump aides saying they would not support him this time. "Take it from the people who know Donald Trump best - he is unfit to be president," Biden said on X.</p>

<p>Biden advisers say he will emphasize Trump's role in threatening abortion access, portray him as a danger to democratic norms and remind voters of Trump's often chaotic 2017-2021 term in office.</p>

<p>Trump will focus on the high levels of inflation and record numbers of migrants who have entered the country illegally under Biden's watch, and will also question his world leadership at a time of war in Gaza and Ukraine, Trump advisers said.</p>

<p>Trump, whose plane landed in Georgia about 3-1/2 hours before the debate, posted on social media what appeared to be advice from a former member of his administration about how to respond to attacks on his environmental record. The notes from former Environmental Protection Agency chief Andrew Wheeler urged Trump to say he will lower carbon dioxide emissions and encourage domestic energy production.</p>

<p>A campaign spokesman said the post was not a mistake. "The Biden team has been previewing their attacks -- albeit moronic attacks -- all week," spokesman Stephen Cheung said.</p>

<p><strong>DISLIKED DUO</strong></p>

<p>While national polls show a tied race, Biden has trailed Trump in polls of most battleground states and recently saw his financial edge erased after Trump was criminally convicted over trying to cover up hush money payments to porn star Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>"Biden needs a change in the status quo, and this debate is his best opportunity yet to do it," said Jacob Rubashkin, an elections analyst at the nonpartisan website Inside Elections.</p>

<p>Neither Biden nor Trump is popular and many Americans remain deeply ambivalent about their choices. About a fifth of voters say they have not picked a candidate, are leaning toward a third-party candidate or may sit the election out, the latest Reuters/Ipsos poll showed.</p>

<p>"They're horrible candidates," said Kathy Elder, a 59-year-old sales manager who voted for Trump in 2016 before switching to Biden in 2020.</p>

<p>Elder said she cringes whenever they speak – for different reasons.</p>

<p>When it comes to Biden, she said, "Can he speed this up and actually talk?" As for Trump, she said, "What the hell is going to come out of his mouth?"</p>

<p>Biden and Trump have made little effort to disguise their mutual dislike. During their first debate in 2020, Trump aggressively talked over Biden in a performance that turned off many voters.</p>

<p>CNN will attempt to avoid cross-talk by muting the candidates' microphones when it is not their turn. The debate will take place without an audience, and neither candidate is allowed to bring notes or props, though they will have a pen and paper.</p>

<p>Trump's niece Mary Trump, who has been critical of her uncle, will join Biden's campaign in its media spin room following the debate, a campaign official said.</p>

<p>The second and final debate in this year's campaign is scheduled for September.</p>

<p>See a Reuters photo slide show of previous debates.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/sd77uu9g_biden-trump-split-image_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden-Trump Debate: Biden and Trump have made little effort to disguise their mutual dislike.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-to-vote-today-for-new-president-following-ebrahim-raisis-death-in-helicopter-crash-5985970]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran To Vote Today For New President Following Ebrahim Raisi's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-to-vote-today-for-new-president-following-ebrahim-raisis-death-in-helicopter-crash-5985970]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 05:06:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iranians will vote for a new president on Friday following Ebrahim Raisi's death in a helicopter crash, choosing from a tightly controlled group of four candidates loyal to the supreme leader, at a time of growing public frustration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Iranians will vote for a new president on Friday following Ebrahim Raisi's death in a helicopter crash, choosing from a tightly controlled group of four candidates loyal to the supreme leader, at a time of growing public frustration.</p>

<p>While the election is unlikely to bring a major shift in the Islamic Republic's policies, the outcome could influence the succession to Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Iran's 85-year-old supreme leader, in power for three-and-a-half decades.</p>

<p>Khamenei has called for a "maximum" turnout to offset a legitimacy crisis fuelled by public discontent over economic hardship and curbs on political and social freedoms.</p>

<p>Voter turnout has plunged over the past four years, with a mostly young population chafing at political and social restrictions.</p>

<p>Polls open at 8:00 am local time (0430 GMT) and close at 6:00 pm (1430 pm GMT), but are usually extended until as late as midnight. As ballots are counted manually, the final result is expected to be announced only in two days although initial figures may come out sooner.</p>

<p>If no candidate wins at least 50 percent plus one vote from all ballots cast including blank votes, a run-off round between the top two candidates is held on the first Friday after the election result is declared.</p>

<p>Three of the candidates are hardliners and one a low-profile comparative moderate, backed by the reformist faction that has largely been sidelined in Iran in recent years.</p>

<p>Critics of Iran's clerical rule say the low and declining turnout of recent elections shows the system's legitimacy has eroded. Just 48% of voters participated in the 2021 election that brought Raisi to power, and turnout hit a record low of 41% in a parliamentary election three months ago.</p>

<p>The election now coincides with escalating regional tensions due to war between Israel and Iranian allies Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon, as well as increased Western pressure on Iran over its fast-advancing nuclear programme.</p>

<p>The next president is not expected to produce any major policy shift on Iran's nuclear programme or support for militia groups across the Middle East, since Khamenei calls all the shots on top state matters. However, the president runs the government day-to-day and can influence the tone of Iran's foreign and domestic policy.</p>

<p>A hardline watchdog body made up of six clerics and six jurists aligned with Khamenei vets candidates. It approved just six candidates from an initial pool of 80. Two hardline candidates subsequently dropped out.</p>

<p>Prominent among the remaining hardliners are Mohammad Baqer Qalibaf, parliament speaker and former commander of the powerful Revolutionary Guards, and Saeed Jalili, a former nuclear negotiator who served for four years in Khamenei's office.</p>

<p>The sole comparative moderate, Massoud Pezeshkian, is faithful to the country's theocratic rule but advocates detente with the West, economic reform, social liberalisation and political pluralism.</p>

<p>His chances hinge on reviving the enthusiasm of reform-minded voters who have largely stayed away from the polls for the last four years after previous pragmatist presidents achieved little change. He could also benefit from his rivals' failure to consolidate the hardline vote.</p>

<p>All four candidates have vowed to revive the flagging economy, beset by mismanagement, state corruption and sanctions reimposed since 2018 after the U.S. ditched Tehran's 2015 nuclear pact with six world powers.</p>

<p>The hashtag #ElectionCircus has been widely posted on social media platform X by Iranians in the past few weeks, with some activists at home and abroad calling for an election boycott, arguing that a high turnout would legitimise the Islamic Republic.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/pcm37tm8_iran-vote_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran Vote: Polls open at 8:00 am local time (0430 GMT) and close at 6:00 pm (1430 pm GMT).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-leaders-nominate-von-der-leyen-to-head-commission-for-2nd-term-5985915]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EU Leaders Nominate Von Der Leyen To Head Commission For 2nd Term]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-leaders-nominate-von-der-leyen-to-head-commission-for-2nd-term-5985915]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 04:46:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[European Union leaders agreed on Friday to nominate Ursula von der Leyen of Germany for a second five-year term as president of the European Commission, the EU's powerful executive body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>European Union leaders agreed on Friday to nominate Ursula von der Leyen of Germany for a second five-year term as president of the European Commission, the EU's powerful executive body.</p>

<p>At a summit in Brussels, the bloc's 27 national leaders also picked former Portuguese premier Antonio Costa as the future chair of their European Council meetings and selected Estonian Prime Minister Kaja Kallas as the next EU foreign policy chief.</p>

<p>The leadership package represents continuity for the 27-member bloc, with centrist pro-EU factions keeping hold of top posts despite a far-right surge in elections to the European Parliament earlier this month.</p>

<p>The deal was announced by the current European Council president, Charles Michel, on social media.</p>

<p>The trio won broad backing from leaders but diplomats said right-wing Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni abstained from the vote on von der Leyen and voted against Costa and Kallas.</p>

<p>Von der Leyen's nomination still needs approval from the European Parliament in a secret ballot - widely seen as a trickier proposition than her endorsement by EU leaders.</p>

<p>At the summit, the EU also signed a security agreement with Ukraine, debated how to bolster EU defences against Russia and agreed bloc's strategic priorities for the next five years.</p>

<p>The security deal underlines EU support for Kyiv fighting off Moscow's invasion for a third year, despite gains by the far-right in European elections, uncertainty created by French snap elections and the U.S. presidential vote in November.</p>

<p>The agreement lays out the EU's commitments to help Ukraine in nine areas of security policy - including arms deliveries, military training, defence industry cooperation and demining.</p>

<p>"These commitments will help Ukraine defend itself, resist destabilisation, and deter future acts of aggression - more concrete proof of the EU's unshakeable resolve to support Ukraine for the long haul," Michel said.</p>

<p>The leaders will reiterate their pledge to support Ukraine as long as it takes, stressing that "Russia must not prevail" and that Ukraine must get back the land annexed by Moscow.</p>

<p><strong>DEFENCE DEBATE</strong></p>

<p>The war in Ukraine laid bare the EU's lack of preparedness for a conflict as the bloc struggles to supply Kyiv with enough weapons against Russia, prompting calls for more EU coordination of defence systems and investment in defence industries.</p>

<p>Diplomats said von der Leyen told the summit that between 1999 and 2021, the EU increased defence spending by 20%, China by 600% and Russia by 300%, even before Moscow's massive rise in military spending after its invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</p>

<p>According to diplomats, von der Leyen told leaders the EU needed to invest 500 billion euros ($535.30 billion) in defence over the next 10 years. Financing options ranged from national contributions, dedicated revenue streams - called the EU's own resources - and joint borrowing, von der Leyen said.</p>

<p>Investment in defence is part of the EU's "strategic agenda" that the leaders aim to agree before dinner on Thursday - a document that tells EU institutions what European governments want them to focus on during their 2024-2029 term.</p>

<p>Apart from defence, the agenda calls for a more competitive EU to withstand economic pressure from China and the United States and for preparing the bloc for enlargement that would include Ukraine, Moldova and the Western Balkans.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/ogonc1v_ursula-von-der-leyen_625x300_26_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Von der Leyen's nomination still needs approval from the European Parliament in a secret ballot.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-tells-clients-russian-hackers-viewed-emails-report-5985878]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Tells Clients Russian Hackers Viewed Emails: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-tells-clients-russian-hackers-viewed-emails-report-5985878]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 04:34:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp is informing some of its customers that a Russian state-sponsored hacking group breached its internal systems and accessed their emails, Bloomberg News reported on Thursday, citing a company spokesperson.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Corp is informing some of its customers that a Russian state-sponsored hacking group breached its internal systems and accessed their emails, Bloomberg News reported on Thursday, citing a company spokesperson.</p>

<p>The technology giant is also providing previously notified clients with details of which data was taken, the report said.</p>

<p>Microsoft did not immediately respond to a request emailed by Reuters for comment and calls to spokespersons went unanswered.</p>

<p>The company had said in January, too, that a Russian state-sponsored group had hacked into its corporate systems and stolen some emails and documents from staff accounts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/0qs8jbe8_microsoft_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company had said in January, too, that a Russian hackers had hacked into its corporate systems.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-rockets-at-israeli-base-says-4-fighters-killed-5985469]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Fires Rockets At Israeli Base, Says 4 Fighters Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-rockets-at-israeli-base-says-4-fighters-killed-5985469]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 02:19:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah said it fired "dozens" of rockets Thursday at a military base in northern Israel in retaliation for Israeli strikes on Lebanon, announcing four of its fighters had been killed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah said it fired "dozens" of rockets Thursday at a military base in northern Israel in retaliation for Israeli strikes on Lebanon, announcing four of its fighters had been killed.</p>

<p>Fears of all-out war between Israel and Hezbollah have risen in recent weeks as threats have intensified between the sides, which have traded regular cross-border fire since Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel sparked war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Hamas ally Hezbollah said that "in response to the enemy attacks that targeted the city of Nabatiyeh and village of Sohmor", its fighters bombed "the main air and missile defence base of the (Israeli) northern area command... with dozens of Katyusha rockets".</p>

<p>It said in separate statements that four of its fighters, one from eastern Lebanon's Sohmor, had been killed, and claimed two other attacks on Israeli troops and positions, including one with drones.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement that "approximately 35 launches were identified crossing from Lebanon".</p>

<p>Air defences "successfully intercepted most of the launches. No injuries were reported," it added.</p>

<p>It said air strikes "eliminated" three Hezbollah operatives, one in the Sohmor area and two in the country's south.</p>

<p>The military also said that "two UAVs (drones) that were identified crossing from Lebanon fell" in northern Israel, reporting no injuries.</p>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency reported Israeli attacks in several areas of south Lebanon on Thursday, and said a strike a day earlier in Nabatiyeh wounded "more than 20" people when a two-storey building was targeted.</p>

<p>Fears have grown the Gaza war could become a regional conflagration if the Israel-Hezbollah conflict, which so far has been largely limited to the border area, expands.</p>

<p>France's foreign ministry said Thursday that Paris was "extremely concerned" about the fighting, calling "all sides to exercise the greatest restraint".</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said during a visit to Washington on Wednesday that his country did not want war in Lebanon, but could send it back to the "Stone Age" if diplomacy failed.</p>

<p>Amid Western diplomatic efforts to dial down tensions in recent months, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock on Tuesday visited Beirut and cautioned that "miscalculation" could trigger all-out war, also urging "extreme restraint".</p>

<p>The violence has killed 485 people in Lebanon, most of them fighters but also including 94 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, at least 15 soldiers and 11 civilians have been killed, according to authorities.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t0borbr4_hezbollah_625x300_28_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On the Israeli side, at least 15 soldiers and 11 civilians have been killed, according to authorities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-war-israeli-anti-government-protesters-march-on-benjamin-netanyahus-home-5985376]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid War, Israeli Anti-Government Protesters March On Netanyahu's Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-war-israeli-anti-government-protesters-march-on-benjamin-netanyahus-home-5985376]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 01:53:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anti-government protesters gathered in Jerusalem on Thursday and converged on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's home, lighting a bonfire on the street outside and calling for his resignation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anti-government protesters gathered in Jerusalem on Thursday and converged on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's home, lighting a bonfire on the street outside and calling for his resignation.</p>

<p>"We've been abandoned - Elections now!" read one sign that rose above the crowd. Demonstrators yelled through megaphones, waved flags and banged on snare drums while police officers stood at barricades.</p>

<p>Such demonstrations have grown more frequent as the war against Hamas in Gaza rages on and fighting with Hezbollah in Lebanon threatens to escalate, but they have not reached the fever pitch of a year ago when Netanyahu's government tried to overhaul Israel's justice system.</p>

<p>Many in the crowd, which appeared to number in the thousands, also chanted their support for reaching a deal to free some 120 Israeli hostages being held by Palestinian Islamist group Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>As the sun began to set, protesters blocked traffic and lit a large bonfire on the central Jerusalem street. But there were no reports of major scuffles and police did not use a water cannon to control the crowd, as they have during more rowdy demonstrations.</p>

<p>The protest movement has yet to change the political landscape, and Netanyahu still controls a stable majority in parliament.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/588mi5m8_israel-anti-government-protest_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anti-government protesters gathered in Jerusalem on Thursday and called for Netanyahu's resignation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>