<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:35:16 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-calls-for-ceasefire-in-lebanon-but-israeli-incursion-seems-imminent-6687175]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Calls For Ceasefire In Lebanon But Israeli Incursion Seems Imminent]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-calls-for-ceasefire-in-lebanon-but-israeli-incursion-seems-imminent-6687175]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:22:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden called for a ceasefire in Lebanon on Monday but a US official said Israeli troop deployments suggested a ground incursion against Hezbollah militants could be imminent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden called for a ceasefire in Lebanon on Monday but a US official said Israeli troop deployments suggested a ground incursion against Hezbollah militants could be imminent.</p>

<p>Asked about reports that Israeli ground troops were preparing to move into southern Lebanon, Biden told reporters that he was "comfortable with them (Israel) stopping."</p>

<p>Several top aides reinforced Biden's call for a ceasefire by urging a diplomatic resolution to the violence to allow tens of thousands of displaced Israelis and Lebanese to return to their homes along the border.</p>

<p>Washington "will continue to work with our partners in the region and around the world to advance a diplomatic resolution," Secretary of State Antony Blinken told a State Department conference.</p>

<p>But a U.S. official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said that the positioning of Israeli troops as observed by the United States suggested a ground incursion into Lebanon could be imminent.</p>

<p>The official declined to comment further or to provide details on the posture of Israeli forces.</p>

<p>The US call for de-escalation follows two weeks of Israeli airstrikes and assassinations of Hezbollah commanders, including the Iran-backed group's leader, Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, on Friday.</p>

<p>Israeli officials say they will do what is necessary to return some 70,000 citizens evacuated from northern Israeli communities after Hezbollah on Oct. 8 began rocket strikes in support of a Hamas assault on Israel from Gaza the previous day.</p>

<p>Speaking to troops deployed along Israel's northern border, Defence Minister Yoav Gallant hinted at a looming ground incursion.</p>

<p>"We will use all the means that may be required - your forces, other forces, from the air, from the sea, and on land. Good luck," Gallant said.</p>

<p>The Biden administration fears the killing of Nasrallah and further Israeli military action could ignite a wider regional conflict.</p>

<p>The U.S. envoy to the United Nations urged continued diplomacy to halt the violence in Lebanon and Gaza.</p>

<p>"We want to find a path to peace, so that Palestinians and Israelis have safety and Lebanese and Israelis living on the northern border find security and safety as well," U.S. Ambassador to the U.N. Linda Thomas-Greenfield told reporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jvv72ca_israel-attack-on-beirut_625x300_30_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US call for de-escalation follows two weeks of Israeli airstrikes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-list-of-important-dates-in-2024-us-presidential-election-6687136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A List Of Important Dates In 2024 US Presidential Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-list-of-important-dates-in-2024-us-presidential-election-6687136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:16:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the November 5 US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Here is a timeline of events related to the election between now and Inauguration Day next January.</p>

<p>- <strong>Oct. 1</strong>: Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance and Democratic rival Tim Walz will take part in a debate hosted by CBS News.</p>

<p>-<strong> Nov. 5: Election Day</strong></p>

<p>- Later in November: It could take days for the election result to be known, especially if it is close and mail-in ballots are a factor.</p>

<p>- <strong>Nov. 26</strong>: Trump, the first sitting or former U.S. president to be convicted of a crime, is due to be sentenced in the Manhattan hush money case where he was found guilty of falsifying documents to cover up a payment to silence a porn star. Trump has denied wrongdoing and sentencing was originally due to take place on Sept. 18.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- <strong>Dec. 17</strong>: Electors, who together form the Electoral College, meet in their respective states or the District of Columbia to select the president and vice president.</p>

<p>- <strong>Dec. 25</strong>: The electoral votes must be received by the president of the Senate - a role held by the vice president, currently Harris - and the archivist by this date.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>2025</strong></p>

<p>- <strong>Jan. 6</strong>: The vice president presides over the Electoral College vote count at a joint session of Congress, announces the results and declares who has been elected.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ahead of the count on Jan. 6, 2021, Trump lambasted his vice president, Mike Pence, for refusing to try to prevent Congress from certifying Biden's win. On that day, the U.S. Capitol was attacked by Trump supporters trying to stop the count. Biden's win was certified early the next day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Congress has since passed the Electoral Count Reform and Presidential Transition Improvement Act of 2022, which requires approval of one-fifth of the House and Senate to consider a challenge to a state's results - a much higher bar than existed before, when any single lawmaker from each chamber could trigger a challenge.</p>

<p>- <strong>Jan. 20:</strong> The inauguration of the election winner and their vice president takes place. At this ceremony, the victor and the vice president are officially sworn into office.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/tiie9gi4_us-elections-reuters_625x300_08_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The voting will take place on November 5.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-explain-mount-everests-more-than-expected-growth-6686986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Explain Mount Everest's 'More Than Expected' Growth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-explain-mount-everests-more-than-expected-growth-6686986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:51:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mount Everest is Earth's tallest mountain - towering 5.5 miles (8.85 km) above sea level - and is still growing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mount Everest is Earth's tallest mountain - towering 5.5 miles (8.85 km) above sea level - and is still growing.</p>

<p>While it and the rest of the Himalayas are continuing an inexorable uplift that dates back to their birth roughly 50 million years ago when the Indian subcontinent collided with Eurasia, Everest is growing more than expected from this alone. Scientists now think they know the reason why, and it has to do with the monumental merger of two nearby river systems.</p>

<p>Everest has gained roughly 49-164 feet (15-50 meters) in height due to this change in the regional river system, with the Kosi river merging with the Arun river approximately 89,000 years ago, the researchers estimated. That translates to an uplift rate of roughly 0.01-0.02 inches (0.2-0.5 millimetres) per year.</p>

<p>The geological process at work, they said, is called isostatic rebound. It involves the rise of land masses on Earth's crust when the weight of the surface diminishes. The crust, Earth's outermost layer, essentially floats atop a mantle layer made of hot, semi-liquid rock.</p>

<p>In this case, the merger of the rivers - more like a hostile takeover, with the Kosi subjugating the Arun as the rivers changed course over time - resulted in accelerated erosion that has carried off huge amounts of rock and soil, reducing the weight of the region near Everest.</p>

<p>"Isostatic rebound can be likened to a floating object adjusting its position when weight is removed," said geoscientist Jin-Gen Dai of China University of Geosciences in Beijing, one of the leaders of the study published on Monday in the journal Nature Geoscience.</p>

<p>"When a heavy load, such as ice or eroded rock, is removed from the Earth's crust, the land beneath slowly rises in response, much like a boat rising in water when cargo is unloaded," Dai added.</p>

<p>The main gorge of the merged river system is located approximately 28 miles (45 km) east of Everest.</p>

<p>The researchers, who used numerical models to simulate the evolution of the river system, estimated that isostatic rebound accounts for about 10% of Everest's annual uplift rate.</p>

<p>This geological process is not unique to the Himalayas.</p>

<p>"A classic example is in Scandinavia, where the land is still rising in response to the melting of thick ice sheets that covered the region during the last Ice Age. This process continues today, affecting coastlines and landscapes, thousands of years after the ice retreated," Dai said.</p>

<p>Study co-author Adam Smith, a University College London doctoral student in Earth sciences, said GPS measurements reveal the continued rising of Everest and the rest of the Himalayas.</p>

<p>This uplift outpaces the continued surface erosion caused by factors such as wind, rain and river flow. As this erosion continues, Everest's uplift rate from isostatic rebound may increase, Smith said.</p>

<p>Neighbouring peaks including Lhotse, the world's fourth highest, and Makalu, the fifth highest, also get a boost from the same process. Lhotse is experiencing an uplift rate similar to Everest. Makalu, situated closer to the Arun, has a slightly higher uplift rate.</p>

<p>"This research underscores our planet's dynamic nature. Even a seemingly immutable feature like Mount Everest is subject to ongoing geological processes, reminding us that Earth is constantly changing, often in ways imperceptible in our daily lives," Dai said.</p>

<p>Earth's rigid outer part is divided into colossal plates that move gradually over time in a process called plate tectonics, with the Himalayas rising following a collision between two plates.</p>

<p>Everest, also called Sagarmatha in Nepali and Chomolungma in Tibetan, is situated on the border between Nepal and the Tibet Autonomous Region of China. It was named for George Everest, a 19th-century British surveyor in India.</p>

<p>"Mount Everest occupies a unique place in human consciousness," Dai said.</p>

<p>"Physically, it represents Earth's highest point, giving it immense significance simply by virtue of its stature," Dai added. "Culturally, Everest is sacred to local Sherpa and Tibetan communities. Globally, it symbolizes the ultimate challenge, embodying human endurance and our drive to surpass perceived limits."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q82v1fjo_mount-everest_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The geological process at work, they said, is called isostatic rebound.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nowhere-in-middle-east-israel-cannot-reach-benjamin-netanyahu-warns-iran-6686791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Nowhere In Middle East Israel Cannot Reach": Netanyahu Warns Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nowhere-in-middle-east-israel-cannot-reach-benjamin-netanyahu-warns-iran-6686791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:28:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu issued a fresh warning to Iran Monday, saying there was no place in the Middle East beyond Israel's reach amid a flurry of strikes against Hezbollah in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu issued a fresh warning to Iran Monday, saying there was no place in the Middle East beyond Israel's reach amid a flurry of strikes against Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>In a video statement made in English, Netanyahu addressed the people of Iran and warned that their government was bringing them "closer to the abyss".</p>

<p>"With every passing moment, the regime is bringing you -- the noble Persian people -- closer to the abyss," said Netanyahu.</p>

<p>"There is nowhere in the Middle East Israel cannot reach," the prime minister added, warning the people of Iran that their "regime plunges our region deeper into darkness and deeper into war".</p>

<p>"Don't let a small group of theocrats crush your hopes and your dreams," Netanyahu said.</p>

<p>Israel has in recent days been mounting heavy air strikes in Lebanon against the "Axis of Resistance", a network of Iran-aligned militant groups in the region, including in Syria, Yemen and Iraq.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike in Beirut Friday killed Hassan Nasrallah, the head of the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah which has been armed and financed by the Islamic Republic for years.</p>

<p>Iran has also vowed to avenge the killing of Abbas Nilforoushan, a top commander of the Quds Force, the foreign operations arm of Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, who died alongside the Hezbollah leader on Friday.</p>

<p>In his video statement, Netanyahu expressed hope for a future "when Iran is finally free", saying it would "come a lot sooner than people think".</p>

<p>"Everything will be different," he said. "Our two countries, Israel and Iran, will be at peace. Iran will thrive as never before."</p>

<p>Netanyahu's comments came hours after Iran's foreign ministry spokesman said the country had no plans to send its fighters to directly confront Israel.</p>

<p>"There is no need to send extra or volunteer forces of the Islamic Republic of Iran," said foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani, adding that Lebanon and fighters in the Palestinian territories "have the capability and strength to defend themselves against the aggression".</p>

<p>Earlier Monday, Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian visited Hezbollah's office in Tehran "to pay tribute" to Nasrallah, according to the government's website.</p>

<p>Supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei -- who has the final say in all matters of the state in Iran -- has vowed that Nasrallah's death "will not be in vain".</p>

<p>Khamenei said Israel was "too weak to cause significant damage to the solid construction of Hezbollah in Lebanon" and called on the "Axis of Resistance" to stand with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"Lebanon will make the aggressor and the evil enemy regretful," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3b6ofdcg_netanyahu_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu expressed hope for a future "when Iran is finally free". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-vows-to-keep-fighting-israel-after-nasrallahs-killing-in-strikes-6686787]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Vows To Keep Fighting Israel After Nasrallah's Killing In Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-vows-to-keep-fighting-israel-after-nasrallahs-killing-in-strikes-6686787]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:27:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah vowed on Monday to keep fighting Israel and said it was ready to face any ground operation into Lebanon, after its leader was killed in an air strike that dealt the group a seismic blow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah vowed on Monday to keep fighting Israel and said it was ready to face any ground operation into Lebanon after its leader was killed in an air strike that dealt the group a seismic blow.</p>

<p>In a televised address, the Iran-backed group's deputy chief Naim Qassem said a new leader to replace Hassan Nasrallah, who enjoyed cult status among his supporters, would be selected "at the earliest opportunity".</p>

<p>He also said the group was ready for any Israeli ground offensive, even though Israel's bombardment of its strongholds has in the past week killed a large number of its top commanders and officials.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began low-intensity cross-border strikes on Israeli troops a day after its Palestinian ally Hamas staged its unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7, triggering war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Israel said earlier this month that it was shifting its focus from Gaza to securing its northern border with Lebanon, in order to allow Israelis displaced since October to return to their homes.</p>

<p>It has also not ruled out a ground offensive in order to achieve its goals.</p>

<p>Israel's strikes on Lebanon have killed hundreds and forced hundreds of thousands more to flee their homes, and left people across the region fearful of more violence to come.</p>

<p>Qassem said Hezbollah would continue "confronting the Israeli enemy in support of Gaza and Palestine, in defence of Lebanon and its people, and in response to the assassinations and the killing of civilians".</p>

<p>Warning that any battle with Israel would be long, he said: "We will face any scenario and we are ready if Israel decides to enter by land, the resistance forces are ready for any ground confrontation."</p>

<p>On the other side of the border, Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant told troops: "The elimination of Nasrallah is an important step, but it is not the final one."</p>

<p>"In order to ensure the return of Israel's northern communities, we will employ all of our capabilities, and this includes you," he said.</p>

<p><strong>- Beirut strike -</strong></p>

<p>Most of Israel's strikes have targeted Hezbollah strongholds in eastern and southern Lebanon and the southern suburbs of Beirut, the group's main bastion.</p>

<p>On Monday, a drone strike hit a building in the Cola district in central Beirut, with an armed Palestinian group saying it had killed three of its members.</p>

<p>The strike, the first in the centre of the city in years, sparked panic, with 41-year-old resident Mohammed al-Hoss saying "the kids were in shock" after his house was damaged.</p>

<p>"We are with Gaza and support the Palestinian cause, but our country cannot cope with us going to war," he said.</p>

<p>"Our country is in a wretched state. They (Israel) finished with Gaza and they have come to Lebanon."</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry also reported the strike, saying it had killed four people and wounded four others. Israel has yet to comment.</p>

<p>Palestinian Islamist group Hamas later announced that its leader in Lebanon, Fatah Sharif Abu al-Amine, had been killed along with his wife and two children in another strike on Al-Bass refugee camp in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Israeli military confirmed it had "eliminated" Sharif in a strike.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said six rescuers affiliated with Hezbollah were killed in an Israeli strike Monday.</p>

<p>Around Lebanon, Israeli strikes killed more than 100 people on Sunday, including 45 near the southern city of Sidon, according to the ministry.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Health Minister Firass Abiad said Saturday that 1,030 people including 87 children had been killed since September 16.</p>

<p>UN refugee agency chief Filippo Grandi said "well over 200,000 people are displaced inside Lebanon", while more than 100,000 have fled to neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Najib Mikati said up to one million people may have been uprooted, in potentially the "largest displacement movement" in Lebanon's history.</p>

<p><strong>- Yemen strikes -</strong></p>

<p>The violence in Lebanon has raised fears of a much wider conflagration in the region.</p>

<p>On Monday, the Israeli army said it "successfully intercepted a suspicious aerial target that crossed from Lebanon into Israeli territory".</p>

<p>Israel said it also carried out strikes on Sunday targeting Iran-backed Huthis in Yemen that the rebels said killed four people and wounded 33.</p>

<p>The raids in Yemen came a day after the Huthis said they launched a missile at Israel's Ben Gurion airport, trying to hit it as Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was returning from New York.</p>

<p>Iran has said Nasrallah's killing would bring about Israel's "destruction", though the foreign ministry said Monday it would not deploy any fighters to confront Israel.</p>

<p>Lebanon began a three-day national mourning period for Nasrallah on Monday, with flags flying at half-mast.</p>

<p>In Israel, some had mixed feelings about the Hezbollah chief's killing.</p>

<p>"Nasrallah was responsible for the deaths of many Israelis, so it is good news," said Matan Sofer, 24, in the northern town of Rosh Pina.</p>

<p>"But do we risk it getting worse, who knows?"</p>

<p><strong>- Calls for halt -</strong></p>

<p>World leaders have called for a de-escalation.</p>

<p>French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot met with the Lebanese premier in Beirut Monday, and said his government sought "an immediate halt" in the strikes.</p>

<p>He is the first high-level foreign diplomat to visit since the Israeli strikes intensified.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, whose government is Israel's top arms supplier, said Sunday a wider war "really has to be avoided".</p>

<p>In Gaza, AFP journalists said the number of air strikes across the territory has dropped significantly in recent days.</p>

<p>Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,615 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/edmrg2ao_israelhezbollah-conflict_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[srael said earlier this month that it was shifting its focus from Gaza to Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-issues-helpline-numbers-for-citizens-stranded-in-nepal-floods-6686776]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Issues Helpline Numbers For Citizens Stranded In Nepal Floods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-issues-helpline-numbers-for-citizens-stranded-in-nepal-floods-6686776]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:25:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Monday issued helpline numbers for its citizens stranded in Nepal due to floods and landslides during the past few days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Monday issued helpline numbers for its citizens stranded in Nepal due to floods and landslides during the past few days.</p>

<p>The advisory follows severe flooding and landslides triggered by record rainfall over the weekend, which caused widespread damage across Nepal.</p>

<p>In a post on social media platform X, the Indian Embassy in Nepal expressed concern at the current situation, stating, "There has been widespread damage due to floods and landslides on account of record rainfall over the weekend. Our thoughts are with everyone affected."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">3/3 Indian citizens in Nepal who require assistance may contact the following emergency numbers (with WhatsApp):<br />
<br />
+977-9851316807 - [Emergency Helpline]<br />
<br />
+977-9851107021- [Attache (Consular)]<br />
<br />
+977-9749833292 - [ASO (Consular)]</p>
— IndiaInNepal (@IndiaInNepal) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiaInNepal/status/1840680229406453998?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Embassy acknowledged that it has received reports of Indian citizens being stranded due to the natural disaster and is coordinating with Nepali authorities to ensure the safe evacuation and return of these individuals.</p>

<p>"The Embassy is in touch with some of these groups and arranging for their safe return," the advisory stated.</p>

<p>To assist stranded citizens, the Embassy issued three helpline numbers for those in need of help.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the death count from the devastating floods and landslides in Nepal neared 200 by Monday afternoon, with 30 people reported missing and 194 others injured, according to Nepal's Home Ministry.</p>

<p>Rescue operations have saved over 4,500 people, with security forces continuing efforts to clear blocked highways and reach affected areas.</p>

<p>Government data also revealed that 1,327 houses were destroyed, and 19 major highways across Nepal suffered damage, further complicating rescue and recovery efforts.</p>

<p>Security forces remain mobilised to clear blocked roads and assist in ongoing rescue missions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f2ibqhho_nepal-floods-ians_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian Embassy in Nepal issued three helpline numbers for those in need of help. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/only-patriotic-choice-new-york-times-endorses-kamala-harris-for-president-6686382]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Only Patriotic Choice": NYT Endorses Kamala Harris For President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/only-patriotic-choice-new-york-times-endorses-kamala-harris-for-president-6686382]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 21:30:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The New York Times editorial board on Monday endorsed Kamala Harris, calling the Democrat "the only patriotic choice for president" in the race against Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New York Times editorial board on Monday endorsed Kamala Harris, calling the Democrat "the only patriotic choice for president" in the race against Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>But the paper did not even mention the vice president's name until the fourth paragraph of its written endorsement -- instead focusing attention on Trump's unworthiness for the presidency, calling him morally and temperamentally "unfit."</p>

<p>"This unequivocal, dispiriting truth -- Donald Trump is not fit to be president -- should be enough for any voter who cares about the health of our country and the stability of our democracy to deny him re-election."</p>

<p>It's an "anyone but Trump" approach that The New Yorker took one day prior, with editors at the magazine saying the Republican represents the "ongoing assault on the stability, the nerves, and the nature of the United States."</p>

<p>In its lengthy endorsement, the Times acknowledged Harris "may not be the perfect candidate for every voter, especially those who are frustrated and angry about our government's failures to fix what's broken."</p>

<p>"Yet we urge Americans to contrast Ms. Harris's record with her opponent's," the paper said. "Ms. Harris is more than a necessary alternative."</p>

<p>The Times editorial board has not thrown its weight behind a Republican for president since 1956 when it backed Dwight Eisenhower.</p>

<p>But the paper emphasized that this election is "about something more foundational" than "competing politics and principles" in a two-party system.</p>

<p>"Unless American voters stand up to him, Mr Trump will have the power to do profound and lasting harm to our democracy," the paper wrote.</p>

<p>The Times said voters are right to ask more from Harris when it comes to policy specifics: "Given the stakes of this election, Ms. Harris may think that she is running a campaign designed to minimize the risks of an unforced error... under the belief that being the only viable alternative to Mr. Trump may be enough to bring her to victory."</p>

<p>"That strategy may ultimately prove winning, but it's a disservice to the American people and to her own record."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, it called the Republican Party "little more than an instrument" of Trump's "quest to regain power" and claimed a second Trump term "would be much more damaging and divisive than the first."</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris is the only choice," the editorial board said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hvdvasi_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Times said voters are right to ask more from Harris when it comes to policy specifics.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-to-pay-22-6-million-to-settle-women-trainees-sex-bias-lawsuit-6686042]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI To Pay $22.6 Million To Settle Women Trainees' Sex Bias Lawsuit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-to-pay-22-6-million-to-settle-women-trainees-sex-bias-lawsuit-6686042]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:43:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of Justice has agreed to pay $22.6 million to settle a lawsuit by 34 women who claim they were wrongly dismissed from the FBI's agent training academy because of their sex.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Department of Justice has agreed to pay $22.6 million to settle a lawsuit by 34 women who claim they were wrongly dismissed from the FBI's agent training academy because of their sex, according to a court filing on Monday.</p>

<p>The settlement, which must be approved by a federal judge in Washington, D.C., would resolve a 2019 class action claiming the FBI, which is part of the Justice Department, had a widespread practice of forcing out female trainees.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/laabhvko_fbi-generic_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It claimed FBI had a widespread practice of forcing out female trainees.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-diljit-dosanjh-met-fan-from-pakistan-borders-drawn-by-politicians-6685655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Borders Drawn By Politicians": When Diljit Dosanjh Met Fan From Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-diljit-dosanjh-met-fan-from-pakistan-borders-drawn-by-politicians-6685655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 19:56:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A heartwarming gesture by popular Punjabi singer Diljit Dosanjh has been winning hearts. He met one of his fans during his "Dil-luminati Tour" in Manchester and gifted her a box of shoes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A heartwarming gesture by popular Punjabi singer Diljit Dosanjh has been winning hearts. He met one of his fans during his "Dil-luminati Tour" in Manchester and gifted her a box of shoes. On learning that she was from Pakistan, he gave a priceless and powerful message of love and peace.</p>

<p>"Hindustan and Pakistan are the same for me. Punjabis have love for all in their hearts. The borders are drawn by politicians. Punjabis don't care, Punjabis love everyone," he said amid a thunderous round of applause.</p>

<p>"I welcome those who have come from my country India and also those who have come from Pakistan," Mr Dosanjh, dressed in an all-black traditional Punjabi attire, addressed the crowd gathered to see him perform.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Diljit Dosanjh Love For Pakistan<br />
<br />
Singer Diljit Dosanjh taking Aman Ki Asha, "BhaiChara" &amp; Ganga-Jamuni Tehzeeb to new heights!<br />
<br />
~ During his recent Manchester Concert, He said: For us, India &amp; Pakistan are same. POLITICIANS Divided us. There's no difference." <a href="https://t.co/jPJeueTOKC">pic.twitter.com/jPJeueTOKC</a></p>
— Shivraj_meena (@shivrajlalsotya) <a href="https://twitter.com/shivrajlalsotya/status/1840726935984337004?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Another video of the singer went viral recently when he introduced his mother and sister at the Manchester show.</p>

<p>He interacted with the audience gathered at the Co-op Live internal arena on Saturday night as he sang his popular track "Hass Hass". Unexpectedly, the singer then held an elderly woman's hand and raised it in the air before declaring through the microphone: "By the way, this is my mom".</p>

<p>Mr Dosanjh's mother became emotional as he bowed in front of her and hugged her through the barricades.</p>

<p>He then pointed towards his sister: "She is my sister. My family is also here today."</p>

<p>Diljit Dosanjh, known for songs such as "GOAT", "Mombattiye", "Proper Patola", and "Do You Know?" will visit India next month to kick off the "Dil-Luminati Tour" on October 26 in New Delhi.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/79v7051o_diljit-dosanjh-with-fan_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh gave a priceless and powerful message of love and peace.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-thirds-of-buildings-in-gaza-damaged-since-war-began-last-year-un-6685216]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Two-Thirds Of Buildings In Gaza Damaged Since War Began Last Year: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-thirds-of-buildings-in-gaza-damaged-since-war-began-last-year-un-6685216]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 19:08:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two-thirds of the buildings in the Gaza Strip have been damaged or destroyed since the Gaza war began in October 2023, the United Nations said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two-thirds of the buildings in the Gaza Strip have been damaged or destroyed since the Gaza war began in October 2023, the United Nations said on Monday.</p>

<p>Updating its damage assessment, the UN Satellite Centre (UNOSAT) said very high-resolution imagery collected on September 3 and 6 showed a clear deterioration.</p>

<p>"This analysis... shows that two-thirds of the total structures in the Gaza Strip have sustained damage," UNOSAT said.</p>

<p>"Those 66 per cent of damaged buildings in the Gaza Strip account for 163,778 structures in total," it said.</p>

<p>The last assessment, based on images from early July, determined that 63 per cent of structures in the Palestinian territory had been damaged.</p>

<p>Monday's update said the damage now included "52,564 structures that have been destroyed; 18,913 severely damaged; 35,591 possibly damaged structures; and 56,710 moderately affected".</p>

<p>Gaza City has been notably affected, with 36,611 structures destroyed, it added.</p>

<p>UNOSAT and the UN's Food and Agriculture Organization said that approximately 68 per cent of the permanent crop fields in the Gaza Strip showed "a significant decline in health and density" in September.</p>

<p>Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,615 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p>

<p>Part of the UN Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR), Geneva-based UNOSAT says its satellite imagery analysis helps the humanitarian community assess the extent of conflict-related damage and helps shape emergency relief efforts.</p>

<p>"Over the past year, UNOSAT's team has worked tirelessly to provide the world with precise and timely insights into the impact of the conflict on buildings and infrastructure in Gaza," said UNITAR's executive director Nikhil Seth.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/45959ij8_gaza-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gaza City has been notably affected, with 36,611 structures destroyed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-first-deflation-since-1995-6685087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cash-Strapped Sri Lanka Records First Deflation Since 1995]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-first-deflation-since-1995-6685087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 18:49:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cash-strapped Sri Lanka's economy recorded falling consumer prices for the first time in 29 years, official data showed Monday, with the September inflation figure dipping to negative 0.5 per cent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cash-strapped Sri Lanka's economy recorded falling consumer prices for the first time in 29 years, official data showed Monday, with the September inflation figure dipping to negative 0.5 per cent.</p>

<p>Census and Statistics Department data showed price drops in both food and non-food goods contributing to deflation in September, compared to inflation of 0.5 per cent in August.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka last recorded deflation in March 1995 with a figure of negative 0.9 per cent. The previous price fall to that was in 1985 when inflation was negative 2.1 per cent.</p>

<p>Inflation peaked at 69.8 per cent two years ago at the height of an unprecedented economic crisis in the island nation.</p>

<p>Acute shortages of food, fuel and medicines led to months of protests that eventually forced then-president Gotabaya Rajapaksa to temporarily flee the country and resign in July 2022.</p>

<p>His successor Ranil Wickremesinghe secured a $2.9 billion International Monetary Fund bailout and raised taxes and prices to stabilise the economy.</p>

<p>Wickremesinghe lost office after a presidential election this month.</p>

<p>The winner of that contest, President Anura Kumara Dissanayake, has vowed to maintain the IMF programme but relax some of the austerity measures it imposed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/pqpaltag_sri-lanka-generic_625x300_13_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Inflation peaked at 69.8 per cent two years ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pm-calls-for-ceasefire-with-israel-as-strikes-intensify-6684481]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon PM Calls For Ceasefire With Israel As Strikes Intensify]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pm-calls-for-ceasefire-with-israel-as-strikes-intensify-6684481]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:40:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's Prime Minister Najib Mikati on Monday called for a ceasefire in the fighting between Israel and Hezbollah during a meeting with French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot in Beirut.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Prime Minister Najib Mikati on Monday called for a ceasefire in the fighting between Israel and Hezbollah during a meeting with French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot in Beirut.</p>

<p>"The key to the solution is to put an end to the Israeli aggression against Lebanon and to revive the appeal launched by the United States and France... in favour of a ceasefire," Mikati said, according to a statement from his office.</p>

<p>Barrot arrived in Beirut Sunday, the first foreign diplomat to visit Lebanon since Israel escalated its strikes against Hezbollah strongholds.</p>

<p>Mikati added that the "priority is applying resolution 1701" of the United Nations Security Council, which ended the 2006 war between Israel and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The French envoy's visit came as a deadly strike hit a building in the centre of the Lebanese capital.</p>

<p>Israeli strikes have been largely concentrated on Hezbollah's strongholds in the south and east of the country, and in south Beirut.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ch043to8_israel-strike-lebanon-reuters_625x300_29_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli strikes have been largely concentrated on Hezbollah's strongholds.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-vladimir-putin-vows-to-achieve-all-goals-in-ukraine-as-russia-claims-new-ground-6684429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Vows To Achieve All "Goals" In Ukraine As Russia Claims New Ground]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-vladimir-putin-vows-to-achieve-all-goals-in-ukraine-as-russia-claims-new-ground-6684429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:36:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin vowed Monday to achieve all his "goals" in Ukraine and celebrated the second anniversary of annexing four Ukrainian regions, as his army claimed fresh advances in the conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin vowed Monday to achieve all his "goals" in Ukraine and celebrated the second anniversary of annexing four Ukrainian regions, as his army claimed fresh advances in the conflict.</p>

<p>Moscow has captured dozens of Ukrainian towns and villages this year, pressing forward even as Kyiv mounts a cross-border offensive into Russian territory.</p>

<p>"The truth is on our side. All goals set will be achieved," Putin said in a video address marking what he calls "Reunification Day" -- when Moscow annexed four southern and eastern Ukrainian regions in 2022.</p>

<p>He also repeated his justification for sending troops into Ukraine, saying he was protecting Russian speakers against a "neo-Nazi dictatorship" that aimed to "cut them off forever from Russia, their historic homeland".</p>

<p>"Together we are defending a safe, prosperous future for our children and grandchildren," Putin said.</p>

<p>Russia claimed to annex the Ukrainian regions of Lugansk, Donetsk, Zaporizhzhia and Kherson in September 2022, but it does not fully control any of them.</p>

<p>The Kremlin has pursued a relentless assault in eastern Ukraine in recent months, pressing its advantage as Ukrainian soldiers grapple with exhaustion and relentless bombardment.</p>

<p>The Russian army said Monday its troops had "liberated" the Ukrainian village of Nelipivka, which had a population of around 1,000 before the conflict.</p>

<p>It lies just north of the Ukrainian town of New York, where Kyiv claimed to have made rare gains earlier in September.</p>

<p>The main target of Moscow's assault in recent months has been the Ukrainian logistics hub of Pokrovsk, a city on road and rail routes that supply Kyiv's forces across the frontline.</p>

<p><strong>- 'One-on-one talks' -</strong></p>

<p>Putin's comments came shortly after Russia launched a fresh wave of missile and drone attacks at Ukraine overnight, some of which were aimed at the capital Kyiv.</p>

<p>"The enemy carried out another massive attack with drones on the Kyiv region overnight. Air defence forces worked effectively in the region," the head of the Kyiv regional military administration, Ruslan Kravchenko, said.</p>

<p>Wreckage from some of the downed barrage caused fires but there were no casualties or hits on critical infrastructure, he added.</p>

<p>Ukraine's Foreign Minister Andriy Sybiga was in Budapest on Monday to meet Hungarian counterpart Peter Szijjarto.</p>

<p>Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban is the only EU leader to have maintained close ties with the Kremlin since the conflict began in 2022 and has refused military support for Kyiv.</p>

<p>"The one-on-one talks between Andriy Sybiga and Peter Szijjarto lasted about an hour, twice as long as planned," the Ukrainian foreign ministry said, without elaborating.</p>

<p>Hungary has previously blocked substantial funds for Ukraine, a source of frustration for Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky and his EU allies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/14dvuelo_vladimir-putin-afp-putin-in-office-afp_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Kremlin has pursued a relentless assault in eastern Ukraine in recent months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-in-a-million-china-woman-with-two-uteruses-delivers-a-baby-from-each-6684330]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["One In A Million": China Woman With 2 Uteruses Delivers A Baby From Each]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-in-a-million-china-woman-with-two-uteruses-delivers-a-baby-from-each-6684330]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:26:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The condition known as uterus didelphys affects only 0.3% of women worldwide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in northwest China has made international headlines after giving birth to twins from two separate uteruses, a rare medical phenomenon. The condition known as uterus didelphys affects only 0.3% of women worldwide. What's remarkable is that both uteruses were fully formed, complete with ovaries and oviducts. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3280157/1-million-china-woman-2-uteruses-gives-birth-1-child-each-womb">South China Morning Post</a></em>, the woman&nbsp;surnamed Li,&nbsp;delivered a boy and girl in early September at Xi'an No 4 Hospital in Shaanxi province when she was eight and a half months pregnant.&nbsp;The babies were born healthy, with the boy weighing 3.3kg and the girl 2.4kg.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cai Ying, a senior obstetrician at the hospital, described Li's pregnancy as a "one in a million" event. "Being pregnant in each of the two uteruses through natural conception is very rare. We have only heard of a couple of such cases from both China and abroad," Cai told <em>SCMP.</em></p>

<p>Li, whose age remains undisclosed, experienced a miscarriage at 27 weeks in a previous pregnancy due to unknown factors. When she became pregnant again in January, doctors at Xi'an No 4 Hospital developed a specialised plan to ensure her safety.</p>

<p>To minimize risks, Li underwent a caesarean section. Fortunately, she and her newborn twins – a boy and a girl – were discharged from the hospital just four days after birth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to China state broadcaster CCTV, a similar case occurred in December last year in the US state of Alabama. A woman gave birth to twin girls, each developing in a separate uterus. Notably, this mother had previously given birth to three children, but those pregnancies involved only one of her two uteruses.</p>

<p><strong>The Double Uterus Condition:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Uterus didelphys occurs when two small tubes in the female fetus fail to join during development, resulting in two distinct uteruses&nbsp;</li>
	<li>In some cases, each uterus has its cervix, and a thin tissue wall may divide the vagina into two separate chambers.</li>
	<li>Women who have two uteruses face no symptoms till they become pregnant</li>
	<li>During pregnancy, they face&nbsp;a high risk of miscarriage, fetal underdevelopment, premature birth, and post-partum haemorrhages.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r2jmtnl_twins_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The condition known as uterus didelphys affects only 0.3% of women worldwide.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/solar-eclipse-on-october-2-how-fast-it-will-travel-6683968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Solar Eclipse On October 2: How Fast It Will Travel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/solar-eclipse-on-october-2-how-fast-it-will-travel-6683968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:47:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The much-anticipated annular solar eclipse is set to grace the skies on October 2. The eclipse will begin at 9:13 pm IST on October 2 and conclude at 3:17 pm IST the next day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The much-anticipated annular solar eclipse is set to grace the skies on October 2. The eclipse will begin at 9:13 pm IST on October 2 and conclude at 3:17 pm IST the next day. During this time, the Moon will appear smaller than the Sun, creating a brilliant <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/ring-of-fire-solar-eclipse-2024-check-timing-visibility-in-india-and-other-details-6671693 ">“ring of fire”</a> effect – a halo of sunlight visible around the darkened centre.</p>

<p><strong>How fast the eclipse will travel</strong></p>

<p>During the upcoming annular solar eclipse, the speed of the Moon's shadow across Earth will vary significantly depending on location. In some areas, it will travel faster than 10 million kmph, while in others, it will slow to about 2,057 kmph, roughly the speed of a fighter jet, reported <a href="https://www.space.com/how-fast-will-the-annular-solar-eclipse-october-2-travel ">Space.com</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Path of the eclipse</strong></p>

<p>The Moon's shadow will move from northwest to southeast, and due to Earth's curvature and the Moon's changing distance and orbital speed, the shadow's velocity will fluctuate dramatically across different regions. The eclipse will start with an eclipsed sunrise, peak at midday and end with an eclipsed sunset.</p>

<p><strong>Where the eclipse will touch and leave Earth</strong></p>

<p>The Moon's shadow will first strike south of Hawaii in the Pacific Ocean, moving at 8.55 million kmph. When it leaves Earth near the island of South Georgia, it will travel at 10 million km/h. However, these extreme speeds occur as the shadow touches and leaves Earth, rendering them less meaningful.</p>

<p><strong>Where can you view the eclipse?</strong></p>

<p>The shadow's speed will be slower when the eclipse is visible at the horizon, around 8,258 kmph at sunrise and 14,312 kmph at sunset. The slowest speed of 2,057 kmph will be observed in the Pacific Ocean northwest of Easter Island, where the ‘ring of fire' will last for 7 minutes and 25 seconds. This slower speed is due to the Moon's shadow being nearly perpendicular to Earth at local midday – the longest duration of the eclipse.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/hii8n5ng_ring-of-fire-annual-solar-eclipse_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Moon's shadow will first strike south of Hawaii in the Pacific Ocean (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rescue-operations-continue-as-over-200-people-killed-in-floods-landslides-in-nepal-6683768]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[200 Killed In Floods, Landslides In Nepal, Rescue Operations Continue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rescue-operations-continue-as-over-200-people-killed-in-floods-landslides-in-nepal-6683768]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:21:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Search and rescue operations continued in Nepal for the third consecutive day on Monday after monsoon-induced floods and landslides killed more than 200 people in one of the worst rain-related disasters in the Himalayan nation in recent years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Search and rescue operations continued in Nepal for the third consecutive day on Monday after monsoon-induced floods and landslides killed more than 200 people in one of the worst rain-related disasters in the Himalayan nation in recent years.</p>

<p>Incessant rainfall over the weekend triggered floods and landslides, wreaking havoc in Kathmandu and most of the districts of Nepal.</p>

<p>At least 204 people have been killed in the continuous rainfall, floods, landslides and inundation, MyRepublica news portal reported, quoting the Armed Police Force (APF).</p>

<p>It added that 89 others have also been injured nationwide in the disaster, while 33 others remain missing.</p>

<p>An all-party meeting convened on Sunday by Officiating Prime Minister Prakash Man Singh at the Prime Minister's Office in Singha Durbar decided to enhance rescue, relief, and re-establishment efforts during the ongoing disaster caused by heavy rains.</p>

<p>The Home Ministry said it would provide grants for temporary housing construction, repair blocked roads to restore transportation and ensure effective free health treatment for citizens injured in disaster incidents.</p>

<p>A task force was also formed to assess the details of the damage caused within a 15-day deadline, the news portal reported.</p>

<p>The Disaster Management Executive Committee&nbsp;said it will provide a relief amount to the families of those missing. If the missing person is not found within 10 days, their family will be provided the same amount as that given to the kin of a person killed in the rain-induced disaster, the report said.</p>

<p>The Home Ministry said all security agencies have been deployed for relief efforts following the floods and landslides, and the Nepal Army, Nepal Police and Armed Police Force personnel have rescued around 4,500 disaster-affected individuals so far.</p>

<p>While those injured are receiving free treatment, food and other emergency relief materials have been provided to others affected by the floods.</p>

<p>Hundreds of people are facing a shortage of food, safe drinking water and sanitation in Kathmandu following the natural disaster, according to eyewitnesses.</p>

<p>Market prices have also soared as vegetables coming from India and other districts of the country have been temporarily halted due to obstruction in major highways due to landslides.</p>

<p>Numerous roads throughout the nation are severely damaged, and all routes leading to the capital city, Kathmandu, are still blocked, leaving thousands of travellers stranded, The Kathmandu Post newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Home Ministry Spokesperson Rishiram Tiwari said efforts are underway to clear the obstructed highways to resume transportation.</p>

<p>At least 20 hydropower plants with a combined capacity of 1100 MW suffered damages due to floods and landslides triggered by the incessant rainfall in the past three days, which has led to the disruption in power supply in Kathmandu and other major cities.</p>

<p>"Heavy rains since Friday have caused widespread flooding across Kathmandu Valley, and across Nepal. This is the worst flooding experienced in recent years," said Jagan Chapagain, the Chief Executive Officer and Secretary General of the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies, in a post on X.</p>

<p>"In response to the crisis, local branches of the @NepalRedCross are working closely with authorities and (the) Emergency Operations Centre of Nepal Red Cross to coordinate rescue and relief operations," he added. Kathmandu's main river, the Bagmati, was flowing above danger levels after incessant rain lashed large swathes of eastern and central Nepal on Friday and Saturday, a report published by the International Centre for Integrated Mountain Development (ICIMOD) said.</p>

<p>"A low-pressure system in the Bay of Bengal and the more northerly than usual position of the monsoon trough was the reason" behind the exceptionally intense rain, it said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Scientists say that while climate change is changing the amount and timing of rainfall across Asia, a key reason for the rise in the impact of floods is the built environment, including unplanned construction, especially on floodplains, which leaves insufficient areas for water retention and drainage.</p>

<p>The floods and landslides have thrown life out of gear in many parts of the country, with many highways and road stretches disrupted, hundreds of houses and bridges buried or swept away, and hundreds of families displaced.</p>

<p>Thousands of passengers have been stranded in various places due to road disruption.</p>

<p>During the all-party meeting, it was also decided that the Ministry of Health and Population will conduct awareness programmes and other initiatives in potential and suitable locations to prevent the spread of diseases, as epidemics can spread after such disasters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f2ibqhho_nepal-floods-ians_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Heavy rains since Friday have caused widespread flooding across Kathmandu Valley.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-tesla-catches-fire-inside-florida-garage-flooded-from-hurricane-helene-6683715]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tesla Catches Fire Inside Florida Garage Flooded From Hurricane Helene]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-tesla-catches-fire-inside-florida-garage-flooded-from-hurricane-helene-6683715]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:17:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Officials advised people not to charge, drive, or store their EVs or E-bikes in their homes or garages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dramatic video footage released by Pinellas County officials shows a Tesla bursting into flames inside a Florida garage flooded by Hurricane Helene. The shocking incident serves as a warning to electric vehicle owners in areas affected by the storm. Surveillance footage reveals the fire starting underneath the car and spreading rapidly, fully engulfing it in under a minute. Thick smoke quickly fills the cluttered garage.</p>

<p>The warning comes after Hurricane Helene brought widespread flooding to parts of Florida, North Carolina, and other southeastern states. Pinellas County Government posted the surveillance video to Facebook on Saturday to warn electric vehicle owners of the risk.</p>

<p>''Electric Vehicles that have been flooded in saltwater can catch fire.&nbsp;If you evacuated and left an electric vehicle or golf cart in your garage or under a building and you are not able to get to it or move it, we want you to let us know,'' the county said in a Facebook post.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="329" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=329&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FPinellasGov%2Fvideos%2F1886706438505288%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p></p>

<p>Officials also urged electric car owners to take precautions to prevent similar incidents. Pinellas county advised people not to charge, drive, or store their EVs or E-bikes in their homes or garages. They added that the electric vehicle should be moved 50 feet away from combustible material and towed to a dealership for inspection.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hurricane Helene made landfall in Florida's Big Bend region late Thursday as a Category 4 storm, bringing 140 mph winds and widespread devastation. As it swept through Georgia, the Carolinas, and Tennessee, Helene uprooted trees. splintered homes, caused creeks and rivers to overflow, spawned tornadoes and strained dams.&nbsp;The powerful hurricane left at least 93 people dead and left millions without power, as per<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/29/us-news/shocking-video-shows-entire-bridge-washed-away-by-hurricane-helen-floodwater/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em> </em></a><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/29/us-news/tesla-erupts-into-flames-inside-flooded-fla-garage-following-hurricane-helene-video/"><em>New York Post.&nbsp;</em></a></p>

<p>President Joe Biden is planning to visit areas affected by Hurricane Helene this week, but only if it doesn't hinder ongoing rescue and recovery efforts. He assured that his administration is providing all available resources to support the affected states in their response. The American Red Cross has launched a massive relief effort, deploying over 1,400 disaster workers and opening hundreds of shelters for those affected.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g48e3m9o_-tesla-car-on-fire_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The garage where the incident took place was flooded with saltwater by the storm.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-paid-2-7-billion-to-rehire-ai-genius-noam-shazeer-to-co-lead-gemini-report-6683643]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Paid $2.7 Billion To Rehire AI Genius To Co-Lead Gemini: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-paid-2-7-billion-to-rehire-ai-genius-noam-shazeer-to-co-lead-gemini-report-6683643]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:08:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google re-hired its long-time researcher, Naom Shazeer, to co-lead its AI models in a $2.7 billion deal, the Wall Street Journal reported. Mr Shazeer quit Google in 2021 after being a part of the company for 21 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google re-hired its long-time researcher, Noam Shazeer, to co-lead its AI models in a $2.7 billion deal, the Wall Street Journal reported. Mr Shazeer quit Google in 2021 after being a part of the company for 21 years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He reportedly quit when the company refused to launch a chatbot head had built along with a colleague. He went on to head the Character. AI.</p>

<p>He was a co-author of a seminal 2017 research paper which catalyzed the current AI boom. Character.AI utilizes the technical advancements pioneered in the paper. It has raised $193 million and was valued at $1 billion last year by venture capitalists.</p>

<p>Character.AI reached a valuation of $1 Billion last year. Google paid $2.7 Billion to Character.AI for a transfer of technology and bringing back Mr Shazeer to Google, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/ai/noam-shazeer-google-ai-deal-d3605697" rel="no follow, no index">the report said</a>.</p>

<p>AI-boom has prompted startups to release new features to their chatbots as competitors such as Microsoft-backed OpenAI, Google and Amazon-backed Anthropic are looking to gain market share by engaging new users.</p>

<p>Last year, Google was in talks to invest hundreds of millions of dollars in Character.AI, but chose to bring him back.</p>

<p>The deal, which resembles similar moves by Amazon and Microsoft to nab top talent from AI startups, comes at a time when the Big Tech companies are facing regulatory scrutiny.</p>

<p>Shazeer is serving as a technical lead on Gemini - Google's AI chatbot - joining the other co-leaders Jeff Dean and Oriol Vinyals. Gemini is the line of AI models being developed by DeepMind, Google's AI division, and which are being integrated into products such as Search and Pixel smartphones.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/75hvov8o_noam-shazeer-google_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He quit Google when it refused to launch a chatbot head had built along with a colleague]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-houthis-on-camera-oil-tank-explodes-in-yemen-after-israeli-air-strikes-6683607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Camera, Oil Tank Explodes In Yemen After Israeli Air Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-houthis-on-camera-oil-tank-explodes-in-yemen-after-israeli-air-strikes-6683607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:04:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forceslaunched airstrikes on Yemen's Ras Isa Port on Sunday, targeting oil facilities and power stations controlled by the Houthi rebels.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-houthi-controlled-port-power-plants-in-yemen-6678794 ">launched airstrikes on Yemen</a>'s Ras Isa Port on Sunday, targeting oil facilities and power stations controlled by the Houthi rebels. The strikes were part of Israel's response to recent Houthi missile attacks, including one aimed at Ben Gurion Airport in Tel Aviv. Now, newly surfaced footage shows the aftermath of one of the airstrikes on the nearby port of Hudeidah.<br />
<br />
The video, which has been widely circulated on social media, shows oil tanks at the port engulfed in flames, with thick black smoke billowing into the sky. “When an oil tank exploded inside the port of Hudaidah in Yemen; As a result of bombing by @Israel,” the caption of the video read.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">When an oil tank exploded inside the port of Hudaidah in Yemen; As a result of bombing by <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Israel</a>. <a href="https://t.co/7lGTDCnkd8">pic.twitter.com/7lGTDCnkd8</a></p>
— Jordan ???????????????????????????????????????? (@Mhmmd_Jordan) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mhmmd_Jordan/status/1840472084108960143?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Houthi-controlled Al-Masirah TV reported that four workers -- a port employee and three engineers -- were killed and over 30 sustained injuries. Rescue operations are underway.</p>

<p>Eyewitnesses saw plumes of smoke and fire from oil tanks struck by Israeli missiles that also hit power stations in the area.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Israeli military, dozens of aircraft, including fighter jets, refuelling planes and reconnaissance aircraft, participated in the operation. “Today's operation was a significant escalation in our response to the Houthi threat,” Israel's military spokesperson, Captain David Avraham, told AFP. “We will not tolerate attacks on Israeli territory, and we will take all necessary measures to protect our citizens.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The IAF struck military targets belonging to the Houthi terrorist regime in Yemen in response to their recent attacks against Israel.<br />
<br />
The targets included power plants and a seaport, which were used by the Houthis to transfer Iranian weapons to the region, in addition to…</p>
— Israeli Air Force (@IAFsite) <a href="https://twitter.com/IAFsite/status/1840412854630973725?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), the airstrikes targeted power plants and a seaport used by the Houthi regime to import oil and transfer Iranian weapons and military supplies. These facilities were reportedly used by the Houthis to support their ongoing military campaign, which has been funded and directed by Iran, with cooperation from Iraqi militias.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="iw">מבצע אווירי רחב היקף בתימן:<br />
עשרות כלי טיס של חיל-האוויר בהם מטוסי קרב, מטוסי תדלוק ומודיעין, תקפו כ-1,800 ק״מ מגבול ישראל, מטרות אשר בשימוש צבאי של שלטון הטרור החות׳י, במרחבים ראס עיסא וחודידה שבתימן.<br />
<br />
במבצע הותקפו תחנות כוח ונמל ימי, אשר משמשים לייבוא נפט, באמצעותם השלטון החות׳י… <a href="https://t.co/5I6Ud4TnVP">pic.twitter.com/5I6Ud4TnVP</a></p>
— Israeli Air Force (@IAFsite) <a href="https://twitter.com/IAFsite/status/1840404744789188823?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This latest strike comes as part of Israel's broader regional military offence, which has intensified in recent weeks. Last week, Israeli airstrikes in Lebanon killed over 1,000 people and displaced hundreds of thousands. Israel's ongoing assault on Gaza, which began on October 7 last year, has already killed over 42,000 Palestinians and displaced nearly the entire population of the narrow strip.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7hcpg3sg_oil-tank-explosion_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israel strikes targeted ports and oil stations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-makes-a-person-seem-wise-various-cultures-differ-according-to-study-6683476]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Makes A Person Seem Wise? Various Cultures Differ, According To Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-makes-a-person-seem-wise-various-cultures-differ-according-to-study-6683476]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:48:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[We all admire wise people, dont we? Whether its a thoughtful teacher, a compassionate doctor, or an elder in the community, we recognise wisdom when we see it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title"><span style="font-size: 13px;">We all admire wise people, don't we? Whether it's a thoughtful teacher, a compassionate doctor, or an elder in the community, we recognise wisdom when we see it. But have you ever thought about how people in different cultures perceive wisdom? Does someone in Morocco view a wise person in the same way as someone in Ecuador? Our recent </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-50294-0" style="font-size: 13px;">study</a><span style="font-size: 13px;"> explored how people across cultures think of wisdom.</span></p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>This large-scale project required a joint effort of 34 researchers across fields of philosophy, psychology, anthropology, social science and psychometrics – and from all over the world, connected in a research consortium called <a href="https://www.geographyofphilosophy.com/">The Geography of Philosophy</a>.</p>

<p>What we found was somewhat surprising. Wisdom may appear to be shaped by cultural differences, but the core aspects of what makes someone wise are largely the same across cultures. From urban college students in Japan to villagers in South Africa, participants associated wisdom with two key characteristics: reflective orientation and socio-emotional awareness. We explain what that means below.</p>

<p>Contrary to widespread stereotypes, people recognise the wisdom in a similar way across East and West, South and North. Despite the divisions of the world, we see wisdom in the same individuals and associate it with similar traits. Are we indeed more alike than we are different when it comes to how we perceive wisdom? And what characterises wise people?</p>

<h3><strong>These are the characteristics of wise people</strong></h3>

<p>There are two key characteristics. Reflective orientation is about people who think before acting, carefully consider different perspectives, and use logic and past experiences to guide their decisions. They're the type of person who keeps their cool in difficult situations, taking time to weigh all the options before making a move.</p>

<p>The second is socio-emotional awareness. Wise people are good at understanding and caring about the thoughts and feelings of others. They pay attention to emotions and consider different views on the situation. Such an individual might be skilled at mediating conflicts by understanding each party's point of view, or be adept at providing emotional support during difficult times.</p>

<p>Together, these two dimensions combine to form the global image of wisdom. The study suggests that the wisest people are those who balance both, showing strong abilities in reasoning while also being emotionally and socially aware.</p>

<p>A highly reflective person who is suppressing their own emotions but doesn't notice the social context of the problem wouldn't be called wise. Likewise, someone who is entirely driven by emotion and the social environment but fails to make logical connections wouldn't be called wise either. Real wisdom, according to our study, is about finding a balance between thoughtful reasoning, social understanding, and emotional awareness.</p>

<h3><strong>Cultures do differ, but not as much as you might think</strong></h3>

<p>To uncover these dimensions, we employed a method sometimes called <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/12/09/magazine/09wwln-idealab-t.html">experimental philosophy</a>. Participants across 16 different cultures in 12 countries on five continents compared a set of targets to each other. For example, one of the questions asked participants to compare whether a doctor or a religious person was more likely to think logically when making a hard life decision with no right or wrong answers. Our participants also rated themselves. Then we asked how wise each of these persons were.</p>

<p>When we started this project, we expected to find big differences between cultures. <a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/The-Geography-of-Thought/Richard-Nisbett/9780743255356">Previous research</a> suggested that people in “the West” use and value analytical thinking, which tends to dismiss social and emotional parts of the situation. In contrast, individuals in “the East” emphasise holistic thinking, that is, all-encompassing views of complex situations.</p>

<p>But that's not what we found. While there were some small differences – people in South Africa, for example, placed more importance on nature and divinity when thinking about socio-emotional awareness – the overall picture was strikingly similar. Across the globe, people rated individuals who were both reflective and socially and emotionally aware as the wisest. For instance, they named a doctor and a 75-year-old person as the wisest, and at the same time the highest on both dimensions.</p>

<p>What was particularly fascinating was that people tended to rate themselves differently from how they rated others. Most people saw themselves as less reflective but more socially and emotionally aware than the “wise” figures they were asked to rate. In other words, people were ready to admit a moderate level of their own intellectual capabilities, but they were quite confident in their ability to understand and care for others.</p>

<h3><strong>Why this matters</strong></h3>

<p>This research defies stereotypes of a cold analytical ideal of “the west” and a social-minded and emotionally driven image of “the east” and “the south”. The idea that wisdom is purely intellectual, or conversely, purely social or divine, is too simplistic. It also highlights that wisdom manifests in a balance of traits traditionally attributed to different cultures.</p>

<p>In a time when global cooperation is more important than ever, recognising our shared appreciation for certain qualities can help bridge cultural divides.</p>

<p>The study opens up new avenues for research. Could these dimensions of wisdom help us understand how to solve global problems? Are people more likely to trust leaders who show both reflective thinking and socio-emotional awareness? And how do these qualities affect the way we handle personal relationships, difficult decisions, or conflicts?</p>

<p>One thing is clear: wisdom is something we all value, no matter where we come from. By understanding it better, we can not only become wiser ourselves but also learn to appreciate wisdom in others, wherever they may be.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238808/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/maksim-rudnev-2208633">Maksim Rudnev</a>, Research Associate, Department of Psychology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-waterloo-1284">University of Waterloo</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/veli-mitova-2208636">Veli Mitova</a>, Professor in Philosophy and Director of the African Centre for Epistemology and Philosophy of Science, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-johannesburg-1275">University of Johannesburg</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/what-makes-a-person-seem-wise-global-study-finds-that-cultures-do-differ-but-not-as-much-as-youd-think-238808">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hvh3lkhg_brain_625x300_29_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reflective orientation is about people who think before acting (Representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>