<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 21:05:49 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/elon-musks-starlink-satellites-blocking-view-of-the-universe-report-6595679]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Starlink Satellites 'Blocking' View Of The Universe: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/elon-musks-starlink-satellites-blocking-view-of-the-universe-report-6595679]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 20:50:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dutch scientists from ASTRON are raising concerns about the second-generation Starlink satellites, claiming they cause significant interference with radio telescopes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's new generation of Starlink satellites is raising concerns among Dutch scientists who claim the new satellites will bring fast internet worldwide and are proving to be interference for astronomers on a massive scale.</p>

<p>Thousands of orbiting Starlink satellites "are blinding" radio telescopes, perhaps causing damage to astronomical research, according to researchers at the Netherlands Institute for Radio Astronomy (<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.astron.nl/starlink-satellites/">ASTRON</a>). As these telescopes work on radio waves to examine the universe, it makes the collection of clean data much more complicated because of the interference caused by these satellites.</p>

<p>Starlink satellites connect remote areas with broadband internet, be it challenging conditions like in Ukraine and Yemen or the rural districts of the UK, for that matter. The Department for Digital, Culture, Media, and Sport reported how tests conducted in 2022 showed that Starlink could deliver internet speeds four times faster than the average.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OIqLn152th8?si=4kYTvvqh5rdDXDz6" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Scientists argue, however, that such privilege comes at an appreciable cost in terms of research.</p>

<p>"With LOFAR (Low Frequency Array), we have started a program to monitor unintended emission from satellites belonging to different constellations, and our observations show that the second-generation Starlink satellites emit stronger emission and do so over a larger range of radio frequencies, compared to the first-generation satellites," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.astron.nl/starlink-satellites/">says Cees Bassa</a> from ASTRON (the Netherlands Institute for Radio Astronomy), the lead author of the study.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.astron.nl/starlink-satellites/"><em>release by ASTRON,</em></a> the analysis revealed that these newer satellites emit up to 32 times brighter unintended radio waves compared to the first generation, with levels potentially exceeding internationally regulated thresholds for interference set for intentional emissions and even more relaxed terrestrial electromagnetic compatibility standards.</p>

<p>"Compared to the faintest astrophysical sources that we observe with LOFAR, UEMR from Starlink satellites is 10 million times brighter. This difference is similar to the faintest stars visible to the naked eye and the brightness of the full moon. Since SpaceX is launching about 40 second-generation Starlink satellites every week, this problem is becoming increasingly worse," adds Cees Bassa."</p>

<p>"Humanity is clearly approaching an inflexion point where we need to take action to preserve our sky as a window to explore the universe from Earth. Satellite companies are not interested in producing this unintended radiation, so minimising it should also be a priority in their sustainable space policies," says Federico Di Vruno from the SKA Observatory. "Starlink is not the only big player in LEO, but they have a chance to set the standard here," he continues.</p>

<p>The researchers emphasise that while the second-generation satellites have been designed to enhance connectivity and provide communication services, the unintended radio emissions are a growing threat to the integrity of astronomical observations. As the consequences of such interference become increasingly evident, collaboration between satellite companies, regulatory agencies, and the astronomical community is essential to devise effective mitigation strategies.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8c9nv46g_elon-musks-starlink-satellites_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Radio waves from these satellites are blocking scientists' ability to peer into universe.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-shows-explosion-at-funeral-of-hezbollah-member-killed-in-pager-blast-6595590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Shows Explosion At Funeral Of Hezbollah Member Killed In Pager Blast]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-shows-explosion-at-funeral-of-hezbollah-member-killed-in-pager-blast-6595590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 20:41:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A source close to Lebanon's Hezbollah said walkie talkies used by its members exploded in the group's Beirut stronghold, with a live stream on social media showing the chaos that unfolded during the explosion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A source close to Lebanon's Hezbollah said walkie talkies used by its members exploded in the group's Beirut stronghold, with a live stream on social media showing the chaos that unfolded during the explosion.</p>

<p>One of the explosions occurred during a funeral procession of a Hezbollah member who was killed yesterday in the pager blast. People can be seen scrambling for safety after a device detonated.</p>

<p>Three people have died in the walkie-talkie blast, according to Lebanon's state media.</p>

<p>How many devices blew up is not known yet. There have been reports of landline telephones exploding too at various locations in East Lebanon.</p>

<p>This comes a day after pagers exploded across the country, killing nine people and injuring more than 2,800 others, Lebanese Health Minister Firass Abiad confirmed.</p>

<p>Iran's state media also reported that its Ambassador to Lebanon, Mojtaba Amani, was also wounded in yesterday's pager incident.</p>

<p>The handheld wireless walkie talkies were bought at the same time as the pagers, as per reports.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah has blamed Israel for the attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The group said today that it attacked Israeli artillery positions with rockets in the first strike at its arch-rival since pager blasts wounded thousands of its members.</p>

<p>Israel's spy agency Mossad planted explosives inside pagers imported by Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told news agency Reuters.</p>

<p>Mossad has a long history of sophisticated operations on foreign soil.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sgcvh0lg_hezbollah-walkie-talkie-blast_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One of the explosions occurred during the funeral of a Hezbollah member]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/walkie-talkies-explode-in-hezbollahs-beirut-stronghold-day-after-pager-blasts-6595278]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Dead, 100 Injured As Walkie-Talkies Explode In Hezbollah Units In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/walkie-talkies-explode-in-hezbollahs-beirut-stronghold-day-after-pager-blasts-6595278]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:58:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three people have died as walkie-talkies have blown up across Hezbollah strongholds across Lebanon. This comes a day after pagers exploded across the middle-eastern country, killing twelve people and injuring more than 2,800 others.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three people have died as walkie-talkies have blown up across Hezbollah strongholds across Lebanon. This comes a day after pagers exploded across the middle-eastern country, killing twelve people and injuring more than 2,800 others.</p>

<p>How many walkie-talkies blew up are not know yet. There are reports that landline telephones are blowing up too at various locations in East Lebanon.</p>

<p>According to reports, the hand-held wireless radio devices and walkie-talkies were bought around five months ago, approximately the same time as the pagers.</p>

<p>Today's blasts happened across southern Lebanon as well as Beirut's suburbs. At least one of the blasts happened near a funeral organised by Hezbollah for people who were killed in yesterday's pager blasts.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah said today that it attacked Israeli artillery positions with rockets in the first strike at its arch-rival since pager blasts wounded thousands of its members in Lebanon and raised the prospect of a wider Middle East war.</p>

<p>Israel's spy agency Mossad, which has a long history of sophisticated operations on foreign soil, planted explosives inside pagers imported by Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told news agency Reuters.</p>

<p>This morning Lebanese Health Minister Firass Abiad confirmed that twelve people were killed and around 2,800 wounded in the incident.</p>

<p>The minister, in a televised press conference, said the blasts "killed twelve people, including a girl", adding that "About 2,800 people were injured and more than 200 of them critically". The injuries were mostly on the face, hands and stomach, he had said.</p>

<p>Iran's state media had reported that its Ambassador to Lebanon, Mojtaba Amani, was also wounded in yesterday's pager incident.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which is banned both by the United States and the European Union is the political and military establishment in Lebanon and is backed by Iran. Hezbollah backs Hamas, which has been at war with Israel in Gaza since October 2023.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had on Tuesday blamed Israel for the attack and has claimed that this is the "biggest security breach" it has faced yet.</p>

<p>Just like the pagers, all the walkie-talkie devices also exploded at the same time, Hezbollah has claimed.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had called the blasts an "Israeli breach" of its communications network, and has vowed to avenge the attack.</p>

<h2><strong>WHO MADE THESE DEVICES?</strong></h2>

<p>Initial reports suggested that the pagers were made by a Taiwanese company, but the firm has denied this. The Taiwanese pager manufacturer - Gold Apollo - said that the devices were made under a licence by a company called BAC, which is situated in Budapest, the capital city of Hungary.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gobv8mb8_walkie-talkie-split_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Walkie-talkies have blown up at Hezbollah strongholds across Beirut, Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-ordered-to-pay-rs-12-lakh-after-his-dog-triggers-pregnant-womans-miscarriage-6595265]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Man Told To Pay Rs 12 Lakh After His Dog Triggers Woman's Miscarriage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-ordered-to-pay-rs-12-lakh-after-his-dog-triggers-pregnant-womans-miscarriage-6595265]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:57:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The dog suddenly bolted out of a building, causing Yan to step back and injure her back.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Shanghai court has ordered a dog owner to pay 90,000 yuan (Rs 10,64,011) in compensation to a pregnant woman who suffered a miscarriage after his unleashed golden retriever startled her. The woman, surnamed Yan, had undergone multiple IVF surgeries over three years to conceive. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3278716/china-dog-owner-pays-woman-us12600-after-she-has-miscarriage-because-animal-startled-her">South China Morning Post,</a></em> the incident happened when Yan, 41, was walking through her residential community to collect a package. The dog suddenly bolted out of a building, causing Yan to step back and injure her back. She immediately felt discomfort in her waist and lower abdomen.</p>

<p>Later that day, Yan visited the hospital and was kept overnight. The next morning, doctors couldn't detect a fetal heartbeat.</p>

<p>''I've been pregnant for nearly four months. After the dog frightened me, I felt pain in my belly. I went to the hospital, but sadly my baby could not be saved. It's really hard for me to have this baby. I've had IVF treatment for three years. Now I have miscarried. I am heartbroken,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She filed a lawsuit against the dog's owner, Li, who acknowledged his dog was unleashed but claimed it was an assistance animal and wouldn't harm anyone. He also suggested she should have been more cautious given her pregnancy's high-risk nature due to IVF.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the court ruled in Yan's favour, citing China's Animal Epidemic Prevention Law, which requires dogs to be leashed in public areas. The court determined that Yan's miscarriage resulted from being frightened by Li's unleashed dog.</p>

<p>The case has sparked a heated online debate, with 110 million views on Weibo. Many internet users expressed sympathy for the woman, while others&nbsp;debated about the issue of dogs not being leashed in public spaces.</p>

<p>One user said, ''It astounded me that this pet owner remained indifferent when seeing his dog jump on a pregnant woman.'' Another commented, ''Poor woman. It will be difficult for her to get pregnant again.''</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ua95u23o_golden-retriever-_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman, surnamed Yan, had undergone multiple IVF surgeries over three years to conceive.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-launched-1st-attack-on-israel-since-lebanon-pager-blasts-6595235]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Says Launched 1st Attack On Israel Since Lebanon Pager Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-launched-1st-attack-on-israel-since-lebanon-pager-blasts-6595235]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:51:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran-backed Hezbollah said on Wednesday it attacked Israeli artillery positions with rockets in the first strike at its arch-foe since pager blasts wounded thousands of its members in Lebanon and raised the prospect of a wider Middle East war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah said on Wednesday it attacked Israeli artillery positions with rockets in the first strike at its arch-foe since pager blasts wounded thousands of its members in Lebanon and raised the prospect of a wider Middle East war.</p>

<p>Israel's spy agency Mossad, which has a long history of sophisticated operations on foreign soil, planted explosives inside pagers imported by Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told Reuters.</p>

<p>The deaths rose to 12, including two children, Lebanese Health Minister Firass Abiad said on Wednesday. Tuesday's attack wounded nearly 3,000 people, including many of the group's fighters and Iran's envoy to Beirut.</p>

<p>A Taiwanese pager maker denied that it had produced the pager devices which exploded in an audacious attack that raised the prospect of a full-scale war between the Iran-backed Hezbollah and Israel.</p>

<p>Gold Apollo said the devices were made by under licence by a company called BAC, based in Hungary's capital Budapest.</p>

<p>There was no immediate word on when Hezbollah had launched its latest rocket attack, but normally the group announces such strikes shortly after carrying them out, suggesting it fired at the Israeli artillery positions on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has vowed to retaliate against Israel, whose military declined to comment on the blasts. The two sides have been engaged in cross-border warfare since the Gaza conflict erupted last October, fuelling fears of a wider Middle East conflict that could drag in the United States and Iran.</p>

<p>Jordan's Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi accused Israel of pushing the Middle East to the brink of a regional war by orchestrating a dangerous escalation on many fronts.</p>

<p>"Hezbollah wants to avoid an all-out war. It still wants to avoid one. But given the scale, the impact on families, on civilians, there will be pressure for a stronger response," said Mohanad Hage Ali of the Carnegie Middle East Center.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, Iran's most powerful proxy in the Middle East, said in a statement it would continue to support Hamas in Gaza and Israel should await a response to the pager "massacre" which left fighters and others bloodied, hospitalised or dead.</p>

<p>One Hezbollah official said the detonation was the group's "biggest security breach" in its history.</p>

<p>Footage from hospitals reviewed by Reuters showed men with various injuries, some to the face, some with missing fingers and gaping wounds at the hip where the pagers were likely worn.</p>

<p>The plot appears to have been many months in the making, several sources told Reuters. It followed a series of assassinations of Hezbollah and Hamas commanders and leaders blamed on Israel since the start of the Gaza war.</p>

<p><strong>TRAIL LEADS TO BUDAPEST</strong></p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source said the group had ordered 5,000 pagers from Gold Apollo, which several sources say were brought into the country earlier this year.</p>

<p>Gold Apollo founder Hsu Ching-Kuang said the pagers used in the explosion were made by a company in Europe that Gold Apollo named in a statement as BAC.</p>

<p>"The product was not ours. It was only that it had our brand on it," Hsu told reporters at the company's offices in the northern Taiwanese city of New Taipei on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The stated address for BAC Consulting in Hungary's capital Budapest was a peach building on a mostly residential street in an outer suburb. The company name was posted on the glass door on an A4 sheet.</p>

<p>A person at the building who asked not to be named said BAC Consulting was registered there but did not have a physical presence. The CEO of BAC Consulting, Cristiana Barsony-Arcidiacono says on her LinkedIn profile that she has worked as an adviser for various organisations including UNESCO. She did not respond to emails from Reuters.</p>

<p>BAC's registered activities are wide ranging, from computer game publishing to IT consulting to crude oil extraction.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source identified a photograph of the model of the pager, an AR-924. Hezbollah fighters have been using pagers as a low-tech means of communication in an attempt to evade Israeli location-tracking.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese source said the devices had been modified by Israel's spy service "at the production level." Israeli officials did not immediately respond to Reuters requests for comment.</p>

<p>"The Mossad injected a board inside of the device that has explosive material that receives a code. It's very hard to detect it through any means," the source said.</p>

<p>The source said about 3,000 of the pagers exploded when a coded message was sent to them, simultaneously activating the explosives.</p>

<p>Another security source told Reuters that up to three grams of explosives were hidden in the new pagers and had gone "undetected" by Hezbollah for months.</p>

<p>In a televised speech on Feb. 13, the group's Secretary General Hassan Nasrallah sternly warned supporters that their phones were more dangerous than Israeli spies, saying they should break, bury or lock them in an iron box.</p>

<p>Instead, Hezbollah opted to distribute pagers to its members across the group's various branches - from fighters to medics working in its relief services.</p>

<p>Israel's Mossad has gained notoriety for its complex operations stretching back to the daring 1960 abduction of high-ranking Nazi Adolf Eichmann. More recently, the spy agency has been blamed for cyber attacks and the assassination of a top Iranian scientist in 2020 with a remote-controlled machinegun.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rak94pko_beirut_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has vowed to retaliate against Israel. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-wanted-to-kill-trump-hid-at-golf-course-for-12-hours-no-one-knew-6595036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Who Wanted To 'Kill' Trump Hid At Golf Course For 12 Hours, No One Knew]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-wanted-to-kill-trump-hid-at-golf-course-for-12-hours-no-one-knew-6595036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:23:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two months after Donald Trump narrowly survived an assassination attempt, a gunman hid undetected for nearly 12 hours on the edge of the golf course where Trump played on Sunday under the protection of an agency that is being pushed to its limits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two months after Donald Trump narrowly survived an assassination attempt, a gunman hid undetected for nearly 12 hours on the edge of the golf course where Trump played on Sunday under the protection of an agency that is being pushed to its limits.</p>

<p>As the 2024 presidential election enters its final stretch, the US Secret Service is operating with about 400 fewer employees than Congress has authorized, government records show.</p>

<p>The problem is not likely to be fixed before the Nov. 5 election, as the agency typically takes more than 200 days to fill open positions.</p>

<p>Since President Joe Biden ended his re-election bid in July and Vice President Kamala Harris took over as the Democratic presidential candidate in a tight race against the Republican Trump, the Secret Service has had to expand its protective coverage to a wider group of officials.</p>

<p>That has placed unprecedented strains on the agency, according to interviews with three former Secret Service agents and a former head of the department that oversees it.</p>

<p>"The pace, the expectations, the pressure has never been worse than it is right now," Kenneth Valentine, a former agent, said in a phone interview.</p>

<p>Trump's desire to golf, in private, at one of his Florida clubs on Sunday also meant that agents did not perform the sort of routine site survey that might have led them to find the alleged gunman before Trump came within a few hundred yards of where the man had holed up for hours, with food, near the fifth hole of the Trump International golf course.</p>

<p>Acting Secret Service Director Ronald Rowe - who stepped into his role in July when the agency's former leader resigned after Trump narrowly survived the first assassination attempt - says his agents are already working at high levels of stress.</p>

<p>"We are redlining them," Rowe said at a news conference on Monday.</p>

<p>Democrats and Republicans in Congress say they could sign off on additional funding in the coming weeks. But that will do little in the short term to fix a personnel shortage that forces agents to work long hours in pressure-filled situations.</p>

<p>The risk of failure was made clear on July 13, when a gunman fired six shots from atop a building at a Trump rally in Pennsylvania, killing a rallygoer and grazing the Republican candidate's ear.</p>

<p>Secret Service agents quickly hustled Trump to safety and killed the gunman, but agency leaders acknowledge he should have never been able to fire shots in the first place.</p>

<p><strong>AGENCY 'ASHAMED'</strong></p>

<p>Rowe told lawmakers on July 30 that he was "ashamed" of security lapses in the incident.</p>

<p>On Sunday, a Secret Service agent spotted the suspected gunman at the Florida golf course, glimpsing the muzzle of his AK-47-style rifle. The agent opened fire, driving him away before he had a direct line of sight to Trump or could fire a shot.</p>

<p>The suspect, Ryan Routh, was apprehended shortly after.</p>

<p>Still, security experts question why the agency did not find him sooner.</p>

<p>"How was Routh not spotted by an advance team? Did the (Secret Service) use a drone over the golf course? Dogs? If not, why not?" said Lora Ries, who oversaw the Secret Service as a top official at the US Department of Homeland Security during Trump's administration.</p>

<p>Rowe told reporters that Trump's Sunday golf outing was not announced to the public. That meant that the agency did not mount an intense security sweep beforehand, which could have signaled his imminent arrival.</p>

<p>Trump's penchant for playing golf on his own courses, which are open to members, creates greater security challenges than past presidents like Barack Obama and Bill Clinton, who typically played on military courses that could be closed to the public, former agents say.</p>

<p>Trump said Monday he wants more agents protecting him. As a candidate and former president, he is afforded fewer agents and resources than a sitting president.</p>

<p><strong>STAFFING SHORTFALL</strong></p>

<p>The Secret Service employed 7,879 people as of February, the most recent figures available.</p>

<p>That trails a plan that a previous agency director, James Murray, laid out to Congress in 2022, when he said he aimed to have 8,305 staffers within a year and 10,000 by 2027.</p>

<p>Though Congress boosted the Secret Service's budget by 9% this year to account for the 2024 election, the agency cannot quickly staff up. The demanding nature of the job means that only 2% of applicants typically are hired, Rowe told Congress in July.</p>

<p>The agency also has struggled in recent years to retain agents lured by more lucrative private-sector work, he said.</p>

<p>That shortage makes it more difficult for agents to remain on the job, as they must rush from one assignment to another.</p>

<p>"The Secret Service does not have the resources, it doesn't have the bodies," said former agent Bill Gage in an interview.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kfo62j0o_ryan-wesley-routh_625x300_16_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Acting Secret Service Chief said Trump's Sunday golf outing was not announced to public (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-year-old-us-girl-drives-mothers-suv-to-store-police-find-her-shopping-6594941]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8-Year-Old US Girl Drives Mother's SUV To Store, Police Find Her Shopping]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-year-old-us-girl-drives-mothers-suv-to-store-police-find-her-shopping-6594941]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:10:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police traced the vehicle to a Target parking lot in Bainbridge, where they found the child shopping inside.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A shocking dashcam video has been released showing an 8-year-old girl driving her mother's vehicle,&nbsp; to a Target store in Ohio, US. Bedford police reported that the child, initially declared missing, was found safe and shopping at the store after driving for nearly 30 minutes on busy roads. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fox8.com/news/8-year-old-girl-found-driving-to-local-target-police/">Fox 8,&nbsp;</a></em>the incident happened on Sunday morning when the&nbsp;police received a call about the missing child, followed by a report of a small child driving a 2020 Nissan Rogue erratically on Rockside road.&nbsp;A dashcam video captured the shocking moment the young driver was spotted on the road. As the recording began, a man's voice was heard alerting authorities to a vehicle behind him, saying, "The car behind me is swerving everywhere."</p>

<p>A neighbour also provided crucial evidence to authorities, revealing that their home security camera captured the 8-year-old girl getting into the SUV alone and driving away.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Police traced the vehicle to a Target parking lot in Bainbridge, where they found the child shopping inside. The girl admitted to striking a mailbox during her 10-mile journey, estimated to be around 20-25 minutes via Google Maps.&nbsp;Her relatives were called to the store to get her and the vehicle.</p>

<p>Though no one was hurt, the incident raises concerns about child supervision and road safety. Authorities have not released information on the mother's whereabouts or potential charges.</p>

<p>Police told Nexstar's&nbsp;<a href="https://fox8.com/tag/i-team/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">FOX 8 I-Team</a>&nbsp;the girl is too young to be charged criminally, and they are grateful no one was injured. On <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/bedford.police.1/posts/pfbid0jSv2ZjWEP9Duiamzhda4EkYsLSyzBQDBuQA6nw5bGvMsuEUw8gacHh8DU6QSmdJKl?ref=embed_POST">Facebook</a>, the Bedford Police Department joked about the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="250" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fbedford.police.1%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0jSv2ZjWEP9Duiamzhda4EkYsLSyzBQDBuQA6nw5bGvMsuEUw8gacHh8DU6QSmdJKl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>''Well, I've finally found a woman who's in more of a hurry to shop at Target than my wife. More of a hurry by 8 years. That's right an 8-year-old took mommy's car this morning and drove to Target in Bainbridge to shop. Thankfully she made it and was immediately located by Bainbridge Police. She's now home safe. Not sure what she bought, or if she was even able to use her Target app to save 5%. We did let her finish her Frappuccino. We're not mean,'' the post read.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0428ikg_clothing-store_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Her relatives were called to the store to get her and the vehicle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worst-drought-on-record-lowers-amazon-rivers-to-all-time-lows-6594908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Worst Drought On Record Lowers Amazon Rivers To All-Time Lows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worst-drought-on-record-lowers-amazon-rivers-to-all-time-lows-6594908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:08:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The worst drought on record has lowered the water level of the rivers in the Amazon basin to historic lows, in some cases drying up riverbeds that were previously navigable waterways.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The worst drought on record has lowered the water level of the rivers in the Amazon basin to historic lows, in some cases drying up riverbeds that were previously navigable waterways.</p>

<p>The Solimoes, one of the main tributaries of the mighty Amazon River whose waters originate in the Peruvian Andes, has fallen to its lowest level on record in Tabatinga, the Brazilian town on the border with Colombia.</p>

<p>Downriver in Tefe, a branch of the Solimoes has dried up completely, as seen by Reuters reporters who flew over the river on Sunday.</p>

<p>The nearby Lake Tefe, where more than 200 freshwater dolphins died in last year's drought, has also dried up, depriving the endangered pink mammals of a favorite habitat.</p>

<p>"We are going through a critical year," said Greenpeace spokesperson Romulo Batista, pointing to where the riverbed of the branch of the Solimoes had turned to mounds of sand. "This year, several months have broken last year's records."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fqup3mn_amazon-river-drought-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The second-consecutive year of critical drought has parched much of Brazil's vegetation and caused wildfires across South American nations, cloaking cities in clouds of smoke.</p>

<p>"Climate change is no longer something to worry about in the future, 10 or 20 years from now. It's here and it's here with much more force than we expected," Batista added.</p>

<p>The Solimoes in Tabatinga was measured at 4.25 meters below average for the first half of September.</p>

<p>At Tefe, the river was 2.92 meters below the average level for the same two weeks last year and is expected to drop further to its lowest-ever.</p>

<p>In Manaus, the Amazon's largest city, where the Solimoes joins the Rio Negro to form the Amazon River proper, the level of the Rio Negro is approaching the record low reached in October last year.</p>

<p>"Last year, we were in this situation by October," said Indigenous leader Kambeba. "This year, the drought has gotten worse."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fpui867c_amazon-river-drought-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The worst drought on record has lowered water level of the rivers to historic lows.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/jay-chaudhry-secret-to-success-an-nri-billionaire-shares-the-one-essential-trait-6594638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Secret To Success? An NRI Billionaire Shares The One Essential Trait]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/jay-chaudhry-secret-to-success-an-nri-billionaire-shares-the-one-essential-trait-6594638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:38:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-American billionaire Jay Chaudhry, co-founder and CEO of Zscaler, believes that passion is the essential trait for success in business.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-American billionaire and co-founder of cybersecurity giant Zscaler, Jay Chaudhry, believes that passion for your work is one trait that can provide ultimate success in any business, according to a report by <em>CNBC. </em>The 66-year-old businessman, who launched his first entrepreneurial venture even back in 1996 by cofounding SecureIT with his wife, sold it in an all-stock deal two years later for $70 million. Since then, Chaudhry has founded three more companies-AirDefense, CipherTrust, and CoreHarbor-all of which he eventually sold.</p>

<p>In 2008, he started Zscaler, which he currently serves as the company's CEO. To Thursday, Zscaler's market capitalisation is $25.31 billion, and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/jay-chaudhry/"><em>Forbes</em></a> puts Chaudhry's wealth at $9.5 billion.</p>

<p>In a recent interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/09/16/the-no-1-trait-for-success-according-to-billionaire-jay-chaudhry.html"><em>CNBC,</em></a> Jay Chaudhry, an entrepreneur with a notable track record of success, emphasised that the key trait for achieving success is passion. He specifically highlighted the importance of having a "passion to achieve something meaningful."</p>

<p>"When you strongly or deeply have a passion for something, you'd do that so much that work becomes your hobby because you are enjoying it," Chaudhry said, adding that motivation leads to harder work and better results.</p>

<p>In contrast, he also mentions here that a lack of passion can undermine success even with experience. "If people don't have passion, it doesn't matter how much experience they have," he said. Without that inner drive, employees would not want to drive enthusiasm to tackle the challenges; therefore, work becomes less enjoyable.</p>

<p>While recruiting, Chaudhry evaluates candidates by their research work and the type of question they raise to measure their passion. As he believed, one's interest can foster them to deliver more in the workplace. In the end, he says, "Success drives success," as passion is an ultimate energy to propel a person to realise business objectives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ebmet1u8_jay-chaudhry_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jay Chaudhry explained that a "passion to achieve something" transforms work into a hobby.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jealous-husband-in-japan-makes-100-calls-daily-to-wife-from-private-number-arrested-6594051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Jealous' Husband In Japan Makes 100 Blank Calls To Wife Daily, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jealous-husband-in-japan-makes-100-calls-daily-to-wife-from-private-number-arrested-6594051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 17:25:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While his sentencing remains pending, the incident has ignited a national conversation in Japan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a strange incident in Japan, a man was arrested for making over 100 silent phone calls daily to his wife for several weeks. The disturbing event unfolded between July and August, captivating public attention due to the husband's bizarre behaviour.&nbsp;According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3278699/japan-wife-discovers-jealous-husband-made-100-nuisance-calls-day-entire-month">South China Morning Post</a></em>, a 31-year-old woman from Hyogo prefecture reported to police that she received unsettling blank calls every day in July and August. However, upon answering, the caller remained silent. Initially, she brought her concerns to her husband, but his nonchalance and lack of concern frustrated her.</p>

<p>A turning point came when she observed the calls stopped when her husband was asleep, gaming, or spending time with her. Her suspicion was piqued, and she devised a test. While shopping together, she closely monitored his actions, noticing he didn't touch his phone, and that's when the calls stopped.</p>

<p>She then reported her concerns to the police, who investigated the couple's phone records.&nbsp;Investigations revealed that the husband was indeed the mastermind behind the mysterious silent calls, leaving his wife distressed. Further probe revealed that he had been using private numbers to conceal his identity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The couple had no known relationship issues and appeared to live harmoniously. According to reports, his motives stemmed from jealousy and possessiveness. A specific incident in the past triggered his insecurity when he discovered his wife engaging in a conversation with another man. Feeling threatened, he began making silent calls as a form of punishment.&nbsp;However, he also claimed that he ''loved her so much.''</p>

<p>In Japan, causing significant emotional distress through nuisance phone calls is considered a criminal offence. Violators may face up to one year in prison or a fine of up to 1 million yen (US$7,000), and a prohibition order will be issued.</p>

<p>On September 4, authorities apprehended the husband, taking him into custody. While his sentencing remains pending, the incident has ignited a national conversation in Japan. Many called for greater awareness and action against emotional harassment and domestic abuse.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One user wrote, ''The husband's control over his wife is too much. This kind of love is suffocating.''</p>

<p>Another commented, ''Communication is the best way for a couple to resolve issues, not harassment or violence.''</p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f9dm735o_man-on-phone_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Japan, causing emotional distress through nuisance phone calls is considered a criminal offence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-youtuber-sydney-watson-sparks-outrage-after-calling-indian-spices-dirt-in-viral-post-6593746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian YouTuber Sparks Outrage After Calling Indian Spices "Dirt"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-youtuber-sydney-watson-sparks-outrage-after-calling-indian-spices-dirt-in-viral-post-6593746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:51:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian YouTuber has found herself in the middle of a social media storm after criticising Indian cuisine for its "dirt spices". Sydney Watson's remarks have drawn severe backlash, with users quickly jumping to defend Indian food.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian YouTuber has found herself in the middle of a social media storm after criticising Indian cuisine for its "dirt spices". Sydney Watson's remarks have drawn severe backlash, with users quickly jumping to defend the historical and cultural significance of Indian food.</p>

<p>The controversy began when an X user shared a post praising Indian cuisine, saying, "Indian food is the best on earth. Fight me." Accompanying the post was a colourful photo of various curries and rice. While the post was meant to celebrate Indian food, the conversation quickly took a different turn when Sydney Watson responded with, "It really, really isn't."</p>

<p>However, it was her follow-up comments that ignited outrage. Watson added, "If your food requires you to put dirt spices all over it in order for it to be palatable, your food is not good."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">If your food requires you to put dirt spices all over it in order for it to be palatable, your food is not good.</p>
— Dr. Sydney Watson (@SydneyLWatson) <a href="https://twitter.com/SydneyLWatson/status/1835771598768402529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In another comment, she wrote, "It all tastes like burning. People who like this are masochistic."</p>

<p>Her remarks did not sit well with social media users.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">yep.<br />
It all tastes like burning. People who like this are masochistic.</p>
— Dr. Sydney Watson (@SydneyLWatson) <a href="https://twitter.com/SydneyLWatson/status/1835771926360248352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A user commented under the post, "Sydney, as far back as the Romans people have been importing spices from India in quantities so great, Ptolemy complained 'There is no year in which India does not drain the Roman Empire of fifty million sesterces'. The point is spice goes on nearly all food."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sydney , as far back the as the Romans people have been importing spices from India in quantities so great, Ptolemy complained "There is no year in which India does not drain the Roman Empire of fifty million sesterces". Point is spice goes on nearly all food.</p>
— anu mathimugan (@deedeewhiteshep) <a href="https://twitter.com/deedeewhiteshep/status/1836289247931994216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another taunted, "It's okay to like bland food without projecting."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's okay to like bland food without projecting.</p>
— Aaron Binder (@theaaronbinder) <a href="https://twitter.com/theaaronbinder/status/1835807081955574076?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"This of course, coming from the country that brought us true delicacies like 'pineapple beetroot hamburger' and 'vegemite on toast'," a comment read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This of course, coming from the country that brought us true delicacies like "pineapple beetroot hamburger" and "vegemite on toast"</p>
— Chairman Birb Bernanke (@Bonecondor) <a href="https://twitter.com/Bonecondor/status/1835827234365460575?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone said, "It's okay if you don't like spicy but condemning is where we draw the line please."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's okay if you don't like spicy but condemning is where we draw the line please. <a href="https://t.co/SKailtFyam">pic.twitter.com/SKailtFyam</a></p>
— Duchess_Beeyah???????? (@KhadijaGarba19) <a href="https://twitter.com/KhadijaGarba19/status/1835827788806328585?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Who cares! You stick with your boiled potatoes while we savour our flavorful delicacy," read a comment.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Who cares!<br />
You stick with your boiled potatoes while we savor our flavorful delicacy.</p>
— Smile&amp;Shine ???????????????? (@smileandshine20) <a href="https://twitter.com/smileandshine20/status/1835882971410382924?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Indian cuisine continues to make its mark on the global stage, with four dishes featured in Taste Atlas' prestigious list of the "100 Best Dishes in the World" this year. Leading is the ever-popular Butter Garlic Naan, which secured an impressive 7th place. Following closely behind were Murgh Makhani (Butter Chicken) at 43, Tikki at 47, and Tandoori Chicken at 48.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/genp568o_sydney-watson_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sydney Watson's remarks did not sit well with social media users.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/lebanons-pager-attacks-whats-next-for-hezbollah-6593630]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Pager Attacks: What Next For Hezbollah?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/lebanons-pager-attacks-whats-next-for-hezbollah-6593630]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:37:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the short term, if not tactically, Israel has been managing to secure at least psychological victories against Hezbollah and its ilk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3egae548_lebanon-hospital_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>One could easily dismiss it as a spy film plot if it weren't so real: a highly sophisticated 'pager attack' purportedly by Israeli agencies has left dozens dead and opened a new front in the ongoing Gaza crisis. Nine people were reported killed and over 2,700, including civilians, were injured when a series of text pagers supposedly used by Hezbollah members exploded in various parts of the country. Iran's ambassador to Lebanon, Mojtaba Amani, was also injured in the explosions.</p>

<p>Reports suggest Israel had intercepted the group's supply chains and laced more than 5,000 of these devices with explosives. A Taiwanese company, Gold Apollo, has denied charges that it was the provider of the consignment. Earlier, in February, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah had warned his group against the use of mobile phones.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>More Complexity To Deal With</strong></h2>

<p>Israel has not officially taken credit for the attack. However, the incident adds one more layer to an intricate and clandestine face-off between Israeli agencies and the Lebanese militia group as both try to avoid a full-scale confrontation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The intent behind such an audacious attack appears to be to inflict a psychological and strategic blow rather than a tactical one. The attack would be added to a not-too-long but notable list of Israeli operations in the recent past that have primarily been designed to highlight the state's intrusions within its enemy's infrastructure, whether political, military, or technological. Examples include the use of automated AI-assisted weapons to assassinate Iranian scientist Mohsen Fakhrizadeh on the outskirts of Tehran in 2021, the elimination of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh in central Tehran a few months ago, and various other clandestine operations aimed at disrupting Iran's nuclear programme. The basic idea behind these operations, including ones now involving low-grade tech like pagers, is optics, to show that the Israeli state can target its detractors at the time and place of its choosing.</p>

<p>The cat-and-mouse game between Hezbollah and Israel has been on the brink of turning into a full conflict for months now. Recently, Israel flew fighter jets over Beirut just before a sermon by Nasrallah, to show force and awareness. It has also been on a mission to eliminate his immediate deputies, such as Fuad Shukr. Recent reports have once again suggested that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu may look to remove Defense Minister Yoav Gallant, who has criticised the way decisions have been taken on the war in Gaza. Despite the political fault lines within Israel on these issues - including the far too public discrepancies between civil and military leaderships - there is a consensus to target both Hamas and Hezbollah in order to secure long-term security narratives, which were deemed lost after the October 7 terror attack.</p>

<h2><strong>Will Iran Intervene?</strong></h2>

<p>As a critical part of the 'Axis of Resistance', Hezbollah, backed by Iran, remains strong compared to Hamas, which has seen its fighting strength deplete significantly in recent months. Also, in choosing not to join Hamas in the aftermath of the October 2023 attack in Israel, Hezbollah managed to buy some time. The reason for this approach could be attributed to two lines of thinking. First, direct aggression against Israel in the country's north would in all likelihood not only invite a response of Israeli air power but that of the US as well, causing mass casualties on the ground in Lebanon, for which Hezbollah would have to be answerable. Second, there seems to be a lack of clarity on whether Iran would directly intervene in support of the said axis. For instance, Tehran hasn't yet directly responded to the killing of Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Hezbollah thus seemingly prefers a more protracted response, causing nuisance and displacement in Israel's north instead of going for a traditional, full-scale border conflict that it very well will not be able to afford.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, the growing tensions between Israel and Hezbollah are threatening to jeopardise diplomatic tracks being promoted by the likes of the US to put a ceasefire in place. Israeli hostages remain under Hamas captivity in Gaza, and Israeli military operations in response are set to continue. Netanyahu has made no qualms in admitting that such warfare will prevail till Hamas is eliminated.</p>

<h2><strong>A Psychological Strike</strong></h2>

<p>Ultimately, both Hamas and Netanyahu have, in their own way, obstructed ceasefire efforts. A political settlement today will require a prolonged secession of hostilities. While Nasrallah claims that his group does not want total war, both sides are sliding towards tactical exchanges. But even these tactical attacks can very well lead to a broader conflict.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With the latest explosions, Hezbollah's 'low-tech' pager communication network has already been busted, making it harder for the group to operate, debate, and deploy forces. In the short term, if not tactically, Israel has been managing to secure at least psychological victories against Hezbollah and its ilk. In the long term, things remain as uncertain as before. It won't be surprising if the Gaza crisis and accompanying regional tensions spill well into 2025.</p>

<p><em>[Kabir Taneja is a Fellow with the Strategic Studies Programme at the Observer Research Foundation. He is the author of 'The ISIS Peril: The World's Most Feared Terror Group and its Shadow on South Asia' (Penguin Viking, 2019)]</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3egae548_lebanon-hospital_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukrainian-strike-triggers-earthquake-sized-blast-at-russian-arsenal-report-6593249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Strike Triggers Earthquake-Sized Blast At Russian Arsenal: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukrainian-strike-triggers-earthquake-sized-blast-at-russian-arsenal-report-6593249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:49:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A large-scale Ukrainian drone attack on Russia triggered an earthquake-sized blast at a major arsenal in the Tver region on Wednesday, forcing the evacuation of a nearby town, war bloggers and some media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A large-scale Ukrainian drone attack on Russia triggered an earthquake-sized blast at a major arsenal in the Tver region on Wednesday, forcing the evacuation of a nearby town, war bloggers and some media reported.</p>

<p>Unverified video and images on social media showed a huge ball of flame blasting high into the night sky and multiple detonations thundering across a lake about 380 km (240 miles) west of Moscow.</p>

<p>NASA satellites picked up intense heat sources emanating from an area of about 14 square kilometres (5 square miles) at the site in the early hours and earthquake monitoring stations picked up what sensors thought was a small earthquake in the area.</p>

<p>"The enemy hit an ammunition depot in the area of Toropets," said Yuri Podolyaka, an Ukrainian-born, pro-Russian military blogger.</p>

<p>"Everything that can burn is already burning there (and exploding)."</p>

<p>There was no information about casualties.</p>

<p>Russian state media have in the past reported that a major arsenal for conventional weapons was located at the site of the blasts. State media, which is now subject to military censorship laws, was muted in its reporting on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Igor Rudenya, the governor of the Tver region, said that Ukrainian drones had been shot down, that a fire had broken out and that some residents were being evacuated. He did not say what was burning.</p>

<p>One woman told Reuters that members of her family had been evacuated from Toropets.</p>

<p>"A fire started with explosions," the woman said, giving only a first name, Irina.</p>

<p>A source in Ukraine's SBU state security service told Reuters the drone attack destroyed a warehouse storing missiles, guided bombs and artillery ammunition. There was no immediate comment from the Ukrainian government.</p>

<p>Russia and Ukraine each reported dozens of enemy drone attacks on their territory overnight, with Russian forces advancing in eastern Ukraine.</p>

<p><strong>MAJOR EXPLOSION</strong></p>

<p>The size of the main blast shown in the unverified social media video was consistent with 200-240 tons of high explosives detonating, according to George William Herbert of the Middlebury Institute of International Studies at Monterey in California.</p>

<p>A Toropets chatroom on the Russian social media site VK was flooded with messages of support from other parts of the country and offers of help to people fleeing the town.</p>

<p>Some people were asking whether buildings at specific addresses were still standing.</p>

<p>"People, does anyone know what's happened to Kudino village??? They told me nothing is left of our house," posted one woman.</p>

<p>Another woman replied: "It's horror there." Kudino is a village 4.5 km (2.8 miles) northeast of Toropets.</p>

<p>Some war bloggers questioned how drones could trigger such large explosions at what was thought to be a highly fortified facility.</p>

<p>According to an RIA state news agency report from 2018, Russia was building an arsenal for the storage of missiles, ammunition and explosives in Toropets, a 1,000-year-old town, which has a population of just over 11,000.</p>

<p>Dmitry Bulgakov, then a deputy defence minister, told RIA in 2018 that the facility could defend weapons from missiles and even a small nuclear attack. Bulgakov was arrested earlier this year on corruption charges. He denies the charges.</p>

<p>"It (the concrete facilities) ensures their reliable and safe storage, protects them from air and missile strikes and even from the damaging factors of a nuclear explosion," RIA quoted Bulgakov as saying at the time.</p>

<p>Some Russians on chat groups expressed anger.</p>

<p>"Why wasn't the ammunition underground?! What are you doing???? In Kudino, houses were blown away! Why is the forest burning and no one is there... what kind of negligence is this!!!!" one woman posted.</p>

<p>Russia reported that its air defence units had destroyed 54 drones launched against five Russian regions overnight, without mentioning Tver. Ukraine said it had shot down 46 of 52 drones launched by Moscow overnight and that Russia had used three guided air missiles which did not reach their targets.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4l3l8cto_tver-russia_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia and Ukraine each reported dozens of enemy drone attacks on their territory overnight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/are-smartphones-safe-lebanons-hezbollah-pager-explosions-raise-concerns-6593213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Are Smartphones Safe? Lebanon Pager Explosions Raise Concerns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/are-smartphones-safe-lebanons-hezbollah-pager-explosions-raise-concerns-6593213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:43:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The explosions occurred in various public places, with reports flooding in from grocery stores, street markets, and other busy locations. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon witnessed a series of explosions on Tuesday after thousands of pagers, allegedly used by the militant group Hezbollah, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100 ">detonated simultaneously across the country</a>. The coordinated blasts killed at least nine people and left over 3,000 injured.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The explosions occurred in various public places, with reports flooding in from grocery stores, street markets, and other busy locations. Video footage from a grocery store showed a man shopping when the pager attached to his waist suddenly exploded, throwing him to the ground. Bystanders fled in terror as chaos erupted around them.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hundreds of Hezbollah fighters injured after mass explosions — Reuters<br />
<br />
Hospitals in Lebanon are overflowing with mostly Hezbollah terror group members being taken to hospitals. A mass pager blast has killed and injured thousands of militants and ordinary Lebanese.<br />
<br />
There are… <a href="https://t.co/1bUC5FcJf1">pic.twitter.com/1bUC5FcJf1</a></p>
— Insider News (@Ins1der_News) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ins1der_News/status/1836263406321479901?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>With pagers being outdated technology, attention has shifted to more modern devices like smartphones, which are widely used by billions worldwide. Could a similar malfunction happen with smartphones?</p>

<p>The notion of hackers turning smartphones into bombs is frightening but unlikely. Smartphone technology's complexity and safeguards minimise risks.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's use of pagers stemmed from security concerns. Simpler and less connected, pagers are harder to track and hack. However, reports suggest explosives may have been embedded in pagers. A New York Times report speculated that Israeli intelligence had inserted explosives into pagers ordered from a Taiwanese manufacturer, although the company denied the claims. If true, this suggests that the explosion was triggered remotely through advanced means.</p>

<p>When it comes to smartphones, they are more complex, with software systems and network connections. In theory, hackers could exploit vulnerabilities in smartphone firmware to cause overheating or malfunction, but mass-scale attacks would be far more difficult to execute compared to pagers. This is because smartphones have multiple security layers and safety measures to prevent battery overheating.</p>

<p>Modern smartphones are equipped with built-in safety mechanisms like temperature regulation circuits, which automatically cut off charging when the device overheats. Advanced cooling systems such as vapour chambers and graphite layers are also present, to ensure that any excess heat is dissipated.</p>

<p>As a result, while smartphones can occasionally malfunction and overheat, they rarely explode. In the rare cases where a smartphone catches fire, it is often due to physical damage or manufacturing defects rather than malicious interference.</p>

<p>Even if hackers could remotely manipulate a smartphone's battery to generate heat, the chances of causing a mass explosion are slim. In most instances, the phone would overheat and possibly swell, leak or catch a small fire, but an explosion on the scale of the Hezbollah pager incident is unlikely.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7dffoi9_phone-generic_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Modern smartphones are equipped with built-in safety mechanisms like temperature regulation circuits.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-bound-easyjet-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-bag-of-vapes-explode-6593117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EasyJet Flight Makes Emergency Landing After Bag Of Vapes Explode]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-bound-easyjet-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-bag-of-vapes-explode-6593117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:31:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eyewitnesses described a terrifying scene, with one passenger recounting a "very large red flash and flame followed by thick black smoke."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chaos erupted on an EasyJet flight carrying 236 passengers when a suspected bag of vapes exploded. The London Gatwick-bound plane, which had taken off from Heraklion, Greece, was forced to evacuate passengers on the runway after reports of "popping noises and smoke" filled the aircraft, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/09/18/easyjet-passengers-bag-vapes-explodes-plane-forcing-evacuation-21624573/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Metro</em></a> reported.&nbsp;Eyewitnesses described a terrifying scene, with one passenger recounting a "very large red flash and flame followed by thick black smoke." Panic spread quickly, with some shouting "bomb" and others rushing to exit the plane.</p>

<p>A witness said, ''Fire and acrid smoke billowed from the bag, popping exploding noises, smoke filled the cabin around the bag.'' Another witness claimed that a British woman carrying a vape in her bag was seen waving it around as smoke began to emanate from it, sparking widespread alarm.</p>

<p>Authorities believe a power bank and e-cigarettes inside a passenger's bag caused the explosion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fortunately, none of the 236 passengers suffered burn injuries from the blast, which occurred shortly after takeoff. However, one passenger sustained a minor friction burn while exiting the plane via the evacuation slide.</p>

<p>Emergency services swiftly responded to the incident, ensuring passenger safety. Following a thorough investigation, authorities cleared the aircraft for re-entry, allowing passengers to retrieve their belongings. Police forces also rushed to the scene to investigate the incident.</p>

<p>After the incident,&nbsp;EasyJet said: "EasyJet can confirm that flight EZY8216 from Heraklion to London Gatwick was evacuated during boarding prior to departure, due to a fire in a passenger's cabin bag. Fire services attended the aircraft and cabin crew evacuated the aircraft in line with procedures. Customers are currently being looked after in the terminal and a replacement aircraft and crew have been arranged to fly customers home later today. Safety is our highest priority.''</p>

<p>The incident highlights the potential risks of carrying lithium-ion batteries and electronic devices on commercial flights.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/nt2dgg3g_-easyjet-_625x300_20_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Panicked passengers evacuated the plane after the explosion]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-seeks-review-of-indus-water-treaty-serves-notice-to-pakistan-6592974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Seeks Review Of Indus Water Treaty, Serves Notice To Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-seeks-review-of-indus-water-treaty-serves-notice-to-pakistan-6592974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:18:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has served a formal notice to Pakistan seeking a review of the Indus Water Treaty, arguing that "fundamental and unforeseen" changes in the circumstances require a reassessment of the pact.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has served a formal notice to Pakistan seeking a review of the Indus Water Treaty, arguing that "fundamental and unforeseen" changes in the circumstances require a reassessment of the pact.</p>

<p>The notice was issued to Pakistan on August 30 under Article XII(3) of the Indus Water Treaty (IWT), government sources said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>India and Pakistan signed the IWT on September 19, 1960, after nine years of negotiations, with the World Bank being a signatory to the pact, which sets out a mechanism for cooperation and information exchange between the two sides on the use of the waters of a number of cross-border rivers.</p>

<p>India's notification highlights fundamental and unforeseen changes in circumstances that require a reassessment of obligations under various articles of the treaty, the sources said.</p>

<p>Among various concerns, the important ones include a change in population demographics, environmental issues and the need to accelerate the development of clean energy to meet India's emission targets, they said.</p>

<p>India has also cited the impact of persistent cross-border terrorism as one of the reasons for demanding the review.</p>

<p>"The notification was issued in the background of a separate prolonged controversy with respect to the Kishanganga and Ratle hydro projects," a source said.</p>

<p>"In this regard, the World Bank has simultaneously activated both the neutral-expert mechanism and the Court of Arbitration on the same set of issues," the source added.</p>

<p>"The Indian side has, therefore, also called for a reconsideration of the dispute-resolution mechanism under the treaty," the source said.</p>

<p>India has not cooperated with the Court of Arbitration process to resolve the dispute.</p>

<p>New Delhi considers that the start of the two concurrent processes to resolve the dispute violates the provision of the three-step graded mechanism prescribed in the IWT.</p>

<p>India has been pushing for the resolution of the dispute through the neutral-expert proceedings.</p>

<p>With this notification, India has called on Pakistan to begin government-to-government negotiations in order to review the treaty under the provisions of Article XII(3), the sources said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/india-pakistan-flags-afp_650x400_41521105457.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has not cooperated with the Court of Arbitration process to resolve the dispute.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-pager-attack-on-hezbollah-could-mean-for-volatile-middle-east-6592973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Pager Attack On Hezbollah Could Mean For Volatile Middle-East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-pager-attack-on-hezbollah-could-mean-for-volatile-middle-east-6592973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:17:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The alleged Israeli attack on members of Hezbollah via their pagers is another ominous development propelling the Middle East towards a full-scale regional war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>The alleged Israeli attack on members of Hezbollah via their pagers is another ominous development propelling the Middle East towards a full-scale regional war. It leaves Hezbollah with little option but to retaliate with the full support of the Iran-led “axis of resistance”.</p>

<p>The sophistication and impact of targeting the pagers is unprecedented. The attack resulted in at least <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/17/world/middleeast/israel-hezbollah-pagers-explosives.html">11 deaths</a>, including some of Hezbollah's fighters, and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/sep/17/hundreds-of-hezbollah-members-hurt-in-lebanon-after-pagers-explode">up to 3,000 people</a> wounded.</p>

<p>The main aim of the attack, which US officials <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/17/world/middleeast/israel-hezbollah-pagers-explosives.html">have reportedly said</a> was carried out by Israel, was intended to disrupt Hezbollah's means of communication and its command and control system in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Since Hezbollah has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/pagers-drones-how-hezbollah-aims-counter-israels-high-tech-surveillance-2024-07-09/">reduced the use of mobile phones</a> by its forces because Israel can easily detect and target them, pagers have increasingly become the preferred messaging device within the group.</p>

<p>The attack may have also been designed to cause panic within the group and among the Lebanese public, many of whom <a href="https://www.newarab.com/news/support-hezbollah-growing-lebanon">do not support Hezbollah</a>, given the political divisions in the country.</p>

<p>Since Hamas' October 7 attacks on southern Israel, the Israeli leadership under Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has repeatedly said it is <a href="https://www.afr.com/world/middle-east/israel-approves-battle-plans-for-hezbollah-edging-closer-to-war-20240619-p5jn3v">determined</a> to remove the threat of Hezbollah, which has operated in solidarity with Hamas.</p>

<p>Hours before the pager attack, Netanyahu's government <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/sep/17/israel-war-goals-netanyahu-hamas-gaza-palestine">clarified</a> that Israel's war goals would expand to include a return of the tens of thousands of residents to their homes in northern Israel, which they have fled due to constant rocket fire from Hezbollah. Israel's defence minister, Yoav Gallant, said the only way to do this was through military action.</p>

<p>The simultaneous pager explosions on Tuesday, then, may be a prelude to an all-out Israeli offensive against Hezbollah.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BREAKING via Reuters<br />
<br />
Hundreds of members of Hezbollah were seriously wounded on Tuesday when the pagers they use to communicate exploded.<br />
<br />
Here is one video of one of the pager explosions. <a href="https://t.co/UDepHvkkEe">pic.twitter.com/UDepHvkkEe</a></p>
— Yashar Ali ? (@yashar) <a href="https://twitter.com/yashar/status/1836038437264368078?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<h2>The consequences of war with Hezbollah</h2>

<p>Hezbollah has already declared it will retaliate. What form this will take remains to be seen. The group has a massive military capability to not only to pound northern Israel with drones and missiles, but also attack other parts of the Jewish state, including heavily populated cities such as Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>Hezbollah showed this capability in its 2006 war with Israel. The war lasted 34 days, during which <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/hezbollah-to-air-new-footage-on-raid-that-sparked-2006-lebanon-war/">165 Israelis were killed</a> (121 IDF soldiers and 44 civilians) and Israel's economy and tourist industry were markedly damaged. Hezbollah and Lebanese losses were far greater, with at least 1,100 deaths. However, the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2006/08/15/opinion/15iht-edsaikal.2491556.html">failed to destroy or incapacitate</a> the group.</p>

<p>Any successful retaliatory attack on Israel's cities could result in serious civilian casualties, giving Israel a further pretext to pursue its long-held aim of destroying Hezbollah and punishing its main backer, the Islamic Republic of Iran.</p>

<p>In a wider conflict, the United States is committed to defending Israel, while Iran would support Hezbollah in whatever way necessary. If Israeli and US leaders think Iran will continue to refrain from any action that could propel it into war with Israel and the US, they are mistaken.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is a central piece in the regime's national and regional security paradigm. Tehran has invested heavily in the group, along with other regional affiliates – Iraqi militias, the Yemeni Houthis and the Syrian regime of Bashar al-Assad, in particular. The aim of this “axis of resistance” has been to build a strong deterrent against Israel and the US.</p>

<p>Ever since its foundation 45 years ago, the Iranian regime has viewed Israel and its main backer, the US, as an existential threat, just as Israel has regarded Iran in the same way. For this, the regime has reoriented its foreign relations towards America's major adversaries, especially Russia and China. <a href="https://carnegieendowment.org/russia-eurasia/politika/2024/02/united-against-america-russia-iran-military-cooperation-is-a-looming-threat?lang=en">Russo-Iranian military cooperation</a> has grown so strong, in fact, that Moscow will have little hesitation in backing Iran and its affiliates in any war.</p>

<p>Tehran is fully cognisant of Israel's nuclear prowess. To guard against it, Iran has developed its own nuclear program to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/27/us/politics/iran-president-nuclear-bomb.html">threshold level</a> of developing a weapon. Iranian leaders may have also gained Russia's assurances it would help defend Iran should Israel resort to the use of its nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, it is important to remember that after nearly a year of demolishing Gaza and devastating its inhabitants, Israel has not been able to wipe out Hamas.</p>

<p>Its own actions speak to this. It has constantly forced Gazans to relocate so IDF soldiers can operate in areas they had previously declared to be cleared of fighters.</p>

<p>The task of defeating Hezbollah and its backers would be a far greater objective to achieve. It carries the serious risk of a war that all parties have been saying that they do not want, yet all are preparing for.</p>

<p>The pager attack is just the latest in a string of operations that keeps imperilling any chances of a permanent Gaza ceasefire that could stabilise the region and contribute to the causes of peace rather than war.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/239302/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amin-saikal-1413547">Amin Saikal</a>, Emeritus professor of Middle Eastern and Central Asian Studies, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/australian-national-university-877">Australian National University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/will-the-exploding-pager-attack-be-the-spark-that-ignites-an-israel-hezbollah-war-239302">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qcrllkug_israel-hezbollah-attack-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bruised-by-fresh-election-loss-justin-trudeau-shows-no-sign-of-stepping-down-6592944]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bruised By Election Loss, Justin Trudeau Shows No Sign Of Stepping Down]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bruised-by-fresh-election-loss-justin-trudeau-shows-no-sign-of-stepping-down-6592944]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:11:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Doubts about the leadership Justin Trudeau intensified after his ruling Liberal Party suffered a second humiliating loss in a special election, but the unpopular leader is determined to cling to office ahead of a looming national vote.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Doubts about the leadership of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau intensified after his ruling Liberal Party suffered a second humiliating loss in a special election, but the unpopular leader is determined to cling to office ahead of a looming national vote.</p>

<p>The Liberals, who have governed for almost nine years, suffered a narrow defeat on Monday in a Montreal constituency that had been one of the party's safest seats.</p>

<p>The loss, following a defeat in Toronto in late June, reinforced the perception that Liberal prospects in the next national election are dim. The mandate for Trudeau's minority government expires at the end of October 2025, but an early election has become increasingly likely after the smaller New Democratic Party dropped its support.</p>

<p>Even so, Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign. And the party's mechanisms to force him out are limited.</p>

<p>Andrew McDougall, an assistant professor of political science at the University of Toronto, said the Liberals were losing "the crown jewels" in urban strongholds, not marginal seats, highlighting the party's bleak prospects.</p>

<p>"This is obviously a very difficult moment for Justin Trudeau," McDougall said. "It seems to reinforce the narrative that he's yesterday's man, and that if the Liberals are going to win the next election, they're going to have to do it with somebody else."</p>

<p>Although polls indicate the Liberals will lose badly to the official opposition right-of-center Conservatives in the next election amid unhappiness over inflation and a housing crisis, Trudeau and his closest aides say he is going nowhere and has time to help the party recover.</p>

<p>"Obviously, it would have been nicer to be able to win ... but there is more work to do and we're going to stay focused on doing it," Trudeau told reporters on Tuesday.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Justin Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vr64s064_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Justin Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Justin Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign.</p>
</div>

<p>His main immediate challenge is that he has lost control of the House of Commons, where the Liberals hold only a minority of seats. The left-leaning NDP signed a deal in 2022 to keep the Liberals in power but tore up the agreement this month.</p>

<p>The NDP increased its share of the vote in Montreal while retaining a seat in the western province of Manitoba, fending off a strong Conservative challenge.</p>

<p>The Liberals face a number of confidence votes by legislators in the next few months and a defeat would trigger an election, although the NDP may choose to keep the government afloat until it can buoy its own popularity.</p>

<p>"The Liberals gave both opposition parties a reason to believe that they can defeat Trudeau," said Darrell Bricker, CEO of polling firm Ipsos-Reid. "The potential they can trigger (an election) sooner is definitely there."</p>

<p>Keeping a minority government alive can be difficult and how much Trudeau can press ahead with his legislative agenda remains unclear.</p>

<p>The Liberals said on Monday they would focus on legislation regarding defense and citizenship.</p>

<h2><strong>SPECIAL CONVENTION</strong></h2>

<p>Unlike in the United States, where President Joe Biden stepped down as Democratic presidential candidate in favor of Vice President Kamala Harris, there is no smooth way for Trudeau to hand over power.</p>

<p>In Australia and the UK, prime ministers are chosen by legislators and can be quickly overthrown. Trudeau was selected by a special convention of party members and cannot be forced out if he wants to stay.</p>

<p>One senior Liberal said if the polls continued to look miserable, senior ministers could urge Trudeau to leave.</p>

<p>But the Liberal, who requested anonymity given the sensitivity of the situation, said there was no guarantee Trudeau - a stubborn man according to insiders - would listen.</p>

<p>Bricker said those in charge of Liberal fundraising could make the same pitch to Trudeau.</p>

<p>"If the money dries up, they are not in a position to fight," he said.</p>

<p>If Trudeau steps down, an interim leader would be chosen while the party set up another convention.</p>

<p>Tradition dictates a stand-in must come from the ranks of legislators, ruling out former Bank of Canada governor Mark Carney, often mentioned as a potential Trudeau replacement.</p>

<p>The interim leader does not run to be the permanent replacement, according to party custom. That could deter cabinet heavyweights such as Finance Minister Chrystia Freeland and Innovation Minister Francois-Philippe Champagne from seeking to replace Trudeau in the short term.</p>

<p>Regardless, changing leaders might not boost Liberal prospects, said Frank Graves, president of the Ekos polling firm.</p>

<p>"The difficulties Mr. Trudeau and the Liberals are experiencing are pretty similar to those progressive incumbents are experiencing in other advanced western democracies," he said by email, citing rising populism and economic uncertainty.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/eqti80h4_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canadas Prime Minister Justin Trudeau shows no signs of stepping down despite recent setbacks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-discover-new-blood-group-solve-50-year-old-mystery-6592794]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Discover New Blood Group, Solve 50-Year-Old Mystery]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-discover-new-blood-group-solve-50-year-old-mystery-6592794]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:59:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A team of scientists from NHS Blood and Transplant (NHSBT) and the University of Bristol has identified a new blood group system called MAL.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A team of scientists from NHS Blood and Transplant (<a href="https://www.nhsbt.nhs.uk/news/nhs-blood-and-transplant-led-team-discovers-new-blood-group-system-mal/ ">NHSBT</a>) and the University of Bristol has identified a new blood group system called MAL. This breakthrough solves a 50-year-old mystery surrounding the AnWj blood group antigen, first discovered in 1972.</p>

<p>The research team, led by senior research scientist Louise Tilley, has developed a genetic test to identify patients missing the AnWj antigen. This innovation will enable better care for rare patients and facilitate finding compatible blood donors. Tilley, who has dedicated 20 years to this project, told BBC, “It's challenging to quantify the exact number of people who will benefit from this test. However, NHSBT is the last resort for around 400 patients each year worldwide.”</p>

<p>The discovery has far-reaching implications, benefiting patients worldwide. NHSBT's International Blood Group Reference Laboratory in Filton provides countries with antibodies for research and has developed a test that can be added to existing genotyping platforms.<br />
<br />
<strong>Key findings of the research:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>AnWj Antigen: The team identified the genetic background of the AnWj antigen, allowing for a better understanding and treatment of rare patients lacking this blood group.</li>
	<li>MAL Blood Group System: The discovery establishes MAL as the 47th blood group system, home to the AnWj antigen.</li>
	<li>Genetic Cause: Researchers found homozygous deletions in the MAL gene associated with the inherited AnWj-negative phenotype.</li>
	<li>Transfusion Safety: The study enables the development of new genotyping tests to detect rare AnWj-negative individuals, reducing transfusion-associated complications.</li>
</ul>

<p>Blood group antigens are proteins on red blood cells, and a lack of these can lead to severe reactions during transfusions. Philip Brown, a laboratory technician and leukaemia survivor, stressed the importance of the discovery. “Having undergone multiple blood transfusions and a bone marrow transplant, I understand firsthand the critical need for safer blood matches,” Brown told BBC.<br />
<br />
Nicole Thornton, Head of the Laboratory, noted the international significance of this discovery. “Unraveling the genetic basis of the AnWj antigen has been a major challenge. With this breakthrough, we can now design genotyping tests to identify patients and donors with this rare antigen,” Thornton explained.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0qoettt_blood-test-generic_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-how-cancer-cells-may-be-using-lipids-to-hide-from-immune-system-6592758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Shows How Cancer Cells May Be Using Lipids To Hide From Immune System]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-how-cancer-cells-may-be-using-lipids-to-hide-from-immune-system-6592758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:51:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have long known that cancer cells alter lipid metabolism, but it was generally assumed that cancer cells were gobbling up these lipids for energy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cancer cells rarely begin stealthily. Quite the contrary, they alert the immune system to their presence by displaying chemical red flags on their membranes. When detected, the body's defences can swoop in and destroy renegade cells before they can do significant damage. Lipids, fatty molecules traditionally thought to be largely a fuel supply for developing tumours, are at the heart of this early detection system.</p>

<p>However, a new study in Nature shows that one specific lipid type is essential for cancer immune evasion -- so much so that certain cancer cells cannot reproduce without it. The findings validate long-held assumptions that not only is this lipid a crucial factor in cancer biology (and thus a key therapeutic target).</p>

<p>"Cancer cells are altering how this lipid is metabolized, which in turn distorts the 'eat me' signals that malignant cells usually produce," says first author Mariluz Soula, a former graduate student in the laboratory of Kivanc Birsoy, and now a scientist Lime Therapeutics. "This paints a very different picture of the role lipids play in cancer growth."</p>

<p>Scientists have long known that cancer cells alter lipid metabolism, but it was generally assumed that cancer cells were gobbling up these lipids for energy--consuming the fatty molecules to help the tumor grow and spread far beyond that of healthy cells.</p>

<p>"We knew from the literature that elevated lipid levels correlate with severity of cancer growth and metastasis, but it was unclear how," Soula says. The Birsoy lab, in conjunction with the laboratory of Gabriel D. Victoria, set out to answer this question by screening the genes involved in this process. They then implanted a series of cancer cells, each missing a different such gene, into mice with and without immune systems--thereby revealing which lipids a cancer cannot live without.</p>

<p>The result: so-called "sphingolipids." Discovered in the late 1800s by German chemist Johann Ludwig Wilhelm Thudichum, sphingolipids were named after the enigmatic Sphinx of Greek lore because of their puzzling structure and function. Two centuries later, sphingolipids are less of a mystery. "We know that sphingolipids aren't really used for energy," Soula says. "They're mainly in the cell membrane to create scaffolding for signaling proteins."</p>

<p>This finding raised an intriguing possibility. Was lipid metabolism in cancer cells really just the story of hungry cells trying to consume more energy? Or was it a key part of the cancer cell's efforts to subtly manipulate cell signaling and dodge the immune system?</p>

<p>To test how sphingolipids were driving cancer growth, the team turned to an FDA-approved drug used to treat Gaucher disease--a genetic disorder characterized by an impaired ability to break down lipids. The drug essentially blocks glycosphingolipid synthesis, and the team found that this impaired tumor growth in pancreatic, lung, and colorectal cancer models.</p>

<p>They also found that depleting glycosphingolipids prevented the formation of the "lipid nanodomains" that bunch signalizing molecules together on the membrane, impacting the cell's surface receptors on the cell surface in a way that made them more sensitive to an immune response. These findings suggest that cancer cells hoard glycosphingolipids in order to obscure inflammatory signals, and that disrupting glycosphingolipid production can leave cancer cells vulnerable to the immune system.</p>

<p>"Everyone thought of elevated lipid levels as an energy source for cancer cells to consume," Soula says. "We discovered that it's far more nuanced. Lipids are not just fuel, but a protection mechanism for cancer cells that modulates how they communicate with the immune system."</p>

<p>Future work will determine whether this holds true for multiple cancers. The team tested a variety of types, but found this mechanism at work in KRAS-dependent cancers (so named for the mutated oncogene that drives them). Still, the initial results could have significant clinical impact, given how aggressive many KRAS-dependent cancers, such as pancreatic cancer, tend to be. Based on their findings, the team suggests that drug and dietary interventions that stunt sphingolipid production may help increase the efficacy of existing immunotherapies.</p>

<p>"Diets may impact many aspects of cancer biology," Birsoy says. "We believe modulating dietary lipids may be an interesting avenue to target cancer cells' ability to evade immune cells."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tlop50jo_surgery_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>