<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 04:10:48 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-5-points-in-latest-survey-6296461]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Leads Trump By 5 Points In Latest Poll Survey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-5-points-in-latest-survey-6296461]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 04:10:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>The nationwide poll of 2,045 U.S. adults, conducted Aug. 2-7, found 4% of those surveyed backed independent candidate Robert Kennedy Jr., down from 10% in July.</p>

<p>Ipsos conducted the August poll independently from Reuters. The poll, conducted online, had a margin of error of around 3 percentage points.</p>

<p>Harris entered the race on July 21 when President Joe Biden, 81, folded his campaign and endorsed Harris following a disastrous debate performance on June 27 against Trump.</p>

<p>Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>The nationwide poll of 2,045 U.S. adults, conducted Aug. 2-7, found 4% of those surveyed backed independent candidate Robert Kennedy Jr., down from 10% in July.</p>

<p>Ipsos conducted the August poll independently from Reuters. The poll, conducted online, had a margin of error of around 3 percentage points.</p>

<p>Harris entered the race on July 21 when President Joe Biden, 81, folded his campaign and endorsed Harris following a disastrous debate performance on June 27 against Trump.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/jhmacdl_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_19_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-misleading-election-posts-viewed-1-2-billion-times-report-6296247]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Misleading Election Posts On X Viewed 1.2 Billion Times: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-misleading-election-posts-viewed-1-2-billion-times-report-6296247]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 03:01:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[False or misleading US election claims posted on X by Elon Musk have amassed nearly 1.2 billion views this year, a watchdog reported Thursday, highlighting the billionaire's potential influence on the highly polarized White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>False or misleading US election claims posted on X by Elon Musk have amassed nearly 1.2 billion views this year, a watchdog reported Thursday, highlighting the billionaire's potential influence on the highly polarized White House race.</p>

<p>Ahead of the November election, researchers have raised alarm that X, formerly Twitter, is a hotbed of political misinformation.</p>

<p>They have also flagged that Musk, who purchased the platform in 2022 and is a vocal backer of Donald Trump, appears to be swaying voters by spreading falsehoods on his personal account.</p>

<p>Researchers from the Center for Countering Digital Hate (CCDH) identified 50 posts since January by Musk -- who has more than 193 million followers on the social media site -- with election claims debunked by independent fact-checkers.</p>

<p>None of the posts displayed a "Community Note," a crowd-sourced moderation tool that X has promoted as the way for users to add context to posts, CCDH said, raising questions about its effectiveness to combat falsehoods.</p>

<p>"Elon Musk is abusing his privileged position as owner of a... politically influential social media platform to sow disinformation that generates discord and distrust," warned CCDH chief executive Imran Ahmed.</p>

<p>"The lack of Community Notes on these posts shows that his business is failing woefully to contain the kind of algorithmically-boosted incitement that we all know can lead to real-world violence."</p>

<p>The posts analyzed by CCDH carried widely debunked claims, such as that Democrats are encouraging illegal migration with the aim of "importing voters" or that the election is vulnerable to fraud. Both claims amassed hundreds of millions of views.</p>

<p>Last week, Musk faced a firehose of criticism for sharing with his followers an AI deepfake video featuring Trump's Democratic rival, Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>In it, a voiceover mimicking Harris calls President Joe Biden senile before declaring that she does not "know the first thing about running the country."</p>

<p>The video, viewed by millions, carried no indication that it was parody -- save for a laughing emoji. Only later did Musk clarify that the video was meant as satire.</p>

<p>"Musk behaves as if he is beyond reproach despite growing evidence of the harmful role he is personally playing to fuel disinformation and division ahead of the US elections," Nora Benavidez, from the advocacy group Free Press Action Fund, told AFP.</p>

<p>"As his behavior edges closer to election interference, it's up to others -- the public, regulatory agencies and advertisers -- to hold him accountable for his anti-democratic behavior."</p>

<p>Musk, who purchased the platform in 2022 for $44 billion, is facing growing scrutiny over his potential influence on voters.</p>

<p>On Monday, a bipartisan group of five US secretaries of state sent an open letter to Musk, urging him to fix X's AI chatbot known as Grok after it produced election misinformation.</p>

<p>Hours after Biden stepped down from the presidential race last month and endorsed Harris as the Democratic nominee, Grok churned out false information about ballot deadlines, which was amplified by other platforms.</p>

<p>X -- which also faced criticism for stoking tensions during recent far-right riots across England -- has gutted trust and safety teams and scaled back content moderation efforts once used to tame misinformation, making it what researchers call a haven for disinformation.</p>

<p>X did not respond to an AFP request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ldckr8sg_elon-musk_625x300_18_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk had purchased X platform in 2022 for $44 billion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-qatar-egypt-invite-israel-and-hamas-to-resume-talks-on-august-15-6296188]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US, Qatar, Egypt Invite Israel And Hamas To Resume Talks On August 15]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-qatar-egypt-invite-israel-and-hamas-to-resume-talks-on-august-15-6296188]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 02:48:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Qatari, Egyptian and U.S. leaders called on Israel and Hamas to resume urgent talks on Aug. 15 either in Doha or Cairo to bridge all remaining gaps in the proposed Gaza ceasefire agreement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Qatari, Egyptian and U.S. leaders called on Israel and Hamas to resume urgent talks on Aug. 15 either in Doha or Cairo to bridge all remaining gaps in the proposed Gaza ceasefire agreement and start implementing it without any delay, the three countries said in a joint statement on Thursday.</p>

<p>"It is the time to conclude a ceasefire agreement and release hostages and prisoners," the statement added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/1nebbspo_israel-hamas-war_625x300_08_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 37,000 people have been killed since war began between Israel and Hamas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-vows-to-fight-aggression-from-hezbollah-with-all-its-might-6295832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Vows To Fight Aggression From Hezbollah "with All Its Might"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-vows-to-fight-aggression-from-hezbollah-with-all-its-might-6295832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 01:00:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Thursday that Israel would fight Hezbollah "with all its might" if the Lebanese armed group continued its "aggression" across the border.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Thursday that Israel would fight Hezbollah "with all its might" if the Lebanese armed group continued its "aggression" across the border.</p>

<p>"We will not allow the Hezbollah militia to destabilise the border and the region. If Hezbollah continues its aggression, Israel will fight it, with all its might," Gallant said in a message addressed to the people of Lebanon, according to a statement from his office.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has traded near-daily fire with Israeli forces in support of ally Hamas since the Palestinian militant group's October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Fears of all-out war have mounted after Israel killed Hezbollah's top military commander Fuad Shukr in an air strike in a Beirut suburb last week.</p>

<p>Reminding the people of Lebanon of the 2006 war between Israel and Hezbollah, Gallant warned Lebanon to "learn the lesson of the past so as not to fall into a dangerous scenario in August 2024".</p>

<p>The devastating 34-day war in July-August 2006 killed more than 1,200 people in Lebanon, mostly civilians, and some 160 Israelis, mostly soldiers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/g7dminco_yoav-gallant-_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel Defence Minister said that it will not allow the Hezbollah militia to destabilise the border.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-will-peaceful-transfer-of-power-if-us-election-is-fair-6295719]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Will Be "Peaceful Transfer" Of Power If...: Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-will-peaceful-transfer-of-power-if-us-election-is-fair-6295719]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:30:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Thursday there would be a peaceful transfer of power after the US presidential vote -- but immediately questioned whether there would be "honest elections."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said Thursday there would be a peaceful transfer of power after the US presidential vote -- but immediately questioned whether there would be "honest elections."</p>

<p>"Of course there'll be a peaceful transfer, and there was last time," Trump told a news conference, despite a mob of his supporters storming Congress in 2021 after his loss. "I just hope we're going to have honest elections."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7s3biquo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_30_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I just hope we're going to have honest elections," Trump said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-offers-three-tv-debates-against-kamala-harris-next-month-6295682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Offers Three TV Debates Against Kamala Harris Next Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-offers-three-tv-debates-against-kamala-harris-next-month-6295682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:20:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump proposed three September debates against Kamala Harris Thursday as he sought to wrest back some of the attention lavished on his rival since her blockbuster entry into the US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump proposed three September debates against Kamala Harris Thursday as he sought to wrest back some of the attention lavished on his rival since her blockbuster entry into the US presidential election.</p>

<p>Harris has ignited the Democratic ticket in the last 18 days, pulling in record fundraising and obliterating the Republican ex-president's polling lead to open up a much broader path to victory than her party would dare to have hoped for just a month ago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The country's first female, Black and South Asian vice president heads into her party's national convention in Chicago in mid-August on the back of a series of packed rallies that have won plaudits for a positive message that has reenergized the Democratic base.</p>

<p>Meanwhile Trump -- who addressed journalists at his oceanfront estate in Florida -- has found himself on unfamiliar ground as something of a bystander, eclipsed by Harris's rise as he has scaled back his own campaigning.</p>

<p>"I hope she agrees," Trump told journalists, after he said he had arranged debates with television networks on September 4, 10 and 25.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump revived a series of familiar attacks on his opponent -- repeatedly questioning the intelligence of the former state attorney general and US senator, in an event punctuated by falsehoods.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Same policies' -</strong><br />
Trump made untrue claims on all manner of topics around the election and his record in office, from the price of gasoline to his crowd sizes, US military deaths in Afghanistan and the 2021 insurrection at the US Capitol by his supporters.</p>

<p>He assured reporters there would be a peaceful transfer of power after the November 5 vote -- but questioned whether the election would be honest and claimed that the last transfer had been peaceful, despite the deadly Capitol riot.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump also rejected a suggestion that he would need to recalibrate his campaign to take account of his new opponent after Harris replaced President Joe Biden on the ticket on July 21.</p>

<p>"It's the same policies, open borders, weak on crime. She is, I think, she's worse than Biden," he said.</p>

<p>The rival campaigns had sparred over Trump backing out of a previously scheduled ABC presidential debate on September 10. The network said Thursday both candidates have now agreed to the face off.</p>

<p>Trump-friendly Fox News would host the first of the three debates while NBC would take the final slot. There was no immediate word those dates from the Harris campaign.</p>

<p>The former president's debate with a dismally performing Biden in June spelled the end of the president's reelection campaign, but Trump had been reluctant to face Harris on neutral territory.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old has been struggling to come up with effective attack lines to define Harris while delivering a series of increasingly confounding nicknames for his opponent.</p>

<p><strong>- 'True stre</strong>ngth' -<br />
The news conference was his first public appearance since Harris -- a generation younger than Trump at 59 -- announced running mate Tim Walz and embarked on a tour of closely fought election battlegrounds.</p>

<p>She and Walz appeared Thursday in Michigan ahead of a trip to the racially diverse "Sun Belt" states of Arizona and Nevada for rallies on Friday and Saturday.</p>

<p>"The true measure of the strength of a leader is not based on who you beat down. It's based on who you lift up," she told a crowd of around 170 supporters in Detroit, at a much smaller event than her recent arena rallies.</p>

<p>Sabato's Crystal Ball, a leading election forecaster, shifted three of its ratings in favor of Democrats on Wednesday, moving Minnesota and New Hampshire from "leans Democratic" to "likely Democratic" and Georgia from "leans Republican" to "toss-up."</p>

<p>Meanwhile Marquette University Law School released a nationwide survey showing that, among likely voters, Harris now leads Trump by six points -- 53 percent to 47 percent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite her intensive campaign schedule, Harris has taken almost no questions from reporters since entering the race and Trump had been seeking to turn her lack of media exposure into an election issue even before Thursday's news conference.</p>

<p>"She hasn't done an interview -- she can't do an interview, she's barely competent... But I look forward to the debates, because I think we have to set the record straight," he said in Florida.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/06lu95io_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump also assured reporters there would be a peaceful transfer of power after November elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-spy-agency-isi-fuelling-unrest-in-bangladesh-claims-sheikh-hasinas-son-6295392]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak's ISI Fuelling Unrest In Bangladesh, Claims Sheikh Hasina's Son]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-spy-agency-isi-fuelling-unrest-in-bangladesh-claims-sheikh-hasinas-son-6295392]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:26:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, who quit as prime minister and fled Bangladesh, will be back in the country as soon as democracy is restored, his son Sajeeb Wazed Joy said on Thursday and blamed Pakistan's intelligence agency, ISI, for fuelling the ongoing unrest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina, who quit as prime minister and fled Bangladesh, will be back in the country as soon as democracy is restored, his son Sajeeb Wazed Joy said on Thursday and blamed Pakistan's intelligence agency, ISI, for fuelling the ongoing unrest in the country.</p>

<p>In an interview with PTI, Mr Joy said that although 76-year-old Sheikh Hasina would return to Bangladesh, it has not yet been decided whether she will be back as a "retired or active" politician.</p>

<p>He also asserted that the members of the Sheikh Mujib (Sheikh Mujibur Rahman) family will neither abandon its people nor leave the beleaguered Awami League in the lurch.</p>

<p>He expressed gratitude to Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his government for protecting his mother and appealed to India to help build international opinion and exert pressure to restore democracy in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Yes, it is true that I had said she wouldn't return to Bangladesh. But a lot has changed in the last two days following continuous attacks on our leaders and party workers across the country. Now we are going to do whatever it takes to keep our people safe; we are not going to leave them alone."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Awami League is the largest and oldest political party in Bangladesh, so we cannot just walk away from our people. She will definitely return to Bangladesh once democracy is restored," he told PTI over the phone.</p>

<p>Terming Awami League an "all-weather ally of India", he said India must ensure the security of Awami League leaders in Bangladesh by building international pressure.</p>

<p>Mr Joy also urged the interim government, headed by Nobel laureate Mohammad Yunus, to restore law and order, noting that "the country is turning into a state of anarchy and becoming a second Afghanistan in the region." He said he also expects the interim government to create a level playing field whenever democracy is restored and fresh elections are held.</p>

<p>"You cannot exclude the Awami League and have a representative democracy in Bangladesh ever. Whatever his (Mohammed Yunus) personal views are, he has said that he wants a government of unity and wants to move forward and not let the mistakes of the past cloud over the future. I hope he stays true to his word," he asserted.</p>

<p>Prof Yunus took oath as the head of Bangladesh's interim government on Thursday and was administered the oath of office by President Mohammed Shahabuddin at a ceremony in Dhaka.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country following violent protests against her government over a controversial quota system in jobs. She flew to the Hindon air base, near Delhi, in a Bangladesh military aircraft on Monday.</p>

<p>Mr Joy mentioned that once democracy is restored, either the Awami League or BNP will come to power, and the "Mujib family and Sheikh Hasina will be around." "She has been in touch with all our party leaders for the last two days. My mother was going to retire anytime soon, so we thought now that she is gone, they (rioters) would leave our party people alone, but that did not happen. Instead, they started attacking," he said.</p>

<p>Declining to comment directly on whether he and his sister Saima Wazed, who is currently the South East Asian regional director for the World Health Organization, would enter politics, Joy said he would do whatever it takes to protect Bangladesh from total anarchy.</p>

<p>"I can't give a definite reply to this question. But I will do whatever it takes to save Bangladesh and protect the Awami League. The Mujib family would not leave them in a lurch," said Joy, the former Information and Communication Technology Advisor to Hasina.</p>

<p>Blaming Pakistan for fueling the unrest in Bangladesh, Joy said there is circumstantial evidence suggesting foreign interference and alleged involvement of Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence agency.</p>

<p>"I am quite certain given the circumstantial evidence; I suspect Pakistan ISI's involvement. The attacks and protests were very coordinated, meticulously planned, and intentional efforts to keep inflaming the situation through social media. No matter what the government did to control the situation, they kept trying to worsen it," he said.</p>

<p>He also pointed out that the rioters attacked police with guns which could only be provided by terror outfits and foreign powers.</p>

<p>On reports of involvement of a US intelligence agency like the CIA, Joy said he had no evidence but added, "maybe, they are". He dismissed any Chinese involvement when asked about it.</p>

<p>Dismissing reports of Hasina seeking asylum in the UK or any other country as "rumours", Joy said the reports of her US Visa being revoked are also untrue.</p>

<p>"Nothing of this sort has been planned (seeking asylum). Sooner or later, there has to be a restoration of democracy in Bangladesh and hopefully, that will be between the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Awami League. Then Sheikh Hasina will be back." "At this point, she wants to go back to Bangladesh. It's a question of when rather than if," he said, hinting that the ousted Bangladesh PM will be staying at an undisclosed location in India for now.</p>

<p>Joy, who spent much of his childhood studying in India, appealed to the Indian government to ensure the quick restoration of democracy for stability in the region.</p>

<p>"I want to thank the Indian government for protecting my mother. I owe my heartfelt gratitude to Prime Minister Modi. If India wants stability in its eastern backyard, then they have to pressure the international community and take the lead to ensure the quick restoration of democracy," he said.</p>

<p>Speaking on the 'INDIA-out' campaign in Bangladesh, he said, "the anti-India forces are already very active, and with Awami League out of power, the ISI is now free to supply as many weapons as it wants to the anti-India forces." Joy said India must act fast before anti-India forces gain more ground.</p>

<p>Refuting claims that Ms Hasina ran away to save her own life, he said the family insisted on stopping the bloodshed.</p>

<p>"She was not willing to leave the country. The Prime Minister's security was ready to protect her till the end. But that would have led to hundreds of deaths of protestors who were marching towards the PM's residence. We convinced her for the sake of Bangladesh, we cannot let her get killed," he said.</p>

<p>"Our government was not weak, but my mother did not want to harm the students. Even after her leaving the country, the bloodshed has not stopped. The people will now understand the difference with and without Sheikh Hasina," he said.</p>

<p>The death toll in the anti-government protests in Bangladesh climbed to 440 on Wednesday, with the recovery of 29 more bodies of Hasina's Awami League party members across the country through Tuesday, taking the overall death toll to 469 in nearly three weeks since the protests began in July"Asatya Not J: When Amit Shah Helped Out Kiren Rijiju In Parliament</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d3t8m64g_bangladesh-protests-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He expressed gratitude to PM Modi and his government for protecting his mother]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-banksy-murals-depicting-animals-appear-in-london-6295151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 New Banksy Murals Depicting Animals Appear In London. What Do They Mean]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-banksy-murals-depicting-animals-appear-in-london-6295151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:57:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A goat, two elephants, three monkeys and one wolf. Four Banksy murals which have appeared in London this week have left many pondering the meaning behind the elusive street artist's latest work.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A goat, two elephants, three monkeys and one wolf.</p>

<p>Four Banksy murals which have appeared in London this week have left many pondering the meaning behind the elusive street artist's latest work.</p>

<p>It began with the mountain goat on Monday, appearing to be perched on a ledge with rocks falling off and depicted in Banksy's signature stencil style on a wall in Richmond, west London.</p>

<p>Next came two elephant heads, peering out of two blocked out windows on the side of a house in affluent Chelsea, followed by three monkeys which appear to be hanging from a railway bridge near east London's Brick Lane.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p577brm8_banksy-elephant-mural-reuters_625x300_08_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>The silhouette of a wolf, howling at the sky, appeared on a satellite dish atop a heavily graffitied building in Peckham, southeast London, on Thursday. Banksy has posted pictures of each on his Instagram account.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police said the satellite dish had been reported stolen within hours of being unveiled. Pictures in local media showed it being removed by a person who had their face covered with a mask.</p>

<p>Theories swirled on social media as to the meaning of the works, by an artist who has highlighted themes such as war and climate change in his previous work.</p>

<p>Some speculated they could be related to the riots and racist attacks that have swept the country in the past week, others to the idea that humanity is seeding its own downfall.</p>

<p>"Nice one Banksy. I see this as a critique on the wild and chaotic behaviour currently erupting across the UK. Far right thugs on the prowl," one user "barrybrexiter" commented on Banksy's Instagram post.</p>

<p>Another "leticia_vega" wrote "Humanity is not going to last ... animals will be taking over."</p>

<p>The Bristol-based artist's last mural, also in London, depicted green paint sprayed across the side of a building to mimic the foliage of a real, heavily pruned tree that stands a few metres in front of it. Many took that mural as speaking to a need to preserve nature.</p>

<p>In December, Banksy depicted three drones on a stop sign, again in Peckham. It was stolen very shortly after it went up.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qpgh614_banksy-animal-mural-reuters_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A mural depicted three monkeys that appeared to be hanging from a railway bridge.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-f-22-stealth-warplanes-arrive-in-middle-east-amid-fears-of-iran-israel-war-6295101]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US F-22 Warplanes Arrive In Middle East Amid Fears Of Iran-Israel War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-f-22-stealth-warplanes-arrive-in-middle-east-amid-fears-of-iran-israel-war-6295101]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:38:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Advanced American F-22 stealth warplanes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, as Washington boosts its forces in the region ahead of an expected Iranian counterattack on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Advanced American F-22 stealth warplanes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, as Washington boosts its forces in the region ahead of an expected Iranian counterattack on Israel.</p>

<p>The deployment is part of "force posture changes in the region to mitigate the possibility of regional escalation by Iran or its proxies," US Central Command said on social media, without specifying the number or exact location of the planes.</p>

<p>The Pentagon said last week that Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin had ordered assets including additional warships and a fighter squadron to the region.</p>

<p>Seven American personnel were wounded in a rocket attack in Iraq earlier this week that Washington blamed on an Iran-backed militia group.</p>

<p>And Tehran and its allies are expected to launch an attack on Israel in retaliation for the killing of top Hamas and Hezbollah figures in strikes last week either blamed on or claimed by Israel.</p>

<p>The killings are among the most serious in a series of tit-for-tat attacks that have heightened fears of a regional conflagration stemming from the Gaza war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h4dem9g_us-f22-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Seven American personnel were wounded in a rocket attack in Iraq earlier this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/residents-flee-beiruts-hezbollah-stronghold-fearing-israeli-airstrikes-6295064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Residents Flee Beirut's Hezbollah Stronghold Fearing Israeli Airstrikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/residents-flee-beiruts-hezbollah-stronghold-fearing-israeli-airstrikes-6295064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:34:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Batoul and her family have been scrambling to secure housing outside Beirut's southern suburbs where an Israeli strike killed a senior Hezbollah commander last week, but spiking demand has sent prices soaring.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Batoul and her family have been scrambling to secure housing outside Beirut's southern suburbs where an Israeli strike killed a senior Hezbollah commander last week, but spiking demand has sent prices soaring.</p>

<p>Many in the southern suburbs -- a packed residential area known as Dahiyeh which is also a Hezbollah bastion -- have been trying to leave, fearing full-blown war between the Iran-backed group and Israel in the wake of the commander's killing.</p>

<p>"We are with the resistance (Hezbollah) to death," said Batoul, a 29-year-old journalist, declining to give her last name as the matter is sensitive.</p>

<p>"But it's normal to be scared... and look for a safe haven," she told AFP.</p>

<p>Iran and its regional allies have vowed revenge for the killing, blamed on Israel, of Hamas's political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week, just hours after the Israeli strike in Beirut's southern suburbs killed Hezbollah's top military commander Fuad Shukr.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has traded near-daily fire with Israeli forces in support of ally Hamas since the Palestinian militant group's October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza.</p>

<p>After the twin killings, fears have mounted of an all-out war, with foreign airlines suspending Beirut flights and countries urging their nationals to leave.</p>

<p>Last week's Beirut strike also killed an Iranian adviser and five civilians -- three women and two children.</p>

<p>"Whoever says they want to stay in Dahiyeh while it's being bombed is lying to themself," Batoul said.</p>

<p><strong>'No choice'</strong></p>

<p>On Tuesday, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah said his Shiite Muslim movement and Iran were "obliged to respond" to Israel "whatever the consequences".</p>

<p>Batoul said she had been trying unsuccessfully to rent in "safe areas" -- unaffiliated to Hezbollah -- outside Beirut, but landlords were charging "exorbitant prices".</p>

<p>She said one landlord cancelled suddenly even after she agreed to pay six months' rent in advance for a flat in the mountain town of Sawfar.</p>

<p>A 55-year-old teacher and Hezbollah supporter, who requested anonymity because the matter is sensitive, said she felt lucky to find a flat about 15 kilometres (nine miles) outside Beirut.</p>

<p>But it came with a price tag of $1,500 a month, in a country battered by more than four years of economic crisis.</p>

<p>The teacher, also a Dahiyeh resident, said price gouging was rampant, noting another apartment was listed online for $1,500 a month "but when we arrived, they asked for $2,000".</p>

<p>"They know we have no choice. When there is a war, people will pay any amount of money to be safe," she said.</p>

<p>But "many people will stay (in Dahiyeh) because they cannot afford to rent," she added.</p>

<p>Riyad Bou Fakhreddine, a broker who rents out homes in the Mount Lebanon area near Beirut, said apartments were being snapped up "within half an hour to an hour of being listed".</p>

<p>Some landlords have asked him to raise apartments normally priced at around $500 a month to as high as $2,000, he said.</p>

<p>He said he refused.</p>

<p>"I tell them I'm not a crisis profiteer. I don't want to take advantage of people's fears," he said.</p>

<p><strong>'Polarisation'</strong></p>

<p>Almost 10 months of cross-border violence have killed some 558 people in Lebanon, most of them fighters but also including at least 116 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, including in the annexed Golan Heights, 22 soldiers and 25 civilians have been killed, according to army figures.</p>

<p>Ali, who rents serviced apartments in central Beirut, said his phone had "not stopped ringing" ahead of Nasrallah's speech.</p>

<p>"I booked 10 flats in two days," he said.</p>

<p>"Many people walked in and booked on the spot... Or called me and were here within an hour," said the 32-year-old, who requested to be identified only by his first name.</p>

<p>In 2006, Hezbollah fought a devastating war with Israel, whose air force bombarded Beirut's southern suburbs nightly for a month, flattening hundreds of apartment blocks.</p>

<p>Back then, many people from across Lebanon's sectarian divides expressed support for Hezbollah and solidarity with the Shiite Muslim community, many of whom lost their homes and livelihoods.</p>

<p>But this time, Dahiyeh resident Batoul said solidarity was lacking, with politicians divided after Hezbollah decided unilaterally to begin attacking Israeli positions on October 8.</p>

<p>In 2006, "there wasn't such polarisation," she said.</p>

<p>Landlords and others profiting from high demand on housing now are simply driven by greed, Batoul said.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kceck6_beirut-afp-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Almost 10 months of cross-border violence have killed some 558 people in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-north-korea-expert-detained-in-switzerland-on-espionage-charges-reports-6294998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canadian North Korea Expert Detained In Switzerland On Espionage Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-north-korea-expert-detained-in-switzerland-on-espionage-charges-reports-6294998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:30:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former UN official from Canada who now works as a North Korea specialist has been detained in Switzerland on charges of spying, likely for China, media reports said on Thursday, citing unnamed intelligence sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former UN official from Canada who now works as a North Korea specialist has been detained in Switzerland on charges of spying, likely for China, media reports said on Thursday, citing unnamed intelligence sources.</p>

<p>The reports were part of a joint investigation by the German news outlet Der Spiegel, the Swiss media company Tamedia and North Korea-focused website NK News.</p>

<p>The Swiss attorney general's office did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the case.</p>

<p>The suspect regularly travelled to China for his work as an environmental consultant before being arrested earlier in the spring on espionage charges, said NK News, an online outlet that has staff in the US, Europe and South Korea.</p>

<p>It said it did not publish the official's full name as he has not been convicted and authorities have not made public charges against him.</p>

<p>The person, in his 50s and a resident of Geneva, was in pretrial detainment for several months pending the conclusion of an investigation by the Swiss attorney general's office, the NK News report said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/l1qrg5s8_belarus-spying_625x300_07_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The person was in pretrial detainment for several months. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-israel-wants-to-expand-war-amid-de-escalation-efforts-6294881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Says Israel Wants To "Expand War" Amid De-Escalation Efforts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-israel-wants-to-expand-war-amid-de-escalation-efforts-6294881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:29:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran accused Israel on Thursday of wanting to spread war in the Middle East, as diplomatic efforts sought a regional de-escalation following the killings of Tehran-allied militant leaders.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran accused Israel on Thursday of wanting to spread war in the Middle East, as diplomatic efforts sought a regional de-escalation following the killings of Tehran-allied militant leaders.</p>

<p>Ali Bagheri, Iran's acting foreign minister, told AFP that Israel had committed "a strategic mistake" by killing Hamas's political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week -- hours after the assassination in Beirut of Hezbollah's military chief.</p>

<p>Although Israel has not admitted to killing Haniyeh, Iran and its allies have vowed to retaliate, setting the region on edge as the Gaza war raged on into its 11th month.</p>

<p>Israel seeks "to expand tension, war and conflict to other countries", but has neither "the capacity nor the strength" to fight Iran, Bagheri said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, speaking at a military base on Wednesday, said Israel was "prepared both defensively and offensively" and "determined" to defend itself.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's group named a successor on Wednesday -- Yahya Sinwar, who Israel says had a key role in planning Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack that sparked the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Analysts believe Sinwar -- Hamas's leader in the Gaza Strip since 2017 -- has been both more reluctant to agree to a ceasefire and closer to Tehran than Haniyeh, who lived in Qatar.</p>

<p>On the ground in Gaza, fighting continued on Thursday with the Israeli military issuing its latest evacuation order and rescuers and medics reporting at least 13 killed in strikes.</p>

<p><strong>'Cycle of reprisals'</strong></p>

<p>The front pages of some of Israel's leading newspapers on Thursday cited "assessments" that Iran may be rethinking its course of action, reportedly in part due to US pressure.</p>

<p>Officials and leaders in the Middle East and beyond have called for calm, with Britain's minister for international development, Anneliese Dodds, telling AFP on a visit to Jordan: "We must see a de-escalation".</p>

<p>The United States, which has sent extra warships and jets to the region, has urged both Iran and Israel to avoid an escalation.</p>

<p>France's President Emmanuel Macron spoke Wednesday with his Iranian counterpart Masoud Pezeshkian and later with Israel's Netanyahu, telling both to "avoid a cycle of reprisals", according to the French presidency.</p>

<p>Israel's military chief Herzi Halevi told troops "we are not stopping" targeting the leaders of "our most dangerous enemies", vowing to "find" and "attack" Sinwar too, according to an army statement.</p>

<p>Also on Wednesday, the 57-member Organisation of Islamic Cooperation, meeting in the Saudi city of Jeddah, declared that Israel was "fully responsible" for Haniyeh's "heinous" killing.</p>

<p>Bagheri said OIC members voiced support for Iranian retaliation.</p>

<p>"Western countries, who claim they have asked Iran to restrict its response... are not in the position to advise the Islamic Republic of Iran."</p>

<p><strong>'Inevitable'</strong></p>

<p>The Israel-Hamas war in the Gaza Strip has already drawn in Tehran-aligned militants in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Lebanese Hamas ally Hezbollah, which has traded near-daily cross-border fire with Israeli troops throughout the Gaza war, has vowed retaliation for military chief Fuad Shukr's killing.</p>

<p>Israel said the Beirut strike that killed him was in response to deadly rocket fire from Lebanon last month on the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>And in Yemen, the Iran-backed Huthis said Thursday their retaliation for a deadly Israeli strike last month on the Red Sea port of Hodeida was "inevitable and will come".</p>

<p>The Huthis, who have carried out maritime attacks since November in a campaign they say is in solidarity with Gaza, claimed a drone attack on Tel Aviv a day before the Hodeida strike.</p>

<p>A Lebanese government official told AFP on Thursday that "there are efforts to calm the situation" across the region including with a continued push to secure a Gaza truce after months of stalled negotiations.</p>

<p>"But we must stay alert, even if tensions have relatively subsided over the past two days," said the source, requesting anonymity.</p>

<p>Numerous airlines have suspended flights to Lebanon due to security fears.</p>

<p><strong>Israel PM 'sorry'</strong></p>

<p>The Hamas attack that triggered the war in Gaza resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,699 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, who has resisted making an apology for security failures over Israel's worst-ever attack, said in an interview published Thursday that he was "sorry, deeply, that something like this happened".</p>

<p>"You always look back and you say, 'Could we have done things that would have prevented it?'" Netanyahu told Time magazine.</p>

<p>The Israeli military meanwhile issued a new evacuation order for parts of Khan Yunis, southern Gaza's main city, telling Palestinians to flee places from where "rockets are launched" at Israel.</p>

<p>The civil defence agency said an Israeli strike targeting a Khan Yunis house killed at least five people.</p>

<p>In the territory's north, AFP journalists reported air strikes and constant shelling overnight in Gaza City, where medics said eight people were killed in two separate incidents.</p>

<p>On the diplomatic front, an Israeli decision to revoke the diplomatic status of Norway's envoys to the Palestinian Authority over "anti-Israel behaviour" drew anger from Oslo.</p>

<p>"Today's decision will have consequences for our relationship with the Netanyahu government," said Norwegian Foreign Minister Espen Barth Eide.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/tlb179lg_iran_625x300_04_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crew-of-doomed-titan-submersible-knew-they-were-going-to-die-lawsuit-6294847]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Crew Of Doomed Titan Submersible "Knew They Were Going To Die": Lawsuit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crew-of-doomed-titan-submersible-knew-they-were-going-to-die-lawsuit-6294847]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:01:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The family of Paul Henri-Nargeolet hopes that by holding OceanGate accountable, they can prevent similar tragedies from occurring in the future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The family of renowned Titanic explorer Paul Henri-Nargeolet is seeking $50 million in damages from OceanGate, the company behind the doomed Titan submersible. The lawsuit alleges that the company's reckless disregard for safety led to the tragic deaths of all five crew members, including Nargeolet, who endured unimaginable terror before the vessel's catastrophic implosion.</p>

<p>At the heart of the suit are accusations of gross negligence against OceanGate and its CEO, Stockton Rush. The company is alleged to have prioritized profit and publicity over the safety of its passengers. By circumventing industry standards, ignoring expert advice, and cutting corners, OceanGate created a perilous environment for those aboard the Titan, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/titan-submersible-wrongful-death-lawsuit-b2592900.html"><em>Independent </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The lawsuit contends that Rush's obsessive pursuit of innovation blinded him to the critical importance of safety. His alleged disregard for established protocols, coupled with the company's failure to disclose the full extent of the risks involved, created a deadly recipe for disaster.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The family of Paul Henri-Nargeolet hopes that by holding OceanGate accountable, they can prevent similar tragedies from occurring in the future. The legal battle promises to shed light on the circumstances surrounding the fatal expedition and may lead to significant changes in the regulation of deep-sea exploration.</p>

<p>For instance, while titanium is typically used in deep-sea submersibles, Rush believed it was unnecessarily heavy and chose carbon fiber for the Titan's hull instead. The lawsuit notes that carbon fiber "breaks down over time under pressure," and although Rush acknowledged the potential for "catastrophic failure" due to imperfections in the carbon fiber structure, he installed an acoustic safety system to detect problems.</p>

<p>The Titan had only made a few trips to the depth of the wreck site before the mission, but these journeys may have weakened the vessel's "carbon-fiber hull and/or the connections and seals between disparate types of material," the suit contends.</p>

<p>OceanGate's head of marine operations, who was "ultimately most responsible for the safety of anyone sailing" on Titan, requested a scan of the carbon fiber hull as part of a detailed safety report. This request reportedly angered Rush, who not only refused to conduct the scan but also fired the safety chief after addressing the report.</p>

<p>In addition to this expert's concerns, Rush received warnings from other experts and the Marine Technology Society, which sent a letter to OceanGate in 2018 cautioning that the company's "experimental" approach "could result in negative outcomes (from minor to catastrophic)." According to the lawsuit, "None of the warnings were heeded."</p>

<p>The vessel was also never certified by the leading certification group DNV. Rush declined to seek DNV certification for Titan, believing it would be too difficult to "educate" DNV personnel-who are world-class experts on the requirements and dangers of deep-sea diving-on the supposed advantages of Titan's "innovative" design, the complaint states.</p>

<p>The lawsuit also alleges that crew members were required to sign a waiver that "failed to disclose many key, relevant risk factors...regarding the design and operation of TITAN or the materials used in its construction."</p>

<p>Despite his extensive knowledge of the ocean floor near the Titanic wreck, the 77-year-old Nargeolet was never fully informed about the safety of the vessel, the suit claims. "Neither Rush nor OceanGate ever fully or accurately disclosed all of the material facts regarding Titan's design and construction...On the contrary, Rush and OceanGate actively fostered Nargeolet's (and others') false impressions about the safety and seaworthiness of the vessel."</p>

<p>Tragically, when the acoustic safety system's alarm indicated that the hull was "cracking under extreme pressure," the pilot attempted to abort the expedition by releasing weight.</p>

<p>The crew, however, had no communications and likely no power. "Common sense dictates that the crew were well aware they were going to die, before dying," the suit states.</p>

<p>"The crew may well have heard the carbon fiber's crackling noise grow more intense as the weight of the water pressed on TITAN's hull," the filing says. "By experts' reckoning, they would have continued to descend, in full knowledge of the vessel's irreversible failures, experiencing terror and mental anguish prior to the Titan ultimately imploding."</p>

<p>Aside from the Titan, no commercial manned submersible has ever suffered an implosion, the suit says.</p>

<p>Both Mr Rush and Mr Nargeolet died in the implosion, along with British explorer Hamish Harding, 58, UK-based Pakistani businessman Shahzada Dawood, 48, and his 19-year-old son Suleman.</p>

<p>Tony Buzbee, one of the lawyers for the family, said in a statement: "We are hopeful that through this lawsuit we can get answers for the family as to exactly how this happened, who all were involved, and how those involved could allow this to happen."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/76i5h4h_titanic-sub_625x300_21_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company is alleged to have prioritized profit and publicity over the safety of its passengers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bangladeshs-caretaker-leader-muhammad-yunus-economic-thinking-6294710]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Bangladesh Caretaker Leader Muhammad Yunus' Economic Thinking]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bangladeshs-caretaker-leader-muhammad-yunus-economic-thinking-6294710]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:43:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Peace Prize-winning economist Muhammad Yunus takes over as the head of Bangladesh's caretaker government on Thursday when the country is facing tough economic challenges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel Peace Prize-winning economist Muhammad Yunus takes over as the head of Bangladesh's caretaker government on Thursday when the country is facing tough economic challenges.</p>

<p>Here is a look at his economic beliefs as he takes the helm of the South Asian country until elections are held and a new administration is put in place.</p>

<p><strong>Social Businesses</strong></p>

<p>Mr Yunus advocates "social businesses" that solve problems rather than simply create wealth, with any profit generated being ploughed back to create more value.</p>

<p>Grameen Bank, the microfinance lender he founded, was rooted in this idea and lauded for helping to boost growth and alleviate poverty in Bangladesh.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Yunus was awarded the 2006 Nobel Peace Prize for his pioneering work in microfinance which was replicated in other developing countries and led to him being known as "banker to the poor".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Poverty</strong></p>

<p>Mr Yunus' belief that poverty - which plagued more than 18% of Bangladesh's population in 2022 - is a "threat" and causes problems ranging from terrorism to trafficking, informs most of his work.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You can't leave people poor and live happily...they are in a desperate situation. When you are desperate, you disturb peace," Mr Yunus told Nobelprize.org in 2006.</p>

<p>It was to solve this problem that he sought to inculcate "sound financial principles" in the poor through his microcredit system.</p>

<p><strong>Globalisation</strong></p>

<p>Mr Yunus has called for "multi-national social businesses" that either give the poor ownership or keep profits within poor countries.</p>

<p>When he dabbled in politics in 2007, he suggested upgrading the Chittagong port to a continental seaport - a plan critics said could endanger national security, jobs and the environment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Yunus also spoke of a "global civilisation" in an interview with The Indian Express newspaper last week, in which he criticised India for saying the upheaval in Bangladesh was an "internal matter" and warned the chaos could spill over to its neighbours.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Diplomacy has a much richer vocabulary than saying it is their internal affair," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Women</strong></p>

<p>Mr Yunus emphasises the role of women in building the future and has been part of multiple international commissions catering to them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Women currently outnumber men in Bangladesh and constitute 97% of Grameen Bank's members.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Women want to build up something for the future with their money. Men want to spend it enjoying themselves," he told Harvard Business Review in 2012.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/56nalei8_muhammad-yunus_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus emphasises the role of women in building the future]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-changes-eu-app-store-policy-after-commission-probe-6294650]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple Changes Its App Store Policy In EU After Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-changes-eu-app-store-policy-after-commission-probe-6294650]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:36:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple on Thursday changed its policy in the European Union to allow developers to communicate with their customers outside the app after the Commission]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple on Thursday changed its policy in the European Union to allow developers to communicate with their customers outside the app after the Commission charged the iPhone maker in June for breaching the bloc's tech rules.</p>

<p>The Commission had said that under most of the business terms, Apple allows steering only through "link-outs", meaning that app developers can include a link in their app that redirects the customer to a web page where the customer can conclude a contract.</p>

<p>Apple said developers will now be able to communicate and promote offers that are available anywhere, not just on their own website, from within their app.</p>

<p>However, Apple will introduce two new fees - an initial 5% acquisition fee for new users and a 10% store services fee for any sales made by app users on any platform within the 12 months of the app installation.</p>

<p>Currently, Apple charges three types of fees: a core technology fee for the less than 1% of apps, a reduced commission for all digital goods and services sold through the App Store, and an optional fee for the payments and commerce services.</p>

<p>The two new fees will replace the reduced commission for all digital goods and services sold through the App Store.</p>

<p>The Commission had earlier criticised the fees charged by Apple for facilitating via the App Store the initial acquisition of a new customer by developers, saying they went beyond what was strictly necessary for such remuneration.</p>

<p>The charge against Apple is the first by the Commission under its landmark Digital Markets Act which seeks to rein in the power of Big Tech and DMA violations could result in a fine of as much as 10% of a company's global annual turnover.</p>

<p>Apple said there has been an ongoing dialogue with the European Commission and the changes made were in response to the announcements made in June.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jr2volug_apple-iphone-reuters_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The charge against Apple is the first by the Commission under its Digital Markets Act]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-didnt-agree-to-discuss-israel-arms-embargo-says-aide-6294561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Didn't Agree To Discuss Israel Arms Embargo, Says Aide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-didnt-agree-to-discuss-israel-arms-embargo-says-aide-6294561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:24:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris did not agree to discuss imposing an arms embargo on Israel during an exchange with pro-Palestinian activists who are pushing for changes to US policy toward its ally over the Gaza war, an aide said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris did not agree to discuss imposing an arms embargo on Israel during an exchange with pro-Palestinian activists who are pushing for changes to US policy toward its ally over the Gaza war, an aide said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The Uncommitted National Movement had said late on Wednesday that Harris, the 2024 Democratic presidential candidate, had "shared her sympathies and expressed an openness to a meeting with Uncommitted leaders to discuss an arms embargo" during the interaction while campaigning in Detroit, the aide said.</p>

<p>The aide, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Harris did not express a willingness to discuss an arms embargo. But a campaign spokesperson said the vice president did tell members of the Muslim and Palestinian community she would continue to engage with them on the war between Israel and Palestinian militants Hamas in Gaza, which local officials say has killed nearly 40,000 people.</p>

<p>"The vice president has been clear: She will always work to ensure Israel is able to defend itself against Iran and Iran-backed terrorist groups. The vice president is focused on securing the ceasefire and hostage deal currently on the table," the campaign spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Two founders of the group, Layla Elabed and Abbas Alawieh, said they spoke briefly with both Harris and newly minted running mate Tim Walz of Minnesota about their concerns about the U.S. supplying weapons to Israel as it wages war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Alawieh said on Thursday that both he and Elabed specifically asked for a meeting to discuss the demand for an arms embargo on Israel, "and in both cases, Vice President Harris expressed an openness to following up."</p>

<p>He said he was very encouraged by his engagements with Harris' office and "we're hopeful that continued discussions will continue to be fruitful."</p>

<p><strong>HUMANITARIAN CRISIS</strong></p>

<p>Israel launched its assault on the besieged Palestinian enclave in retaliation for an Oct. 7 attack on southern Israel by Hamas militants who killed 1,200 people and took some 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The Uncommitted political group was organized to oppose President Joe Biden's staunch support for Israel's war, which has displaced nearly 80 percent of Gaza's 2.3 million people and caused severe food shortages.</p>

<p>The humanitarian catastrophe in Gaza has prompted calls for Washington to put conditions on the billions of dollars in military funding and other assistance it provides to Israel, which has received more U.S. foreign aid since World War Two than any other country.</p>

<p>The United States in May paused a shipment of 2,000-pound and 500-pound bombs due to concern over the impact they could have in Gaza.</p>

<p>The Uncommitted movement amassed sizable vote totals in presidential nominating contests in Michigan, Minnesota and Hawaii, and has won at least 25 delegates. Leaders have said they want to use their influence at this month's Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</p>

<p>In a reminder of how divisive the issue has been for Democrats, a group of pro-Palestinian protesters briefly interrupted Harris' speech in Detroit on Wednesday, chanting, "Kamala, Kamala, you can't hide, we won't vote for genocide."</p>

<p>She paused for a moment, saying she believed in democracy and the importance of every voice, and then added, "But I am speaking now." When the chants continued, she repeated, "You know what? If you want Donald Trump to win, then say that. Otherwise, I'm speaking."</p>

<p>Trump has criticized Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for Israeli security failures that enabled Hamas to carry out the Oct. 7 attack and said he would work to bring about a quick end to the war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9jgs0hjg_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States in May paused a shipment of 2,000-pound and 500-pound bombs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-led-by-nobel-prize-winner-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-6294401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus Takes Oath As Head Of Interim Government In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-led-by-nobel-prize-winner-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-6294401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:03:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Signalling the beginning of a new chapter after 15 years of Sheikh Hasina as the prime minister, Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus took oath as the head of the interim government in Bangladesh on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Signalling the beginning of a new chapter after 15 years of Sheikh Hasina as the prime minister, Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus took oath as the head of the interim government in Bangladesh on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I will uphold, support and protect the constitution and will perform my duties sincerely," Mr Yunus said at the swearing-in event, which comes at a tumultuous time for Bangladesh. The country has witnessed violence and clashes even after the student-led protests forced Ms Hasina to resign and flee the country on Monday.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus, 84, was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006 for pioneering microcredit and microfinance, which he put into action through the Grameen Bank. He was sworn in hours after he returned to Dhaka from Paris, where he had been undergoing medical treatment. The oath was administered by Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin at his official residence, 'Bangabhaban'.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi extended his best wishes to Mr Yunus and said India is hoping for an early return to normalcy in Bangladesh, which would also ensure the safety of Hindus and other minorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My best wishes to Professor Muhammad Yunus on the assumption of his new responsibilities. We hope for an early return to normalcy, ensuring the safety and protection of Hindus and all other minority communities. India remains committed to working with Bangladesh to fulfill the</p>
 Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1821574094195769549?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>"My best wishes to Professor Muhammad Yunus on the assumption of his new responsibilities. We hope for an early return to normalcy, ensuring the safety and protection of Hindus and all other minority communities. India remains committed to working with Bangladesh to fulfill the shared aspirations of both our peoples for peace, security and development," PM Modi wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Advisory Council</strong></p>

<p>Mr Yunus has been sworn in as the chief adviser in the interim government, a position akin to that of prime minister, and a 16-member council of advisers will be assisting him. The advisers include Nahid Islam and Asif Mahmud, two key leaders of the protests that led to Ms Hasina's ouster.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the other members of the council are Adilur Rahman Khan, a prominent rights activist who was sentenced to a two-year jail term under Ms Hasina; women's rights activist Farida Akhtar; Grameen Telecom trustee Nurjahan Begum; former foreign secretary Touhid Hossain; and AFM Khalid Hossain, deputy chief of right-wing party Hefazat-e-Islam.</p>

<p>Speaking before the swearing-in ceremony, Mr Yunus said, "Today is a glorious day for us... Bangladesh has created a new victory day. Bangladesh has got a second independence."</p>

<p>Urging a return to normalcy, he added, "We cannot take a step forward unless we fix the law and order situation. My call to the people is that if you have trust in me, make sure there will be no attacks against anyone, anywhere in the country... We are one big family."</p>

<p><strong>Violent Protests</strong></p>

<p>Trouble had been brewing in Bangladesh since before the January 7 elections, which was won by Sheikh Hasina's Awami League in a landslide, but the electoral exercise was widely seen as being far from free and fair.</p>

<p>A fresh wave of protests led by students began in June - in which over 450 people have been killed so far - &nbsp;after a Bangladeshi high court reinstated 30 per cent reservation in government jobs for family members of freedom fighters and veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 War of Independence. The quota was later scaled back by the country's Supreme Court but Ms Hasina's handling of the protests and her alleged use of an offensive label for the protesters infuriated students.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Protests continued with students demanding that Ms Hasina step down and clashes between agitators and the police left over 100 dead and dozens injured across the country on Sunday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Monday saw lakhs of students flooding the streets and heading towards the prime minister's official residence, Ganabhaban, forcing Ms Hasina to resign and flee to India. Violence continued in some places even after Ms Hasina resigned and there have been reports of minorities, including Hindus, being targeted.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em><strong>(With agency inputs)</strong></em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/k4mimtrg_muhammad-yunus-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi has extended his best wishes to Mr Yunus.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attend-mosque-or-be-punished-taliban-chief-orders-government-workers-6293812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Attend Mosque Or Be Punished, Taliban Chief Orders Government Workers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attend-mosque-or-be-punished-taliban-chief-orders-government-workers-6293812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 20:31:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Afghan government employees must attend mosque five times a day or face punishment, Taliban supreme leader Hibatullah Akhundzada said Thursday in his latest edict enforcing an austere interpretation of Islam.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Afghan government employees must attend mosque five times a day or face punishment, Taliban supreme leader Hibatullah Akhundzada said Thursday in his latest edict enforcing an austere interpretation of Islam.</p>

<p>Since the 2021 Taliban takeover Akhundzada has overseen sweeping restrictions on society -- shutting many women and girls out of education, ordering male chaperones for females and effectively banning music.</p>

<p>"The officials of the ministries and institutions of the (Taliban government) are obliged by Sharia to pray in congregation at their fixed times," said the order signed by Akhundzada.</p>

<p>It added that employees who miss a prayer "without a reasonable excuse" should receive a warning, and if they repeat the transgression "the relevant official is obliged to appropriately punish him".</p>

<p>A Taliban government spokesman did not respond to a query from AFP asking what the punishment would entail.</p>

<p>According to Islam, Muslims must strive to pray five times a day, either in private or at a mosque.</p>

<p>The times are adjusted according to the sun, but some fall within working hours.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear how the order for employees to attend prayer during non-work hours would be policed.</p>

<p>Akhundzada directs the government from his hideout in southern Kandahar, the spiritual heartland of the Taliban movement which first ruled Afghanistan from 1996 to 2001.</p>

<p>He rarely appears in public, and when he does bodyguards prohibit spectators from taking photographs or video of the man who has led the Taliban since 2016.</p>

<p>But his intermittent edicts now define how Afghans can lead their lives.</p>

<p>A United Nations report last month said "restrictive measures to regulate activities of individuals in both public and private spheres contribute to a climate of fear and intimidation among segments of the population".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/hrfdt17o_taliban-generic_625x300_16_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since the 2021 Taliban takeover, Akhundzada has overseen sweeping restrictions on society]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-sorry-about-hamas-october-7-attack-6294009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu Says He Is "Sorry" About Hamas October 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-sorry-about-hamas-october-7-attack-6294009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 20:15:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in an interview published Thursday that he was "sorry" that Hamas was able to carry out its October 7 attack, without explicitly taking responsibility.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in an interview published Thursday that he was "sorry" that Hamas was able to carry out its October 7 attack, without explicitly taking responsibility.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, who has resisted making an apology for security failures over Israel's worst-ever attack and focused on destroying Hamas, was asked if he would apologize during an interview with Time magazine.</p>

<p>"Apologize?" he was quoted as replying.</p>

<p>"Of course, of course. I am sorry, deeply, that something like this happened. And you always look back and you say, 'Could we have done things that would have prevented it?'" he said.</p>

<p>The right-wing leader is Israel's longest-serving prime minister and has long billed himself as a staunch protector of Israel's security.</p>

<p>Shortly after the October 7 attack, Netanyahu posted on social media that intelligence services had failed to anticipate the Hamas operation and warn him.</p>

<p>He deleted and apologized for that post after numerous Israelis accused him of deflecting blame and jeopardizing national unity.</p>

<p>In the interview, Time asked Netanyahu what his message would be to a political rival who presided over the country's worst security failure.</p>

<p>Netanyahu replied that it depended on whether the leader could lead Israel "to victory."</p>

<p>"Can they assure that the postwar situation will be one of peace and security? If the answer is yes, they should stay in power."</p>

<p>Hamas on October 7 carried out the deadliest attack in Israel's history. A total of 1,198 people died, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,677 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/ap4d2k3o_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu has resisted making an apology for security failures over Israel's worst-ever attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-minister-suggests-starving-millions-in-gaza-sparks-global-outrage-6292847]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Minister Says Starving Millions In Gaza Is "Justified And Moral"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-minister-suggests-starving-millions-in-gaza-sparks-global-outrage-6292847]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 20:04:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich's suggestion that starving millions to death in Gaza was "justified and moral" has sparked global outrage. His comments, made during a speech last week, have been widely condemned by global powers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich's suggestion that starving millions to death in Gaza was "justified and moral" has sparked global outrage. His comments, made during a speech last week, have been widely condemned by global powers, including the European Union, the United Kingdom and France.</p>

<p>Smotrich remarked that halting aid to the besieged territory could be a means to "free the hostages".</p>

<p>"No one in the world will allow us to starve two million people, even though it might be justified and moral in order to free the hostages," the far-right minister said, as quoted by news agency AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The EU swiftly responded, labelling the deliberate starvation of civilians a "war crime" and demanding the Israeli government distance itself from the minister's words. They said the remarks showed "contempt for international law and for basic principles of humanity".</p>

<p>France expressed "deep dismay" and criticised the far-right minister, stating that providing humanitarian aid to Gaza is an "obligation under international humanitarian law" due to Israel's control over the territory's access, AFP reported.</p>

<p>Germany strongly denounced the remarks, calling them "completely unacceptable and outrageous". A spokesman for the Foreign Office in Berlin stated that civilians must be protected in war and have access to essential resources like water and food as it was a "basic principle" mandated by international humanitarian law.</p>

<p>UK Foreign Secretary David Lammy called on the Israeli government to "retract and condemn" the remarks, while in a separate development, the US State Department demanded a full investigation into allegations of sexual abuse against Palestinian detainees by Israeli soldiers. The allegations came to light following the release of a video on Israel's Channel 12, which appeared to show soldiers leading a detainee out of camera view to commit acts of abuse.</p>

<p>The video has intensified scrutiny of Israel's treatment of Palestinian detainees, with Israeli authorities launching an investigation into alleged abuse by soldiers. The investigation has already led to the arrest of nine soldiers, which led to protests from right-wing Israelis who stormed two military facilities in response.</p>

<p>Amid growing concerns, Israeli rights group B'Tselem has published a report stating the mistreatment of Palestinian prisoners had become so widespread that it amounted to a policy of "institutionalised abuse."</p>

<p>In May, International Criminal Court Chief Prosecutor Karim Khan announced plans to issue arrest warrants for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Defense Minister Yoav Gallant. The warrants are related to war crimes and crimes against humanity committed in Gaza. The devastating conflict, now nearing 10 months, has left vast areas of Gaza in ruins. A crippling blockade has severely limited access to essential resources like food, clean water, and medicine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel's war in Gaza has created a dire humanitarian crisis, displacing almost all 2.4 million residents, killing nearly 40,000 and injuring almost 1 lakh Palestinians. Israel faces accusations of genocide at the International Court of Justice, which has ordered an immediate halt to military operations in Rafah. The southern city had provided refuge for over 1 million Palestinians before being invaded and bombed in May.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/0vlg7p5_gaza-children_625x300_18_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video has intensified scrutiny of Israel's treatment of Palestinian detainees.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>