<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 15:57:39 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-embassy-thanks-india-for-first-tranche-of-2-5-million-for-refugees-6117451]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Palestine Embassy Thanks India For 1st Tranche Of $2.5 Million For Refugees]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-embassy-thanks-india-for-first-tranche-of-2-5-million-for-refugees-6117451]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 15:01:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Palestinian Embassy on Tuesday thanked India as it released the first tranche of USD 2.5 million to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) as a part of its annual contribution of USD 5 Million for the year 2024-2025.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Palestinian Embassy on Tuesday thanked India as it released the first tranche of USD 2.5 million to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) as a part of its annual contribution at USD 5 Million for the year 2024-2025.</p>

<p>The embassy said we extend our sincere thanks and appreciation to the Indian Government for releasing the first tranche of USD 2.5 million to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East as a part of its annual contribution at USD 5 Million for the year 2024-2025.</p>

<p>We also followed with great interest India's pledge of support to UNRWA during the UNRWA conference held in New York and announced that in addition to financial assistance, New Delhi will provide medicines to UNRWA upon request, it said.</p>

<p>This Indian assistance and this pledge an important step to support and strengthen the role of UNRWA in the face of attempts to target its role and existence by the Israeli government</p>

<p>While we appreciate the Indian contribution to UNRWA, we believe that this assistance, whether financial or medical, constitutes an important part of the assistance provided to the Palestinian people in various fields, which we look forward to increasing during the next stage due to the urgent need due to the Israeli war on Gaza, which has created a new and dangerous reality.</p>

<p>About 2.2 million Palestinians were residing in the Gaza Strip an area of 365 km2, representing about 41% of the population of Palestine. Most of this population (about 66%) are refugees, about 2 million Palestinians left their homes out of about 2.2 million Palestinians who were residing in the Gaza Strip on the eve of the Israeli occupation aggression, the statement said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA) is facing Israeli plans to target the body of the United Nations Foundation, which witnesses the case of more than 6 million Palestinian refugees and provides services to them in its five areas of operation (Gaza Strip, West Bank, Jordan, Syria and Lebanon).</p>

<p>We hope that India, through its bilateral relationship with the pillars of the international community and through its effective position in many important political and economic blocs and groupings around the world, will work to preserve UNRWA and strengthen its status and role, for which it was founded in 1949, and that Israeli attempts to replace it with other institutions will fail.</p>

<p>The importance of UNRWA for Palestinians goes beyond access to vital services, as they see its existence as linked to the preservation of their rights as refugees, especially their hope to return to their homes from which they or their ancestors were expelled during the Nakba.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j71u1lb8_gaza-july-2024-afp_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 2.2 million, or about 41% of the total population, of Palestinians were residing in the Gaza Strip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-reaffirms-continued-support-to-mauritius-in-its-quest-for-progress-6117387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Reaffirms Continued Support To Mauritius In Its Quest For Progress]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-reaffirms-continued-support-to-mauritius-in-its-quest-for-progress-6117387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:54:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Tuesday reaffirmed India's consistent and continued support to Mauritius in its quest for progress and prosperity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Tuesday reaffirmed India's consistent and continued support to Mauritius in its quest for progress and prosperity.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar is in Mauritius for a two-day visit for "productive engagements" with the leadership of Mauritius to take forward the special bilateral ties.</p>

<p>The visit to the Indian Ocean island nation marks one of the first bilateral engagements undertaken by Mr Jaishankar following his re-appointment in the third term of Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government.</p>

<p>"India's ties with Mauritius have blossomed into a robust and multifaceted partnership. The bilateral relation with Mauritius serves as a role model for India's successful development collaboration abroad," Mr Jaishankar said at an event attended by Mauritius Prime Minister Pravind Jugnauth.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Honored to call on PM <a href="https://twitter.com/KumarJugnauth?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KumarJugnauth</a> today in Port Louis. Conveyed the warm greetings of PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a>.<br />
<br />
Took stock of our special and enduring partnership and appreciated its further broadening.<br />
<br />
Looking forward to the continued collaboration and strengthening of ??-??… <a href="https://t.co/P9phPhhM9d">pic.twitter.com/P9phPhhM9d</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1813145870172348601?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The event saw the inauguration of 12 High Impact Community Development Projects that are funded by India, the exchange of MoUs on education, culture, digitisation of Immigration Archives and collaboration in the field of space and innovation.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar and Mr Jugnauth also handed over OCI cards to seventh-generation Indian-origin people in Mauritius.</p>

<p>The visit underscores the importance of the India-Mauritius relationship and is a reflection of India's 'Neighbourhood First Policy', Vision SAGAR, and commitment to the Global South.</p>

<p>According to the Indian High Commission at Mauritius website, India has close, long-standing relations with Mauritius, an island nation in the Western Indian Ocean, owing to historical, demographic and cultural reasons.</p>

<p>A key reason for the special ties is the fact that Indian-origin people comprise nearly 70 per cent of the island's population of 1.2 million, it added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1pm3125g_s-jaishankar-mauritius-president_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar is in Mauritius for a two-day visit for "productive engagements"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/kamala-harris-to-rishi-sunak-indians-must-be-realistic-about-the-rise-of-indian-origin-leaders-6117384]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Kamala Harris To Rishi Sunak, Indians Must Be Realistic About Indian-Origin Leaders Abroad]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/kamala-harris-to-rishi-sunak-indians-must-be-realistic-about-the-rise-of-indian-origin-leaders-6117384]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:54:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In case Biden withdraws from the US presidential race and Kamala Harris replaces him I am sure people in India, more particularly in Tamil Nadu, will feel proud. But do not expect any favours from her if she wins.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/onflnjc_indian-origin_625x300_16_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Donald Trump's defiant act of pumping his fist in the air, moments after his brush with death, could potentially sink President Joe Biden's chances of victory in the November election. Democrats may disagree, but it has certainly relegated Biden's age concerns to the background. At least for now. The 81-year-old President's mental and physical fitness issue is bound to resurface in the coming days and weeks, leading up to the Democratic Party Convention on August 19-22 in Chicago, when the party candidate will officially be announced.</p>

<p>If Biden, who has remained defiant so far, decides to withdraw from the race, a prominent alternative being considered is Vice-President Kamala Harris.</p>

<h2><strong>Harris and Her Indian Heritage</strong></h2>

<p>Harris, half Indian by heritage, has a familial connection to Thulasendrapuram in Tamil Nadu. Her family from her mother's side come from there. Her appointment in 2020 was celebrated with fireworks and prayers in India, with Prime Minister Narendra Modi calling it a "historic occasion" and expressing his eagerness to work with her to strengthen India-US relations.</p>

<p>Despite the initial excitement, it is clear that the strengthening of India-US relations under Biden's administration has been driven by the President's initiatives rather than Harris's Indian heritage. While Harris often speaks about her Indian roots, her policies and actions are primarily shaped by the strategic interests of the United States, not India.</p>

<h2><strong>The Political Strategy of Indian-Origin Politicians</strong></h2>

<p>A few Indian-origin politicians in the US, such as Nikki Haley and Bobby Jindal, tend to downplay their Indian heritage to appeal to broader voter bases, which can be seen as a political strategy.&nbsp;<br />
In the UK, Indian-origin politicians like Priti Patel and Suella Braverman, despite their immigrant backgrounds, have adopted strict anti-immigrant stances, aligning with conservative values to secure support within their parties.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak's appointment as the UK Prime Minister in 2022 sparked significant excitement among Indians. I met jubilant members of the Indian community in Southampton, Sunak's hometown, who felt immense pride. However, their enthusiasm later dampened as they realised that Sunak's policies were driven by the priorities of the UK, not his Indian heritage. He turned out to be just another politician who was co-opted by the establishment, they felt.</p>

<h2><strong>Symbolism vs. Substance</strong></h2>

<p>The celebrations over Indian-origin politicians achieving high office in Western countries often overlook the reality that these leaders primarily serve the interests of their respective countries. For instance, Sunak's policies were guided by national interests rather than ethnic connections, as evidenced by the stalled Free Trade Agreement (FTA) talks between the UK and India.</p>

<p>Similar cases include Antonio Costa and Leo Varadkar, former Prime Ministers of Portugal and Ireland, respectively, whose political actions did not necessarily favour India. Costa, with Goan roots, and Varadkar, with Maharashtrian heritage, focused on their countries' priorities, not their ancestral ties.</p>

<p>For the Indian diaspora, the rise of leaders like Sunak, Harris, Costa, and Varadkar is a source of inspiration and pride, demonstrating that individuals of Indian descent can achieve the highest political offices in foreign lands. However, the tangible benefits for the diaspora are limited. For example, the Indian community in Southampton has become divided over whether Sunak's premiership has provided any real advantages.</p>

<h2><strong>Starmer's Cabinet And Lack Of Diversity&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>In the recent UK elections, a record 26 MPs of Indian origin were elected, with 19 from Labour, including 12 Sikhs and six female Sikh MPs. Despite this representation, the Indian community was disappointed that only one half-Indian MP received a senior ministerial position in Prime Minister Keir Starmer's cabinet. This cabinet appears predominantly white, a stark contrast to Boris Johnson's diverse 2019 cabinet.</p>

<p>The Biden administration has appointed around 130 Indian-Americans to key positions, reflecting the growing influence and integration of Indian-Americans in US politics. While these appointments are a source of pride and potentially facilitate stronger India-US relations, the primary allegiance of these officials is to the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Indian diaspora is indeed an influential group in many countries, which can be leveraged to India's advantage. That explains why diaspora outreach is one of PM Modi's key foreign policy priorities.&nbsp;<br />
The Modi government has also been advocating for more representations for India at influential global institutions, such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the World Bank, and important United Nations (UN) bodies. If we have more Indians or Indian-origin people in key positions in these institutions, it will surely bring more prestige and power to India.</p>

<h2><strong>Indian-Origin CEOs in Global IT Firms</strong></h2>

<p>Apart from politics, Indian-origin CEOs of global IT firms, such as Sundar Pichai of Google and Satya Nadella of Microsoft, bring indirect benefits to India. They foster stronger business ties, create job opportunities, invest in Indian startups, and promote technology and education initiatives. Their success elevates India's global standing in the tech world.</p>

<p>There is no doubt that the achievements of Indian-origin politicians and business leaders in Western countries or anywhere else are commendable and a source of pride, but it is important to maintain a realistic perspective on their impact. Their primary duty is to serve the interests of their respective countries, and their policies are shaped by the political and strategic priorities of those nations. The symbolic importance of their success does not necessarily translate into tangible benefits for India or the Indian diaspora.&nbsp;</p>

<p>So, in case Biden withdraws from the race and Kamala Harris replaces him I am sure people in India, more particularly in Tamil Nadu, will feel proud. But do not expect any favours from her if she wins. If Trump comes back to power we are bound to remember neither President Biden nor Kamala Harris.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qcqmeks_indian-origin_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-dials-down-attacks-on-donald-trump-after-rally-shooting-6117217]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Dials Down Attacks On Donald Trump After Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-dials-down-attacks-on-donald-trump-after-rally-shooting-6117217]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:31:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The assassination attempt on Donald Trump has forced Joe Biden's campaign to dial down its attacks for now, with the US president admitting he was wrong to say his rival should be put in the "bullseye."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The assassination attempt on Donald Trump has forced Joe Biden's campaign to dial down its attacks for now, with the US president admitting he was wrong to say his rival should be put in the "bullseye."</p>

<p>But Biden has more broadly defended his rhetoric describing his Republican predecessor as a threat to democracy, and is signaling he will not hold back for long while criticizing the man he beat in 2020.</p>

<p>When Biden urged Americans to "lower the temperature" in a rare Oval Office speech on Sunday after the Trump shooting, it seemed it could deprive him of his core attack line.</p>

<p>Just last week the 81-year-old had tried to pivot his campaign back on to his Republican rival, following weeks of turmoil in the Democratic Party over his age and health after a disastrous debate performance.</p>

<p>In the light of the Trump attack, Biden told broadcaster NBC on Monday that was a "mistake" to say in a call with donors a week ago that it was "time to put Trump in the bullseye."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Democrat said he had meant that the party should "focus on what he's doing" instead of calling him to quit after the debate.</p>

<p>Republicans have pointed to the bullseye comment in particular as they accuse Biden himself of creating the political conditions that led a shooter to try to kill Trump -- ignoring their own candidate's history of encouraging violence.</p>

<p>But while Biden's campaign has toned down its language in the immediate aftermath of the shooting, Biden himself hinted that he would not hold back.</p>

<p>"How do you talk about the threat to democracy, which is real, when a president says things like he says. Do you just not say anything because it may incite somebody?" he told NBC.</p>

<p>"I have not engaged in that rhetoric. Now my opponent has engaged in that rhetoric, he talks about how there'll be a bloodbath when he loses."</p>

<p>He also slammed Trump for pledging to pardon those involved in the January 6, 2021 Capitol attack by pro-Trump supporters and for joking about former US House speaker Nancy Pelosi's husband being attacked with a hammer.</p>

<h3><strong>'Changes the calculus'</strong></h3>

<p>Facing repeated questions over Biden's comment at a White House briefing, Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said it was "OK to speak to someone's record, speak to someone's character."</p>

<p>Despite canceling a trip to Texas on Monday, Biden is continuing with a planned visit to the battleground state of Nevada, setting up a split-screen with Trump's convention appearances.</p>

<p>In an opinion piece in the Washington Post, political columnist Karen Tumulty wrote that there could "hardly be a worse moment for Biden to be compelled to redraw his strategy against Trump."</p>

<p>The Trump shooting could, however, help Biden as he fights for his own political survival.</p>

<p>"Obviously this changes the calculus for people calling for Biden to stand down," Peter Loge, a political scientist at George Washington University, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It buys Biden some time."</p>

<p>The Democratic meltdown over Biden's age following the debate had dominated the airwaves for weeks, but with the gunshots on Saturday the revolt over his candidacy fell abruptly silent.</p>

<p>Biden has also sought to strike a presidential tone over the shooting, coming out quickly to react on Saturday and addressing the nation Sunday in just the third Oval Office speech of his presidency.</p>

<p>But if the shooting could unify Democrats, it could also doom Biden's reelection bid, with the president already behind in most polls.</p>

<p>Iconic images of a bloodied Trump waving his fist after the shooting are already galvanizing Republican hopes that voters will further rally behind him for a landslide victory in November.</p>

<p>Loge, however, said there may be little effect as "a lot of voters see Trump as too nuts and Biden as too old, and an assassination attempt doesn't change that."</p>

<p>He added that focusing on the immediate impact of the shooting on the campaigns was the "wrong question" and missed the wider need to tackle the threats and violence plaguing US politics.</p>

<p>"If we make political violence part of a campaign strategy we miss the point of political violence, and we end up kind of normalizing it," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/m1g4332_joe-biden-donald-trump_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump rally shooting could, however, help Biden as he fights for his own political survival]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-might-not-be-backed-by-key-labour-union-teamsters-in-us-this-time-6117205]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Might Not Be Backed By Key Labour Union Teamsters In US This Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-might-not-be-backed-by-key-labour-union-teamsters-in-us-this-time-6117205]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:30:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden is on the brink of failing to win a key labor endorsement as leaders of the 1.3 million-member Teamsters union consider backing no candidate at all in the US presidential race, according to two people familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden is on the brink of failing to win a key labor endorsement as leaders of the 1.3 million-member Teamsters union consider backing no candidate at all in the US presidential race, according to two people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The International Brotherhood of Teamsters decision has not been finalized and is expected to be made in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>Not backing Biden, who the union endorsed in 2020, would compound political damage to the Democratic president's reelection bid.</p>

<p>A Teamsters endorsement for Republican candidate Donald Trump appears unlikely, sources say, but deep internal divisions mean the union may not back any candidate at all. That would mark the first time since 1996, according to news reports.</p>

<p>Since his halting performance in a presidential debate on June 27, Biden has already seen a number of lawmakers and donors ask him to stand aside, worried about his ability to get reelected and to serve another four-year term. Some allies say they believe Saturday's Trump assassination attempt could quiet those calls, but other Democrats doubt that.</p>

<p>Biden's team once viewed the Teamsters endorsement as all but inevitable and still counts a number of senior leaders there as supporters. But months of deteriorating relations and rising concerns about Biden's political endurance have soured sentiment among some of the leaders at the union, which represents workers in fields ranging from trucking to manufacturing and office work.</p>

<p>"No final decision has been made," said Kara Deniz, a spokesperson for the Teamsters, adding that any reporting that suggests an outcome is speculative.</p>

<p>Teamsters President Sean O'Brien spoke at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee on Monday night, where he offered no endorsement but thanked Trump profusely for opening the convention doors to him. He praised the former president as tough and attacked Washington as being run in a way that hurts working people.</p>

<p>He also praised Trump's running mate JD Vance as one of several lawmakers that "truly care about working people."</p>

<p>"We are not beholden to anyone or any party," O'Brien said on stage, as Trump watched.</p>

<p>"The Teamsters are not interested if you have a 'D,' 'R' or an 'I' next your name. We want to know one thing: what are you doing to help American workers?"</p>

<p>O'Brien is not yet scheduled to speak at the Democratic convention in August.</p>

<p>The Teamsters leader had reached out simultaneously to the Democratic and Republican national committees to speak at their conventions but only heard back from Republicans, Deniz told Reuters.</p>

<p>A person familiar with the planning of the Democratic convention said no final decisions had been made about their programming.</p>

<p>"We are building a convention in Chicago that will tell our story to the American people, including the stories of labor and union leaders and workers that President Biden has been delivering for as the most pro-union president in modern history," said convention spokesperson Matt Hill.</p>

<h3><strong>BIDEN, CLINTON, OBAMA</strong></h3>

<p>The Teamsters, founded in 1903, endorsed Biden in 2020, as well as Democrats Hillary Clinton in 2016 and Barack Obama in 2008 and 2012, though they have sometimes picked Republicans in earlier elections.</p>

<p>The group's frustrations with Biden's team have mounted in recent months. On one key priority, rescuing trucking giant Yellow Corp and its 30,000 union jobs from bankruptcy, O'Brien sought and was denied an Oval Office meeting to discuss the issue with Biden, according to one of the people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The White House did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Those frustrations were compounded as some Democratic lawmakers and donors have since the debate called for Biden to drop his reelection bid and open the door for another candidate, another person familiar with the union's deliberations said.</p>

<p>Last week, United Auto Workers President Shawn Fain met with that union's executive board to discuss his concerns over Biden's ability to defeat Trump.</p>

<p>Working-class groups helped power Biden's 2020 election victory in closely contested states such as Michigan, Pennsylvania and Nevada.</p>

<p>Union groups encourage their members to vote, volunteer and donate to campaigns, and they form a particularly important source of cash and labor for Democratic presidential campaigns.</p>

<p>In return, they expect policies that increase union jobs, wages and make it easier to collectively bargain contracts with employers. Biden's gestures have included a $36 billion bailout of a union pension fund that prevented cuts to the income of over 350,000 Teamsters union workers and retirees.</p>

<p>Across many unions, rank-and-file workers are more divided about Democrats than their leadership, and Trump has actively courted workers' support.</p>

<p>The Teamsters held roundtables with Trump and Biden this year and hosted some 300 local events with workers to gauge their opinions on the race.</p>

<p>Charles Lutvak, a Biden campaign spokesperson, said the campaign had drawn vast union support reflecting Biden's "record of delivering results for working families while Donald Trump delivers for his wealthy donors and himself."</p>

<p>He said Biden is "a champion for working people over greedy corporations - whether they vote for him or not."</p>

<p>O'Brien has said the union would conduct polling and likely make a decision on an endorsement after the parties' conventions have concluded next month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opt29ctk_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The International Brotherhood of Teamsters had backed Joe Biden back in 2020. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-womans-suspicious-behaviour-during-trump-rally-shooting-is-viral-6116928]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Woman's "Suspicious" Behaviour During Trump Rally Shooting Is Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-womans-suspicious-behaviour-during-trump-rally-shooting-is-viral-6116928]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 13:51:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump narrowly escaped an assassination attempt at a campaign rally on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump narrowly escaped an assassination attempt at a campaign rally on Saturday.&nbsp;The 78-year-old Republican had just started his speech during at the event in Butler, Pennsylvania when the shots rang out and one of the bullets grazed his ear.</p>

<p>A video is now going viral that shows a woman sitting right behind Donald Trump acting strange -&nbsp; moments after the shooting.</p>

<p>The video shows the woman - wearing sunglasses, a white shirt and a black hat - ducking and pulling out her phone as the shots rang out.</p>

<p>One user also pointed out that she was looking in the direction of the snipers.</p>

<p>The viral video has added fuel to several conspiracy theories doing rounds on social media following the shooting incident.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This video of a woman located behind Donald Trump during his attempted assassination is HIGHLY suspicious.<br />
<br />
Her body language &amp; behavior seem to indicate she knew that something was coming. <a href="https://t.co/L4sEHArSrA">pic.twitter.com/L4sEHArSrA</a></p>
— Dominic Michael Tripi (@DMichaelTripi) <a href="https://twitter.com/DMichaelTripi/status/1812659285039501385?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>Several people on social media called her behaviour "highly suspicious, while others opined it could be a "harmless coincidence".</p>

<p>A moment of terrifying political violence at the rally instantly turned into a piece of Donald Trump iconography that's likely to turbocharge his presidential bid.</p>

<p>Images of a defiant Trump - with his fist raised over his head and his bloody right ear, as Secret Service agents surround him and the American flag waving in the background - are blazing across social media and television.</p>

<p>Applause and cheering spread through the grounds as Trump, clearly dazed, pumped his fist and waved through the linked arms of his security detail at the stunned crowd.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8od8vok_donald-trump_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump Rally Shooting: The video has added fuel to several conspiracy theories]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-denies-pledging-45-million-a-month-for-trump-election-6116809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Denies Pledging $45 Million A Month For Trump Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-denies-pledging-45-million-a-month-for-trump-election-6116809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 13:35:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla CEO Elon Musk has rejected a report claiming that he plans to give $45 million a month to a new super political-action committee (PAC) supporting former US President Donald Trump's presidential run, calling it "fake."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk has rejected a report claiming that he plans to give $45 million a month to a new super political-action committee (PAC) supporting former US President Donald Trump's presidential run, calling it "fake."<br />
<br />
In a sarcastic post on X, Elon Musk posted a picture of two gnus (wildebeest) having human limbs and captioned it, "Fake GNUS." He even shared The Wall Street Journal's report on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="qme"><a href="https://t.co/RJdF7MWeEi">pic.twitter.com/RJdF7MWeEi</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1813097084595163643?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>His statement comes after The Wall Street Journal, citing people familiar with the matter, reported that Musk plans to give USD 45 million a month to a new super political-action committee supporting Trump's presidential run.</p>

<p>America PAC, formed in June, is focused on registering voters and urging constituents to vote early and request mail-in ballots in swing states, according to one of the people.</p>

<p>The coalition assessed that the Democrats have historically had very robust "get out the vote" campaigns and took note of the money that the Biden camp has dedicated to so-called on-the-ground efforts in swing states. America PAC will attempt to counter that, according to The Wall Street Journal Street.</p>

<p>Currently, Musk is the world's richest person, with an estimated fortune of more than USD 250 billion. For its efforts, America PAC has hired a number of employees and has been registering voters, holding discussions with constituents in swing states and urging voters to request mail-in ballots, according to some of the people familiar with the matter, the report said.</p>

<p>According to a filing made on Monday, America PAC had USD 8.75 million in contributions for the three-month duration, which ended on June 30, The Wall Street Journal stated.</p>

<p>Earlier in March, Elon Musk, in a post on X, said that he did not intend to make donations to the campaigns of Trump or US President Joe Biden. However, the Tesla CEO has gotten closer to Donald Trump in recent months, The Wall Street Journal reported.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Musk formally announced support for Trump after a shooter tried to assassinate the former US President at a rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Musk stated, "I fully endorse President Trump and hope for his rapid recovery." In a subsequent post, he stated, "Last time America had a candidate this tough was Theodore Roosevelt."</p>

<p>Trump was on stage at a campaign rally on Saturday when gunshots rang out and Secret Service agents stormed the stage.</p>

<p>Hours after the shooting, Trump said that the bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear. In addition, one of the rally attendee was killed and two others were injured in the shooting at the event.</p>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) identified the gunman as Thomas Matthew Crooks, 20, from Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, with the case continuing to be under investigation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8trrs42_elon-musk_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Saturday, Elon Musk formally announced support for Trump for US president]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-trump-biden-dialled-widow-of-rally-shooting-victim-she-didnt-pick-up-6116808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Not Trump, Biden Dialled Widow Of Rally Shooting Victim. She Didn't Pick Up]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-trump-biden-dialled-widow-of-rally-shooting-victim-she-didnt-pick-up-6116808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 13:34:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The wife of the firefighter, who was killed during an attack at a Donald Trump rally, received a call from President Joe Biden after the tragedy struck her family on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The wife of the firefighter, who was killed during an attack at a Donald Trump rally, received a call from President Joe Biden after the tragedy struck her family on Saturday. Helen Comperatore, however, did not talk to Biden and said Trump hadn't reached out, reported New York Post.</p>

<p>"I didn't talk to Biden. I didn't want to talk to him. My husband was a devout Republican and he would not have wanted me to talk to him," said Corey Comperatore's wife.</p>

<p>Corey, father of two children, was shot by a sniper's bullet during the assassination attempt on Trump during a rally in Pennsylvania. Trump survived the attack but a bullet pierced his right ear. He was seen with a bloodied face with his fist in the air as the Secret Service agents bundled him to safety.</p>

<p>When the shots were heard, Corey shouted "Get down" and shielded his family from the bullets with his body. He died while two other rallygoers were wounded in the chaos.</p>

<p>His wife, Helen, said though Trump hadn't contacted her, Biden's call wasn't welcome.</p>

<p>"I don't have any ill will towards Joe Biden. I'm not one of those people that gets involved in politics. I support Trump. That's who I'm voting for, but I don't have ill will towards Biden. He didn't do anything bad to my husband. A 20-year-old despicable kid did," she said.</p>

<p>The gunman who targeted Trump was identified as Thomas Mathew Crooks, a 20-year-old. He was shot dead by snipers on the spot. The FBI, which is probing the assassination bid, is still trying to find motive behind the attack.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b5q03l7g_corey-comperatore_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Helen said though Trump hadn't contacted her, Biden's call wasn't welcome. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-used-us-bombs-in-strike-on-gazas-safe-zone-that-killed-92-6116696]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Used US Bombs In Strike On Gaza's "Safe Zone" That Killed 92]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-used-us-bombs-in-strike-on-gazas-safe-zone-that-killed-92-6116696]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 13:17:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's deadly strike on Al-Mawasi, one of the bloodiest attacks in more than nine months of the war in Gaza, used massive payload bombs provided by the United States, according to weapons experts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's deadly strike on Al-Mawasi, one of the bloodiest attacks in more than nine months of the war in Gaza, used massive payload bombs provided by the United States, according to weapons experts.</p>

<p>The bombing of the Israeli-declared "safe zone" transformed the tent city on the Mediterranean coast into a charred wasteland, with nearby hospitals overrun with casualties.</p>

<p>According to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, the barrage killed at least 92 people and wounded more than 300.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it targeted two "masterminds" of the October 7 attacks by Hamas that triggered the war. It said a top commander, Rafa Salama, was killed in the strike, but uncertainty remains over Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>AFP videos of the attack showed a white mushroom cloud billowing over a busy street, leaving behind a huge crater strewn with the wreckage of tents and a building blown to bits.</p>

<p>Here is what we know about the weaponry used in the attack:</p>

<h3><strong>US-made JDAM&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Two weapons experts told AFP that a sliver of munition seen in a video of the blast site circulating online was a tail fin from a US-made Joint Direct Attack Munition (JDAM). AFP could not independently verify the video.</p>

<p>The GPS-aided kit converts unguided free-fall bombs -- so-called "dumb bombs" -- into precision-guided "smart" munitions that can be directed towards single or multiple targets.</p>

<p>The United States developed the kit to improve accuracy in adverse weather after Operation Desert Storm in 1991.</p>

<p>The first JDAMs were delivered in 1997 and, according to the US Air Force, have a 95 percent system reliability.</p>

<p>Trevor Ball, a former US Army explosive ordnance disposal technician, concluded from images of the Al-Mawasi strike "it's 100 percent a JDAM kit" made in the United States.</p>

<p>He said that given the types of bombs compatible with the guidance system and the size of the fin fragment, the JDAM was most likely used with either a 1,000 or 2,000 pound (450 or 900 kilogramme) payload.</p>

<p>He said the fragment could also be compatible with the BLU-109 "bunker buster" warhead, which is designed to penetrate concrete.</p>

<p>Ball said it was not possible to definitively determine where the payload itself was made without "very specific fragments of the bomb body".</p>

<h3><strong>New delivery&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Repeated use of such large bombs in the densely populated Gaza Strip has sparked humanitarian outcry and heaped pressure on US President Joe Biden to reconsider the munitions supplied to Israel.</p>

<p>On July 12, Israel's main military backer announced it was ending a pause on supplying 500-pound bombs, though Biden said the 2,000-pound type would be withheld.</p>

<p>The White House has repeatedly voiced frustration over the civilian casualties in Gaza as Israel attempts to eradicate Hamas.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken told two top Israeli officials on Monday that the civilian casualties was "unacceptably high", his spokesman said.</p>

<p>Israeli officials said their "precise strike" in Al-Mawasi hit an open area that housed a Hamas compound and not a civilian camp.</p>

<p>When contacted by AFP regarding the weapons used, the Israeli military declined to comment.</p>

<p>Based on Israel's stated target, Wes Bryant, a retired US Air Force master sergeant and strike and joint targeting expert, said it would have been feasible to avoid collateral damage in the surrounding area.</p>

<p>"My assessment is that any civilians killed in this strike were in the compound -- not in the surrounding vicinity. So the IDF either failed to assess presence of civilians, or... deemed the risk to civilians proportional to the military advantage of taking out the Hamas leaders."</p>

<h3><strong>'Absolute destruction'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The strike left Al-Mawasi a scene of "absolute destruction" with no water, electricity or sewage treatment, the Islamic Relief charity said.</p>

<p>It condemned Israel for its willingness "to kill innocent men, women and children in pursuit of its end goals".</p>

<p>Hamas said that by arming Israel, the Biden administration is "legally and morally responsible" for spawning a "major humanitarian catastrophe".</p>

<p>It said US-supplied weapons used by Israel included GPS-guided bombs, dumb bombs, bunker busters and JDAMs.</p>

<p>After repeated high-casualty strikes in recent days, a Hamas official said the group was withdrawing from indirect talks for a truce and hostage release deal with Israel.</p>

<p>The war was sparked by Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel responded with a military offensive that has killed at least 38,664 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to the Hamas-ruled territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/11me6u6g_israel-bombing-afp_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bombing of the Israeli-declared "safe zone" transformed the tent city into a charred wasteland.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-service-faces-backlash-for-security-lapse-over-donald-trump-rally-shooting-6116690]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secret Service Faces Backlash For Security Lapse Over Trump Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-service-faces-backlash-for-security-lapse-over-donald-trump-rally-shooting-6116690]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 13:17:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facing growing criticism over a massive security failure, the US Secret Service on Monday vowed to cooperate with an independent review after a shooter was allowed to open fire on Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facing growing criticism over a massive security failure, the US Secret Service on Monday vowed to cooperate with an independent review after a shooter was allowed to open fire on Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old former president was injured but survived an assassination attempt at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday, a brazen attack that shocked a nation already deeply polarized ahead of the November election.</p>

<p>"The Secret Service is working with all involved federal, state and local agencies to understand what happened, how it happened, and how we can prevent an incident like this from ever taking place again," the agency's director Kimberly Cheatle said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We understand the importance of the independent review announced by President (Joe) Biden yesterday and will participate fully," Cheatle added.</p>

<p>Trump was speaking at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, when multiple bangs rang out.</p>

<p>He clutched his ear, with blood visible on his ear and cheek, then ducked to the floor as Secret Service agents swarmed onto the podium, surrounding him and rushing him to a nearby vehicle.</p>

<p>The shooter and a bystander were killed, and two spectators were injured.</p>

<p>Newly surfaced video backs up reports from witnesses that they had called out to police and physically pointed at the shooter as he lay on the roof preparing to open fire, the Washington Post reported Monday.</p>

<p>The shots targeting Trump rang out 86 seconds after the first audible attempts to warn the police, the Post said, citing an analysis it did of video clips from the scene of the attack.</p>

<p>Biden ordered a full review of the security at the rally, as well as at this week's Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, where Trump will be crowned the party's presidential nominee.</p>

<p>In an interview with NBC on Monday, the president said he feels "safe with the Secret Service," though he added it was an "open question" whether they should have better anticipated the shooting at the Trump rally.</p>

<p>Biden has also ordered Secret Service protection for independent candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr., an environmental lawyer and long-time vaccine skeptic who has no chance of winning in November, but whose candidacy could potentially sway close contests in key swing states.</p>

<h3><strong>Heightened risk&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Secret Service faces intense scrutiny over how a gunman aiming an assault rifle was able to take position on a roof some 500 feet (150 meters) from one of the most protected political figures on the planet.</p>

<p>With Trump set to star at the convention, Cheatle said the agency was working to toughen security.</p>

<p>The Secret Service designs plans for major events "to respond to a kinetic security environment and the most up-to-date intelligence," her statement said.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Trump had called for Secret Service protection for Kennedy "in light of what is going on in the world today."</p>

<p>"Given the history of the Kennedy Family, this is the obvious right thing to do!" Trump wrote on his Truth Social website.</p>

<p>Kennedy's uncle, President John F. Kennedy, was assassinated in Dallas, Texas in 1963. Five years later, the candidate's father, Robert, was shot to death in Los Angeles while on the campaign trail.</p>

<p>The US Secret Service is responsible for the safety of the president, vice president and former presidents, and their families, as well as major election candidates and visiting foreign heads of state.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/t8vi6jio_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump was speaking at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, when multiple bangs rang out. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-riding-wave-of-wins-after-struggling-to-stay-afloat-6116553]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Riding Wave Of Wins After Struggling To Stay Afloat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-riding-wave-of-wins-after-struggling-to-stay-afloat-6116553]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:57:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After dodging a bullet at a rally and seeing the US Supreme Court bolster his presidential immunity claims this month, Donald Trump was handed another gift Monday: the dismissal of his classified documents case.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After dodging a bullet at a rally and seeing the US Supreme Court bolster his presidential immunity claims this month, Donald Trump was handed another gift Monday: the dismissal of his classified documents case.</p>

<p>As the only president ever to be twice impeached -- and twice acquitted -- and the country's only ex-president convicted of criminal charges, the septuagenarian has often struggled to stay afloat.</p>

<p>His blunders, multitude of scandals and vitriolic statements have shocked millions of Americans. Many heads of state see him as a danger to global stability and the fight against global warming, and he has stood accused of indulging far-right groups and disparaging immigrants.</p>

<p>But each time he is said to be sunk, he roars back to the surface, and this week he is heading into Milwaukee riding very high.</p>

<p>On Thursday, the Republican National Convention will overlook Trump's vows of vengeance against his political enemies and swat aside his various legal woes to formally nominate him as the party's flagbearer going into the November election against President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Trump, the brash billionaire who burst onto the political landscape a decade ago as a super disruptor and champion of conservatives, appears unstoppable.</p>

<p>"It sure seems he's on a roll," Texas alternate delegate Orlando Dona, wearing Trump pins and a straw-colored cowboy hat, told AFP.</p>

<p>The 64-year-old Dona, like many conservatives, believes the various cases against Trump have been politically motivated, "and he is coming out of all this justified."</p>

<p>As for the shooting, some are chalking it up to divine intervention.</p>

<p>"I personally think it was the hand of God," Wisconsin former governor Scott Walker told AFP at the convention.</p>

<p>Walker, who ran for president against Trump briefly in 2016, said Trump the man has earned a reputation for taking on anything.</p>

<p>"He's never going to stop being a fighter," he said. "And I think people here realize he's fighting for them, and these wins are not just about wins for him, they're wins for the American people."</p>

<p>'A lot of obstacles'</p>

<p>Trump earned the nickname "Teflon Don" for weathering a multitude of storms.</p>

<p>The #MeToo movement precipitated the downfall of dozens of powerful Americans. Not Trump, despite multiple accusations of sexual abuse, a 2023 civil trial finding of liability for the sexual assault of writer E. Jean Carroll, and an alleged affair with pornographic actress Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>After an explosive "Access Hollywood" tape emerged in 2016 in which Trump makes degrading remarks about women and boasted about groping their genitals, some Republican heavyweights withdrew their support, and he was predicted to lose the female vote.</p>

<p>That collapse didn't happen, and he won the White House a month later.</p>

<p>Now, it appears he will pull off another miracle, avoiding three of the four lawsuits he had been facing before the election.</p>

<p>"If the story of even the last 18 months teaches us anything, there were a lot of obstacles that were put up to president Trump, and the fact that he's gotten through them shows, I think, part of what gives me faith in this country," businessman and former 2024 Vivek Ramaswamy told reporters at the convention.</p>

<p>"As Martin Luther King said, the arc of history is long but it bends towards justice," Mr Ramaswamy said. "I believe that's exactly what it is doing in recent months, days, and over the last year of president Trump's journey as well."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8nt2pmuo_trump96_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Each time he is said to be sunk, Trump roars back to the surface. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-congratulates-jd-vance-on-his-vice-president-pick-by-trump-6116554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Congratulates JD Vance For Being Trump's Vice President Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-congratulates-jd-vance-on-his-vice-president-pick-by-trump-6116554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:57:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris left a congratulatory voicemail to GOP Ohio Senator JD Vance on Monday after he was announced as the Republican vice presidential pick on Truth Social by former President Donald Trump, The New York Post reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris left a congratulatory voicemail to GOP Ohio Senator JD Vance on Monday after he was announced as the Republican vice presidential pick on Truth Social by former President Donald Trump, The New York Post reported.</p>

<p>In her message, Ms Harris expressed her congratulations and said that "she hoped to see [Vance] at the CBS News debate," as confirmed by a Biden-Harris campaign official.</p>

<p>While the Biden campaign has agreed to a vice presidential debate hosted by CBS News, the Trump camp has been advocating for a Fox News debate instead.</p>

<p>During their convention in Milwaukee, Republican National Committee delegates unanimously nominated Mr Vance as the official GOP vice presidential candidate.</p>

<p>CNN reported that Ms Harris "welcomed him to the race," and congratulated Mr Vance on his selection.</p>

<p>If elected alongside Trump, Mr Vance would become the second youngest vice president in American history, as reported by The New York Post.</p>

<p>"After lengthy deliberation and thought, and considering the tremendous talents of many others, I have decided that the person best suited to assume the position of Vice President of the United States is Senator JD Vance of the Great State of Ohio," Trump wrote on Truth Social.</p>

<p>"JD honourably served our Country in the Marine Corps, graduated from Ohio State University in two years, Summa Cum Laude, and is a Yale Law School Graduate, where he was Editor of The Yale Law Journal, and President of the Yale Law Veterans Association.</p>

<p>"JD's book, 'Hillbilly Elegy,' became a Major Best Seller and Movie, as it championed the hardworking men and women of our Country," the former president wrote.</p>

<p>"JD has had a very successful business career in Technology and Finance, and now, during the Campaign, will be strongly focused on the people he fought so brilliantly for, the American Workers and Farmers in Pennsylvania, Michigan, Wisconsin, Ohio, Minnesota, and far beyond," his post added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c69vc5t_kamala-harris-jd-vance-afp_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In her message, Kamala Harris expressed her congratulations to JD Vance.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-was-called-american-hitler-by-his-running-mate-jd-vance-list-of-criticism-6116500]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Shocking Comments Trump's Running Mate Once Made On Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-was-called-american-hitler-by-his-running-mate-jd-vance-list-of-criticism-6116500]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:48:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican JD Vance, picked by Donald Trump as his running mate for the US elections, has been kind to the former president in the past. A harsh critic in the past, the Ohio Senator had called Trump a "moral disaster" and "America's Hitler".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican JD Vance, picked by Donald Trump as his running mate for the US elections, has been kind to the former president in the past. A harsh critic in the past, the Ohio Senator had called Trump a "moral disaster" and "America's Hitler".</p>

<p>But now a Vice-Presidential nominee, he finds himself "overwhelmed with gratitude" to be running alongside Trump. "What an honour...he delivered peace and prosperity once, and with your help, he'll do it again," said a confident Vance on X.</p>

<p>A White House candidate usually picks a running mate who can appeal to new voters or compensate for weaknesses in image or policy - though Trump has picked a white conservative like himself.</p>

<p>In a 2016 message to a former law school roommate, Vance had said he went "back and forth between thinking Trump is a cynical as***le like Nixon who wouldn't be that bad (and might even prove useful) or that he's America's Hitler," Washington Post reported.</p>

<p>Josh Mclaurin, the roommate, had shared the message on social media in 2022 when Vance was contesting the Senate race.</p>

<p>Vance had also called Trump a "cultural heroin" and a "new pain reliever" - who promised easy solutions to social problems of suffering communities, but "could not fix what ails them".</p>

<p>"Trump's promises are the needle in America's collective vein... Trump is cultural heroin. He makes some feel better for a bit. But he cannot fix what ails them, and one day they'll realize it," he had written in a 2016 piece for the Atlantic Magazine.</p>

<p>He had also said he "can't stomach Trump" in a 2016 interview.</p>

<p>"I think that he's noxious and is leading the White working class to a very dark place," he told NPR's Terry Gross.</p>

<p>Vance had lamented Trump's video of bragging about groping women. His now-deleted online post read: "Fellow Christians, everyone is watching us when we apologize for this man. Lord help us."</p>

<p>Another post, which too stands deleted, called Trump "reprehensible". "Trump makes people I care about afraid. Immigrants, Muslims, etc. Because of this, I find him reprehensible. God wants better of us," the post read.</p>

<p>Vance had even admitted he was "never Trump guy" and never liked Trump, in an interview with Charlie Rose.</p>

<p>He had also called the then-president a "moral disaster" and "just another opioid", and agreed in public that Trump was a "total fraud" who didn't care about the people.</p>

<p>The list runs long.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/it4ekqog_jd-vance-donald-trump_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-an-honor-jd-vance-after-being-declared-donald-trumps-vice-president-pick-6116429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["What An Honor": JD Vance After Being Declared Trump's Vice President Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-an-honor-jd-vance-after-being-declared-donald-trumps-vice-president-pick-6116429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:36:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[JD Vance, a Republican US Senator from Ohio, expressed gratitude on Tuesday for being picked as the running mate of US presidential candidate Donald Trump and called it an "honour" to run alongside him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>JD Vance, a Republican US Senator from Ohio, expressed gratitude on Tuesday for being picked as the running mate of US presidential candidate Donald Trump and called it an "honour" to run alongside him. He said that Trump has delivered it once and will do it again.</p>

<p>In a post on X, JD Vance stated, "Just overwhelmed with gratitude. What an honor it is to run alongside President Donald J. Trump. He delivered peace and prosperity once, and with your help, he'll do it again. Onward to victory!"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Just overwhelmed with gratitude.<br />
<br />
What an honor it is to run alongside President Donald J. Trump. He delivered peace and prosperity once, and with your help, he'll do it again.<br />
<br />
Onward to victory!</p>
— J.D. Vance (@JDVance1) <a href="https://twitter.com/JDVance1/status/1813062451853738415?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>His statement comes after former US President Donald Trump made his pick for Vice President, selecting JD Vance as his running mate on Monday. Trump confirmed Vance's candidature through a post on Truth Social.</p>

<p>"After lengthy deliberation and thought, and considering the tremendous talents of many others, I have decided that the person best suited to assume the position of Vice President of the United States is Senator JD Vance of the Great State of Ohio," Trump posted on Truth Social.</p>

<p>After years of criticising Trump, Vance has embraced the populist ideology of the former president; this choice further elevates him.</p>

<p>After getting support from Trump in a fierce Republican primary, Vance--a venture entrepreneur and the author of the best-selling memoir "Hillbilly Elegy"--was elected to the US Senate in 2022, according to CNN.</p>

<p>"JD honorably served our Country in the Marine Corps, graduated from Ohio State University in two years, Summa Cum Laude, and is a Yale Law School Graduate, where he was Editor of The Yale Law Journal and President of the Yale Law Veterans Association. J.D.'s book, 'Hillbilly Elegy,' became a Major Best Seller and Movie, as it championed the hardworking men and women of our Country. JD has had a very successful business career in Technology and Finance, and now, during the Campaign, will be strongly focused on the people he fought so brilliantly for, the American Workers and Farmers in Pennsylvania, Michigan, Wisconsin, Ohio, Minnesota, and far beyond....," Trump further said in his post.</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/112792061935980928/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>"...As Vice President, J.D. will continue to fight for our Constitution, stand with our Troops, and will do everything he can to help me MAKE AMERICA GREAT AGAIN. Congratulations to Senator J.D. Vance, his wife, Usha, who also graduated from Yale Law School, and their three beautiful children. MAGA2024!" the post added.</p>

<p>Marco Rubio of Florida and Governor Doug Burgum of North Dakota, who were considered to be the frontrunners in the race, are now out of it. Vance has been a supporter of Trump in the Senate and frequently casts votes in the former president's favour.</p>

<p>He echoed Trump's criticism of increasing aid by opposing a bill aimed at assisting Ukraine earlier this year. He is also close with Donald Trump Jr., according to CNN report. According to the report, Vance--a veteran, author, and former venture capitalist--was one of the contenders who obtained vice-presidential vetting materials from the Trump campaign.</p>

<p>Vance was born James David Bowman in Middletown, Ohio, to a mother who struggled with addiction and a father who left the family when JD was a toddler. He was raised by his grandparents.</p>

<p>In 2017, Vance returned to Ohio and continued to work in venture capital. He and his wife, Usha Chilukuri Vance, whom he met at Yale, have three children. Usha Vance, born Usha Chilukuri, is an attorney who has carved out a successful career in the legal field.</p>

<p>Born to Indian immigrant parents, she grew up with a strong emphasis on education and hard work in a San Diego, California, suburb. Usha attended Yale University and also graduated from Yale Law School.</p>

<p>While at Yale, Usha served as managing editor of the Yale Journal of Law &amp; Technology and executive development editor of The Yale Law Journal, according to a biography from the Munger, Tolles &amp; Olson law firm.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ie6h2jc4_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance has been a supporter of Donald Trump in the Senate. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/x-recorded-all-time-high-of-417-billion-user-seconds-globally-elon-musk-6116423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[X Recorded "All-Time High" Of 417 Billion User Seconds Globally: Elon Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/x-recorded-all-time-high-of-417-billion-user-seconds-globally-elon-musk-6116423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:33:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tech billionaire and Tesla CEO Elon Musk claimed on Tuesday that his platform X, formerly Twitter, reached a 'record high in usage'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech billionaire and Tesla CEO Elon Musk claimed on Tuesday that his platform X, formerly Twitter, reached a 'record high in usage'.</p>

<p>Musk said that X experienced a total of "417 billion user-seconds globally" in one day.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Musk said, "X usage hit another all-time high yesterday with 417 billion user-seconds globally! In the US, user-seconds reached 93B, 23% higher than the previous record of 76B. In a single day."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">???? usage hit another all-time high yesterday with 417 billion user-seconds globally!<br />
<br />
In the US, user-seconds reached 93B, 23% higher than the previous record of 76B.<br />
<br />
In a single day.</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1812924962627592524?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">July 15, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script></p>

<p>In March, XData claimed that 250 million people use X every day for 30 minutes on an average.</p>

<p>"You're absolutely right @XNews. 250 million people use X every day. 550 million people visit the global town square every month. On average, users spend 30 minutes a day on X," the post said.</p>

<p>You're absolutely right @XNews. 250 million people use X every day. 550 million people visit the global town square every month.</p>

<p>On average, users spend 30 minutes a day on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">You're absolutely right <a href="https://twitter.com/XNews?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@XNews</a>. 250 million people use X every day. 550 million people visit the global town square every month.<br />
<br />
On average, users spend 30 minutes a day on X. <a href="https://t.co/RoEX4RzIxL">https://t.co/RoEX4RzIxL</a> <a href="https://t.co/L9mkoWll44">pic.twitter.com/L9mkoWll44</a></p>
— Data (@XData) <a href="https://twitter.com/XData/status/1769826435576037702?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">March 18, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script></p>

<p>XNews said that X is 'indispensible'.</p>

<p>In a post, it said, "X is indispensable - and the numbers prove it! What's the latest @XData?"</p>

<p>X is indispensable - and the numbers prove it!</p>

<p>What's the latest @XData?</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">X is indispensable – and the numbers prove it!<br />
<br />
What's the latest <a href="https://twitter.com/XData?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@XData</a>? <a href="https://t.co/HMZlHC8RwI">pic.twitter.com/HMZlHC8RwI</a></p>
— News (@XNews) <a href="https://twitter.com/XNews/status/1769825845005127929?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">March 18, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><script src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script></p>

<p><br />
Musk in October 2022, took ownership of the influential social media platform - Twitter in USD 44 billion deal.</p>

<p>In the ensuing days, Musk fired top executives, laid off half of the company's staff, formed a content moderation council to review account reinstatements and revamped the platform's subscription service.</p>

<p>There have been many changes in the company since Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk took over, some of which have been rather contentious, such as when he opted to restore suspended accounts.<br />
With controversial decisions, Twitter started losing huge amounts of advertisement revenue, after which Musk introduced paid verifications in the form of Twitter Blue.</p>

<p>Musk, in July 2023, rebranded the platform as X over the summer, replacing the well-known blue bird associated with Twitter.</p>

<p>To boost platform engagement, Musk announced on March 28, 2024 that X accounts with over 2,500 verified subscriber followers would be granted free access to Premium features, while those with over 5,000 followers would enjoy Premium features at no cost.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/tl29m2d_x-generic_625x300_09_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk said that X experienced a total of "417 billion user-seconds globally" in one day (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-diplomat-defects-from-cuba-to-south-korea-report-6116390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korean Diplomat Defects From Cuba To South Korea: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-diplomat-defects-from-cuba-to-south-korea-report-6116390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:30:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A high-ranking North Korean diplomat stationed in Cuba defected to South Korea last November -- just months before Seoul and Havana established diplomatic ties, a report said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A high-ranking North Korean diplomat stationed in Cuba defected to South Korea last November -- just months before Seoul and Havana established diplomatic ties, South Korea's spy agency said Tuesday.</p>

<p>North Korean diplomat Ri Il Kyu had been responsible for political affairs at Pyongyang's embassy in Cuba since 2019, tasked specifically "with obstructing the establishment of diplomatic relations between South Korea and Cuba", according to South Korea's Chosun Daily.</p>

<p>Ri defected to South Korea with his wife and children in early November, making him the highest-ranking North Korean diplomat known to have defected since Thae Yong Ho, Pyongyang's deputy ambassador to Britain, in 2016, the report said.</p>

<p>South Korea's spy agency told AFP Tuesday that it was "true" there had been a "defection of the counselor of political affairs from the North Korean embassy in Cuba", without giving further details.</p>

<p>Seoul's unification ministry has previously flagged a rising number of defections by North Korean elites, which they said made up around 10 of the 196 defections in 2023, the highest in years.</p>

<p>Around three months after Ri's reported defection, Seoul and Havana -- which is one of Pyongyang's oldest allies, and a fellow communist state -- announced they were establishing diplomatic ties.</p>

<p>In an exclusive interview with South Korea's Chosun Daily, Ri said he decided to defect after Pyongyang rejected his request to seek medical treatment in Mexico after an injury, even though he could not receive the necessary treatment in Cuba due to a lack of specialist equipment.</p>

<p>He also claimed to have received unfair performance reviews after rejecting a demand from a senior foreign ministry official in the North for bribes when he visited Pyongyang in August 2019 to discuss opening a North Korean restaurant in Cuba.</p>

<p>"Every North Korean thinks at least once about living in South Korea," he told the Chosun Daily.</p>

<p>"Disillusionment with the North Korean regime and a bleak future led me to consider defection."</p>

<p>Ri also told the newspaper that North Korea's former foreign minister Ri Yong Ho and his family had been sent to a political prisoner camp in December 2019 on "suspicion of corruption", over a bribery case involving the country's embassy in Beijing.</p>

<h3><strong>Diplomatic defections&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In 2019, Jo Song Gil, North Korea's former acting ambassador to Italy, also defected to the South after disappearing from the mission in Rome in 2018.</p>

<p>Ryu Hyun Woo, North Korea's acting ambassador to Kuwait, also defected, and arrived in South Korea in 2019.</p>

<p>Analysts say North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has long been "distrustful" of his foreign ministry, especially diplomats stationed overseas.</p>

<p>"The defection of Thae Yong Ho, Jo Song Gil ... and Ri Il Kyu reflect how Kim perceives his country's diplomats," Ahn Chan-il, a defector-turned-researcher who runs the World Institute for North Korea Studies, told AFP.</p>

<p>Seoul's spy agency said in May that Pyongyang was plotting "terrorist" attacks targeting Seoul's officials and citizens overseas, with the foreign ministry raising the alert level for diplomatic missions in five countries.</p>

<p>The agency said it appeared to be a response by Pyongyang to the wave of defections by elite North Koreans who were trapped overseas during the pandemic and were seeking to avoid returning home after border controls were eased.</p>

<p>North Korean embassy officials may be submitting false reports blaming "external" factors -- such as South Koreans based overseas -- for defections by their colleagues in a bid to evade punishment, Seoul's spy agency said at the time.</p>

<p>Pyongyang treats defections as a serious crime and is believed to hand harsh punishments to transgressors, their families, and even people tangentially linked to the incident.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2885brr4_kim-jong-un_625x300_11_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Analysts say North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has long been "distrustful" of his foreign ministry (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/republican-harmeet-dhillon-leads-sikh-prayers-at-convention-trump-present-6116294]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Republican Harmeet Dhillon Leads Sikh Prayers At Convention, Trump Present]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/republican-harmeet-dhillon-leads-sikh-prayers-at-convention-trump-present-6116294]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:15:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Harmeet Dhillon, a civil rights attorney and Republican Party leader led Sikh prayer 'ardas' at the Republican National Convention in the presence of presidential nominee Donald Trump, in Milwaukee today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Harmeet Dhillon, a civil rights attorney and Republican Party leader led Sikh prayer 'ardas' at the Republican National Convention in the presence of presidential nominee Donald Trump, in Milwaukee today.</p>

<p>Ms Dhillon, who previously served as the vice chairwoman of the California Republican Party, said she was honoured to recite the ardas, usually offered by the Sikh community worldwide before any new endeavour. It is done to thank God and seek protection and help in upholding values such as humility, truth, and justice for all.</p>

<p>Ms Dhillon pointed out to the gathering that as a member of a Sikh immigrant family, she must follow the practice of covering one's head while offering prayers as a sign of respect.</p>

<p>In her prayer, she called America a "safe haven" that allows people to freely worship according to their faith.</p>

<p>Donald Trump, who was officially declared the Republican Presidential Candidate for the upcoming 2024 US elections, was present at the convention. This marks his first public appearance since he survived an assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, he picked his critic-turned-ally JD Vance as his potential vice president.</p>

<p>Ms Dhillon recalled the last 48 hours after Trump's assassination attempt as one of the most "intense" and "fearful" events. She also called Trump one of the most fearless people in the face of adversity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/sp7mjamg_harmeet-dhillon-x-_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harmeet Dhillon called the US a "safe haven" that lets people freely worship according to their faith.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-jd-vances-wife-usha-vance-said-about-her-hindu-upbringing-its-influence-on-life-6116180]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Vice President Pick Reveals How His Hindu Wife Helped Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-jd-vances-wife-usha-vance-said-about-her-hindu-upbringing-its-influence-on-life-6116180]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:03:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In an interview, Usha Vance talked about her upbringing in a “religious household” with Indian Hindu parents. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Senator JD Vance, who Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump chose as his running mate, has credited his Hindu wife Usha Chilukuri Vance for shaping his personal and spiritual life.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News, he explained how his Indian-origin wife's Hindu faith had been instrumental in helping him navigate challenges and reconcile his Catholic beliefs.</p>

<p>He revealed he "was raised Christian but never baptised."</p>

<p>"I was first baptised in 2018. Usha was actually raised non-Christian. But I remember when I started to re-engage with my faith, Usha was very supportive," said the 38-year-old.</p>

<p>The couple met at Yale Law School and married in Kentucky in 2014.</p>

<p>They had two ceremonies - a traditional wedding ceremony and a separate Hindu ceremony conducted by a Hindu priest, honouring Usha's Hindu heritage. They have three children - Ewan, 6, Vivek, 4, and Mirabel, 2.</p>

<p>Usha, reflecting on her upbringing in a "religious household", attributed her support for Vance's religious journey to her parents' influence. "My parents are Hindu and that's one of the things that made them such good parents and good people. And I have seen the power of that in my own life," said Usha. "And I knew that JD was searching for something. This just felt right for him," she added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">“My parents' Hindu faith made them great parents” - Usha Vance<br />
<br />
She's a Hindu &amp; was supportive of her husband's rediscovery of his own faith (One of her sons is named Vivek too ????)<br />
<br />
Vance, anti-war &amp; Trump's VP, so far seems to be a net positive for India<a href="https://t.co/KtbOUNT9ba">pic.twitter.com/KtbOUNT9ba</a></p>
— Alexei Arora (@AlexeiArora) <a href="https://twitter.com/AlexeiArora/status/1812939370523160971?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Asked how they raise their children, given their different religious backgrounds, Usha stressed the importance of communication. "We just talk a lot," she said, stating there are certain values and principles that she and Vance "simply agree on" family matters.</p>

<p>Usha Chilukuri Vance is a lawyer, as per her LinkedIn profile. She was raised in a San Diego suburb and attended Mt. Carmel High School. She graduated with a BA in history from Yale University in 2007.</p>

<p>She later pursued further studies at the University of Cambridge, earning an MPhil in 2009 as a Gates Cambridge Scholar. She worked as an associate at Munger, Tolles &amp; Olson LLP. She was a Law Clerk at the Supreme Court of the US and the US Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. She also worked as a Summer Associate at Taft Stettinius &amp; Hollister LLP.</p>

<p>JD Vance has often credited Usha for her support in his success. During a 2020 interview with The Megyn Kelly Show, Vance described his wife as a "powerful female voice" guiding him. "Usha definitely brings me back to earth. If I get a little too cocky or a little too proud, I remind myself that she's way more accomplished than I," he said back then.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jpavgc2_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple met at Yale Law School and married in Kentucky in 2014.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-ai-chip-sohu-new-ai-chip-in-making-claims-it-will-revolutionise-chatgpt-6116225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New AI Chip In Development May Revolutionise ChatGPT]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-ai-chip-sohu-new-ai-chip-in-making-claims-it-will-revolutionise-chatgpt-6116225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 12:02:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA['Sohu' claims to be 20 times faster in running transformers like ChatGPT than Nvidia's flagship- H100s, betting on transformer ASIC (Application Specific Integrated Circuits) chipset.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The reason why you are able to ask ChatGPT "how to eat a mango without spilling it" and much more is Nvidia's H100 and B200 Graphics Processing Units (GPUs). These magical chipsets that power AI chatbots have propelled Nvidia to become the frontrunners of the AI hardware industry, with market capitalization reaching the 3 trillion-dollar mark-more than Microsoft and Apple last month.</p>

<p>But now, a relatively young startup founded by two Harvard dropouts have set their eyes on their share of the AI hardware pie. Etched, the California based startup, is looking to disrupt the AI chipset market with their transformer ASIC (Application Specific Integrated Circuits) chip called Sohu.</p>

<p>Sohu claims to be 20 times faster in running transformers like ChatGPT than Nvidia's flagship- H100. The B200, which is the more powerful Nvidia offering than H100, is reportedly 10 times slower then Sohu, according to the claims made by the company based on emulation tests.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Source: X/@Etched" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mfs4l3n8_etched-ai-chip_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg" title="Source: X/@Etched" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Source: X/@Etched</p>
</div>

<p>Sohu is taking an entirely different approach to providing high computational power to run billions of parameters (Variables that are used in training an AI Model) for transformer models. Unlike GPUs that can do multiple computationally heavy tasks (like rendering graphics in real time), Etched is choosing to create a specialised chip that caters to only transformer AI models - ones that run ChatGPT, Sora (OpenAI's text to video AI model) and Google's Gemini.</p>

<p>What this means is it cannot run other AI models like Convolutional Neural Networks (used for image recognition). This opens up the possibility of exploring new AI products by developers that were till now not possible due to limited power on GPUs.</p>

<p>For example, Sohu can potentially lead to a real-time translator that can hear and read Hindi, Gujarati or Tamil and respond back in French, English and German. Of course, such multimodal and multilingual translation needs more than just the computational power, but in theory, it opens up the possibility.</p>

<p>Another multimodal application of transformers that the chipset might tap into is integrating visual and language areas. This essentially means that such a model will understand both text and images simultaneously, throwing open the possibility of visual questions and answers- like an interview.</p>

<p>But all of this remains a theory. Etched has raised 120 million USD on 25 June to make it a reality, with a real timeline as to an actual release of the Sohu ASIC remaining elusive.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Today we announced our $120M fundraise to bring Sohu to the world. Thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/EdLudlow?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@edludlow</a> for hosting us! <a href="https://t.co/khzMPAofng">https://t.co/khzMPAofng</a> <a href="https://t.co/Q4SeuUjP2h">pic.twitter.com/Q4SeuUjP2h</a></p>
— Etched (@Etched) <a href="https://twitter.com/Etched/status/1805775989500428739?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Etched has claimed it already has "tens of million dollars" worth of hardware reserved in preorders. The company has also secured a deal with TSMC (Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company) to fabricate the 4-nanometer chip, promising the deal is going to help "ramp up our first year of production."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vb1csiio_etched-ai-chip_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sohu, the new chipset will run only transformer AI models]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thomas-matthew-crooks-firing-practice-buying-ladder-what-gunman-did-before-donald-trump-rally-shooting-6115989]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Trump Rally Shooter Did On Last Day Of His Life]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thomas-matthew-crooks-firing-practice-buying-ladder-what-gunman-did-before-donald-trump-rally-shooting-6115989]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 11:25:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 20-year-old who allegedly tried to assassinate former US President Donald Trump at his campaign rally, made a series of stops in and around to collect arms and ammunition before the incident, the CNN reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 20-year-old who tried to assassinate former US President Donald Trump at his campaign rally in Pennsylvania made a series of stops to stock up on ammo before the attack, the CNN reported.</p>

<p>Thomas Matthew Crooks also practised firing at a shooting range on Friday, a day before the Trump rally. The next morning, Crooks went to the Home Depot to buy a five-foot ladder. He then bought 50 rounds of ammunition from a gun store, the report said.</p>

<p>Sources say he used the same ladder to climb the building from where he opened fire at the 78-year-old Republican nominee.</p>

<p>Crooks was gunned down by the Secret Service agents after he attacked Trump. Investigators are trying to piece together a timeline of his actions leading up to the failed assassination bid. The motive remains unknown.</p>

<p>Even after breaking into his phone and searching his computer, officials still haven't found evidence that would suggest political or ideological impetus for the shooting, law enforcement sources told CNN.</p>

<p>Trump survived with a nicked ear during his rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday after Thomas Matthew Crooks opened fire at him. The attack left him with a bloodied face as the former president said the bullet pierced his "upper part of right ear".</p>

<p>The early details that have emerged about Thomas Matthew Crooks show that he was a math whiz, working an entry-level job near his hometown in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>He graduated high school in 2022 with a reputation as a bright but "quiet" classmate.</p>

<p>His counselor at Bethel Park High School described him as "respectful" and said he never knew him to be political.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks practiced firing at a shooting range on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>