<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 09:25:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earths-biodiversity-crisis-1-million-species-face-extinction-6889562]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earth's Biodiversity Crisis: 1 Million Species Face Extinction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earths-biodiversity-crisis-1-million-species-face-extinction-6889562]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 09:25:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over a quarter of plants and animals assessed on the International Union for Conservation of Nature's Red List of threatened species risk extinction.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The experts' assessment is clear: humans are the major threat to Earth's land, seas and all the living things they shelter, including ourselves.</p>

<p>The COP16 biodiversity summit in Cali, Colombia, enters its second week Monday to assess, and ramp up, progress towards achieving 23 targets agreed in Canada two years ago to halt and reverse nature destruction by 2030.</p>

<p>The science in numbers:</p>

<p><strong>2/3 of oceans degraded</strong></p>

<p>Three-quarters of Earth's surface has already been significantly altered and two-thirds of oceans degraded by humankind's rapacious consumption, according to the IPBES intergovernmental science and policy body on biodiversity.</p>

<p>Globally, over a third of inland wetlands declined from 1970 to 2015 -- a rate three times that of forest loss.</p>

<p>"Land degradation through human activities is undermining the well-being of at least 3.2 billion people," according to the IPBES's latest report.</p>

<p>But it highlights that not all is lost, and the benefits of restoration would be 10 times higher than the costs.</p>

<p>One of the 23 targets of the so-called Kunming-Montreal Global Biodiversity Framework is for 30 percent of degraded land, inland water, marine and coastal ecosystems to be under "effective restoration" by 2030.</p>

<p><strong>A million species threatened</strong></p>

<p>Over a quarter of plants and animals assessed on the International Union for Conservation of Nature's Red List of threatened species risk extinction.</p>

<p>According to the IPBES, about a million species are at risk.</p>

<p>Pollinators, essential to the reproduction of plants and three-quarters of crops that feed humanity, are at the forefront, dying off fast.</p>

<p>Corals -- on which the food and labor of some 850 million people depend -- are another striking example.</p>

<p>These animals, whose reefs provide feeding and spawning grounds for a multitude of creatures, could all but disappear in a world 2 degrees Celsius (3.6 degrees Fahrenheit) warmer than pre-industrial levels.</p>

<p>This is the upper limit of average planet warming the world is seeking not to exceed under the 2015 Paris Agreement on curbing Earth-warming greenhouse gases.</p>

<p><strong>Five horsemen of the apocalypse</strong></p>

<p>For the UN, the biodiversity crisis has five causes, all human-induced and nicknamed the "Five Horsemen of the Apocalypse."</p>

<p>They are habitat destruction (for agriculture or human infrastructure), over-exploitation of resources such as water, climate change, pollution and the spread of invasive species.</p>

<p>Climate change is likely to become the main driver of biodiversity destruction by 2050, experts say.</p>

<p><strong>Half of GDP</strong></p>

<p>More than half (55%) of the world's gross domestic product, some $58 trillion, depends "heavily or moderately" on nature and its services, according to auditing giant PwC.</p>

<p>Agriculture, forestry, fisheries and aquaculture, the food and beverage industry and construction are the sectors most exposed to nature loss.</p>

<p>Pollination services, safe water, and disease control are other, nigh-incalculable, benefits derived from nature.</p>

<p>Indian economist Pavan Sukhdev, who led a research project entitled The Economics of Ecosystems and Biodiversity (TEEB) had estimated that biodiversity loss comes at a cost of between 1.35 trillion and 3.1 trillion euros ($1.75 trillion and $4 trillion) per year.</p>

<p><strong>$2.6 billion in subsidies</strong></p>

<p>A report in September by the Earth Track monitor said environmentally harmful subsidies to industries were worth at least $2.6 trillion, equivalent to 2.5 percent of global GDP.</p>

<p>This dwarfs the Kunming-Montreal framework's target of mobilizing $200 billion per year by 2030 for nature protection.</p>

<p>Harmful industries that benefit from subsidies include fisheries, agriculture and fossil fuel producers.</p>

<p>Another target of the biodiversity framework is to reduce harmful subsidies and tax benefits by "at least $500 billion per year" by 2030.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/lflm0p18_biodiversity-park_625x300_05_June_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Humans are the major threat to Earth's land, seas and all the living things they shelter, warn experts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-polls-opposition-calls-for-protest-eu-demands-investigation-into-irregularities-6889434]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Georgian Opposition Calls For Protest, EU Demands Investigation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-polls-opposition-calls-for-protest-eu-demands-investigation-into-irregularities-6889434]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 09:00:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Georgian opposition called for protests on Monday and the European Union demanded an investigation into "irregularities" after a disputed legislative vote that showed a win for the ruling party accused of moving towards Russia's orbit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Georgian opposition called for protests on Monday and the European Union demanded an investigation into "irregularities" after a disputed legislative vote that showed a win for the ruling party accused of moving towards Russia's orbit.</p>

<p>Pro-Western President Salome Zurabishvili on Sunday accused Moscow of orchestrating election fraud, calling it a "Russian special operation".</p>

<p>Amid angry opposition claims over the result, Zurabishvili called for a rally on Monday. Jailed former president Mikheil Saakashvili also called for mass protests.</p>

<p>The European Union had warned that Saturday's vote, seen as a crucial test of democracy in the Caucasus country, could determine Tbilisi's chances of joining the bloc.</p>

<p>EU council president Charles Michel wrote on social media that Georgian authorities should "swiftly, transparently and independently investigate and adjudicate electoral irregularities and allegations thereof."</p>

<p>"These alleged irregularities must be seriously clarified and addressed," he said.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken also said he supported calls for investigations into "election-related violations", citing reports from international and local observers of "vote buying and voter intimidation".</p>

<p>After meeting with opposition leaders in Tbilisi, Zurabishvili said there had been a "total falsification of the election".</p>

<p>"We are witnesses and victims of a Russian special operation, a modern form of hybrid war against the Georgian people," she said.</p>

<p>International observers said Saturday's election was "marred by an uneven playing field, pressure and tension".</p>

<p>An EU parliament mission also expressed concern about "democratic backsliding", saying it had seen instances of "ballot box stuffing" and the "physical assault" of observers.</p>

<p><strong>'Fighting for freedom'</strong></p>

<p>Saakashvili, who spearheaded the bloodless Rose Revolution in 2003, said on Facebook that opposition lawmakers should renounce their parliamentary seats.</p>

<p>"Now is the time for mass protests. We must show the world that we are fighting for freedom and that we are a people who will not tolerate injustice," he said.</p>

<p>Official tallies from more than 99 percent of precincts showed the ruling Georgian Dream party winning 54 percent of the vote, with the main pro-Western opposition coalition on 37.5 percent.</p>

<p>The result gives Georgian Dream 91 seats in the 150-member parliament -- enough to govern but short of the supermajority it had sought to pass a constitutional ban on all main opposition parties.</p>

<p>"Our victory is impressive," Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze said in a statement, accusing the opposition of "undermining the country's constitutional order" by questioning his party's victory.</p>

<p>The government said that Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, an ally of the ruling party and current holder of the EU's rotating presidency, would visit Georgia on Monday and Tuesday.</p>

<p>Orban rushed to congratulate Georgian Dream for an "overwhelming victory" on Saturday after one exit poll showed the government in the lead and before preliminary results had been published.</p>

<p>Another exit poll by US pollster Edison Research had projected an opposition victory by an 11-percent margin.</p>

<p><strong>EU hopes 'dimmed'</strong></p>

<p>Opposition parties lined up to denounce the vote.</p>

<p>"This is an attempt to steal Georgia's future," said Tina Bokuchava, leader of Saakashvili's United National Movement (UNM).</p>

<p>Nika Gvaramia, leader of the liberal Akhali party, called the way the vote was held "a constitutional coup" by the government.</p>

<p>Analyst Gela Vasadze of the Georgian Strategic Analysis Centre said the country was plunging "into political instability for an indefinite period" and that its EU hopes had "dimmed".</p>

<p>He said, however, that the opposition lacked "charismatic leaders who could channel popular anger into a protest wave capable of bringing about political change."</p>

<p><strong>'Global war party'</strong></p>

<p>Georgia was gripped by mass demonstrations this year against what the opposition saw as government attempts to curtail democratic freedoms and steer the country of four million off its pro-Western course and towards Russia.</p>

<p>In power since 2012, Georgian Dream initially pursued a liberal pro-Western policy agenda.</p>

<p>But it has reversed course over the last two years.</p>

<p>Its campaign centred on a conspiracy theory about a "global war party" that controls Western institutions and is seeking to drag Georgia into the Russia-Ukraine war.</p>

<p>In a country scarred by Russia's 2008 invasion, the party has offered voters bogeyman stories about an imminent threat of war, which only Georgian Dream could prevent.</p>

<p>Georgian Dream's controversial "foreign influence" law which targeted civil society sparked weeks of street protests and was criticised as a Kremlin-style measure to silence dissent.</p>

<p>The move prompted Brussels to freeze Georgia's EU accession process, while Washington imposed sanctions on dozens of Georgian officials.</p>

<p>In a campaign against sexual minorities, the ruling party has adopted measures that ban LGBTQ "propaganda", nullify same-sex marriages conducted abroad, and outlaw gender reassignment.</p>

<p><strong>READ |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidzina-ivanishvili-secretive-billionaire-called-georgias-puppet-master-6889122">Bidzina Ivanishvili, Secretive Billionaire Called Georgia's "Puppet Master"</a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ii920tto_georgia-elections_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Supporters and members of the ruling Georgian Dream party attend a gathering at the party's headquarters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wiped-off-the-face-of-the-earth-how-russia-erased-a-ukrainian-city-6889218]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wiped Off The Face Of The Earth": How Russia Erased A Ukrainian City]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wiped-off-the-face-of-the-earth-how-russia-erased-a-ukrainian-city-6889218]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:52:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vovchansk had a population of about 20,000 before the war. It now lives only in the memories of the survivors who managed to flee.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"It barely exists anymore," said the mayor of Vovchansk, an industrial town razed by a Russian onslaught shocking even for the killing fields of eastern Ukraine.</p>

<p>Vovchansk has no great history but its geography could not be more tragic. Just five kilometres (three miles) from the Russian border, drone footage from the Ukrainian military this summer shows a lunar landscape of ruins stretching for miles.</p>

<p>And it has got worse since.</p>

<p>"Ninety percent of the centre is flattened," said mayor Tamaz Gambarashvili, a towering man in uniform, who runs what is left of Vovchansk from the regional capital of Kharkiv, an hour and a half's drive away.</p>

<p>"The enemy continues its massive shelling," he added.</p>

<p>Six out of 10 of Vovchansk's buildings have been totally destroyed, with 18 percent partially ruined, according to analysis of satellite images by the independent open-source intelligence collective Bellingcat. But the destruction is much worse in the city centre, which has been levelled north of the Vovcha River.</p>

<p>AFP and Bellingcat joined forces to tell how, building by building, an entire city was wiped off the map in just a few weeks -- and to show the human toll it has taken.</p>

<p>The sheer pace of the destruction dwarfed that of even Bakhmut, the "meatgrinder" Donbas region city where some of the most brutal killing of the war has been done, a Ukrainian officer who fought in both cities told AFP.</p>

<p>"I was in Bakhmut, so I know how the battles unfolded there," Lieutenant Denys Yaroslavsky insisted.</p>

<p>"What took two or three months in Bakhmut happened in just two or three weeks in Vovchansk."</p>

<p><strong>Invaded, then freed</strong></p>

<p>Vovchansk had a population of about 20,000 before the war. It now lives only in the memories of the survivors who managed to flee.</p>

<p>Beyond its factories, the city had a "medical school, a technical college, seven schools and numerous kindergartens," Nelia Stryzhakova, the head of its library, told AFP in Kharkiv.</p>

<p>It even had a workshop that made "carriages for period films. We were even interesting, in our own way," insisted Stryzhakova, 61.</p>

<p>Add to that a regional hospital, rebuilt in 2017 with nearly 10 million euros ($10.8 million) of German aid, a church packed for religious feasts, and a vast hydraulic machinery plant. Once the town's economic lifeblood, its ruins are now being fought over by both armies.</p>

<p>Vovchansk was quickly occupied by the Russian army after it invaded Ukraine in February 2022, but was then retaken by Kyiv in a lightning counter attack that autumn.</p>

<p>Despite enduring regular Russian bombardment, it was relatively calm. Then something very different happened on May 10.</p>

<p><strong>Badly defended</strong></p>

<p>Exhausted after weeks of hard fighting 100 kilometres to the south, the Ukrainian 57th Brigade was regrouping near Vovchansk when one of its reconnaissance units noticed something strange.</p>

<p>"We spotted two Russian armoured troop carriers that had just crossed the border," recalled Lieutenant Yaroslavsky, who was leading the unit.</p>

<p>They were the advance guard of one of the most intense Russian offensives since the beginning of the war, with Moscow throwing several thousand soldiers at the city.</p>

<p>"There were no fortifications, no mines" to slow down their advance, Yaroslavsky said, still furious at the "negligence or corruption" that allowed this to happen.</p>

<p>Some "17,000 people lost their homes. Why? Because someone didn't build fortifications," fumed the 42-year-old officer.</p>

<p>"We control the city today, but what we control is a pile of rubble," he added bitterly.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky cancelled an overseas trip to rush to Kharkiv, admitting that the Russian army had pushed between five and 10 kilometres into Ukraine.</p>

<p>The people of Vovchansk, meanwhile, were living a nightmare.</p>

<p><strong>'Drones like mosquitoes'</strong></p>

<p>"The Russians started bombing," said Galyna Zharova, who lived at 16A Stepova Street -- an apartment building now reduced to ruins, as images analysed by Bellingcat and AFP confirmed.</p>

<p>"We were right on the front line. No one could come and get us out," added the 50-year-old, who now lives with her family in a university dormitory in Kharkiv.</p>

<p>"We went down to the cellar. All the buildings were burning. We were crammed into basements (for nearly four weeks) until June 3," her husband Viktor, 65, added.</p>

<p>Eventually, the couple decided to flee on foot. "Drones were flying around us like wasps, like mosquitoes," Galyna remembered. They walked for several kilometres before being rescued by Ukrainian volunteers.</p>

<p>"The city was beautiful. The people were beautiful. We had everything," sighed librarian Stryzhakova. "No one could have imagined that in just five days, we would be wiped off the face of the Earth."</p>

<p>The 125,000 books in the library she had run at 8 Tokhova Street went up in smoke.</p>

<p>More than half of the families in eastern Ukraine have relatives in Russia. In Vovchansk, before the war in the Donbas region began in 2014, people crossed the border daily to shop, with Russians flocking to the city's markets.</p>

<p>"There are many mixed families," said Stryzhakova. "Parents, children, we're all connected. And now we've become enemies. There's no other way to put it."</p>

<p>The Russian defence ministry did not respond to AFP's questions asking for its account of what happened in the city.</p>

<p>Mayor Gambarashvili, who was hit in the leg by shrapnel as he oversaw the city's evacuation, shook his head when asked to estimate the number of civilian casualties.</p>

<p>Dozens, no doubt. Perhaps more. There were still around 4,000 people in Vovchansk on May 10, mostly older people, since most families with children had been evacuated months earlier.</p>

<p><strong>Families divided by war</strong></p>

<p>Kira Dzhafarova, 57, believes her mother, Valentina Radionova, who had lived at 40 Dukhovna Street in a small house with a charming garden, is likely dead.</p>

<p>Their last phone conversation was on May 17. "At 85, I'm not going anywhere," her mother insisted. Satellite images and witnesses have since confirmed that the house was completely destroyed.</p>

<p>"Since then I know it's over," sighed Kira, who provided DNA for identification, if and when the fighting ends.</p>

<p>In a particularly cruel irony, her mother, a Russian national, had moved to Vovchansk so she could be equidistant between her two children, who had fallen out.</p>

<p>Kira has lived in Kharkiv for 35 years and became officially Ukrainian two years ago. Her older brother, who she believes supports Russian President Vladimir Putin, remained in Belgorod, the family's hometown and the first big Russian city on the other side of the border.</p>

<p>Kira, a psychiatrist, now only refers to him as her "former brother".</p>

<p>AFP was unable to contact him directly.</p>

<p>Volodymyr Zymovsky, 70, is also missing. On May 16, he decided to flee the bombardment in a car with his 83-year-old mother, his wife Raisa, and a neighbour. Zymovsky and his mother were both shot dead, "most likely by a Russian sniper", Raisa said.</p>

<p>Amid the hail of bullets, the 59-year-old paediatric nurse had barely got out of the car when she was grabbed by Russian soldiers and held for two days. She managed to escape, hid in a neighbour's cellar for a night, and eventually fled through the forest.</p>

<p>She recounted her harrowing odyssey in a calm, measured voice. One thing alone seems to matter to her now: finding the bodies of her husband and mother-in-law and giving them a proper burial.</p>

<p><strong>'They took my son'</strong></p>

<p>A rumour has circulated among the survivors that the bodies that littered the streets of Vovchansk for days were thrown into a mass grave. Where and by whom, no one knows.</p>

<p>A handful of civilians still remain in Vovchansk. Oleksandre Garlychev, 70, claims to have seen at least three when he returned to his former apartment on a bicycle in mid-September to retrieve belongings.</p>

<p>Garlychev lived at 10A Rubezhanskaya Street, in a southern part of the city that was relatively spared. He only left on August 10.</p>

<p>Vovchansk's survivors -- and even a few of its officials -- quietly wonder whether it will ever be rebuilt given its proximity to the border, regardless of how the war ends.</p>

<p>Asked whether she could ever forgive her husband's killer, Raisa Zymovska fell silent for a long time. Then, in a whisper, she replied: "I don't know, I really don't. As a Christian, yes, but as a human being... What can I say?"</p>

<p>As for the librarian Stryzhakova, she can no longer bring herself to open a Russian book, even the classics, since her only son Pavlo was killed in the Battle of Bakhmut.</p>

<p>"I know that literature is not to blame, but Russia, all of it disgusts me. They took my son, it's personal."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d4h8mtj8_vovchansk-ukraine_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tamaz Gambarashvili, Mayor of Vovchansk shows the emblem of Vovchansk city.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidzina-ivanishvili-secretive-billionaire-called-georgias-puppet-master-6889122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bidzina Ivanishvili, Secretive Billionaire Called Georgia's "Puppet Master"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidzina-ivanishvili-secretive-billionaire-called-georgias-puppet-master-6889122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:29:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Georgia's richest man first burst into politics 12 years ago, he vowed to "astonish Europe" with the democracy he would bring to the Black Sea nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Georgia's richest man first burst into politics 12 years ago, he vowed to "astonish Europe" with the democracy he would bring to the Black Sea nation.</p>

<p>But Bidzina Ivanishvili, the billionaire founder of Tbilisi's ruling party, has done what many critics say is the opposite: led the country into international isolation while curbing the power of his political opponents.</p>

<p>This month, the European Parliament called for sanctions against the powerful tycoon, accusing him of "undermining democracy" with the aim of pulling Georgia away from the West towards Russia's orbit.</p>

<p>As the Caucasus nation gears up for crunch parliamentary elections Saturday, all eyes will be on what the reclusive 68-year-old oligarch does if his Georgian Dream party, in power since 2012, wins again.</p>

<p><strong>'Absolute power'</strong></p>

<p>Born into poverty in the village of Chorvila in western Georgia, Ivanishvili made his fortune in Russia during the cutthroat 1990s, amassing huge wealth as state-owned Soviet assets were privatised.</p>

<p>He is now worth $4.9 billion, according to Forbes magazine -- just under a sixth of Georgia's GDP -- and holds dual Georgian and French citizenship.</p>

<p>In 2012, he became Georgia's prime minister after founding his own political party, serving for just over a year before officially retiring from politics.</p>

<p>In 2023, he returned to become Georgian Dream's honorary chairman, assuming the role of a kingmaker who nominates prime ministers from among his loyal lieutenants.</p>

<p>After initially pursuing a liberal pro-Western agenda, his party has over the last two years intensified its anti-Western and anti-liberal positions.</p>

<p>Under his de-facto rule, Georgian Dream has "managed to gradually capture all branches of power and independent institutions in the country," the Georgian branch of the Transparency International rights group said in May.</p>

<p>"The arrangement allows Ivanishvili to have near absolute power without any formal accountability," it added.</p>

<p>He maintains control by placing close associates, such as personal bodyguards, ex-CEOs of his companies, personal assistants and family doctors in charge of state institutions, "with law enforcement and security services being the key", it said.</p>

<p><strong>Modern art, sharks, baobabs</strong></p>

<p>"He thinks of the country as his personal property, as a private corporation," said political analyst Gia Khukhashvili, Ivanishvili's former adviser and one-time close confidant.</p>

<p>The billionaire is "detached from reality" and surrounded by a small circle of "sycophantic favourites", he added.</p>

<p>Giorgi Bachiashvili, the former head of Ivanishvili's Co-Investment Fund who used to be the tycoon's right-hand man, called him a "power-drunk criminal" who "is trading away the future of our country."</p>

<p>Ivanishvili has also faced accusations of having ties with Russia, a charge his party has rejected.</p>

<p>In addition to property and land in Georgia worth hundreds of millions of dollars, Ivanishvili owns luxury real estate in New York and Paris through a complex web of offshore companies and trusts.</p>

<p>His Georgian Co-Investment Fund is registered in Luxembourg and operates 25 projects in Georgia, including shopping malls, cement factories, and luxury hotels.</p>

<p>He is also the founder of a charity fund that has failed to publish financial reports for the last four years and faced accusations of vote-buying.</p>

<p>Now sporting a splash of grey in his neatly coiffed hair, Ivanishvili lives in a lavish glass-and-steel mansion overlooking the capital Tbilisi, where he keeps a priceless collection of contemporary paintings.</p>

<p>Among his possessions is a private zoo with exotic animals, a huge aquarium with sharks and a collection of giant baobab trees transported from Africa by boat in a journey that cost millions of dollars.</p>

<p><strong>'Global war party'</strong></p>

<p>In recent weeks, Ivanishvili has attracted ridicule on social media for appearing at campaign rallies inside a bulletproof glass booth and for canned applause being played at his speeches.</p>

<p>He says his party is seeking to win a supermajority in the new parliament to enable a constitutional ban on pro-Western opposition parties.</p>

<p>His campaign has focused on a conspiracy theory about a mysterious "global war party" that controls Western institutions and seeks to drag Georgia into the Russia-Ukraine war.</p>

<p>Opposition parties, he said, "are trying to seize power by opening a second front (against Russia) in Georgia" with the help of their foreign partners.</p>

<p>"On October 26, we must once again save the country and choose between slavery and freedom, submission to foreign powers and sovereignty, war and peace," he told a campaign rally in the Black Sea city of Batumi.</p>

<p>In spring, Georgian Dream lawmakers passed a Russian-style "foreign influence" law that targeted civil society and sparked weeks of unprecedented street protests, prompting Brussels to halt Tbilisi's European Union integration process.</p>

<p>Recent opinion polls suggest that four leading opposition alliances are poised to garner enough votes to form a coalition government in the upcoming ballot.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1mcq7q38_bidzina-ivanishvili_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-finds-20-on-ground-buys-lottery-ticket-and-wins-1-million-6889090]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Finds $20 On Ground, Buys Lottery Ticket And Wins $1 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-finds-20-on-ground-buys-lottery-ticket-and-wins-1-million-6889090]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:18:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Jerry Hicks, a master carpenter from Banner Elk was headed to a convenience store, he found a $20 bill lying on the ground and then he won a lottery.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A $20 bill lying on the ground, outside a convenience store, became the road to a $1 million lottery for a North Carolina man. On October 22, when Jerry Hicks, a master carpenter from Banner Elk was headed to a convenience store, he found a $20 bill lying on the ground.</p>

<p>“I found $20 in the parking lot outside the Speedway,” Hicks recalled, as per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nclottery.com/News/2024/10/25/Avery-County-man-finds-20-on-ground-and-uses-it-to-win-1-million-" rel="nofollow,noindex">press release</a>. “I used that to buy the ticket.”</p>

<p>He picked it up, walked into the Speedway on N.C. 105 in Boone, and bought an Extreme Cash scratch-off.</p>

<p>“They actually didn't have the ticket I was looking for so I bought that one instead,” he laughed.</p>

<p>He hit the jackpot with a $1 million lottery.</p>

<p>The winner had two options to claim his prize money - receive the prize as an annuity of $50,000 over 20 years or a lump sum of $600,000. He chose the latter and took $429,007 after required state and federal tax withholdings.</p>

<p>Hicks has plans for the family. He wants to use the winning amount to help out his children and retire after working as a carpenter for 56 years.</p>

<p>When asked, what is the first thing he would do to celebrate the big win, he said, “We are going to head straight to Golden Corral and eat everything they've got.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/a7qj1b2o_us-nc-education-lottery_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jerry Hicks is a master carpenter from Banner Elk]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-supreme-leaders-hebrew-x-account-suspended-last-post-was-6889056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Supreme Leader's Hebrew X Account Suspended, Last Post Was...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-supreme-leaders-hebrew-x-account-suspended-last-post-was-6889056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:06:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Hebrew language account opened by Iran's leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on social media platform X has been suspended after just two posts, as per Jerusalem Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Hebrew language account opened by Iran's leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on social media platform X has been suspended after just two posts, as per Jerusalem Post.</p>

<p>The latest post from Sunday read, "The Zionist regime made a mistake, and erred in its calculation regarding Iran. We will make it understand what power, ability, initiative and desire the Iranian nation has."</p>

<p>The first Hebrew language post came on Saturday, reading, "In the name of Allah the merciful." Both posts came after Israel's strikes on Iran's military targets last week.</p>

<p>On his main X account, Khamenei often posts in Hebrew,&nbsp;often using strong language against Israel.</p>

<p>Khamenei had said that Israel's airstrikes on Iran should not be magnified nor downplayed. While Israel would like to amplify the impacts of its actions against Iran, Khamenei said on Sunday, adding it would also not be right for Iran to dismiss the strikes as insignificant, CNN reported.</p>

<p>"They're making a miscalculation concerning Iran," he said in comments published on his website. "They still haven't been able to correctly understand the power, capability, ingenuity, and determination of the Iranian people. We need to make them understand these things."</p>

<p>Iran said Israeli air strikes targeting its military sites killed two soldiers on Saturday, after Israel simultaneously struck missile manufacturing facilities, surface-to-air missile arrays and other "aerial capabilities".</p>

<p>It said later that the air attack had "concluded" its response to Iran's October 1 missile attack, saying its warplanes had returned safely and the mission was "fulfilled".&nbsp;Iran's air force confirmed strikes on military bases in Tehran, Khuzestan and Ilam provinces that "caused limited damage".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/b3d2u2tg_ayatollah-ali-khamenei_625x300_01_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-dials-911-claiming-a-bear-is-chasing-him-hes-now-a-key-murder-suspect-6889023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Dials 911 Claiming A Bear Is Chasing Him. He's Now A Key Murder Suspect]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-dials-911-claiming-a-bear-is-chasing-him-hes-now-a-key-murder-suspect-6889023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 06:59:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man called 911 and said that he had fallen off of a cliff while running from a bear and that he was injured and partially in the water, leading first responders to a dead body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man in the US is wanted in a murder case after he called the emergency number 911, claiming he had been chased by a bear and leading first responders to a dead body.</p>

<p>According to a news release from the Monroe County Tennessee Sheriff's Office, 911 received a call about a "distressed hiker" on October 18 who claimed to be Brandon Andrade. He told the dispatcher that he had fallen off of a cliff while running from a bear and that he was injured and partially in the water.</p>

<p>When officials conducted a search in Tellico Plains, the area where they received the call from, a body of a man was recovered with an identification of Brandon Kristopher Andrade.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After investigation, the officials found that Brandon Andrade was not the victim and that the identification had been "stolen and used" on multiple occasions.</p>

<p>"A male that was using the stolen identification of Mr Andrade, was discovered to be a Nicholas Wayne Hamlett, who was wanted out of the State of Alabama on a parole violation," the Sheriff's Office said.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="250" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fphoto.php%3Ffbid%3D1044339974374056%26set%3Da.284744377000290%26type%3D3&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>Hamlett had used a false name when speaking with law enforcement after the distressed hiker call.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Before his real identity was verified, he was believed to have fled from his Tennessee residence.</p>

<p>The victim has so far not been identified, and an arrest warrant has been issued for Hamlett, who is considered "armed and dangerous", for First Degree Murder,&nbsp;the Sheriff's Office said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/86npog38_nicholas-wayne-hamlett_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man has been identified as Nicholas Wayne Hamlett]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-blames-souths-military-for-drone-intrusion-6888603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Blames South's Military For Drone Intrusion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-blames-souths-military-for-drone-intrusion-6888603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 04:38:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea's defence ministry blamed South Korea's military for sending drones into its territory for political purposes, calling it an infringement upon the country's sovereignty]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea's defence ministry blamed South Korea's military for sending drones into its territory for political purposes, calling it an infringement upon the country's sovereignty, state media KCNA said on Monday.</p>

<p>The ministry announced final results of its investigation after claiming that South Korean drones flew over Pyongyang at least three times this month to distribute anti-North leaflets. KCNA has also published photos of what it described as a crashed South Korean military drone.</p>

<p>During an analysis of the drone's flight control programme, North Korean authorities said they uncovered more than 230 flight plans and flight logs since June 2023, including a plan to scatter "political motivational rubbish."</p>

<p>An Oct. 8 record showed that the drone had departed the South's border island of Baengnyeongdo late at night and released leaflets over the foreign and defence ministry buildings in Pyongyang a few hours later.</p>

<p>Seoul's defence ministry did not immediately have comment but has said Pyongyang's unilateral claims were "not worth verifying or a response."</p>

<p>A North Korean spokesperson warned that the country would respond with "merciless offensive" if such a case recurs, KCNA said.</p>

<p>Tensions between the Koreas have rekindled since the North began flying balloons carrying trash into the South in late May, prompting the South to restart loudspeaker propaganda broadcasts.</p>

<p>Seoul and Washington have said North Korea has sent 3,000 troops to Russia for possible deployment in Ukraine, which could mean a significant escalation in their conflict. Pyongyang said on Friday that any move to send its troops to support Russia would be in line with international law.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fst13ff8_north-korea-_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korean authorities said they uncovered more than 230 flight plans and flight logs since June 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egypt-proposes-2-day-truce-in-gaza-with-limited-hostage-prisoner-exchange-6887823]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Egypt Proposes 2-Day Truce In Gaza With Limited Hostage-Prisoner Exchange]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egypt-proposes-2-day-truce-in-gaza-with-limited-hostage-prisoner-exchange-6887823]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:05:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Egypt has proposed an initial two-day ceasefire in Gaza to exchange four Israeli hostages of Hamas for some Palestinian prisoners, Egypt's president said on Sunday as Israeli military strikes killed 45 Palestinians across the enclave.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Egypt has proposed an initial two-day ceasefire in Gaza to exchange four Israeli hostages of Hamas for some Palestinian prisoners, Egypt's president said on Sunday as Israeli military strikes killed 45 Palestinians across the enclave.</p>

<p>Egyptian leader Abdel Fattah al-Sisi made the announcement as efforts to defuse the devastating, more than year-long war resumed in Qatar with the directors of the CIA and Israel's Mossad intelligence agency taking part.</p>

<p>Speaking alongside Algerian President Abdelmadjid Tebboune during a press conference in Cairo, Sisi also said that talks should resume within 10 days of implementing the temporary ceasefire in efforts to reach a permanent one.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Israel or Hamas but a Palestinian official close to the mediation effort told Reuters: "I expect Hamas would listen to the new offers, but it remains determined that any agreement must end the war and get Israeli forces out of Gaza."</p>

<p>Israel has said the war cannot end until Hamas has been wiped out as a military force and governing entity in Gaza.</p>

<p>The US, Qatar and Egypt have been spearheading negotiations to end the war that erupted after Hamas fighters entered southern Israel on October 7 last year, killing 1,200 people and taking more than 250 hostages, by Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The death count from Israel's retaliatory air and ground onslaught in Gaza is approaching 43,000, Gaza health officials say, with the densely populated enclave in ruins.</p>

<p>An official briefed on the talks told Reuters earlier on Sunday that negotiations in Doha will seek a short-term ceasefire and the release of some hostages being held by Hamas in exchange for Israel's release of Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>The objective, still elusive after multiple mediation attempts, is to get Israel and Hamas to agree to a halt in fighting for less than a month in the hope this would lead to a more permanent ceasefire.</p>

<p>At least 43 of those killed in Gaza on Sunday were in the north of the enclave, where Israeli troops have returned to root out Hamas fighters who it says have regrouped there.</p>

<p><strong>'UNBEARABLE' CONDITIONS IN NORTH GAZA</strong></p>

<p>The United Nations said the plight of Palestinian civilians in northern Gaza was "unbearable" and the conflict was being "waged with little regard for the requirements of international humanitarian law".</p>

<p>"The Secretary-General (Antonio Guterres) is shocked by the harrowing levels of death, injury and destruction in the north, with civilians trapped under rubble, the sick and wounded going without life-saving health care, and families lacking food and shelter, amid reports of families being separated and many people detained," U.N. spokesperson Stephane Dujarric said in a statement.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities were hampering efforts to deliver food, medicine and other essential humanitarian supplies, putting lives at risk, he said. The devastation and deprivation resulting from Israeli military operations in the north were making life there untenable.</p>

<p>Israel says its forces operate in accordance with international law. It says it targets Hamas operatives who conceal themselves among the civilian population which they use as human shields, a charge Hamas denies.</p>

<p>It denies blocking humanitarian aid to Gaza, blaming international organisations for problems distributing it and accusing Hamas of stealing from aid convoys.</p>

<p><strong>JABALIA IN FOCUS</strong></p>

<p>Earlier on Sunday, 20 people were killed following an airstrike on houses in Jabalia, the largest of the Gaza Strip's eight historic refugee camps, which has been the focus of an Israeli military offensive for more than three weeks, medics and the Palestinian official news agency WAFA said.</p>

<p>Another Israeli airstrike on a school sheltering displaced Palestinian families in Shati camp in Gaza City, killed nine people and wounded 20 others, with many in critical condition, medics said.</p>

<p>Footage circulated on Palestinian media, which Reuters could not immediately verify, showed people rushing to the bomb site to help evacuate the casualties. Bodies were scattered on the ground, while some carried wounded children in their arms before loading them in a vehicle.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it was looking into the report on the strike on the school.</p>

<p>Three local journalists were among those killed at the school in Shati - Saed Radwan, head of digital media at Hamas Al-Aqsa television, Hanin Baroud, and Hamza Abu Selmeya, according to Hamas media.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Israel's military said it had killed more than 40 militants in the Jabalia area in the past 24 hours, as well as dismantling infrastructure and locating large quantities of military equipment.</p>

<p>Israeli military strikes on the towns of Jabalia, Beit Hanoun and Beit Lahiya in northern Gaza have so far killed around 800 people during a three-week offensive, the Gaza health ministry said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1qvfgfig_gaza-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There was no immediate comment from Israel or Hamas (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-5-soldiers-killed-in-combat-in-south-lebanon-6886902]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Says 5 Soldiers Killed In "Combat" In South Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-5-soldiers-killed-in-combat-in-south-lebanon-6886902]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 21:01:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military on Sunday said five soldiers were killed in southern Lebanon, bringing to 37 the death toll for soldiers fighting there since the start of ground operations on September 30.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military on Sunday said five soldiers were killed in southern Lebanon, bringing to 37 the death count for soldiers fighting there since the start of ground operations on September 30.</p>

<p>The soldiers "fell during combat in southern Lebanon," the army said in a statement, adding that they were killed on Saturday.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began launching rockets at Israel on October 8, 2023, in support of Hamas after the Palestinian group launched its unprecedented attack on Israel the previous day.</p>

<p>Israel dramatically escalated its air strikes on Lebanon late last month before launching ground operations in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>The war has left at least 1,615 people dead in Lebanon since September 23, according to an AFP tally based on official figures, though the real number is likely to be higher due to gaps in the data.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/psho2ggg_lebanon-afp_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel dramatically escalated its air strikes on Lebanon late last month (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-to-continue-foreign-tours-after-being-diagnosed-with-cancer-6886851]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles To Continue Foreign Tours After Being Diagnosed With Cancer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-to-continue-foreign-tours-after-being-diagnosed-with-cancer-6886851]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:55:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles III's cancer diagnosis will not prevent him flying abroad next year for foreign visits, a Buckingham Palace official said, as the monarch wrapped up a tour of Australia and Samoa.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>King Charles III's cancer diagnosis will not prevent him flying abroad next year for foreign visits, a Buckingham Palace official said, as the monarch wrapped up a tour of Australia and Samoa.</p>

<p>"We're now working on a pretty normal looking full overseas tour programme for next year, which is a high for us to end on, to know that we can be thinking in those terms," the official said late Saturday.</p>

<p>King Charles was diagnosed with an undisclosed cancer earlier this year but doctors agreed he could pause his treatment to allow him to travel to Australia and Samoa.</p>

<p>The palace announced in April that he would make a limited return to public duties, as doctors were "very encouraged" by his progress.</p>

<p>The official added that the king had "thrived" on the tour's programme which had lifted "his spirits, his mood and his recovery".</p>

<p>"In that sense, the tour, despite its demands, has been the perfect tonic," he added.</p>

<p>The tour was King Charles' first to Australia, where he is also head of state, since he became king following the death of Queen Elizabeth II in September 2022.</p>

<p>King Charles and Queen Camilla left Samoa Saturday after the marathon 11-day tour that saw the king carry out more than 30 engagements.</p>

<p>The royal couple visited Sydney, Canberra and the Samoan capital Apia, where King Charles attended a meeting of Commonwealth nations.</p>

<p>The 56-nation bloc -- made up mostly of British ex-colonies -- had hoped to focus on a future threatened by climate change, but instead bickered over a troubled past marked by slavery and colonisation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/svej0b98_king-charles_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[King Charles was diagnosed with an undisclosed cancer earlier this year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-alaska-airlines-after-his-dog-dies-during-flight-6886850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Sues Alaska Airlines After His Dog Dies During Flight]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-alaska-airlines-after-his-dog-dies-during-flight-6886850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:55:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The sudden relocation caused significant distress to Ash, who began exhibiting signs of respiratory distress, including heavy panting and gasping for air.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lawsuit filed against Alaska Airlines alleges negligence in the death of a French bulldog during a flight from New York to San Francisco. Michael Contillo, a San Francisco resident, claims that his beloved pet, Ash, died due to the airline's mishandling, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/news-and-advice/alaska-airlines-dog-dies-flight-first-class-coach-b2634145.html" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Independent</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Contillo and his father had purchased first-class tickets to ensure ample space and comfort for their two French bulldogs, Ash and Kora. Before the flight, both dogs were examined by a veterinarian and declared fit to fly. However, Alaska Airlines staff insisted on moving the passengers and their pets further back in the plane, citing safety concerns.</p>

<p>The sudden relocation caused significant distress to Ash, who began exhibiting signs of respiratory distress, including heavy panting and gasping for air. Mr Contillo was unable to monitor his pet during takeoff and landing due to airline regulations. Upon arriving at San Francisco International Airport, Mr Contillo discovered that Ash had died.</p>

<p><strong>The lawsuit highlights several key allegations against Alaska Airlines:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Negligence in Handling Brachycephalic Breeds: The airline allegedly failed to consider the specific needs of brachycephalic breeds like French bulldogs, which are particularly vulnerable to respiratory problems during air travel.</li>
	<li>Breach of Contract: The lawsuit claims that Alaska Airlines breached the contract by downgrading the passengers from first class without a valid reason.</li>
	<li>Inadequate Staff Training: Mr Contillo alleges that the airline's staff lacked proper training in handling animals, especially those with specific health concerns.</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition to seeking financial compensation, Mr Contillo is also seeking punitive damages to hold Alaska Airlines accountable for its negligence. The lawsuit emphasizes the emotional distress caused by the loss of his pet and the airline's lack of empathy following the incident.</p>

<p>The American Veterinary Medical Association has warned that brachycephalic breeds are at a higher risk of respiratory issues during air travel. The organization recommends that these breeds should be kept in the passenger cabin and not transported as cargo or in confined areas.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/l5q13kco_alaska-airlines-boeing-737-max-9-afp_625x300_25_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The lawsuit highlights several key allegations against Alaska Airlines]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-praises-israels-strikes-iran-warns-against-exaggeration-6886758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Praises Israel's Strikes, Iran Warns Against "Exaggeration"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-praises-israels-strikes-iran-warns-against-exaggeration-6886758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:35:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's airstrikes "hit hard" Iran's defences and missile production, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Sunday, but Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said the damage from Saturday's attack should not be exaggerated.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's airstrikes "hit hard" Iran's defences and missile production, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Sunday, but Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said the damage from Saturday's attack should not be exaggerated.</p>

<p>With warfare raging in Gaza and Lebanon, direct confrontation between Israel and Iran risks spiralling into a regional conflagration. But a day after the airstrikes, there was no sign they would spark another round of escalation.</p>

<p>However, heavy fighting in Lebanon between Israeli forces and Iran-backed Hezbollah, which sharply intensified over recent weeks, continued on Sunday with an Israeli airstrike killing eight people in a residential block in Sidon, medics said.</p>

<p>"The air force attacked throughout Iran. We hit hard Iran's defence capabilities and its ability to produce missiles that are aimed at us," Netanyahu said in a speech, calling the attack "precise and powerful" and saying it met all its objectives.</p>

<p>The Islamic Republic has not signalled how it will respond to Saturday's long-anticipated strikes, which involved scores of fighter jets bombing targets near the capital Tehran and in the western provinces of Ilam and Khuzestan.</p>

<p>The heavily armed arch-enemies have engaged in a cycle of retaliatory moves against each other for months, with Saturday's strike coming after an Iranian missile barrage on Oct. 1, much of which Israel said was downed by its air defences.</p>

<p>Khamenei said Israel's calculations "should be disrupted". The attack on Iran, which killed four soldiers and caused some damage, "should neither be downplayed nor exaggerated", he said.</p>

<p>The Iranian parliament speaker, Mohammad Baqer Qalibaf, said Iran was entitled to self-defence and its response "will be definite, in compliance with the requirements".</p>

<p>U.S. President Joe Biden called for a halt to escalation that has raised fears of a wider Middle East war arising from the year-old Israeli-Hamas conflict in Gaza and Israel's thrust into south Lebanon to stop Hezbollah rocketing northern Israel.</p>

<p>Separately, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said Iran was no longer able to use its allies Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon against Israel. The two groups "are no longer an effective tool" of Tehran, he said in a speech.</p>

<p>Gallant added that Hamas was no longer functioning as a military network in Gaza and that Hezbollah's senior command and most of its missile capabilities had been eliminated.</p>

<p>Hamas has repeatedly said it is still able to function militarily, and Israel has recently conducted major new operations in devastated north Gaza against what it calls regrouping Hamas militants.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said its command structure remains intact and that it retains significant missile capabilities.</p>

<p><strong>LEBANON FIGHTING</strong></p>

<p>On Sunday, the Israeli military urged residents of 14 villages in southern Lebanon to evacuate immediately and move north of the Awali river.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike on Sidon, a city in coastal south Lebanon, killed at least eight people and wounded 25 on Sunday, the country's health ministry said.</p>

<p>Elsewhere in the south, a strike on Zawtar al-Sharkiya killed three people and a Saturday bombing of Marjayoun killed five, it said.</p>

<p>Israel said four of its soldiers were killed in south Lebanon fighting.</p>

<p>Hezbollah also said it had fired a large missile salvo at the Zevulon military industries facility north of Haifa in northern Israel. Hezbollah rockets hit a house and cars and rescue crews responded to put out the fire.</p>

<p>One woman was seriously injured, according to Israel's ambulance service.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2lceiu2_netanyahu-khamenei-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ayatollah Khamenei said Israel's calculations "should be disrupted" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-requests-1-4-billion-loan-from-china-amid-financial-challenges-6886704]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Requests $ 1.4 Billion Loan From China Amid Financial Challenges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-requests-1-4-billion-loan-from-china-amid-financial-challenges-6886704]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:20:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a bid to address its persistent external financing issues, Pakistan has formally requested a supplementary loan of 10 billion yuan (CNY) (approximately USD 1.4 billion) from China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>In a bid to address its persistent external financing issues, Pakistan has formally requested a supplementary loan of 10 billion yuan (CNY) (approximately USD 1.4 billion) from China.</p>

<p>The announcement was made on Saturday, underscoring the fiscal pressures the nation continues to face, the Express Tribune reported.</p>

<p>During a meeting with China's Vice Minister of Finance, Liao Min, Pakistan's Finance Minister Muhammad Aurangzeb urged the Chinese side to elevate the limits under the Currency Swap Agreement to CNY 40 billion. As stated by the Ministry of Finance, Pakistan has already fully utilised the existing CNY 30 billion (USD 4.3 billion) Chinese trade facility for debt repayment and is now seeking to raise this limit by an additional CNY 10 billion, which translates to USD 1.4 billion based on current exchange rates.</p>

<p>The finance minister's appeal occurred on the sidelines of the annual meetings of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank. If approved by Beijing, the total facility would amount to approximately USD 5.7 billion.</p>

<p>This request is not unprecedented; Pakistan has previously sought increases in its debt limit, but Beijing has declined these appeals in the past. Notably, this request follows closely behind China's extension of the current USD 4.3 billion (CNY 30 billion) facility for an additional three years. This extension was formalised during the recent visit of Chinese Prime Minister Li Qiang, which also saw the debt repayment period for Pakistan extended to 2027.</p>

<p>Pakistan has fully consumed the existing trade finance facility of USD 4.3 billion under the China-Pakistan currency swap agreement. Although the Ministry of Finance did not specify the reasons behind the new request, reports suggest that uncertainties regarding some pipeline loans have prompted the need for additional financial support.</p>

<p>In a parallel move to fill the financing gap, Pakistan accepted terms for a costly USD 600 million commercial loan. However, this decision raised concerns, leading the IMF to clarify that the loan was not tied to the requirements of Pakistan's USD 7 billion bailout package. Aurangzeb later informed the National Assembly Standing Committee on Finance that the government secured USD 600 million in financing at an 11 per cent interest rate for IMF program purposes.</p>

<p>The finance ministry confirmed that both ministers reiterated the strength of the all-weather strategic cooperative partnership between Pakistan and China. Originally signed in December 2011, the bilateral currency swap agreement (CSA) aimed to promote bilateral trade, foreign direct investment, and provide short-term liquidity support.</p>

<p>In the fiscal year 2021, the initial limit of the CSA was extended from 20 billion CNY to 30 billion CNY (USD 4.5 billion) for a period of three years, with maturity periods ranging from three months to one year, according to the central bank.</p>

<p>This is not the first instance of Pakistan seeking an increase in its loan limit from China; in November 2022, then-Finance Minister Ishaq Dar also requested an additional 10 billion yuan (USD 1.5 billion) due to delays in loans from other bilateral and multilateral creditors.</p>

<p>Pakistan has primarily utilised the Chinese trade finance facility to repay foreign debts and stabilise its foreign currency reserves, preventing potential market turmoil. The current USD 4.3 billion facility is part of the State Bank of Pakistan's foreign exchange reserves, which are approximately USD 11 billion. Additionally, China has extended USD 4 billion in SAFE deposits, which are included in these reserves, along with another USD 4 billion in commercial loans. Despite these supports, Pakistan's foreign exchange reserves remain insufficient to meet its debt obligations to China.</p>

<p>The finance ministry stated that Aurangzeb expressed gratitude to the Chinese government for its unwavering support in Pakistan's socio-economic development and assistance in securing the IMF's Extended Fund Facility (EFF).</p>

<p>Furthermore, the finance minister highlighted Pakistan's eagerness to learn from China's experience in economic reform and mentioned plans to issue an inaugural Panda bond in the Chinese market to diversify its financing options.</p>

<p>Aurangzeb also assured China of comprehensive security measures for Chinese workers in Pakistan. Both parties emphasised the importance of enhancing online payment settlements and integrating the two nations' payment systems, marking a collaborative step forward in their economic partnership.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/4vc4ho7g_pak-fm-_625x300_23_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is not the first instance of Pakistan seeking an increase in its loan limit from China (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/painful-concessions-needed-to-free-gaza-hostages-israel-defence-minister-6886599]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Painful Concessions" Needed To Free Gaza Hostages: Israel Defence Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/painful-concessions-needed-to-free-gaza-hostages-israel-defence-minister-6886599]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:06:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant warned Sunday that "painful concessions" would be needed to secure the release of hostages held in Gaza and that military action alone will not achieve the country's war aims.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant warned Sunday that "painful concessions" would be needed to secure the release of hostages held in Gaza and that military action alone will not achieve the country's war aims.</p>

<p>"Not all objectives can be achieved through military operations alone... to realise our moral duty to bring our hostages home, we will have to make painful concessions," Gallant said, in a speech marking the Hebrew calendar anniversary of the Hamas attack on October 7 last year.</p>

<p>Gallant went on to name the country's military accomplishments in over a year of fighting.</p>

<p>"In the south, Hamas has ceased to act as a military structure, in the north, Hezbollah continues to suffer blows and its leadership has been eliminated, the majority of its rocket arsenal has been destroyed and its forces have retreated from the border line," he added.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>At least 42,924 Palestinians, a majority of them civilians, have since been killed in the Israeli offensive on Gaza, according to figures from the Hamas-ruled territory's health ministry, which the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>The war has also drawn in Iran-backed groups across the region, most notably Hezbollah in Lebanon, where Israel has launched a major aerial campaign and ground incursions since late September.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/v2n14a5_yoav-gallant-reuters_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Not all objectives can be achieved through military operations alone," said Yoav Gallant (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-8-killed-in-israel-strike-near-coastal-city-6886377]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Says 8 Killed In Israel Strike Near Coastal City]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-8-killed-in-israel-strike-near-coastal-city-6886377]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 19:25:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's health ministry said at least eight people were killed and 25 others wounded Sunday in an Israeli strike near the southern city of Sidon, where an AFP correspondent said a building was targeted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's health ministry said at least eight people were killed and 25 others wounded Sunday in an Israeli strike near the southern city of Sidon, where an AFP correspondent said a building was targeted.</p>

<p>The strike hit a densely-populated area in a Sidon suburb that saw an influx of families displaced from areas further south.</p>

<p>It was the first strike there since the Israel-Hezbollah war erupted last month.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy's raid on Haret Saida resulted in a... toll of eight killed," the health ministry said, revising an earlier toll of two dead.</p>

<p>The official National News Agency said a child was among the victims.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent said one apartment was destroyed in the strike on a three-storey residential complex.</p>

<p>Surrounding shops and buildings were also damaged, the correspondent said, as paramedics rushed to the site of the attack to search for survivors.</p>

<p>The Israeli army had issued an evacuation warning for several areas in south Lebanon on Sunday, but Haret Saida was not listed among the areas to be targeted.</p>

<p>The war since September 23 has left at least 1,615 people dead in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally of nationwide health ministry figures, though the real number is likely to be higher due to gaps in the data.</p>

<p>At least 1.3 million people have been displaced, more than 800,000 of them within Lebanon's borders, according to the UN's migration agency.</p>

<p>More than half a million people have crossed into Syria, according to Lebanese authorities, most of them Syrians.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/psho2ggg_lebanon-afp_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was the first strike in Sidon since the Israel-Hezbollah war erupted last month.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahus-speech-interrupted-by-hamas-attack-victims-relatives-6886188]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["My Father Was Killed": Netanyahu's Speech Interrupted By Protesters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahus-speech-interrupted-by-hamas-attack-victims-relatives-6886188]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 18:52:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Screaming relatives of Hamas attack victims interrupted a speech by Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Sunday during October 7 commemorations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Screaming relatives of Hamas attack victims interrupted a speech by Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Sunday during October 7 commemorations.</p>

<p>Netanyahu stood motionless at a lectern during the ceremony in Jerusalem as audience members in the crowd shouted, interrupting him for more than a minute, according to a live broadcast of the speech.</p>

<p>One of the protesters repeatedly shouted, "My father was killed".</p>

<p>Public and diplomatic pressure has been on Netanyahu's administration to do more to strike a deal for securing the release of captives still held in Gaza.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Netanyahu?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Netanyahu</a> | "Be ashamed of yourself"... Hurtful words from the families of Israeli prisoners of the resistance attack Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu during his speech on the anniversary of Operation Al-Aqsa Flood. <a href="https://t.co/uASeLsk1co">pic.twitter.com/uASeLsk1co</a></p>
— Jerusalem Captive (@JerusalemCapti) <a href="https://twitter.com/JerusalemCapti/status/1850525807904477360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 27, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Israeli spy chief David Barnea is scheduled to head to Doha on Sunday for talks aimed at restarting negotiations towards reaching a Gaza hostage release deal.</p>

<p>Families of the remaining hostages along with several Western leaders have called on the Israeli government to broker an agreement after the killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar earlier this month.</p>

<p>Israeli and US officials as well as some analysts said Sinwar had been a key obstacle to a deal allowing for the release of 97 hostages still held by militants in Gaza, 34 of whom the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Critics in Israel have also accused Netanyahu of obstructing mediation for a truce and hostage-release deal.</p>

<p>Earlier Sunday, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said military action by itself will not achieve the country's war aims, which include bringing home the hostages.</p>

<p>"Not all objectives can be achieved through military operations alone... To realise our moral duty to bring our hostages home, we will have to make painful concessions," Gallant said in a separate speech marking the Hebrew calendar anniversary of the Hamas attack, which on October 7 last triggered the ongoing war in the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ceenahl8_netanyahu_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu's speech was interrupted him for more than a minute.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-rs-16-lakh-raised-for-family-of-walmart-teen-found-dead-in-oven-6885300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over Rs 16 Lakh Raised For Family of Walmart Teen Found Dead In Oven]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-rs-16-lakh-raised-for-family-of-walmart-teen-found-dead-in-oven-6885300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 16:08:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to Halifax Regional Police, Ms Kaur was found dead inside an oven in the bakery section of a Halifax Walmart.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Support has poured in for the family of Gursimran Kaur, a 19-year-old Walmart employee found dead earlier this month in a walk-in oven at a Canadian Walmart store.&nbsp;The Maritime Sikh Society, to which Ms Kaur's family belongs, announced in an update on their <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/support-the-family-of-gursimran-who-lost-her-life-at-walmart" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>GoFundMe page </em></a>on Friday, October 25, that they had raised over $194,949 to assist her "bereaved family," some of whom had been in India and were working to travel to Canada for her funeral.</p>

<p>"We want to express our deepest gratitude to everyone who has donated to support Gursimran Kaur's family during this unimaginable time. Your kindness and generosity have been a source of strength for the family as they navigate through this tragedy," a representative of the group shared.</p>

<p>The society also announced that they would "turn off donations" to begin "distributing the funds to the family," with the contributions intended to support them in the coming steps.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"... We cannot thank you enough for standing with them during this painful period," the representative continued. "Thank you again for your support, compassion, and for being a part of this effort to help Gursimran's family in their time of need."</p>

<p>According to Halifax Regional Police, Ms Kaur was found dead inside an oven in the bakery section of a Halifax Walmart on the night of Saturday, October 19.</p>

<p>The Maritime Sikh Society described Kaur as "a young beautiful girl who came to Canada with big dreams." She had been at the store with her mother, who, after losing contact with her for an hour, eventually found her inside the oven. Both Kaur and her mother had been employed at the Walmart store for two years.</p>

<p>Constable Martin Cromwell told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/family-of-walmart-employee-who-died-in-oven-share-gratitude-for-public-support-8734910" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>PEOPLE</em></a> on Oct. 25 that police have not yet determined how Kaur entered the oven, noting that the investigation is "complex."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7rappps8_gursimran-kaur_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[They had raised over $194,949 to assist her "bereaved family"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truck-rams-into-bus-stop-in-tel-aviv-dozens-injured-6884771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Truck Rams Into Bus Stop In Israel's Tel Aviv, Dozens Injured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truck-rams-into-bus-stop-in-tel-aviv-dozens-injured-6884771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 14:42:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A truck rammed into a bus stop north of the commercial hub Tel Aviv on Sunday, injuring dozens of people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli emergency service and police said a truck rammed into a bus stop north of the commercial hub Tel Aviv on Sunday, injuring dozens of people.</p>

<p>Police did not immediately say what caused the incident or whether it was an attack.</p>

<p>"At 10:08 am (0808 GMT), a report was received... of a truck hitting a bus stop on Aharon Yariv Boulevard in Ramat Hasharon... Paramedics are currently providing medical treatment on site to dozens of casualties," the Magen David Adom service said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At least 16 people were initially transported to nearby hospitals, the emergency service said in a later update. Police confirmed multiple injuries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Officers and ambulances rushed to the scene, where Israeli television channels showed police cordoning off the area as medics helped the injured. A helicopter hovered above.</p>

<p>The incident comes as Israel marks the Hebrew calendar anniversary of the unprecedented Hamas attack on October 7 last year that sparked the ongoing wars in Gaza and Lebanon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/02s6q2s8_truck-rams-into-bus-stop_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 16 people were initially transported to nearby hospitals]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-iranian-officials-will-decide-how-to-respond-to-israel-irans-supreme-leader-6884708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iranian Officials Will Decide How To Respond To Israel: Ayatollah Khamenei]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-iranian-officials-will-decide-how-to-respond-to-israel-irans-supreme-leader-6884708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 14:39:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Khamenei said Iran's power should be demonstrated to Israel, adding that the way to do so should be "determined by the officials and that which is in the best interest of the people and the country should take place".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iranian officials should determine how best to demonstrate Iran's power to Israel after the Israeli attack on Iran two nights ago, Iran's official IRNA news agency cited the country's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei as saying on Sunday.</p>

<p>"The evil committed by the Zionist regime (Israel) two nights ago should neither be downplayed nor exaggerated", IRNA cited Khamenei as saying.</p>

<p>Iran on Saturday played down Israel's overnight air attack against Iranian military targets, saying it caused only limited damage, as US President Joe Biden called for a halt to escalation that has raised fears of an all-out conflagration in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Scores of Israeli jets completed three waves of strikes before dawn against missile factories and other sites near Tehran and in western Iran, Israel's military said.</p>

<p>Khamenei said Iran's power should be demonstrated to Israel, adding that the way to do so should be "determined by the officials and that which is in the best interest of the people and the country should take place".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8i699gdo_-ayatollah-khamenei_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran on Saturday played down Israel's overnight air attack against Iranian military targets]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>