<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 04:55:18 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-few-israelis-remain-in-sri-lanka-surfing-town-despite-terrorism-warning-6881460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Few Israelis Remain In Sri Lanka Surfing Town Despite Terrorism Warning]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-few-israelis-remain-in-sri-lanka-surfing-town-despite-terrorism-warning-6881460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:49:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The last of the Israelis left in a scenic surfing hotspot in Sri Lanka said they felt safe and would stay put despite a warning from the Israeli government to immediately leave due to the threat of a possible terrorist attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The last of the Israelis left in a scenic surfing hotspot in Sri Lanka said they felt safe and would stay put despite a warning from the Israeli government to immediately leave due to the threat of a possible terrorist attack.</p>

<p>Israel's national security council called on Israelis on Wednesday to get out of tourist areas in the south of the Indian Ocean island nation, saying it had information about a terrorist threat focused on tourist areas and beaches.</p>

<p>The agency did not specify the nature of the threat but said the warning pertained to the Arugam Bay area - a popular haunt for Israelis - and beaches in the south and west of the country.</p>

<p>The US embassy in Sri Lanka and the German foreign ministry also followed with similar warnings, prompting Colombo to step up security and go on high alert.</p>

<p>Sri Lankan police have arrested three suspects for questioning in connection with an unspecified threat.</p>

<p>"We are working to ensure that all tourists are protected and their safety assured at all times," police spokesman Nihal Thalduwa told Reuters.</p>

<p>There were about 600-700 Israeli tourists through September to early October in Arugam Bay, local authorities said, but that number had dwindled to just 20 when the security warning was issued this week which came at the tailend of the tourist season.</p>

<p>By Friday, 17 had moved out of the area with some of them flying out of the country, leaving behind three Israelis in the south-eastern town of about 7,000 residents.</p>

<p>One of them, who has been coming to Sri Lanka since 1991 and is a long-term resident, said he feels safe and is expecting his wife and 17-year-old twin sons to join him in a week's time.</p>

<p>"I love coming here and my family loves coming here, and we surf for about three to four hours every day when my sons are here," he told Reuters on Friday after returning home from his morning surfing. "I don't think there is a serious security threat."</p>

<p>The man, who declined to be identified, said two policemen showed up after the first security warnings. Now, there are 16 security personnel, including police special forces, stationed around his small, blue-painted house in Arugam Bay.</p>

<p>Two other Israeli men, brothers who were lounging in their room at a nearby homestay, surrounded by about eight police and special forces personnel, also said they would remain until the end of the month and then relocate to nearby Ahangama town.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka has nevertheless tightened security, with the memory of Easter Sunday bombings of 2019 still fresh. Those attacks blamed on Islamic State targeted churches and three hotels, killing 267 people, including at least 45 foreign nationals.</p>

<p><strong>UNPRECEDENTED SECURITY</strong></p>

<p>Checkpoints have sprung up on the main roads and bridges in Arugam Bay and the surrounding area, and as many as 500 police, military and special forces were deployed.</p>

<p>Police stopped vehicles and checked identification cards of passengers.</p>

<p>Israeli officials have warned of an increase in threats of attacks on Israelis outside their country since the start of the war in Gaza. &nbsp; &nbsp; There has also been a surge in reports of antisemitic incidents in many parts of the world since war broke out in the Middle East after Palestinian Islamist group Hamas attacked Israel on Oct. 7, 2023.</p>

<p>Arugam Bay residents dismissed social media speculation of tensions in the Muslim-majority town over the presence of Israelis in the wake of the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"I started renting out rooms to foreigners last year and they are happy to stay here because they are not scared," said Abubakar Rinosha, 41, who owns the homestay of the Israeli brothers.</p>

<p>Other residents said Israeli tourists are a major source of income, accounting for 70% of the town's revenue.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/eg19dnp8_arungam-bay-sri-lanka_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were 600-700 Israeli tourists through September to early October in Arugam Bay, authorities said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-blows-up-houses-in-border-villages-in-lebanon-report-6881380]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Blows Up Houses In Border Villages In Lebanon: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-blows-up-houses-in-border-villages-in-lebanon-report-6881380]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:32:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanese state media said the Israeli army dynamited houses in Lebanese border villages on Saturday, as Israel said it used 400 tonnes of explosives to destroy a Hezbollah tunnel, more than a month into an all-out war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese state media said the Israeli army dynamited houses in Lebanese border villages on Saturday, as Israel said it used 400 tonnes of explosives to destroy a Hezbollah tunnel, more than a month into an all-out war.</p>

<p>The official National News Agency said "the army of the Israeli enemy has since dawn blown up and destroyed houses" in the border village of Adaisseh.</p>

<p>The NNA also reported "large explosions" in the border village of Kfar Kila, saying the blasts were heard across the south as columns of smoke rose above the area.</p>

<p>Israeli military spokesman Avichay Adraee said 400 tonnes of explosives were used to blow up a "strategic underground facility" in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>The "tunnel" was more than 1.5 kilometres (around a mile) long, Adraee said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military had earlier reported "the explosion of a large quantity of explosives in Lebanon" that was strong enough to trigger earthquake warnings in large parts of Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli army published a video showing massive detonations at the border.</p>

<p>Lebanese state media has reported several incidents of Israeli blasts targeting houses in border villages in recent days.</p>

<p>Israel's Channel 12 broadcast footage on Friday that appeared to show one of its presenters detonating a building while embedded with Israeli troops in the south Lebanon village of Aita al-Shaab.</p>

<p>Hezbollah says it is fighting Israeli troops at close quarters in Lebanese border villages.</p>

<p>The two sides began exchanging cross-border fire last year, but all-out war erupted on September 23, when Israel ramped up its air campaign against Hezbollah strongholds in south Lebanon, the capital Beirut and the eastern Bekaa Valley.</p>

<p>The war has left at least 1,615 people dead in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally of health ministry figures though the real number is likely to be higher due to gaps in the data.</p>

<p>The war has displaced at least 1.3 million people, according to the International Organization for Migration. More than 800,000 have sought refuge inside Lebanon while more than half a million have fled to Syria, most of them Syrians, according to Lebanese authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i95ri4vo_lebanon-afp_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah says it is fighting Israeli troops at close quarters in Lebanese border villages.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-strikes-reuven-azar-could-have-inflicted-much-more-damage-israel-envoy-to-ndtv-after-iran-strikes-6881332]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Could Have Inflicted Much More Damage": Israel Envoy After Iran Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-strikes-reuven-azar-could-have-inflicted-much-more-damage-israel-envoy-to-ndtv-after-iran-strikes-6881332]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:26:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel wants peace in the region but is not ready to be attacked by Iran directly or indirectly, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel wants peace in the region but is not ready to be attacked by Iran directly or indirectly, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV on Saturday, Mr Azar said this was one of the signals that his country wanted to send with its strikes on Iran earlier in the day and the other message is that it has the capability to hit many more targets in Iran if Tehran chooses to escalate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What Israel did is a very precise strike that took out Iran's air defence systems, and targeted military installations connected to their missile and drone programmes. The signal here is very clear: Israel will not agree to continue to be attacked by Iran either directly or indirectly," the ambassador said, hinting at Iran's proxies like Hamas and Hezbollah, with which Israel is already engaged in conflicts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran had earlier launched 200 ballistic missiles at Israeli targets on October 1.</p>

<p>Claiming that Iran is now exposed, Mr Azar said Israel is not worried about comments from the regime in Tehran warning of a "proportionate reaction" to the Israeli strike.</p>

<p>"We are ready for it. We are completely coordinating with our allies, especially the United States, which is completely backing our moves. It is very clear that Israel could have done much more to inflict damage on Iran but it chose to limit its response out of responsibility because we want to stay focused on this operation that the Israeli cabinet has determined - to completely eradicate the military capabilities of Hamas, to bring back our hostages and make sure Hamas doesn't rearm," the ambassador said.</p>

<p>In the north, where Israel shares a border with Lebanon, the ambassador said that the objective is to resettle Israeli communities in the areas from which they were evacuated because of attacks from Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"We are operating there as well, we have uprooted the military infrastructure that Hezbollah has created there for decades. And we will not agree that Iran will try to intervene in that and attack Israel. If they continue doing that, Israel will feel free to act in a much more decisive manner," he warned.</p>

<p><strong>'Will Pay The Price'</strong></p>

<p>To a question on whether Israel is locked in a never-ending war, Mr Azar said while that may seem to be the case, his country is defending itself and has created a situation in which Hamas can no longer attack it with missiles and the leadership of Hezbollah has been eliminated - and it is now for Iran to "accept the new reality".</p>

<p>"If they don't accept the new reality and come to the table to create a more stable situation in our region, they will pay the price," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ambassador said routes of diplomacy are always available and insisted that Israel did not start the war, which began after the October 7, 2023, attacks by Hamas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We want to restore peace in our region. We are prepared for diplomacy, but it has to lay on the foundation of the understanding of the other side that Israel will be relentless. We will not rest until we are sure that assurances for our security are met and we will maintain the right to self-defence against any aggression in the future," he said.</p>

<p><strong>'Downplaying Is Good'</strong></p>

<p>On Iran claiming that the Israeli attack caused limited damage and its defence systems worked, Mr Azar said he was happy that Tehran was "downplaying" it because it could be a sign that it was not interested in continuing the aggression.</p>

<p>"Anybody that knows something about military capabilities knows that the S-300 (air defence system) that the Iranians have is not capable of stopping the F-35s and the F-16s of the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) and not capable of stopping our pilots from hitting any targets they want. So they can continue saying what they want but the situation is very clear and the message has been conveyed in a very clear way," he said. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/htj4obo8_reuven-azar-marya-shakil_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Azar said Israel is pursuing a list of stated objectives.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-killed-after-cargo-truck-collides-with-passenger-bus-in-mexico-6881324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[24 Killed After Cargo Truck Collides With Passenger Bus In Mexico]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-killed-after-cargo-truck-collides-with-passenger-bus-in-mexico-6881324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 23:21:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A cargo truck collided with a passenger bus in northern Mexico on Saturday, leaving at least 24 people dead and five others injured, local authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A cargo truck collided with a passenger bus in northern Mexico on Saturday, leaving at least 24 people dead and five others injured, local authorities said.</p>

<p>"So far, the preliminary information available is that 24 passengers have died and five people are injured and are being treated," Rodrigo Reyes, a senior official in the government of Zacatecas state, said in a video on social media.</p>

<p>The accident, on a highway that connects Zacatecas with the central state of Aguascalientes, occurred when a container filled with corn fell off the truck, causing the bus to overturn.</p>

<p>The bus was traveling between the city of Tepic, in western Nayarit state, and Ciudad Juarez on the US border.</p>

<p>The highway was closed to traffic, Reyes said, adding that army, National Guard and civil protection forces were deployed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/s625qv4o_accident-generic-_625x300_16_December_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bus was traveling between the city of Tepic and Ciudad Juarez on the US border (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/town-of-kyle-saskatchewan-this-canadian-town-cant-find-anyone-to-run-for-mayor-6880885]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Canadian Town Can't Find Anyone To Run For Mayor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/town-of-kyle-saskatchewan-this-canadian-town-cant-find-anyone-to-run-for-mayor-6880885]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 21:51:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With Kyle, Saskatchewan's November municipal election approaching, the town faces a notable obstacle: no candidates have stepped up to run for mayor or fill an open Town Council seat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the November municipal election draws near, Kyle, a small town in Saskatchewan, Canada, is facing an unforeseen problem: there are no contenders for the mayorship, according to <em>CKOM.COM.</em></p>

<p>This year, current Mayor George Williams, who assumed office in November 2021, is scheduled to resign, leaving his position unfilled and without any candidates. Furthermore, there are still no nominees for a Town Council position.</p>

<p>Two rounds of candidate applications have been released to promote mayor nominations, but thus far, no one has shown interest, according to Chief Administrative Officer Amber Dashney.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's a little concerning, but I am confident that someone will step forward," Dashney told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ckom.com/2024/10/24/its-not-unusual-town-of-kyle-looking-for-mayor-candidate/"><em>CKOM.COM.</em></a></p>

<p>The council will designate a deputy mayor to assume the duties of mayor if the post is not filled by the election on November 13.</p>

<p>"At that meeting, we will decide on a date for a by-election, and we will continue calling a by-election until we fill the mayor spot and the other councilor spot, as well," Dashney said.</p>

<p>Gordon Barnhart, former President of the Saskatchewan Urban Municipalities Association (SUMA), said it can occur from time to time were nobody steps forward for council or mayoral nominations.</p>

<p>"I'm not sure that it's common, but it's not unusual," he said.</p>

<p>He said it can be hard for small communities to find enough people willing and able to run for mayor or for council.</p>

<p>In 2016, Barnhart was elected as a councillor for the Town of Saltcoats - a community 30 kilometres southeast of Yorkton - through a byelection after some convincing from local community members.</p>

<p>Due to several vacant councillor positions, Barnhart said the town risked not meeting quorum at council meetings. He would go on to serve as a councillor in Saltcoats until 2020, before being elected as mayor where he sat until 2022.</p>

<p>"It is really a dedication to your community where you feel that you can make a difference," Barnhart said.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www12.statcan.gc.ca/census-recensement/2021/dp-pd/prof/index.cfm?Lang=E">2021 Statistics Canada census data,</a> the Town of Kyle has population of 413, and the Town of Saltcoats has a population of 473.</p>

<p>While towns and villages have smaller populations to choose from, Barnhart said people's time and confidence may be factors that prevent people from running for a seat.</p>

<p>In a statement, SUMA said as long as council can maintain quorum, it can continue with meetings.</p>

<p>"While it's rare, it's not unheard of for no one to put their name forward for mayor, or for too few people to put their names forward for council," the statement read. "In nearly all cases, someone will put their name in for the following byelection and the spot will be filled."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e2ea6348_town-of-kyle-saskatchewan_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite two rounds of applications, no one has stepped up.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-gambling-boom-results-in-80-million-people-facing-disorders-worldwide-6880617]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Digital Gambling Boom Results In 80 Million Facing Disorders Worldwide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-gambling-boom-results-in-80-million-people-facing-disorders-worldwide-6880617]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 21:01:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent study by The Lancet Public Health Commission reveals that approximately 80 million people worldwide suffer from gambling disorders, with adolescents being the most affected.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An estimated 80 million people worldwide suffer from gambling disorders or problematic gambling as a result of the digital revolution's substantial expansion of the online casino and sports betting markets. Adolescents are the most affected group, according to a recent study by the Lancet Public Health Commission.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thelancet.com/commissions/gambling">Commission's research</a> further states that children and teenagers are being exposed to gambling product marketing in previously unheard-of ways. Because of this exposure, they are especially vulnerable to the allure of quick cash and the addictive qualities of online gambling sites.</p>

<p>There is a pressing need for greater knowledge and preventative measures to protect vulnerable people from the dangers of online gambling as the prevalence of gambling problems rises, particularly among younger populations.</p>

<p>The author of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thelancet.com/commissions/gambling">reports said </a>that "gambling is not an ordinary kind of leisure; it can be a health-harming, addictive behaviour. The harms associated with gambling are wide-ranging, affecting not only an individual's health and wellbeing but also their wealth and relationships, families, and communities, and deepening health and societal inequalities."</p>

<p>"By examining these harms, the Commission unveils the intersections between the social, commercial, legal, and political determinants of health. The Commission sheds light on the increasingly complex commercial ecosystem for gambling and its digital transformation, which offers unparalleled capacities for gambling," the report further said.</p>

<p>The Commission calls on governments and policymakers to treat gambling as a public health issue-just as for other addictive and health-harming commodities, such as alcohol and tobacco-and provides recommendations to prevent and mitigate the broad range of harms associated with gambling," the report further said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3e1t8gr_gambling_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The research highlights unprecedented exposure of teenagers to gambling.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-it-has-right-to-defend-itself-after-todays-strikes-israel-warns-of-heavy-price-6880052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Says It Has "Right" To Defend Itself After Today's Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-it-has-right-to-defend-itself-after-todays-strikes-israel-warns-of-heavy-price-6880052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 19:33:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran warned on Saturday it would defend itself after Israeli air strikes killed at least two soldiers and further stoked fears of a full-scale regional war in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran warned on Saturday it would defend itself after Israeli air strikes killed at least two soldiers and further stoked fears of a full-scale regional war in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Israel warned Iran would "pay a heavy price" if it responded to the strikes, and the United States, Germany and Britain demanded Tehran not escalate the conflict further.</p>

<p>Other countries, including many of Iran's neighbours, condemned Israel's strikes and some, such as Russia, urged both sides to show restraint and avoid what Moscow dubbed a "catastrophic scenario".</p>

<p>The Islamic republic insisted it had the "right and the duty" to defend itself, while its Lebanese ally Hezbollah said it had already launched rocket salvos targeting five residential areas in northern Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli army said 80 projectiles were fired across the border on Saturday.</p>

<p>Confirming its own strikes after explosions and anti-aircraft fire echoed around Tehran, the Israel military said it had hit Iranian missile factories and military facilities in several regions.</p>

<p>The "retaliatory strike has been completed and the mission was fulfilled", while Israeli aircraft "returned safely", a military spokesman added.</p>

<p>Iran confirmed Israel had targeted military sites in Tehran province around the capital and other parts of the country, saying the raids caused "limited damage" but killed two soldiers.</p>

<p><strong>Direct attack</strong></p>

<p>Israel had vowed to retaliate after October 1, when Iran fired around 200 missiles in only the second ever direct attack against its arch-foe. Most of those missiles were intercepted but one person was killed.</p>

<p>The Israeli retaliation drew condemnation from Hamas, Iraq, Pakistan, Syria and Saudi Arabia, which warned against further escalation. Jordan stated that Israeli jets had not used its airspace. Turkey was one of the most outspoken critics, calling for an end to "terror created by Israel".</p>

<p>Israel is already engaged in combat on two fronts.</p>

<p>Since last month, it has been fighting a war against Hezbollah in Lebanon, including strikes that have killed the group's senior leadership and ground incursions seeking to destroy missile sites.</p>

<p>And, for more than a year since Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack, Israel has been fighting a war in Gaza that has caused mass civilian casualties in the densely populated Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>The United Nations has warned the "darkest moment" of that conflict was unfolding, with Palestinians facing a dire humanitarian crisis and daily Israeli bombing.</p>

<p>Along with Hezbollah and Hamas, Iranian-allied groups in Yemen, Iraq and Syria, have carried out attacks during the fallout from the Gaza war.</p>

<p>At roughly the same time as Israel struck targets in Iran, the Syrian state news agency SANA said an Israeli air attack targeted military positions in central and southern Syria.</p>

<p><strong>'Iranian proxies'</strong></p>

<p>The Islamic Resistance in Iraq, a loose network of pro-Iran factions, claimed responsibility before dawn Saturday for a drone attack against a "military target" in northern Israel.</p>

<p>On Friday, two people died from shrapnel wounds after a Hezbollah rocket barrage into Israel's north, Israeli officials said.</p>

<p>In addition to the residential strikes, Hezbollah said it had fired rockets at Israeli soldiers near the village of Aita al-Shaab in southern Lebanon and at an intelligence base as well as launching drones against Israel's Tel Nof air base south of Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Lebanon's health ministry said an Israeli strike had killed a Hezbollah-affiliated medic in Bazuriyeh in the south of the country.</p>

<p>US National Security Council spokesman Sean Savett said Israel's response to Iran was "an exercise in self-defence".</p>

<p>He urged Iran to "cease its attacks on Israel so that this cycle of fighting can end without further escalation".</p>

<p>The Israeli military has blamed "Iran and its proxies" in the region for "relentlessly attacking Israel since October 7", when Hamas's attack against Israel triggered the Gaza war.</p>

<p>That attack resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Dozens of hostages seized on that day are still held by militants in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory bombardment and ground war in Gaza has killed 42,924 people, the majority civilians, according to data from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, figures the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>In late September Israel turned its focus to Lebanon hitting, Hezbollah targets and leaders and then sending in ground troops.</p>

<p>Israel says the aim is to make the north of its country safe for tens of thousands of displaced civilians to return.</p>

<p>At least 1,580 people have been killed in Lebanon since September 23, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures.</p>

<p>In April, in its first-ever direct assault against Israeli territory, Iran launched more than 300 drones and missiles.</p>

<p>Tehran said the barrage was retaliation for a strike on Iran's consular annexe in Damascus that killed members of its Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps.</p>

<p>Explosions later in April shook Iran's Isfahan province in what US officials, cited by American media, said was Israeli retaliation.</p>

<p><strong>Hospital under threat</strong></p>

<p>Iran said its October 1 missile attack on Israel was retaliation for an Israeli air raid that killed Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah as well as the assassination in Tehran of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>On Friday, Gaza's health ministry accused Israeli forces of storming the last functioning hospital in the territory's north in a raid it said left two children dead.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its forces were operating around Kamal Adwan Hospital in north Gaza's Jabalia refugee camp but it was "not aware of live fire and strikes in the area of the hospital".</p>

<p>The Israeli military says it is seeking to destroy operational capabilities Hamas is trying to rebuild in the north.</p>

<p>Also on Friday, Gaza's civil defence agency said Israeli drone strikes killed 12 people waiting to receive aid near the Al-Shati refugee camp.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0l0tnul8_tehran-afp_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran confirmed Israel had targeted military sites in Tehran province, killing two soldiers (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-depsang-demchok-disengagement-military-worked-in-unimaginable-conditions-s-jaishankar-on-china-pact-6879775]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Military Worked In Unimaginable Conditions": S Jaishankar On China Pact]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-depsang-demchok-disengagement-military-worked-in-unimaginable-conditions-s-jaishankar-on-china-pact-6879775]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 18:48:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite the patrolling agreement with China, which was announced earlier this week, it will take time to rebuild trust and for the two countries to be willing to work with each other, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite the patrolling agreement with China, which was announced earlier this week, it will take time to rebuild trust and for the two countries to be willing to work with each other, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar has said.</p>

<p>During an interaction with students from a university in Pune on Saturday, Mr Jaishankar said the breakthrough with China was possible because the military enabled India to stand its ground and make its point and diplomacy also did its part. A focus on infrastructure in border areas, which enabled effective deployment of the military, also played a key role.</p>

<p>Responding to a question on the patrolling and disengagement agreement in the Depsang and Demchok areas in Eastern Ladakh and what can be expected from the future of India-China relations, the minister said, "From 2020, the situation at the border has been very disturbed and that has, understandably, had a very negative impact on the overall relationship. Since September 2020, we have been negotiating with the Chinese on how to find a solution."</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said there were different aspects to the solution but the pressing one was disengagement because "the troops are very very close up to each other and the possibility of something happening, god forbid, is there". The other aspects, he said are de-escalation, given the troop buildup by China and India's response to it, and the larger question of boundary settlement.</p>

<p>The focus, for now, is disengagement, the minister said, stressing that while there had been understandings in some areas after 2020, blocking of patrolling remained an issue which was being negotiated for two years. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"So, what happened on October 21 was that in Depsang and Demchok, we came to the understanding that patrolling would be resumed how it used to be before... This was important because it was an affirmation that if we can do the disengagement, then it is possible for the leadership level to meet, which is what happened (with the Prime Minister Narendra Modi-Chinese President Xi Jinping meeting) in Russia's Kazan during the BRICS summit," he said during the interaction at FLAME University in Pune.</p>

<p><strong>Future Of Ties</strong></p>

<p>On the question of where the India-China relationship goes from here, Mr Jaishankar said, "I think it is a bit early. We have to wait for things to settle themselves. Because, after four years of a very disturbed border where peace and tranquillity have been shattered, it will naturally take time to rebuild a degree of trust and a willingness to work with each other."</p>

<p>"If we have reached where we have today, there are two reasons for it. The first is a very determined effort on our part to stand our ground and make our point and this would only happen because the military was there in very, very unimaginable conditions to defend the country. The military did its part and diplomacy did its part," he emphasised.</p>

<p>The second reason, the minister said, was the importance given to improving infrastructure in the border areas in the past decade.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Today, we have put in almost five times annually the resources that would be there a decade ago. That's showing results and that enables the military to be effectively deployed. I would be patient. When PM Modi and President Xi met, it was decided that the foreign ministers and national security advisers would meet and see how this should be taken forward," he explained.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Process On</strong></p>

<p>NDTV had reported on Friday on satellite images showing tents and semi-permanent structures being removed by the Chinese side in Depsang and Demchok.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The patrolling agreement had been announced by Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri on Monday and army sources had said on Friday that the process of disengagement would be completed in the two contentious areas by October 29. PM Modi and Mr Jinping welcomed the agreement when they met on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The stand-off between the Indian and Chinese armies began on May 2020 and a deadly clash took place in Ladakh's Galwan the next month in which 20 Indian soldiers were killed in action and an unspecified number on the Chinese side also died.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A troop buildup followed and, after months of talks, Indian and Chinese troops withdrew from the contentious Gogra-Hot Springs area in Ladakh in September 2022 and returned to the pre-April-2020 position.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s43j36bc_s-jaishankar-brics-summit-pti_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The minister said a focus on border infrastructure has also paid dividends.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/16-vloggers-tiktokers-arrested-in-pakistans-punjab-for-spreading-fake-news-of-rape-6879764]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[16 Vloggers, TikTokers Arrested In Pakistan For Spreading Fake News Of Rape]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/16-vloggers-tiktokers-arrested-in-pakistans-punjab-for-spreading-fake-news-of-rape-6879764]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 18:45:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Law enforcement agencies have arrested more than a dozen vloggers and TikTokers accusing them of spreading fake stories about an alleged rape of a girl student that led to violent protests across Punjab province over a week ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Law enforcement agencies have arrested more than a dozen vloggers and TikTokers accusing them of spreading fake stories about an alleged rape of a girl student that led to violent protests across Punjab province over a week ago.</p>

<p>Senior Punjab police officer Imran Kishwar said on Saturday that police have also identified 40 students involved in vandalism and violence.</p>

<p>The Federal Investigation Agency (FIA) and the local police have already arrested 16 individuals, mostly vloggers and tiktokers, during the week for their alleged involved in spreading a fake rape story, he said, adding, those identified for vandalism and violence will be arrested soon.</p>

<p>"We have also blocked 138 social media accounts spreading fake news about the incident," he added.</p>

<p>The FIA said that technical reports of the cybercrime wing had identified social media accounts of 38 senior journalists, lawyers, vloggers and TikTokers who were found involved in sharing the news of the alleged fake propaganda, instigating the general public to involve in ransacking the government and private infrastructure.</p>

<p>At least 50 students were injured and one security guard killed during massive protests that had turned violent across several cities of Punjab province last week following a social media report about a female student allegedly raped by a security guard at a women's college in Lahore. Police had also detained over 600 students.</p>

<p>Later, an investigative committee formed by Punjab Chief Minister Maryam Nawaz found no evidence of rape at the college, nor did it find any eyewitnesses.</p>

<p>The committee conducted interviews with around 28 students, who mentioned they had heard about the incident from others. The committee's report stated that the matter was sensationalised through social media posts.</p>

<p>Maryam Nawaz blamed former jailed prime minister Imran Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf for exploiting the matter through social media.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/hnf0rnu_pakistan-police-generic_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[16 individuals have already been arrested by cops (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-health-workers-injured-44-detained-at-gaza-hospital-who-6879705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Health Workers Injured, 44 Detained At Gaza Hospital: WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-health-workers-injured-44-detained-at-gaza-hospital-who-6879705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 18:34:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization said it has regained contact with staff at a besieged northern Gaza hospital, finding that three health workers had been injured and 44 detained.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization said it has regained contact with staff at a besieged northern Gaza hospital, finding that three health workers had been injured and 44 detained.</p>

<p>Kamal Adwan, northern Gaza's last functioning hospital, "is still under siege, but we managed to get in touch with the staff", WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said on X late Friday.</p>

<p>"Three health workers and another employee have been injured, 44 health workers have been detained and four ambulances damaged," he said.</p>

<p>On Friday Gaza's health ministry accused Israeli forces of storming Kamal Adwan hospital in the Jabalia camp, where it launched a major operation earlier this month.</p>

<p>It said the raid left two children dead, and accused the Israeli forces of detaining hundreds of staff, patients and displaced people during the raid.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its forces were operating around Kamal Adwan, but was "not aware of live fire and strikes in the area of the hospital".</p>

<p>Amid the chaos, WHO said Friday afternoon that it had lost contact with staff at Kamal Adwan, with Tedros describing the development in an earlier post on X the development as "deeply disturbing".</p>

<p>Tedros said the WHO and partner agencies had reached the hospital late on Wednesday night and managed to transfer 23 patients and 26 caregivers to the Palestinian territory's main Al-Shifa Hospital.</p>

<p>"Kamal Adwan Hospital has been overflowing with close to 200 patients -- a constant stream of horrific trauma cases. It is also full of hundreds of people seeking shelter," he said.</p>

<p>In his second post, Tedros highlighted that, in all, "around 600 patients, health workers and individuals are currently sheltering in the hospital".</p>

<p>"The siege and attacks on health workers occurred just hours after the WHO-led mission which delivered essential supplies to keep the facility operational and took critical patients to Al-Shifa Hospital," he said.</p>

<p>"We urge for hospitals, health workers and patients to be protected. Ceasefire!"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q478s5m_kamal-adwan-hospital-gaza_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Friday, Gaza's health ministry accused Israeli forces of storming Kamal Adwan hospital (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-in-suicide-bombing-in-pakistan-cops-6879568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8 Killed In Suicide Bombing In Pakistan: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-in-suicide-bombing-in-pakistan-cops-6879568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 18:19:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A suicide bomber detonated at a checkpoint in western Pakistan on Saturday, killing eight people and wounding five more, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A suicide bomber detonated at a checkpoint in western Pakistan on Saturday, killing eight people and wounding five more, officials said.</p>

<p>The bomber set off the blast from the back of a motorbike rickshaw near the town of Mir Ali in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province, a local police officer told AFP on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>Four police officers were killed alongside two members of a state paramilitary force and two civilians in the attack near the border with Afghanistan, he said.</p>

<p>Pakistan has seen an increase in militancy since the Afghan Taliban returned to power in 2021, with Islamabad claiming hostile groups are now using the neighbouring country for shelter.</p>

<p>"Among the five injured personnel, the condition of three is critical, and they have been transferred to a local military hospital," the police officer said.</p>

<p>A local government official who also did not want to be named confirmed the same toll of dead and wounded.</p>

<p>The attack was claimed by a little-known militant group calling itself "Aswad ul-Harb".</p>

<p>Another checkpost near the Afghan border was raided this week by the Pakistani Taliban, killing 10 police officers.</p>

<p>Last year, the country saw more suicide attacks than any year since 2014, according to the Pakistan Institute for Conflict and Security Studies.</p>

<p>There were 29 suicide attacks registered, killing 329 people in Pakistan's deadliest year in a decade.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-06/5npl2qas_pakistan-flag-reuters_625x300_24_June_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack was claimed by a little-known militant group calling itself "Aswad ul-Harb" (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-in-terrorist-attack-in-iran-report-6879419]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Cops Killed In "Terrorist Attack" In Iran: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-in-terrorist-attack-in-iran-report-6879419]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 17:53:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 10 police officers were killed in a "terrorist attack" in an area of southeastern Iran long plagued by unrest, local media reported on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 10 police officers were killed in a "terrorist attack" in an area of southeastern Iran long plagued by unrest, local media reported on Saturday.</p>

<p>They were killed during an attack on "police vehicles" in Sistan-Baluchistan province's Taftan county, the Mehr and Tasnim news agencies reported, without saying how it was carried out.</p>

<p>No group immediately claimed responsibility for the attack, which occurred some 1,200 kilometres (745 miles) southeast of the capital Tehran.</p>

<p>The official IRNA news agency, citing a police statement, reported the death of "10 personnel in two patrol units" in what it called an ambush.</p>

<p>Sistan-Baluchistan borders Pakistan and Afghanistan, and is one of the most impoverished provinces in the Islamic republic.</p>

<p>It is home to a large number of the Baluch minority, an ethnic group spread between Iran, Pakistan and Afghanistan who practise Sunni Islam in contrast to the country's predominantly Shiite population.</p>

<p>The province has experienced recurring clashes between Iranian security forces and rebels from the Baluch minority, radical Sunni groups and drug traffickers.</p>

<p>Saturday's attack was one of the deadliest attacks in the area in recent months.</p>

<p>In early October, at least six people, including police officers, were killed in the province in two separate attacks.</p>

<p>The Pakistan-based Sunni jihadist group Jaish al-Adl -- Army of Justice in Arabic -- claimed responsibility for the two attacks in a message on Telegram.</p>

<p>Formed in 2012 by Baluch separatists, the group is considered a "terrorist organisation" by both Iran and the United States.</p>

<p>Iran and Pakistan frequently accuse each other of allowing rebel groups to operate and launch attacks from their respective territories.</p>

<p>In mid-January, Iran carried out a strike in Pakistan and targeted the Jaish al-Adl headquarters, according to the Mehr agency.</p>

<p>Describing themselves as "soldiers of Allah", the group's members regularly call for "armed jihad" against the Islamic republic.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/cvee6ek_iran-flag-generic-_625x300_18_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[No group immediately claimed responsibility for the attack (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chronic-kidney-disease-cases-in-women-tripled-in-last-3-decades-study-6878622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chronic Kidney Disease Cases In Women Tripled In Last 3 Decades: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chronic-kidney-disease-cases-in-women-tripled-in-last-3-decades-study-6878622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 15:34:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The number of chronic kidney disease (CKD) cases in women has nearly tripled in the past three decades globally, according to a new study led by researchers from the Gujarat Adani Institute of Medical Sciences (GAIMS).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The number of chronic kidney disease (CKD) cases in women has nearly tripled in the past three decades globally, according to a new study led by researchers from the Gujarat Adani Institute of Medical Sciences (GAIMS).</p>

<p>Type 2 diabetes and hypertension were the leading causes of CKD-related deaths in women, said the research which was presented at the ASN Kidney Week 2024' in San Diego in the US from October 2327.</p>

<p>This calls for immediate policy interventions, targeted prevention programmes, and investment in health care infrastructure to curb the rise of CKD, particularly in high-risk regions, senior author Hardik Dineshbhai Desai, an independent clinical and public health researcher at GAIMS.</p>

<p>GAIMS is the first public-private-partnership (PPP) endeavour between the Gujarat government and Adani Education and Research Foundation.</p>

<p>The analysis, titled Global, National, and Regional Trends in the Burden of Chronic Kidney Disease among Women from 1990- 2021: A Comprehensive Global Analysis,' drew from the Global Burden of Disease' study 2021, a comprehensive effort to quantify health loss across the world over time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From 1990 to 2021, the average annual percentage change in CKD prevalence in women increased by 2.10 per cent, mortality by 3.39 per cent, and disability-adjusted life years by 2.48 per cent.</p>

<p>There have also been significant disparities in CKD-related mortality and morbidity across the world, with marked increases observed particularly in Latin America, North America, and among older adults.</p>

<p>The study showed an alarming increased mortality rate attributable to metabolic risk factor over the last decade after a slight decrease between 2000 and 2010.</p>

<p>Public awareness campaigns about the importance of early diagnosis, healthy lifestyles, and the management of underlying conditions like diabetes and hypertension are critical, said Desai.</p>

<p>Without swift action, the continued rise of CKD could overwhelm health care systems and lead to increased mortality and morbidity worldwide, he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vo1tp10g_kidney-_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chronic Kidney Disease Cases In Women Tripled In Last 3 Decades: Study (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-syria-backs-irans-right-to-self-defense-after-israeli-strikes-6878324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syria Backs Iran's "Right To Self-Defense" After Israeli Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-syria-backs-irans-right-to-self-defense-after-israeli-strikes-6878324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 14:46:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Syria condemned Israeli air strikes against Iran on Saturday, saying it affirmed its ally's right to self-defence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syria condemned Israeli air strikes against Iran on Saturday, saying it affirmed its ally's right to self-defence.</p>

<p>Expressing its "solidarity" with Iran, the Syrian foreign ministry said in a statement that it supported "Iran's legitimate right to defend itself and protect its territory and the lives of its citizens".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/phn98hb8_israel-iran-conflict-generic-_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Syria expressed its "solidarity" with Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/six-russian-convicts-escape-prison-through-secret-tunnel-manhunt-launched-6878257]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Russian Convicts Escape Prison Through Secret Tunnel, Manhunt Launched]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/six-russian-convicts-escape-prison-through-secret-tunnel-manhunt-launched-6878257]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 14:30:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian authorities announced a manhunt on Saturday after six convicts tunnelled their way out a correctional facility.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian authorities announced a manhunt on Saturday after six convicts tunnelled their way out a correctional facility.</p>

<p>Four of the six fugitives have now been detained, while local law enforcement are in hot pursuit of the remaining two.</p>

<p>"I realise that the news may cause concern, but I ask you not to panic," said Igor Artamonov, governor of the western Lipetsk region.</p>

<p>"Security forces are continuing efforts to track down and detain the criminals," he added.</p>

<p>Prison guards were alerted to their disappearance after carrying out a routine inspection.</p>

<p>"In general regime penal colony No. 2, an underground tunnel was discovered during a patrol of the premises," the prison service of the Lipetsk region said.</p>

<p>"Immediately a count of convicts got underway, which revealed the absence of six inmates," it added.</p>

<p>It did not reveal their identities, but said in a statement the suspects were "from Central Asia".</p>

<p>Four of the escapees were detained, two of whom were caught in the neighbouring Tambov region, the local governor said.</p>

<p>"The search for the remaining two criminals continues," he said.</p>

<p>The Lipetsk region is about 300 kilometres (190 miles) south of Moscow.</p>

<p>Russia has one of the highest prison populations in the world, totalling more than 400,000 people last year, but numbers have decreased as convicts are sent to fight in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Prison escapes are relatively rare in Russia and those who manage to break out are often quickly caught.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/c9cdh8ao_us-prison-generic-us-jail-generic-getty_625x300_24_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The suspects were "from Central Asia". (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-long-distance-strikes-on-iran-today-has-parallels-to-1981-attack-on-iraq-nuclear-reactor-6878213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Long-Distance Strike On Iran Has Parallels To 1981 Attack On Iraq]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-long-distance-strikes-on-iran-today-has-parallels-to-1981-attack-on-iraq-nuclear-reactor-6878213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 14:25:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli attack on Iran targeted military sites today, killing two soldiers, almost a month after Israel vowed to avenge a missile barrage that raised fears of a full-scale Middle East war. The airstrikes hit Iran's missile manufacturing units.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="sp_only-ul-ol sp_only-ul-ol-2">
<ol>
	<li>Today's Israeli airstrikes on Iran have parallels to a June 1981 airstrike on Iraq, called Operation Opera - simply on the distance covered and the level of risk. NDTV <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/operation-opera-daring-1981-airstrike-on-nuclear-reactor-in-focus-as-israel-faces-multi-front-war-4471744">reported last year</a> that Israel would not hesitate to carry out a similar strike on Iran if it found itself cornered.</li>
	<li>Just like today's airstrikes, which according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.jpost.com/middle-east/iran-news/article-826126" rel="nofollow,noindex"><em>The Jerusalem Post</em></a> involved over 100 aircraft including the US-made stealth fighter jet F-35 flying a roundtrip of 2,000 km, a concern in 1981's Operation Opera was about selecting the flight path as there were several constraints - a great distance to target (1,100 km), several hostile countries on the way, and limited amount of fuel.</li>
	<li>The Jerusalem Post reported today's massive air operation likely began with initial waves attacking radar and air defence systems, which set the airspace safe and clear for subsequent strikes on military bases in Iran.</li>
	<li>In Operation Opera, on June 7, 1981 at 4 pm, 14 fighter jets took off from Etzion airport in Israel. At approximately 5.30 pm, they struck and destroyed the Osirak nuclear reactor in Iraq, successfully completing their mission with no loss of any Israeli aircraft.</li>
	<li>Israel used F-16As in the strike on Iraq in 1981, with F-15As providing escort. The jets carried a massive amount of fuel in external tanks and flew extremely low for a long distance. However, with improvement in technology - modern versions of F-15 and F-16 are still in service - Israel likely did not have to face the kind of stress it did back in 1981, though the risk would still be high due to a parallel improvement in air defence technology.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0a94e6e_iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A view of Tehran after several explosions were heard in the city due to Israeli airstrikes]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/seoul-is-spending-327-million-to-tackle-lonely-deaths-epidemic-6877705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Seoul Spending $327 Million To Stop "Lonely Deaths" Epidemic. What It Is]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/seoul-is-spending-327-million-to-tackle-lonely-deaths-epidemic-6877705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 14:23:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Seoul authorities, while announcing the $327 million initiative this week, stated that they want to "create a city where no one is lonely."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in South Korea's capital city Seoul plan to spend 451.3 billion won (around $327 million) in the next five years to tackle "lonely deaths" - a crisis that sees thousands of its citizens, mostly middle-aged men, dying alone every year after getting unnoticed by their family and friends.</p>

<p>Known as 'godoksa' in Korea, these deaths are part of a larger problem of loneliness and isolation in the country, as the government is making all possible efforts to fight it. Sometimes, it takes days and even weeks for the authorities to find these bodies, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/24/asia/south-korea-loneliness-deaths-intl-hnk/index.html">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>Seoul authorities, while announcing the $327 million initiative this week, stated that they want to "create a city where no one is lonely."</p>

<p>Apart from this, they will provide loneliness counsellors on a 24/7 hotline and an online platform for similar counselling, besides other follow-up measures like in-person visits and consultations.</p>

<p>In an official release, Seoul Mayor Oh Se-hoon said the city authorities will mobilise all its municipal capacity to help the people feeling lonely to heal and "return to society". "Loneliness and isolation are not just individual problems, but tasks that society must solve together," Oh Se-hoon said.</p>

<p>The city also plans to introduce several other measures like expanded psychological services, green spaces, nutritional meal plans for middle-aged and elderly people as well as a dedicated "search system" for identifying the isolated residents who are seeking help.</p>

<p>Also, there will be activities carried out to encourage people to venture outside and connect with others. Among these are sports, gardening, book clubs and more, the CNN report said.</p>

<p>As per the latest figures by South Korea's Ministry of Health and Welfare, the number of "lonely deaths" reached 3,661 last year, significantly higher from 3,559 in 2022 and 3,378 in 2021.</p>

<p>However, part of that increase might be due to the broader definition of "lonely death" by the ministry concerned. To qualify as a 'lonely death,' a body had to be found only after a certain amount of time earlier, but the term now is applied to any individual, who stays in social isolation, away from family and relatives and dies by suicide or illness.</p>

<p>South Korea's demographic crisis could be another factor behind this rise. A downtrend in the birth rate and ageing population shows that there have been consistently more deaths in the country than births in recent years. The overall death rate in South Korea, including "lonely deaths," is rising. Also, men in their 50s and 60s made up over half the total group.</p>

<p dir="ltr"></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rk6naja8_seoul-lonely-deaths_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-hamas-war-blatant-violation-of-iranian-sovereignty-hamas-on-israeli-strikes-on-iran-6878043]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Blatant Violation Of Sovereignty": Hamas After Israel Strikes Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-hamas-war-blatant-violation-of-iranian-sovereignty-hamas-on-israeli-strikes-on-iran-6878043]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:54:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas, at war with Israel in Gaza, on Saturday said it strongly condemned Israeli strikes on military targets in Iran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian Islamist movement Hamas, at war with Israel in Gaza, on Saturday said it strongly condemned Israeli strikes on military targets in Iran.</p>

<p>"We... condemn in the strongest terms the Zionist aggression against the Islamic Republic of Iran, and the targeting of military sites in several provinces", the movement said in a statement, calling the move "a blatant violation of Iranian sovereignty and an escalation that threatens the security of the region".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nkjh1hco_israel-iran_625x300_05_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas called Israel's strikes a "blatant violation of Iranian sovereignty".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sends-back-illegal-indian-immigrants-on-chartered-flight-ahead-of-polls-6877764]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sends Back Illegal Indian Immigrants On Chartered Flight Ahead Of Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sends-back-illegal-indian-immigrants-on-chartered-flight-ahead-of-polls-6877764]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:08:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US hired a chartered flight to deport Indian nationals who were staying in the country illegally, the Department of Homeland Security has said, noting that this has been done in cooperation with the Indian government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US hired a chartered flight to deport Indian nationals who were staying in the country illegally, the Department of Homeland Security has said, noting that this has been done in cooperation with the Indian government.</p>

<p>The charter flight was sent to India on October 22, the department said on Friday. "Indian nationals without a legal basis to remain in the United States are subject to swift removal, and intending migrants should not fall for the lies of smugglers who proclaim otherwise," said Kristie A. Canegallo, a senior official performing the duties of Deputy Secretary of Homeland Security.</p>

<p>The statement said the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) continues to enforce <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indians-form-third-largest-illegal-immigrant-population-in-us-study-4595873">US immigration</a> laws and deliver tough consequences for those who enter unlawfully and encourages the use of lawful pathways.</p>

<p>Since June 2024, when the Securing the Border Presidential Proclamation and accompanying Interim Final Rule went into effect, encounters between ports of entry along the southwest border of the US have decreased by 55 per cent.</p>

<p>In fiscal year 2024, the DHS removed or returned over 160,000 individuals and operated more than 495 international repatriation flights to more than 145 countries, including India, the statement said.</p>

<p>It said the department regularly engaged with foreign governments throughout the hemisphere and around the world to accept repatriations of their nationals without a legal basis to remain in the US.</p>

<p>This was one tool among many that the US used to reduce irregular migration, promote the use of safe, lawful and orderly pathways, and hold transnational criminal networks accountable for smuggling and exploitation of vulnerable people, it said.</p>

<p>Over the last year, DHS has removed individuals from a range of countries worldwide, including Colombia, Ecuador, Peru, Egypt, Mauritania, Senegal, Uzbekistan, China, and India.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gupo5gp_us-illegal-immigration-generic-_625x300_26_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This was one tool among many that the US used to reduce irregular migration. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rejecting-escalation-saudi-arabia-condemns-israels-strikes-on-iran-6877661]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Rejecting Escalation": Saudi Arabia Condemns Israel's Strikes On Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rejecting-escalation-saudi-arabia-condemns-israels-strikes-on-iran-6877661]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 12:48:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia condemned Israeli strikes on military targets in Iran on Saturday, warning against any further expansion of the conflict in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia condemned Israeli strikes on military targets in Iran on Saturday, warning against any further expansion of the conflict in the Middle East.</p>

<p>"The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia expresses its condemnation and denunciation" of the Israeli strikes and emphasised its "firm position rejecting escalation of the conflict in the region", which "threatens the security and the stability of countries and peoples" in the Middle East, the foreign ministry said on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/phn98hb8_israel-iran-conflict-generic-_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Kingdom of Saudi Arabia expresses its condemnation and denunciation," it said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>