<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:10:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hong-kong-court-dismisses-first-legal-challenge-to-new-national-security-law-7187014]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Court Dismisses First Legal Challenge To New Security Law]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hong-kong-court-dismisses-first-legal-challenge-to-new-national-security-law-7187014]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:05:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Hong Kong judge sided with the government on Friday and dismissed the first legal challenge to the city's newly enacted national security law, which had been brought by a jailed protester.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Hong Kong judge sided with the government on Friday and dismissed the first legal challenge to the city's newly enacted national security law, which had been brought by a jailed protester.</p>

<p>Ma Chun-man -- known as "Captain America 2.0" for carrying a replica of the Marvel superhero's shield during democracy rallies in 2019 -- was imprisoned for "inciting secession" under a national security law imposed by Beijing in 2020.</p>

<p>He had hoped to receive a one-third sentence remission -- typically granted to inmates for good behaviour -- and be released in March.</p>

<p>But the passage of another national security law this year effectively banned remission for people convicted of national security crimes, and Ma's request for early release was denied.</p>

<p>Ma challenged the decision, but on Friday the court said the new system was "sufficiently precise and certain".</p>

<p>"There is no question of Mr Ma being subject to any additional or heavier penalty by operation" of the new rules, High Court judge Alex Lee ruled.</p>

<p>"The applicant's substantive judicial review is dismissed," said Lee, who is among a pool of jurists selected by Hong Kong's leader to hear security cases.</p>

<p>Both of Hong Kong's national security laws have been criticised by Western nations such as the United States for quashing dissent and curtailing freedoms in the city.</p>

<p>Hong Kong authorities have defended the laws as necessary to restore order following the huge and sometimes violent pro-democracy protests in 2019.</p>

<p>Under the second law, national security prisoners are now "not entitled to remission", city leader John Lee has said, with the rule change covering those already serving time.</p>

<p>An exception can be made only if Hong Kong's prison chief is satisfied that an early release would not be contrary to national security interests.</p>

<p>Ma's lawyers argued that the definition of "interests of national security" was too vague.</p>

<p>But government lawyers responded that "national security is really a constantly evolving concept... not capable of being inflexibly defined".</p>

<p>Ma, a former food delivery worker, was sentenced to nearly six years in jail after being found guilty of "inciting secession" by chanting Hong Kong independence slogans, an offence under the first national security law.</p>

<p>The sentence was reduced to five years after a successful appeal in 2022.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ghaabet8_hong-kong-security-law_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both of Hong Kong's national security laws have been criticised by Western nations. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-guardian-agrees-sale-of-the-observer-worlds-oldest-sunday-paper-7186946]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Guardian Agrees Sale Of 'The Observer', World's Oldest Sunday Paper]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-guardian-agrees-sale-of-the-observer-worlds-oldest-sunday-paper-7186946]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:56:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Guardian Media Group announced Friday it had agreed to sell the world's oldest Sunday newspaper, The Observer, to online news company Tortoise Media, brushing aside strikes by staff.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Guardian Media Group announced Friday it had agreed to sell the world's oldest Sunday newspaper, The Observer, to online news company Tortoise Media, brushing aside strikes by staff.</p>

<p>The announcement by GMG and its owner came despite a 48-hour strike this week by more than 500 journalists at the Guardian daily and Observer opposing the deal.</p>

<p>"The boards of the Guardian Media Group and its owner, the Scott Trust, have in principle approved the sale of The Observer to Tortoise Media," a statement said.</p>

<p>"The new ownership model will protect The Observer's future, championing the voice of liberal values and investing in exceptional journalism," it added.</p>

<p>Tortoise, a "slow news" outlet founded in 2019, had approached GMG with an offer to buy the publication and invest more than £25 million ($32 million) over the next five years in the "editorial and commercial renewal of the title".</p>

<p>Unionised staff members last month voted 93 percent in favour of strike action, accusing the Scott Trust of "betrayal" over the sale.</p>

<p>"I recognise how unsettling this period has been for Observer staff, but we're confident we have agreed the best possible way forward," Katharine Viner, editor-in-chief of Guardian News &amp; Media, said in Friday's statement.</p>

<p>Tortoise, run by former BBC News director James Harding, plans to continue publishing The Observer on Sundays and combine it with its own podcasts and live events.</p>

<p>The weekly dates back to 1791.</p>

<p>"This investment will preserve the Observer's 233-year legacy and protect the paper's future," said Anna Bateson, GMG's chief executive.</p>

<p>Following a deal expected to be signed in the coming days, the Scott Trust will invest in Tortoise Media and become one of its largest shareholders, the statement added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/s15rsfbo_the-observer_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The weekly dates back to 1791.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/david-sacks-musks-friend-is-white-house-crypto-ai-czar-what-hell-do-7186854]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[David Sacks, Musk's Friend, Is White House Crypto, AI Czar. What He'll Do]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/david-sacks-musks-friend-is-white-house-crypto-ai-czar-what-hell-do-7186854]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:43:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Since it is a new role, it is unclear as of now how the vertical would function with the government and what authority David Sacks would have to make or implement changes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Continuing his pattern of compensating donorship with political power, President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday announced podcaster and former PayPal chief operating officer David Sacks as White House artificial intelligence and crypto czar.</p>

<p>Since it is a new role, it is unclear as of now how the vertical would function with the government and what authority David Sacks would have to make or implement changes.</p>

<p>"In this important role, David will guide policy for the Administration in Artificial Intelligence and Cryptocurrency, two areas critical to the future of American competitiveness," Trump had said on Truth Social when he made the announcement.</p>

<p>He added that Sacks has the "knowledge, business experience, intelligence, and pragmatism to MAKE AMERICA GREAT".</p>

<p>The latter had hosted a fundraiser for Trump at his mansion in San Francisco, with tickets that cost as much as $300,000 to attend. More than $12m was secured from this which beat the initial goal of $5m. This event was also co-sponsored by Sacks' co-host Chamath Palihapitiya.</p>

<p>Interestingly enough, Sacks and Palihapitiya, over an informal dinner suggested Trump to pick J D Vance as his VP. Apart from this, Sacks is also closely associated with Elon Musk and backed his decision of taking Twitter over.</p>

<p>It is expected that Sacks and Musk will work together on the AI front since the latter has an AI company xAI and an AI chatbot called Grok. However, both of them will be special government employees which means they can serve a maximum of 130 days a year without publicly divesting their assets.</p>

<p>Apart from this Trump has also designated Sacks to head the council of advisors for science and technology. The work involved ranges in sectors like energy, environment, public health and national security.</p>

<p>"He will work on a legal framework so the Crypto industry has the clarity it has been asking for, and can thrive in the US" Trump said, talking about Sacks' role in the administration.</p>

<p>And for the first time in its 15 year history, Bitcoin blasted the $100 barrier, ahead of Trump's pick of Sacks, in anticipation of a friendly regulatory environment for the digital currency.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4jedgb1g_david-sacks-afp_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[David will guide policy for the Administration in Artificial Intelligence and Cryptocurrency said Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-rebel-leader-says-goal-is-to-overthrow-assad-regime-7186811]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syria Rebel Leader Says Goal Is To "Overthrow" Assad Regime]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-rebel-leader-says-goal-is-to-overthrow-assad-regime-7186811]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:39:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rebel forces pressing a lightning offensive in Syria aim to overthrow President Bashar al-Assad's rule, their Islamist leader said in an interview published on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rebel forces pressing a lightning offensive in Syria aim to overthrow President Bashar al-Assad's rule, their Islamist leader said in an interview published on Friday.</p>

<p>The Islamist-led rebels were at the gates of Syria's Homs, a war monitor said, after wresting other key cities from government control.</p>

<p>In little over a week, the offensive has seen Syria's second city Aleppo and strategically located Hama fall from President Bashar al-Assad's control for the first time since the civil war began in 2011.</p>

<p>Should the rebels capture Homs, that would cut the seat of power in the capital Damascus from the Mediterranean coast, a key bastion of the Assad clan, which has ruled Syria for the past five decades.</p>

<p>By Friday morning, the rebels were just five kilometres (three miles) from the edge of Homs, according to the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitor.</p>

<p>Abu Mohammed al-Jolani, the leader of the Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS) rebel alliance, said the goal of the offensive was to overthrow Assad's rule.</p>

<p>"When we talk about objectives, the goal of the revolution remains the overthrow of this regime. It is our right to use all available means to achieve that goal," Jolani told CNN in an interview.</p>

<p>The rebel alliance conducting the offensive that began on November 27 is led by HTS, which is rooted in the Syrian branch of Al-Qaeda but has sought to moderate its image in recent years.</p>

<p>The rebels launched their offensive in northern Syria the same day a ceasefire took effect in the war between Israel and Lebanese group Hezbollah, which along with Russia and Iran have been crucial backers of Assad's government.</p>

<p>Turkey, which has backed the opposition, on Friday said its Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan would meet with his Russian and Iranian counterparts this weekend in Qatar to discuss the situation in Syria.</p>

<p>- Fear -</p>

<p>Fearing the rebels' advance, tens of thousands of members of Assad's Alawite minority were fleeing Homs on Thursday, residents and the Observatory said.</p>

<p>Khaled, who lives on the city's outskirts, told AFP that "the road leading to (coastal) Tartus province was glowing... due to the lights of hundreds of cars on their way out".</p>

<p>Homs was the scene of a months-long government siege of opposition areas and deadly sectarian attacks in the early years of the civil war.</p>

<p>Early in the war, which began with Assad's brutal crackdown on democracy protests, activists referred to the city as "the capital of the revolution" against the government.</p>

<p>Syrians who were forced out of the country by the crackdown on the revolt were glued to their phones as they watched the developments unfold.</p>

<p>"We've been dreaming of this for more than a decade," said Yazan, a 39-year-old former activist who survived the siege and is now living as a refugee in France.</p>

<p>Asked whether he was worried about HTS's Islamist agenda, he said: "It doesn't matter to me who is conducting this. The devil himself could be behind it. What people care about is who is going to liberate the country."</p>

<p>On the other side of the sectarian divide, however, there was fear among Homs's Alawite community.</p>

<p>Haidar, 37, who lives in an Alawite-majority neighbourhood, told AFP by telephone that "fear is the umbrella that covers Homs now".</p>

<p>"I've never seen this scene in my life. We are extremely afraid, we don't know what is happening."</p>

<p>On Friday, the rebel alliance "entered the cities of Rastan and Talbisseh" on the main road between Hama and Homs, the Observatory said.</p>

<p>The factions were faced with "a total absence" of government forces, it added.</p>

<p>Footage posted on social media and verified by AFP showed rebels firing into the air as they drove through Talbisseh.</p>

<p>The Syrian defence ministry said the army launched strikes against "terrorist" fighters in Hama province.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory, which relies on a network of sources in Syria, said 826 people, mostly combatants but also including 111 civilians, have been killed since the offensive began last week.</p>

<p>The United Nations said that the violence has displaced 280,000 people, warning that numbers could swell to 1.5 million.</p>

<p>Observatory head Rami Abdel Rahman said there was a "massive exodus of Syrian Alawites from parts of Homs, tens of thousands are heading towards the Syrian coast, fearing the rebels' advance".</p>

<p>- 'Massive blow' -</p>

<p>Many of the scenes witnessed in recent days would have been unimaginable earlier in the war.</p>

<p>The rebels announced on Telegram their capture of Hama following street battles with government forces, describing it as "the complete liberation of the city".</p>

<p>Many residents turned out to welcome the rebel fighters. An AFP photographer saw some residents set fire to a giant poster of Assad on the facade of city hall.</p>

<p>The army admitted losing control of the city, though Defence Minister Ali Abbas insisted that its withdrawal was a "temporary tactical measure".</p>

<p>In a video posted online, HTS leader Jolani said his fighters had entered Hama to "cleanse the wound that has endured in Syria for 40 years", referring to an army massacre in the 1980s.</p>

<p>In another message on Telegram congratulating "the people of Hama on their victory," he used his real name, Ahmed al-Sharaa, instead of his nom de guerre for the first time.</p>

<p>Aron Lund, a fellow of the Century International think tank, called the loss of Hama "a massive, massive blow to the Syrian government".</p>

<p>Should Assad lose Homs, it wouldn't mean the end of his rule, Lund said, but "with no secure route from Damascus to the coast, I'd say it's over as a credible state entity."</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres said Thursday that the escalation in Syria is the result of a "chronic collective failure" of diplomacy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/i6as6d3g_-abu-mohammed-algolani_625x300_06_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Our right to use all available means to achieve that goal," Al-Jolani said in an interview. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-to-reflect-on-difficult-times-at-christmas-service-in-uk-7186781]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton To Reflect On "Difficult Times" At Christmas Service In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-to-reflect-on-difficult-times-at-christmas-service-in-uk-7186781]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:32:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's Catherine, Princess of Wales, on Friday will host a Christmas service at Westminster Abbey that will reflect on "the most difficult times" as she returns to public life after her cancer diagnosis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Catherine, Princess of Wales, on Friday will host a Christmas service at Westminster Abbey that will reflect on "the most difficult times" as she returns to public life after her cancer diagnosis.</p>

<p>The London carol service will "reflect upon the importance of love and empathy, and how much we need each other, especially in the most difficult times of our lives", according to Catherine's Kensington Palace office.</p>

<p>Each guest will receive an order of service illustrated by British artist Charlie Mackesy that will ask "how did I help?", with the reply "you were by my side, which was everything".</p>

<p>Catherine is expected to attend alongside husband Prince William and their children Prince George, Princess Charlotte and Prince Louis.</p>

<p>The princess said in September that she had completed her chemotherapy treatment for an unspecified cancer and was looking forward to undertaking more engagements "when I can".</p>

<p>She attended Remembrance Day events last month and visited Southport in northwest England in October to meet people affected by a knife attack in July that killed three young girls.</p>

<p>Families affected by the attack are among the 1,600 people invited to the service, according to the BBC.</p>

<p>Among the guests are those "who have supported others in their communities, whether on a personal level with friends and family, through their work, or as they selflessly give up their time through volunteering," said Kensington Palace.</p>

<p>Six-time Olympic cycling champion Chris Hoy, who recently revealed he has terminal cancer, will light a candle and the event will hear musical performances from UK singer Paloma Faith and US jazz performer Gregory Porter.</p>

<p>Each guest will receive a letter of thanks written by Catherine.</p>

<p>In it, she writes that "this carol service is a heartfelt celebration of every one of you, and a reminder that at Christmas, and throughout the year, we must all shine for each other.</p>

<p>"Because in times of joy and sadness, we are all each other's light."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/srid2l7g_princess-catherine_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Princess Catherine is expected to attend alongside husband Prince William and their children. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/watch-author-aija-mayrock-shares-unique-experience-of-renting-old-man-in-japan-7186504]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Author Aija Mayrock Shares Experience Of "Renting" Old Man In Japan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/watch-author-aija-mayrock-shares-unique-experience-of-renting-old-man-in-japan-7186504]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:58:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Author Aija Mayrock recently took to Instagram to share her experience of "renting" an older man for a day in Japan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Author Aija Mayrock recently took to Instagram to share her experience of "renting" an older man for a day in Japan. At first, this may sound like a romantic or dodgy dating scam, but the reality is far from that. The arrangement allows young people to "rent" an older man - often retirees - to connect with younger people to share their life experiences, wisdom and even just some much-needed company. In the clip, Ms Mayrock reveals she "rented" the old man from a Japanese platform called Ossan Rental. As the video progresses, the author asks the old man for his advice on everything from life to career to relationships. She also explores Japan with him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sharing the video on Instagram, Mr Mayrock wrote, "I rented an older man for the day. This is the 5th video in my series, Aging Around The World, where I explore how different countries and cultures tackle aging and longevity."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBn9gzMJk8x/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBn9gzMJk8x/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBn9gzMJk8x/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBn9gzMJk8x/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Aija Mayrock (@aijamayrock)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Ms Mayrock shared the video a few days back. Since then, it has accumulated more than 19,000 likes and over 779,000 views. In the comments section, users praised the concept.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Im really impressed about Japanese culture. This is so inspiring and a good way to serve others with experience and example. Thank you for this content," wrote one user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is a wonderful idea. In the USA older people are over looked, ignored and thrown away. I'm an older woman. As our exteriors change our mind are still young. I still create art, and am physically as active as I was in my younger days. At 61 I'm playing bass/singing in a rock band. We don't let America tell us we're not relevant," expressed another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Indeed, it is a very innovative way to combat loneliness, depression, and a miriad of other illnesses in the aging population. I love this idea!" commented a third user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Awesome! I love it. Hopefully this will spread all over the world and extend to women as well. This would help young and old to connect better," said a fourth user.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/angi-angie-hicks-woman-turned-down-job-to-pursue-her-dreams-built-a-rs-10-000-crore-empire-7185960">Woman Turned Down Job To Pursue Her Dreams, Built A Rs 10,000 Crore Empire</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, according to the official website, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://ossanrental.thebase.in/" rel="noindex,nofollow">Ossan Rental</a> is a "service that lets you rent an old man for 1,000 yen per hour". Over the years, members have received requests such as chatting, listening to complaints, playing a sport, advice on career or love, tidying up a room, correcting an essay, taking the trash out and walking pets.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The company also has strict rules that are "unacceptable." These rules include requests to go "against public order and morals, touching, erotic requests and commercial requests."&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/d5cect4_aija-mayrock_625x300_06_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[the post garnered more than 19,000 likes and over 779,000 views.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/angi-angie-hicks-woman-turned-down-job-to-pursue-her-dreams-built-a-rs-10-000-crore-empire-7185960]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Turned Down Job To Pursue Her Dreams, Built A Rs 10,000 Crore Empire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/angi-angie-hicks-woman-turned-down-job-to-pursue-her-dreams-built-a-rs-10-000-crore-empire-7185960]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 14:43:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Once terrified of speaking to strangers, Hicks developed strategies to build confidence and grow Angi into a household name, now valued at $1.2 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's hard to imagine that someone afraid to speak to strangers could go on to own a billion-dollar business. But that's exactly the story of Hicks, co-founder of Angi, previously known as Angie's List.A self-described introvert, Hicks once considered talking to strangers her biggest fear. Despite this, she co-founded Angi, an online home services platform that connects millions of users with trusted professionals. Today, the company has grown into a household name, with a valuation of $1.2 billion (Rs&nbsp;9997 Crore).</p>

<p>According to CNBC, Hicks is Angi's chief customer officer, a role she's had since 2017. But when the business launched in 1995, she wore many hats-often literally walking door-to-door to recruit Angi's first customers. It was a daunting task for someone who shied away from socialising with strangers.</p>

<p>"I'm very shy," Hicks, 51, tells <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcchicago.com/news/business/money-report/51-year-old-introvert-overcame-her-worst-nightmare-to-build-her-1-2-billion-company/3565916/"><em>CNBC</em></a> Make It. "Going door to door like that was my worst nightmare."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hicks' journey is an inspiring example of overcoming personal challenges to achieve extraordinary success.</p>

<p>However, becoming an entrepreneur wasn't her first choice. A boutique consulting firm in Washington, DC, had offered a job to her with a starting salary of $40,000. She didn't opt for the job and joined her former boss on half of the pay she was offered.</p>

<p>Angi connects homeowners with local service professionals for various tasks like home repairs, cleaning, and renovations. Users can browse service providers, read reviews, request quotes, and book appointments directly through the platform.</p>

<p>As an introvert, Hicks says socialising and marketing the business didn't come naturally. But she developed strategies to become a more confident leader, like practicing her script before a daunting presentation or sales pitch and setting small, realistic goals to celebrate.</p>

<p>"If I sold one membership in a day, I was thrilled," she says. "I also learnt to tackle the hardest tasks first and save the fun tasks for later in the day, which helped me stay motivated and be more productive."</p>

<p>However, after years of persistent work, Angi's efforts paid off, and the company became well-known.</p>

<p>In the $90 billion home services sector in the United States today, Angi is a major player. Homeowners submitted almost 23 million service requests to Angi in 2023 alone, bringing in over $1.3 billion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r1njuj2g_angie-hicks_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Angie Hicks, transformed from a shy introvert into a business leader.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-behind-golds-wild-ride-this-year-7185812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Behind Gold's Wild Ride This Year?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-behind-golds-wild-ride-this-year-7185812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 14:24:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gold prices have been on a rampage, hitting record after record since the beginning of the year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gold prices have been on a rampage, hitting record after record since the beginning of the year. The conventional wisdom has always been that gold spikes when geopolitical tensions escalate or economic uncertainty spreads-the traditional bread and butter of gold bugs. The prospect of a US soft landing and lower interest rates have also added fuel to the sparkly fire.</p>

<p>But 2024's gold rush is different from most in at least one key way. In the Bloomberg Originals mini-documentary Who Is Behind Gold's Crazy Rise? we reveal that-along with conflicts like Russia's war on Ukraine and the regional conflagration in the Middle East-something else has been driving gold prices this year.</p>

<p>It's hard to think of a safer asset than gold-a fact that hasn't been lost on central banks or consumers. One derivative of the Kremlin's botched effort to annex its neighbor has been the West's successful effort to freeze Russian assets. The move set off alarm bells around the world, spurring central banks to protect themselves. The People's Bank of China led the way, loading up on gold to diversify away from dollars.</p>

<p>But it was the Chinese people who really drove the gold train in 2024. Unsettled not only by global instability but a struggling domestic economy, the nation's massive consumer market moved to scoop up gold jewelry-and even bullion-to protect against the unknown, sending prices skyward. By October though, a funny thing was happening to the red-hot gold market. Watch Who Is Behind Gold's Crazy Rise? to find out more.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vv59slno_gold-deposit_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was the Chinese people who really drove the gold train in 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-middle-east-tensions-iran-launches-heaviest-space-payload-into-orbit-7185623]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Middle East Tensions, Iran Launches Heaviest Space Payload Into Orbit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-middle-east-tensions-iran-launches-heaviest-space-payload-into-orbit-7185623]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:59:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran successfully launched on Friday its heaviest space payload, which includes a satellite and a space tug, using a domestically developed satellite carrier, official media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran successfully launched on Friday its heaviest space payload, which includes a satellite and a space tug, using a domestically developed satellite carrier, official media reported.</p>

<p>Weighing 300 kilogrammes (660 pounds), the payload consisted of the Fakhr-1 telecommunications satellite and the Saman-1 space tug, according to state television.</p>

<p>The Saman-1 is an "orbital transmission system" designed to transport satellites from lower orbits to higher ones, as described by the Iran Space Research Center when it was unveiled in 2017.</p>

<p>The launch marks an "operational step" toward transferring satellites into higher orbits, the TV report said.</p>

<p>The system was first introduced in February 2017 at a ceremony attended by Iran's then-president, Hassan Rouhani, and was test-launched in 2022.</p>

<p>The payloads were launched using the homegrown Simorgh satellite carrier from the Imam Khomeini launch base in Semnan province.</p>

<p>Named after a mythical Iranian bird, the Simorgh is a two-stage, liquid-fuelled satellite launch vehicle developed by Iran's defence ministry.</p>

<p>In September, Iran said it successfully put the Chamran-1 research satellite into orbit using the Ghaem-100 carrier, which is produced by the Revolutionary Guards' aerospace division.</p>

<p>Western governments, including the United States, have repeatedly warned Iran against such launches, arguing technology used for satellites could be applied to ballistic missiles, potentially capable of carrying nuclear warheads.</p>

<p>Iran denies it wants nuclear weapons. It has consistently stated that its satellite and rocket launches are focused on civil and defence applications.</p>

<p>Last month, Russia launched 55 satellites, including two built by Iran -- Koswar and Hodhod -- reflecting the deepening political, economic and military relations between the two nations.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2r55j0ko_iran-space-reuters-_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The payloads were launched using the homegrown Simorgh satellite carrier.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-dior-handbag-caused-one-of-south-koreas-biggest-political-scandals-7185360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Dior Handbag Caused One Of South Korea's Biggest Political Scandals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-dior-handbag-caused-one-of-south-koreas-biggest-political-scandals-7185360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:45:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid talks of his impeachment, South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is battling a series of blunders, including the brief but controversial imposition of martial law, to save his political career.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid talks of his impeachment, South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is battling a series of blunders, including the brief but controversial imposition of martial law, to save his political career. Among the several incidents that have eroded his public support and shifted sentiment against the government is a luxury handbag from Dior that was given to First Lady Kim Keon Hee under questionable circumstances.</p>

<p>Although this incident took place in 2022, it came into the spotlight in November 2023 and escalated into a political storm this year, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-05/south-korea-how-first-lady-s-dior-bag-uproar-shook-politics?srnd=homepage-asia">Bloomberg</a> reported.</p>

<p>While prosecutors have cleared Kim of criminal charges, the Opposition parties in South Korea claim the luxury bag was given as a bribe and have demanded an independent investigation into the matter.</p>

<p>On their behalf, both Yoon and the First Lady have denied all charges and claimed the gift was part of a “manoeuvre” to discredit them.</p>

<p>It all began after a video shot by a pastor, Choi Jae-young, showed the purchase of the Dior bag for 3 million won ($2,250 or roughly ₹1,90,000 back then).</p>

<p>Choi, who has taken a stand against the president's tough stance towards the neighbouring country, North Korea, shot the controversial video through a camera concealed on a watch.</p>

<p>In the video, he is seen walking into what looks like the office of a planning firm run by Kim and giving her a shopping bag, which apparently had the Dior bag. “Why do you keep bringing these?” Kim was heard saying in the video. She then added, "Never buy something expensive like this."</p>

<p>However, the video emerged a year later on a left-leaning political site, which usually expresses views opposed to Yoon's policies.</p>

<p>The incident soon reminded the people of the past “pay-to-play” scandals where individuals used their access to power for personal gains. Further, it started a debate over whether the First Lady brought the unwelcome publicity upon herself or was she being targeted for raising her profile.</p>

<p>In July this year, Kim was questioned by the prosecutors for nearly 12 hours in connection with the incident. After that, her lawyer told Yonhap News that the South Korean First Lady responded in a “sincere manner and told the truth.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a result, the prosecutors did not find any evidence of favours offered in return for the luxury bag.&nbsp; Addressing the issue, Yoon said that it stemmed from his wife not being able to cut ties with the pastor.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It will be important to draw a clearer line to ensure that such incidents do not happen again," Yoon noted.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h62h2s4o_south-korea-first-lady-afp-_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prosecutors did not find any evidence of favours offered in return for the luxury bag.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jewish-synagogue-set-on-fire-by-masked-men-in-australias-melbourne-7185494]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jewish Synagogue Set On Fire By Masked Men In Australia's Melbourne]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jewish-synagogue-set-on-fire-by-masked-men-in-australias-melbourne-7185494]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:35:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mask-wearing arsonists set a synagogue ablaze in a pre-dawn attack Friday in the Australian city of Melbourne, police said, sparking widespread condemnation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mask-wearing arsonists set a synagogue ablaze in a pre-dawn attack Friday in the Australian city of Melbourne, police said, sparking widespread condemnation.</p>

<p>The fire broke out at 4:10 am (1710 GMT) in the Adass Israel Synagogue when some congregants were already inside, police said, gutting much of the building in the southeast Melbourne suburb of Ripponlea.</p>

<p>No serious injuries were reported.</p>

<p>A witness entering the synagogue for morning prayers saw "two individuals wearing masks", Detective Inspector Chris Murray of the Victorian police arson and explosive squad told reporters at the scene.</p>

<p>"They appeared to be spreading an accelerant of some type in the premises," he said.</p>

<p>The synagogue was "engulfed in flames", he added.</p>

<p>"We believe it was deliberate. We believe it has been targeted. What we don't know is why."</p>

<p>Police will increase patrols as they hunt for the arsonists, who were wearing dark clothing, he said.</p>

<p>Detectives would be looking at CCTV footage and interviewing any witnesses, Murray said.</p>

<p>Television images showed firefighters hosing down the embers through the blackened door of the single-storey building, which has a grey concrete facade.</p>

<p>A board member of the synagogue, Benjamin Klein, said a few congregants were sitting and praying inside when the fire started.</p>

<p>"They heard loud banging," Klein told AFP.</p>

<h2><strong>'Completely gutted'</strong></h2>

<p>Liquid was poured inside the synagogue and set alight, he said.</p>

<p>"If this had happened an hour later, there would have been hundreds of people inside," Klein said.</p>

<p>The congregants "ran out the back of the synagogue. One man who ran out -- his hand got burnt," he said.</p>

<p>"The fire was extensive," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"Inside is completely gutted."</p>

<p>Holy books and furniture had been destroyed, he said, vowing however that the community would "rebuild".</p>

<p>Members of the congregation formed a human chain to remove religious items from the damaged synagogue, including Torah scrolls -- one of which was brought to Australia from Germany in World War II, the Age newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Klein said the synagogue had increased security over the past 12 months amid safety concerns, without giving further details.</p>

<p>In 1995, the synagogue was damaged by a deliberately lit fire, with walls and Torah scrolls burned.</p>

<p>Klein, who was a child at the time, said he remembered standing inside the damaged synagogue with his grandfather, who he said was a Holocaust survivor.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese "unequivocally" condemned the fire and said federal police would help the state to investigate it.</p>

<p>"This violence and intimidation and destruction at a place of worship is an outrage," Albanese said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This attack has risked lives and is clearly aimed at creating fear in the community."</p>

<p>The prime minister said he had "zero tolerance" for anti-Semitism.</p>

<p>"It has absolutely no place in Australia."</p>

<h2><strong>'Fear'&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>The war in Gaza has sparked protests from supporters of Israel and Palestinians in cities around Australia, as in much of the world.</p>

<p>Executive Council of Australian Jewry president Daniel Aghion said the community had been living in fear of such an incident since the start of the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>"This for us is just evidence of that fear," he told reporters.</p>

<p>"This is something that is the greatest manifestation of what we have been seeing and hearing in terms of threatening e-mails, threatening social media, threatening letters and all sorts of other material."</p>

<p>Hamas' October 7, 2023 attack which triggered the Gaza war resulted in the deaths of 1,208 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 44,580 people in Gaza, mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run health ministry that the United Nations considers reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ftm19em_australia-synagogue-fire-afp-_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[No serious injuries were reported.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-youre-welcome-after-bitcoin-hits-new-all-time-high-of-100-000-7185207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You're Welcome", Says Trump After Bitcoin Hits New All-Time High]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-youre-welcome-after-bitcoin-hits-new-all-time-high-of-100-000-7185207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:56:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday took credit for bitcoin's historic surge past $100,000, telling his social media followers "you're welcome" after the cryptocurrency jumped more than 50 percent since his election victory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday took credit for bitcoin's historic surge past $100,000, telling his social media followers "you're welcome" after the cryptocurrency jumped more than 50 percent since his election victory.</p>

<p>"CONGRATULATIONS BITCOINERS!!! $100,000!!! YOU'RE WELCOME!!! Together, we will Make America Great Again!" Trump, who in September launched his own crypto platform, wrote on Truth Social.</p>

<p>Bitcoin broke $100,000 for the first time Thursday after Trump nominated cryptocurrency backer Paul Atkins to head the US securities regulator, reinforcing optimism the incoming president will deregulate the sector.</p>

<p>The digital unit has enjoyed a blistering rally since the November 5 election of Trump, who pledged to make the United States the "bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world".</p>

<p>Bitcoin hit a record of $103,800.45 in Asian trading hours Thursday before dipping back to around $101,000.</p>

<p>Following Trump's remarks, it began climbing again, reaching $103,320.</p>

<p>The volatile asset has soared by around 140 percent since the turn of the year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, its advance had stalled in recent weeks, sitting just below $100,000 as traders awaited new catalysts before jumping in to buy.</p>

<p>That came after Trump, who takes office in January, announced Wednesday that he would nominate Atkins to take over as chair of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>

<p>Atkins, an SEC commissioner from 2002 to 2008, founded risk consultancy firm Patomak Global Partners in 2009, whose clients include companies in the banking, trading and cryptocurrency industries.</p>

<p>An announcement from the Trump transition team noted that Atkins had been co-chairman of the Digital Chamber of Commerce, which promotes the use of digital assets, since 2017.</p>

<p>"Paul is a proven leader for common sense regulations," Trump said in a statement that emphasised Atkins' commitment to "robust, innovative" capital markets.</p>

<p>"He also recognises that digital assets and other innovations are crucial to making America greater than ever before," Trump added.</p>

<p>- Trump's U-turn -<br />
Atkins replaces Gary Gensler, who led a crackdown on the sector after a 2022 market rout.</p>

<p>Even so, the SEC this year authorised the trading on the American market of two new financial products, allowing a wider public to buy cryptocurrencies, called ETFs (exchange-traded funds).</p>

<p>"Institutional interest and regulatory shifts are adding legitimacy, turning what once seemed like a fringe asset into a force reshaping finance," said Matt Britzman, a senior analyst at Hargreaves Lansdown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Love it or doubt it, bitcoin's climb is rewriting the rule book for digital assets," he added.</p>

<p>Despite having once branded cryptocurrencies a "scam", Trump changed his stance and has been a major advocate of the unit during his election campaign.</p>

<p>In September, he announced that he, along with his sons and entrepreneurs, would launch a digital currency platform named World Liberty Financial.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump has also become close to tycoon Elon Musk, who he said would lead a new US government-efficiency group tasked with cutting federal waste.</p>

<p>Musk, a cryptocurrency fan himself, reportedly spent more than $100 million to help Trump regain the White House, repeatedly boosting his candidacy on his X social media platform.</p>

<p>Reacting on X to the news of bitcoin hitting the $100,000 mark, Musk wrote: "Wow".</p>

<p>- Integration hopes -<br />
Among measures expected with Trump at the helm is the creation of a strategic reserve of bitcoins in the United States, consisting mainly of tokens seized by the courts, which could push other countries to grant more legitimacy to the virtual currency.</p>

<p>Cryptocurrencies have made headlines since their creation, from their extreme volatility to the collapse of several industry giants, foremost among them the FTX exchange platform.</p>

<p>"It's volatile, unpredictable and is driven by speculation, none of which makes for a sleep-at-night investment," said Dan Coatsworth, an analyst at investment group AJ Bell.</p>

<p>Bitcoin was conceived in 2008 by a person or group writing under the name Satoshi Nakamoto.</p>

<p>It was pitched as a way to break free of mainstream financial institutions by establishing a decentralised platform for transactions.</p>

<p>The digital currency is created -- or "mined" -- as a reward when powerful computers solve complex problems to validate transactions made on a meddle-proof register known as the blockchain.</p>

<p>Bitcoin has long been criticised for being the currency of choice for making untraceable payments on the dark web, the hidden part of the internet used for criminal activities.</p>

<p>The asset has often come under attack for facilitating money laundering and allowing extortion through ransomware attacks.</p>

<p>In September 2021, the unit was accepted by El Salvador as legal tender, though according to a study by Central America University, in 2023, 88 percent of Salvadorans have never used it.</p>

<p>Its carbon footprint has also come under scrutiny as mining cryptocurrencies requires huge amounts of energy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ncepoq1g_donald-trump_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Following Trump's remarks, it began climbing again, reaching $103,320.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-university-vice-chancellor-james-tooley-suspended-over-allegations-of-affair-with-hyderabad-woman-7185199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK University Vice Chancellor Suspended Over Affair With Hyderabad Woman]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-university-vice-chancellor-james-tooley-suspended-over-allegations-of-affair-with-hyderabad-woman-7185199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:55:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Professor James Tooley's wife accused him of having affair with a woman in Hyderabad when he was working there.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Professor James Tooley, the vice-chancellor of University of Buckingham, has been suspended due to "serious allegations", including his relationship with a woman in India. According to <em>The Telegraph</em>, the allegations have been levelled by his estranged wife Cynthia, who also accused Professor Tooley of possessing a junior air rifle. The decision was announced in an email sent to almost 4,000 staff members and students in October, the outlet further said. However, as the issue started gaining traction, senior academics accused the university of suspending Professor Tooley over his "Right-wing" views.</p>

<p>He was suspended by Mark Qualter, chair of the university council, with immediate effect on October 11. Professor's estranged wife had claimed that the academician, now 65, was in a relationship with a woman in Hyderabad while working there in his fifties, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2024/12/05/university-buckingham-vice-chancellor-ousted-anti-woke-view/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>The Telegraph</em> report</a>.</p>

<p>Professor Tooley held the position since 2020 and was known for his work helping to set up low-cost private schools, especially in developing countries, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cly6ry6y6nzo" rel="noindex,nofollow">the <em>BBC</em></a> said in a report.</p>

<p>But other professors at the university accused the staff of seizing upon the allegations, as it gave them opportunity to oust him.</p>

<p>One professor told <em>The Telegraph</em> on condition of anonymity: "The paradox here is that this so-called free market university appears to be populated at its high levels with people who don't believe anything of the sort. And they particularly don't seem to believe in freedom of expression and freedom of speech."</p>

<p>The professor is a staunch free speech advocate who has spoken out publicly against the "cancel culture" he claimed had taken root across British campuses. He succeeded Sir Anthony Seldon as Buckingham's vice-chancellor in 2020.</p>

<p>The university has now set up an independent investigation panel to look into the issue. A meeting of the panel was held on Wednesday in which members raised concerns about how Professor Tooley was treated, according to&nbsp;<em>The Telegraph</em>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kbtd3r8_professor-james-tooley_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Professor James Tooley was suspended in October this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/gencast-all-about-googles-new-ai-agent-that-aces-15-day-weather-forecast-7184707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[GenCast: All About Google's New AI Agent That Aces 15-Day Weather Forecast]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/gencast-all-about-googles-new-ai-agent-that-aces-15-day-weather-forecast-7184707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:28:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google DeepMind has introduced a new artificial intelligence tool, claiming it possesses unmatched skill and speed to devise 15-day weather forecasts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google DeepMind has introduced a new artificial intelligence tool, claiming it possesses unmatched skill and speed to devise 15-day weather forecasts. In their latest report in the Nature Journal, published on Wednesday, the London-based company claimed its new model could outperform best forecasts in the world meant to track deadly storms and save lives.</p>

<p>Ilan Price, the lead author of the new study and a senior research scientist at DeepMind, said their new AI agent, 'GenCast', was much faster than the traditional methods. “And it's more accurate,” he claimed.</p>

<p>The team discovered that GenCast ran circles around the company's earlier AI weather program that debuted in late 2023, featuring a reliable 10-day forecast.</p>

<p>"I'm a little bit reluctant to say it, but it's like we've made decades' worth of improvements in one year. We're seeing really, really rapid progress," said Rémi Lam, the lead scientist on the other project and was also among one of the dozen co-authors on the new study.</p>

<p>The European Center for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts is often considered the global leader in atmospheric prediction. Its projections exceed all others in accuracy during regular comparative tests.</p>

<p>The new AI program by DeepMind was tested against the centre's Ensemble Prediction System, which is utilised by 35 countries in the world to produce weather forecasts.</p>

<p>During the study, the team compared how the 15-day forecasts of both systems performed while making predictions about a designated set of 1,320 global wind speeds, temperatures and other atmospheric features.</p>

<p>The latest report claimed the new agent outperformed the centre's forecasts 97.2% of the time. This achievement, according to the authors, “helps open the next chapter in operational weather forecasting.”</p>

<p>"It's a big deal... It's an important step forward," <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/04/science/google-ai-weather-forecast.html">The New York Times </a>quoted Kerry Emanuel, a professor emeritus of atmospheric science at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, as saying.</p>

<p>Dr Emanuel and six other experts had in 2019 argued that further advancing the development of reliable forecasts from 10 days to the length of 15 days would have “enormous socioeconomic benefits” as it can help people avoid the worst effects of extreme weather.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p378ak18_gencast_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The latest report claimed the new agent outperformed the centre's forecasts 97.2% of the time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-chile-president-michelle-bachelet-awarded-indira-gandhi-peace-prize-2024-7184996]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Chile President Michelle Bachelet Awarded Indira Gandhi Peace Prize 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-chile-president-michelle-bachelet-awarded-indira-gandhi-peace-prize-2024-7184996]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:25:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Michelle Bachelet, the former President of Chile and a global advocate for human rights, has been awarded the 2024 Indira Gandhi Prize for Peace, Disarmament, and Development.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Michelle Bachelet, the former President of Chile and a global advocate for human rights, has been awarded the 2024 Indira Gandhi Prize for Peace, Disarmament, and Development.</p>

<p>The announcement was made by an international jury chaired by Shivshankar Menon, former National Security Advisor and Foreign Secretary of India.</p>

<p>“The Indira Gandhi Prize for Peace, Disarmament and Development for 2024 is awarded to Her Excellency Michelle Bachelet for the example and inspiration that she is to women and men around the world of steadfastly striving for peace, gender equality, human rights, democracy and development in difficult circumstances and her contributions to India's relations with Chile,” a statement said.</p>

<p>Bachelet, whose full name is Veronica Michelle Bachelet Jeria, is celebrated worldwide for her steadfast commitment to peace, equality, and human rights. In her illustrious career, she has held key positions, including being the Founding Director of UN Women, the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights, and serving two terms as Chile's first female President.</p>

<p>She has consistently championed gender equality and the rights of marginalised communities, leaving an indelible impact both domestically and internationally.</p>

<p>Born on September 29, 1951, in La Cisterna, Santiago Province, Chile, Bachelet faced significant personal and political challenges during General Augusto Pinochet's dictatorship. Following her arrest, imprisonment, and torture in 1973, she went into exile in Australia and later Germany. Undeterred, she returned to Chile to contribute to its political transformation and was elected President in 2006 and again in 2014.</p>

<p>During her presidency, Bachelet introduced sweeping education and tax reforms. Her tenure also witnessed the signing of a free trade agreement between India and Chile, enhancing bilateral ties.</p>

<p>Beyond her presidency, Bachelet led global efforts to promote gender equality as the first Director of UN Women from 2010 to 2013. Later, as UN High Commissioner for Human Rights from 2018 to 2022, she vocally addressed critical global issues, including the denial of human rights in Palestine and other conflict zones.</p>

<p>Her unwavering commitment to LGBTQ rights, democracy, and progressive values has made her an inspirational figure worldwide. Despite facing criticism, she has remained a tireless advocate for peace and justice.</p>

<p>The Indira Gandhi Prize recognises Bachelet's extraordinary contributions to promoting gender equality, democracy, and development, as well as strengthening India-Chile relations. Her resilience and dedication serve as a beacon of hope for men and women across the globe.</p>

<p>--IANS</p>

<p>skp/rad</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6tl9oveg_michelle-bachelet_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Michelle Bachelet is celebrated for her steadfast commitment to peace, equality, and human rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-colombian-hitwoman-arrested-for-multiple-murders-including-her-ex-boyfriend-7184470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Colombian Hitwoman, Known As 'The Doll,' Arrested For Multiple Murders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-colombian-hitwoman-arrested-for-multiple-murders-including-her-ex-boyfriend-7184470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:08:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 23-year-old Colombian woman has been arrested in connection with several targeted killings, including the recent murder of her former boyfriend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 23-year-old Colombian woman has been arrested in connection with several targeted killings, including the recent murder of her former boyfriend. Karen Julieth Ojeda Rodriguez, known to police by the alias “La Muneca,” which translates to “The Doll,” was taken into custody over her alleged involvement in several high-profile murders in the municipality of Barrancabermeja, New York Post reported.</p>

<p>These killings were said to have been carried out at the behest of the Los de la M gang, according to Spanish language outlet Libertad Digital. At the time of arrest, Rodriguez was looking forward to expanding her career. She led a small cadre of hitmen, who terrorised the region before her arrest.</p>

<p>Her arrest came after an ambush following the assassination of her ex-boyfriend on July 23 in a rural area of Colombia called Piedecuesta, the Magdalena Medio Police said.</p>

<p>According to police, Rodriguez called her ex-boyfriend, Deyvy Jesus, and beckoned him to meet and supposedly resolve a money dispute between them.</p>

<p>When Devvy moved, two bike-borne men killed him, allegedly at the behest of Rodriguez. "The Doll", along with an accomplice Paula Valentina Joya Rueda, 24,&nbsp; was arrested by police.</p>

<p>Rueda was also on the police radar and was known under the alias “Gorda Sicaria,” translating to “Fat Hitwoman”.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, another accomplice, identified as “Leopoldo,” was arrested by the police at the same time as “The Doll”. Police officials said they seized a revolver and a 9-millimeter calibre pistol at the time of arrest.</p>

<p>As of now, the police are investigating whether any of these weapons were used in the recent killings.</p>

<p>Lieutenant Colonel Mauricio Herrara of the Magdalena Medio Police said that with the arrest of 'La Muneca' and 'Leopoldo', "a period of calm has been created in the region."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"These arrests mark progress in the dismantling of criminal structures responsible for the recent homicides,” Herrara added.</p>

<p>According to the World Population Review, a case of homicide is reported every three days in Bucaramanga, Colombia, which has a total population of more than 13 lakh people.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6q43q098_colombian-hitwoman-twitter_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police officials said they seized a revolver and a 9-millimeter calibre pistol at the time of arrest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-call-for-exemplary-punishment-in-bangladesh-after-attacks-on-hindus-7184837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Attacks On Hindus, Bangladesh's Minority Rights Group Says This]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-call-for-exemplary-punishment-in-bangladesh-after-attacks-on-hindus-7184837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:01:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council, the largest minority advocacy group in the country, has condemned the recent attacks on Hindus in the eastern Sunamganj district.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council, the largest minority advocacy group in the country, has condemned the recent attacks on Hindus in the eastern Sunamganj district. In a statement released on Thursday, the council recounted instances of violence and called for swift government action to hold the perpetrators accountable.</p>

<p>According to a press release from the group, violence erupted on the night of December 3. More than 100 houses and businesses belonging to the Hindu community in Manglargaon and Monigaon East Gunigram were allegedly attacked, looted, and vandalised.</p>

<p>The statement added that a temple was damaged. The council estimated the damages to exceed 1.5 million Bangladeshi taka (over Rs 10 lakh), noting that many minority villagers fled their homes out of fear.</p>

<p>The attacks reportedly stemmed from allegations against Akash Das, a 20-year-old Hindu villager accused of blasphemy for a Facebook post. Mr Das had already been arrested before the attacks unfolded.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Oikya Parishad strongly condemns and protests such communal attacks and immediately arrests the attackers, compensates and rehabilitates the victims and the attackers", the press statement said.</p>

<p>It further demanded the government ensure "exemplary punishment" for those responsible to deter future incidents.</p>

<h2><strong>Heightened Tensions</strong></h2>

<p>These events come amid rising tensions over the treatment of minority communities in Bangladesh. The arrest of Hindu spiritual leader Chinmoy Krishna Das on sedition charges has amplified concerns. Mr Das, a spokesperson for the Bangladesh Sammilit Sanatan Jagran Jote, remains in custody despite calls from India for his release.</p>

<p>Protests have erupted outside the Bangladesh Deputy High Commission in Kolkata and other Indian cities, with political and religious groups voicing outrage.</p>

<p>In response, Bangladesh summoned Shikder Mohammad Ashrafur Rahman, its Acting Deputy High Commissioner in Kolkata, for consultations. Mr Rahman also joined the Bangladesh delegation for upcoming foreign secretary-level talks with India. The Bangladesh Assistant High Commission in Tripura, has suspended visa and consular services citing "security reasons" after protesters breached the mission's premises recently.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh foreign ministry, in turn, summoned the Indian High Commissioner in Dhaka to protest the vandalism at its Agartala mission.</p>

<h2><strong>Yunus Government's Position</strong></h2>

<p>Amid escalating criticism, Muhammad Yunus, head of Bangladesh's interim government, has sought to address the concerns of minority communities. At a meeting with religious leaders from various faiths, Yunus urged the need for accurate reporting and urged collaboration to bridge gaps between reality and media narratives.</p>

<p>"We want to establish a process for obtaining accurate information and holding perpetrators accountable," Mr Yunus said.</p>

<p>Yunus reiterated that all citizens of Bangladesh, regardless of faith, are entitled to equal rights.</p>

<p>The Hindu community in Muslim-majority Bangladesh has reportedly faced over 200 attacks across 50 districts since the fall of Sheikh Hasina's Awami League government on August 5.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/as2juek8_bangladesh-iskcon_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These events come amid rising tensions over the treatment of minority communities in Bangladesh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/harry-potters-invisibility-cloak-now-a-reality-scientists-unveil-novel-camouflage-material-7184800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harry Potter's Invisibility Cloak Now A Reality? Scientists Unveil Material]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/harry-potters-invisibility-cloak-now-a-reality-scientists-unveil-novel-camouflage-material-7184800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:59:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The scientists added that SAP can also be used as a spray-on coating by adding polycaprolactone - a biodegradable polyester.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taking inspiration from Harry Potter movies, Chinese scientists may have finally created the 'Cloak of Invisibility', that could make us disappear in plain sight. Researchers at China's University of Electronic Science and Technology have devised a camouflage material that adjusts its molecular composition to blend into the background -- making the wearer imperceptible to the naked eye. The details regarding the 'chameleon' material have been published in the journal <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.ads2217" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Science Advances</em></a>.</p>

<p>The researchers said they managed to achieve 'invisibility' through a process called self-adaptive photochromism (SAP) in which molecules rearrange themselves when exposed to certain wavelengths of light. This causes the substance to change colour and effectively become unseeable. Notably, in nature, both chameleons and octopuses rely on active camouflage to change their appearance by blending into the surroundings.</p>

<p>"Applying this technology to clothing could make an individual effectively 'invisible'," head researcher Wang Dongsheng was quoted as saying by&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3289121/scientists-china-achieve-invisibility-chameleon-colour-breakthrough?module=AI_Recommended_for_you_In-house&amp;pgtype=homepage" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>South China Morning Post (SCMP).</em></a></p>

<p>As per Wang, the SAP technology offers a simpler and more efficient way to achieve adaptive camouflage effects. Currently, most man-made systems achieve the effect using complex electronic devices, resulting in high costs and limited usability.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/science-fiction-into-reality-real-life-invisibility-shield-hides-users-in-plain-sight-5367208" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | "Science Fiction Into Reality": Real Life 'Invisibility Shield' Hides Users In Plain Sight</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>How was invisibility achieved?</strong></h3>

<p>According to the study, the "SAP materials are in primary black state under dark". They spontaneously switch to another colour after being triggered by transmitted and reflected light in the background.</p>

<p>The researchers tested the material by placing a transparent container of SAP solution in coloured acrylic boxes. In turn, the SAP solution changed colour, matching the acrylic box. Next, the scientists placed a SAP solution-filled container in environments with matching colours. The solution adapted its colour to blend seamlessly with the surroundings within 30 to 80 seconds.</p>

<p>"A white light LED (10,000 lux) was used as the light source for triggering photochromism and illumination," the study added.</p>

<p>Despite the advancement, scientists are yet to mimic the entire spectrum of colour with Mr Wang hopeful of achieving the same in his future work.</p>

<p>"We have not yet fully mimicked all colours within the visible light spectrum in this work, that would be revealed in our future work. By adding more photochromic molecules to the material or adjusting its composition, we aim to achieve finer distinctions in colour, and faster changing speed."</p>

<p>The scientists added that SAP can also be used as a spray-on coating by adding polycaprolactone - a biodegradable polyester.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9bkf4c6g_invisible-_625x300_06_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 'invisibility' was achieved through a process called self-adaptive photochromism (SAP).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/most-mispronounced-words-of-the-year-kamala-harris-zendaya-and-more-7184401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Most Mispronounced Words Of The Year: Kamala Harris, Zendaya And More]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/most-mispronounced-words-of-the-year-kamala-harris-zendaya-and-more-7184401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:57:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Language learning platform Babbel has revealed the list of the most mispronounced words of 2024 in the United States and the United Kingdom.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Language learning platform Babbel has revealed the list of the most mispronounced words of 2024 in the United States and the United Kingdom. It features the names of several politicians, public figures, and many foreign words that entered the English lexicon, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/12/05/world/babbel-mispronounced-words-scli-intl/index.html">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>One of the prominent names on the list is US Vice President Kamala Harris, who lost to Donald Trump in the November 5 presidential election. Her first name, 'Kamala', has long been a source of plenty of confusion. Babbel says it should be pronounced as "COM-a-la".</p>

<p>The pronunciation was widely discussed during the presidential campaign as well. Her great-nieces, Amara and Leela, once even took to the stage to share how to pronounce it correctly. “First you say ‘Kama,' like a comma in a sentence,” Amara said, while Leela added, "Then you say ‘La,' like ‘la-la-la-la-la'.”</p>

<p>The other name that featured on US and UK lists was Barry Keoghan. The actor appeared in films such as Bird and Bring Them Down this year, besides his role in the mini-series Masters of the Air.</p>

<p>Another dual entry that has made it to the list is the Chinese fashion brand Shein. It's to be pronounced 'SHE-in', rather than SHEEN.</p>

<p>Another notable entrant was actress Zendaya, who featured in Dune: Part Two and Challengers this year. Her name should be pronounced "zen-DAY-uh".</p>

<p>Besides them, other entries are semaglutide, which is an active ingredient in the popular weight loss drug Ozempic, pronounced as 'sem-ah-GLOO-tide' as well as music star Chappell Roan, who should be called 'CHAP-uhl ROHN'.</p>

<p>The UK list also features two words from the Swedish language. Among these are smokeless tobacco Snus, which should be pronounced as 'SNOOZ' and flygskam, the name of a movement aimed towards discouraging people from flying. It should be called 'FLEEG-skam'.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, another popular word on the list is espresso. The word became widely popular this year as Sabrina Carpenter's single, Espresso, topped the UK charts.</p>

<p>The language learning platform has now suggested it be called 'es-PRESS-oh' and not 'EX-press-oh'.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ve2sodu8_zendaya-_625x300_13_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zendaya's name should be pronounced "zen-DAY-uh".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/professor-who-fled-gaza-teaches-trapped-students-from-canada-7184722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Professor Who Fled Gaza Teaches Trapped Students From Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/professor-who-fled-gaza-teaches-trapped-students-from-canada-7184722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:48:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[University professor Ahmed Abu Shaban often gets up at 3:00 am in Toronto to remotely teach his students in Gaza -- motivated by loyalty to his trapped pupils, and a deep sense of guilt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>University professor Ahmed Abu Shaban often gets up at 3:00 am in Toronto to remotely teach his students in Gaza -- motivated by loyalty to his trapped pupils, and a deep sense of guilt.</p>

<p>Shaban, an academic who fled Gaza days after October 7, 2023, said he has an obligation to students in the Palestinian Territory desperate to study in defiance of unimaginable challenges.</p>

<p>He also said he has a responsibility to help preserve higher education in Gaza, while the world is focused on the humanitarian emergency.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But the 50-year-old conceded that guilt also weighs on him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Guilty for leaving Gaza," he told AFP. "Like we just abandoned our country, our people, our institution."</p>

<p>Shaban is still the dean of the Faculty of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine at Al-Azhar University, which was destroyed -- along with most university buildings -- by Israeli air strikes.</p>

<p>Shaban crossed to Egypt shortly after the war began, anticipating Israel's response to the Hamas attack would be "massive," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Canadian contacts arranged a posting at Toronto's York University, where he is a visiting professor in the Faculty of Environmental and Urban Change.</p>

<p>In a campus office with empty book shelves and mostly bare walls, Shaban explained that he felt compelled to help make Al-Azhar operational in some form.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He wanted "to give the very clear message for the whole world: Yes, they just destroyed our infrastructure. Yes, they destroyed our buildings... but we are still alive and we will just continue," he said.</p>

<p>"This is actually a responsibility for our students, for our nation, and for our independent state in the future."</p>

<p>- Hunger to study -<br />
Shaban, who is on Al-Azhar's board, said its pre-war enrolment was 14,000 students.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When registration opened for online courses earlier this year he expected 1,000 students to join.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We got 10,000," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It was really, for me, shocking because, just imagine: you live in a tent, you have no electricity, you have no internet. You have nothing at all.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"But you still have the hope to go to sign up for online courses and to walk for five (kilometres) to get internet connection and even to communicate, to sit and study. And sometimes you risk your life even while you are searching for internet."</p>

<p>Shaban conceded his personal schedule is "stressful," as he tries to work in two time zones.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One day last month, he was up at 3:00 am to join a workshop on Gaza's food system, before an Al-Azhar board meeting at 6:00 am. He then headed to his Toronto office to prepare a guest lecture on the Gaza war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On evenings and weekends he records and uploads lectures for his Palestinian students.</p>

<p>Shaban said the study program is flexible, given the challenges of internet access. Students watch lectures and complete assigments when they can get online. &nbsp;</p>

<p>- Star student killed -<br />
He said students in Gaza can be "angry" and "pushy": they want to know, for example, when they will able to do lab work, even though all the labs have been destroyed.</p>

<p>Shaban said he understands their frustrations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Sometimes you feel the students are looking at us like we can do things that actually are not doable," he said. "I have to be responsive in a gentle way." &nbsp;</p>

<p>As agitated student messages pour in, Shaban said he reminds himself that he is living comfortably in a city with electricity and grocery stores stocked with food.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"(I) try just to provide them with whatever support that I can. There are many things that I cannot do," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Students who have died are always front of mind.</p>

<p>He recalled five engineering students killed as they gathered by an internet source to work on an assignment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Shaban said he will never forget his "star student" Bilal al Aish, who, days before the war started, was trying to decide whether to pursue a scholarship in Germany or the American Fulbright.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I saw the hope in his eyes, not only for his own future, but also the future of our institutions."</p>

<p>Shaban said Aish was killed by an Israeli strike early in the war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I got the feeling they are killing the future," the professor said. "That was really painful for me."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/cm9foito_ahmed-abu-shaban-afp_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ahmed Abu Shaban said he has a responsibility to help preserve higher education in Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>