<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 04:34:48 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-moves-to-forgive-4-7-billion-in-us-loans-to-ukraine-7067784]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Administration Moves To Forgive $4.7 Billion In US Loans To Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-moves-to-forgive-4-7-billion-in-us-loans-to-ukraine-7067784]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 04:34:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden administration has moved to forgive about $4.7 billion in US loans to Ukraine, State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden administration has moved to forgive about $4.7 billion in US loans to Ukraine, State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller said on Wednesday, as outgoing officials seek to do what they can before leaving office to bolster Ukraine in its war against Russia.</p>

<p>A funding bill passed by the US Congress in April included just over $9.4 billion of forgivable loans for economic and budgetary support to Ukraine's government, half of which the president could cancel after November 15. The bill appropriated a total of $61 billion to help Ukraine fight the full-scale invasion Moscow launched in February 2022.</p>

<p>"We have taken the step that was outlined in the law to cancel those loans," Miller told a press briefing, adding that the step was taken in recent days.</p>

<p>Congress could still block the move, Miller said.</p>

<p>The Senate is due to vote later on Wednesday on a motion of disapproval of loan forgiveness for Ukraine put forward by Republican Senator Rand Paul, a frequent critic of US support for Ukraine. The majority of senators from both parties support aid to Ukraine.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden has ordered officials to rush as much aid to Ukraine as possible before he leaves office on Jan. 20 amid concerns President-elect Donald Trump could limit US support.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/tjjj9r4s_biden-zelensky_625x300_13_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden has ordered officials to rush as much aid to Ukraine as possible before he leaves office.(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-parliament-approves-labour-partys-bill-to-renationalise-rail-services-7067726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Parliament Approves Bill To Renationalise Rail Services]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-parliament-approves-labour-partys-bill-to-renationalise-rail-services-7067726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 04:13:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Legislation put forward by the UK's new Labour government to renationalise the country's rail services, most of which are privately owned, was on Wednesday given the go-ahead by parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Legislation put forward by the UK's new Labour government to renationalise the country's rail services, most of which are privately owned, was on Wednesday given the go-ahead by parliament.</p>

<p>The bill will bring rail operators into public ownership when the private companies' contracts expire -- or sooner in the event of poor management -- and will be managed by "Great British Railways".</p>

<p>The TSSA rail union hailed the law as a "landmark" after an attempt by the opposition Conservatives to amend the legislation was defeated in the House of Lords, the upper house of parliament, by 213 votes to 210.</p>

<p>"This really is a landmark moment paving the way for our railways to return to public hands, where they belong, as a vital service," said TSSA General Secretary Maryam Eslamdoust.</p>

<p>Labour triumphed over the Conservative party in elections on July 4, re-entering Downing Street after 14 years in opposition with promises to fix the country's ailing transport services.</p>

<p>The government has said it will be able to avoid having to pay compensation fees to rail operators, with all the current contracts set to expire by 2027.</p>

<p>The privatisation of rail operations took place in the mid-1990s under the Conservative prime minister John Major, but the rail network remained public, run by Network Rail.</p>

<p>Four of 14 operators in England have been taken over by the state in recent years because of poor performance, but this was meant to be a temporary fix before a return to the private sector.</p>

<p>The main rail operators in Scotland and Wales, where transport policy is handled by the devolved administrations in Edinburgh and Cardiff, are also state-owned.</p>

<p>British railways have faced a constant stream of strikes over pay and conditions in the last few years due to a cost-of-living crisis.</p>

<p>Train cancellations are commonplace and passengers regularly complain about high ticket prices.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/uk-train-station-reuters_650x400_81500915566.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Passengers regularly complain about high ticket prices. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-calls-for-peace-in-ukraine-ceasefire-in-gaza-during-brazil-visit-7067467]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping Calls For Peace In Ukraine, Ceasefire In Gaza During Brazil Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-calls-for-peace-in-ukraine-ceasefire-in-gaza-during-brazil-visit-7067467]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:40:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese leader Xi Jinping urged "more voices" to end the Ukraine war and a ceasefire in Gaza, as he conducted a state visit to Brazil's capital, Chinese state media said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese leader Xi Jinping urged "more voices" to end the Ukraine war and a ceasefire in Gaza, as he conducted a state visit to Brazil's capital, Chinese state media said.</p>

<p>Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva echoed those points as he met with Xi in a red-carpet welcome in Brasilia, and stressed a joint roadmap for peace in Ukraine that they are proposing.</p>

<p>"In a world plagued by armed conflicts and political strife, China and Brazil put peace, diplomacy and dialogue first," Lula said.</p>

<p>Xi said he wanted to see "more voices committed to peace to pave the way for a political solution to the Ukraine crisis," the Chinese state news agency Xinhua reported.</p>

<p>He also called for "a ceasefire and an end to the war at an early date" in Gaza, the agency said.</p>

<p>On Ukraine, the China-Brazil roadmap for mediating peace has been endorsed by Russia -- which is China's ally -- but rejected by Kyiv and its Western backers.</p>

<p>The Chinese president's appeal for a halt to fighting in Gaza -- where Israel is pressing an offensive against Hamas -- echoed one he and the other G20 leaders made during a summit held Monday and Tuesday in Rio.</p>

<p>That summit's joint statement called for a "comprehensive" ceasefire in both Gaza and Lebanon, where Israel is also waging an offensive against the Iran-backed Hezbollah group.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the UN Security Council held a vote on a resolution calling for "an immediate, unconditional and permanent ceasefire" in Gaza, but it was vetoed by Israel's ally the United States.</p>

<p><strong>China filling 'vacuum'</strong></p>

<p>Xi's state visit to Brasilia showcased closer relations between the biggest economies in Asia and Latin America, which analysts said also reflected shrinking US influence.</p>

<p>The two leaders signed 35 cooperation accords on areas including agriculture, trade, technology and environmental protection.</p>

<p>Xi said China-Brazil relations "are at their best in history" and the two countries are now "reliable friends," according to Xinhua.</p>

<p>Lula said he believed the growing Brazil-China ties "will exceed all expectations and pave the way for a new phase of bilateral relations."</p>

<p>He added that he looked forward to welcoming Xi to Brazil again next July for a BRICS summit.</p>

<p>The Chinese leader figured prominently at the G20 summit, and at an APEC one held last week in Peru -- in contrast with outgoing US President Joe Biden, who cut a spectral figure.</p>

<p>Fellow leaders looked past Biden, politically, to the coming US presidency of Donald Trump, which starts January 20.</p>

<p>"Xi Jinping is clearly looking to fill the vacuum that will come following the election of Trump, who does not value multilateralism," Oliver Stuenkel, an international relations expert at Brazil's Getulio Vargas Foundation think tank, told AFP.</p>

<p><strong>'Synergies'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>China is Brazil's biggest trading partner, with two-way commerce exceeding $160 billion last year.</p>

<p>The South American agricultural power sends mainly soybeans and other primary commodities to China, while the Asian giant sells Brazil semiconductors, telephones, vehicles and medicines.</p>

<p>Since returning to power in early 2023, Lula has sought to balance efforts to improve ties with both China and the United States.</p>

<p>A visit to Beijing this year by Vice President Geraldo Alckmin was seen as paving the way for Brazil to potentially join China's Belt and Road Initiative to stimulate trade -- a central pillar of Xi's bid to expand China's clout overseas.</p>

<p>But there was no announcement in that direction during Xi's visit. Instead both leaders spoke of finding "synergies" between that Chinese program and Brazil's own infrastructure development program.</p>

<p>South American nations that have signed up to Beijing's initiative include Argentina, Chile, Bolivia, Ecuador, Peru, and Venezuela.</p>

<p>One of the accords signed Wednesday was on Brazil opening its market to a Chinese satellite company, SpaceSail, that competes with Starlink, founded and run by South African-born US billionaire Elon Musk, which already covers remote Brazilian regions.</p>

<p>Musk has a turbulent history with Brazil, whose courts forced his social media platform X to comply with national laws against disinformation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/00gpup8_xi-jinping-g20_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[That summit's joint statement called for a "comprehensive" ceasefire in both Gaza and Lebanon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-vivek-ramaswamy-plan-to-slash-us-federal-spending-and-regulation-7067416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk, Vivek Ramaswamy Plan To Slash US Federal Spending And Regulation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-vivek-ramaswamy-plan-to-slash-us-federal-spending-and-regulation-7067416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:28:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk outlined plans Wednesday for his new role as "efficiency" czar -- signaling an assault on federal spending and staffing that would be backed by President-elect Donald Trump's executive powers and a conservative Supreme Court.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk outlined plans Wednesday for his new role as "efficiency" czar -- signaling an assault on federal spending and staffing that would be backed by President-elect Donald Trump's executive powers and a conservative Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In the Wall Street Journal, the world's richest man said he was taking aim at hundreds of billions of dollars in government spending -- including funding for public broadcasting and abortion rights group Planned Parenthood -- as well as at bureaucracy that represents an "existential threat" to US democracy.</p>

<p>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO said that he, along with fellow businessman and Trump loyalist Vivek Ramaswamy, would work to slash federal regulations and make major administrative cuts and cost savings.</p>

<p>"We are entrepreneurs, not politicians. We will serve as outside volunteers, not federal officials or employees," Musk and Ramaswamy wrote in their most detailed remarks since Trump named them heads of a new Department of Government Efficiency.</p>

<p>Musk said DOGE -- a nod to Musk's support for a cryptocurrency -- will prepare a list of regulations issued by government agencies without Congress approval, which Trump could then invalidate by executive order.</p>

<p>"When the president nullifies thousands of such regulations, critics will allege executive overreach. In fact, it will be correcting the executive overreach of thousands of regulations enacted by administrative fiat that were never authorized by Congress," Musk said.</p>

<p>He added that a reduction in regulations would pave the way for "mass head-count reductions across the federal bureaucracy," and said DOGE would aim to cut more than $500 billion in government expenditures.</p>

<p>"With a decisive electoral mandate and a 6-3 conservative majority on the Supreme Court, DOGE has a historic opportunity for structural reductions in the federal government," Musk said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hsb5uvqo_trump-elon-musk_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk said DOGE will prepare a list of regulations issued by government agencies. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-no-hostage-for-prisoner-swap-with-israel-unless-gaza-war-ends-7067381]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Says No Hostage-For-Prisoner Swap With Israel Unless Gaza War Ends]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-no-hostage-for-prisoner-swap-with-israel-unless-gaza-war-ends-7067381]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:15:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas' acting Gaza chief Khalil al-Hayya said in an interview with Al-Aqsa TV released on Wednesday that there would be no hostages-for-prisoners swap deal with Israel unless the war in the Palestinian enclave ended.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas' acting Gaza chief Khalil al-Hayya said in an interview with Al-Aqsa TV released on Wednesday that there would be no hostages-for-prisoners swap deal with Israel unless the war in the Palestinian enclave ended.</p>

<p>"Without an end to the war, there can be no prisoner swap," Hayya said in a televised interview with the group's Al-Aqsa television channel, reiterating the group's position on how to bring the war to an end.</p>

<p>"If the aggression is not ended, why would the resistance and in particular Hamas, return the prisoners (hostages)?" he said. "How would a sane or an insane person lose a strong card he owns while the war is continuing?"</p>

<p>Hayya, who led the group's negotiating team in talks with Qatari and Egyptian mediators, blamed the lack of progress on Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who in turn holds the Islamist group responsible for the stalled talks.</p>

<p>"There are contacts under way with some countries and mediators to revive this file (negotiation). We are ready to continue with those efforts but it is more important to see a real will on the side of the occupation to end the aggression," said Hayya.</p>

<p>"The reality proves that Netanyahu is the one who undermines it (negotiations)," he added.</p>

<p>Speaking during a visit to Gaza on Tuesday, Netanyahu said that Hamas would not rule the Palestinian enclave after the war had ended and that Israel had destroyed the Islamist group's military capabilities.</p>

<p>Netanyahu also said Israel had not given up trying to locate the 101 remaining hostages believed to be still in the enclave, and he offered a $5 million reward for the return of each one.</p>

<p>Hamas wants a deal that ends the war and sees the release of Israeli and foreign hostages held captive in Gaza as well as Palestinians jailed by Israel, while Netanyahu vowed the war can only end once Hamas is eradicated.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m9qq4ic8_hamas_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas seeks a deal ending the war and the release of Israeli and foreign hostages in Gaza. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-slams-canadian-report-on-nijjar-murder-plot-calls-it-smear-campaign-7067116]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Slams Canadian Report On Nijjar Murder Plot, Calls It "Smear Campaign"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-slams-canadian-report-on-nijjar-murder-plot-calls-it-smear-campaign-7067116]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:59:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Wednesday strongly trashed as "smear campaign" a Canadian media report that claimed that the Indian prime minister was aware of the alleged plot to kill Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Wednesday strongly trashed as "smear campaign" a Canadian media report that claimed that the Indian prime minister was aware of the alleged plot to kill Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</p>

<p>Referring to the report quoting an unnamed official, External Affairs Ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said such "ludicrous statements" should be dismissed with the contempt they deserve.</p>

<p>"We do not normally comment on media reports. However, such ludicrous statements made to a newspaper purportedly by a Canadian government source should be dismissed with the contempt they deserve," he said.</p>

<p>"Smear campaigns like this only further damage our already strained ties," he said.</p>

<p>Jaiswal was responding to media queries regarding the report in Canadian newspaper The Globe and Mail.</p>

<p>In the report, the newspaper cited inputs from a senior national security official.</p>

<p>The report claimed the Indian national security advisor and the external affairs minister were also in the loop of the plot.</p>

<p>Nijjar was gunned down on Canadian soil last year.</p>

<p>India-Canada ties nosedived last month after Canada linked Indian High Commissioner Sanjay Verma and some other diplomats to the murder.</p>

<p>India has strongly rejected all the allegations made by Ottawa in connection to the case and subsequently recalled the high commissioner. The Canadian government had said the Indian diplomats were expelled from the country.</p>

<p>New Delhi expelled Canadian Charge d'Affaires Stewart Wheeler and five other diplomats following Canada's allegations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/122o7v0g_modi-trudeau-afp_625x300_23_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has strongly rejected all the allegations made by Ottawa in connection to the case. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-automaker-jaguar-rebrands-itself-with-new-logo-netizens-unimpressed-7067019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Automaker Jaguar Rebrands Itself With New Logo, Netizens Unimpressed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-automaker-jaguar-rebrands-itself-with-new-logo-netizens-unimpressed-7067019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:23:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prior to its relaunch as an electric-only brand, luxury car manufacturer Jaguar announced its 'new era ' by unveiling its new logo and branding.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to its relaunch as an electric-only brand, luxury car manufacturer Jaguar announced its 'new era ' by unveiling its new logo and branding. The Tata Motors-owned British vehicle maker on Tuesday revealed a new bespoke logo, written as JaGUar, alongside a new prancing "leaper" cat design and marketing slogans like ‘delete ordinary', ‘live vivid' and ‘copy nothing'.</p>

<p>The new logo emphasized the brand's posh English pronunciation “Jag-you-are" instead of the American “Jag-wahr." The company said the new branding "seamlessly blended upper and lower case characters in visual harmony."</p>

<p>The 102-year-old luxury automaker announced its transition to electric vehicles in 2021. The brand is reportedly set to launch three new electric cars by 2026 after it took new cars off-sale over a year ago to focus on reinventing itself.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“This is a reimagining that recaptures the essence of Jaguar, returning it to the values that once made it so loved, but making it relevant for a contemporary audience,” said Gerry McGovern, Jaguar Land Rover's chief creative officer, in a press release.</p>

<p>As per a report by Car and Driver, the pouncing cat logo called 'the Leaper', which has adorned Jaguar cars for decades, is being eliminated in favour of the badge.</p>

<p>Jaguar's Managing Director Rawdon Glover called the rebranding as the "biggest step change" in the company's history.</p>

<p>"A new era begins for Jaguar. This is an incredibly exciting time for the whole team. To re-imagine such a globally renowned brand really is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity. Today, Jaguar unveils its new brand identity, recapturing its ethos to "Copy Nothing" that can trace its roots back to the words of our founder, Sir William Lyons," he posted on LinkedIn.&nbsp;</p>

<p>How the new branding will look on the cars will be unveiled at a Miami Art Week event on December 2.</p>

<p>"Watch out for the global unveiling of the first physical manifestation of our brand reinvention in Miami on December 2, where Jaguar will champion true originality, as a creator and advocate of artistic expression, in all its forms," Mr Glover said.</p>

<p>However, the social media reactions to the rebranding have not been very reassuring. Replying to the relaunch video posted by Jaguar on X, one internet user wrote: “Umm where are the cars in this ad? Is this for fashion?” To this, the brand replied, “Think of this as a declaration of intent.”&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Copy nothing. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Jaguar?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Jaguar</a> <a href="https://t.co/BfVhc3l09B">pic.twitter.com/BfVhc3l09B</a></p>
— Jaguar (@Jaguar) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jaguar/status/1858800846646948155?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another user wrote, "Jaguar took a year off for this? This is how companies fail." Replying to this, the brand said, "This is not the end. This is the new beginning."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Jaguar took a year off for this?<br />
<br />
This is how companies fail.</p>
— BitS (@BotintheShell) <a href="https://twitter.com/BotintheShell/status/1859021742783787277?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Tesla chief Elon Musk also joined the cacophony to express his confusion over the rebranding and wrote: “Do you sell cars?” To this, Jaguar's official X account responded: "Yes. We'd love to show you. Join us for a cuppa in Miami on 2nd December?"<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/67gomnq8_jaguar-twitter_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new logo emphasized the brand's posh English pronunciation "Jag-you-are".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-told-employees-to-destroy-messages-to-avoid-antitrust-scrutiny-report-7066976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Told Employees To Destroy Messages To Avoid Antitrust Suits: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-told-employees-to-destroy-messages-to-avoid-antitrust-scrutiny-report-7066976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:14:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Even as Google, the internet giant, stored the world's information, it kept a lid on its internal communications - telling employees to destroy messages, to not use certain words - to avoid antitrust suits, claimed a report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even as Google, the internet giant, stored the world's information, it kept a lid on its internal communications - telling employees to destroy messages and not use certain words - to avoid antitrust suits, claimed a report.</p>

<p>The company has been deploying such strategies since 2008, when it faced antitrust scrutiny over an advertising deal with its then-rival Yahoo and sent out a confidential memo to its employees, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/20/technology/google-antitrust-employee-messages.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">New York Times report</a> said.</p>

<p>"Google said employees should refrain from speculation and sarcasm and think twice before writing one another about hot topics," said the report, adding that the employees were asked to not comment before they have "all the facts".</p>

<p>The technology, said the Times, was tweaked, too. "The setting for the company's instant messaging tool was changed to "off the record." An incautious phrase would be wiped the next day," it said.</p>

<p>"How Google developed this distrustful culture was pieced together from hundreds of documents and exhibits, as well as witness testimony, in three antitrust trials against the Silicon Valley company over the last year," said the report.</p>

<p>The testimony showed that Google took numerous steps to keep a lid on internal communication, it said.</p>

<p>"It encouraged employees to put 'attorney-client privileged' on documents and to always add a Google lawyer to the list of recipients, even if no legal questions were involved and the lawyer never responded," said the report.</p>

<p>Companies anticipating litigation are required to preserve documents, mandate the US laws. "But Google exempted instant messaging from automatic legal holds. If workers were involved in a lawsuit, it was up to them to turn their chat history on. From the evidence in the trials, few did," the report said.</p>

<p>Google has faced the broadest criticism for its actions, with the judges in all three antitrust cases chastising the company for its communications practices, said the report.</p>

<p>"Judge James Donato of the US District Court for the Northern District of California, who presided over the Epic (2020 Epic Games) case, said that there was 'an ingrained systemic culture of suppression of relevant evidence within Google' and that the company's behavior was 'a frontal assault on the fair administration of justice,'" the report said.</p>

<p>In another case involving the company's advertising technology, a district court judge in Virginia remarked that Google's document retention policies were designed in a way that an "awful lot of evidence has likely been destroyed".</p>

<p>Google produced 13 times as many emails as the average company per employee did before it was a decade old, Kent Walker, Google's top lawyer, testified in the Epic trial, said the report. Google felt overwhelmed, he said, and it was clear to the company that things would only become worse if changes weren't made, the report said quoting him.</p>

<p>The 2008 memo that said chat messages would be automatically purged was signed by Mr. Walker and Bill Coughran, an engineering executive.</p>

<p>Mr Walker, said the report, was asked to explain Google's behaviour to the judge. He denied that there was "a culture of concealment" but said one problem was Googlers unsure of the meaning of certain words, the report said.</p>

<p>"Last year, Google changed its procedures. The default became saving everything, including chats. Employees on litigation holds can no longer turn chat history off," the report said further.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/uspt4bmg_google-generic-reuters_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-hybrid-warfare-russias-potential-response-to-ukrainian-strike-7066728]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Hybrid Warfare? Russia's Potential Response To Ukrainian Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-hybrid-warfare-russias-potential-response-to-ukrainian-strike-7066728]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 23:22:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A strike using US-made missiles has sparked concerns of a Russian retaliation that could expand the conflict's scope.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine's recent strike inside Russia using US-made missiles has raised fears of Russian retaliation through "hybrid warfare." This strategy combines cyberattacks, sabotage, disinformation, and even physical violence to destabilise opponents, according to a report by The Guardian.</p>

<p>Hybrid warfare aims to cause disruption, interfere with military supplies, and put pressure on Ukraine's allies by blurring traditional battle lines. Mark Rutte, the secretary general of NATO, emphasised how Moscow is increasingly using these strategies to escalate tensions from Ukraine to Europe and beyond.</p>

<p>The news report further mentions that in the past, Russia has been connected to sabotage attempts, election-related disinformation campaigns, and hacking campaigns. Cyberattacks from Estonia and drone-related arrests in Norway close to vital infrastructure are examples of incidents. Global security is complicated by hybrid warfare.</p>

<p>"What is new about attacks seen in recent years is their speed, scale and intensity, facilitated by rapid technological change and global interconnectivity," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nato.int/cps/en/natohq/topics_156338.htm">Nato said in June.</a> "Counter-hybrid support teams" would provide assistance, but it was primarily up to individual countries to protect themselves.</p>

<p><strong>Emerging Signs of Hybrid Warfare in the North and Baltic Seas</strong></p>

<p>In April, Estonia and other Baltic states warned that widespread GPS jamming increased the threat of an aviation accident. The disturbance to location services was blamed on Russian "hybrid activity" in the region, Estonia said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The disruption led Finnish carrier Finnair to suspend flights to the Estonian city of Tartu, near the Russian border.&nbsp;The airline's pilots had noticed an increase in interference since 2022, including the airspace close to Russia's Kaliningrad region on the Baltic Sea.</p>

<p><strong>Border trouble</strong></p>

<p>Russia has also created alarm by starting disputes over borders in the Baltic Sea. Moscow published a resolution this year which showed it planned to unilaterally change its maritime frontiers with Finland and Lithuania from 2025.</p>

<p>Russian border guards in May removed buoys from the Narva River which showed the border with Estonia, officials in Tallinn said. The disappearance of the markers was part of a "broader pattern" by Moscow to use "tools related to the border to create fear and anxiety", Estonian Prime Minister Kaja Kallas said.<br />
<br />
<em>(With inputs from AFP)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cr5f0kf_hybrid-warfare_625x300_20_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[European nations face cyberattacks, arson, sabotage, and plots, fueling tensions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-liam-payne-given-final-farewell-by-family-one-direction-bandmates-in-private-funeral-7066563]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pics: Liam Payne's Final Farewell By Family, Bandmates In Private Funeral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-liam-payne-given-final-farewell-by-family-one-direction-bandmates-in-private-funeral-7066563]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 22:53:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Friends, family and former bandmates of One Direction star Liam Payne came together on Wednesday to pay the final tribute to the British singer at his funeral in Buckinghamshire, England.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Friends, family and former bandmates of One Direction star Liam Payne came together on Wednesday to pay the final tribute to the British singer at his funeral in Buckinghamshire, England. Mr Payne died at age 31 last month after falling from a hotel room in &nbsp;Argentina's Buenos Aires.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the mourners at the private service at St Mary's Church in Amersham, just outside London, were Payne's former bandmates Harry Styles, Niall Horan, Zayn Malik and Louis Tomlinson.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Former One Direction band members Harry Styles at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/olou8ug_liam-payne-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Former One Direction band members Harry Styles at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>Former One Direction band member Harry Styles at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The late singer's girlfriend Kate Cassidy also attended the service, as did his former partner, the Girls Aloud singer Cheryl Tweedy, with whom he shares 7-year-old son Bear.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Kate Cassidy (2L) and model Damian Hurley (2R) at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qhoi23qg_liam-pyane-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Kate Cassidy (2L) and model Damian Hurley (2R) at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em>Kate Cassidy (2L) and model Damian Hurley (2R) at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)</em></small></p>
</div>

<p>Payne's coffin arrived in a white horse-drawn hearse topped with floral tributes spelling the words "Son" and "Daddy" followed by his parents, while several dozen fans and onlookers lined a quaint street. The members of the public stood silently as they observed the arriving guests.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Pallbearers carry the coffin of Liam Payne, ahead of his funeral service (AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f9u60c68_liam-payne-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Pallbearers carry the coffin of Liam Payne, ahead of his funeral service (AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em>Pallbearers carry the coffin of Liam Payne, ahead of his funeral service (AFP)</em></small></p>
</div>

<p>Guests were seen hugging each other before walking past floral tributes into the 12th-century church to pay their final respects to the singer.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Flowers are carried into the church ahead of the funeral service of Payne (AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q2pohkgg_liam-pyane-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Flowers are carried into the church ahead of the funeral service of Payne (AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em>Flowers are carried into the church ahead of the funeral service of Payne (AFP)</em></small></p>
</div>

<p>Payne was found dead on October 16 after falling from the balcony of his third-floor room at the Casa Sur Hotel in the Argentinian capital. He died from "multiple traumas" and "internal and external haemorrhaging", a post-mortem examination found. Investigators have said he was alone at the time of his death and appeared to have been "going through an episode of substance abuse".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Former One Direction band member Zayn Malik (L) at funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kd0iur1_liam-pyane-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Former One Direction band member Zayn Malik (L) at funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>Former One Direction band member Zayn Malik (L) at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The singer's death prompted an outpouring of grief from family, former bandmates and fans across global, with thousands gathering in cities around the world to offer condolences.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCmfB15zYX1/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCmfB15zYX1/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCmfB15zYX1/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCmfB15zYX1/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by NDTV WORLD (@ndtvworld)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>In a short statement following his death, Payne's family said: "We are heartbroken. Liam will forever live in our hearts and we'll remember him for his kind, funny and brave soul."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Former One Direction band member Niall Horan at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP Photo)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q8dtslfo_liam-pyane-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Former One Direction band member Niall Horan at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP Photo)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>Former One Direction band member Niall Horan at the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP Photo)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>One Direction said they had been "completely devastated" by his death.</p>

<p>Payne was born and raised in Wolverhampton, in central England. He is survived by his parents, two sisters and a son with Cheryl Tweedy. He shot to stardom as a teenager alongside Mr Styles, Mr Horan, Mr Tomlinson and Mr Malik after they formed the band 'One Direction' on the hit UK talent show "The X Factor" 14 years ago.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="A mourner carries an order of service as they leave after attending the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2f8ij028_liam-pyane-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="A mourner carries an order of service as they leave after attending the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em>A mourner carries an order of service as they leave after attending the funeral service of Liam Payne (AFP)</em></small></p>
</div>

<p>After forming in 2010, the band went on to release an album of radio-ready songs each year in time for the holiday shopping season and became one of the highest-grossing live acts in the world. In 2016, after Mr Malik left, the group said it was on an indefinite hiatus but not splitting up.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kitenrlo_liam-payne-obit_625x300_18_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Payne's first solo single "Strip That Down" peaked at number three on the UK charts and number 10 on the US Billboard top songs list. His last solo work, a single called "Teardrops", was released in March, with a second album promised at the time.</p>

<p>In recent years he had spoken publicly about struggles with substance abuse and coping with fame from an early age.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lda9ags8_liam-payne-funeral-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pallbearers carry the coffin of the late One Direction singer Liam Payne, ahead of his funeral service]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/narendra-modi-1st-indian-pm-in-56-years-to-visit-guyana-signs-key-agreements-7066480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Narendra Modi 1st Indian PM In 56 Years To Visit Guyana, Signs Key Pacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/narendra-modi-1st-indian-pm-in-56-years-to-visit-guyana-signs-key-agreements-7066480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 22:39:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and Guyana on Wednesday agreed to ramp up cooperation in areas of defence, trade, energy, pharmaceutical and agriculture as Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Guyanese President Mohamed Irfaan Ali held extensive bilateral talks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and Guyana on Wednesday firmed up 10 agreements to shore up cooperation in a range of key sectors such as hydrocarbons, digital payment systems, pharmaceutical and defence following talks between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Guyanese President Mohamed Irfaan Ali.</p>

<p>In his media statement, PM Modi said Guyana will play an important role in India's energy security and a blueprint for long-term partnership in the sector will be prepared.</p>

<p>"The visit of an Indian Prime Minister to Guyana after 56 years is an important milestone in our relations. I have had a deep personal bond with Guyana," he said while recalling his visit as a common citizen to the South American country about 24 years back.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister arrived here last night from the Brazilian city of Rio de Janeiro, where he attended the G20 summit.</p>

<p>One of the MoUs will provide for the possibility for deployment of India's UPI (Unified Payments Interface)&nbsp; digital payments system in Guyana.</p>

<p>"In today's meeting, we have identified many new initiatives to strengthen our cooperation. We will continue to make efforts to increase our mutual trade and economic cooperation," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said India will continue to contribute to the capacity building of Guyana's military through scholarships and training.</p>

<p>"Close cooperation in the field of defence is a symbol of our deep mutual trust. I am happy that this year India has supplied two Dornier aircraft to Guyana," he said.</p>

<p>The agreements signed between the two sides will provide for cooperation in a vast range of areas, including hydrocarbons, agriculture, medicines, digital payment systems, culture and digital transformation.</p>

<p>In his remarks, PM Modi said India has made a significant contribution to the skill development and capacity building of the people of Guyana as per their needs.</p>

<p>The two sides also agreed to expand cooperation in the agriculture sector.</p>

<p>"With the millet seeds provided by India last year, we were able to contribute to increasing the food security of Guyana as well as the entire region," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"Similarly, we will also cooperate in increasing the cultivation of rice milling, sugarcane, corn, soya and other crops," he said.</p>

<p>In the talks, the Indian side also agreed to set up a Jan Aushadhi Kendra in Guyana.</p>

<p>"Along with increasing pharma exports, we will also work on building Jan Aushadhi Kendra in Guyana. India has been contributing as a reliable partner in the infrastructure development of Guyana," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>The two leaders also deliberated on regional and global issues.</p>

<p>"We also discussed many global and regional issues. India and Guyana agree that all problems should be resolved through dialogue and diplomacy," the Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>"We are unanimous that reform in global institutions is the need of the hour. Climate Justice is a priority issue for both of us. We will continue to work together on all issues," he said.</p>

<p>On his part, President Ali said PM Modi's visit to Guyana represents a significant milestone in enhancing cooperation between the two nations.</p>

<p>He praised Prime Minister Modi, calling him a 'champion among leaders' for his impactful leadership and contribution to the developing world.</p>

<p>"Thank you very much, Prime Minister Modi. It is our greatest honour to have you here. You are a champion among leaders. You have led incredibly," President Ali said during a joint press statement with PM Modi.</p>

<p>He lauded PM Modi's governance style, noting its relevance and adoption in Guyana and other nations.</p>

<p>"You have shown the light to the developing world, and you have created development metrics and a framework that many are adopting in their own country. And much of it is relevant to us here in Guyana," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mlanv2gg_narendra-modi-guyana-president-mohamed-irfaan-ali-pti_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi being received by Guyana President Mohamed Irfaan Ali.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-tops-worlds-best-cities-2025-no-indian-city-in-top-100-report-7066478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[London Tops World's Best Cities 2025, No Indian City In Top 100: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-tops-worlds-best-cities-2025-no-indian-city-in-top-100-report-7066478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 22:38:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[London has topped a definitive ranking of the World's Best Cities 2025 released on Wednesday for the tenth year in a row, even as Indian cities failed to make the cut based on the criteria of perception and perception.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>London has topped a definitive ranking of the World's Best Cities 2025 released on Wednesday for the tenth year in a row, followed closely by New York and Paris, even as Indian cities failed to make the cut based on the criteria of perception and performance.</p>

<p>The annual rankings produced by Resonance Consultancy in partnership with Ipsos are an analysis of large urban regions around the world that are leading in aspects most important to attracting workforce, visitors, and businesses.</p>

<p>The 2025 report marks a first in incorporating perception-based data by surveying more than 22,000 people in 31 countries for the first time - the results of which also demonstrate that people all over the world still very much aspire to live, visit, and work in the world's largest cities.</p>

<p>"Mumbai and Delhi are just outside of the top 100; those cities in the Asia Pacific context are in the top but at a global scale don't make the top 100," Chris Fair, President &amp; CEO of Resonance Consultancy, told PTI in response to a question at the launch of the report in London.</p>

<p>"Mumbai and Delhi have some particular strengths, but they have some particular weaknesses from a livability perspective relative to these other cities and a livability perspective as well. But in our Asia-Pacific report in February, they are in the top 20," he said.</p>

<p>The World's Best Cities ranking is drawn up on "livability", or the physical sense of a city based on the quality of its natural and built environments; "lovability", or the quality of life in terms of culture, dining and nightlife; and "prosperity", or the human capital of a city and the support it receives to thrive. The goal is to create the most comprehensive and holistic approach to measuring and benchmarking both the perception and performance of the cities.</p>

<p>"London continues to set the bar for what a truly great city should be," said Laura Citron, CEO of London &amp; Partners, the UK capital's growth agency.</p>

<p>"Our iconic attractions, world-class financial sector, and fast-growing tech industry are proof of our city's strength. But it's the diversity of our people and ideas that drives the innovation, opportunities, and progress that shape our future. No city embodies this quite like London," she said.</p>

<p>After London (UK), New York (US), Paris (France), Tokyo (Japan), Singapore, Rome (Italy), Madrid (Spain), Barcelona (Spain), Berlin (Germany) and Sydney (Australia) complete the top 10.</p>

<p>While the United States is in the lead with 36 cities in the Top 100, Canada comes in a distant second with six cities and Cape Town and Rio de Janeiro make a mark as new entrants to the 2025 ranking.</p>

<p>"The phrase 'perception is reality' is often used when developing reputation management strategies for companies, but the same holds true for destinations. By merging the top-of-mind destinations where people tell us they want to live, work, and visit with the rigorous evaluation of places that Resonance has been conducting for nearly a decade, we have created a more comprehensive evaluation of cities and can better advise destinations on how to strengthen their reputation," said Jason McGrath, Executive Vice President at Ipsos.</p>

<p>The overall World's Best Cities rankings are determined by analysing public perception, combined with a wide range of factors that have demonstrated moderate to strong correlations with attracting prime-age population (aged 25-44), visitor expenditure, and/or business formation. The key takeaway from the latest analysis is the strength and resilience of some of the world's large cities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/hblgr79k_london-generic_625x300_05_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The World's Best Cities ranking is drawn up on "livability".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/johnson-johnson-risks-uk-lawsuit-over-talcum-powder-cancer-claim-by-thousands-7066062]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Johnson & Johnson Risks UK Lawsuit Over Powder Cancer Claim By Thousands]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/johnson-johnson-risks-uk-lawsuit-over-talcum-powder-cancer-claim-by-thousands-7066062]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 21:34:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK claimants on Wednesday announced legal action against US pharmaceutical and cosmetics giant Johnson & Johnson, alleging that women diagnosed with cancers were exposed to asbestos in the company's talcum powder.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK claimants on Wednesday announced legal action against US pharmaceutical and cosmetics giant Johnson &amp; Johnson, alleging that women diagnosed with cancers were exposed to asbestos in the company's talcum powder.</p>

<p>J&amp;J risks UK court action for the first time over the allegations, having faced a series of similar lawsuits in North America.</p>

<p>KP law, the firm representing about 2,000 claimants, said "women who have been diagnosed with life-changing and life-limiting cancers were exposed to asbestos contained within the company's talcum powder".</p>

<p>In response Erik Haas, J&amp;J's worldwide vice president of litigation, said "Johnson &amp; Johnson takes the issue of talc safety incredibly seriously and always has".</p>

<p>Haas added that J&amp;J's own analysis found an absence of asbestos contamination in its products and said "independent science makes clear that talc is not associated with the risk of ovarian cancer nor mesothelioma".</p>

<p>J&amp;J has until the end of the year to respond to a letter sent on behalf of KP Law's clients, following which documents will be filed in the UK's High Court.</p>

<p>The law firm is representing predominantly women regarding the case, and says it has been contacted by thousands more, adding that some have died of their cancers.</p>

<p>Lawyers claim that the US-based corporation knew "as early as the 1970s that asbestos in its talc products was dangerous but failed to warn consumers and carried on producing and selling the products in the UK until as recently as 2022".</p>

<p>J&amp;J said that Kenvue, its former consumer-health division that it separated out in 2023, is responsible for "any alleged talc liability that arises outside the US or Canada".</p>

<p>Kenvue did not immediately respond to a request for comment from AFP . &nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>SETTLED CLAIMS</strong></h2>

<p>However, in September, J&amp;J increased its offer to settle talc claims relating to ovarian cancer in the US to around $8 billion to be paid over 25 years.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, the company agreed to pay $700 million to settle allegations it misled customers about the safety of its talcum-based power products in North America.</p>

<p>The company did not admit wrongdoing in its settlement but withdrew the product from the North American market in 2020.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization's cancer agency in July classified talc as "probably carcinogenic" for humans.</p>

<p>A summary of studies published in 2020 covering 250,000 women in the United States did not find a statistical link between the use of talc on the genitals and the risk of ovarian cancer.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ah814mac_johnson-johnson-powder-johnson-and-johnson-powder-getty_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK claimants announced legal action against US pharmaceutical and cosmetics giant Johnson & Johnson]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-cant-support-unconditional-us-vetoes-gaza-ceasefire-call-at-un-7065762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Can't Support Unconditional...": US Vetoes Gaza Ceasefire Call At UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-cant-support-unconditional-us-vetoes-gaza-ceasefire-call-at-un-7065762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:59:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Wednesday vetoed a UN Security Council push to call for a ceasefire in Gaza that Washington said would have emboldened Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Wednesday vetoed a UN Security Council push to call for a ceasefire in Gaza that Washington said would have emboldened Hamas.</p>

<p>The resolution demanded "an immediate, unconditional and permanent ceasefire" in the war between Israel and the Palestinian group, along with "the immediate and unconditional release of all hostages."</p>

<p>But the wording angered Israel, with a senior US official warning ahead of the vote that the resolution had "the potential only to buoy Hamas, which will have no reason to come to the negotiating table."</p>

<p>Israel's UN ambassador Danny Danon said "The resolution being considered by the Security Council today is nothing short of a betrayal."</p>

<p>"For us, it has to be a linkage between a ceasefire and the release of hostages," said Robert Wood, the deputy US ambassador to the United Nations. "It has been our principal position from the beginning and it still remains."</p>

<p>The war was triggered by the assault on Israel by Hamas militants on October 7, 2023, a stunning cross-border raid that resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza said the death toll from the resulting war had reached 43,985 people, the majority civilians. The United Nations considers the figures reliable.</p>

<p>Of 251 hostages seized during the October 7 attack, 97 remain in Gaza, including 34 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Almost all of Gaza's 2.4 million people have been displaced by the war, which has caused a humanitarian catastrophe.</p>

<p><strong>- Gaza 'will haunt' -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Since the beginning of the conflict, the Security Council has struggled to speak with one voice, as the United States used its veto power several times, although Russia and China have as well.</p>

<p>"China kept demanding 'stronger language'," said the US official who also claimed that Russia had been "pulling strings" with the countries responsible for pushing the latest resolution.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The few resolutions that the United States did allow to pass by abstaining stopped short of calling for an unconditional and permanent ceasefire.</p>

<p>In March, the council called for a temporary ceasefire during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, but this appeal was ignored by the warring parties.</p>

<p>And in June, the 15-member body pledged support for a US resolution that laid out a multi-stage ceasefire and hostage release plan that ultimately went nowhere.</p>

<p>"We regret that the Council could have incorporated compromise language the UK put forward to bridge the existing gaps... With that language, This resolution should have been adopted," Wood, the US envoy, said following the vote.</p>

<p>Some diplomats have expressed optimism that following Donald Trump's election win on November 5, President Joe Biden might be more flexible in his few remaining weeks in power.</p>

<p>They hoped for a repeat of December 2016 when then-president Barack Obama's second term was finishing and the council passed a resolution calling for a halt to Israeli settlement building in the occupied territories, a first since 1979.</p>

<p>The United States refrained from using its veto then, a break from traditional US support for Israel on the sensitive issue of settlements.</p>

<p>The resolution vetoed on Wednesday calls for "safe and unhindered entry of humanitarian assistance at scale," including in besieged northern Gaza, and denounces any attempt to starve the Palestinians.</p>

<p>The Palestinian delegation at the United Nations has suggested the text did not go far enough.</p>

<p>"Gaza's fate will haunt the world for generations to come," Ambassador Riyad Mansour warned.</p>

<p>He said the only course of action for the Security Council is to call for an immediate and unconditional ceasefire under Chapter 7 of the UN charter.</p>

<p>That chapter allows the council to take steps to enforce its resolutions, such as sanctions, but the latest text made no reference to this option.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1qvfgfig_gaza-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-us-missile-ukraine-fires-uks-storm-shadow-into-russia-report-7065709]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After US Missile, Ukraine Fires UK's 'Storm Shadow' Into Russia: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-us-missile-ukraine-fires-uks-storm-shadow-into-russia-report-7065709]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:50:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine's armed forces fired British cruise missiles at military targets inside Russia for the first time, a Western official familiar with the matter said, as the 1,000-day conflict enters a new phase.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine's armed forces fired British cruise missiles at military targets inside Russia for the first time, a Western official familiar with the matter said, as the 1,000-day conflict enters a new phase.</p>

<p>The UK approved the use of Storm Shadow missiles in response to Russia deploying North Korean troops in its war against Ukraine, a move the British government considered to be an escalation, according to the person, who spoke on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The issue dominated the Group of 20 leaders' summit in Brazil this week after US President Joe Biden gave the go-ahead for Ukraine to fire long-range ATACMS missiles at Russian targets. But Starmer didn't publicly back the move, despite long being seen as an advocate, leading to questions about whether his government would allow the use of British-made Storm Shadows.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy has long called for Western governments to bolster military support, including allowing the use of long-range missiles to hit targets in Russia that are crucial to Vladimir Putin's war effort.</p>

<p>Storm Shadow debris was found in Russia's Kursk region to the north of Ukraine and two missiles were intercepted over Yeysk, a Black Sea port in the southern Krasnodar region, according to the Telegram channel Rybar, which has connections to the army and more than 1.3 million subscribers. The information couldn't be independently verified.</p>

<p>US Treasuries pared declines after the latest missile launch was announced.</p>

<p>It comes a day after the Russian Defense Ministry said Ukraine had used Western-supplied ATACMS for the first time to strike a military facility inside Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jcghstvc_storm-shadow-missile-ukraine_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Storm Shadow debris was found in Russia's Kursk region to the north of Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-un-watchdog-said-on-israels-claim-of-destroying-irans-secret-nuke-site-7065603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What UN Watchdog Said About Israel Destroying Iran's 'Top Secret Nuke Site']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-un-watchdog-said-on-israels-claim-of-destroying-irans-secret-nuke-site-7065603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:31:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UN nuclear watchdog chief Rafael Grossi said Wednesday that the agency did not consider Iran's Parchin site "a nuclear facility" after Israel claimed it hit Tehran's nuclear programme in a strike last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UN nuclear watchdog chief Rafael Grossi said Wednesday that the agency did not consider Iran's Parchin site "a nuclear facility" after Israel claimed it hit Tehran's nuclear programme in a strike last month.</p>

<p>"We don't have any information that would confirm (the) presence of nuclear material" in Parchin, even though the site "could have been involved in the past in some activities," Grossi told reporters&nbsp;in Vienna.</p>

<p>"But as far as the IAEA is concerned, we do not see this as a nuclear facility," he said.</p>

<p>"I leave it to those military decision makers to judge and characterise places," he added.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said that Israel's late October attack on Iran damaged "a component" of the Islamic Republic's nuclear programme.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Image Posted On X By @TheGoodISIS" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/famt62ko_iran-top-secret-nuclear-site-parchin-taleghan-twitter_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Image Posted On X By @TheGoodISIS" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em>Image Posted On X By @TheGoodISIS</em></small></p>
</div>

<p>"It has been published that a certain component of their nuclear programme was hit in this attack," Netanyahu told the Israeli parliament.</p>

<p>"The programme itself and its ability to operate here have not yet been thwarted," he added.</p>

<p>US news portal Axios reported that the attack on Iran had "destroyed an active<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-military-destroys-top-secret-iranian-nuclear-weapons-lab-report-7033453" target="_blank"> top secret nuclear weapons research facility</a> in Parchin", quoting unidentified US and Israeli officials.</p>

<p>The site is some 50 kilometres (31 miles) southeast of Tehran.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel has repeatedly accused Iran of wanting to acquire an atomic bomb, a claim Tehran has denied.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fl16v0vg_iran-to-secret-nuclear-site-parchin-taleghan-twitter_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has repeatedly accused Iran of wanting to acquire an atomic bomb]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-may-be-forced-to-sell-its-chrome-browser-heres-why-7065231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google May Be Forced To Sell Its Chrome Browser. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-may-be-forced-to-sell-its-chrome-browser-heres-why-7065231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:41:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Department of Justice (DoJ) reportedly wants the court to order Alphabet Inc. to sell off the Chrome browser to dismantle the monopoly Google has over the internet search market and related advertising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alphabet Inc.'s Google might have to sell Chrome, the world's most widely used browser. The US Department of Justice (DoJ) reportedly wants the court to order Alphabet Inc. to sell off the browser to dismantle the monopoly Google has over the internet search market and related advertising. Google, meanwhile, said that if it is forced to sell Chrome, the move would harm its consumers and businesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last month, the Department of Justice filed papers in the court saying it was considering enforcing "structural remedies" to prevent Google from using some of its products. On Wednesday, the antitrust enforcers will propose the measure to a judge, according to a report by Bloomberg.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Chrome holds almost 90 per cent share of the global search engine market as of October, according to StatCounter. Moreover, it controls about 61 per cent of the US market.</p>

<h2><strong>Case Against Google's Monopoly</strong></h2>

<p>The DoJ brought the case against Google during US president-elect Donald Trump's first four-year term. In a landmark ruling in August, Judge Amit Mehta ruled that Google operates an online search monopoly and has been considering what remedies or penalties to impose.</p>

<p>Since then, prosecutors have suggested several potential ways forward in the case, including ending billions of dollars with exclusive agreements that Google has with Apple and other companies to remain the default search engine on their tablets and smartphones, and divesting parts of its business, such as its Android operating system.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the DoJ is likely to go ahead with several of those proposals, including one that requires Google to divest its Chrome browser. The antitrust officials, along with states that have joined the case, are also planning to recommend that federal judge Amit Mehta impose data licensing requirements on Google, the Bloomberg reported quoting sources.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Should a sale proceed, Chrome would be worth "at least USD 15 - USD 20 billion, given it has over 3 billion monthly active users," according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://mercury.bloomberg.com/news/SN5JQ9DWRGG000" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Bloomberg </a>Intelligence analyst Mandeep Singh.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Google's Response</strong></h3>

<p>Google has called the proposal 'radical' and said it would harm its consumers and businesses in the US and also shake American competitiveness in artificial intelligence.</p>

<p>Previously, the company has denied operating a monopoly in the online search market. Responding to the DoJ's filing in October, Google has said that "splitting off" parts of its business like Chrome or Android would "break them".</p>

<p>"Breaking them off would change their business models, raise the cost of devices, and undermine Android and Google Play in their robust competition with Apple's iPhone and App Store," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy4g193qezno" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">BBC </a>quoted the company as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now, Google is reportedly planning an appeal after US District Judge Amit Mehta makes his final ruling by August 2025. The company will have a chance to make its proposal in December.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k09plus8_google-reuters_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google Chrome holds almost 90 per cent share of the global search engine market]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-return-bringing-china-india-closer-india-us-advocacy-group-head-7065111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Return Bringing India-China Closer: India-US Advocacy Group Head]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-return-bringing-china-india-closer-india-us-advocacy-group-head-7065111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:26:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During his presidential election campaign, Trump proposed a 60 per cent tariff on goods from China -- and a tariff of up to 20 per cent on every other US import.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China is trying to improve ties with India in an attempt to ease pressure from the incoming Trump administration, the head of a top India-centric US business advocacy and strategic group said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>During his presidential election campaign, Trump proposed a 60 per cent tariff on goods from China -- and a tariff of up to 20 per cent on every other US import.</p>

<p>Mukesh Aghi, president of the US-India Strategic and Partnership Forum (USISPF), said: "So, we are seeing an early impact of the Trump administration coming in that has created pressure on China to ease dealing with India. So that's why border patrolling has been agreed upon. Direct flights have been agreed upon."</p>

<p>"They will also issue more visas to Chinese coming to India. You are seeing the impact of Trump coming in having a positive impact on the India-China relationship," he further said.</p>

<p>Last month, India announced that it had reached an agreement with China on patrolling along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in eastern Ladakh, in a breakthrough in ending the over four-year-long military standoff.</p>

<p>"The calculation on the part of the Chinese was that Trump was coming in. The relationship with the US will get stressful. So, why have multiple fronts of this stressful relationship? 'Let's at least ease the partnership or potential relationship with India itself'," Aghi told PTI in an interview.</p>

<p>India is likely to play an important role in Trump's "America First" policy by offering a place for secure sourcing while the new administration plans to move manufacturing away from China and create jobs in the US, he added.</p>

<p>"Efforts by the Trump administration to put in tariffs so it can put pressure on companies to move manufacturing back to the US, it's not going to happen overnight. It took almost 40 years for manufacturing to move out of the US. The challenge we have is we don't have enough skills. We don't have enough manpower to help us from that perspective. So, the transition will take time," Aghi said.</p>

<p>"That's where India can play a pivotal role by saying, 'Yes, we'll help you move manufacturing back to the US but we will also manufacture a lot of these components in India' and they become part of the global supply chain. It helps you because you're not dependent geopolitically on a risk factor in China but you depend on a friend. I see the concept of secure sourcing becoming much more pivotal and stronger than outsourcing or friend-shoring itself," the USISPF boss added.</p>

<p>"You will see India's role becoming much more pivotal as you look at building America first. At the same time, Atmanirbhar Bharat also within that supply chain becomes very critical," he said.</p>

<p>Aghi also claimed that corporate America was "very happy" with the election results.</p>

<p>"They feel Trump understands how challenging it is to run and grow businesses. He will hopefully bring the taxes down for corporations, which will help them to become much more profitable and grow the business itself. The corporate community welcomes the new administration, which is the Trump administration," he said.</p>

<p>"The market has gone up. What's interesting is also that the dollar has become stronger. That shows the confidence in the incoming administration by corporate America," Aghi said.</p>

<p>Responding to a question on the impact of the elections on the India-US relationship, the business leader said it was not just dependent on administrations.</p>

<p>"It is dependent on the geopolitical alignment between the two countries. It's dependent on economics. It's dependent on trade. It's dependent on people to people. When you look at geopolitics, India-US is aligned, especially with China itself," he said.</p>

<p>"We are seeing a tremendous amount of activities taking place between the two countries, under the umbrella of Quad with Japan and Australia. On the trade side, you have USD 200 billion in trade, which is expected to keep growing. On the technology side, what we're seeing is Indians are building a lot of US technology in India itself. The global capability centres are generating a substantial amount of IP (intellectual property) for US companies," said the USISPF chief.</p>

<p>Aghi also said the five million Indian-Americans generated almost 6 per cent of the US's GDP while only being 1 per cent of the population.</p>

<p>"The Trump administration will come in looking at how you create jobs in the US. That's where India has to play a very strong role by saying, 'Yes, we will support the US plus one strategy'. Will that interfere with India's strategy of Atmanirbhar Bharat? No. I think both can coexist and support each other for mutual success," he noted.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ujo0i4l_modi-xi-jinping-reuters_625x300_20_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China is trying to improve ties with India in an attempt to ease pressure from the Trump administration]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putins-chilling-new-nuclear-doctrine-what-it-says-7065052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin's Chilling New Nuclear Doctrine - What It Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putins-chilling-new-nuclear-doctrine-what-it-says-7065052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:18:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Titled "Basic Principles of State Policy on Nuclear Deterrence", Vladimir Putin approved changes to the nuclear doctrine on Tuesday, chilling rules by which the country would now use its atomic arsenal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Titled "Basic Principles of State Policy on Nuclear Deterrence", Vladimir Putin approved changes to the nuclear doctrine on Tuesday, chilling rules by which the country would now use its atomic arsenal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The big change in the doctrine now says that an attack from a non-nuclear state backed by a nuclear state will be viewed by Russia as a joint attack on it.</p>

<p>Although the new changes were proposed in September, the document was approved only on Tuesday - which was coincidentally the 1,000th day of the Russo-Ukrainian War.</p>

<p>This development took place after the Biden administration had made a significant policy change, allowing Ukraine to use US-made ATACMS missiles to strike targets inside Russia for the first time.</p>

<p>This decision came just two months before President Joe Biden hands over power to Donald Trump, who has expressed scepticism about US military aid to Ukraine.</p>

<p>Now, even a large attack with missiles, drones or aircraft could be met with a nuclear response. The nuclear doctrine will also be extended to Russia's close ally Belarus.</p>

<p>Moreover, any attack from a state which is a member of a coalition would be seen as aggression from the entire group.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although Putin has threatened to use nuclear weapons earlier, Ukraine has dismissed it as "nuclear sabre-rattling" to discourage its allies from providing support.</p>

<p>However, Sergey Lavrov, Russia's Foreign Minister has said that "we strongly are in favour of doing everything to not allow nuclear war to happen".</p>

<p>Russia has signed a declaration at the G20 Summit in Rio de Janeiro along with the other countries, about which Lavrov said, "clearly said we want to move towards a world free of nuclear weapons".</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov has said that the doctrine should go through a "deep analysis" and that it is a "very important text".</p>

<p>On the other hand, Matthew Miller said, "I'm unfortunately not surprised by the comments the Kremlin has made around the publication of this new, revised document," and that since the start of the war, Russia has tried to "coerce and intimidate both Ukraine and other countries around the world through irresponsible nuclear rhetoric and behaviour."</p>

<p>Tatiana Stanovaya, a political scientist, of the Carnegie Russia and Eurasia Center, said, "the current situation offers Putin a significant temptation to escalate" and that Putin offers the West two choices "'Do you want a nuclear war? You will have it,' or 'Let's end this war on Russia's terms,'" she posted on X.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dg0ait4_vladimir-putin-reuters_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin approved changes to the nuclear doctrine on Tuesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/will-trumps-doge-be-a-failed-experiment-7064954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Will Trump's DOGE Be A Failed Experiment?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/will-trumps-doge-be-a-failed-experiment-7064954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:01:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In his first term, the OAI received flak for influencing Trump's government policies. The office was silently closed during the transition after President Joe Biden took charge in 2021. Would DOGE meet the same fate?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/p9khknjg_doge_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The US president-elect, Donald Trump, recently appointed tech billionaire Elon Musk and biotech investor Vivek Ramaswamy to lead the new DOGE (Department of Government Efficiency) in his second administration.</p>

<p>On their selection, Trump said that the “two wonderful Americans” shall “dismantle government bureaucracy, slash excess regulations, cut wasteful expenditures, and restructure federal agencies” through the newly formed department. However, Trump made it clear that the pair would act in an advisory capacity and that the DOGE would not be an official government department.</p>

<p>With this announcement, Trump created a seemingly important role for his ‘buddy' Musk, who supported him with his time and money during the presidential campaign. Ramaswamy ran as a Republican candidate for President earlier this year against Trump, before dropping out and endorsing him. Since his re-election, Trump has been busy naming his core team with his loyalists, overriding concerns about impartiality and conflicting interests.</p>

<p>Both Musk and Ramaswamy have companies with ongoing government contracts. Even as advisors, they will have occasions to further their business interests directly or indirectly, and this will not attract US government conflict of interest laws.</p>

<p>Both Republican and Democratic presidents have in the past adopted different approaches to make the government efficient and to cut spending. In fact, a similar attempt was made in Trump 1.0, with the OAI (Office of American Innovation) set up under his son-in-law Jared Kushner to “make government operate like a business”. However, the OAI saw little success.</p>

<h2><strong>What Exactly Is DOGE?</strong></h2>

<p>The concept of DOGE was suggested by Trump in early September during the election campaign. At one of the meetings, Trump said that in 2022, “fraud and improper payments alone cost taxpayers an estimated hundreds of billions of dollars”. Then, just days after his win, Trump declared that Musk and Ramaswamy would work with the White House and Office of Management &amp; Budget to tackle "massive waste and fraud" in $6.5 trillion of annual government spending.</p>

<p>Not much is known about the official composition and functioning of the newly announced DOGE, or about its funding. Since it won't be a government department, it will not require the US Congress's approval for its creation.</p>

<p>Trump expects Musk and Ramaswamy's work to conclude by no later than July 4, 2026, which will also be the 250th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence. On November 14, an X account for DOGE said that the group was ‘‘accepting resumes from super high-IQ small-government revolutionaries willing to work 80+ hours per week on unglamorous cost-cutting". In a separate post, Musk said "compensation is zero”.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why Many Are Sceptical</strong></h2>

<p>The eventual goal of DOGE is to rationalise federal operations and cut significant government spending by at least $2 trillion, which would mean substantial reductions across all programmes, including essential services like Social Security and Medicare, potentially antagonising millions of voters. However, experts are sceptical about DOGE's success.</p>

<p>“The chances of DOGE succeeding are slim because of several reasons. The bureaucracy is too entrenched for any major gains in reducing the federal workforce; in any case, their salaries are a very small part of the budget,” says Uma Purushothaman, Associate Professor, US Studies, School of International Studies, JNU. DOGE can provide recommendations to the White House but actually lacks direct authority to make spending cuts or regulatory changes. “The US Constitution gives Congress 'the power of the purse'. This means that any change or reduction in allocation will have to go through Congress, where Trump has a very slim majority,” says Purushothaman. “And it is quite possible that some Republicans in both houses might not want to support some of these reforms,” she adds.</p>

<h2><strong>Castles In The Air?</strong></h2>

<p>Instead of comparing the DOGE experiment with other past presidents' similar initiatives that were largely unsuccessful, it would be better to compare it with the OAI conceived during Trump's first term.</p>

<p>The OAI was a part of the White House office lasting from 2017 until 2021. Under the leadership of Kushner, the group was to be the link between the American technology industry and the Trump administration. It was supposed to reform the federal bureaucracy with “new thinking and real change” to tackle the country's hardest problems. From workforce shortages and infrastructure challenges to reforming prisons and addressing the opioid crisis, the tasks were enormous.</p>

<p>However, other than carrying out IT modernisation in the government and organising the CEO summit, attended by Amazon's Jeff Bezos, Apple's Tim Cook, Microsoft's Satya Nadella, IBM's Ginni Rometty and more, there isn't much to report about it. The OAI definitely received flak for influencing Trump's government policies. The office was silently closed during the transition after President Joe Biden took charge in 2021. Would DOGE meet the same fate?</p>

<p>“The DOGE's aims are too ambitious, whether in terms of money or time. It is unlikely that DOGE will succeed at this scale or within this time frame. Yes, it will probably suffer the same fate as the Office of American Innovation, especially if the next administration is a Democratic one,” says Purushothaman.</p>

<p>The DOGE epitomises yet another exploratory method of governance in the US – one where businessmen would apply their corporate experiences to resolve public sector issues. Whether this will lead to any meaningful changes or remain largely symbolic, only time will tell. Until then, the world can't dodge the DOGE stories.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dpi50emo_doge_625x300_20_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>