<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 09:38:00 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-sent-to-jail-for-overfeeding-53-kg-dog-to-death-in-new-zealand-6219720]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Sent To Jail For Overfeeding 53 Kg Dog To Death In New Zealand]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-sent-to-jail-for-overfeeding-53-kg-dog-to-death-in-new-zealand-6219720]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:52:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Veterinarians using a stethoscope were unable to detect Nuggi's heartbeat because of his extreme weight, according to the SPCA statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman from New Zealand was sentenced to two months in prison after her dog, who weighed 53 kilograms (118 pounds) and was severely obese, died, as per a report in <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/dog-owner-jailed-obese-dog-dies-1930819">Newsweek</a></em>. According to a statement from the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (SPCA), the dog, named Nuggi, was found by police in 2021 weighing about 54 kilograms (120 pounds) and nearly immobile.</p>

<p>Nuggi was taken from his owner's Auckland house, where police discovered "a number of" dogs, and given over to the SPCA.</p>

<p>Nuggi died of a liver haemorrhage even though it lost 8.8 kilograms (19.6 pounds) or around 16.5 per cent of his body weight in two months while in the care of the SPCA. The organisation claims that an autopsy disclosed additional health issues, including Cushing's illness and liver problems.</p>

<p>According to the statement, the owner pleaded guilty to failing to provide for the dog's medical, behavioural, and physical needs. As a result, the Manukau District Court in Auckland sentenced the owner to two months in jail and a fine of $1,222 NZD ($720). It is also said that she will not be allowed to own dogs for a year.</p>

<p>Veterinarians using a stethoscope were unable to detect Nuggi's heartbeat because of his extreme weight, according to the SPCA statement. The dog also had a lot of skin growths, especially on contact regions like his elbows and tummy, and his claws were enlarged. Further, Nuggi had conjunctivitis as well.</p>

<p>Todd Westwood, SPCA Chief said that the dog was "drastically overfed" and "clearly" did not have proper care. "Nuggi was one of the most obese animals we've ever come across," Mr Westwood said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Sadly, we see animals on a daily basis that are underweight, starved or malnourished, but it's equally heartbreaking to see a helpless animal that's been severely overfed," he continued.</p>

<p>The SPCA added that the pet dog was fed around 10 pieces of chicken every day along with dry food. Nuggi allegedly struggled to travel around 10 meters to the car when veterinarians took him away from his owner, pausing three times to gather breath. The SPCA said, "His legs could not support his huge body."</p>

<p>"Part of being a responsible dog owner is providing your pet with an appropriate diet and daily exercise, which was clearly not the case here. Nuggi was being drastically overfed, and instead of seeking help or amending the behaviour, his owner continued to overfeed him until he could barely walk. This is unacceptable," Mr Westwood added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4pt777mo_woman-sent-to-jail-for-overfeeding-53-kg-dog-to-death-in-new-zealand_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nuggi died of a liver haemorrhage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-priest-sues-grindr-after-he-was-outed-and-forced-to-step-down-6219691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Priest Sues Grindr After He Was Outed And Forced To Step Down]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-priest-sues-grindr-after-he-was-outed-and-forced-to-step-down-6219691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:43:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Burrill was forced to resign from his position after the Christian news website published a story exposing his visits to gay bars and use of the dating app.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Wisconsin priest who lost his job after being outed for using Grindr is suing the queer dating app, alleging that his data was sold without his knowledge or consent.</p>

<p>Monsignor Jeffrey Burrill, who served as the top administrator of the US Conference of Catholic Bishops (USCCB) until his resignation in 2021, claims that Grindr failed to inform him that his data was being sold to vendors, thereby allowing people outside the app to discover his presence on it.</p>

<p>Burrill's lawsuit, obtained by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2024/07/27/priest-grindr-privacy-lawsuit/"><em>Washington Post</em></a>, states that the release of his data caused "significant damage" to his reputation, particularly given his vow of celibacy as a priest and the Catholic Church's long-standing stance against homosexual acts.</p>

<p>Burrill was forced to resign from his position after the Christian news website "The Pillar" published a story exposing his visits to gay bars and use of the dating app, reporting that it had tracked and verified his behaviour using online data.</p>

<p>In his lawsuit, Burrill alleges that The Pillar obtained the data from Catholic Laity and Clergy for Renewal (CLCR), a Christian non-profit organization that purchased data from queer dating apps to identify Church leaders using them in violation of their vows, implying that Grindr had sold the data to the organization.</p>

<p>“We want answers so we can use that as a warning to other Grindr users,” said Gregory Helmer, an attorney for Burrill.</p>

<p>The priest said he'd never have joined the app had he known his data would be available to the public, according to the lawsuit.</p>

<p>“To have that decision forced out of your hands and into the public realm is reprehensible,” James Carr, another attorney representing Burrill, told the Washington Post.</p>

<p>Burrill, who is still "getting on his feet" following the "shame and embarrassment" of his outing, according to his lawyer Helmer, requested $5 million in damages from Grindr in June.</p>

<p>After Grindr declined his request, Burrill filed a lawsuit on July 18, seeking damages and the implementation of policies to prevent user data from being publicly available without users' knowledge.</p>

<p>Grindr told the Washington Post it would "respond vigorously to these allegations, which are based on mischaracterizations of practices relating to user data," and previously denied making user data publicly available.</p>

<p>CLCR admitted to obtaining data from Grindr in the past to expose clergy members but claimed it did not provide any data to The Pillar.</p>

<p>Burrill's ousting sparked widespread criticism, with many condemning The Pillar's use of data as dangerously homophobic.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/p8kr9iv8_monsignor-jeffrey-burrill_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Burrill alleges that The Pillar obtained the data from Catholic Laity]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nicolas-maduro-edmundo-gonzalez-explained-whats-happening-with-venezuela-election-and-why-us-is-concerned-6219507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What's Happening With Venezuela Election And Why US Is Concerned]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nicolas-maduro-edmundo-gonzalez-explained-whats-happening-with-venezuela-election-and-why-us-is-concerned-6219507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 07:52:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro claimed victory in the country's presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro claimed victory in the country's presidential election in the early hours of Monday morning, even as the country's opposition said its candidate Edmundo Gonzalez was the victor and it had the polling to prove it.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT HAPPENED WITH THE COUNT?</strong></h3>

<p>The country's electoral authority (CNE) said just after midnight on Monday that Maduro had won a third six-year term with 51% of the vote.</p>

<p>The authority said Gonzalez won 44%, but opposition leader Maria Corina Machado said opposition candidate Gonzalez had secured 70% of the vote and that multiple independent exit polls and quick counts decisively showed his victory.</p>

<p>Gonzalez said he was not calling for supporters to take to the streets or commit any acts of violence and Machado said the opposition has copies of about 40% of voting records.</p>

<p>Edison Research, known for its polling of U.S. elections, had predicted in an exit poll that Gonzalez would win 65% of the vote, while Maduro would win 31%.</p>

<p>Local firm Meganalisis predicted a 65% vote for Gonzalez and just under 14% for Maduro.</p>

<h3><strong>WAS VOTING PEACEFUL?</strong></h3>

<p>The government said that except for some isolated minor incidents, voting was peaceful.</p>

<p>Motorcycle-riding ruling party supporters known as 'collectives' clashed briefly in the evening with opposition supporters outside the country's largest polling place, a school in central Caracas.</p>

<p>Armed collectives were reported in at least six other locations, according to a local NGO, which also reported the gun death of one man in the border state of Tachira during a confrontation with collective members.</p>

<p>The tense campaign was marked by arrests of opposition figures and other moves by the authorities that the opposition said were meant to prevent a fair election.</p>

<p>Maduro, a former bus driver who was the hand-picked successor of his mentor Hugo Chavez, has been in power since Chavez's death in 2013.</p>

<p>His government has presided over a sharp economic and social deterioration. The U.S. reimposed oil sanctions in April, accusing Maduro of reneging on deals reached with the opposition to ensure free elections.</p>

<h3><strong>WHO IS GONZALEZ?</strong></h3>

<p>A long-time but low-profile member of the opposition, Gonzalez, 74, a former diplomat, is known for his calm demeanor.</p>

<p>He was originally registered as a placeholder in March, after neither primary winner Machado nor her alternate were able to register. In April, he was named as the opposition's definitive candidate.</p>

<p>Machado, 56, has thrown herself into campaigning for Gonzalez.</p>

<p>The two - speaking to large crowds around the country - have employed emotional rhetoric, including about their hope for the many who have emigrated from Venezuela in recent years to return home.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT WAS THE INTERNATIONAL RESPONSE?</strong></h3>

<p>The United States has serious concerns that the results announced by the electoral authority do not reflect the votes of the people, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Monday, asking that a detailed tabulation of votes be published.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, reactions from Latin American leaders were mixed.</p>

<p>Argentine President Javier Milei called the official result fraud, while Costa Rica and Peru rejected it and Chile said it would not accept any result that was not verifiable.</p>

<p>Cuba, Honduras and Bolivia cheered Maduro's victory.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cp0topv_nicolas-maduro_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro claimed victory in the country's presidential election]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-why-the-israel-hezbollah-conflict-is-heating-up-again-6219438]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explainer: Why The Israel-Hezbollah Conflict Is Heating Up Again]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-why-the-israel-hezbollah-conflict-is-heating-up-again-6219438]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 07:35:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A deadly rocket strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights has added to concerns that Israel and the Iran-backed Lebanese group Hezbollah could be sucked into a full-scale war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A deadly rocket strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights has added to concerns that Israel and the Iran-backed Lebanese group Hezbollah could be sucked into a full-scale war - something they have both previously indicated they want to avoid but for which they have also said they are ready.</p>

<p>Israel said on Sunday it would strike hard at Hezbollah after accusing the group of killing 12 children and teenagers in a rocket attack on a football field in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights. Hezbollah denied any responsibility for the attack on Majdal Shams, the deadliest in Israel or Israeli-annexed territory since Hamas' Oct. 7 assault sparked the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>This is the background to hostilities between Israel and Hezbollah:</p>

<p><strong>Why Are They Fighting?</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah began trading fire with Israel on Oct. 8, a day after the Palestinian militant group Hamas attacked communities in southern Israel and sparked the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, a Hamas ally, says its attacks aim to support Palestinians who are under Israeli bombardment in Gaza.</p>

<p>The Gaza war has drawn in Iran-backed militants across the region. Hezbollah is widely deemed the most powerful member of the Iran-backed network, known as the Axis of Resistance.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said repeatedly it will not halt its attacks on Israel unless a ceasefire in Gaza comes into force.</p>

<p>While linked to Gaza, the conflict has its own dynamics.</p>

<p>Israel and Hezbollah have fought numerous wars.</p>

<p>The last was in 2006.</p>

<p>Israel has long viewed Hezbollah as the biggest threat at its borders and has been deeply alarmed by its growing arsenal, and the foothold it has established in Syria.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's ideology is largely defined by conflict with Israel. It was founded by Iran's Revolutionary Guards in 1982 to fight Israeli forces that had invaded Lebanon that year, and waged years of guerrilla war that led Israel to withdraw from south Lebanon in 2000.</p>

<p>Hezbollah deems Israel an illegitimate state established on occupied Palestinian lands and wants to see it gone.</p>

<p><strong>What's The Impact So Far?</strong></p>

<p>The current conflict has already taken a toll on both sides.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of people have been forced to flee their homes on both sides of the border. Israeli airstrikes have pounded areas where Hezbollah operates in southern Lebanon and struck the Bekaa Valley near the Syrian border.</p>

<p>Israel has also occasionally hit elsewhere, notably killing a senior Hamas commander in Beirut on Jan. 2.</p>

<p>Israeli strikes have killed some 350 Hezbollah fighters in Lebanon and more than 100 civilians, including medics, children and journalists, according to security and medical sources and a Reuters tally of death notifications issued by Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said after Saturday's attack the death toll among civilians killed in Hezbollah attacks had risen to 23 since October, along with at least 17 soldiers. Hezbollah denied it was responsible for Saturday's attack.</p>

<p>In Israel, the displacement of so many Israelis is a big political issue. Officials had hoped they would be able to go home for the school year beginning Sept. 1 but that has looked increasingly unlikely as the standoff has continued.</p>

<p><strong>How Much Worse Could It Get?</strong></p>

<p>A lot. Despite the ferocity of these hostilities, this is still seen as a relatively contained confrontation.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned in December that Beirut would be turned "into Gaza" if Hezbollah started an all-out war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has previously signalled it is not seeking to widen the conflict while also saying it is ready to fight any war imposed on it and warning that it has used only a small part of its capabilities so far.</p>

<p>Any move by Israel to expand the conflict would be met by "devastation, destruction and displacement" in Israel, Hezbollah deputy leader Sheikh Naim Qassem said in an interview with Al Jazeera in June.</p>

<p>Past wars have inflicted heavy damage.</p>

<p>In 2006, Israeli strikes levelled large areas of Beirut's Hezbollah-controlled southern suburbs, knocked out Beirut airport, and hit roads, bridges and other infrastructure. Nearly 1 million people in Lebanon fled their homes.</p>

<p>In Israel, the impact included 300,000 people fleeing their homes to escape Hezbollah rockets and some 2,000 homes destroyed.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has a far bigger arsenal than in 2006, including rockets it says can hit all parts of Israel.</p>

<p>It has demonstrated advances in its weaponry since October, shooting down Israeli drones, launching its own explosive drones into Israel, and firing more sophisticated guided missiles.</p>

<p>Israeli troops have invaded Lebanon several times in the past, reaching as far as Beirut in the 1982 invasion that aimed to crush Lebanon-based Palestinian guerrillas.</p>

<p><strong>Is Escalation Avoidable?</strong></p>

<p>Much will depend on what happens in Gaza, where efforts to agree a ceasefire and a return of Israeli hostages have faltered. A ceasefire there could help bring about a rapid de-escalation of tensions in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>The United States, which deems Hezbollah a terrorist group, has been at the heart of diplomatic efforts aimed at easing the conflict.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has signalled its eventual openness to an agreement that benefits Lebanon, but has said there can be no discussions until Israel halts the Gaza offensive.</p>

<p>Israel has also said it would prefer a diplomatic settlement that would restore security in the north, but says it is also prepared for a military offensive to achieve the same goal.</p>

<p>The U.S. official at the heart of diplomatic contacts, Amos Hochstein, brokered an unlikely diplomatic deal between Lebanon and Israel in 2022 over their disputed maritime boundary.</p>

<p>Hochstein said on May 30 he did not expect peace between Hezbollah and Israel but that a set of understandings could remove some of the impetus for conflict and establish a recognised border between Lebanon and Israel.</p>

<p>A French proposal submitted to Beirut in February included elite Hezbollah fighters withdrawing 10 km (6 miles) from the frontier and negotiations aimed at settling disputes over the land border.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/he0073tg_lebanon-rocket-attack-reuters_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah denied any responsibility for the attack on Majdal Shams.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/peru-orders-venezuelan-diplomats-to-leave-country-within-72-hours-6219210]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Peru Orders Venezuelan Diplomats To Leave Within 72 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/peru-orders-venezuelan-diplomats-to-leave-country-within-72-hours-6219210]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 06:26:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Peru's foreign ministry on Monday ordered Venezuelan diplomats accredited in the Andean nation to leave the country within 72 hours, after Venzuela's ruling party declared an election]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Peru's foreign ministry on Monday ordered Venezuelan diplomats accredited in the Andean nation to leave the country within 72&nbsp;hours after Venzuela's ruling party declared an election victory that the Venezuelan opposition and independent pollsters called implausible.</p>

<p>The ministry made the announcement in a statement citing the "serious and arbitrary decisions made today by the Venezuelan regime."</p>

<p>Peru had said earlier on Monday it would not accept a violation of Venezuelans' popular will and that it had recalled its ambassador.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cd10ugeg_peru-venezuela-reuters-_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Peru had said earlier it would not accept a violation of Venezuelans' popular will.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-paris-2024-opening-ceremony-6219174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm Very Open-Minded, But...": Trump Slams Paris 2024 Opening Ceremony]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-paris-2024-opening-ceremony-6219174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 06:14:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Monday called the Olympics opening ceremony in Paris a "disgrace," after its creators came under fire for what some said was a show gone too far.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Monday called the Olympics opening ceremony in Paris a "disgrace," after its creators came under fire for what some said was a show gone too far.</p>

<p>"I'm very open-minded but I thought what they did was a disgrace," Trump told Fox News.</p>

<p>His comments followed condemnation from Catholic groups and French bishops of a ceremony scene involving dancers, drag queens and a DJ in poses that appeared to recall depictions of the Last Supper, although creators have said it was not meant to represent the religious setting.</p>

<p>The sequence drew international criticism from Christian groups and far-right politicians on social media.</p>

<p>When asked by host Laura Ingraham what he would do if he's reelected president in time for the 2028 Olympics in Los Angeles, Trump replied: "We won't be having a 'Last Supper' as portrayed the way they portrayed it last night."</p>

<p>Thomas Jolly, the director of the opening ceremony, later responded to criticism by saying he intended for the production to "reconcile" and "repair."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0k183qe_donald-trump_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has criticised the opening ceremony of Paris 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-faces-criticism-over-deepfake-kamala-harris-video-6218487]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Faces Criticism Over Deepfake Kamala Harris Video]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-faces-criticism-over-deepfake-kamala-harris-video-6218487]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 02:12:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire X owner ElonMuskwas facingcriticismMonday for sharing adeepfakevideofeaturing US Vice PresidentKamalaHarris, which tech campaigners said violated the platform's own policies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire X owner Elon&nbsp;Musk&nbsp;was facing&nbsp;criticism&nbsp;Monday for sharing a&nbsp;deepfake&nbsp;video&nbsp;featuring US Vice President&nbsp;Kamala&nbsp;Harris, which tech campaigners said violated the platform's own policies.</p>

<p>Musk&nbsp;reposted a manipulated&nbsp;Harris&nbsp;campaign&nbsp;video&nbsp;in which a voiceover mimicking her calls President Joe Biden senile, and declares that she does not "know the first thing about running the country," adding that as a woman and a person of color, she is the "ultimate diversity hire.</p>

<p>The&nbsp;video&nbsp;was originally posted by an X account linked to the conservative podcaster Chris Kohls and labeled a "parody."</p>

<p>But&nbsp;Musk's repost on Friday made no such disclosure, stating only: "This is amazing," along with a laughing emoji.</p>

<p>Musk's repost garnered more than 130 million views and comes amid growing alarm&nbsp;over&nbsp;AI-enabled political disinformation ahead of the US presidential election in November.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We believe the American people want the real freedom, opportunity, and security Vice President&nbsp;Harris&nbsp;is offering; not the fake, manipulated lies of Elon&nbsp;Musk&nbsp;and Donald Trump,"&nbsp;Harris's presidential campaign said in a statement.</p>

<p>With nearly 192 million followers,&nbsp;Musk&nbsp;is a highly influential voice on the platform, previously called Twitter, which he purchased in 2022 in a $44 billion deal.</p>

<p>Earlier this month,&nbsp;Musk&nbsp;endorsed Trump&nbsp;in a post on X shortly after the Republican narrowly escaped an assassination attempt during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Gavin Newsom, the Democratic governor of California, posted on X that the manipulated&nbsp;Harris&nbsp;video&nbsp;"should be illegal" and that he would soon sign a bill banning such media.</p>

<p>A defiant&nbsp;Musk&nbsp;responded to his post, saying "parody is legal in America," while including the original&nbsp;video&nbsp;below it.</p>

<p>Musk's repost appeared to violate X's policies, which prohibit sharing "synthetic, manipulated or out-of-context media that may deceive or confuse people and lead to harm."</p>

<p>X did not respond to AFP's request for comment.</p>

<p>"Ignoring the rules of the road (because) he bought the road," Nora Benavidez, senior counsel at the watchdog Free Press, wrote on X, referring to&nbsp;Musk's apparent violation of the site's policies.</p>

<p>Disinformation researchers are fearful of rampant misuse of AI technology in a major election year, thanks to proliferating online tools that are cheap and easy to use while lacking sufficient guardrails.</p>

<p>AI-generated content -- particularly audio, which experts say is difficult to identify -- sparked national alarm in January when a fake robocall posing as Biden urged New Hampshire residents not to vote in the state's primary.</p>

<p>"Platforms play an outsized role in election cycles," Benavidez wrote. "They must do better."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/a945hc54_elon-musk_625x300_24_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tech campaigners said Elon Musk violated the platform's own policies by sharing deepfake video.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-foreign-ministers-warn-of-terrorists-using-new-technology-6218459]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Quad Foreign Ministers Warn Of Terrorists Using New Technology]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-foreign-ministers-warn-of-terrorists-using-new-technology-6218459]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 02:03:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Quad foreign ministers have reinforced their call for concerted international action against Pakistan-based Lashkar-e-Tayyiba (LeT), Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), as well as Al-Qa'ida and the Islamic State outfit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Warning against terrorists deploying new technologies, the Quad foreign ministers have reinforced their call for concerted international action against Pakistan-based Lashkar-e-Tayyiba (LeT), Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), as well as Al-Qa'ida and the Islamic State outfit.</p>

<p>After their meeting in Tokyo, the Quad ministers said in a joint statement on Monday that they were committed to working with international and regional partners to forestall "threats posed by the use of new and emerging technologies for terrorist purposes".</p>

<p>"We reiterate the call for concerted action against all UN-listed terrorist groups including Al-Qa'ida, ISIS/Daesh, Lashkar-e-Tayyiba (LeT), Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), and their proxy groups," External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Foreign Ministers Penny Wong of Australia and Yoko Kamikawa of Japan said in their statement.</p>

<p>"We deplore the use of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), drones, tunnels, and information and communication technologies by terrorists and terrorist entities," they said.</p>

<p>Recalling the 26/11 Mumbai and the 2016 Pathankot terrorist attacks, they called for "bringing the perpetrators of these attacks to justice without delay".</p>

<p>The ministers said the first meeting of the Quad Working Group on Counter-Terrorism established at the ministerial meeting in New Delhi last year had "fruitful discussions" at its first meeting and at the fourth tabletop exercise in Honolulu in December, and added that they looked forward to next exercise to be hosted by Japan in November.</p>

<p>The tabletop exercises look at scenarios to develop responses to an overwhelming terrorist incident in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<p>The 4,000-word joint statement ran the gamut from the conflicts in Ukraine and Palestine, and China's regional threats to cooperation on undersea cable connectivity and environment.</p>

<p>On Ukraine, where there are differences in nuances between India and the other three Quad partners who are all in on aiding Kiev, the statement said unequivocally, "We reiterate the need for a comprehensive, just, and lasting peace in line with international law, consistent with the purposes and principles of the UN Charter, including respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity."</p>

<p>India reiterating, this time in this forum, its joint commitment to upholding international law and the UN Charter in Ukraine comes days after Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Moscow which drew criticism from the West and Ukraine and underlined its independent stand on international relations.</p>

<p>The joint statement did not name Russia.</p>

<p>The ministers' statement made pointed references to the dangers to regional peace and security posed by China, but again, without naming it.</p>

<p>They reiterated their fundamental "steadfast commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive and resilient, and are united in our commitment to upholding the free and open rules-based international order".</p>

<p>They called for upholding "sovereignty and territorial integrity, and peaceful settlement of disputes and prohibition on the threat or use of force in accordance with the UN Charter", while also committing to "the principle of freedom, human rights, rule of law, (and) democratic values".</p>

<p>Regarding foreign manipulation through exploitation of the information infrastructure, the four ministers vowed to "leverage our collective expertise and capacity to respond" to those threats.</p>

<p>They warned of "foreign information manipulation and interference, including disinformation, which undermines trust and sows discord in the international community" which are tactics that are "intended to interfere with domestic and international interest".</p>

<p>The ministers said they would promote human rights while "supporting media freedom, addressing online harassment and abuse, and countering unethical practices".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gml2soq8_quad-foreign-minister_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The statement made pointed references to the dangers to regional peace and security posed by China.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-foreign-minister-calls-on-nato-to-expel-turkey-6218273]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Foreign Minister Calls On NATO To Expel Turkey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-foreign-minister-calls-on-nato-to-expel-turkey-6218273]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 01:14:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's foreign minister on Monday called on NATO to expel Turkey as a member of the organization, in a move likely to further raise tensions between the countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's foreign minister on Monday called on NATO to expel Turkey as a member of the organization, in a move likely to further raise tensions between the countries.</p>

<p>"In light of Turkish President Erdogan's threats to invade&nbsp;Israel&nbsp;and his dangerous rhetoric, Foreign Minister&nbsp;Israel&nbsp;Katz instructed diplomats to urgently engage with all NATO members, calling for the condemnation of Turkey and demanding its expulsion from the regional alliance," the foreign ministry said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/b81i2gm8_israel-katz-x_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's foreign minister on Monday called on NATO to expel Turkey as a member of the organization.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-airport-flights-cancelled-or-delayed-amid-israeli-attack-fears-6217968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Airport Flights Cancelled Or Delayed Amid Israeli Attack Fears]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-airport-flights-cancelled-or-delayed-amid-israeli-attack-fears-6217968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 23:52:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Flights to and from Beirut airport were cancelled or delayed on Monday as tensions escalated between Israel and armed political group Hezbollah after a strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights killed 12 children and teenagers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Flights to and from Beirut airport were cancelled or delayed on Monday as tensions escalated between Israel and armed political group Hezbollah after a strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights killed 12 children and teenagers.</p>

<p>Air France said on Monday that due to the security situation at the destination, it will suspend flights between Paris-Charles de Gaulle and Beirut for the days of July 29 and 30, 2024.</p>

<p>"Air France is monitoring the situation in Lebanon in real time," the airline said.</p>

<p>Lufthansa, Swiss and Eurowings of the Lufthansa Group have decided to suspend their flights from and to Beirut up to and including Aug. 5 due to the current developments in the Middle East, a group spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Middle East Airlines (MEA) said disruptions to its schedule were related to insurance risks.</p>

<p>The rocket strike in the Golan Heights on Saturday has added to concerns that Israel and the Iran-backed group could engage in a full-scale war.</p>

<p>Israel's security cabinet on Sunday authorised the government to respond to the strike. Hezbollah denied any responsibility for the attack, the deadliest in Israel or Israeli-annexed territory since Hamas' Oct. 7 assault sparked the war in Gaza, which has since spread to several fronts.</p>

<p>Beirut airport's flight information board and flight tracking website Flightradar24 show Turkish Airlines also cancelled two flights overnight on Sunday.</p>

<p>Turkey-based budget carrier SunExpress, Turkish Airlines subsidiary AJet, Greek carrier Aegean Airlines, Ethiopian Air and MEA have also cancelled flights scheduled to land in Beirut on Monday, Flightradar24 shows.</p>

<p>The airlines did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Beirut-Rafic Hariri International Airport is Lebanon's only airport. It has been targeted in the country's civil war, and previous fighting with Israel, including in the last war between Hezbollah and Israel in 2006.</p>

<p>On Sunday, MEA said it had delayed the departure of some flights set to land in Beirut overnight. Additional delays to flights landing on Monday were then announced due to "technical reasons related to the distribution of insurance risks for aircraft between Lebanon and other destinations", MEA said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah and the Israeli military have increased cross-border exchanges of fire since the Gaza war began. The conflict has disrupted flights and shipping across the region, including during reciprocal drone and missile attacks between Israel and Iran in April.</p>

<p>Lufthansa has already suspended night-time flights to and from Beirut for July due to "current developments" in the Middle East.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-03/07go9fbg_airplane-generic_650x400_21_March_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lufthansa has already suspended night-time flights to and from Beirut  (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-children-killed-9-injured-in-knife-attack-in-uk-say-cops-6217922]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Children Killed, 9 Injured In Knife Attack In UK, Say Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-children-killed-9-injured-in-knife-attack-in-uk-say-cops-6217922]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 23:46:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two children have been killed and nine more injured, six critically, in a knife attack in northern England on Monday, police said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two children have been killed and nine more injured, six critically, in a knife attack in northern England on Monday, police said.</p>

<p>A 17-year-old male has been arrested on suspicion of murder and attempted murder over the attack in Southport, near Liverpool in northwest England, which also left two adults with critical injuries, Merseyside Police said in a news conference.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2hmhj068_uk-police_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 17-year-old male has been arrested on suspicion of murder: UK Police (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/raging-park-fire-grows-to-californias-6th-largest-wildfire-ever-6217864]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Raging Park Fire Grows To California's 6th Largest Wildfire Ever]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/raging-park-fire-grows-to-californias-6th-largest-wildfire-ever-6217864]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 23:33:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of firefighters battling a massive northern California wildfire were working in milder temperatures and higher humidity Monday, but the blaze that has destroyed more than 100 structures since it began five days ago continues to grow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of firefighters battling a massive northern California wildfire were working in milder temperatures and higher humidity Monday, but the blaze that has destroyed more than 100 structures since it began five days ago continues to grow.</p>

<p>The Park Fire, which officials said was started by a man who pushed a flaming car into a gully, grew slightly overnight to 368,000 acres (148,924 hectares). The sixth largest wildfire in state history is rolling through a remote area some 180 miles (290 km) northeast of San Francisco, according to Cal Fire.</p>

<p>Crews were "still in for quite a firefight today, just because (of) the sheer magnitude and the sheer size of the fire," said Dan Collins, a Cal Fire captain, noting that temperatures were to be in the high 80s with 25% percent humidity during the day.</p>

<p>Some 4,800 firefighters were building and strengthening control lines on Monday morning hoping to increase the 12% they had contained. The more favorable weather conditions compared to those they faced over the past several days were helping, Collins added.</p>

<p>Butte County District Attorney Mike Ramsey said in a statement that the accused arson suspect, Ronnie Dean Stout II, was jailed without bond on a Butte County judge's warrant after he was identified as the person seen pushing a flaming car into a gully on Wednesday afternoon.</p>

<p>The fire rapidly grew, doubling in size from Friday to Sunday and destroying at least 114 structures in four counties.</p>

<p>The fire has also caused officials to issue evacuation warnings and orders to several communities, including Paradise, the town that was devastated by the 2018 Camp Fire, the deadliest in the state's history.</p>

<p>Cal Fire also reported on Monday that 33% of the SQF Lightning Complex was contained. That fire has raged for the past two weeks some 350 miles (563 km) to the south of the Park Fire. Part of that complex, dubbed the Borel Fire, swept through Havilah, torching much of that historic gold mining town on Friday.</p>

<p>The Park and Borel fires were just two of the 102 large active fires burning nationwide. A total of 25 had forced evacuations as of Monday morning, according to the National Interagency Fire Center.</p>

<p>A cold front in the Pacific Northwest, where many of the fires burn, was forecast to bring rain and thunderstorms to the region on Monday. However, the system will carry strong wind gusts of up to 50 miles (80 km) per hour that could hamper firefighting efforts, the center said in a statement.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jnnn764o_california-fire_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fire destroyed at least 114 structures in four counties.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-visits-golan-rocket-fire-site-vows-severe-response-6217462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Visits Golan Rocket Fire Site, Vows "Severe Response"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-visits-golan-rocket-fire-site-vows-severe-response-6217462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 22:26:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who on Monday visited the site of a deadly attack in the annexed Golan Heights, vowed Israel would deliver a "severe response" to the rocket fire that killed 12 children.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who on Monday visited the site of a deadly attack in the annexed Golan Heights, vowed Israel would deliver a "severe response" to the rocket fire that killed 12 children.</p>

<p>"Like all Israeli citizens, and I must say like many around the world, we were deeply shaken by this horrific killing," Netanyahu said at the site of the attack, according to a statement issued by his office.</p>

<p>"These children are our children ... The State of Israel will not, and cannot, let this pass. Our response will come and it will be severe."</p>

<p>Scores of residents of Majdal Shams protested at Netanyahu's visit which came after the last of the victim was buried on Monday, with hundreds of Druze men and women gathering for the funeral, an AFP journalist reported.</p>

<p>Many residents of Majdal Shams have not accepted Israeli nationality since Israel seized the Golan Heights from Syria in 1967.</p>

<p>The 12 children aged between 10 and 16 were killed on Saturday when a rocket fired from Lebanon struck a football pitch in the Druze Arab town of Majdal Shams where they were playing.</p>

<p>According to the Israeli military, they were hit by an Iranian-made rocket carrying a 50-kilogramme warhead, adding it was fired by Lebanese armed group Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has traded regular cross-border fire with Israeli forces since the Gaza war began in early October, has denied responsibility for the strike, though it claimed multiple attacks on Israeli military positions that day.</p>

<p>Hezbollah says its actions against Israeli forces are in support of Palestinians in Gaza and its ally, the Hamas group.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has denied responsibility for the strike. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-including-children-wounded-in-horrendous-england-knife-attack-6217420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8 Including Children Wounded In "Horrendous" England Knife Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-including-children-wounded-in-horrendous-england-knife-attack-6217420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 22:19:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A knife attack in northern England on Monday wounded at least eight people, reportedly including children, emergency services said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A knife attack in northern England on Monday wounded at least eight people, reportedly including children, emergency services said.</p>

<p>Police said armed officers detained a man and seized a knife after being called to a property in Southport, near Liverpool in northwest England.</p>

<p>"There are a number of reported casualties," police said in a statement.</p>

<p>The North West Ambulance Service (NWAS) said it had "treated eight patients with stab injuries who have been taken to Alder Hey Children's Hospital, Aintree University Hospital and Southport and Formby hospital."</p>

<p>Alder Hey Children's Hospital said: "We can confirm that the trust has declared a major incident."</p>

<p>Local business owner Colin Parry, one of the people who called police, told the domestic Press Association news agency that he believed several "young girls" had been stabbed.</p>

<p>Bare Varathan, who owns a local shop, told PA he saw "seven to 10 kids" who were "injured, bleeding", adding that he saw they had been stabbed.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer called the incident "horrendous and deeply shocking," adding on X, formerly called Twitter, that "my thoughts are with all those affected".</p>

<p>The area where the incident took place is located in a quiet, leafy neighbourhood of residential streets.</p>

<p>Some residents who were allowed to come out from the police cordon sealing it off looked visibly shocked, according to an AFP reporter at the scene.</p>

<p>One man who lives in an adjoining street and did not wish to be named told AFP: "It's not what you expect to see in Southport."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2hmhj068_uk-police_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Keir Starmer called the incident "horrendous and deeply shocking" (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-agrees-to-meet-with-fbi-for-victim-interview-about-rally-shooting-6217394]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Agrees To Meet With FBI For "Victim Interview" About Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-agrees-to-meet-with-fbi-for-victim-interview-about-rally-shooting-6217394]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 22:15:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump has agreed to meet with the FBI for a "victim interview" about this month's assassination attempt, bureau officials said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump has agreed to meet with the FBI for a "victim interview" about this month's assassination attempt, bureau officials said Monday.</p>

<p>Providing an update on the status of the probe into the July 13 shooting, Federal Bureau of Investigation officials said they have still not determined a motive for the attack by the 20-year-old gunman, Thomas Matthew Crooks.</p>

<p>They said Crooks, who was shot dead by a Secret Service sniper after firing eight shots during Trump's campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, appeared to be a "loner" and they have not identified any co-conspirators.</p>

<p>FBI special agent Kevin Rojek said the interview with Trump will be "a standard victim interview like we would do for any other victim of crime under any other circumstances.</p>

<p>"We want to get his perspective on what he observed," Rojek said.</p>

<p>FBI officials said they have interviewed dozens of people who knew or interacted with Crooks, including family members, co-workers, former teachers, classmates and others.</p>

<p>"We have learned the subject was highly intelligent, attended college and maintained steady employment," Rojek said. "His primary social circle appears to be limited to his immediate family as we believe he had few friends and acquaintances."</p>

<p>The FBI officials said Crooks's parents have said they had no advance knowledge of their son's plot. "We do find that to be credible at this stage," Rojek said.</p>

<p>FBI Director Christopher Wray, testifying before a congressional committee last week, said Crooks had searched online for details about the November 1963 shooting of US president John F. Kennedy by Lee Harvey Oswald.</p>

<p>"On July 6, he did a Google search for, quote, 'How far away was Oswald from Kennedy?'" Wray said.</p>

<p>Rojek said the investigation has revealed that Crooks "also made searches related to power plants, mass shooting events, information on improvised explosive devices and the attempted assassination of the Slovakian prime minister earlier this year."</p>

<p>- 'Suspicious person' -</p>

<p>Crooks was perched on the roof of a nearby building and opened fire on Trump with an AR-style assault rifle shortly after 6:00 pm, as the Republican White House candidate was addressing the rally in Butler.</p>

<p>Trump was wounded in the ear, two rally attendees were seriously injured and a 50-year-old Pennsylvania firefighter was shot dead.</p>

<p>Rojek said Crooks was identified as a "suspicious person" by law enforcement about an hour before the shooting.</p>

<p>"A local officer took a photo of the subject and sent it to other SWAT operators on scene, as well as local command personnel," he said.</p>

<p>SWAT operators observed Crooks about 30 minutes later, shortly after 5:30 pm, using a range finder and browsing news websites on his phone, he said.</p>

<p>At approximately 6:08 pm police dashcam video observed Crooks traversing the roof of the building from where he ultimately fired his shots, Rojek said.</p>

<p>"At approximately 6:11 pm a local police officer was boosted onto the roof by another officer where he encountered the subject," he said.</p>

<p>Crooks pointed his rifle at the officer, who "immediately dropped to the ground," he said. "Approximately 25 to 30 seconds after this encounter, the subject fired eight rounds before being successfully neutralized."</p>

<p>US Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle resigned last week after acknowledging the agency had failed in its mission to prevent the assassination attempt.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5vb5dgi8_donald-trump-_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We want to get his perspective on what he observed," Kevin Rojek said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-was-spotted-over-an-hour-before-shooting-says-fbi-6217226]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooter Was Spotted Over An Hour Before Shooting, Says FBI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-was-spotted-over-an-hour-before-shooting-says-fbi-6217226]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 21:48:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police noticed the Pennsylvania man who tried to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump more than an hour before the July 13 shooting and took a photo to share with other law enforcement officers, an FBI official said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police noticed the Pennsylvania man who tried to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump more than an hour before the July 13 shooting and took a photo to share with other law enforcement officers, an FBI official said on Monday.</p>

<p>"The shooter was identified by law enforcement as a suspicious person," Kevin Rojek, the special agent in charge of the FBI's Pittsburgh field office, told reporters at a briefing on the agency's investigation into the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>He said a local officer took a photo of gunman Thomas Crooks and sent it to other law enforcement officials at the scene of Trump's Pennsylvania rally that day. Some 30 minutes later, Rojek said, SWAT team operators saw Crooks using a rangefinder and browsing news sites.</p>

<p>Crooks was seen carrying a backpack around 5:56 p.m., less than 20 minutes before the shooting took place, and at 6:08 p.m. he was caught on a police dashboard camera walking on the roof from where he ultimately fired the shots, Rojek said.</p>

<p>Although the FBI is not the agency responsible for investigating any lapses in Trump's security, FBI personnel are putting together a timeline of events, he said.</p>

<p>FBI officials said they had yet to identify a motive for Crooks, the 20-year-old gunman, who was shot dead by a Secret Service agent after opening fire.</p>

<p>But they said he had conducted online searches on prior mass shooting events, on improvised explosive devices and on the attempted assassination of the Slovakian prime minister in May.</p>

<p>Trump, who has been highly critical of the FBI, has agreed to sit for a standard victim's interview, which "will be consistent with any victim interview we do," Rojek said. "We want to get his perspective."</p>

<p>Rojek confirmed Trump was struck by a bullet, whether "whole or fragmented into smaller pieces."</p>

<p>FBI officials have described Crooks as a loner who had no close friends or acquaintances, with his social circle limited primarily to immediate family members.</p>

<p>Using encrypted applications, he made 25 firearm-related purchases and six chemical precursors used to make explosive devices, FBI officials told reporters.</p>

<p>His longtime interest in science and doing science experiments did not rouse any suspicion by his parents, whom the FBI said have been cooperative with their investigation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bv51s1j_thomas-matthew-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has agreed to sit for a standard victim's interview with FBI (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iowa-becomes-latest-us-state-to-adopt-near-total-abortion-ban-6217155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iowa Becomes Latest US State To Adopt Near-Total Abortion Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iowa-becomes-latest-us-state-to-adopt-near-total-abortion-ban-6217155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 21:39:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After a year-long legal battle, Iowa became the latest US state to enact a near-total abortion ban on Monday, keeping the charged issue of reproductive rights at the forefront of November's presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a year-long legal battle, Iowa became the latest US state to enact a near-total abortion ban on Monday, keeping the charged issue of reproductive rights at the forefront of November's presidential election.</p>

<p>The law prohibits terminating nearly all pregnancies after six weeks -- the point at which a fetal heartbeat can be detected -- even though many women do not realize they are pregnant at this stage.</p>

<p>Previously, abortion was permitted in the Midwestern state up to 20 weeks of gestation.</p>

<p>Initially passed last year and signed into law by Governor Kim Reynolds, the ban was placed on hold by a judge but then reinstated following a narrow 4-3 ruling by the Iowa Supreme Court last month.</p>

<p>"This morning, more than 1.5 million women in Iowa woke up with fewer rights than they had last night because of another Trump Abortion Ban," US Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic presidential nominee, wrote on X.</p>

<p>Her Republican opponent, former president Donald Trump, appointed three conservative Supreme Court justices who in 2022 helped overturn Roe v. Wade, the landmark decision that had guaranteed a national right to abortion for nearly 50 years.</p>

<p>The Iowa law includes exceptions for cases of rape and incest, as well as situations where the life of the fetus or mother is at risk.</p>

<p>However, in states with similar bans, these exemptions have often proven ineffective, with hospitals and doctors hesitant to risk prosecution, forcing women to seek care out of state.</p>

<p>"Patients will be forced to travel hundreds of miles from home to find abortion care, if they have the means to do so," said Nancy Northup, president of the Center for Reproductive Rights.</p>

<p>"Others will be forced to carry pregnancies to term, regardless of their determination of what is best for their lives, health, families, and future. People with dire pregnancy complications will be turned away from hospitals until they are crashing."</p>

<p><strong>Challenging issue for Republicans</strong></p>

<p>Iowa is now among 22 states that have set stricter standards for abortion since the fall of Roe, ranging from full bans to earlier gestational limits.</p>

<p>Trump carried Iowa by more than eight points in 2020, and is expected to win handily this time around too.</p>

<p>Still, the topic of abortion remains challenging for Republicans, who must navigate the risk of alienating independent and moderate voters.</p>

<p>A March poll by the Des Moines Register/Mediacom found that 61 percent of Iowans believe abortion should be legal in all or most cases, while 35 percent believe it should be illegal in most or all cases -- a trend consistent with national polling.</p>

<p>Democrats, on the other hand, have been energized by President Joe Biden's decision to withdraw from the race in favor of Harris, long seen as the administration's true champion of reproductive rights.</p>

<p>"I don't think people fully understand just how angry women are about Roe being overturned -- Harris has the ability to drive that home," feminist author Jessica Valenti, who runs "Abortion, Every Day" on Substack, told AFP recently.</p>

<p>Polling by YouGov released last week found Harris enjoying a 12-point advantage over Trump on abortion, significantly higher than the five-point lead Biden held over Trump in early July.</p>

<p>On the Republican side, Trump's running mate J.D. Vance has made the divide between the two parties even starker, expressing a desire to make abortion "illegal nationally," voting against protections for in vitro fertilization, and likening abortion to "slavery."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-01/etq8m1g8_abortions-pregnancy-generic-unsplash-_650x400_29_January_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iowa law includes exceptions for cases of rape and incest. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-bbc-presenter-huw-edwards-charged-with-indecent-child-picture-crimes-6217070]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-BBC Presenter Huw Edwards Charged With Indecent Child Picture Crimes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-bbc-presenter-huw-edwards-charged-with-indecent-child-picture-crimes-6217070]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 21:25:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former British TV news presenter Huw Edwards, a household name in Britain, has been charged with three counts of making indecent pictures of children, police said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former British TV news presenter Huw Edwards, a household name in Britain, has been charged with three counts of making indecent pictures of children, police said on Monday.</p>

<p>Edwards, 62, was the BBC's highest paid news presenter and anchored the broadcaster's "BBC News at Ten" bulletin for more than two decades. He resigned in April.</p>

<p>He has been charged with three counts of making an indecent photograph or pseudo-photograph of a child relating to images found on a child's phone, according to court documents.</p>

<p>"The offences, which are alleged to have taken place between December 2020 and April 2022, relate to images shared on a WhatsApp chat," a London police spokesperson said.</p>

<p>"Edwards was arrested on 8 November, 2023. He was charged on Wednesday, 26 June following authorisation from the Crown Prosecution Service."</p>

<p>He was bailed to appear at London's Westminster Magistrates' Court on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Edwards was one of the main faces at the BBC until his departure, announcing the death of Queen Elizabeth to the nation, and leading coverage of the biggest events in Britain since the turn of the century, including elections, royal weddings and the 2012 Olympics.</p>

<p>He quit on medical advice after allegations emerged that he had paid a young person thousands of pounds for sexually explicit photos.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2a721q1o_huw-edwards_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Huw Edwards was one of the main faces at the BBC until his departure. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-skin-melts-off-his-feet-after-walking-barefoot-in-death-valley-hospitalised-6216851]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tourist's Skin Melts Off His Feet After Walking Barefoot In Death Valley]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-skin-melts-off-his-feet-after-walking-barefoot-in-death-valley-hospitalised-6216851]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 20:50:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 42-year-old Belgian tourist suffered third-degree burns after losing his flip-flops in the dunes of Death Valley.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A man was rescued after suffering full-thickness burns on his feet at Mesquite Flat Sand Dunes in Death Valley National Park. According to the<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nps.gov/deva/learn/news/7-20-2024-sand-dunes.htm"> National Park Service</a></em>, the incident happened on&nbsp;July 20 when a 42-year-old Belgian tourist suffered third-degree burns after losing his flip-flops in the dunes of Death Valley.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Park rangers said that the tourist was taking a short walk in the scorching Mesquite Flat Sand Dunes at Death Valley National Park on Saturday. The 42-year-old man was exposed to the blistering 123-degree heat, causing his skin to melt off his foot, according to Park Ranger Gia Ponce. Unable to move due to extreme pain, the man and his family enlisted the help of fellow park visitors to carry him to the parking lot, where rangers assessed his injuries.</p>

<p>Due to the heat-thinned air, helicopters were unable to fly in, so an ambulance transported him to higher ground, where it was cooler (109 degrees), and he was then airlifted to safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''People think it's going to be like the beach where you can get out there with flip-flops or sandals, but because of the extreme temperatures, those dunes heat up just as much as the pavement does,” Ms Ponce said.</p>

<p>On a sand dune, the ground temperature is much hotter than in the air. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/travel/2024/07/24/man-who-lost-flip-flops-death-valley-hospitalized-burned-feet/">Washington Post</a></em>, that's because sand doesn't require much energy to warm up. When the sand's high-density traps that heat, the result is a hot, hot surface.</p>

<p>Park officials recommend walking in the park and its soft dunes only in closed-toe shoes to avoid similar incidents. They also gave some advice to those interested in visiting Death Valley during the heat.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''Park rangers recommend that summer travellers to Death Valley National Park stay within a 10-minute walk of an air-conditioned vehicle, not hike after 10 am, drink plenty of water, eat salty snacks, and wear a hat and sunscreen,'' a release from National Park Service read.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2955m95g_sand-dunes_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Park rangers said that the tourist was taking a short walk in the scorching Mesquite Flat Sand Dunes]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exercise-caution-indian-embassy-in-beirut-amid-israel-hezbollah-conflict-6216457]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Exercise Caution: Indian Embassy In Beirut Amid Israel-Hezbollah Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exercise-caution-indian-embassy-in-beirut-amid-israel-hezbollah-conflict-6216457]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 19:58:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian nationals currently in Lebanon and those planning to travel to the West Asian country are advised to "exercise caution," the Indian Embassy in Beirut said in an advisory issued on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian nationals currently in Lebanon and those planning to travel to the West Asian country are advised to "exercise caution," the Indian Embassy in Beirut said in an advisory issued on Monday.</p>

<p>Tensions in the region have escalated following a rocket strike on a soccer field in northern Israel's Majdal Shams on July 27 that resulted in the death of 12 children and injured several others.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Advisory for Indian Nationals. <a href="https://t.co/SuFyv23dhq">pic.twitter.com/SuFyv23dhq</a></p>
— India in Lebanon (@IndiaInLebanon) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiaInLebanon/status/1817833311483404755?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Israel and the USA blamed Hezbollah for the air strike with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu saying that Hezbollah will pay a "heavy price which it has not paid up to now" for the attack.</p>

<p>Netanyahu also held a security assessment meeting in Tel Aviv on Sunday during which "the manner and timing of the response" against Hezbollah was decided.</p>

<p>Several flights heading to Beirut have also been suspended over the last couple of days following the Israeli threat of military action against Hezbollah.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who was in Tokyo on Monday, also expressed Washington's support for Israel, highlighting Israel's right to self-defence while also urging the need to avoid escalation of the conflict on Israel's northern border.</p>

<p>"We don't want to see the conflict escalate. We don't want to see it spread," Blinken said on the sidelines of the Quad Foreign Ministers Meeting.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Indian Embassy in Beirut shared an emergency mail ID and phone number, asking the Indian nationals in the country to remain in touch.</p>

<p>According to the Indian embassy, there are nearly 4000 Indian nationals in Lebanon, with a majority of them employed as workers in companies, construction sector, agricultural farms, etc.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/5husnh3_israel-lebanon_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are nearly 4000 Indian nationals in Lebanon (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>