<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 11:07:54 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-freed-but-why-is-wikileaks-founder-flying-to-remote-pacific-island-of-saipan-5964135]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Julian Assange Is Flying To Remote Pacific Island Of Saipan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-freed-but-why-is-wikileaks-founder-flying-to-remote-pacific-island-of-saipan-5964135]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 10:27:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Julian Assange is en route to a courtroom on the Pacific island of Saipan where he is expected to plead guilty on Wednesday to a single criminal charge in a plea deal that will see him walk free after a 14-year legal odyssey.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange is en route to a courtroom on the Pacific island of Saipan where he is expected to plead guilty on Wednesday to a single criminal charge in a plea deal that will see him walk free and return home to Australia after a 14-year legal odyssey.</p>

<h3><strong>WHERE IS SAIPAN?</strong></h3>

<p>Saipan is the capital of the Northern Mariana Islands (NMI), a US commonwealth in the western Pacific which begins roughly 70 kilometers (44 miles) north of Guam and stretches across 14 islands.</p>

<p>Like territories such as Guam or Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands are part of the U.S. without the full status of a state. Residents are U.S. citizens but cannot vote in presidential elections. Crucially, some, like Saipan, also host U.S. district courts.</p>

<p>Assange will appear in court at 9 a.m. local time on Wednesday (2300 GMT Tuesday)</p>

<h3><strong>WHY IS ASSANGE HEADING THERE?</strong></h3>

<p>U.S. prosecutors said Assange wanted to go to a court close to his home in Australia but not in the continental United States.</p>

<p>Saipan has the advantage of being relatively close to Assange's home in Australia, roughly 3,000 km (1800 miles) south. Hawaii is more than twice as far away.</p>

<p>"He has to front up to charges that have been brought under U.S. law," said Emily Crawford, a professor at the University of Sydney's law school.</p>

<p>"It had to be U.S. territory but it had to be the U.S. territory closest to Australia that wasn't a U.S. state like Hawaii."</p>

<h3><strong>SAIPAN AND THE UNITED STATES</strong></h3>

<p>After time as a colony of Spain, Germany and then Japan, the United States took control of the island in World War Two after the Battle of Saipan in 1944.</p>

<p>After decades under U.S. control, residents in 1975 voted to join the United States as a territory.</p>

<p>The Northern Mariana Islands elected a delegate to the U.S. House of Representatives for the first time in 2008, but the delegate has no vote in Congress.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT HAPPENS NEXT</strong></h3>

<p>U.S. prosecutors said Assange has agreed to plead guilty to a single criminal count of conspiring to obtain and disclose classified U.S. national defense documents. He will be sentenced to 62 months of time that he has already served. If the judge approves his plea, Assange is expected to return to Australia after the hearing, U.S. prosecutors said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/bqrap8mg_assange-reuters-_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange is en route to a courtroom on the Pacific island of Saipan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-netanyahu-biggest-danger-to-israel-ex-spy-handler-of-hamas-co-founders-son-5963957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Netanyahu Is Danger To Israel": Ex Spy Handler Of Hamas Co-Founder's Son]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-netanyahu-biggest-danger-to-israel-ex-spy-handler-of-hamas-co-founders-son-5963957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:53:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On a Tel Aviv overpass, former spy Gonen Ben Itzhak addresses a small gathering of flag-waving protesters worried about the future of Israel under longest-serving premier Benjamin Netanyahu.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On a Tel Aviv overpass, former spy Gonen Ben Itzhak addresses a small gathering of flag-waving protesters worried about the future of Israel under longest-serving premier Benjamin Netanyahu. Motorists honk enthusiastically to the group from the road as they drive past, and a man on a scooter passing underneath shouts "Traitor!"</p>

<p>A former Shin Bet intelligence agent, Ben Itzhak once handled the son of a Hamas co-founder as an informant, to prevent attacks in the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>Now he protests on the streets against Netanyahu and his right-wing coalition government.</p>

<p>"Netanyahu is really the biggest danger to the state of Israel, and believe me I arrested some of the biggest terrorists during the Second Intifada," the 53-year-old told AFP at his home in Modiin, referring to the 2000-2005 Palestinian uprising.</p>

<p>"I know what is a terrorist. I think Netanyahu is dragging Israel into destruction."</p>

<p>He cites Netanyahu's recent tensions with US President Joe Biden -- he accused him of delaying American arms deliveries for Israel's Gaza war -- as an example of why many believe the Israeli leader must go.</p>

<p>"Biden is the biggest supporter of Israel... and Netanyahu spit on his face," said Ben Itzhak.</p>

<p>"He's destroying the very important relationship with the United States."</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'The Green Prince'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Ben Itzhak -- who joined the security services in the 1990s after premier Yitzhak Rabin's assassination -- has become a leading figure in protests against Netanyahu.</p>

<p>He is part of the "Crime Minister" movement, and once stepped in front of the premier's motorcade during a 2018 anti-corruption protest.</p>

<p>He ended up being tackled by the very security service he once worked for.</p>

<p>Prosecutors are still pressing ahead with a corruption trial against Netanyahu despite the war, and some protesters have tried to break through police lines to get to his home.</p>

<p>Years before his own protest, Ben Itzhak was the handler for Mosab Hassan Yousef, known as "The Green Prince" and the eldest offspring of Hamas co-founder Sheikh Hassan Yousef.</p>

<p>He worked with the Hamas collaborator to follow Palestinian militants to thwart suicide operations, including arresting jailed Fatah figurehead Marwan Barghouti.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel could have been prevented by a double agent like Yousef reporting the plan, and the country's security elite underestimated Hamas, the former spy believes.</p>

<p>"You need an old asset to call you and to tell you something is going wrong. And it seems like we didn't have it," he said.</p>

<p>"We think that our enemy is stupid. In the end, Hamas was smarter. It's very hard to say."</p>

<p>Ben Itzhak believes it is time to "change the equation" in Gaza -- end the war and rally international support to put Mahmud Abbas's Palestinian Authority in charge.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Everything is explosive'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"The military rules the West Bank, rules Gaza. Enough. We need to find the solution," he said.</p>

<p>Ben Itzhak accuses Netanyahu of propping up Hamas while seeking to nix any peace process so he can stay in power.</p>

<p>"Netanyahu thinks only about himself, about his criminal problems, how to survive politically in Israel," he said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu has repeatedly denied allegations of corruption, and on Monday reiterated that Israeli forces will eliminate Hamas.</p>

<p>"We will not end the war (in Gaza) until we eliminate Hamas, and until we return residents of the south and north to their homes securely," he told parliament.</p>

<p>The former agent also claims the Israeli leader has let ultranationalist security minister Itamar Ben Gvir use the police as his own "militia" to disrupt weekly anti-government protests in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>He questions Netanyahu's allegiance with the far-right Jewish Power party frontman who was once barred from the Israeli military and investigated by the country's security services for extremism.</p>

<p>"God... didn't help us on October 7, the way he didn't help us in Auschwitz," he said.</p>

<p>Ben Itzhak said he himself has jumped in front of a water cannon to protect protesters from increasing police brutality, which landed him with a conviction that was overturned in March.</p>

<p>"Today Israel from the inside is destroyed. He (Netanyahu) is destroying everything," he said.</p>

<p>The more Netanyahu bends to the ultranationalist allies, the weaker Israel's security, says Ben Itzhak, claiming that they are also taking control of the army and prison service.</p>

<p>"Everything is explosive now," he said.</p>

<p>"I will tell Netanyahu... resign. This will be the biggest help you can do to the people of the State of Israel."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/109p0llo_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_19_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ben Itzhak now protests on the streets against Netanyahu and his right-wing coalition government.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millionaire-banker-quits-job-after-video-showed-him-punching-woman-at-new-york-pride-event-5963906]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Millionaire Banker Who Punched Woman At New York Pride Event Quits Job]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millionaire-banker-quits-job-after-video-showed-him-punching-woman-at-new-york-pride-event-5963906]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:41:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video showed him hitting a woman's face, causing her to collapse on the ground in front of a crowd at a Brooklyn Pride event in Park Slope.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A millionaire investment banker who was under scrutiny after punching a Black woman during a pride event in New York has resigned from his job.&nbsp;Melissa Chiles, a spokesperson for Moelis &amp; Company, confirmed the information in an email to&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/banker-nyc-pride-festival-attack-b2568124.html"><em>The Independent</em>.</a>&nbsp;''Jonathan Kaye has resigned and is no longer with the firm,'' she said. As of Monday, his profile is no longer available on the Moelis website.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier this month, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millionaire-investment-banker-punches-woman-in-the-face-at-brooklyn-pride-watch-5857850">video showed Mr Kaye</a>, head of the global business services franchise at Manhattan-based Moelis &amp; Co, hitting a woman's face, causing her to collapse on the ground in front of a crowd at a Brooklyn Pride event in Park Slope.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the video, the man claimed that the woman, who has not been identified, ''threw s*** all over me.''&nbsp; The 38-year-old woman told police that the assault left her with a broken nose, lacerations and a black eye.'' It is being said that Mr Kaye, who is Jewish, and the unidentified woman got into a verbal altercation over the Israel-Hamas war.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Millionaire investment banker Jonathan Kaye filmed punching an anti-Israel woman he claims hurled "antisemitic" slurs at him. <a href="https://t.co/ZWmPBrVwiK">pic.twitter.com/ZWmPBrVwiK</a></p>
— D. Scott @eclipsethis2003 (@eclipsethis2003) <a href="https://twitter.com/eclipsethis2003/status/1800918433825194000?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>A spokesperson for Mr Kaye said he had been ''in fear for his physical safety when he was surrounded by an angry mob of agitators who encircled him, physically assaulted him, and threw unknown liquids on him.''</p>

<p>''He could not identify any of these individuals and was left bloodied from the attack,'' the spokesperson said, adding that ''given the sharp rise in antisemitic incidents, any Jewish person in this situation would naturally feel threatened and feel the need to defend themselves and return safely to their family.''</p>

<p>After the video went viral, he was put on leave by his firm, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/06/24/business/millionaire-banker-filmed-punching-woman-at-brooklyn-pride-event-quits-job/">New York Post</a></em> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The New York City Police Department last week confirmed it had opened an investigation into Mr Kaye after receiving an official complaint of assault.</p>

<p>Mr Kaye previously held a position as managing director of the Global Mergers &amp; Acquisitions Group at CitiBank.&nbsp;He reportedly lives in a $4m home in the borough's Park Slope neighbourhood, holds a bachelor's degree from Tufts University, and graduated cum laude from Duke University School of Law.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hjtn9ug_jonathan-kaye-_625x300_10_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 38-year-old woman told police that the assault left her with a broken nose]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/dasari-gopikrishna-murder-21-year-old-arrested-for-murder-of-indian-man-in-us-5963761]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[21-Year-Old Arrested For Murder Of Indian Man In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/dasari-gopikrishna-murder-21-year-old-arrested-for-murder-of-indian-man-in-us-5963761]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:27:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police in the US state of Texas have arrested a man in connection with the killing of a 32-year-old Indian national during a robbery at a convenience store in Dallas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police in the US state of Texas have arrested a man in connection with the killing of a 32-year-old Indian national during a robbery at a convenience store in Dallas.</p>

<p>Dasari Gopikrishna, who came to the US only eight months ago, was shot dead&nbsp; at the convenience store in Pleasant Grove, Dallas, on June 21.</p>

<p>He hailed from the Yajali village of the Bapatla district in Andhra Pradesh.</p>

<p>Police have arrested 21-year-old Davonta Mathis for murdering Gopikrishna.</p>

<p>He faces capital murder charges for fatally shooting Gopikrisna multiple times, including in the head.</p>

<p>During the robbery, Mathis walked into the store, approached the counter and shot Gopikrishna. He stole items before running away, police said.</p>

<p>Gopikrishna was taken to the hospital in critical condition and later died.</p>

<p>Mathis was originally arrested and charged with robbery, but the charge was upgraded to capital murder because of Gopikrishna's death.</p>

<p>His bond is set at USD 7.5 million.</p>

<p>Sgt. Curtis Phillip of the Mesquite Police described Mathis' behaviour as "very bizarre," noting the significant impact of his decisions at such a young age.</p>

<p>Mathis is also charged in a separate fatal shooting in Waco city on June 20. He shot Muhammad Hussain, 60, multiple times, who died from injuries at the hospital.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Indian consulate here is finalising arrangements with Gopikrishna's family to repatriate his body, officials said.</p>

<p>Representatives from the Telugu Association of North America (TANA) and family friends are collaborating with the consulate to facilitate the transportation of Gopikrishna's body to his hometown in India.</p>

<p>The consulate has confirmed that all police autopsies and necessary formalities have been completed, and they are prioritising the shipment of the body by Tuesday.</p>

<p>Gopikrishna's murder is the second in as many days of a convenience store clerk working the night shift.</p>

<p>The incident has deeply affected the Indian community in Dallas and surrounding areas. Gopikrishna is survived by his wife and son.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ogn1mt_dasari-gopikrishna_625x300_24_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police have arrested 21-year-old Davonta Mathis for murdering Dasari Gopikrishna.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-france-jordan-urge-israel-to-lift-land-based-restrictions-on-gaza-aids-5963554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France, Jordan Urge Israel To Lift "Land-Based Restrictions" On Gaza Aids]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-france-jordan-urge-israel-to-lift-land-based-restrictions-on-gaza-aids-5963554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 08:20:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron and King Abdullah II of Jordan Monday called on Israel to lift all land-based "restrictions" on the delivery of aid to war-torn Gaza, the presidency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron and King Abdullah II of Jordan Monday called on Israel to lift all land-based "restrictions" on the delivery of aid to war-torn Gaza, the presidency said.</p>

<p>UN agencies have repeatedly warned of severe shortages of vital supplies in Gaza, exacerbated by restrictions on access by land and the closure of the key Rafah crossing with Egypt since Israeli forces seized the Palestinian side in early May.</p>

<p>Over lunch at the Elysee Palace, Macron and Abdullah II reiterated the need for an "immediate and lasting ceasefire in Gaza" and called for the release of all hostages -- including two French nationals.</p>

<p>The leaders also "expressed their deep concern about the situation in the West Bank and strongly condemned the violence committed by settlers", the Elysee Palace said in a statement.</p>

<p>They agreed to continue to work together on a "lasting and credible solution" to the war based on the "two-state solution" and welcomed reforms undertaken by the Palestinian government and called for them to be continued.</p>

<p>Referring to the intensification of tensions on the Israeli-Lebanese border, Macron and Abdullah II warned against a "conflagration that would be catastrophic for the region", and reiterated their calls to all parties for "responsibility and restraint".</p>

<p>Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on southern Israel that triggered the Gaza war resulted in the deaths of 1,194 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The Hamas operatives also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 42 are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,626 people, also mostly civilians, the health ministry in Hamas-ruled Gaza said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/jc9gl098_gaza-nuseirat-camp-afp_625x300_11_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UN agencies have repeatedly warned of severe shortages of vital supplies in Gaza since Israeli occupation]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-deeply-disturbed-with-texas-woman-trying-to-drown-us-palestinian-child-5963484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Tries To Drown Palestinian Child, Joe Biden Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-deeply-disturbed-with-texas-woman-trying-to-drown-us-palestinian-child-5963484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 08:01:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Monday he was "deeply disturbed" by reports that a woman allegedly attempted to drown a Palestinian-American child at a pool in Texas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said Monday he was "deeply disturbed" by reports that a woman allegedly attempted to drown a Palestinian-American child at a pool in Texas.</p>

<p>The woman has been charged with capital murder, court records show, following the May incident which gained national attention over the weekend.</p>

<p>The 42-year-old, identified as Elizabeth Wolf, allegedly approached a mother who was wearing a hijab at a suburban apartment pool near Dallas.</p>

<p>She then asked whether the mother's six-year-old son and three-year-old daughter belonged to her and also made racial statements, according to US media reports.</p>

<p>The woman reportedly grabbed the boy, who was able to wrangle free, then grabbed the girl, whom she pushed underwater.</p>

<p>"No child should ever be subjected to a violent attack, and my heart goes out to the family," Biden said on X on Monday.</p>

<p>"I am deeply disturbed by the reports of an attempted drowning of a 3-year-old Palestinian-American at a neighborhood pool," he said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am deeply disturbed by the reports of an attempted drowning of a 3-year old Palestinian-American at a neighborhood pool.<br />
<br />
No child should ever be subjected to a violent attack, and my heart goes out to the family. <a href="https://t.co/WpLDxUgP2O">https://t.co/WpLDxUgP2O</a></p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1805289457610117275?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>On Saturday, the Texas chapter of the Council on American-Islamic Relations (CAIR), which has called for a hate crimes probe, held a press conference on the incident.</p>

<p>In a statement from CAIR, the mother said her family were American citizens of Palestinian origin.</p>

<p>The episode comes with the war in Gaza igniting fierce passions in the United States, particularly on university campuses, where there have been numerous protests.</p>

<p>It has also led to a number of anti-Semitic and Islamophobic acts across the country.</p>

<p>In November, a man shot and injured three students of Palestinian origin in the northeast state of Vermont.</p>

<p>And in early October, a six-year-old Muslim boy was stabbed to death near Chicago in a crime linked directly to the war in Gaza, according to police.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/pjvrktko_elizabeth-wolf-x_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elizabeth Wolf reportedly grabbed the boy and then the girl, whom she pushed underwater.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-biden-deal-what-is-us-new-plea-deal-with-julian-assange-and-when-will-he-be-freed-5963450]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is US' New Plea Deal With Julian Assange And When Will He Be Freed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-biden-deal-what-is-us-new-plea-deal-with-julian-assange-and-when-will-he-be-freed-5963450]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 07:59:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Julian Assange, the founder of WikiLeaks, is set to plead guilty to a single count of conspiring to obtain and disclose classified US national defence documents, as part of a deal with the Biden administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange, the founder of WikiLeaks, is set to plead guilty to a single count of conspiring to obtain and disclose classified US national defence documents, as part of a deal with the Biden administration. This agreement is expected to end Assange's legal saga, which spanned nearly 15 years.</p>

<p><strong>Case Against Assange</strong></p>

<p>The case against Assange originates from WikiLeaks' publication of sensitive US military documents, war logs, and diplomatic cables between 2010 and 2011. These disclosures, including footage of a US airstrike in Baghdad, constituted one of the largest breaches of state secrets in US history. Assange was accused of conspiring with Chelsea Manning, a former Army intelligence analyst, to obtain classified materials.</p>

<p>Chelsea Manning, who leaked the documents, was convicted in 2013 but had her 35-year prison sentence commuted by President Barack Obama in 2017.</p>

<p>The US criminally charged Assange in 2019 under the Trump administration with violating the Espionage Act and was seeking to extradite him from the UK, where he has been in prison ever since. The initial charges — 17 related to espionage and one to computer misuse — carried a maximum penalty of 175 years in prison if he was found guilty on all counts.</p>

<p><strong>Plea Deal</strong></p>

<p>Assange, 52, has agreed to plead guilty to violating US espionage law. As part of the deal, he will be sentenced to 62 months, which corresponds to the time he has already served in UK prisons. The sentencing will take place at a hearing scheduled on Wednesday in Saipan, Northern Mariana Islands.</p>

<p>After sentencing, he will return to his home in Australia.</p>

<p><strong>Global Campaign And Support</strong></p>

<p>During his ordeal, Assange became a hero to free speech campaigners around the world and a villain to those who thought he endangered US national security and intelligence sources by revealing secrets.</p>

<p>He has spent more than a decade either in custody or holed up in Ecuador's London embassy, trying to avoid extradition. Assange has been detained in London's high-security Belmarsh prison for the last five years.</p>

<p>According to WikiLeaks, Assange's plea deal and imminent return to Australia are the result of a global campaign involving grassroots organizers, press freedom advocates, legislators, and leaders from various political backgrounds. This support extended to international bodies such as the United Nations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/olrfr8p8_julian-assange_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange will be sentenced at a court in US.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/korean-air-plane-drops-26-900-feet-mid-flight-passengers-forced-to-use-oxygen-masks-5963445]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Korean Air Flight Drops 26,900 Feet, Passengers Forced To Use Oxygen Masks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/korean-air-plane-drops-26-900-feet-mid-flight-passengers-forced-to-use-oxygen-masks-5963445]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 07:57:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[50 minutes into its journey, the Boeing 737 Max 8 plane started descending sharply and fell about 26,900 feet in around 15 minutes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Korean Air plane was forced to U-turn and make an emergency landing after dropping more than 25,000 feet due to a fault in the aircraft's pressurization system. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/news-and-advice/korean-air-flight-diverted-taiwan-b2567663.html">Independent</a></em>, flight KE189 departed Seoul's Incheon International Airport (ICN) on June 22, 2024, at about 16:45 local time, headed for Taichung International Airport (RMQ) in Taiwan.</p>

<p>However, 50 minutes into its journey, the Boeing 737 Max 8 plane started descending sharply and fell about 26,900 feet in around 15 minutes. According to FL360aero, the message ''pressure system (pressure control function of the aircraft) abnormality'' was displayed while the aircraft was flying over Jeju Island.</p>

<p>As a result, several passengers experienced hyperventilation and ear pain,&nbsp;prompting oxygen masks to be released inside the cabin of the plane.&nbsp;One passenger told&nbsp;<em>The Taipei Times&nbsp;</em>that children on the flight were crying when oxygen masks were deployed during the flight's plunge.</p>

<p>&nbsp;Another passenger said she felt something was amiss as the aircraft seemed to be hovering in the air and the flight attendants remained in their seats.</p>

<p>Upon landing in Taichung, Taiwan, 17 people were evaluated at medical facilities and were later&nbsp;discharged without severe injuries.</p>

<p>Korean Air apologised to ''all affected by this incident'', and said, ''We are fully cooperating with all relevant authorities to investigate the circumstances surrounding the incident. We have provided comprehensive support to affected passengers, including accommodation, meals, and transportation arrangements.'</p>

<p>The flight resumed on the morning of June 23 with a different aircraft, about 19 hours after the initial departure schedule.&nbsp;passengers, who arrived at Taichung International Airport, said they were frightened and that they would not take a flight for a while, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/taiwan/archives/2024/06/24/2003819818">Taipei Times</a></em> reported.</p>

<p>A Korean Air spokesperson said the airline is conducting a thorough investigation to determine the cause of the pressurisation system malfunction, intending to address any maintenance issues before returning the aircraft to service.</p>

<p>Boeing, the plane that suffered a malfunction during the flight, has been under massive pressure following a string of incidents involving their planes.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/qm26llk_plane-generic-_625x300_26_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The flight resumed the next morning with a different aircraft]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/11-year-old-indian-student-bags-top-honours-in-international-academic-championship-5962335]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Student, 11, Wins Top Honours In International Academic Championship]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/11-year-old-indian-student-bags-top-honours-in-international-academic-championship-5962335]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 07:45:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's Advay Misra, an 11-year-old student from New Delhi, participated in the International Academic Championship and won the Science and Academic Bee Competitions at the Championships and was runner-up in the Geography Bee Competition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's Advay Misra, an 11-year-old student from New Delhi, participated in the International Academic Championship and won the Science and Academic Bee Competitions at the Championships and was runner-up in the Geography Bee Competition.</p>

<p>Held over three days from June 14 to June 16, the competition saw participation from over 300 students from 30 different cities across 14 different countries vying for a chance at the Asian Championship.</p>

<p>Advay holds the unique distinction of being the Asian Science Bee Champion for three years in a row, and it was his second consecutive win in the Academic Bee Championship.</p>

<p>Last year, representing India as the All India Winner of the National Academic Competition, Advay had achieved the feat of winning all the four Bees (Academic, Science, Geography and History) in offing. Prior to his achievements in the Asian Championships, Advay was the Runner-up in the National Science Bee Championship of the US for the year 2020-21.</p>

<p>The Bees are an intense individual competition where the contestants vie to answer a number of buzzer based questions. The format tests both the depth and the breadth of knowledge of the contestants. The format consists of a written Qualifier, followed by regional finals and then the Championships, which involve 4 preliminary rounds and one final round for each Bee.</p>

<p>Going beyond just being a collection/recollection of facts, a Bee Competition actually tests critical thinking and the ability to absorb details and discern linkages between a wide variety of subjects and helps bring alive classroom pedagogy.</p>

<p>Advay credited his success to his habit of reading extensively and guidance from his parents for his continuing success. As an 8-year old, Advay was named one of the brightest kids in the world by John's Hopkins University in the US and is a member of their Center for Talented Youth (CTY).</p>

<p>He has won numerous other Academic accolades and enjoys math and programming besides quizzing and reading. His project 'Moodmeter' that was made to take care of his peers' health during the pandemic was adjudged as one of the best school work across all grades by the New York City Department of Education. He is currently an 8th grader at Sanskriti School in New Delhi.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/vengiom8_advay-misra-international-academic-championship-facebook_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Advay Misra credited his success to his habit of reading extensively]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-resignation-enters-third-year-as-workers-embrace-ai-upskilling-5963346]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Great Resignation' Enters Third Year As Workers Embrace AI, Upskilling]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-resignation-enters-third-year-as-workers-embrace-ai-upskilling-5963346]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 07:24:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The proportion of workers who expect to switch employers in the next 12 months is higher than that from the "Great Resignation" period of 2022, a PwC survey of the global workforce found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The proportion of workers who expect to switch employers in the next 12 months is higher than that from the "Great Resignation" period of 2022, a PwC survey of the global workforce found.</p>

<p>Around 28% of more than 56,000 workers surveyed by PwC said they were "very or extremely likely" to move from their current companies, compared to 19% in 2022, and 26% in 2023.</p>

<p>PwC's 2024 "Hopes and Fears" survey also showed workers are embracing emerging technologies such as generative artificial intelligence (GenAI) and prioritising upskilling amid rising workloads and heightened workplace uncertainty.</p>

<p>Pete Brown, global workforce leader at PwC UK, said employees are placing an "increased premium" on organisations that invest in their skills growth, and so, businesses must prioritise upskilling and employee experience.</p>

<p>About 45% of the workers surveyed said they have experienced rising workloads and an accelerating pace of workplace change in the last 12 months, with 62% saying they have seen more change at work in the past year than in the previous 12 months.</p>

<p>Among employees who use GenAI daily, 82% said they expect it to increase their efficiency in the next 12 months.</p>

<p>Reflecting confidence that GenAI opportunities would support their career growth, nearly half of those surveyed by PwC expected GenAI to generate higher salaries, with almost two-thirds hoping these emerging tools will improve the quality of their work.</p>

<p>Carol Stubbings, global markets and tax and legal services leader at PwC UK, said employers must invest in staff and tech platforms to mitigate pressures and retain talent.</p>

<p>"The findings suggest that job satisfaction is no longer enough," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/r468t91_employee-hiring-reuters_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PwC's 2024 survey also showed workers are embracing emerging technologies such as generative AI.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assanges-long-fight-against-extradition-to-us-5963209]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Wikileaks Founder Julian Assange's Long Fight Against Extradition To US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assanges-long-fight-against-extradition-to-us-5963209]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:48:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jailed WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange has been fighting for years to avoid extradition from Britain in connection with the 2010 publication of thousands of US classified documents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jailed WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange has been fighting for years to avoid extradition from Britain in connection with the 2010 publication of thousands of US classified documents.</p>

<p>Here is a timeline of his legal troubles after he agreed to plead guilty to revealing military secrets in exchange for his release from prison, ending his years-long legal drama:</p>

<h3><strong>2010: Assault charges&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In July 2010, Assange's WikiLeaks whistleblowing website begins publishing hundreds of thousands of leaked US military documents about the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, some of which detail US abuses.</p>

<p>It later follows up with a huge batch of secret US diplomatic cables, which show that Washington spied on the leadership of the United Nations and that Saudi Arabia pressured the US to attack Iran, among other revelations.</p>

<p>In November that year, a Swedish prosecutor issues an arrest warrant for Assange over sexual assault allegations involving two women.</p>

<p>Assange denies the claims, saying they had consensual sex, but is arrested after he reports to police in London. A week later he is released on bail.</p>

<h3><strong>2012: Embassy refuge&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In February 2011, a British judge rules Assange can be extradited to Sweden.</p>

<p>He appeals, claiming the Swedish allegations are a pretext to transfer him to the US to face charges over Wikileaks.</p>

<p>In June 2012, he takes refuge in Ecuador's embassy in London. Ecuador, then ruled by left-wing president Rafael Correa, grants him asylum.</p>

<p>In May 2017, Swedish prosecutors drop the sex assault investigation after failing to obtain Assange's transfer.</p>

<p>In December, Ecuador grants Assange nationality but is blocked by Britain from according him diplomatic status.</p>

<h3><strong>2019: Arrest, prison&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In January 2018, Ecuador, now ruled by conservative President Lenin Moreno, says hosting Assange has become "untenable".</p>

<p>Tensions peak in April 2019 when Moreno says Assange has "repeatedly violated" the conditions of his asylum and revokes his citizenship.</p>

<p>The next day, British police drag Assange from the embassy and arrest him on a US extradition request.</p>

<p>In May, he is sentenced to 50 weeks in jail for having breached bail in 2010.</p>

<p>The legal process for his extradition to the US begins.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Swedish prosecutors reopen the rape investigation.</p>

<h3><strong>US charges&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In May 2019, the US Justice Department charges Assange with violating the US Espionage Act by publishing military and diplomatic files in 2010. If convicted, he faces jail terms of up to 175 years.</p>

<p>Assange makes his first court appearance since being jailed via video-link.</p>

<h3><strong>Swedish charge dropped&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In November 2019, Swedish prosecutors drop the rape investigation because "the evidence is not strong enough" despite "credible" claims from Assange's alleged victim.</p>

<p>- 2020: Trump claim -</p>

<p>In February 2020 court hearings, Assange's lawyers claim then US president Donald Trump had promised him a pardon if he denied Russia had leaked him damaging emails about Hillary Clinton ahead of the 2016 presidential election.</p>

<p>The White House denies the claim.</p>

<h3><strong>2021: Victory, then setback&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Assange's supporters celebrate after a London court blocks his extradition in January 2021, on the grounds he would be a suicide risk if sent to the US.</p>

<p>But a High Court appeal overturns the verdict and sends the case back to the original court after a US promise he would not be held in isolation in jail and would receive proper medical treatment.</p>

<h3><strong>2022: Permission to appeal&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Judges in January 2022 grant Assange permission to appeal. But in March, the Supreme Court refuses to hear the challenge.</p>

<p>On June 17, 2022, the British government approves his extradition in what Wikileaks calls a "dark day for press freedom and for British democracy".</p>

<p>Assange appeals the government's decision.</p>

<h3><strong>'He will die' if extradited&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Assange's wife Stella tells a news conference in February 2024 that her husband "will die" if sent to the US, saying his physical and mental health are "in decline".</p>

<p>In May, Assange wins permission to appeal against the 2022 court ruling that approved his extradition, with a two-day hearing in London later scheduled for July 9.</p>

<h3><strong>2024: Plea deal and release&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Assange agrees to plead guilty to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate national defence information, according to US court documents released on Monday night.</p>

<p>WikiLeaks says "Julian Assange is free," writing on X that he has left prison and flown out of Britain after being granted bail by a high court judge.</p>

<p>Assange is scheduled to appear Wednesday morning local time at a court in the Northern Mariana Islands, a US territory in the Pacific, close to his native Australia.</p>

<p>He is expected to be sentenced to 62 months in prison, with credit for the five years he has already served behind bars in Britain, meaning he can go free.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3pumrucg_julian-assange-2024-afp_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Assange is scheduled to appear Wednesday morning at a court in the Northern Mariana Islands.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-envoy-to-india-eric-garcetti-says-relationship-between-india-us-is-multiplicative-5963141]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Relationship Between India, US Is Multiplicative: US Envoy To India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-envoy-to-india-eric-garcetti-says-relationship-between-india-us-is-multiplicative-5963141]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:37:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The relationship between India and the US is not just "addictive", it is "multiplicative", US envoy to India Eric Garcetti has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The relationship between India and the US is not just "addictive", it is "multiplicative", US envoy to India Eric Garcetti has said.</p>

<p>Garcetti also said that the relationship between the two countries has never been so good. The Indian-American community is the most successful immigrant community in America.</p>

<p>He made these remarks on Monday at an event on the sidelines of the SelectUSA Investment Summit, to which the largest delegation is from India.</p>

<p>“This (India US) is a relationship that isn't just additive. It's not just the US plus India. It's multiplicative. It's the United States times India,” Garcetti said on the sidelines of the summit, to which the largest delegation is from India.</p>

<p>The SelectUSA Investment Summit is the highest-profile event in the US to facilitate business investment by connecting thousands of investors, companies, economic development organisations (EDOs), and industry experts to make deals happen.</p>

<p>Garcetti was speaking at the event wherein India's JSW Steel announced its plans to invest USD 140 million in Bayton, Texas.</p>

<p>“Now, Americans are getting more and more familiar with Indian brands and Indian companies... Together we're investing in third countries, infrastructure, energy, climate solutions, empowering tomorrow's prosperity,” Garcetti said as he announced investment from JW Steel in Texas.</p>

<p>“We are so excited that JSW Steel is announcing a USD 140 million investment in America, in Baytown, in Texas. JSW is one of the largest Indian investors in the United States, investing more than USD 2 billion here in this country, in Texas and in Ohio. They have seen tremendous return on their investment,” he said. This FDI would result in jobs for more than 800 American workers.</p>

<p>Garcetti also said that the relationship between India and the US has never been so good.</p>

<p>“We've never had a closer relationship with India. Americans of Indian descent are now about 1.5% of our population. And pay six per cent of the taxes in America. It is the most successful immigrant community in America,” he said.</p>

<p>“While the story used to be about American companies going to India to invest, which we still do,... increasingly we're seeing this two-way street, a bridge in the Indo-pacific coming from India into the United States, savings steel mills, looking at mines that have been shut down, investing in electrolytes for electric vehicles of the future, the services, the health care,” Garcetti said.</p>

<p>Diane Farrell, Deputy Under Secretary for International Trade, from the Department of Commerce said India has the largest country delegation to the SelectUSA Investment Summit.</p>

<p>Divyakumar Bhair, Board Member, JSW Steel USA said that these investments would go into manufacturing high-end steel plates which are used for offshore wind, monopile, transition pieces, and towers.</p>

<p>“This will not only help realise the dream of clean energy for the generations to come in the United States but will also catalyse the local economies of Texas,” he said. JSW USA is part of the diversified USD 24 billion JSW Group.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/hlaj9hvs_us-envoy-eric-garcetti_625x300_14_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Envoy to India said that relationship between India and US has never been so good.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-timeline-of-wikileaks-founders-legal-battles-5963055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WikiLeaks Founder Julian Assange's Legal Battles: A Timeline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-timeline-of-wikileaks-founders-legal-battles-5963055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 05:59:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange has reached a deal to plead guilty to one count of violating the U.S. espionage law, prosecutors said in court papers on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange has reached a deal to plead guilty to one count of violating the U.S. espionage law, prosecutors said in court papers on Monday.</p>

<p>He is due to appear in a U.S. federal court in the Northern Mariana Islands this week where he is expected to be sentenced to time served and allowed to return home to Australia.</p>

<p>Following are some key events and details in Assange's life:</p>

<p>July 1971 - Assange is born in Townsville, Australia, to parents involved in theatre. As a teenager, he gains a reputation as a computer programmer. In 1995, he is fined for computer hacking but avoids prison on condition he does not offend again.</p>

<p>2006 - Assange founds WikiLeaks, creating an internet-based "dead letter drop" for leakers of classified or sensitive information.</p>

<p>April 5, 2010 - WikiLeaks releases leaked video from a U.S. helicopter showing an air strike that killed civilians in Baghdad, including two Reuters news staff.</p>

<p>July 25, 2010 - WikiLeaks releases more than 91,000 documents, mostly secret U.S. military reports about the Afghanistan war.</p>

<p>October, 2010 - WikiLeaks releases 400,000 classified military files chronicling the Iraq war. The next month, it releases thousands of U.S. diplomatic cables, including candid views of foreign leaders and blunt assessments of security threats.</p>

<p>Nov. 18, 2010 - A Swedish court orders Assange's arrest on sex crime allegations, which he denies. He is arrested in Britain the next month on a European arrest warrant but freed on bail.</p>

<p>February 2011 - London's Westminster Magistrates' Court orders Assange's extradition to Sweden. He appeals.</p>

<p>June 14, 2012 - The British Supreme Court rejects Assange's final appeal. Five days later, he takes refuge in Ecuador's embassy in London and seeks political asylum, which Ecuador grants in August 2012.</p>

<p>May 19, 2017 - Swedish prosecutors discontinue their investigation, saying it is impossible to proceed while Assange is in the Ecuadorean embassy.</p>

<p>April 11, 2019 - After Ecuador revokes his political asylum, Assange is carried out of the embassy and arrested. He is sentenced on May 1 to 50 weeks in prison by a British court for skipping bail. He completes the sentence early but remains in jail pending extradition hearings.</p>

<p>May 13, 2019 - Swedish prosecutors reopen their investigation and say they will seek Assange's extradition.</p>

<p>June 11, 2019 - The U.S. Justice Department formally asks Britain to extradite Assange to the United States to face charges that he conspired to hack U.S. government computers and violated an espionage law.</p>

<p>Nov. 19, 2019 - Swedish prosecutors drop their investigation, saying the evidence is not strong enough to bring charges, in part because of the passage of time.</p>

<p>Feb. 21, 2020 - A London court begins the first part of extradition hearings.</p>

<p>Jan. 4, 2021 - A British judge rules that Assange should not be extradited to the U.S. to face criminal charges, saying his mental health problems mean he would be at risk of suicide.</p>

<p>Dec. 10, 2021 - The U.S. wins an appeal against the ruling after a judge says he is satisfied with a U.S. package of assurances about the conditions of Assange's detention. &nbsp;</p>

<p>March 14, 2022 - Britain's Supreme Court denies Assange permission to appeal against the decision to extradite him to the United States.</p>

<p>March 23, 2022 - Assange marries his long-term partner Stella Moris, the mother of his two children fathered inside the Ecuadorean embassy, inside a British high-security prison.</p>

<p>June 17, 2022 - Britain orders Assange's extradition to the United States, prompting Assange to appeal.</p>

<p>June, 2023 - Judge at London's High Court rules Assange has no legal grounds to appeal.</p>

<p>Feb. 20, 2024 - Assange launches what his supporters say will be his final attempt to prevent extradition.</p>

<p>March 26, 2024 - The extradition is put on hold when the court says the U.S. must provide assurances that Assange will not face a potential death penalty.</p>

<p>May 20, 2024 - The High Court gives Assange permission to launch a full appeal against his extradition on grounds that, as a foreign national on trial, he might not be able to rely on the First Amendment right to free speech that U.S. citizens enjoy.</p>

<p>June 24, 2024 - The U.S. Justice Department and Assange reveal a deal in which he will plead guilty to one criminal count and be sentenced to time served.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-02/u416kqsk_julian-assange-reuters_625x300_23_February_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange to plead guilty in deal with the US authorities as he appears in the US court this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-ties-achieve-escape-velocity-says-top-us-official-5963044]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India-US Ties Achieve "Escape Velocity", Says Top US Official]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-ties-achieve-escape-velocity-says-top-us-official-5963044]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 05:51:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A top US official said on Monday that progress in the bilateral relationship with India has finally achieved "escape velocity", using a term from space exploration to describe the velocity required by a body to soar without the pull of gravity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A top US official said on Monday that progress in the bilateral relationship with India has finally achieved "escape velocity", using a term from space exploration to describe the velocity required by a body to soar without the pull of gravity.</p>

<p>Deputy Secretary of State Kurt Campbell was speaking on a sustainable and enduring US policy in the Indo-Pacific region at an event at the Council on Foreign Relations, a leading think tank.</p>

<p>He was recently in India along with National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan for a much-anticipated visit that also turned out to be the first trip by senior US officials to New Delhi in Prime Minister Narendra Modi's third term.</p>

<p>Campbell also made a strong pitch for according to a higher preference to increasing the intake of Indian students in STEM fields in US universities, than to students from China, who are not trusted in high-technology fields.</p>

<p>"The United States and India have launched an effort to intensify defence industrial cooperation on jet engines and armoured vehicles," Campbell said about ties with India in the context of America's sustained engagement with the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<p>"After working in India for decades, I can tell you that it is my view that finally, the use-end rate relationship has reached escape velocity. I think we have a partnership that can be sustained and there is ambition in both Delhi and Washington to take important next steps. We've worked together on a variety of other issues between the United States and India including announcing new initiatives where we will work together for the first time in the Indian Ocean."</p>

<p>Campbell was previously the White House czar for President Joe Biden's Indo-Pacific policy, which has seen this administration elevate the Quad platform with India, Australia, and Japan to the level leaders, the launch of the Australia, UK and US partnership called AUKUS and deepening bilateral, trilateral and multilateral ties with Indo-Pacific countries with the shared goal of managing China's aggressive rise.</p>

<p>The jet engine cooperation that Campbell mentioned is the joint production of GE's F414 jet engine with HAL that was announced during Prime Minister Modi's state visit in June last year.</p>

<p>India and the US are also in talks to co-produce Stryker armoured infantry fighting vehicles (IFVs or infantry combat vehicles). India is looking to this vehicle as a replacement for its fleet of ageing Russian-made ICVs.</p>

<p>India and the United States cooperate on a wide suite of issues and people-to-people is one of the most important of them. Indian students in US universities are a key part of it. Indians account for the second largest cohort of foreign students and their numbers are growing rapidly.</p>

<p>Campbell's strong pitch for a larger intake of Indian students came in response to a question on what needs to be done to shore up declining numbers of Chinese students. "Right now the largest increase that we need to see going forward would be much larger numbers of Indian students that come to study in American universities on a range of technology and other fields more directly," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-09/q35u6gic_india-us-flags-reuters_625x300_18_September_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A top US official said that progress in bilateral ties with India has finally achieved "escape velocity".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-says-israel-committed-to-gaza-ceasefire-proposal-5963017]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Says Israel "Committed" To Gaza Ceasefire Proposal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-says-israel-committed-to-gaza-ceasefire-proposal-5963017]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 05:42:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has announced that Israel is "committed" to the deal proposal outlined by US President Joe Biden for a ceasefire in Gaza in return for the release of hostages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has announced that Israel is "committed" to the deal proposal outlined by US President Joe Biden for a ceasefire in Gaza in return for the release of hostages.</p>

<p>"We are committed to the Israeli proposal that President Biden endorsed," Netanyahu said on Monday during a special plenum session of the Knesset (parliament) summoned by the opposition, noting "Our position has not changed".</p>

<p>Biden first presented the deal proposal to end the ongoing conflict in late May. Netanyahu's remarks marked the first time the Israeli side has confirmed that Israel has approved and supports the proposal, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Netanyahu told the Knesset that Israel will not end the conflict "until we bring back all the hostages, all 120 of them -- both the living and the fallen" and until Hamas is "eliminated" and the residents in southern and northern can safely return to their homes.</p>

<p>Israel has been carrying out a massive offensive in the Gaza Strip in retaliation for a Hamas rampage on October 7, 2023, during which about 1,200 people were killed and about 250 were taken hostage.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/dci79qa_benjamin-netanyahu-_625x300_08_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu announced that Israel is "committed" to the deal proposal outlined by Biden for Gaza ceasefire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-to-plead-guilty-in-deal-with-us-5962960]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Julian Assange Freed From UK Prison After He Strikes Plea Deal With US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-to-plead-guilty-in-deal-with-us-5962960]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 05:28:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Wikileaks founder Julian Assange has agreed to plead guilty in US court to revealing military secrets in exchange for his freedom, ending his years-long legal drama, according to court documents released Monday night.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange has agreed to plead guilty in US court to revealing military secrets in exchange for his freedom, ending his years-long legal drama, according to court documents released Monday night.</p>

<p>Assange, who had been in custody in Britain, will plead guilty to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate national defense information, according to the document filed in court in the Northern Mariana Islands, a US territory in the Pacific.</p>

<p>WikiLeaks reported early Tuesday morning British time that "Julian Assange is free" and had left the country. He is scheduled to appear Wednesday morning local time in the US territory.</p>

<p>Assange is expected to be sentenced to 62 months in prison, with credit for the five years he has served in prison in Britain. This means he could return to his native Australia.</p>

<p>The publisher now aged 52 was wanted by Washington for publishing hundreds of thousands of secret US documents from 2010 as head of the whistle-blowing website WikiLeaks.</p>

<p>During his ordeal Assange became a hero to free speech campaigners around the world and a villain to those who thought he endangered US national security and intelligence sources by revealing secrets.</p>

<p>US authorities wanted to put Assange on trial for divulging US military secrets about the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>This plea bargain agreement will presumably end Assange's nearly 14-year legal drama.</p>

<p>Assange was indicted by a US federal grand jury in 2019 on 18 counts stemming from WikiLeaks' publication of a trove of national security documents.</p>

<p>Announcement of the deal came two weeks before Assange was scheduled to appear in court in Britain to appeal against a ruling approving his extradition to the United States.</p>

<p>Assange has been detained in the high-security Belmarsh prison in London since April 2019.</p>

<p>He was arrested after spending seven years holed up in Ecuador's London embassy to avoid extradition to Sweden, where he faced accusations of sexual assault that were eventually dropped.</p>

<p>The material he released included video showing civilians being killed by fire from a US helicopter gunship in Iraq in 2007. The victims included two Reuters journalists.</p>

<p>The United States has accused Assange under the 1917 Espionage Act. Supporters have warned this means he could be sentenced to 175 years in prison.</p>

<p>The British government approved his extradition in June 2022.</p>

<p>In the latest twist to the saga, two British judges said in May that he could appeal against his extradition to the United States.</p>

<p>The appeal was to address the question of whether, as a foreigner on trial in America, he would enjoy the protections of freedom of speech accorded under the First Amendment to the US Constitution.</p>

<p>The plea deal was not entirely unexpected. President Joe Biden had been under growing pressure to drop the long-running case against Assange.</p>

<p>In February the government of Australia made an official request to this effect and Biden said he would consider it, raising hopes among Assange supporters that his ordeal might end.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/1u0svmdo_julian-assange_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange to appear in US court this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-lunar-probe-carrying-samples-from-moon-set-to-return-to-earth-today-5962849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Lunar Probe Carrying Samples Set To Return To Earth Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-lunar-probe-carrying-samples-from-moon-set-to-return-to-earth-today-5962849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 04:47:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Chinese probe carrying samples from the far side of the Moon is expected to return to Earth on Tuesday, capping a technically complex 53-day mission heralded as a world first.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese probe carrying samples from the far side of the Moon is expected to return to Earth on Tuesday, capping a technically complex 53-day mission heralded as a world first.</p>

<p>Beijing has not disclosed the spacecraft's estimated arrival time, but experts say it will likely touch down in a barren expanse of desert in the northern Inner Mongolia region at around midday (0400 GMT).</p>

<p>It comes bearing soil and rocks from the side of the moon that faces away from Earth, a poorly understood region that scientists say holds great research promise because its rugged features are less smoothed over by ancient lava flows than the near side.</p>

<p>That means the materials harvested there may help us to better understand how the Moon formed and how it has evolved over time.</p>

<p>Chang'e-6 blasted off from a space centre on the island province of Hainan on May 3 and descended into the Moon's immense South Pole-Aitken Basin almost exactly a month later.</p>

<p>It used a drill and robotic arm to scoop up samples, snapped some shots of the pockmarked surface and planted a Chinese flag in the grey soil.</p>

<p>On June 4, the probe made the first ever successful launch from the far side in what Chinese state news agency Xinhua called "an unprecedented feat in human lunar exploration history".</p>

<p>Authorities have been coy about disclosing updates on the probe's progress since then.</p>

<p>But China's space agency said in a social media post on Friday that it was "70 percent" of the way back to Earth.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Space dream' -</strong></p>

<p>Plans for China's "space dream" have shifted into high gear under President Xi Jinping.</p>

<p>Beijing has poured huge resources into its space programme over the past decade, targeting ambitious undertakings in an effort to catch up to traditional space powers the United States and Russia.</p>

<p>It has built a space station, landed robotic rovers on Mars and the Moon, and become only the third country to send astronauts into orbit.</p>

<p>But the United States has warned that China's space programme masks military objectives and an effort to establish dominance in space.</p>

<p>China aims to send a crewed mission to the Moon by 2030 and plans to eventually build a base on the lunar surface.</p>

<p>The United States also plans to put astronauts back on the Moon by 2026 with its Artemis 3 mission.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/j53fqcpg_china-lunar-probe-afp_625x300_04_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Plans for China's "space dream" have shifted into high gear under President Xi Jinping.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-urges-israels-defence-minister-to-avoid-lebanon-escalation-5962784]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Urges Israel's Defence Minister To Avoid Lebanon Escalation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-urges-israels-defence-minister-to-avoid-lebanon-escalation-5962784]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 04:21:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken called on Israel during a Monday meeting with its defense minister to avoid further escalation in Lebanon as they discussed efforts to reach a deal to free hostages in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken called on Israel during a Monday meeting with its defense minister to avoid further escalation in Lebanon as they discussed efforts to reach a deal to free hostages in Gaza.</p>

<p>Defense Minister Yoav Gallant was on a visit to Washington seeking to reaffirm the value of ties with Israel's top ally, after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu publicly chastised the United States for what he said was a delay in weapons deliveries.</p>

<p>In a two-hour meeting with Gallant at the State Department, Blinken discussed indirect diplomacy between Israel and Hamas on an agreement that "secures the release of all hostages and alleviates the suffering of the Palestinian people," State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said.</p>

<p>Blinken also "underscored the importance of avoiding further escalation of the conflict and reaching a diplomatic resolution that allows both Israeli and Lebanese families to return to their homes," Miller said in a statement.</p>

<p>Tensions have been rising with growing exchanges of fire between Israel and Lebanon's Iranian-backed militant movement Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Netanyahu has said Israeli forces are winding up the most intense part of the Gaza war and will redeploy to the northern border, although he cast the move as defensive.</p>

<p>Gallant also met CIA chief Bill Burns, the key US pointman in negotiations to free hostages from Hamas.</p>

<p>"I would like to emphasize that it is Israel's primary commitment to return the hostages, with no exception, to their families and homes," Gallant said before starting his meetings.</p>

<p>"We will continue to make every possible effort to bring them home," he said.</p>

<p>The minister made no further comment as he left the meeting with Blinken, as a few dozen protesters outside the State Department chanted to call him a "war criminal."</p>

<p><strong>- Arms shipment dispute -</strong></p>

<p>President Joe Biden on May 31 laid out a plan for a ceasefire in Gaza and release of hostages.</p>

<p>Hamas, which launched the conflict with its October 7 attack on Israel, has come back with its own demands, and the United States hopes the gaps can be bridged.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, who has faced major protests calling for him to accept the deal, in recent days has annoyed the Biden administration by accusing Washington of cutting back arms and ammunition deliveries.</p>

<p>Gallant took a different tack, saying: "The alliance between Israel and the United States, led by the US over many years, is extremely important."</p>

<p>Other than Israel's own military, "our ties with the US are the most important element for our future from a security perspective," he said.</p>

<p>Biden, who has faced criticism from parts of his own base over his support for Israel, held back a shipment that included heavy 2,000-pound bombs.</p>

<p>Netanyahu -- who has close relations with Biden's rivals in the Republican Party -- told a cabinet meeting on Sunday that there was a "dramatic drop in the supply" of US weapons around four months ago.</p>

<p>Asked about his latest remark, Miller told reporters, "I don't understand what that comment meant at all."</p>

<p>"We have paused one shipment of high-payload munitions. That shipment remains on pause," Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>"There are other weapons that we continue to provide Israel, as we have done going back years and years, because we are committed to Israel's security. There has been no change in that," Miller said.</p>

<p>Miller said the United States would also press Israel to work on longer-term arrangements after the end of the fighting.</p>

<p>"We don't want to see in Rafah what we've seen in Gaza City and what we've seen in Khan Yunis, which is the end of major combat operations and then the beginning of Hamas reasserting control," he said, referring to two other major cities targeted by Israel earlier in the war.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/vb96d8e8_antony-blinken-reuters_625x300_23_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Blinken called on Israel during meeting with its defense minister to avoid further escalation in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-elections-loom-in-france-emmanuel-macron-warns-of-civil-war-5962380]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Elections Loom In France, Macron Warns Of 'Civil War']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-elections-loom-in-france-emmanuel-macron-warns-of-civil-war-5962380]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 02:08:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron told a podcast episode shown on Monday that both the far right National Rally (RN) party and the left-wing New Popular Front coalition - front runners in parliamentary election- risked bringing "civil war" to France.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron told a podcast episode shown on Monday that both the far right National Rally (RN) party and the left-wing New Popular Front coalition - front runners in the parliamentary election- risked bringing "civil war" to France.</p>

<p>Macron told the podcast "Generation Do It Yourself" that the manifesto of the RN party - which election pollsters put in first place - and their solutions to deal with fears over crime and immigration were based upon "stigmatisation or division".</p>

<p>"I think that the solutions given by the far right are out of the question, because it is categorising people in terms of their religion or origins and that is why it leads to division and to civil war," he told the podcast.</p>

<p>Macron made the same criticism of the France Unbowed (LFI) extreme left-wing party, which forms part of the New Popular Front coalition.</p>

<p>"But that one as well, there is a civil war behind that because you are solely categorising people in terms of their religious outlook or the community they belong to, which in a way is a means of justifying isolating them from the broader national community and in this case, you would have a civil war with those who do not share those same values," said Macron.</p>

<p>Asked to respond to Macron's civil war comments, RN president Jordan Bardella - seen as a possible prime minister if the RN wins the most votes in the election - replied to M6 TV: "A President should not say that."</p>

<p>France Unbowed leader Jean-Luc Melenchon also slammed Macron's comments in an interview with France 2 TV, saying it was Macron's own policies that were bringing about civil French President Emmanuel Macron told a podcast episode shown on Monday that both the far right National Rally (RN) party and the left-wing New Popular Front coalition - front runners in the parliamentary election- risked bringing "civil war" to France.</p>

<p>Macron told the podcast "Generation Do It Yourself" that the manifesto of the RN party - which election pollsters put in first place - and their solutions to deal with fears over crime and immigration were based upon "stigmatisation or division".</p>

<p>"I think that the solutions given by the far right are out of the question, because it is categorising people in terms of their religion or origins and that is why it leads to division and to civil war," he told the podcast.</p>

<p>Macron made the same criticism of the France Unbowed (LFI) extreme left-wing party, which forms part of the New Popular Front coalition.</p>

<p>"But that one as well, there is a civil war behind that because you are solely categorising people in terms of their religious outlook or the community they belong to, which in a way is a means of justifying isolating them from the broader national community and in this case, you would have a civil war with those who do not share those same values," said Macron.</p>

<p>Asked to respond to Macron's civil war comments, RN president Jordan Bardella - seen as a possible prime minister if the RN wins the most votes in the election - replied to M6 TV: "A President should not say that."</p>

<p>France Unbowed leader Jean-Luc Melenchon also slammed Macron's comments in an interview with France 2 TV, saying it was Macron's own policies that were bringing about civil unrest, such as in the French overseas territory of New Caledonia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-04/11394ivo_emmanuel-macron-reuters_625x300_01_April_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Emmanuel Macron said that far-right and left-wing parties are risking bringing "civil war" to France.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-war-with-russia-volodymyr-zelensky-dismisses-senior-ukrainian-army-commander-5962206]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid War With Russia, Zelensky Dismisses Senior Ukrainian Army Commander]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-war-with-russia-volodymyr-zelensky-dismisses-senior-ukrainian-army-commander-5962206]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 01:18:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky replaced a high-ranking army official leading troops in the country's embattled east on Monday after he was accused of incompetence and abuse of power during the Russian invasion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky replaced a high-ranking army official leading troops in the country's embattled east on Monday after he was accused of incompetence and abuse of power during the Russian invasion.</p>

<p>The move came as Kyiv has struggled to hold back Moscow's forces in the east for months, almost two and half years into the war. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"I have decided to replace the Commander of the Joint Forces of the Armed Forces of Ukraine, Lieutenant General Yuriy Sodol, with Brigadier General Andriy Gnatov," Zelensky said in his daily evening address.</p>

<p>He gave no details on the reasons for the dismissal but the decision came after criticism from a commander of the Azov brigade, known for its links with the far right.</p>

<p>The Azov commander, Bogdan Krotevych, had a day earlier filed a complaint to the SBU security service, calling for an investigation into Sodol.</p>

<p>According to media reports, Krotevych accused Sodol of incompetence and blamed him for the death of Ukrainian soldiers at the front.</p>

<p>Ukraine -- outgunned and outmanned by Russia -- has been on the back foot for months, with Moscow's forces claiming new villages in the east almost every week, but without making a major breakthrough.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/o6tn4et4_ukrainian-president-volodymyr-zelensky_625x300_02_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky removed Commander of the Joint Forces of the Armed Forces of Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>