<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 07:15:54 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahus-message-for-people-of-lebanon-after-deadly-strikes-10-points-6635347]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu's Message For People Of Lebanon After Deadly Strikes: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahus-message-for-people-of-lebanon-after-deadly-strikes-10-points-6635347]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 07:13:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hours after Israeli strikes killed nearly 500 people in Lebanon, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu reached out to the Lebanese people and asked them not to become "human shields" for the Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Israel's war is not with the Lebanese people, but with Hezbollah, which has been placing missiles in their homes, said Netanyahu in a video message shared online, and vowed to take out those weapons out to ensure the safety of Israelis.</li>
	<li>"I have a message for the people of Lebanon: Israel's war is not with you, it's with Hezbollah. For too long, Hezbollah has been using you as human shields. It placed rockets in your living rooms and missiles in your garage. Those rockets and missiles are aimed directly at our cities, directly at our citizens. To defend our people against Hezbollah strikes, we must take out those weapons," said the Israeli Prime Minister.</li>
	<li>Netanyahu said the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) has warned the Lebanese people to get out of harms' way and that they must take it seriously. The Lebanese must not endanger their own lives for the Hezbollah cause, he urged.</li>
	<li>"Don't let Hezbollah endanger your lives and the lives of your loved ones. Don't let Hezbollah endanger Lebanon. Please, get out of harm's way now. Once our operation is finished, you can come back safely to your homes," said Netanyahu.</li>
	<li>The latest strikes come as the violence has shifted from Israel's southern frontier with Gaza to its northern border with Lebanon. Hezbollah, which runs Lebanon, has been exchanging fire with Israel in support of the Palestinian group Hamas since the war began.</li>
	<li>The Hezbollah-led health ministry in Lebanon pegged the casualties at 492 until Monday night. These included 35 children and 58 women. At least 1,645 were wounded while thousands of families had been displaced, said Health Minister Firass Abiad.</li>
	<li>Called "Operation Northern Arrows" by the IDF, the Israeli strikes hit southern and eastern Lebanon. Beirut faced a "targeted strike" as well.</li>
	<li>Yesterday's attacks - which marked the deadliest day of cross-border violence since the Gaza war began last year - were condemned by Arab states and other global powers. They have urged Israel and Hezbollah to step back from the brink of all-out war, though both defiant, refusing to leave a single inch for the other.</li>
	<li>Ahead of the attacks, Hezbollah said yesterday it was in a "new phase" of confrontation and that it had fired rockets at Israeli military sites in retaliation for earlier Israeli strikes. The commander of an elite Hezbollah unit was killed in one such attack on southern Beirut on Friday.</li>
	<li>The cross-border violence follows a deadly string of explosions of pagers and walkie-talkies across Lebanon, which Hezbollah has blamed on Israel. Those blasts last week killed at least 39 people and wounded nearly 3,000.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2r29dlqo_lebanon-strikes-afp_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The health ministry in Lebanon has pegged the casualties in Israeli strikes at 492.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/metas-ai-chatbot-to-speak-in-voices-of-judi-dench-john-cena-among-others-6635344]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta's AI Chatbot To Speak In Voices Of Judi Dench, John Cena, Among Others]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/metas-ai-chatbot-to-speak-in-voices-of-judi-dench-john-cena-among-others-6635344]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 07:11:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facebook owner Meta Platforms is planning to announce this week that it has secured deals with actors including Judi Dench, Kristen Bell and John Cena to give voice to its Meta AI chatbot]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facebook owner Meta Platforms is planning to announce this week that it has secured deals with actors including Judi Dench, Kristen Bell and John Cena to give voice to its Meta AI chatbot, a source familiar with the company's plans told Reuters on Monday.</p>

<p>The new audio feature will offer users the option to select a voice for Meta's ChatGPT-like digital assistant from a list of five celebrities, who also include Awkwafina and Keegan-Michael Key, as well as several generic voice options, the person told Reuters.</p>

<p>The social media giant is set to announce the audio capabilities at its annual Connect conference, which starts on Wednesday, the person said.</p>

<p>Meta is also expected to unveil the first version of its augmented-reality glasses at Connect this year and to discuss its road map for other hardware devices like its Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses, which last year became its first product to include an audio version of the Meta AI chatbot.</p>

<p>The celebrity voices will start launching in the U.S. and other English-speaking markets this week across Meta's family of apps, which include Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp, the source told Reuters.</p>

<p>Bloomberg first reported earlier this summer that Meta was in discussions with celebrities about using their voices for AI projects.</p>

<p>Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg posted a promotional video featuring Cena on Instagram last week, showing the two men and several others engaging in stunts while wearing the Ray-Ban Meta glasses.</p>

<p>Meta has been racing to push out generative artificial intelligence products to its billions of users, as it competes against Microsoft-backed ChatGPT maker OpenAI and Alphabet's Google to dominate the emerging technology. As part of that, the company has been adding capabilities to its chatbot and pushing to make it a more prominent part of the experience of using its apps.</p>

<p>OpenAI showed off a similar audio feature for its chatbot in May, but quickly ran into trouble when actor Scarlett Johansson accused the company of making it sound "eerily similar" to her even though she had declined to lend her voice to the project.</p>

<p>Meta's assistant is currently capable of engaging in text chats and generating images in response to user prompts. The company last year experimented with bringing star power to the project by launching text-based "character" versions of the chatbot inspired by celebrities like Paris Hilton and Snoop Dogg, although those never appeared to gain traction with users.</p>

<p>Meta has since shifted focus to an AI Studio product that enables content creators on its platforms to create chatbot versions of themselves.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ud1ml22o_meta-ai-generic-_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta has been racing to push out generative artificial intelligence products to its billions of users]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-chief-vows-support-for-interim-government-come-what-may-6635315]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Army Chief Vows Support For Interim Government 'Come What May']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-chief-vows-support-for-interim-government-come-what-may-6635315]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 07:05:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's army chief vowed to back the country's interim government "come what may" to help it complete key reforms after the ouster of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina so that elections could be held within the next 18 months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's army chief vowed to back the country's interim government "come what may" to help it complete key reforms after the ouster of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina so that elections could be held within the next 18 months.</p>

<p>General Waker-uz-Zaman and his troops stood aside in early August amid raging student-led protests against Hasina, sealing the fate of the veteran politician who resigned after 15 years in power and fled to neighbouring India.</p>

<p>In a rare media interview, Zaman told Reuters at his office in the capital Dhaka on Monday that the interim administration led by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus had his full support and outlined a pathway to rid the military of political influence.</p>

<p>"I will stand beside him. Come what may. So that he can accomplish his mission," Zaman, bespectacled and dressed in military fatigues, said of Yunus.</p>

<p>The pioneer of the global microcredit movement, Yunus has promised to carry out essential reforms to the judiciary, police and financial institutions, paving the way to hold a free and fair election in the country of 170 million people.</p>

<p>Following the reforms, Zaman - who took over as the army chief only weeks before Hasina's ouster - said a transition to democracy should be made between a year and a year-and-a-half, but underlined the need for patience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If you ask me, then I will say that should be the time frame by which we should enter into a democratic process," he said.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's main two political parties, Hasina's Awami League and its bitter rival Bangladesh Nationalist Party, had both previously called for elections to be held within three months of the interim government taking office in August.</p>

<p>Yunus, the interim administration's chief adviser, and the army chief meet every week and have "very good relations", with the military supporting the government's efforts to stabilise the country after a period of turmoil, said Zaman.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I'm sure that if we work together, there is no reason why we should fail," he said.</p>

<p>More than 1,000 people were killed in violent clashes that began as a movement against public sector job quotas in July but escalated into a wider anti-government uprising - the bloodiest period in the country's independent history.</p>

<p>Calm has returned to the teeming streets of Dhaka, a densely packed metropolis that was at the heart of the rebellion, but some parts of the civil service are not yet properly functional after the dramatic fall of Hasina's administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With much of Bangladesh's police, numbering around 190,000 personnel, still in disarray, the army has stepped up to carry out law and order duties nationwide.</p>

<h3><strong>PUNISHMENTS AND REFORMS</strong></h3>

<p>Born out of erstwhile East Pakistan in 1971 after a bloody independence war, Bangladesh came under military rule in 1975, following the assassination of its first prime minister, Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, Hasina's father.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 1990, the country's military ruler Hossain Mohammad Ershad was toppled in a popular uprising, leading to the restoration of democracy.</p>

<p>The military again staged a coup in 2007, backing a caretaker government that ruled until Hasina took power two years later.</p>

<p>A career infantry officer who served through these periods of turmoil, Zaman said that the Bangladesh Army that he leads would not intervene politically.</p>

<p>"I will not do anything which is detrimental to my organisation," he said, "I am a professional soldier. I would like to keep my army professional."</p>

<p>In line with sweeping government reforms proposed since Hasina was shunted from power, the army, too, is looking into allegations of wrongdoing by its personnel and has already punished some soldiers, Zaman said, without providing further details.</p>

<p>"If there is any serving member who is found guilty, of course I will take action," he said, adding that some military officials may have acted out of line while working at agencies directly controlled by the former prime minister or interior minister.</p>

<p>The interim government has formed a five-member commission, headed by a former high court judge, to investigate reports of up to 600 people who may have been forcibly "disappeared" by Bangladesh's security forces since 2009.</p>

<p>In the longer-term, however, Zaman wanted to distance the political establishment from the army, which has more than 130,000 personnel and is a major contributor to United Nations peacekeeping missions.</p>

<p>"It can only happen if there is some balance of power between president and prime minister, where the armed forces can be placed directly under president," he said.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's armed forces currently come under the defence ministry, which is typically controlled by the prime minister, an arrangement that Zaman said a constitutional reform process under the interim government could potentially look to amend.</p>

<p>"The military as a whole must not be used for political purpose ever," he said. "A soldier must not indulge in politics."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/alqeec9_bangladesh-army-chief-reuters-_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[General Waker-uz-Zaman and his troops stood aside amid raging student-led protests against Sheikh Hasina]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-departs-for-india-wrapping-three-day-successful-us-visit-6635172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Departs For India Wrapping Three-Day "Successful" US Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-departs-for-india-wrapping-three-day-successful-us-visit-6635172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 06:57:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday left for home after wrapping up his "successful and substantial" three-day visit to the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday left for home after wrapping up his "successful and substantial" three-day visit to the US during which he attended the Quad Leaders' meeting, an overwhelming Indian community event and addressed the Summit of the Future at the UN General Assembly.</p>

<p>He also held bilateral meetings on Sunday with his Japanese and Australian counterparts on the sidelines of the Quad Summit and exchanged views to deepen bilateral cooperation further for mutual benefits and the 'peace, stability, and prosperity' of the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<p>"PM @narendramodi emplanes for New Delhi after concluding a successful and substantial visit to the USA," the Ministry of External Affairs said in a post on X.</p>

<p>PM Modi arrived in the US on Friday and on Day 1, he attended the Quad Leaders' meeting in Wilmington, Delaware.</p>

<p>Hosted by President Joe Biden, the Quad Leaders' Summit took place on Saturday in his hometown Wilmington, Delaware. It was attended by Prime Minister Modi, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia, and Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of Japan.</p>

<p>In a rare gesture, US President Biden also hosted PM Modi for a bilateral meeting in his home, and the Quad summit was held at the Archmere Academy in Wilmington.</p>

<p>During their meeting, US President Biden welcomed the progress made towards India sealing procurement of 31 long-endurance MQ-9B armed drones from American defence major General Atomics, as he and Prime Minister Modi vowed to boost reciprocal supply of military hardware between the two sides.</p>

<p>PM Modi also held bilateral meetings with his counterparts from Australia and Japan on the sidelines of the summit.</p>

<p>Also,&nbsp;with the United States, a very special feature of the bilateral meeting was the return of 297 antiquities to India, a few of which were on display at President Biden's residence during the meeting.</p>

<p>At the Quad Leadership Summit and others associated with it, Prime Minister Modi underlined India's approach of cooperation, contact, and engagement for growth with a variety of partners in the Indo-Pacific.</p>

<p>Also, during the summit, the leaders announced the Quad Cancer Moonshot, a groundbreaking partnership to save lives in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<p>India pledged USD 7.5 million to combat cervical cancer in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<p>The Quad nations also announced a new regional Maritime Initiative for Training in the Indo-Pacific (MAITRI), to enable their partners in the region to maximise tools provided through Indo-Pacific Maritime Domain Awareness (IPMDA) and other Quad partner initiatives to monitor and secure their waters, enforce their laws, and deter unlawful behaviour.</p>

<p>After wrapping up the Quad Leaders' meeting in Wilmington, PM Modi left on Saturday for New York for Day 2 to attend an Indian community event at Long Island and later address a key conclave at the United Nations on Day 3.</p>

<p>On Saturday, PM Modi addressed a mega gathering of Indian-Americans at the Nassau Coliseum in New York.</p>

<p>Terming India as a "land of opportunities", Prime Minister Modi told the gathering that he has set very ambitious goals for the country during his third term.</p>

<p>During the event, he also announced that India will open two new consulates in Boston and Los Angeles, meeting the long-pending demand of the fast-growing Indian American community in these two large American cities.</p>

<p>While Boston is considered the education and pharma capital of the US, Los Angeles, home to Hollywood, is hosting the next summer Olympics and current US Ambassador to India Eric Garcetti is the city's former mayor.</p>

<p>The event was attended by more than 13,000 Indian-Americans. While the majority of them were from the New York and New Jersey area, Indian-Americans came in from 40 states, organisers said. Sixty charter buses were used for transportation purposes.</p>

<p>Applauding the role of Indian-Americans in strengthening the relationship between India and the US, he called them India's brand ambassadors.</p>

<p>After the event, Prime Minister Modi participated in a "fruitful" roundtable with the CEOs of leading American tech companies where he emphasised India's growth prospects and discussed initiatives to foster bilateral collaborations across various sectors.</p>

<p>The meeting took place at the Lotte New York Palace Hotel on Sunday during the second leg of Modi's three-day US visit. It saw the participation of CEOs of major US-based firms working on cutting-edge technologies such as AI, quantum computing and semiconductors.</p>

<p>He urged CEOs of US majors to take advantage of India's growth story as the country is making all efforts to become the third largest economy in the world in his third term.</p>

<p>On Day 3, Prime Minister Modi addressed the UN's Summit of the Future and said that the "success of humanity lies in our collective strength, not on the battlefield".</p>

<p>Addressing world leaders from the iconic podium of the UN General Assembly hall, Modi, beginning his speech with a "Namaskar", said he brings the voice of 1.4 billion Indians or one-sixth of humanity to the UN.</p>

<p>During the conclave, PM Modi assured the world community that India will continue to work in thought, words and deeds to protect the rights of all humanity and for global prosperity.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j0ramie_pm-modi-twitter_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi also held bilateral meetings with his counterparts from Australia and Japan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-18th-century-necklace-with-500-diamonds-set-for-auction-6635205]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mysterious 18th Century Necklace With 500 Diamonds Set For Auction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-18th-century-necklace-with-500-diamonds-set-for-auction-6635205]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 06:33:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A mysterious 18th century necklace made from around 500 diamonds, some of which are believed to have been taken from a piece that contributed to Marie Antoinette's demise, will go on sale in November, Sotheby's said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mysterious 18th century necklace made from around 500 diamonds, some of which are believed to have been taken from a piece that contributed to Marie Antoinette's demise, will go on sale in November, Sotheby's said on Monday.</p>

<p>The piece, from a private Asian collection, will go under the hammer in Geneva on November 11, with online bidding opening on the auction house's website on October 25.</p>

<p>The necklace, which is composed of three rows of diamonds finished with a diamond tassel at each end, will make its first public appearance in 50 years on Monday, and is expected to fetch between $1.8 and $2.8 million.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's a wonderful find because, normally, jewellery in the 18th century was broken up in order to be repurposed... so to have an intact piece of the Georgian period of this importance, this amount of carats... is absolutely fabulous," Andres White Correal, chairman of the Sotheby's jewelry department, told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The jewel has passed from families to families. We can start at the early 20th century when it was part of the collection of the Marquesses of Anglesey," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Members of this aristocratic family are believed to have worn the jewel twice in public: once at the 1937 coronation of King George VI and once at his daughter Queen Elizabeth II's coronation in 1953.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Beyond that, little is known of the necklace, including who designed it and for whom it was commissioned, although the auction house believes that such an impressive antique jewel could only have been created for a royal family.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It probably would have been made during the decade preceding the French Revolution, it added.</p>

<p>It is thought that some of the diamonds may have come from the famous necklace linked to what became the scandal of the "Affair of the Necklace", which contributed to the advent of the French Revolution and eventually Marie-Antoinette's death, said Sotheby's.</p>

<p>The auction house said the diamonds are likely to have been sourced "from the legendary Golconda mines in India".</p>

<p>The diamonds from Golconda are still considered to be the purest and most dazzling ever mined.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The necklace will be on public display in London until Wednesday before beginning a tour that will take it to Hong Kong, New York and Taiwan.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ojc20log_18th-century-diamond-necklace-afp_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The piece, from a private Asian collection, will go under the hammer in Geneva on November 11.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fake-brad-pitt-scams-two-women-in-spain-of-3-25-000-euros-5-arrested-6635201]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fake 'Brad Pitt' Scams Two Women In Spain Of 3,25,000 Euros, 5 Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fake-brad-pitt-scams-two-women-in-spain-of-3-25-000-euros-5-arrested-6635201]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 06:32:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Spanish police said Monday that they had arrested five people accused of scamming two women of 325,000 euros by posing as the Hollywood star Brad Pitt via online and WhatsApp messages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spanish police said Monday that they had arrested five people accused of scamming two women of 325,000 euros by posing as the Hollywood star Brad Pitt via online and WhatsApp messages.</p>

<p>The suspects made contact with the women on an internet page for fans of the Oscar-winning actor and led them to believe "they had a sentimental relationship with him", Spain's Guardia Civil police force said in a statement.</p>

<p>Posing as Pitt, the members of the gang then allegedly proposed that the women invest in various projects that did not exist.</p>

<p>One woman, from the southern region of Andalusia, was defrauded of 175,000 euros ($195,000) while the other, from the northern Basque Country, lost 150,000 euros.</p>

<p>"The cybercriminals, to capture the victims, had studied their social networks and made a psychological profile of them, thus discovering that both women were two vulnerable people, lacking in affection and in a state of depression," police said.</p>

<p>"They also used instant messaging platforms to exchange messages and emails with the two women until they reached a point where they believed they were chatting via WhatsApp with Brad Pitt himself, who promised them a romantic relationship and a future together."</p>

<p>Police arrested five people in the southern region of Andalusia, including the suspected leaders of the group.</p>

<p>They raided five homes as part of their operations, seizing several mobile phones, bank cards, two computers and a diary "in which the phrases used by the fraudsters to deceive their victims were written down".</p>

<p>Officers were able to recover 85,000 euros of the money that was defrauded from the two women.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6s4542g8_computer-generic_625x300_02_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The suspects made contact with the women on an internet page for fans of the Oscar-winning actor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/california-passes-law-to-ban-or-restrict-smartphones-in-school-6635081]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[California Passes Law To Ban Or Restrict Smartphones In School]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/california-passes-law-to-ban-or-restrict-smartphones-in-school-6635081]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 06:21:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[California Governor Gavin Newsom signed into law on Monday a bill that requires schools to limit or ban the use of smartphones, amid a growing consensus that excess usage can increase the risk of mental illness and impair learning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>California Governor Gavin Newsom signed into law on Monday a bill that requires schools to limit or ban the use of smartphones, amid a growing consensus that excess usage can increase the risk of mental illness and impair learning.</p>

<p>Thirteen other states this year have banned or restricted cellphones in school or recommended local educators do so, after Florida led the way by banning phones in class in 2023, according to Education Week.</p>

<p>California, with nearly 5.9 million public school students, has followed the lead of its own Los Angeles County, whose school board banned smartphones for its 429,000 students in June.</p>

<p>That same month U.S. Surgeon General Vivek Murthy called for a warning label on social media platforms, akin to those on cigarette packages, likening the problem to a mental health emergency.</p>

<p>Murthy cited a study in the medical journal JAMA showing adolescents who spend more than three hours a day on social media may be at heightened risk of mental illness, while referring to a Gallup poll showing the average teen spends 4.8 hours per day on social media.</p>

<p>California's bill, which passed 76-0 in the state assembly and 38-1 in the senate, requires school boards or other governing bodies to develop a policy to limit or prohibit student use of smartphones on campus by July 1, 2026, and update the policy every five years.</p>

<p>"We know that excessive smartphone use increases anxiety, depression, and other mental health issues - but we have the power to intervene. This new law will help students focus on academics, social development, and the world in front of them, not their screens, when they're in school," Newsom said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qskuvaj8_online-mobile-game_625x300_15_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[California has nearly 5.9 million public school students.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-phoenix-breaks-heat-record-with-113-days-straight-over-100-fahrenheit-6634293]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US' Phoenix Breaks Heat Record With 113 Days Straight Over 100 Fahrenheit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-phoenix-breaks-heat-record-with-113-days-straight-over-100-fahrenheit-6634293]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 06:21:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The desert city of Phoenix, Arizona, suffered a record 113 straight days with temperatures over 100 Fahrenheit (38 Celsius) this year, leading to hundreds of heat-related deaths and more acres burned by wildfire across the state, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The desert city of Phoenix, Arizona, suffered a record 113 straight days with temperatures over 100 Fahrenheit (38 Celsius) this year, leading to hundreds of heat-related deaths and more acres burned by wildfire across the state, officials said.</p>

<p>The city of 1.6 million residents, the largest in the Sonoran desert, had its hottest-ever summer, breaking the previous 2023 record by nearly two degrees, according to the National Weather Service.</p>

<p>The 113-day streak reached last week smashed Phoenix's previous record of 76-straight-days over 100 F set in 1993.</p>

<p>"It's very rare that we see, especially two summers in a row, two record breaking summers like we just experienced," said Matt Salerno, meteorologist at the National Weather Service Phoenix office.</p>

<p>Heat has killed 256 people so far this year in Phoenix's Maricopa County and is the suspected cause of 393 other deaths, according to official data. That puts the county on track to surpass a record 645 heat deaths in 2023.</p>

<p>Around half of deaths are of unsheltered people, the county's most vulnerable group.</p>

<p>Deaths peaked in July when Phoenix had regular highs of 118 F, a trend climate scientists attribute to global warming from fossil fuel pollution.</p>

<p>Over the last five years the city has averaged 40 days of 110 degrees or higher compared with about five days in that range at the beginning of the last century, according to the Arizona State Climate Office.</p>

<p>The extreme heat has led to a statewide increase in acreage burned by wildfire in 2024 compared with last year, according to the office's director Erinanne Saffell.</p>

<p>A climate-related combination of record winter precipitation and summer heat fueled wildfires around Los Angeles in recent weeks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8cakbpr8_phoenix-heatwave-reuters_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Deaths peaked in July when Phoenix had regular highs of 118 F.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-thanks-pm-modi-for-indias-peace-efforts-in-ukraine-conflict-6635137]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In New York, Zelensky Thanks PM Modi For Peace Efforts In Ukraine Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-thanks-pm-modi-for-indias-peace-efforts-in-ukraine-conflict-6635137]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 06:10:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi, during his meeting with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy, affirmed that everyone agrees with need to reach a ceasefire in the ongoing conflict in Ukraine and the restoration of peace and stability, Foreign Secretary said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi, during his meeting with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy, affirmed that everyone agrees with the need to reach a ceasefire in the ongoing conflict in Ukraine and the restoration of peace and stability, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said on Monday (local time).</p>

<p>During the special briefing by the Foreign Secretary on the PM's visit to the US, Mr Misri said that Zelenskyy appreciated India's attention to these issues as well as the PM's recent visit to Ukraine to make for "peace and a pathway to finding a way out of this conflict."</p>

<p>"This is the third meeting between the two leaders in the space of probably three months...Their discussions on all matters, the bilateral issues as well as issues surrounding the Russia-Ukraine conflict. President Zelenskyy was very appreciative of India's attention to these issues and said that the Prime Minister's visit had been highly appreciated and he thanked the Prime Minister for the efforts that he was making for peace and a pathway to finding a way out of this conflict," Mr Misri said.</p>

<p>"Both sides appreciated that there was positive momentum on a lot of issues in the bilateral relationship and they agreed to remain in close touch either directly or through exchanges of visits at various other levels," he added.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi held a bilateral meeting with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy in New York, where both leaders showed their commitment to implementing the outcomes of PM Modi's visit to Ukraine last month. This was the third time both leaders have met in the last three months.</p>

<p>The Foreign Secretary, during the briefing, also informed that the bilateral meeting between PM Modi and President Zelenskyy was requested from the Ukrainian side.</p>

<p>Being asked about whether the issue of India purchasing Russian oil was discussed, Mr Misri said the issue wasn't discussed.</p>

<p>PM Modi, affirmed that he has always talked about moving forward on the path of peace by proposing peace. The Prime Minister said that he has talked with leaders of different countries, and all are of the opinion that somehow a ceasefire has to be reached and efforts are ongoing in this regard.</p>

<p>Mr Misri said that since his visit to Ukraine, the Prime Minister has been in touch with Russian President Putin and US President Biden. National Security Advisor Ajit Doval also visited Russia recently.</p>

<p>"In a way, in the meeting with President Zelenskyy, the Prime Minister also got the opportunity to say that he has always talked about moving forward on the path of peace by proposing peace, so it is clear that if there is no peace, then in a way sustainable development cannot happen either. Will the war end, only time will tell, but everyone's efforts are focused on finding an end to the war in some way," Mr Misri said.</p>

<p>"In his conversation with President Zelenskyy, the Prime Minister also told him that he has talked to the leaders of different countries and discussions keep happening on this subject and everyone's opinion is that somehow we will have to find a way to ceasefire in the war and our efforts are also continuing in this regard," he added.</p>

<p>While stressing on attaining peace in the conflict, Vikram Misri also quoted Mahatma Gandhi and said, "There is no path to peace; peace is the path."</p>

<p>Mr Misri said during PM Modi and Zelenskyy's meeting, both sides appreciated the positive momentum on a lot of issues pertaining to both countries' bilateral relationship and also agreed to remain in close touch.</p>

<p>"Both sides appreciated that there was positive momentum on a lot of issues in the bilateral relationship and they agreed to remain in close touch either directly or through exchanges of visits at various other levels," he said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi reiterated India's support for early resolution of the conflict in Ukraine and restoration of peace and stability.</p>

<p>"Met President Zelenskyy in New York. We are committed to implementing the outcomes of my visit to Ukraine last month to strengthen bilateral relations. Reiterated India's support for early resolution of the conflict in Ukraine and restoration of peace and stability," PM Modi said in a post in X.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian President also took to X, and said New Delhi and Kyiv actively developing our relations and working together to strengthen cooperation across various fields.</p>

<p>"This is already the third bilateral meeting this year with the Prime Minister of India, Narendra Modi @narendramodi. We are actively developing our relations and working together to strengthen cooperation across various fields," Zelenskyy said.</p>

<p>"The main focus of our conversation was on enhancing our interaction on international platforms, particularly at the UN and G20, as well as implementing the Peace Formula and preparing for the second Peace Summit. We had a substantive discussion on the available opportunities. I am grateful for the clear support of our sovereignty and territorial integrity," he added.</p>

<p>PM Modi visited Russia in July and Ukraine in August this year.</p>

<p>Notably, India has emphasised the need for sincere and practical engagement between all stakeholders to develop innovative solutions that will have broad acceptability and contribute towards early restoration of peace in the Ukraine conflict that started in February 2022.</p>

<p>India has also expressed its willingness to contribute in all possible ways to facilitate an early return of peace.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3j7037nc_pm-modi-meets-zelensky_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This was the third meeting between PM Modi and Zelensky in the space of probably three months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-ryan-routh-wrote-chilling-letter-months-ago-about-assassination-bid-on-donald-trump-6635087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunman Wrote Chilling Letter Months Ago About Assassination Bid On Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-ryan-routh-wrote-chilling-letter-months-ago-about-assassination-bid-on-donald-trump-6635087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman suspected of planning to kill Donald Trump wrote a chilling letter months ago about an  "assassination attempt" on the former president, US prosecutors said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman suspected of planning to kill Donald Trump wrote a chilling letter months ago about an&nbsp; "assassination attempt" on the former president, US prosecutors said on Monday.</p>

<p>The correspondence emerged as Ryan Routh, 58, was due in court in southern Florida charged with two firearms offenses after he was arrested allegedly fleeing Trump International Golf Course in West Palm Beach on September 15.</p>

<p>Prosecutors say a Secret Service agent fired at Routh after spotting a rifle poking out of the tree line several holes ahead of Trump, and that Routh was spotted by a witness who saw him escaping in a car.</p>

<p>Federal prosecutors said in Monday's filing Routh had dropped off a box at an unidentified person's home "several months" beforehand, containing ammunition, a metal pipe, building materials, phones "and various letters."</p>

<p>After learning of the apparent assassination bid, the witness apparently opened the box and discovered a letter addressed to "The World."</p>

<p>"This was an assassination attempt on Donald Trump but I failed you," it said.</p>

<p>"I tried my best and gave it all the gumption I could muster. It is up to you now to finish the job; and I will offer $150,000 to whomever can complete the job."</p>

<p>It was not clear if he was referring to a separate, earlier attempt on the life of Trump or the one at the golf course.</p>

<p>Detectives believe Routh may have been lying in wait for Trump for nearly 12 hours at the Florida course. He was arrested after police spotted his car driving on a nearby highway.</p>

<p>The government says Routh traveled to Florida a month before his arrest and began casing the golf course and drove by Trump's oceanfront home.</p>

<p>In online posts Routh said he voted for Trump in 2016 but that the president had become a disappointment.</p>

<p>"Everyone across the globe from the youngest to the oldest know that Trump is unfit to be anything, much less a US president," said Routh's letter, the front page of which appeared in a photograph included with the court papers.</p>

<p>"US presidents must at bare minimum embody the moral fabric that is America, and be kind, caring and selfless and always stand for humanity. Trump fails to understand any of (that)."</p>

<p>Routh is accused of possessing a gun with a scratched-out serial number and with possessing a gun illegally as a felon, although more serious charges may come after prosecutors put the case before a federal grand jury.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5taq8aog_ryan-routh-_625x300_16_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In online posts Routh said he voted for Trump in 2016 but that the president had become a disappointment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-6-magnitude-earthquake-hits-japan-tsunami-warning-issued-6634994]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5.6 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Japan, Tsunami Warning Issued]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-6-magnitude-earthquake-hits-japan-tsunami-warning-issued-6634994]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 05:27:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 5.6-magnitude earthquake struck near Japan's Izu Islands on Tuesday, the USGS said, triggering local weather authorities to issue a tsunami warning for the remote Pacific area off Tokyo.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 5.6-magnitude earthquake struck near Japan's remote Izu Islands on Tuesday, the United States Geological Survey said, prompting local weather authorities to issue a tsunami warning.</p>

<p>A one-meter (3.3-inch) tsunami could be expected at Izu Islands by 8:30 am (2330 GMT) and Ogasawara Islands by 9:00 am (0000 GMT), the Japan Meteorological Agency said.</p>

<p>Island residents told national broadcaster NHK that they did not feel the earthquake.</p>

<p>Japan sits on top of four major tectonic plates and experiences around 1,500 quakes every year, most of them minor.</p>

<p>The impact is generally contained even with larger tremors thanks to advanced building techniques and well-practised emergency procedures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-12/earthquake-generic_650x400_71481076561.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 5.6-magnitude earthquake struck near Japan's Izu Islands on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eus-foreign-affairs-chief-says-lebanon-israel-escalation-nearing-full-fledged-war-6634993]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon-Israel Tensions Near "Full-Fledged War": EU Foreign Affairs Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eus-foreign-affairs-chief-says-lebanon-israel-escalation-nearing-full-fledged-war-6634993]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 05:21:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[EU foreign affairs chief Josep Borrell said on Monday that the escalating clashes between Israel and Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah threaten to plunge the Middle East into all-out war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>EU foreign affairs chief Josep Borrell said on Monday that the escalating clashes between Israel and Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah threaten to plunge the Middle East into all-out war.</p>

<p>"I can say we are almost in a full-fledged war," Borrell said ahead of a gathering of world leaders at the United Nations.</p>

<p>"We're seeing more military strikes, more damage, more collateral damage, more victims," he added as Lebanese authorities said Israeli airstrikes killed at least 492 people on Monday, including 35 children.</p>

<p>The strikes marked the deadliest day of cross-border violence since the Gaza war began.</p>

<p>Israel said it killed a "large number" of Hezbollah militants when it hit about 1,300 sites in southern and eastern Lebanon, including a "targeted strike" in Beirut.</p>

<p>"Everybody has to put all their capacity to stop this," Borrell said, pressing for a solution in New York.</p>

<p>On Gaza, he said "despite all the diplomatic capacity that we have deployed, nothing has been able to stop the war," accusing both sides of "procrastinating."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tpn52nro_lebanon_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strikes marked the deadliest day of cross-border violence since the Gaza war began.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-uae-discuss-progress-on-india-middle-east-europe-economic-corridor-6634937]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US, UAE Discuss Progress On India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-uae-discuss-progress-on-india-middle-east-europe-economic-corridor-6634937]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 05:07:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden and his counterpart from the UAE Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed discussed the progress of the landmark India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor (IMEC) and underscored its potential to usher in a "new era of international connectivity".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and his counterpart from the United Arab Emirates Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed discussed the progress of the landmark India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor (IMEC) and underscored its potential to usher in a "new era of international connectivity".</p>

<p>The ambitious project was launched at the 2023 G20 Leaders' Summit in New Delhi, together with the leaders of India, Saudi Arabia, France, Germany, Italy, and the European Union. When complete, it would connect India by ship-to-rail connections through the United Arab Emirates, Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Israel, and Europe through Greece.</p>

<p>At the meeting held at the White House on Monday, Biden and Zayed reaffirmed that the corridor will generate economic growth, increase efficiencies, lower greenhouse gas emissions, and enable the transformative integration of Asia, Europe, and the Middle East, according to a joint statement.</p>

<p>The two leaders underscored that the transformative partnership had the potential to usher in a "new era of international connectivity" to facilitate global trade and clean energy distribution, expand reliable access to electricity, and strengthen telecommunication.</p>

<p>According to the statement, they emphasised the importance of joint initiatives to promote a circular economy and advance sustainable practices, underscoring their commitment to innovation for resource efficiency and environmentally responsible growth.</p>

<p>Earlier, welcoming Zayed to the White House, Biden said UAE is a nation of trailblazers which always looking to the future and making big bets.&nbsp; "That's something our countries have in common, and our people have in common. In fact, it's a cornerstone of our growing cooperation in AI, in clean energy, in space, and investing in infrastructure to connect regions," he said.</p>

<p>Biden also announced plans to make UAE a major defence partner of the United States, which is the only other country after India to get this status.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7nl6aalg_biden-meets-mohamed-bin-zayed-_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden met his counterpart UAE Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed on Monday at White House.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-says-ukraine-closer-to-end-of-war-with-russia-6634903]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Says Ukraine "Closer To End Of War" With Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-says-ukraine-closer-to-end-of-war-with-russia-6634903]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 04:51:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said that his country is "closer to the end of the war" with Russia, according to excerpts of an interview with ABC News released on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said that his country is "closer to the end of the war" with Russia, according to excerpts of an interview with ABC News released on Monday.</p>

<p>"I think that we are closer to the peace than we think," he was quoted as saying. "We are closer to the end of the war."</p>

<p>In the interview, he urged Washington and other partners to continue supporting Ukraine. A full scale Russian invasion of Ukraine began in Feb. 2022.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7ccbgih8_zelensky-afp_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky also urged Washington and other partners to continue supporting Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-discuss-concrete-ideas-with-allies-to-prevent-israel-hezbollah-war-6634875]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US To Discuss "Concrete Ideas" With Allies To Prevent Israel-Hezbollah War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-discuss-concrete-ideas-with-allies-to-prevent-israel-hezbollah-war-6634875]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 04:46:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. does not support the escalation between Israel and Hezbollah across the border, a senior State Department official said, adding that Washington was going to discuss "concrete ideas" with allies and partners to prevent the war from broadening]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. does not support the escalation between Israel and Hezbollah across the border, a senior State Department official said, adding that Washington was going to discuss "concrete ideas" with allies and partners to prevent the war from broadening.</p>

<p>Israel launched airstrikes against Hezbollah targets on Monday, killing 492 people and sending tens of thousands fleeing for safety in Lebanon's deadliest day in decades, according to authorities.</p>

<p>Israeli officials have said the recent uptick in airstrikes on Hezbollah targets in Lebanon was designed to force the Iran-aligned group to agree to a diplomatic solution.</p>

<p>But the U.S. State Department official, briefing reporters in New York on condition of anonymity, pushed back on this Israeli position, saying President Joe Biden's administration was focused on "reducing tensions ... and breaking the cycle of strike-counterstrike."</p>

<p>"I can't recall, at least in recent memory, a period in which an escalation or intensification led to a fundamental de- escalation and led to profound stabilization of the situation," the official said.</p>

<p>Asked if that is a disagreement with the Israeli stance, the U.S. official nodded.</p>

<p>The spiraling conflict over Israel's northern border with Lebanon is a focus for Secretary of State Antony Blinken on the sidelines of the U.N. General Assembly this week. Washington had "concrete ideas" to prevent a broader war and would seek an "off ramp" to tensions, the official said.</p>

<p>"It's an evolution of those discussions on which we're trying to base some practical, concrete steps that will have good chances of reducing tensions and actually getting some traction," the official said.</p>

<p>Asked if Washington believes Israel is preparing for an ground invasion of Lebanon, the U.S. official declined to answer definitively.</p>

<p>"We obviously do not believe that a ground invasion of Lebanon is going to contribute to reducing tensions in the region," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s7a42lto_lebanon_625x300_24_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 490 people killed in Lebanon as Israel launched airstrikes against Hezbollah on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/492-dead-in-israeli-strikes-on-hezbollah-strongholds-in-lebanon-6634643]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nearly 500 Killed In Israeli Strikes On Hezbollah Strongholds In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/492-dead-in-israeli-strikes-on-hezbollah-strongholds-in-lebanon-6634643]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 03:25:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli air strikes on Lebanon killed at least 492 people on Monday, including 35 children, the health ministry said, marking the deadliest day of cross-border violence since the Gaza war began.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli air strikes on Lebanon killed at least 492 people on Monday, including 35 children, the health ministry said, marking the deadliest day of cross-border violence since the Gaza war began.</p>

<p>Arab states strongly condemned Israel for the escalating hostilities with Hezbollah, which have intensified to levels unseen in nearly a year.</p>

<p>The war erupted after Hamas and other Palestinian militants launched the unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel, drawing in Hezbollah and other Iran-backed groups.</p>

<p>Israel said it killed a "large number" of Hezbollah militants when it hit about 1,600 sites in southern and eastern Lebanon, including a "targeted strike" in Beirut in what the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) called "Operation Northern Arrows".</p>

<p>Hezbollah said Ali Karake, its third-in-command, was alive and had moved to safety after a source said the strike on the capital targeted him.</p>

<p>State media reported new raids in eastern Lebanon, while Hezbollah said it targeted five sites in Israel.</p>

<p>In the coastal Israeli city of Haifa, people were seen running for cover when air raid sirens sounded.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said the strikes killed 492 people, including 35 children and 58 women, and wounded 1,645 others. Health Minister Firass Abiad said "thousands of families" had been displaced.</p>

<p>Explosions near the ancient city of Baalbek in eastern Lebanon sent smoke billowing into the sky.</p>

<p>"We sleep and wake up to bombardment... that's what our life has become," said Wafaa Ismail, 60, a housewife from the southern village of Zawtar.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Most difficult week for Hezbollah' -</strong></p>

<p>Global powers urged Israel and Hezbollah to step back from the brink of all-out war, as the violence shifted from Israel's southern border with Gaza to its northern frontier with Lebanon.</p>

<p>France and Egypt called on the United Nations Security Council to intervene, while Iraq requested an urgent meeting of Arab states on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly in New York.</p>

<p>Israeli army chief Herzi Halevi said the strikes hit combat infrastructure Hezbollah had been building for two decades.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant called Monday "a significant peak" in the operation.</p>

<p>"This is the most difficult week for Hezbollah since its establishment - the results speak for themselves," he said.</p>

<p>"Entire units were taken out of battle as a result of the activities conducted at the beginning of the week in which numerous terrorists were injured."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel was acting to change the "security balance" in the north.</p>

<p><strong>- Hezbollah wave of rockets -</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has been trading near-daily fire with Israel in support of Hamas, said it was in a "new phase" of confrontation.</p>

<p>The group said it launched rockets at Israeli military sites near Haifa and two bases in retaliation for Israeli strikes on the south and the Bekaa.</p>

<p>The attack came after an Israeli strike on southern Beirut on Friday killed its elite Radwan Force commander, Ibrahim Aqil, and coordinated communications device blasts that Hezbollah blamed on Israel killed 39 people and wounded almost 3,000 on Tuesday and Wednesday.</p>

<p>Since the cross-border exchanges between Israel and Hezbollah began in October, tens of thousands of people on both sides have fled their homes.</p>

<p>An Israeli military official, who cannot be further identified under military rules, said the operation seeks to "degrade threats" from Hezbollah, push them back from the border, and then to destroy infrastructure.</p>

<p>Lebanese Prime Minister Najib Mikati urged the United Nations and world powers to deter what he called Israel's "plan that aims to destroy Lebanese villages and towns".</p>

<p>- 'Full-fledged war' nearing -</p>

<p>EU foreign affairs chief Josep Borrell warned that Israel and Hezbollah were "almost in full-fledged war", ahead of a gathering of world leaders at the United Nations.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, whose country is Israel's main ally and weapons supplier, said his country was "working to de-escalate in a way that allows people to return home safely".</p>

<p>The Pentagon said it was sending a small number of additional US military personnel to the Middle East after thousands were deployed earlier alongside warships, fighter jets and air defence systems.</p>

<p>A US official, speaking on condition of anonymity at the UN General Assembly, said that Washington opposed an Israeli ground invasion targeting Hezbollah and had "concrete ideas" on how to de-escalate the crisis.</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres was "gravely alarmed" by civilian casualties in Lebanon, his spokesman said.</p>

<p>The United Nations peacekeeping force in south Lebanon warned "any further escalation of this dangerous situation could have far-reaching and devastating consequences".</p>

<p>Qatar, a mediator in Gaza ceasefire talks, said Israel's bombardment of Lebanon "puts the region on the brink of the abyss", while Turkey said the strikes threatened "chaos" and Jordan urged an immediate end to the escalation "before it is too late".</p>

<p>The Palestinian foreign ministry condemned the strikes and ordered Palestinian medical staff in Lebanon to provide support for the wounded.</p>

<p>Iran's newly elected president, Masoud Pezeshkian, accused Israel of seeking "to create this wider conflict".</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Of the 251 hostages also seized by militants, 97 are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,455 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5g8d25mc_lebanon-pager-blasts-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Arab states strongly condemned Israel for the escalating hostilities with Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-commander-alive-after-israel-strike-on-lebanon-6634133]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Says Commander Alive After Israel Strike On Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-commander-alive-after-israel-strike-on-lebanon-6634133]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:47:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's Hezbollah said commander Ali Karake, who a source reported had been the target of an Israeli strike Monday on Beirut, was alive and had moved to safety.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Hezbollah said commander Ali Karake, who a source reported had been the target of an Israeli strike Monday on Beirut, was alive and had moved to safety.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Iran-backed movement said "commander Ali Karake is well... and has moved to a safe place".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tpn52nro_lebanon_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-action-must-match-global-ambition-pm-modi-at-un-summit-6634029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Global Action Must Match Global Ambition": PM Modi At UN Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-action-must-match-global-ambition-pm-modi-at-un-summit-6634029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:11:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi, speaking at the United Nations Summit of the Future on Monday, said alongside terrorism, new areas of conflict are emerging and it is high time that "global action must match global ambition".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi, speaking at the United Nations Summit of the Future on Monday, said alongside terrorism, new areas of conflict are emerging and it is high time that "global action must match global ambition".</p>

<p>Pointing out that terrorism continues to be a serious threat to global peace and security, PM Modi said on the other hand, "cyber, maritime and space are emerging as new areas of conflict".</p>

<p>"On all these issues, I will stress that global action must match global ambition," he added.</p>

<p>Talking of growing global concern over dangers from new and evolving technologies, especially artificial intelligence, PM Modi said, "There is a need for balanced regulation at a global level, for the safe and responsible use of technology."</p>

<p>According to the Wilmington Declaration - made two days ago at the Quad meet -- leaders of the US, Australia, Japan and India announced their intention to enhance cybersecurity partnership.</p>

<p>"In the face of a deteriorating security environment in the cyber domain, Quad countries intend to enhance our cybersecurity partnership to address common threats posed by state-sponsored actors, cybercriminals, and other non-state malicious actors. Our countries commit to taking concrete steps to increase our collective network defense and advance technical capabilities through greater threat information sharing and capacity building," read the joint declaration.</p>

<p>The leaders, in their declaration, had unequivocally condemned terrorism and violent extremism in all its forms and manifestations, including cross-border terrorism.</p>

<p>"We are committed to international cooperation and will work with our regional partners in a comprehensive and sustained manner to strengthen their capability to prevent, detect and respond to threats posed by terrorism and violent extremism, including threats posed by the use of new and emerging technologies for terrorist purposes, consistent with international law," the statement had added.</p>

<p>"When we are discussing the global future, we must accord the highest priority to a human-centric approach while prioritising sustainable development," PM Modi also said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We must also ensure human welfare, food and health security," he added, declaring India was ready to share her experience in poverty eradication and bridging the digital divide.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6vp1g818_narendra-modi-un_625x300_24_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-forest-has-lost-area-the-size-of-germany-and-france-to-deforestation-6633734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Forest Has Lost Area The Size Of Germany, France To Deforestation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-forest-has-lost-area-the-size-of-germany-and-france-to-deforestation-6633734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 23:09:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world's biggest rainforest, the Amazon, has lost an area about the size of Germany and France combined to deforestation in four decades, a study showed Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world's biggest rainforest, the Amazon, has lost an area about the size of Germany and France combined to deforestation in four decades, a study showed Monday.</p>

<p>The South American jungle, spanning nine countries, is seen as crucial to the fight against climate change due to its ability to absorb planet-warming carbon dioxide from the atmosphere.</p>

<p>Deforestation, mainly for mining and agricultural purposes, has led to the loss of 12.5 percent of the Amazon's plant cover from 1985 to 2023, according to RAISG, a collective of researchers and NGOs.</p>

<p>This amounts to 88 million hectares (880,000 square kilometers, 339,773 square miles) of forest cover lost across Brazil, Bolivia, Peru, Ecuador, Colombia, Venezuela, Guyana, Suriname and French Guiana.</p>

<p>RAISG experts reported an "accelerated transformation" of the Amazon, with an "alarming increase" in the use of land previously occupied by forest for mining, crops, or livestock.</p>

<p>"A large number of ecosystems have disappeared to give way to immense expanses of pastures, soybean fields or other monocultures, or have been transformed into craters for gold mining," they said.</p>

<p>"With the loss of the forest, we emit more carbon into the atmosphere and this disrupts an entire ecosystem that regulates the climate and the hydrological cycle, clearly affecting temperatures," Sandra Rio Caceres, from the Institute of the Common Good -- a Peruvian association that took part in the study -- told AFP.</p>

<p>She said she believes the loss of vegetation in the Amazon is directly linked to severe drought and wildfires affecting several South American countries.</p>

<p>The World Weather Attribution network of scientists said Sunday that climate change was increasing the risk and severity of fires in the Amazon and Pantanal wetlands which are releasing "massive amounts" of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere.</p>

<p>"Never-ending heat has combined with low rainfall to turn these precious ecosystems into highly flammable tinderboxes," said Clair Barnes, a researcher from Imperial College London.</p>

<p>"As long as the world burns fossil fuels, the risk of devastating wildfires will continue to increase in the Amazon and Pantanal," she added.</p>

<p>The drought has placed some Amazon rivers at their lowest level in decades, threatening the lifestyle of some 47 million people who live on their banks.</p>

<p>The dry spell has sent fires -- often lit to clear land for farming -- burning out of control in Brazil, Ecuador, Colombia, and Peru.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tpt6dbng_amazon-forets-fire_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The drought has placed some Amazon rivers at their lowest level in decades]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/us-scientists-demonstrate-revolutionary-method-to-deflect-asteroids-using-nuclear-explosion-6633240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Scientists Demonstrate Method To Deflect Asteroids Using Nuclear Blast]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/us-scientists-demonstrate-revolutionary-method-to-deflect-asteroids-using-nuclear-explosion-6633240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 21:44:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In New Mexico, scientists are exploring a futuristic solution to defend Earth against asteroid threats: harnessing X-ray blasts from nuclear explosions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Asteroid collisions with Earth are surprisingly common, with NASA estimating 48.5 tonnes of meteoric material entering our atmosphere daily. Most burn up, producing shooting stars. Although devastating asteroid impacts are rare in Earth's history, humanity has learned a crucial lesson from the catastrophic event 66 million years ago. The asteroid responsible for the dinosaurs' extinction was approximately six miles wide, but significantly smaller objects still pose a significant threat.&nbsp;In the face of potentially catastrophic asteroid impacts, scientists are racing to develop innovative solutions to protect our planet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In New Mexico, scientists are exploring a futuristic solution to defend Earth against asteroid threats: harnessing X-ray blasts from nuclear explosions, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/sep/23/nuclear-blast-could-save-earth-from-large-asteroid">Guardian</a></em> reported. Scientists at Sandia National Laboratories in Albuquerque have&nbsp;successfully demonstrated a revolutionary method to deflect incoming asteroids using nuclear explosions. For the experiment, researchers harnessed the power of X-rays from a nuclear blast to vaporise the surface of a nearby asteroid.</p>

<p>The process works by unleashing an immense pulse of radiation, heating the asteroid's surface to tens of thousands of degrees. This creates a rapidly expanding ball of gas that can nudge the asteroid off its catastrophic course. By precisely calculating the blast's impact, scientists believe this technique can effectively push threatening asteroids away from Earth, potentially saving humanity from doomsday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The primary mechanism involves using X-rays to rapidly heat the target surface, causing it to vaporize and expand into the adjacent vacuum. The expanding gas pushes against the asteroid, transferring momentum (in the opposite direction)," authors of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-024-02633-7">study</a>&nbsp;published Monday in the journal Nature Physics wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Scientists noted that the nuclear option is for larger asteroids, particularly when time is short. Researchers believe this strategy can effectively deflect asteroids up to 2.5 miles wide, although this isn't a rigid limit.</p>

<p>If there is enough warning time, one can certainly deflect larger asteroids, &nbsp;Dr Nathan Moore, the first author of the study said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Moore and his team plan to conduct further experimental tests to refine the X-ray deflection technique, building on their initial success. Their goal is to enhance the method's effectiveness through additional laboratory experiments. Ultimately, they envision a space-based demonstration, similar to NASA's DART (Double Asteroid Redirection Test) mission, to test the technique on a real asteroid.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n34lk0pg_asteroid_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Researchers harnessed the power of X-rays from a nuclear blast to vaporise the surface of a asteroid]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>