<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 07:34:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-donald-trump-kamala-harris-do-us-voters-favour-democrat-or-republican-exit-polls-say-6953729]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Do US Voters Favour Kamala Harris Or Donald Trump? Exit Polls Say...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-donald-trump-kamala-harris-do-us-voters-favour-democrat-or-republican-exit-polls-say-6953729]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 07:34:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Americans on Tuesday voted to decide whether Kamala Harris will win the race to the White House or Donald Trump will retain the top post for a second time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of Americans on Tuesday voted in the US presidential election to decide whether Democrat nominee Kamala Harris will win the race to the White House or the Republican candidate Donald Trump will retain the top post for a second time.</p>

<p>Exit polls showed that most of the voters favoured Harris, 59, over her 78-year-old rival.</p>

<p>According to NBC News, 48 per cent of voters nationwide expressed a favourable view of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-leads-in-red-states-of-indiana-and-kentucky-as-counting-of-votes-begins-for-us-elections-6953293">Harris</a>, while 44 per cent supported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-donald-trump-kamala-harris-over-70-of-voters-not-happy-with-how-things-are-going-in-us-exit-polls-6953111">Trump</a>.</p>

<p>The voters were also asked to choose between five issues - democracy, economy, abortion, immigration and foreign policy.</p>

<p>While 34% of voters said democracy mattered most to their vote, 31% said the economy. Abortion (14%) and immigration (11%) ranked as the next-most important issues and 4% of voters named foreign policy.</p>

<p>An exit poll by CNN said roughly three-quarters of the electorate holds a negative view of the way things are going in the US today. According to the poll, only about one-quarter call themselves enthusiastic or satisfied with the state of the nation, with more than four in 10 dissatisfied and roughly three in 10 saying they are angry.</p>

<p>Exit polls, however, are not always accurate and the preliminary results are subject to change as more voters are surveyed.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-live-updates-its-over-to-voters-as-america-decides-between-kamala-harris-and-donald-trump-6948523" target="_blank">2024 US Presidential elections</a> are historic because if <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-asian-and-proud-how-kamala-harris-is-winning-over-indian-americans-6405829">Harris</a>, the Indian-American who is the first female vice president, wins, she would become the first woman, Black woman and South Asian American to win the presidency.</p>

<p>On the other hand, if the US voters choose Trump, the only president to be impeached twice and the first former president to be criminally convicted, he would become the first president to win non-consecutive terms in more than a century.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g48onubo_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Elections 2024: Exit polls, however, are not always accurate]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-protests-in-tel-aviv-after-israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-fires-defence-minister-yoav-gallant-6953354]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bibi Traitor": Protests In Tel Aviv After Netanyahu Fires Defence Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-protests-in-tel-aviv-after-israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-fires-defence-minister-yoav-gallant-6953354]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 05:38:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of Israelis rallied in Tel Aviv late Tuesday to protest the sacking of defence minister Yoav Gallant, calling on his successor Israel Katz to prioritise a hostage deal to return the captives still held in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of Israelis rallied in Tel Aviv late Tuesday to protest the sacking of defence minister Yoav Gallant, calling on his successor Israel Katz to prioritise a hostage deal to return the captives still held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Chanting slogans against the government and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, the demonstrators carrying Israeli flags gathered in the commercial hub shortly after Gallant's dismissal was announced.</p>

<p>Protesters also blocked traffic and lit fires on the Ayalon highway in Tel Aviv, with some wearing "Bring them home now!" t-shirts referring to the hostages.</p>

<p>They held up signs with slogans such as "We deserve better leaders" and "Leaving no one behind!" and one protester wore handcuffs and a face mask with Netanyahu's likeness.</p>

<p>"Bibi traitor! You're guilty" chanted some, referring to Netanyahu and blaming for failing to prevent the Hamas attack on October 7 last year.</p>

<p>"We, the protesters, believe that Gallant... is actually the only normal person in the government," said 54-year-old teacher Samuel Miller, slamming Netanyahu's administration for opening "new fronts in uncalled-for wars".</p>

<p>"He's doing nothing to safeguard our peace, the peace of the Palestinians, the peace of everybody in this region," Miller told AFP.</p>

<p>He also criticised Netanyahu's government for "doing absolutely nothing to free the hostages" still held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Foreign minister Israel Katz took over the defence portfolio on Tuesday, after Netanyahu fired Gallant over eroded trust over the past months of the Gaza war.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Endangering Israel's security' -</strong></p>

<p>An Israeli group campaigning for the release of hostages in Gaza on Tuesday expressed "deep concern" over the sacking and urged Katz to "prioritise" a deal to free the captives.</p>

<p>"We expect the incoming defence minister, Israel Katz, to prioritise a hostage deal... to secure the immediate release of all hostages," the Hostages and Missing Families Forum said in a statement.</p>

<p>Gallant also called on the government to bring home the hostages, saying in a televised speech: "We must do this quickly, while they are still alive."</p>

<p>Einav Tzangauker, whose son Matan is among the hostages, was among those protesting against Netanyahu in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"If it is possible to replace a defence minister in the middle of a war, then it is surely possible to replace a prime minister who is unqualified to bring back the hostages," she told Israel's Channel 12.</p>

<p>Netanyahu "is intentionally endangering Israel's security and all that because of a dispute between him and Gallant on how to continue the war," she added.</p>

<p>The war erupted on October 7, 2023 after Palestinian militants attacked Israel, resulting in 1,206 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed 43,391 people in Gaza, a majority of them civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>During the October 7 attack, Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, of whom 97 are still in Gaza. The Israeli military says 34 of them are dead.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3tqgtcfg_tel-aviv-protests_625x300_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli protestors block a road in Tel Aviv after the dismissal of the defence minister Yoav Gallant.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-leads-in-red-states-of-indiana-and-kentucky-as-counting-of-votes-begins-for-us-elections-6953293]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Leads In 10 States, Projected To Win 101 Electoral Votes, Harris Trails]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-leads-in-red-states-of-indiana-and-kentucky-as-counting-of-votes-begins-for-us-elections-6953293]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 05:15:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Counting has begun for the US elections and Donald Trump has been announced the winner in the Red states of Indiana and Kentucky and Kamala Harris in the Blue state of Vermont by American networks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Counting has begun for the US elections; US networks have projected that Donald Trump is winning 10 states and Kamala Harris is winning five.&nbsp;&nbsp;As for electoral college numbers, which will determine the winner in this election, the former President is ahead with 101 votes and Harris trails with 71. Each candidate is aiming for the magic figure of 270 electoral college votes.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">These projections are from partisan states that have historically voted either Democratic or Republican and do not include the seven battleground or swing states that hold the key to this election.</p>

<p>The seven swing or battleground states of Pennsylvania, Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina and Wisconsin are expected to effectively decide who will be the 47th President of the United States. The contest between Trump and Harris has been a fiercely fought one and both sides appeared to be in a dead heat even on Tuesday, which was the day of voting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Exit polls showed that the state of democracy and the economy, and abortion were the most important issues for American voters heading into the election. A poll conducted by CBS News revealed that almost six in 10 people ranked the state of democracy as their number one issue, followed by abortion, which was picked by five per cent of voters as an important issue. Economy was picked as a priority issue by one in ten.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An exit poll by CNN said nearly three-quarters of the electorate holds a negative view of the way things are going in the US today. Only about a quarter said they were enthusiastic or satisfied with the state of the nation, with more than four in 10 dissatisfied and roughly 30% saying they are angry, according to the poll.</p>

<p><em>(With PTI inputs)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4supmdv8_trump-afp_650x400_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump is also leading in the swing state of Georgia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-israel-katz-the-new-israeli-defence-minister-6953233]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Israel Katz, The New Israeli Defence Minister?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-israel-katz-the-new-israeli-defence-minister-6953233]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 04:52:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel Katz, formerly Israel's foreign minister, has been appointed defence minister after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sacked Yoav Gallant from the post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Israel Katz, formerly Israel's foreign minister, has been appointed defence minister after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sacked Yoav Gallant from the post.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said he no longer had trust in Gallant's management of Israel's military operations, which include an ongoing war in Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p>Below are some facts about Katz:</p>

<p>* Born in 1955 in the Israeli coastal city of Ashkelon, Katz was drafted into the military in 1973 and served as a paratrooper, leaving the service in 1977. He has not served in any senior military command position, unlike his predecessor Gallant, who had been a general before becoming defence minister in 2022.</p>

<p>* Katz, a member of Netanyahu's right-wing Likud party, has been a member of the Knesset (parliament) since 1998. In the Knesset, he served on several committees including those covering foreign affairs, defence and justice.</p>

<p>* He has held several ministerial posts in the past two decades, including agriculture, transport, intelligence, finance and energy portfolios. He was appointed foreign minister in 2019.</p>

<p>* As foreign minister, Katz declared Antonio Guterres persona non grata in October over what he said was the U.N. secretary-general's failure to "unequivocally" condemn Iran's missile attack on Israel and for what he described as antisemitic and anti-Israel conduct.</p>

<p>* Also in October, he ordered his ministry to start legal proceedings against French President Emmanuel Macron after Paris banned Israeli firms from participating in an upcoming military naval trade show.</p>

<p>* Katz has been a low profile figure in Israeli-U.S. interactions during U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken's 11 trips to Israel since Oct. 7, 2023. The top U.S. diplomat has held only a few meetings with Katz, while Blinken regularly met with Gallant.</p>

<p>* Katz studied as an undergraduate and graduate at Israel's Hebrew University. He is married with two children.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n6di67mg_israel-katz_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel Katz has been appointed defence minister Netanyahu sacked Yoav Gallant from the post.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-raises-claim-of-massive-cheating-in-us-city-of-philadelphia-6953204]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Alleges "Massive Cheating" In Key Swing State Of Pennsylvania]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-raises-claim-of-massive-cheating-in-us-city-of-philadelphia-6953204]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 04:40:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump sought to undermine Tuesday the credibility of voting in the biggest city of must-win Pennsylvania, a soundly Democratic area that was part of the ex-president's unsupported 2020 fraud claims.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump sought to undermine Tuesday the credibility of voting in the biggest city of must-win Pennsylvania, a soundly Democratic area that was part of the ex-president's unsupported 2020 fraud claims.</p>

<p>Amid reports of exceptionally high voter turnout in Philadelphia, Trump said there was "a lot of talk about massive cheating" in the city, as an official promptly denied the claim, calling it "yet another example of disinformation."</p>

<p>"Law enforcement coming!!" Trump wrote on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>He provided no evidence to support his claim made as Americans voted in a tense election that polls have suggested is effectively tied between Trump and Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>"There is absolutely no truth to this allegation," said City Commissioner Seth Bluestein, a Republican.</p>

<p>"Voting in Philadelphia has been safe and secure."</p>

<p>Philadelphia police did not immediately reply to a request for comment on Trump's claim.</p>

<p>Trump rejected his loss in the 2020 election to Joe Biden, a denial that culminated with supporters of the ex-reality TV star violently attacking the US Capitol in a bid to block certification of the vote.</p>

<p>Trump is expected to reject the result if he loses again this year, raising the specter of chaos and violence in an already tense and deeply polarized United States.</p>

<p>The Republican has already started raising questions about the integrity of the vote in Pennsylvania, a battleground state that is a key prize in the battle for the White House.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania's Democratic Governor Josh Shapiro, in a CNN interview last week, rejected Trump's allegations, noting that as the state's attorney general Shapiro defeated 43 challenges to the 2020 vote count from the ex-president and his allies.</p>

<p>When asked Tuesday whether he would accept defeat in the 2024 election, Trump offered a qualified response.</p>

<p>"If I lose an election, if it's a fair election, I would be the first one to acknowledge it. So far I think it's been fair," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-05/6c9i4ep8_donald-trump-reuters-650_625x300_06_May_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential Election: Donald Trump provided no evidence to support his claim.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-donald-trump-kamala-harris-over-70-of-voters-not-happy-with-how-things-are-going-in-us-exit-polls-6953111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 70% Of Voters Not Happy With How Things Are Going In US: Exit Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-donald-trump-kamala-harris-over-70-of-voters-not-happy-with-how-things-are-going-in-us-exit-polls-6953111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 04:33:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The state of democracy, the shape of the economy and abortion are the most important issues for American voters in the US presidential election, according to the first wave of exit polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The state of democracy, the shape of the economy and abortion are the most important issues for American voters in the US presidential election, according to the first wave of exit polls.</p>

<p>Almost six in 10 people ranked the state of democracy as their number one issue, according to polls released by CBS News.</p>

<p>It was followed by abortion as five per cent of the voters felt it was an important issue for them. Over one in 10 chose the economy as a priority issue.</p>

<p>Millions of Americans voted to elect the 47th President between Republican leader Donald Trump and Democratic nominee Kamala Harris in an election billed as one of the most consequential contests for the White House in decades.</p>

<p>An exit poll by CNN said roughly three-quarters of the electorate holds a negative view of the way things are going in the US today.</p>

<p>Only about one-quarter call themselves enthusiastic or satisfied with the state of the nation, with more than four in 10 dissatisfied and roughly three in 10 saying they are angry, according to the poll.</p>

<p>Voters remain generally optimistic, with more than 6 in 10 saying that America's best days are in the future, and only about one-third said that they're already in the past, the CNN poll found.</p>

<p>It said President Joe Biden's approval rating is sliding nationally with about 4 in 10 voters saying they approve of his job performance and a majority disapproving.</p>

<p>The race between Harris and Trump remained stubbornly deadlocked for weeks with some of the election forecasters giving 60-year-old Vice President Harris an edge over former President Trump, 78, in some of the key battleground states like Pennsylvania.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bmajv4lg_us-election_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Almost six in 10 people ranked the state of democracy as their number one issue.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-is-sued-over-1-million-election-giveaway-6953144]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Is Sued Over $1 Million Election Giveaway]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-is-sued-over-1-million-election-giveaway-6953144]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 04:29:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk was sued in a proposed class action on Tuesday by registered voters who signed his petition to support the Constitution for a chance to win his $1 million-a-day giveaway, and now claim it was a fraud.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk was sued in a proposed class action on Tuesday by registered voters who signed his petition to support the Constitution for a chance to win his $1 million-a-day giveaway, and now claim it was a fraud.</p>

<p>The complaint filed by Arizona resident Jacqueline McAferty in the Austin, Texas federal court said Musk and his America PAC organization falsely induced voters to sign by claiming they would choose winners randomly, though they were predetermined.</p>

<p>She also said the defendants profited from the giveaway by driving traffic and attention to Musk's X social media platform, and by collecting personal information such as her name, address and phone number that they could sell.</p>

<p>A lawyer for Musk and lawyers for McAferty did not immediately respond to requests for comment on the complaint.</p>

<p>McAferty sued one day after a Philadelphia judge denied a request by that city's district attorney Larry Krasner to end the giveaway, which Krasner called an illegal lottery.</p>

<p>That ruling was largely symbolic because Musk has no plans to give out more money following the U.S. presidential election.</p>

<p>The world's richest person opened the giveaway to voters in seven battleground states who signed a petition to support free speech and gun rights. Tuesday's lawsuit seeks at least $5 million in damages for everyone who signed.</p>

<p>Musk is a Texas resident and his electric car company Tesla is based in Austin.</p>

<p>He has supported Republican Donald Trump in the presidential race against Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>The case is McAferty v Musk et al, U.S. District Court, Western District of Texas, No. 24-01346.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vvhbh134_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has supported Republican Donald Trump in the presidential race against Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-three-quarters-of-us-voters-believe-democracy-is-under-threat-show-exit-polls-news-agency-reuters-6953080]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Most US Voters Believe Democracy Is Under Threat: Exit Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-three-quarters-of-us-voters-believe-democracy-is-under-threat-show-exit-polls-news-agency-reuters-6953080]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 04:04:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nearly three-quarters of voters in Tuesday's presidential election believe American democracy is under threat, according to national exit poll data from Edison Research]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nearly three-quarters of voters in Tuesday's presidential election believe American democracy is under threat, according to national exit poll data from Edison Research, reflecting the deep anxiety that the nation faces after a contentious campaign between Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Democracy and the economy ranked by far as the most important issues for voters, followed by abortion and immigration, the data showed. The poll showed 73% of voters believed democracy was in jeopardy, against just 25% who said it was secure.</p>

<p>The figures reflect just a slice of the tens of millions of people who have voted, both before and on Election Day, and the preliminary results are subject to change through the course of the night as more people are surveyed.</p>

<p>The two rivals were hurtling toward an uncertain finish after a dizzying campaign as millions of American voters waited in calm, orderly lines on Tuesday to choose between two sharply different visions for the country.</p>

<p>A race churned by unprecedented events - two assassination attempts against Trump, President Joe Biden's surprise withdrawal and Harris' rapid rise - remained neck and neck after billions of dollars in spending and months of frenetic campaigning.</p>

<p>Trump, who has frequently spread false claims that he won the 2020 presidential election against Biden and whose supporters attacked the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021, voted near his home in Palm Beach, Florida.</p>

<p>"If I lose an election, if it's a fair election, I'm gonna be the first one to acknowledge it," Trump told reporters.</p>

<p>Harris, who had earlier sent in her ballot by mail to her home state of California, spent some of Tuesday in radio interviews encouraging listeners to vote. Later, she was due to address students Howard University, a historically Black college in Washington where Harris was an undergraduate.</p>

<p>"To go back tonight to Howard University, my beloved alma mater, and be able to hopefully recognize this day for what it is is really full circle for me," Harris said on a radio interview.</p>

<p>National exit-poll results provide an important window into the thinking of the nation, but may not directly align with the seven battleground states expected to decide the presidential election.</p>

<p>Exit polls capture variations among turnout in various demographic groups, such as men vs women voters or college-educated vs non-college educated voters, and can provide insights into how turnout has changed from past elections.</p>

<p>One key advantage of exit polls is all the people surveyed, by definition, are people who cast ballots in this election.</p>

<p>Opinion polls before the election showed the candidates running neck and neck in each of the seven states likely to determine the winner: Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>No matter who wins, history will be made.</p>

<p>Harris, 60, the first female vice president, would become the first woman, Black woman and South Asian American to win the presidency. Trump, 78, the only president to be impeached twice and the first former president to be criminally convicted, would also become the first president to win non-consecutive terms in more than a century.</p>

<p>The contest reflects a deeply polarized nation whose divisions have only grown starker during a fiercely competitive race. Trump has employed increasingly dark and apocalyptic rhetoric on the campaign trail. Harris has urged Americans to come together, warning that a second Trump term would threaten the underpinnings of American democracy.</p>

<p>Control of both chambers of Congress is also up for grabs. Republicans have an easier path in the U.S. Senate, where Democrats are defending several seats in Republican-leaning states, while the House of Representatives looks like a toss-up.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g4b3a7o_kamala-harris-donald-trump_650x400_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[National exit poll data from Edison Research showed 73% of voters believed democracy was in jeopardy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-if-history-is-any-indicator-tim-walz-on-donald-trump-accepting-election-results-6952928]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If History Any Indicator...": Tim Walz On Trump Accepting Election Results]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-if-history-is-any-indicator-tim-walz-on-donald-trump-accepting-election-results-6952928]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 03:24:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, the running mate of Vice President Kamala Harris, expressed optimism that former President Donald Trump will accept the election results even if he loses, CNN reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, the running mate of Vice President Kamala Harris, expressed optimism that former President Donald Trump will accept the election results even if he loses, CNN reported.</p>

<p>When asked by reporters before Walz boarded his flight from Pennsylvania to Washington, DC, on Tuesday if he believes Trump will concede the election if he loses, Walz said he believes Trump will concede, if "history is ... any indicator".</p>

<p>Walz also pledged to "shake hands and work for the winner" if Harris loses.</p>

<p>This statement comes amidst concerns over potential disruptions to the electoral process, including bomb threats to polling locations across several states.</p>

<p>Trump and other Republicans repeatedly suggested they would accept the results of the presidential election if there was no evidence of fraud, as per CNN. Trump spread false claims of voter fraud during the 2020 presidential election as a pretence to attempt to overthrow the results of the election.</p>

<p>Walz said he did not speak to Harris in the last 24 hours but praised her remarks at her final campaign rally in Philadelphia on Monday, as per CNN.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, talking about the bomb threats in various polling locations, the Federal Bureau of Investigation said on Tuesday (local time) that bomb threats to polling locations across several states appear to have originated from Russian email domains. The FBI added that none of the emails were credible threats, as per CNN.</p>

<p>"The FBI is aware of bomb threats to polling locations in several states, many of which appear to originate from Russian email domains. None of the threats have been determined to be credible thus far," CNN quoted the agency's statement.</p>

<p>US intelligence officials were examining an email account using a Russian internet domain as the potential source of non-credible bomb threats made when Georgia went to polls on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Several non-credible bomb threats briefly disrupted voting at two polling places in Georgia, Georgia Secretary of State Brad Raffensperger, as per CNN.</p>

<p>"We've heard some threats that were of Russian origin. I don't know how to describe that that's viable - we don't think they are, but in the interest of public safety, we always check that out, and we'll just continue to be very responsible when we hear about stuff like that," Raffensperger said. "We identified the source, and it was from Russia," CNN quoted him as saying.</p>

<p>The presidential race between Harris and Trump is going down to the wire, with more states functionally tied in polls at this point than in any comparable election. Over 77.3 million people have now voted ahead of Election Day on Tuesday, just over half of the total ballots cast in 2020.</p>

<p>The battleground states of Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin are expected to be pivotal to the path to victory.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump tied with three votes each in the tiny New Hampshire community of Dixville Notch, which opened and closed its poll just after midnight ET in a decades-old tradition.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/18o8b2h_tim-walz_625x300_30_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The presidential race between Harris and Trump is going down to the wire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fake-bomb-threats-linked-to-russia-briefly-close-georgia-polling-locations-6952493]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fake Bomb Threats Linked To Russia Briefly Close Georgia Polling Locations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fake-bomb-threats-linked-to-russia-briefly-close-georgia-polling-locations-6952493]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 01:43:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least two polling sites in the US election battleground state of Georgia were briefly evacuated on Tuesday after fake bomb threats that election officials in the state blamed on Russian agents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least two polling sites in the US election battleground state of Georgia were briefly evacuated on Tuesday after fake bomb threats that election officials in the state blamed on Russian agents.</p>

<p>The threats, which were deemed to be non-credible, caused two polling locations in Fulton County, Georgia, to be evacuated. Both reopened after about 30 minutes, officials said, and the county is seeking a court order to extend the location's voting hours past the statewide 7 pm deadline.</p>

<p>Republican Georgia Secretary of State Brad Raffensperger said Russian interference was behind the Election Day bomb hoaxes.</p>

<p>"They're up to mischief, it seems. They don't want us to have a smooth, fair and accurate election, and if they can get us to fight among ourselves, they can count that as a victory," Raffensperger told reporters.</p>

<p>The Russian embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>In a statement, the FBI said it was aware of non-credible bomb threats to polling locations in several states, with many of them originating from Russian email domains.</p>

<p>Georgia alone received more than two dozen phony bomb threats on Election Day, most of which occurred in Fulton County, an FBI official said.</p>

<p>A senior official in Raffensperger's office, speaking on the condition of anonymity to speak freely, said the Georgia bomb hoaxes were sent from email addresses that had been used by Russians trying to interfere in previous US elections.</p>

<p>The threats were sent to US media and the two polling locations, the official said. "It's a likelihood it's Russia," the official said.</p>

<p>Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris and Republican former President Donald Trump are locked in a tight race to win the White House. Opinion polls suggest the contest is too close to call.</p>

<p>The phony bomb threats mark the latest in a string of examples of alleged interference by the Russians in the 2024 election.</p>

<p>On Nov. 1, US intelligence officials warned that Russian actors manufactured a video that falsely depicted Haitians illegally casting ballots in Georgia. Intelligence officials also found that the Russians created a separate phony video which falsely accused someone associated with the Harris presidential ticket of taking a bribe from an entertainer.</p>

<p>US intelligence officials have also accused Russia of interfering in previous US presidential elections, especially the 2016 race which Trump won against Democratic candidate Hillary Clinton.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vrolrrl_us-voting_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The polling locations reopened after about 30 minutes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-warns-of-bomb-threats-from-russia-at-us-voting-sites-6952597]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Warns Of Bomb Threats From Russia At US Voting Sites]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-warns-of-bomb-threats-from-russia-at-us-voting-sites-6952597]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 01:21:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The FBI warned of bomb threats at polling stations in "multiple" US states on Election Day, adding that none were credible but many appeared to originate from Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FBI warned of bomb threats at polling stations in "multiple" US states on Election Day, adding that none were credible but many appeared to originate from Russia.</p>

<p>The statement from the Federal Bureau of Investigation came as authorities in the US state of Georgia said bomb threats had briefly disrupted voting there Tuesday.</p>

<p>The 2024 US presidential campaign has been a particularly volatile one, and security for Election Day had been ramped up to unprecedented levels given concerns over possible civil unrest, election chicanery and violence against poll workers.</p>

<p>"The FBI is aware of bomb threats to polling locations in several states, many of which appear to originate from Russian email domains," spokeswoman Savannah Syms said in a statement.</p>

<p>"None of the threats have been determined to be credible thus far," she added, urging the public to "remain vigilant."</p>

<p>Georgia's secretary of state Brad Raffensperger said the state had also identified the source of bomb threats that briefly disrupted voting at polling places there, "and it was from Russia."</p>

<p>He did not elaborate. An election official in Georgia's Fulton County said polling places were briefly closed as the threats were investigated.</p>

<p>With Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump deadlocked at the climax of the 2024 race, authorities are keen to reassure jittery Americans that their votes are secure. But they are also bolstering physical security for election operations nationwide.</p>

<p>Runbeck Election Services, which provides security technology for poll operations, confirmed to AFP Monday it had ordered some 1,000 panic buttons for clients that include election facilities and their workers.</p>

<p>The FBI has set up a national election command post in Washington to monitor threats 24 hours a day through election week, and security has been bolstered at many of the nearly 100,000 US polling stations.</p>

<p>The states of Oregon, Washington and Nevada have activated the National Guard -- and the Pentagon says at least 17 states have placed a total of 600 National Guard troops on standby if needed.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/31pof5s8_fbi-generic_625x300_16_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The FBI has set up a national election command post in Washington to monitor threats 24 hours a day.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-kamala-harris-donald-trump-who-is-winning-the-us-election-right-now-6952499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump vs Kamala Harris: Who Is Winning The US Election Right Now?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-kamala-harris-donald-trump-who-is-winning-the-us-election-right-now-6952499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:58:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Polling aggregator FiveThirtyEight has named Kamala Harris as its favourite to win, switching from Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-live-updates-its-over-to-voters-as-america-decides-between-kamala-harris-and-donald-trump-6948523">have voted</a> in one of the most consequential elections in the history of the United States and while most polls showed Kamala Harris and Donald Trump in a dead heat, polling aggregator FiveThirtyEight has named the Democratic nominee as its favourite to win, switching from the Republican candidate.</p>

<p>The aggregator, which is a key election forecaster, had Mr Trump as its favourite to win for around two weeks and its simulations showed that, out of 100, Mr Trump won 53 times and Ms Harris 47. In a first since October 17, however, Ms Harris became the favourite on election day, leading Mr Trump in simulations 50 to 49.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Economist's final forecast said Ms Harris has a 56% chance of winning, but noted that the lead is narrow and Mr Trump could also win.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Polymarket, a betting platform, said former president Trump has a 62.3% chance of winning against Vice President Harris' 37.9%.</p>

<p>Speaking to NDTV on Tuesday, Allan Lichtman, known for his 13 'Keys to the White House' system, predicted Ms Harris will be the first woman president of the United States.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Consign them (opinion polls) to the flames. Yes, we are going to have Kamala Harris, a new path-breaking president, the first woman president and the first president of mixed African and Asian descent. It is foreshadowing where America is going. We are rapidly becoming a majority-minority country old white guys like me, we are on the decline," Mr Lichtman said.</p>

<p><strong>'If It Is Fair"</strong></p>

<p>Both candidates also spoke to the media on election day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We've got to get it done. Today is voting day, and people need to get out and be active," Ms Harris told Atlanta station WVEE-FM, describing Mr Trump as "full of vengeance. He's full of grievance. It's all about himself."</p>

<p>The former president, who voted near his Mar-a-Lago residence in Florida, said he felt "very confident" and that he wanted to be "very inclusive." But he aired concerns about the vote count - heightening fears that he would reject the result, citing fraud, if he lost. "If it's a fair election, I would be the first one to acknowledge it," he said.</p>

<p>In the most important swing state of Pennsylvania, a court approved a request to extend voting hours in a county after voting machines experienced a software glitch.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ruling means that voting will stay open for an additional two hours in Cambria county, which broke roughly 70% to 30% in favour of Mr Trump in 2020. The case was brought by the local board of elections, which said a "software malfunction" at electronic voting machines had "prevented voters from scanning their completed ballots". &nbsp;The Cambria County Court of Common Pleas ordered that voting hours be extended from 8pm to 10pm local time (0830 IST).&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This morning's ballot processing issues in Cambria have resulted in delays - this is unacceptable, plain and simple," Republican National Committee chairman Michael Whatley said after the case was filed. &nbsp;"Our legal team acted immediately to support extended hours to give voters the opportunity to vote - we need voters to stay in line!" he added.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/njs5i84o_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polymarket, a betting platform, said former president Trump has a 62.3% chance of winning.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/track-live-us-election-updates-on-your-iphone-lock-screen-heres-how-6952292]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Track Live US Election Updates On Your iPhone Lock Screen. Here's How]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/track-live-us-election-updates-on-your-iphone-lock-screen-heres-how-6952292]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:01:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Americans begin to cast their ballots to elect their next president, Apple News will bring live updates to iPhone and iPad users' lock screens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Americans begin to cast their ballots to elect their next president, Apple News will bring live updates to iPhone and iPad users' lock screens.</p>

<p>Starting late on Tuesday (US time), users will be able to have a Live Activity from Apple News that tracks the results of the election, reports Apple Insider.</p>

<p>"The Lock Screen will have a large, interactive widget that will launch to the latest election coverage, and the Dynamic Island will show the electoral count for each candidate continuously," the report mentioned.</p>

<p>If you have the newer version of iPhone, you can keep tabs on the electoral count right in the Dynamic Island while doing other things on your phone.</p>

<p>The widget will be available on iPhones, iPads, and Apple watches as votes in the US presidential and congressional elections are counted.</p>

<p>It'll show the electoral count for Republican Donald Trump and Democrat Kamala Harris, as well as Senate and House election results.</p>

<p>To get the updates on lock screen, the iPhone user needs to register. Open up Apple News and tap on the "Follow the 2024 election live" banner.</p>

<p>According to the report, Live Activities will appear on iPhone and iPad Lock Screens, but only devices with a Dynamic Island will get the special user interface (UI).</p>

<p>Apple Watch can show Live Activity data in the widget view as well.</p>

<p>Apple originally introduced Live Activities to take advantage of the Dynamic Island and present live, updated information to the user.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, more than 82 million voters had already cast their ballot in early voting either in-person or by post. This is more than 51 per cent of 158 million votes cast in the 2020 election.</p>

<p>If Harris prevails, she will become the first woman to win the presidency, and the first African American woman, the first Asian American and the first Indian American to rise to the top of American politics. If Trump wins, he will become only the second president in US history to lose the re-election after the first term and then win on the third try. The first was Grover Cleveland.</p>

<p>The winner must secure at least 270 of the 538 electoral college votes.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/34pgh3lg_apple-news-_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Apple User needs to tap on the "Follow the 2024 election live" banner.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-netanyahu-fires-defence-minister-yoav-gallant-amid-war-6952286]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Fires Defence Minister Yoav Gallant Amid Middle East Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-netanyahu-fires-defence-minister-yoav-gallant-amid-war-6952286]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Tuesday dismissed Defence Minister Yoav Gallant over a breakdown in trust during the Gaza war against Hamas, his office said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu fired defence minister Yoav Gallant Tuesday following public differences over the ongoing war in Gaza, replacing him with former top diplomat Israel Katz.</p>

<p>The surprise move to sack Gallant -- who has been hawkish on Israel's war with Hezbollah but has also recently urged a ceasefire and hostage release deal in Gaza -- comes as elections are held in the United States, Israel's top military backer.</p>

<p>Netanyahu and Gallant have frequently clashed over Israel's retaliatory military offensive against Hamas following the Palestinian militant group's deadly attack on Israel on October 7 last year.</p>

<p>"Over the past few months... trust has eroded. In light of this, I decided today to end the term of the defence minister," a statement from the Netanyahu's office said, adding that he had appointed Katz to take his place.</p>

<p>Gideon Saar was in turn appointed to replace Katz as foreign minister.</p>

<p>After his sacking, Gallant said Israel's security would remain his life's "mission".</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed 43,391 people in Gaza, a majority of them civilians, according to Gaza health ministry figures which the United Nations considers to be reliable.</p>

<p>- Rockets and drones -<br />
From the air and on the ground, Israeli forces pressed their multi-front campaign Tuesday against militants more than a year after the Gaza war began.</p>

<p>Authorities in Lebanon reported deadly raids across the country. The health ministry said an Israeli attack on the coastal town of Jiyeh south of Beirut killed one person and wounded 20.</p>

<p>A security source, speaking on condition of anonymity, said an apartment used by Hezbollah had been the target.</p>

<p>The strike destroyed the top floor of a four-storey complex, an AFP correspondent said.</p>

<p>Air raids also hit southern Lebanon and the eastern Bekaa Valley, Lebanon's official National News Agency reported.</p>

<p>The NNA reported that the Lebanese Red Cross and the army had recovered seven bodies from a village in the southern region of Tyre following recent heavy raids.</p>

<p>Hezbollah on Tuesday claimed it had fired rockets and drones into northern Israel, and also targeted Israeli troops near the border inside Lebanon.</p>

<p>Tuesday's fighting came more than a month into the Hezbollah-Israel war which has left at least 1,964 dead in Lebanon since September 23, according to an AFP tally of health ministry figures.</p>

<p>In neighbouring Syria, close to the border with Lebanon, the town of Al-Qusayr came under air attack for the second time in a week.</p>

<p>Israel's military said it carried out "an intelligence-based strike on weapons storage facilities used by Hezbollah's munitions unit".</p>

<p>Syria's official SANA news agency said the industrial zone in Al-Qusayr was hit and Israel "also targeted some residential buildings surrounding the industrial zone".</p>

<p>SANA did not report any casualties.</p>

<p>- West Bank deaths -<br />
In the West Bank, which has seen spiralling violence since the October 7 attack on Israel, Palestinian officials said Israeli forces killed seven Palestinians in separate operations.</p>

<p>The Israeli military told AFP it had targeted "terrorists".</p>

<p>Israeli troops or settlers have killed at least 757 Palestinians in the West Bank since the start of the Gaza war, according to the Ramallah-based health ministry.</p>

<p>Palestinian attacks on Israelis have also killed at least 24 people in the same period in the West Bank, according to official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Palestinians in Gaza told AFP that whoever wins Tuesday's presidential election in the United States must end the conflict in the territory.</p>

<p>"We are hanging by a thread, and like every other people in the world, we are looking for someone who can stop the war," said Ayman al-Omreiti, 45, in Gaza City.</p>

<p>"Our hope is that the American people will choose someone who can end the suffering of the Palestinian people."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7cr3fg3g_benjamin-netanyahu-yoav-gallant_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Netanyahu added he had appointed Foreign Minister Israel Katz to take his place. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-amid-inflation-rising-fuel-prices-voters-head-to-las-vegas-6952240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Inflation, Rising Fuel Prices, Voters Head To Las Vegas Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-amid-inflation-rising-fuel-prices-voters-head-to-las-vegas-6952240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 23:51:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Inflation, the cost of gasoline and food, rising rents: for Las Vegas voters heading to the polls on Tuesday to choose between Donald Trump and Kamala Harris, the cost of living was paramount.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inflation, the cost of gasoline and food, rising rents: for Las Vegas voters heading to the polls on Tuesday to choose between Donald Trump and Kamala Harris, the cost of living was paramount.</p>

<p>"Here, since COVID, the cost of living has gone out of control," said Lee Lovett, who works in a video equipment store in the city.</p>

<p>"There's people that they have to live three people to a household... because they can't afford to have a home on their own. Young married couples can't afford to live by themselves."</p>

<p>Las Vegas is the biggest city -- and biggest concentration of votes -- in must-win Nevada, one of seven battleground states that are expected to determine the election winner.</p>

<p>Its economy is almost entirely dependent on entertainment, such as sporting events, glitzy shows, quickie weddings and casinos.</p>

<p>All of it came to a shuddering halt during the pandemic, leaving tens of thousands of people with virtually no income.</p>

<p>When the economy reopened, the inflation that plagued the rest of the country was very keenly felt here, with rocketing rents and soaring grocery bills that have left many people struggling.</p>

<p>Michael Pidding, a military veteran who moved to Las Vegas seven years seeking somewhere cheaper to live than his former home of Seattle, looks back fondly on the pre-pandemic times.</p>

<p>He told AFP he is voting to go back to the Trump years.</p>

<p>"I lived through the four years that he was in office before and everything was low," the 79-year-old said.</p>

<p>"Gas prices were low, groceries, everything, the economy was roaring."</p>

<p>It's economics that have led 18-year-old Amy Rivera to her decision but a different one.</p>

<p>Heading to her first presidential election wrapped in a US flag, the young Latina says she will be casting her ballot for Harris.</p>

<p>"She promises incentives for people who are going to buy a house for the first time, something that my brother and I want to do one day, as well as helping students with their college payments."</p>

<p>A recent survey by Emerson College found that for 37 percent of potential voters in Nevada, the economy was the most important issue, while housing was the second.</p>

<p>- 'Promises' -</p>

<p>Democrats have won Nevada in the last four presidential elections, although with increasingly narrow margins.</p>

<p>Joe Biden bagged its six electoral college votes with a wafer-thin majority of 33,500 votes in 2020.</p>

<p>Pollsters are predicting another photo finish this time around, with the state in a technical tie after months of frenzied campaigning by both sides, including multiple visits from Harris and Trump.</p>

<p>Both have pledged to get rid of taxes on tips -- a measure that is popular in a place where the service industry is such a large employer.</p>

<p>For Gina Sanders, who works in a casino and voted for Harris on Tuesday, it is vital that whoever wins sticks to this pledge.</p>

<p>"The most important thing is... each candidate just needs to deliver on their promises," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/uimr6v9o_us-election-when-where-and-how-to-vote_625x300_05_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Las Vegas is the biggest city, and biggest concentration of votes, in must-win Nevada. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-america-elects-47th-us-president-election-result-today-6952139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris vs Trump - America Elects 47th US President. Election Result Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-america-elects-47th-us-president-election-result-today-6952139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 23:40:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The wait to know who will win - Kamala Harris or Donald Trump - is nearly over. Americans have decided who their next President will be.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The wait to know who will win - Kamala Harris or Donald Trump - is nearly over. Americans have decided who their next President will be. After a months-long, bitterly-contested election campaign, dozens of millions of citizens across the United States voted today. The counting of votes happens immediately after voting ends.</p>

<p>Voting began across the country at 6 am local time in each time zone and will end at 8 pm local time. The US has six time zones, of which four are on the US mainland while two are in US territories across the globe. The four main time zones are Eastern, Central, Mountain, and Pacific Standard Time, while the two other time zones include Alaska Standard Time and Hawaii-Aleutian Standard Time, which are observed only by Alaska and Hawaii respectively.</p>

<p>The US Presidential election is closely watched around the world as US's policies have for long had a big impact on other countries. The 2024 US presidential election has been extraordinary in terms of political discourse reaching new lows.</p>

<p>During the election campaign that lasted several months, America and the rest of the planet witnessed an ugly and divisive contest - that saw personal attacks, derogatory language, racist slurs, inflammatory rhetoric and even assassination attempts.</p>

<h2><strong>WHO HAS THE EDGE?</strong></h2>

<p>The latest opinion polls suggest that Kamala Harris has a razor thin lead over Donald Trump - 1 percentage point. However, if the electorate is seen in terms of gender, as per the latest Reuters/Ipsos polls, Kamala Harris has a 12 percentage point lead over Trump among women, while Trump has a 7 percentage point lead over Harris among men.</p>

<p>For those backing Kamala Harris, her promise to protect abortion rights was one of the most compelling reasons to vote for her. The perception that Donald Trump, who made racist and offensive remarks, also played a part in those voting against him.</p>

<p>For those backing Donald Trump, a strict immigration system was one of the topmost reasons for supporting him. High inflation and concerns about the economy during the Biden term in which Kamala Harris was the Vice President were among the reasons to vote against the Democrat nominee.</p>

<p>The election has been very close and both candidates have been neck and neck in the race. While Harris might have a 1 percentage point lead over Trump, there is uncertainty of the final outcome.</p>

<h3><strong>HISTORY IN THE MAKING</strong></h3>

<p>No matter who wins, Harris or Trump, history will be made today.</p>

<p>If 60-year-old Kamala Harris, the first woman Vice President in US history, wins, she will become the first woman, first Black woman, first Indian-American, and first South Asian American to win the presidency.</p>

<p>On the other hand, if 78-year-old Donald Trump, the only US President to be impeached twice and the first to be criminally convicted, wins, he would become the first US President in more than a century to win non-consecutive terms.</p>

<h3><strong>UNDERSTANDING THE ELECTION</strong></h3>

<p>US follows the electoral college voting system. There are a total of 538 electoral college votes; 435 House of Representatives, 100 Senate seats and 3 seats from Washington DC. A candidate needs a minimum of 270 votes to become the President.</p>

<p>Every state has a certain number of electoral votes. California has the maximum number of seats with 54, followed by Texas (40) and Florida (30). On the other hand, states like North Dakota, South Dakota, Delaware, and Vermont have a minimum number of 3 seats.</p>

<p>Out of the total 50 states in USA, there are 7 which are considered battle ground states or swing states. These are crucial for both candidates as these seven states alone have the potential to decide on who will be the next President. These states are - Nevada (6 seats), Arizona (11 seats), North Carolina (16 seats), Georgia (16 seats), Wisconsin (10 seats), Michigan (15 seats), and Pennsylvania (19 seats).</p>

<p>More than 80 million Americans had already voted before the main election day (Nov 5), either via mail or in person, and lines at several polling stations on Tuesday morning were short and orderly.</p>

<p>Control of both chambers of Congress is also up for grabs. Republicans have an easier path in the U.S. Senate, where Democrats are defending several seats in Republican-leaning states, while the House of Representatives looks like a toss-up.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/uk9sorag_kamala-harris-donald-trump-reuters_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Americans have voted for their next President. Today's result will reveal who won - Harris or Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-conflict-palestinians-hope-the-new-us-president-calls-an-end-to-war-6952069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Palestinians In Gaza Hope New US President Calls An End To War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-conflict-palestinians-hope-the-new-us-president-calls-an-end-to-war-6952069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 23:21:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinians in war-ravaged Gaza told AFP on Tuesday that whoever emerges victorious in the US presidential election must end the conflict in the territory, which has taken an appalling human toll.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinians in war-ravaged Gaza told AFP on Tuesday that whoever emerges victorious in the US presidential election must end the conflict in the territory, which has taken an appalling human toll.</p>

<p>"We are hanging by a thread, and like every other people in the world, we are looking for someone who can stop the war," said Ayman al-Omreiti, 45, from Gaza City's Al-Daraj neighbourhood.</p>

<p>"Our hope is that the American people will choose someone who can end the suffering of the Palestinian people."</p>

<p>Millions of Americans began to cast their ballots on Tuesday in a contest that pre-election polling suggested was too close to call.</p>

<p>Omreiti, who has been displaced several times during the 13 months since the war broke out, said he hoped Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris would defeat Republican rival Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"The Palestinian people are worried about a possible Trump victory, and we hope the results will be favourable for his opponent, Harris, because she has called for an end to the war several times," he said.</p>

<p>Another Palestinian resident of Gaza City, Hani Ajur, is clear in his view: Whoever becomes president must end the war.</p>

<p>Ajur's son and brother were killed in the war, while his home was destroyed by Israeli shelling.</p>

<p>"We hope that after all these sacrifices... whoever wins, whether it is Trump or Harris, will put an end to this war and bring peace to the region," he said.</p>

<p>"We are exhausted with the bombings, the destruction, the martyrs, the wounded and the devastation. We're just tired of this life."</p>

<p>Recent polls in Israel show a majority of Israelis favour Trump, but photographer Andy Alpern's choice for the White House is Harris.</p>

<p>He said Trump "might give us more of a free hand (but) do I think it's worth it? I don't," Alpern, 57, who resides in Israeli-occupied Golan Heights said.</p>

<p>"I don't think Kamala is as bad as everyone thinks she is, and she will do good things."</p>

<p>But he hoped the United States would continue to support Israel to "rid Lebanon of Hezbollah and Gaza of Hamas".</p>

<p>"These are evil organisations," he said.</p>

<p>"They have just as much against America and the West as they do against us."</p>

<p>Israel has been fighting Hamas in Gaza since the Palestinian operator group launched a deadly attack on Israel on October 7 last year, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 43,391 Palestinians, most of them civilians, according to the territory's health ministry, figures considered reliable by the UN.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p5kd7dj_israeli-army-in-gaza_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We are exhausted with the bombings, the destruction," says Gaza resident. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-kamala-harris-urges-citizens-to-get-out-and-vote-on-election-day-6951984]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Urges Americans To "Get Out And Vote" On Election Day]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-kamala-harris-urges-citizens-to-get-out-and-vote-on-election-day-6951984]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 23:05:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris urged Americans to "get out and vote" on Election Day, particularly in battleground states, as her White House duel with Donald Trump reached its climax Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris urged Americans to "get out and vote" on Election Day, particularly in battleground states, as her White House duel with Donald Trump reached its climax Tuesday.</p>

<p>"We've got to get it done. Today is voting day, and people need to get out and be active," she said on Atlanta station WVEE-FM.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/io2k2jk8_kamala-harris-_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is in a tightly-contested race with Donald Trump. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-donald-trump-feels-very-confident-about-winning-back-the-white-house-amid-vote-6951918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says He Would Concede Defeat "If It's A Fair Election"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-donald-trump-feels-very-confident-about-winning-back-the-white-house-amid-vote-6951918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:50:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump feels "very confident" about winning back the White House, the Republican said Tuesday after casting his Election Day ballot in Florida in one of the most contentious US elections in decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump feels "very confident" about winning back the White House, the Republican said Tuesday after casting his Election Day ballot in Florida in one of the most contentious US elections in decades.</p>

<p>"I feel very confident," Trump told reporters at a voting facility in West Palm Beach, adding he believes he "ran a great campaign" against his Democratic rival Kamala Harris. Opinion polls show the race is a dead heat.</p>

<p>He also said he would be prepared to concede defeat after Tuesday's vote "if it's a fair election", while again raising concerns about the use of electronic voting machines.</p>

<p>"If I lose an election, if it's a fair election, I would be the first one to acknowledge it. So far I think it's been fair," Trump, repeating a caveat that he has used many times on the campaign trail, told reporters after voting in Florida.</p>

<p>Wearing a red "Make America Great Again" cap, he reiterated his previous criticism of electronic voting machines, suggesting they were less secure than paper ballots and would delay the outcome being known.</p>

<p>"They spend all this money on machines... If they would use paper ballots, voter ID, proof of citizenship, and one-day voting, it would all be over by 10 o'clock in the evening. It's crazy," he told reporters in West Palm Beach.</p>

<p>He added: "Do you know that paper is more sophisticated now than computers? If it's watermarked paper you cannot... It's unbelievable what happens with it. There's nothing you can do to cheat."</p>

<p>Asked about fears of unrest after the election and whether he would call on supporters to avoid violence, he criticized the question.</p>

<p>"I don't have to tell them that, that there'll be no violence. Of course there'll be no violence. My supporters are not violent people," Trump said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0baohu9g_donald-trump_625x300_03_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Republican candidate and Former President Donald Trump believes he ran a great campaign. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/how-the-cold-sore-virus-can-reach-and-infect-your-brain-6951887]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How The Cold Sore Virus Can Reach And Infect Your Brain]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/how-the-cold-sore-virus-can-reach-and-infect-your-brain-6951887]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:47:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The virus affects critical brain regions tied to sleep, mood, and hormonal control, potentially linking HSV-1 to neurodegenerative diseases.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1), which causes cold sores, has long been known to have effects on the brain and central nervous system.</p>

<p>Researchers from the University of Colorado and the University of Bourgogne in France have recently conducted <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://journals.asm.org/doi/10.1128/jvi.00968-24"><em>a study</em></a> that provides new information on how this virus spreads inside the brain.</p>

<p>Researchers mapped the areas affected by the virus by using mouse models to study how HSV-1 affected different parts of the brain. Their findings reveal that HSV-1 can access the central nervous system through two main pathways: the trigeminal nerve, which connects the face and brain, and the olfactory nerve, responsible for the sense of smell. Despite identifying these entry points, the exact mechanism of how HSV-1 spreads further within the brain remains unclear.</p>

<p>"Recently, this common virus has been implicated in neurodegenerative diseases, such as Alzheimer's disease, but no clear route of central nervous system invasion has been established," says Christy Niemeyer, PhD, assistant professor of neurology at the University of Colorado Anschutz Medical Campus and co-first and corresponding author. "Identifying how HSV-1 can get into the brain and what brain regions are vulnerable is key in understanding how it initiates disease."</p>

<p>Once HSV-1 enters the brain, researchers also wanted to determine if the virus migrates at random or to specific areas. They were able to map where and how the virus travels within the brain and infects critical brain regions that control many vital functions, such as the brain stem, which controls sleep and movement. Researchers also found HSV-1 in regions of the brain that produce serotonin and norepinephrine, as well as the hypothalamus, a critical center of appetite, sleep, mood, and hormonal control within the brain.</p>

<p>"Even though the presence of HSV-1 is not causing full-blown encephalitis in the brain, it can still affect how these regions function," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.cuanschutz.edu/news-stories/silent-intruder-how-the-cold-sore-virus-maps-its-way-through-the-brain"><em>says Niemeyer.</em></a></p>

<p>Niemeyer and coauthors also show how HSV-1 interacts with the brain's key immune cells; microglia. They found that microglia became "inflamed" when interacting with HSV-1, but in some brain regions, inflamed microglia persisted even after the virus was no longer detected.</p>

<p>"Identifying the role of microglia provides helpful clues to the consequences of HSV-1 infection, and how it triggers neurological diseases," says Niemeyer. "persistently inflamed cells can lead to chronic inflammation, a known trigger for a number of neurological and neurodegenerative diseases. This research offers important takeaways in better understanding how viruses interact with overall brain health as well as the onset of pervasive neurological diseases."</p>

<p>This study adds to the understanding of HSV-1's impact on the brain, a crucial step towards developing treatments to limit its effects on the nervous system.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gusq3f1o_brain_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[HSV-1 interacts with microglia, the brain's immune cells.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>