<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:58:21 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-have-improved-of-late-foreign-minister-s-jaishankar-briefs-parliament-7161483]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India-China Ties Have Improved Of Late": S Jaishankar In Parliament]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-have-improved-of-late-foreign-minister-s-jaishankar-briefs-parliament-7161483]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:12:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India-China ties - "abnormal" since April 2020, when the two militaries clashed in parts of eastern Ladakh, leading to fatalities on both sides for the first time in 45 years - have improved recently, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/india-china-ties" target="_blank">India-China ties</a> - "abnormal" since April 2020, when the two militaries clashed in parts of eastern Ladakh, leading to fatalities on both sides for the first time in 45 years - have improved recently, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told the Lok Sabha Tuesday, explaining that "continuous diplomatic engagement since then (has) set our ties in the direction of some improvement".</p>

<p>India remains committed, Mr Jaishankar said, to engaging with China "through bilateral talks to arrive at a fair, reasonable and mutually acceptable settlement for the border issue".</p>

<p>It is, however evident, he told Parliament, that management of border areas will require further attention in light of our recent experiences. He flagged three key principles to be observed in all circumstances.</p>

<p>The first is that both sides should strictly respect and observe the LAC. The second is that neither should attempt to unilaterally alter the status quo, and the third is that agreements and understandings reached in the past must be fully abided by in their entirety.</p>

<p>"Members will recall the amassing of a large number of troops by China along the LAC (Line of Actual Control) in eastern Ladakh in April-May 2020 resulted in face-offs with our forces at a number of points. The situation also led to disruption of patrolling activities," the EAM began his remarks.</p>

<p>"It is to the credit of our armed forces that despite logistical challenges, and the then prevailing Covid situation, they were able to counter-deploy rapidly and effectively," he said.</p>

<p>"While a determined counter-deployment of adequate capability was the immediate response, there was also the imperative of a diplomatic effort to defuse tensions and restore peace and tranquility."</p>

<p>That diplomatic effort, which included nearly two dozen rounds of talks between military commanders, the most recent on August 29, led to the October agreement, under which Indian and Chinese troops returned to positions, and resumed patrolling routes, prior to the April 2020 face-off.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-will-be-able-to-go-back-to-2020-patrolling-s-jaishankar-on-lac-border-row-6839082" target="_blank">"Back To 2020 Patrolling": S Jaishankar To NDTV On India-China Pact</a></p>

<p>Last week the government said that deal had been implemented as agreed.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/army-successfully-completes-patrolling-to-key-point-in-ladakhs-depsang-6944072" target="_blank">Army "Successfully" Completes Patrolling To Key Point In Depsang</a></p>

<p>The agreement - announced hours before Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia for a BRICS Summit at which China's Xi Jinping would also be present - was seen as a roadmap to restoration of peace and tranquility along the LAC, a status quo the Indian government has often spoken about as the first, and a necessary, step towards any normalisation of relations between the two countries.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-summit-brics-summit-russia-india-china-patrolling-agreement-pm-modi-xi-welcome-complete-disengagement-between-soldiers-al-6857182" target="_blank">PM Modi, Xi Welcome "Complete Disengagement" Along LAC</a></p>

<p>On that topic, Mr Jaishankar said the immediate priority - of disengagement of troops from friction points in eastern Ladakh, specifically in the Depsang and Demchok areas, had been "fully achieved".</p>

<p>The next priority is to consider de-escalation, which will address amassing of troops along the Line of Actual Control, which serves as the de facto international border, the External Affairs Minister said.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar's remarks came two weeks after Defence Minister Rajnath Singh met his Chinese counterpart,&nbsp;Dong Jun, for a first ministerial-level meet since the disengagement in eastern Ladakh.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-defence-ministers-to-meet-in-laos-rajnath-singh-dong-jun-meeting-post-disengagement-in-ladakh-7025414" target="_blank">India, China Defence Ministers' 1st High-Level Talks Post Disengagement</a></p>

<p>Mr Singh and Mr Dong, a former naval Commander appointed in December last year, met on the sidelines of a two-day, 10-nation ASEAN summit in Laos that began November 20.</p>

<p>Disenagement and patrolling in Depsang and Demchok follows similar positive actions on the north and south banks of the Pangong Lake in 2021, and in the contentious Gogra-Hot Springs area in September a year later. In each case the two sides withdrew to pre-April 2020 positions.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2e3a69s8_s-jaishankar-in-parliament_650x400_03_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Foreign Minister S Jaishankar spoke on the India-China border situation in the Lok Sabha.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-fbi-pick-kash-patel-plans-to-reshape-bureau-release-epstein-diddy-lists-7161417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Kash Patel, Trump's Pick As FBI Chief, Plans To Do After Taking Charge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-fbi-pick-kash-patel-plans-to-reshape-bureau-release-epstein-diddy-lists-7161417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:06:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kash Pate, President-elect Donald Trumps nominee to lead the FBI, has pledged to make the so-called "Diddy list" and the infamous Epstein files public after taking office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kash Patel, President-elect Donald Trump's nominee to lead the FBI, has pledged to make the so-called “Diddy list” and the infamous Epstein files public after taking office. Speaking on a podcast, the Indian American loyalist of Mr Trump, who shares the president-elect's scepticism of the FBI and intelligence community, said he's committed to restoring trust in federal agencies by exposing decades of alleged corruption.</p>

<p>During the conversation on "Benny Johnson" podcast, Mr Patel said "trust in our agencies and departments" can only be restored by "giving the American people the truth."</p>

<p>“And that's what they feared about Donald Trump. He's gonna come in there and maybe give them the Epstein list, and maybe give them the P. Diddy list, you know, maybe he's gonna come up there and do all these things, and they're terrified,” he said</p>

<p>The term "Diddy list" refers to the names of public figures accused of being associated with the rapper Diddy's alleged "freak-off" parties, where sexual misconduct and grooming allegedly took place.</p>

<p>By picking Kash Patel to lead the United State's premier federal law enforcement agency, the incoming US President signalled his intention to overhaul the intelligence agency he has long criticized.</p>

<p>However, Mr Patel is expected to face an uphill battle to get a Senate confirmation to take over his appointed role, not only for&nbsp;professed fealty to Mr Trump but also his beliefs — revealed over the last year in interviews and his own book.</p>

<p>Time and again, the MAGA (Make America Great Again) loyalist has said that the century-old Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) should be radically overhauled. Kash Patel has proposed shutting down the FBI's Washington headquarters at J Edgar Hoover Building and dispersing its employees across the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“I'd shut down the FBI Hoover Building on day one and reopen it the next day as a museum of the deep state,'" Patel said in a September interview on the “Shawn Kelly Show."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Then, I'd take the 7,000 employees that work in that building and send them across America to chase down criminals. Go be cops. You're cops — go be cops," he added.</p>

<p>The first FBI employees moved into the current Pennsylvania Avenue headquarters 50 years ago, according to a report by the Associated Press (AP). Since then, the building reportedly housed scores of supervisors and leaders who make decisions affecting offices around the country and overseas.</p>

<p>Mr Patel's plan to completely shut the building would require legal, logistical and bureaucratic hurdles and the plan may reflect more of a rhetorical flourish than a practical ambition, the AP report said.</p>

<p>In a book last year titled, “Government Gangsters: The Deep State, the Truth and the Battle for Our Democracy,” he proposed a more modest reform of having the headquarters moved out of Washington “to prevent institutional capture and curb FBI leadership from engaging in political gamesmanship.”</p>

<p>As it happens, the long-term fate of the iconic building remains in flux regardless of the leadership transition. The General Services Administration reportedly selected last year Greenbelt in Maryland as the site for a new headquarters. However, current FBI Director Christopher Wray has raised concerns about a potential conflict of interest in the site selection process.</p>

<p>Mr Patel has also been a fierce critic of the FBI's use of its surveillance authorities under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act, and in his “Shawn Kelly Show” interview, he called for “major, major reform. Tons."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ej9qilhk_kash-patel-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kash Patel has also been a fierce critic of the FBI's use of its surveillance authorities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-bill-clinton-donald-trump-biden-in-list-of-us-presidents-pardoning-relatives-7161363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Bill Clinton, Trump, Biden In List Of US Presidents Pardoning Relatives]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-bill-clinton-donald-trump-biden-in-list-of-us-presidents-pardoning-relatives-7161363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:59:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US presidents traditionally dole out pardons as they leave office but Joe Biden's "full and unconditional" pardon of his son Hunter is a rare instance involving a family member.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US presidents traditionally dole out pardons as they leave office but Joe Biden's "full and unconditional" pardon of his son Hunter is a rare instance involving a family member.</p>

<p>Bill Clinton granted a pardon to his half-brother Roger, who had served time in prison on 1985 drug charges, on January 20, 2001, his last day in office.</p>

<p>And Donald Trump pardoned Charles Kushner, a fellow real estate magnate whose son Jared is married to Trump's daughter Ivanka, at the end of his first term in the White House.</p>

<p>Trump, now president-elect, nominated Kushner, 70, who pleaded guilty in 2004 to tax evasion, witness tampering and making illegal campaign contributions, on Saturday to be the next US ambassador to France.</p>

<p>Kushner, who served 14 months in prison, admitted hiring a prostitute to seduce his brother-in-law, who was cooperating in the campaign finance inquiry, and sending a videotape of the encounter to his own sister.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden, who has struggled with alcohol and drug addiction, is the first child of a sitting president to receive a pardon.</p>

<p>His father, who leaves office on January 20, had repeatedly said he would not pardon his son -- but in announcing the move on Sunday he claimed that Hunter had been "selectively, and unfairly, prosecuted."</p>

<p>"I believe in the justice system, but as I have wrestled with this, I also believe raw politics has infected this process and it led to a miscarriage of justice," Biden said.</p>

<p>"No reasonable person who looks at the facts of Hunter's cases can reach any other conclusion than Hunter was singled out only because he is my son -- and that is wrong," the president said.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden pleaded guilty to tax evasion in September and was facing up to 17 years in prison. He risked 25 years in prison for the felony gun charge but was not expected to receive such stiff sentences in either case.</p>

<p>Presidents have also used their constitutionally-mandated pardon powers over the years on close friends and political allies.</p>

<p>One of the most controversial pardons in recent years was that of former president Richard Nixon by his successor in the White House, Gerald Ford.</p>

<p>Ford granted a "full and unconditional" pardon to Nixon, who was facing potential prosecution over the Watergate scandal, on September 8, 1974.</p>

<p>Trump is the first former president convicted of a crime -- falsifying business records to cover up a hush money payment to a porn star -- but he will not be able to pardon himself because the case involved state and not federal charges.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rlndbrjo_joe-biden-accompanied-by-his-son-hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Presidents have also used their constitutionally-mandated pardon powers over the years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-cop16-saudi-arabia-bets-on-climate-tech-to-make-deserts-bloom-7161321]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At COP16, Saudi Arabia Bets On Climate Tech To Make Deserts Bloom]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-cop16-saudi-arabia-bets-on-climate-tech-to-make-deserts-bloom-7161321]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:53:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia is investing in green innovation to transform its deserts, but accusations of greenwashing highlight the challenge of turning ambitious projects into climate solutions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia is investing in green innovation to transform its deserts, but accusations of greenwashing highlight the challenge of turning ambitious projects into climate solutions.</p>

<p>This week, Riyadh is hosting the United Nations COP16 conference on drought and desertification -- topics close to home for the Gulf kingdom, whose officials have said they aim to restore 40 million hectares of degraded land.</p>

<p>But while the country is a major investor in climate tech, it has not abandoned its longstanding defence of oil, and critics say its gestures toward environmental friendliness offer only limited benefits.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia accounts for nearly 75 percent of Middle East investment in climate technology start-ups worldwide, according to a 2023 report by auditor PwC.</p>

<p>But its investment in green tech skews towards energy, with $363 million ploughed into climate-friendly energy solutions -- nearly 10 times as much as was invested in innovations related to food, agriculture and land-use, PwC said.</p>

<p>On a vast campus in the desert north of Jeddah, one project that could prove useful in the parched kingdom is using microorganisms to reduce the energy cost of treating wastewater.</p>

<p>The treatment facility seeks to "purify and treat wastewater in an energy-neutral or even positive way", said Peiying Hong, the environmental science and engineering academic who oversees the facility at the King Abdullah University of Science and Technology.</p>

<p>The process, she said, relies on microorganisms that convert carbon into methane gas, which is collected and used to produce energy for the facility.</p>

<p>The filtered water from the process "can be used to grow micro algae to produce feed for livestock, or to irrigate plants and trees to combat desertification", she added.</p>

<h3><strong>Sand into soil</strong></h3>

<p>Recycled water could prove valuable to the largely desert country with extremely limited water resources.</p>

<p>As part of its so-called Middle East Green Initiative, Saudi Arabia aims to eventually plant 10 billion trees, according to the project's website, and rehabilitate more than 74 million hectares of land.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To achieve these ambitions, efficient management of water and soil resources is essential.</p>

<p>Himanshu Mishra, also an environmental science and engineering expert at KAUST, said his team have developed a product they believe is capable of transforming the kingdom's desert into fertile land.</p>

<p>"We are transforming sand into soil," the professor said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The carbon-enriched compost made from chicken manure -- an abundant and underused resource in Saudi Arabia -- is developed a step further than normal fertiliser.</p>

<p>Mishra explained his innovation "acts like a sponge to retain these nutrients and water, while promoting microbial biodiversity", which plants need to thrive.</p>

<p>The professor's experimental farm has been left teeming with vegetation as a result.</p>

<p>Mishra explained that by selling its carbonated topsoil, made in the kingdom from local waste, Saudi Arabia could become "an exporter of both the product and its technology".</p>

<h3><strong>Greenwashing?</strong></h3>

<p>Despite their potential, deploying such systems on a national or regional level requires financial support and political will.</p>

<p>"We really need venture funding and investment to demonstrate their effectiveness on a large scale," Hong said.</p>

<p>But John Robinson, an investor and partner at Mazarine Ventures, says raising funds for these types of start-ups remains "extremely hard", though some manage to attract private investors.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Saudi Arabia's ambitions have not taken away from its fierce defence of oil, as it continues to be the world's biggest exporter of crude.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In addition to combating desertification, the kingdom is focusing on technologies such as carbon capture and hydrogen production as part of what it calls a "circular carbon economy".</p>

<p>But critics have labelled these efforts greenwashing, saying they aim to allow continued investment in fossil fuels.</p>

<p>In May 2024, the European Centre for Democracy and Human Rights (ECDHR) said the Saudi Green Initiative "conceals the country's ongoing reliance on fossil fuels and contempt for environmental justice behind lofty sustainability promises".</p>

<p>Riyadh justifies the policy as necessary for its energy security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pk9n5i9g_cop16_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia accounts for nearly 75 percent of Middle East investment in climate technology.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pat-gelsinger-after-stepping-down-as-intel-ceo-honour-of-my-lifetime-7160918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Honour Of My Lifetime": Pat Gelsinger After Stepping Down As Intel CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pat-gelsinger-after-stepping-down-as-intel-ceo-honour-of-my-lifetime-7160918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:30:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger has stepped down as the CEO of Intel Corporation effective December 1, just under four years after taking the top job.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pat Gelsinger has stepped down as the CEO of Intel Corporation effective December 1, just under four years after taking the top job. Mr Gelsinger, 63, was reportedly given the option to voluntarily retire or be removed by the company's board. After careful consideration, he chose to retire.</p>

<p>In a post on LinkedIn, Mr Gelsinger wrote, “Leading Intel Corporation has been the honour of my lifetime. I am forever grateful for the many colleagues around the world who I have worked with as part of the Intel family and can look back with pride at all that we have accomplished together. Thank you all!”<br />
<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="286" src="https://www.linkedin.com/embed/feed/update/urn:li:share:7269395411658792960" title="Embedded post" width="504"></iframe><br />
Pat Gelsinger described his departure from Intel as “bittersweet”, acknowledging the company had been central to his career for much of his life. “This company has been my life for the bulk of my working career,” Mr Gelsinger said in a <a href="https://www.intc.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1719/intel-announces-retirement-of-ceo-pat-gelsinger " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">company statement</a>. “I can look back with pride at all that we have accomplished together.”<br />
<br />
He talked about the tough yet essential decisions made to position Intel for the evolving market and expressed deep gratitude for his “colleagues around the world”, recognising their collective efforts as part of the Intel family.<br />
<br />
Intel's board of directors named two senior leaders, David Zinsner and Michelle Johnston Holthaus, as interim co-CEOs, while a search for a permanent replacement is underway. Mr Zinsner, Intel's executive vice president and CFO, and Holthaus, appointed CEO of Intel Products, will lead the company through this transitional period. Frank Yeary, Intel's independent board chair, will step in as interim executive chair.<br />
<br />
Mr Yeary praised Mr Gelsinger for his dedication to Intel. “Pat helped launch and revitalise process manufacturing by investing in state-of-the-art semiconductor manufacturing while working tirelessly to drive innovation throughout the company,” Mr Yeary said.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Pat Gelsinger's legacy at Intel spans several decades. He started his career at the company in 1979 and became Intel's first Chief Technology Officer before eventually returning to the company as CEO in 2021 during a critical time.<br />
<br />
He was forced out after the board lost confidence in his strategy to revitalise the company, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-02/intel-ceo-pat-gelsinger-retires-amid-chipmaker-s-turnaround-plan " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Bloomberg</a> reported. The clash reached its peak when Mr Gelsinger met with the board to discuss Intel's progress in regaining market share and competing with Nvidia. He was given the choice to retire or be removed.<br />
<br />
His resignation comes as the company navigates a rapidly changing semiconductor market. Throughout his tenure, he was known for his focus on innovation and his ability to rally the company around urgent strategic priorities. His leadership was seen as crucial to Intel's ongoing efforts to regain its competitive edge in the global chipmaking industry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7adetsbo_pat-gelsinger-linkedin_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger described his departure from Intel as "bittersweet".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-clues-point-to-possible-alien-life-beneath-mars-surface-7161139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Clues Point To Possible Alien Life Beneath Mars' Surface]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-clues-point-to-possible-alien-life-beneath-mars-surface-7161139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:26:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[By analyzing data from various Mars missions, the team has identified a subsurface zone, between 4.3 and 8.8 kilometres deep, where conditions could support microbial activity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Could Mars, once a warm and wet world, still harbour life? A team of scientists led by Andrea Butturini believes so. Their research suggests that the ancient Martian plain of Acidalia Planitia may be a potential haven for microbial life, particularly methanogens, lurking deep beneath the surface, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2458263-life-on-mars-could-be-surviving-in-an-area-deep-underground/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>New Scientist</em></a>.</p>

<p>By analyzing data from various Mars missions, the team has identified a subsurface zone, between 4.3 and 8.8 kilometres deep, where conditions could support microbial activity. This subsurface environment, shielded from harsh surface conditions, may retain remnants of ancient water and geothermal heat, crucial elements for life. While the idea of Martian microbes may seem far-fetched, this discovery sparks hope for the possibility of extraterrestrial life and opens new avenues for future exploration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Taking data from the multitude of orbiters and rovers that have visited Mars, the researchers found that Acidalia Planitia - a 3000-kilometre-wide plain in the northern hemisphere of Mars - seems to have the right conditions for methanogens, methane-producing bacteria, an estimated 4.3 to 8.8 kilometres beneath the surface.</p>

<p>"[It is] a promising target area for future missions in the search for extant life in Mars' subsurface," the researchers write.</p>

<p>To uncover evidence of life on Mars, researchers would need to drill miles beneath its surface- an endeavour requiring advanced crewed missions and technologies that are still years away from feasibility.</p>

<p>This study, however, marks a significant step forward in the search for extraterrestrial life. By pinpointing a location beneath the Martian surface where microbial life might exist, it sets the stage for future investigations that could resolve the long-standing debate over the presence of methane in Mars' atmosphere.</p>

<p>The researchers suggest that methanogens-methane-producing bacteria could thrive under Mars' Acidalia Planitia region. These extremophiles are known to endure harsh environments on Earth, such as high temperatures, radiation, and ultra-salty conditions. They are anaerobic, requiring neither oxygen nor sunlight, and can survive on minimal nutrients. On Earth, methanogens are found in swamps, marshes, decaying organic matter, and even the guts of herbivores.</p>

<p>While the European Space Agency's Rosalind Franklin rover, set to launch in 2028, will include a drill capable of penetrating seven feet into the Martian surface, this depth is insufficient to reach the potentially habitable zone identified by the researchers. The surface of Mars is far too cold and low-pressure for even extremophiles to survive, but below the surface, conditions improve.</p>

<p>The radioactive decay of elements like thorium generates heat and chemical energy, and water remnants from ancient oceans are buried underground. Together, these factors could create a habitable environment for bacteria, likely at depths of up to five miles.</p>

<p>Biogeochemist Butturini of the University of Barcelona and his team used Mars orbiter data to locate regions with high thorium concentrations that could sustain microbial life. They matched this with subsurface ice maps created by missions like China's Zhurong rover. Their analysis identified the southern Acidalia Planitia as the most promising target, a mid-latitude region with signs of groundwater activity and clay and carbonate deposits.</p>

<p>At this depth, temperatures are more favourable, ranging between 32 to 50 Degrees F, potentially allowing for liquid water mixed with Martian soil-an essential ingredient for bacterial life.</p>

<p>Although the findings, currently available on the preprint server arXiv, have yet to undergo peer review, they are drawing attention for providing a specific site to focus the search for Martian life.</p>

<p>"The subsurface of the southern Acidalia Planitia is a putative target region for hosting cold-adapted Methanosarcinaceae-like and/or Methanomicrobiaceae-like methanogens," the study notes. It highlights the region's abundance of radiogenic heat-producing elements and the likelihood of subsurface water.</p>

<p>If proven correct, this research could not only confirm the existence of alien life on Mars but also provide indirect evidence that methane in Mars' atmosphere may have a biological origin.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jmtbn33g_mars_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This study marks a significant step forward in the search for extraterrestrial life]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-followers-urged-to-avoid-public-display-of-faith-iskcon-kolkata-7161084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Avoid Saffron Robes, Tilak In Public': ISKCON Monk's Bangladesh Advisory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-followers-urged-to-avoid-public-display-of-faith-iskcon-kolkata-7161084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:19:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[ISKCON Kolkata spokesperson Radharamn Das on Tuesday said he has urged its monks and followers from Bangladesh to avoid wearing saffron robes and 'tilak' in public, advising them to practice their faith discreetly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ISKCON Kolkata spokesperson Radharamn Das on Tuesday said he has urged its monks and followers from Bangladesh to avoid wearing saffron robes and 'tilak' in public, advising them to practice their faith discreetly amid safety concerns following targeted attacks against Hindu minorities in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>This suggestion comes in the wake of escalating violence against the Hindu community in Bangladesh after the fall of the Sheikh Hasina government earlier this year, which has heightened anxieties among devotees and their families.</p>

<p>"The situation in Bangladesh is alarming. The monks and devotees, who have been calling us, we have told them to hide their identity as ISKCON followers or monks publicly. We have asked them to practice their faith discreetly inside homes or inside the temples. We have advised them to dress in a manner that does not draw attention," Radharamn Das, who is also ISKCON Kolkata vice-president, told PTI.</p>

<p>He emphasised that the measure was temporary and aimed solely at ensuring their safety.</p>

<p>"This is not any advisory or generic guideline but my personal suggestion to monks and devotees who have been calling us frantically over the last few days," he said.</p>

<p>"Many of our devotees and their families are facing threats and intimidation," Radharamn Das added, referring to incidents of vandalism of temples and attacks on religious gatherings.</p>

<p>Chinmay Krishna, who served as a spokesperson for Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote, was arrested at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday while en route to Chattogram to attend a rally.</p>

<p>He was denied bail and sent to jail on Tuesday by a court in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>Historically, Hindus made up approximately 22 per cent of Bangladesh's population during the 1971 Liberation War.</p>

<p>The Hindu population, once a substantial demographic in Bangladesh, has experienced a significant decline in recent decades, with the minority community now comprising only around 8 per cent of the country's total population.</p>

<p>This drop is largely attributed to a combination of socio-political marginalisation, exodus and sporadic violence over the years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m4ni96vg_iskcon-temple-istock_625x300_27_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The situation in Bangladesh is alarming," said Radharamn Das. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sombrero-galaxy-appears-distinct-in-new-image-from-webb-telescope-7161055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sombrero Galaxy Appears Distinct In New Image From Webb Telescope]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sombrero-galaxy-appears-distinct-in-new-image-from-webb-telescope-7161055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:10:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Sombrero galaxy, or Messier 104 or M104, is roughly 30 million light-years from the Earth in the Virgo constellation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new picture of the Sombrero galaxy, captured by the James Webb Space Telescope, revealed a perspective that appears different from the broad-brimmed Mexican hat after which it was named. The image, taken through the space observatory's Mid-Infrared Instrument, or MIRI, features the Sombrero galaxy's smooth inner disk instead of the glowing core, which usually shines in visible light, as seen in images taken through the Hubble Space Telescope, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/12/02/science/sombrero-galaxy-image-nasa-webb/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a> reported.<br />
<br />
Webb Space Telescope's view makes the galaxy's “crown” invisible, changing its appearance to resemble a bull's-eye. In the background of the image, several distant galaxies can be seen.<br />
<br />
The Sombrero galaxy, also known as Messier 104 or M104, is situated about 30 million light-years from the Earth in the Virgo constellation. It was discovered in 1781 by French astronomer Pierre Méchain.<br />
<br />
The latest image highlights intricate details in Sombrero's outer ring, revealing how dust, a fundamental building block of astronomical objects, is distributed throughout the galaxy.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Earlier, observations from the retired Spitzer Space Telescope of NASA showed this outer ring as smooth and uniform. Webb's advanced imaging, on the contrary, shows a clumpy, textured structure for the first time.<br />
<br />
The researchers have also spotted carbon-containing molecules, like polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons, in the dust ring. This suggests its outer ring could be home to star-forming regions. However, it must be noted that this galaxy is quiet in terms of star formation compared to others, like Messier 82.<br />
<br />
Sombrero galaxy's rings produce less than one solar mass of stars in a year compared to the Milky Way's roughly two solar masses, <a href="https://scitechdaily.com/nasas-webb-telescope-captures-the-sombrero-galaxy-in-breathtaking-detail/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">SciTechDaily</a> reported.<br />
<br />
The supermassive black hole at its centre is less active than the ones present in other galaxies. Still, the Sombrero galaxy is full of 2,000 globular clusters or groups of hundreds of thousands of old stars gravitationally held together.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/e1d59og8_sombrero-galaxy_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deepfakes-target-women-leaders-in-pakistan-i-was-shattered-7160902]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Was Shattered": Deepfakes Target Women Leaders In Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deepfakes-target-women-leaders-in-pakistan-i-was-shattered-7160902]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 12:50:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistani politician Azma Bukhari is haunted by a counterfeit image of herself -- a sexualised deepfake video published to discredit her role as one of the nation's few female leaders.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistani politician Azma Bukhari is haunted by a counterfeit image of herself -- a sexualised deepfake video published to discredit her role as one of the nation's few female leaders.</p>

<p>"I was shattered when it came into my knowledge," said 48-year-old Bukhari, the information minister of Pakistan's most populous province of Punjab.</p>

<p>Deepfakes -- which manipulate genuine audio, photos or video of people into false likenesses -- are becoming increasingly convincing and easier to make as artificial intelligence (AI) enters the mainstream.</p>

<p>In Pakistan, where media literacy is poor, they are being weaponised to smear women in the public sphere with sexual innuendo deeply damaging to their reputations in a country with conservative mores.</p>

<p>Bukhari -- who regularly appears on TV -- recalls going quiet for days after she saw the video of her face superimposed on the sexualised body of an Indian actor in a clip quickly spreading on social media.</p>

<p>"It was very difficult, I was depressed," she told AFP in her home in the eastern city of Lahore.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My daughter, she hugged me and said: 'Mama, you have to fight it out'."</p>

<p>After initially recoiling she is pressing her case at Lahore's High Court, attempting to hold those who spread the deepfake to account.</p>

<p>"When I go to the court, I have to remind people again and again that I have a fake video," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>'A very harmful weapon'</strong></h3>

<p>In Pakistan -- a country of 240 million people -- internet use has risen at staggering rates recently owing to cheap 4G mobile internet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Around 110 million Pakistanis were online this January, 24 million more than at the beginning of 2023, according to monitoring site DataReportal.</p>

<p>In this year's election, deepfakes were at the centre of digital debate.</p>

<p>Ex-prime minister Imran Khan was jailed but his team used an AI tool to generate speeches in his voice shared on social media, allowing him to campaign from behind bars.</p>

<p>Men in politics are typically criticised over corruption, their ideology and status. But deepfakes have a dark side uniquely suited to tearing down women.</p>

<p>"When they are accused, it almost always revolves around their sex lives, their personal lives, whether they're good mums, whether they're good wives," said US-based AI expert Henry Ajder.</p>

<p>"For that deepfakes are a very harmful weapon," he told AFP.</p>

<p>In patriarchal Pakistan the stakes are high.</p>

<p>Women's status is typically tied to their "honour", generally defined as modesty and chastity. Hundreds are killed every year -- often by their own families -- for supposedly besmirching it.</p>

<p>Bukhari describes the video targeting her as "pornographic".</p>

<p>But in a country where premarital sex and cohabitation are punishable offences, deepfakes can undermine reputations by planting innuendo with the suggestion of a hug or improper social mingling with men.</p>

<p>In October, AFP debunked a deepfake video of regional lawmaker Meena Majeed showing her hugging the male chief minister of Balochistan province.</p>

<p>A social media caption said: "Shamelessness has no limits. This is an insult to Baloch culture."</p>

<p>Bukhari says photos of her with her husband and son have also been manipulated to imply she appeared in public with boyfriends outside her marriage.</p>

<p>And doctored videos regularly circulate of Punjab Chief Minister Maryam Nawaz Sharif -- Bukhari's boss -- showing her dancing with opposition leaders.</p>

<p>Once targeted by deepfakes like these, women's "image is seen as immoral, and the honour of the entire family is lost", said Sadaf Khan of Pakistani non-profit Media Matters for Democracy.</p>

<p>"This can put them in danger," she told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Fighting the fakes</strong></h3>

<p>Deepfakes are now prevalent across the world, but Pakistan does have legislation to combat their deployment in disinformation campaigns.</p>

<p>In 2016, a law was passed by Bukhari's party "to prevent online crimes" with "cyberstalking" provisions against sharing photos or videos without consent "in a manner that harms a person".</p>

<p>Bukhari believes it needs to be strengthened and backed up by investigators. "The capacity building of our cybercrime unit is very, very important," she said.</p>

<p>But digital rights activists have also criticised the government for wielding such broad legislation to quash dissent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Authorities have previously blocked YouTube and TikTok, and a ban on X -- formerly Twitter -- has been in place since after February elections when allegations of vote tampering spread on the site.</p>

<p>Pakistan-based digital rights activist Nighat Dad said blocking the sites serves only as "a quick solution for the government".</p>

<p>"It's violating other fundamental rights, which are connected to your freedom of expression, and access to information," she told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/uotocpto_deepfake_625x300_25_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Deepfakes are now prevalent across the world. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/seven-protesters-detained-after-bangladesh-mission-breach-in-tripura-3-cops-suspended-7160817]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tripura's Big Crackdown After Dhaka Flags Mission Breach, Delhi Agrees]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/seven-protesters-detained-after-bangladesh-mission-breach-in-tripura-3-cops-suspended-7160817]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 12:40:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Seven protesters detained after Bangladesh mission breach in Tripura, 3 cops suspended]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Tripura government today suspended three police officers, withdrew a senior officer from his post and detained seven people after the security breach at the Bangladesh diplomatic mission in Agartala stepped up the tension between New Delhi and Dhaka.</p>

<p>About 50 people, who participated in a massive protest against the arrest of Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das in Agartala yesterday, entered the premises of the Bangladesh Assistant High Commission. This drew a sharp response from the interim government in the neighbouring country. Dhaka alleged that local police were "not found to be active in containing the situation". It said the incident had left the mission staff with a "deep sense of insecurity" and called upon New Delhi to take "immediate action".</p>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs responded that the incident in "deeply regrettable". "Diplomatic and consular properties should not be targeted under any circumstances. Government is taking action to step up security arrangements for the Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi and their Deputy/Assistant High Commissions in the country," a statement said.</p>

<p>A top Tripura police officer has said the BJP government in the border state has ordered an inquiry into Monday's incident. Three sub-inspectors -- Dilu Jamatia, Debabrata Sinha, and Joynal Hossain -- have been suspended and Assistant Commandant Kanti Nath Ghosh has been withdrawn from his posting. The officer said the action against the four officers was taken on the grounds of negligence.</p>

<p>The number of cops at the Bangladesh mission in Agartala has been stepped up after yesterday's incident. Tripura Chief Minister Dr Manik Saha has slammed the incident and said while peaceful protests are allowed, such acts are absolutely unacceptable.</p>

<p>Relations between India and Bangladesh, which had started deteriorating after the Sheikh Hasina government toppled and she fled to India, have nosedived over the past couple of weeks amid reports of attacks on Hindu minorities in the neighbouring country. Following the detention of Hindu priest Chinmoy Krishna Das, several organisations have taken out protests in solidarity with the minorities in Bangladesh. The External Affairs Minister has urged the interim government in Bangladesh to protect minorities and the latter has stressed that it won't allow any communal activity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vr14964o_agartala_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michelin-starred-chef-pleads-thieves-after-they-steal-2-500-pies-worth-rs-26-lakh-7160775]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Michelin Chef Pleads Thieves After They Steal 2,500 Pies Worth Rs 26 Lakh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michelin-starred-chef-pleads-thieves-after-they-steal-2-500-pies-worth-rs-26-lakh-7160775]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 12:33:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The staff had kept the pies overnight in the refrigerated van but found the vehicle vanished in the morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British Michelin-starred chef is pleading to the thieves after they ran away with his van that contained 2,500 pies, worth Rs 26 lakh (£25,000), destined for the York Christmas Market. Tommy Banks, a veteran judge on the <em>BBC </em>show, Great British Menu who also owns two restaurants and a pub in North Yorkshire, took to Instagram on Monday (Dec 2) to inform that his van that contained steak and ale, turkey and butternut squash pies, as well as gravy and custard, had been stolen from Barker Business Park in Melmerby on Sunday night.</p>

<p>Mr Banks' staff had kept the pies overnight in the refrigerated van and were planning to make the delivery the next morning when they found that the vehicle had vanished.</p>

<p>"So @matthewalockwood went into @madeinoldstead this morning to pick up the van and it has been stolen. These guys had loaded up the van with stock for @tommyspieshop today and left plugged in overnight. I'm guessing the thieves didn't realise they were stealing 2,500 pies along with the van!" said Mr Banks.</p>

<p>The inventory stolen would have been enough to stock Tommy's Pie Shop for a week, Mr Banks told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gpl8r2e48o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC</em></a>. He urged the thieves to do the 'right thing' and return the pies, even if they wanted to not give up on the van.</p>

<p>"I know you're a criminal, but maybe just do something nice because it's Christmas and maybe we can feed a few thousand people with these pies that you've stolen, do the right thing," he said, adding: "The pies are all in boxes with my name on so not very easy to sell."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEi2T5oJIi/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEi2T5oJIi/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEi2T5oJIi/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDEi2T5oJIi/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Tommy Banks (@tommybanks)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Meanwhile, the North Yorkshire Police said it had been informed of the theft and started the probe. It requested anyone with any information to get in touch.</p>

<p>While the authorities investigate the case, Mr Banks introduced a new butter chicken pie at his shop to make up for the lack of steak and ale pies.</p>

<p>"Since we're a little low on steak and ale pies this week seeing as they're currently being driven around the country in our stolen van, from Wednesday we'll be launching a brand new limited edition pie!" read the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCuACKkM0QX/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&amp;igsh=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==" rel="Noindex, nofollow">statement</a>.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/u45579ag_pie_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The pies were supposed to be delivered at the York Christmas Market.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-creates-fake-arrest-warrant-out-of-boredom-offers-rs-3-51-lakh-reward-7160703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bored Chinese Man Creates Fake Arrest Warrant, Offers Rs 3.51 Lakh Reward]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-creates-fake-arrest-warrant-out-of-boredom-offers-rs-3-51-lakh-reward-7160703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 12:22:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The local police noticed the unusual post on November 12, and after an investigation, arrested Wang within hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man from China has been arrested and detained by police for creating a fake arrest warrant for himself out of boredom. The man, identified by his surname Wang, posted the fake warrant online on November 11, calling it a "Wanted Order" and including a picture of himself.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3288380/bored-chinese-man-creates-fake-arrest-notice-himself-offering-us4000-reward-detained" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>South China Morning Post</em></a>, Wang claimed to be Wang Yibo, a well-known Chinese actor, dancer, and singer. In his post, he stated, "I am a native of Qinyuan County, Changzhi City, Shanxi Province. I extorted 30 million yuan ($4 million) from a company on November 10, 2024. I possess a submachine gun and 500 bullets. If you find me, you will be rewarded 30,000 yuan ($4,000)."</p>

<p>The local police noticed the unusual post on November 12, and after an investigation, arrested Wang within hours. Authorities found no evidence of illegal firearms or ammunition and confirmed that no company had been defrauded.</p>

<p>Wang later confessed to fabricating the arrest warrant due to feelings of boredom and a low mood in his life. His post quickly gained attention, accumulating 350,000 views, 2,500 likes, and 1,155 shares within 24 hours.</p>

<p>As a result, Wang has been subjected to a "criminal coercive measure," which restricts his freedom for a period, as punishment for spreading false information. In China, such measures are used to temporarily restrict an individual's liberty during police investigations.</p>

<p>According to SCMP, speaking about the case, police said, "The internet is not beyond the reach of the law. Fabricating a story and spreading it are both criminal acts. Anyone who concocts or circulates rumours will face judicial consequences."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dmndvpn8_chinese-man_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wang has been subjected to a "criminal coercive measure"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-may-cancel-nasas-giant-moon-rocket-what-it-would-mean-for-elon-musk-7160538]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump May Cancel NASA's Giant Moon Rocket: What It Would Mean For Elon Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-may-cancel-nasas-giant-moon-rocket-what-it-would-mean-for-elon-musk-7160538]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 11:57:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Since Donald Trumps recent electoral victory, rumours and speculation have circulated that Nasas giant Moon rocket, the Space Launch System (SLS), could be under threat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>Since Donald Trump's recent electoral victory, <a href="https://x.com/SciGuySpace/status/1856522880143745133">rumours</a> and <a href="https://eu.floridatoday.com/story/tech/science/space/2024/11/17/elon-musk-president-trump-impact-on-nasa-artemis-sls-moon-mars-spacex-starship/76255421007/">speculation</a> have circulated that Nasa's giant Moon rocket, the Space Launch System (SLS), could be under threat. The rocket is one of several key elements needed for the US space agency's Artemis programme, which aims to return humans to the Moon for the first time since 1972.</p>

<p>For the first <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/artemis_plan-20200921.pdf">lunar landing mission</a>, called Artemis III, the SLS will launch four astronauts on Nasa's Orion crew capsule. Orion will then travel to the Moon. Once in lunar orbit, Orion will dock with Elon Musk's Starship vehicle (which has been launched separately). Two astronauts will float into Starship, which undocks from Orion and travels down to the lunar surface.</p>

<p>After walking on the Moon, the two astronauts return to lunar orbit in Starship, which docks with Orion. The two moonwalkers rejoin their crewmates and go home on Orion, leaving Starship in orbit around the Moon.</p>

<p>The US space journalist Eric Berger recently posted on X: “To be clear we are far from anything being settled, but based on what I'm hearing it seems at least 50-50 that Nasa's Space Launch System rocket will be cancelled.”</p>

<p>No official announcements have been made. However, such a move could be in line with previous speculation that the Trump administration <a href="https://spacenews.com/dont-let-trump-and-musk-gut-nasa/">could gut Nasa</a>, forcing it to contract out much of its work to the private companies.</p>

<p>But could another rocket easily take the place of the SLS? This question goes to the heart of what America wants to achieve amid an emerging 21st-century space race. China has pledged to send its astronauts <a href="https://www.space.com/the-universe/moon/how-china-plans-to-put-astronauts-on-the-moon-by-2030-video">to the lunar surface by 2030</a>. Unlike the US, China is usually conservative in its estimates, so we can assume deadline slippage is unlikely. Meanwhile, several elements of Artemis <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/d24106256.pdf">are holding up</a> the schedule.</p>

<p>One of these delayed elements is Musk's Starship, which acts as the lander on Artemis III. It still needs to demonstrate key milestones including refuelling in space and performing a landing on the Moon without crew. Some in the space community believe that if China were to get to the Moon first this century, it <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/technology/4992934-elon-musk-trump-space-policy/">would deal</a> a <a href="https://spacenews.com/make-space-great-again/">significant blow</a> to US ambitions in space.</p>

<p>Musk has been brought into the incoming administration as one of two chief cost cutters, aiming to make reductions of <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/government-spending-doge-elon-musk-trump-administration-60477bc5">up to US$2 trillion</a> (£1.57 trillion) from the federal budget. Some observers have been alarmed by <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/nov/22/elon-musk-donald-trump">Elon Musk's closeness</a> to Trump and by comments by the president-elect about <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/technology/4992934-elon-musk-trump-space-policy/">shifting focus</a> towards a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2024/10/27/trump-musk-mars/">crewed Mars mission</a>.</p>

<p>These comments seem to mirror the views of Musk, who has focused much of his energy on ambitions to <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/22/science/mars-human-settlement-elon-musk/index.html">settle the red planet</a>, not the Moon. The billionaire has said he wants to send humans on a trip to Mars using his Starship vehicle by 2028 – a timeline that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/11/space-policy-is-about-to-get-pretty-wild-yall/">some view as unrealistic</a>.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="SLS rocket on pad 39B" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/635048/original/file-20241128-15-399hzo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;rect=5%2C2%2C1904%2C1262&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/635048/original/file-20241128-15-399hzo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=398&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635048/original/file-20241128-15-399hzo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=398&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635048/original/file-20241128-15-399hzo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=398&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635048/original/file-20241128-15-399hzo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=500&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635048/original/file-20241128-15-399hzo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=500&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635048/original/file-20241128-15-399hzo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=500&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">The SLS performed very well during the Artemis I mission in 2022.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/exploration-ground-systems/launch-pad-39b/">NASA/Kim Shiflett</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>It was actually the first Trump administration that <a href="https://spacenews.com/national-space-council-calls-for-human-return-to-the-moon/">established the Artemis programme</a> in 2017. After initial missions to the lunar surface, the programme aims to establish <a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/artemis/2020/10/28/lunar-living-nasas-artemis-base-camp-concept/">a permanent base</a> where astronauts can learn how to live and work on the Moon, carrying out cutting-edge research.</p>

<p>However, the schedule <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-shares-progress-toward-early-artemis-moon-missions-with-crew/">has been slipping</a>. US astronauts were to have landed on the Moon this year. Nasa now says the first landing, during the Artemis III mission, will not take place until Autumn 2026.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/d24106256.pdf">Delays have been introduced</a> by redesigns to spacesuits, problems with Orion's heat-shield and life support systems and, as mentioned, with Starship. An upgraded <a href="https://oig.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/ig-24-016.pdf">mobile launch tower</a> for the SLS has also been plagued by cost overruns and schedule slippage.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="Orion during Artemis I mission" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/635576/original/file-20241202-15-1qqon3.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/635576/original/file-20241202-15-1qqon3.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635576/original/file-20241202-15-1qqon3.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635576/original/file-20241202-15-1qqon3.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635576/original/file-20241202-15-1qqon3.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635576/original/file-20241202-15-1qqon3.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635576/original/file-20241202-15-1qqon3.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Could Nasa's Orion crew capsule launch on another rocket?</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/artemis/nasa-to-share-artemis-i-update-with-orion-at-farthest-point-from-earth/">Nasa</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Notably, an element that isn't contributing to delays is <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/analysis-confirms-successful-artemis-i-moon-mission-reviews-continue-2/">the SLS</a>, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/artemis/initial-assessment-shows-excellent-performance-for-artemis-moon-rocket/">which performed</a> <a href="https://arc.aiaa.org/doi/10.2514/6.2024-4600">very well</a> <a href="https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/2022/12/icps-artemis-i-review/">during</a> the Artemis I mission in 2022. Many billions of dollars have <a href="https://www.planetary.org/space-policy/cost-of-sls-and-orion">already been invested</a> in designing and building the SLS and associated infrastructure at Nasa's Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/reference/space-launch-system/">Nasa says</a> the SLS is “the only rocket that can send Orion, astronauts, and cargo directly to the Moon in a single launch”. But its expense has been criticised: each SLS launch is estimated to cost <a href="https://oig.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/ig-24-001.pdf">more than US$2 billion</a> (£1.6 billion).</p>

<p>News of delays and technical issues with Artemis have coincided with hugely positive PR for Musk's SpaceX – especially around its test flights of Starship. This included last month's feat, where the vehicle's massive <a href="https://www.universetoday.com/168874/spacexs-mechazilla-catches-starship-booster/">booster stage was caught</a> in a pair of robotic arms as it fell back from space to the company's launchpad in Texas – wowing space enthusiasts around the world.</p>

<p>Unlike many launch vehicles, Starship is designed to be fully reusable. Its cost efficiency could greatly benefit future crewed missions.</p>

<p>If the SLS were to be cancelled, could Musk's Starship replace it? Under this scenario, the SpaceX vehicle could presumably serve both as the launcher to send astronauts on their way to lunar orbit and as the lander to take them down to the surface. This is technically feasible, but would be far from a straightforward, like-for-like replacement. The SLS is already an operational rocket, whereas Starship is still in its testing phase and has key steps still to achieve before astronauts can board it.</p>

<p>Another SpaceX rocket that has previously been touted as a contender to launch Orion is the Falcon Heavy. However, engineers would <a href="https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/2019/04/nasa-lsp-studies-alternate-orion-options/2/">need to modify</a> both the rocket and procedures for assembly and launch. This would carry <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/04/nasa-chief-says-a-falcon-heavy-rocket-could-fly-humans-to-the-moon/">many uncertainties</a>, and with it the risk of further, significant delays to the Artemis schedule. This all suggests that there <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-us-is-now-at-risk-of-losing-to-china-in-the-race-to-send-people-back-to-the-moons-surface-241716">is not a lot of time</a> to make major changes to Nasa's Moon programme if the US is to get ahead in this 21st-century space race.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="Falcon Heavy launches Europa Clipper" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/635580/original/file-20241202-15-tzncm9.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/635580/original/file-20241202-15-tzncm9.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635580/original/file-20241202-15-tzncm9.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635580/original/file-20241202-15-tzncm9.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635580/original/file-20241202-15-tzncm9.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635580/original/file-20241202-15-tzncm9.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/635580/original/file-20241202-15-tzncm9.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Nasa has previously looked at whether Orion could be launched on a Falcon Heavy rocket.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/nasakennedy/54068615461">SpaceX</a>, <a class="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">CC BY-NC</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Rocket launches require specific designs to meet mission requirements, as well as extensive planning for carrying astronauts, spacecraft and payloads. The aims of Artemis are not just to land astronauts on the Moon, but to be able to land in a variety of regions on the lunar surface, including the relatively unexplored south pole.</p>

<p>The planning and development required is hugely complex and ambitious. It remains to be seen whether SpaceX, or any other commercial launch companies, are ready for such a major undertaking and commitment.</p>

<p>With <a href="https://www.planetary.org/space-policy/cost-of-sls-and-orion">tens of billions of dollars</a> already invested in the SLS, it does not seem economically beneficial to completely scrap the rocket. As indicated by Nasa's willingness to seek an innovative approach and work with commercial companies on future Artemis missions, there could be other ways for commercial space players to get involved.</p>

<p>It's understandable for the incoming Trump administration to raise questions and query cost models in Nasa programmes. But it would be advisable for them to carefully consider the trade offs before making decisions with such wide-ranging consequences.</p>

<p>It might fall down to whether the priority is winning the new space race. Whatever goals that the new administration chooses to prioritise or target, it may have to carefully justify that decision to other legislators and to the American public.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/244762/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/yang-gao-778504">Yang Gao</a>, Professor of Robotics, Head of Centre for Robotics Research, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/kings-college-london-1196">King's College London</a></em></span></p>

<p><em>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/trump-may-cancel-nasas-powerful-sls-moon-rocket-heres-what-that-would-mean-for-elon-musk-and-the-future-of-space-travel-244762">original article</a>.)</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/jbfk3vao_nasa-artemis-1-650_650x400_29_August_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rocket is one of several key elements needed for the US space agencys Artemis programme.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dressing-the-church-one-of-romes-last-clergyman-tailors-7160473]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dressing The Church: One Of Rome's Last Clergyman Tailors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dressing-the-church-one-of-romes-last-clergyman-tailors-7160473]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 11:45:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With a tape measure around his neck and thimble on his finger, Raniero Mancinelli slides a needle into a black cassock with red piping destined for a Catholic cardinal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With a tape measure around his neck and thimble on his finger, Raniero Mancinelli slides a needle into a black cassock with red piping destined for a Catholic cardinal.</p>

<p>"It takes two or three days to make an outfit: taking the measurements, cutting it out, and putting it all together," according to the 86-year-old Italian, one of the last ecclesiastical tailors in Rome.</p>

<p>Mancinelli has been working flat out in his historic shop on the Borgo Pio, a stone's throw from the Vatican, ahead of a ceremony this weekend to make 21 new cardinals.</p>

<p>A third of those being elevated by Pope Francis have placed orders with the tailor.</p>

<p>"They trust me and I know what I have to do, depending on where they live, the climate, their financial means," said Mancinelli, bushy black eyebrows moving animatedly above rectangular glasses, his hands stroking a tiny silver goatee.</p>

<p>Gold chalices, embroidered headdresses, signet rings, and rosaries with gleaming crucifixes fill the shop's display cases.</p>

<p>Entering his workshop at the back of the shop is like stepping back in time: an olive green Necchi sewing machine sits on a wooden bench, underneath a map of the Vatican.</p>

<p>Large scissors and an old cast-iron iron lie on a nearby table.</p>

<h3><strong>Less sumptuous</strong></h3>

<p>Mancinelli, assisted by his daughter and grandson, arms himself with scissors, pins, bobbins and buttons.</p>

<p>Two scarlet cassocks hang ready nearby. The future cardinals will also need a "biretta" (a square cap), "mozzetta" (an elbow-length cape), and "rochet" (a white lace garment).</p>

<p>The tailor also makes the black habits and white collars for priests, and the violet skullcaps and belts worn by bishops.</p>

<p>The luxury silks once used have today been replaced by "light, cheaper wools", and cassocks now cost around 200 euros ($210) each.</p>

<p>Mancinelli, originally from the Marche region in central Italy, has worked under seven popes but fell into the profession "by chance".</p>

<p>"One day I was offered the job of making cassocks for the Vatican," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"I started like that, cautiously, little by little, but I immediately saw that I liked it."</p>

<p>After honing his skills in Rome in the late 1950s under Pius XII, Mancinelli opened his own business in 1962.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He thinks back with nostalgia of long scarlet trains "of 6-7 metres of silk" once worn by cardinals, and the clergy who used to favour very high collars.</p>

<p>But ecclesiastical fashions change.</p>

<p>After the Second Vatican Council in the 1960s brought the Church into a more modern era, outfits became more simple.</p>

<p>And they have become humbler still under Pope Francis, who refused to wear the furs and velvets donned by his predecessors.</p>

<p>Clerical clothing is now "lighter, less expensive, less sumptuous, less flashy", Mancinelli said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Maestro'</strong></h3>

<p>The workshop is lined with photographs of Mancinelli and popes. He personally made cassocks for the last three, including Argentine Francis.</p>

<p>But it is his "exceptional" relationship with common clergymen that drives him, and gave him the strength to reopen after a difficult pandemic.</p>

<p>"They are the ones who give me this energy, this desire to work," he said.</p>

<p>Clerics from all over the world drop in on him during their visits to Rome.</p>

<p>Some have become friends, others have climbed the ranks of the Catholic hierarchy.</p>

<p>Over the decades, he has seen the number of ecclesiastical tailors dwindle as the sector industrialises.</p>

<p>"It's a very particular job, everything is done by hand," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But one person is learning the centuries-old skills.</p>

<p>Mancinelli's 23-year-old grandson Lorenzo di Toro has been working alongside him for the past three years.</p>

<p>"I didn't think it would be so difficult," said di Toro, whose hoodie and sneakers contrast starkly with the decor.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His grandfather is "very demanding" and "attentive to the smallest details".&nbsp;</p>

<p>But di Toro said he is ready to take over the family business from Mancinelli.</p>

<p>"I always try to learn from him, because in the end, he is the maestro," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gs3tp3io_church_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mancinelli, assisted by his daughter and grandson, arms himself with scissors, pins, bobbins and buttons.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bill-gates-laboratory-remark-on-india-revives-2009-vaccine-trials-7159785]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bill Gates Calls India A "Kind Of Laboratory To Try Things", Faces Backlash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bill-gates-laboratory-remark-on-india-revives-2009-vaccine-trials-7159785]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 11:42:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates has landed in hot water after referring to India as "a kind of laboratory to try things" during a podcast with LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates has landed in hot water after referring to India as “a kind of laboratory to try things” during a podcast with LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman. His remarks, while intended to highlight India's progress and its collaboration with the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, have revived a controversial 2009 clinical trial -- funded by Gates' foundation -- which killed seven tribal schoolgirls and left many others severely ill.</p>

<p>Mr Gates said in the recent podcast, “India is an example of a country where there's plenty of things that are difficult there—the health, nutrition, education is improving, and they are stable enough and generating their government revenue enough that it's very likely that 20 years from now people will be dramatically better off. It's kind of a laboratory to try things that then when you prove them out in India, you can take to other places.”&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">"It's a kind of laboratory to try things. When proven in India, they can then be taken to other places."<br />
— Bill Gates on India.<br />
<br />
In 2009, the American NGO PATH (Program for Appropriate Technology in Health), in collaboration with the ICMR, conducted clinical trials of a cervical… <a href="https://t.co/66aFVrxCiM">pic.twitter.com/66aFVrxCiM</a></p>
— THE SKIN DOCTOR (@theskindoctor13) <a href="https://twitter.com/theskindoctor13/status/1863626106173067394?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>His choice of words struck a nerve among the Indian audience. Among the critics was a Scotland-based doctor, known as “The Skin Doctor” on X, who brought up a 2009 clinical trial conducted by PATH (Programme for Appropriate Technology in Health), an NGO funded by the Gates Foundation.</p>

<p>In 2009, PATH collaborated with the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) to conduct clinical trials of a cervical cancer vaccine on 14,000 tribal schoolgirls in Khammam district, Telangana, and Vadodara, Gujarat. Months after the trials began, several participants reported severe side effects and seven deaths were recorded, although the deaths were later attributed to unrelated causes.</p>

<p>An investigation into the trials uncovered serious ethical lapses, revealed the skin doctor. The trials were presented as a public health initiative, concealing their experimental nature. Consent forms were allegedly signed by hostel wardens instead of the girls' parents, leaving families unaware of potential risks.</p>

<p>The trials specifically targeted tribal communities with limited healthcare access and awareness. Severe side effects were reported, fuelling allegations that the trials exploited vulnerable populations under the guise of aid.</p>

<p>PATH denied any wrongdoing, attributing the deaths to infections and suicides.</p>

<p>Critics argue the 2009 vaccine trials are just one example of how India and other developing nations have been used as testing grounds by organisations with foreign funding.</p>

<p>“Who knows how many Gates-funded NGOs are conducting similar trials in India and Africa? It's disturbing how easily they access our governance and policies, while openly treating us as guinea pigs,” the skin doctor concluded.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-07/lgjo80e_bill-gates650_625x300_11_July_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bill Gates' choice of words struck a nerve among the Indian audience.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-disney-channel-shutting-down-in-us-debunking-the-latest-rumours-7160304]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is Disney Channel Shutting Down In US? Debunking The Latest Rumours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-disney-channel-shutting-down-in-us-debunking-the-latest-rumours-7160304]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 11:17:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disney has not made any official announcements about discontinuing the channel in the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new rumour has sparked concern online, suggesting that the Disney Channel may be shutting down in the United States. However, Disney has not made any official announcements about discontinuing the channel in the US.</p>

<p>While the Disney Channel remains active in North America, the company has already closed its channels in various regions, including Australia, Southeast Asia, Italy, the UK, South Korea, and others. Disney XD has been discontinued in even more locations as Disney shifts its focus toward Disney+.</p>

<p>In France, Disney XD has already been phased out, and both Disney Junior and the Disney Channel are scheduled to shut down on January 1, 2025. Similarly, in Spain, the Disney Channel will cease operations on January 7, 2025.</p>

<p>Despite the rumours circulating on social media, one user on X (formerly Twitter) has dismissed the claims of a US shutdown as false.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Disney channel will stop airing for good January 2025 after 27 years of history. ?? <a href="https://t.co/eNm2shsyl7">pic.twitter.com/eNm2shsyl7</a></p>
— solé (@layxsnv) <a href="https://twitter.com/layxsnv/status/1863452057182581151?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The growing popularity of Disney+ has fueled speculation about the future of traditional Disney channels, but Disney has clarified that all content previously aired on the Disney Channel will remain accessible on Disney+. This shift allows viewers greater flexibility with on-demand access while marking the end of an era for linear television. For now, Disney Channel in the United States is not slated for closure, and the rumours appear to stem from confusion about its shutdowns in other countries.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/2vf9rcig_disney-plus-_625x300_11_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Disney has discontinued channels in several countries]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/why-love-feels-like-addiction-the-neuroscience-behind-our-strongest-emotions-7160301]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Love Feels Like Addiction: Neuroscience Behind Our Strongest Emotions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/why-love-feels-like-addiction-the-neuroscience-behind-our-strongest-emotions-7160301]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 11:16:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Based on your brain activity, scientists can even determine who you love or whether you have a pet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new study suggests that love, in all its forms, stimulates the reward and addiction systems of the brain-those same parts of the brain that are involved in behaviours like drug use and video game addiction. The current research outcomes further make it more clear why breakups and losses tend to be marked by a depth of emotional anguish and sharp physical pain.</p>

<p>This research published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://academic.oup.com/cercor/article/34/8/bhae331/7741043"><em>Cerebral Cortex </em></a>explores how different forms of love-romantic, familial, friendly, and even love for pets or for nature-affect the brain. Researchers from Aalto University in Finland, under Parttyli Rinne, mapped out brain activity that had links to various kinds of love and discovered each activates different regions of the brain related to social understanding. However, common to all the varieties of love was the stimulating of the brain's reward system, also implicated in the perception of addictive behaviours.</p>

<p>Lucy Brown, a neuroscientist at Einstein College of Medicine in New York, said this study confirms that romantic love and long-term attachments utilise the brain's reward and addiction circuits. She added that the research is slowly painting a clearer picture of what the brain looks like when somebody is in love.</p>

<p>The researchers used functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI), a brain scanning technique, to analyse the brain activity of 55 people.</p>

<p>"Our results demonstrate that love in closer interpersonal relationships - like for one's child, romantic partner, and friend - is associated with significantly stronger activation in the brain's reward system than love for strangers, pets, or nature," Rinne told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dw.com/en/humans-are-addicted-to-love-heres-how-we-know/a-70858166?maca=en-Whatsapp-sharing"><em>Deutsche Welle.</em></a></p>

<p>Love of people also activates brain areas associated with thinking, feeling, and understanding - also known as social cognition. Differences in brain activity in social cognition regions revealed whether participants had a pet or not.</p>

<p>"In pet owners, love for pets activates these same social brain regions significantly more than in participants without pets," said Rinne.</p>

<p>Love of nature or art are also strong types of love, but we tend to feel it differently than a romantic or familial love of people. Indeed, love of nature lit up the brain's reward system and visual areas associated with viewing landscapes, but not the areas associated with social cognition.</p>

<p>"This provides evidence that different types of love draw on partly distinct and partly overlapping brain regions," said Roland Zahn, a psychiatrist and expert in mood disorders at King's College London, UK, who was not involved in the study.</p>

<p>This study provides new insight into the powerful influence love has on the brain and how it may impact both emotional states as well as physical ones.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/c564gjn_family_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brain imaging studies show love is like a drug addiction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-lawyer-for-hindu-priest-chinmoy-krishna-das-in-bangladesh-next-bail-hearing-after-a-month-7160294]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Lawyer For Hindu Priest In Bangladesh, Next Bail Hearing After A Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-lawyer-for-hindu-priest-chinmoy-krishna-das-in-bangladesh-next-bail-hearing-after-a-month-7160294]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 11:15:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The bail hearing of Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, the Hindu priest arrested and accused of sedition in Bangladesh, has been pushed to next month after no lawyer appeared in court for the hearing on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The bail hearing of Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, the Hindu priest arrested and accused of sedition in Bangladesh, has been pushed to next month after no lawyer appeared in court for the hearing on Tuesday. Earlier, ISKCON (International Society for Krishna Consciousness) claimed that a Bangladeshi lawyer defending the Hindu monk was "brutally attacked at his home by Islamists" and is in the Intensive Care Unit.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, lawyers refused to appear for him during the bail hearing, following which the Chattogram court adjourned the proceedings. The court fixed the next date of hearing on January 2, 2025.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote has alleged that approximately 70 Hindu lawyers were "falsely sued in a case to prevent their participation" in a bail hearing for their spokesperson Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, according to a report by Bangladeshi daily <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.tbsnews.net/bangladesh/court/chinmoys-bail-hearing-rescheduled-2-jan-1008636" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">The Business Standard</a>.</p>

<p>Per the report, the minority coalition linked to the arrested Hindu monk, claimed in a statement on Sunday night that the lawyers were being sued in a case filed under the Explosives Act with Kotwali Police Station in Chattogram, to "sabotage their ability to advocate for Chinmoy Das".</p>

<p>The coalition reportedly also accused "members of a political group" of assaulting lawyers defending the priest.</p>

<p>On Monday, Radharaman Das, the spokesperson for ISKCON Kolkata, said in a post on X, "Please pray for Advocate Ramen Roy. His only 'fault' was defending Chinmoy Krishna Prabhu in court. Islamists ransacked his home and brutally attacked him, leaving him in the ICU, fighting for his life".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Please pray for Advocate Ramen Roy. His only 'fault' was defending Chinmoy Krishna Prabhu in court.<br />
<br />
Islamists ransacked his home and brutally attacked him, leaving him in the ICU, fighting for his life.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SaveBangladeshiHindus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SaveBangladeshiHindus</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FreeChinmoyKrishnaPrabhu?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FreeChinmoyKrishnaPrabhu</a> <a href="https://t.co/uudpC10bpN">pic.twitter.com/uudpC10bpN</a></p>
— Radharamn Das राधारमण दास (@RadharamnDas) <a href="https://twitter.com/RadharamnDas/status/1863593503609303469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Many lawyers in Bangladesh, however, have denied any such event.</p>

<p>Last month too, there were claims on social media and a few news outlets that a lawyer defending Chinmoy Krishna Das was killed. But investigations revealed that the murdered lawyer, Saiful Islam, was an assistant public prosecutor and he was not defending Chinmoy Das.</p>

<p>Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, a prominent former ISKCON leader, is currently serving as a spokesperson of Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote. He was arrested in Dhaka last month after protests by the Hindu community in Rangpur, demanding stronger legal protections for minority groups. The monk has been accused of sedition.</p>

<p>Following the rejection of his bail plea on November 26, clashes erupted between protestors and police outside Chattogram court premises, resulting in the killing of Advocate Saiful Islam Alif.</p>

<p>Four days later, the murdered lawyer's brother reportedly filed a case under the Explosives Act in Chattogram, naming 116 individuals as accused. His father also filed a murder case involving 31 suspects, the Bangladeshi daily report said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ninval3k_isckon-priest-hindu-priest-chinmoy-krishna-das_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-lawmakers-back-covid-chinese-lab-leak-theory-after-two-year-probe-7160244]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Lawmakers Back Covid Chinese Lab Leak Theory After Two-Year Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-lawmakers-back-covid-chinese-lab-leak-theory-after-two-year-probe-7160244]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 11:05:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US lawmakers concluded a two-year investigation Monday into the Covid-19 outbreak that killed 1.1 million Americans -- backing the theory that the virus likely leaked from a Chinese laboratory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US lawmakers concluded a two-year investigation Monday into the Covid-19 outbreak that killed 1.1 million Americans -- backing the theory that the virus likely leaked from a Chinese laboratory.</p>

<p>A 520-page report from the Republican-controlled House Select Sub-committee on the Coronavirus Pandemic looked at the federal and state-level response, as well as the pandemic's origins and vaccination efforts.</p>

<p>"This work will help the United States, and the world, predict the next pandemic, prepare for the next pandemic, protect ourselves from the next pandemic, and hopefully prevent the next pandemic," panel chairman Brad Wenstrup said in a letter to Congress.&nbsp;</p>

<p>US federal agencies, the World Health Organization and scientists across the planet have arrived at different conclusions about the most likely origin of Covid-19, and no consensus has emerged.</p>

<p>Most believe it to have spread from animals in China, but a US intelligence analysis said last year that the virus may have been genetically engineered and escaped from a virology lab in the Chinese city of Wuhan, where human cases first emerged.</p>

<p>The congressional panel was persuaded by the lab leak theory after meeting 25 times, conducting more than 30 transcribed interviews, and reviewing more than one million pages of documents.</p>

<p>The investigation included two days of interviews behind closed doors with Anthony Fauci, the government scientist who became the nation's most trusted expert in the chaotic early days of the 2020 outbreak.</p>

<p>Fauci's clashes with former and incoming president Donald Trump over the response sparked fury on the right, and he now lives with security protection following death threats against his family.</p>

<p>Republicans accuse the 83-year-old immunologist of helping to set off the worst pandemic in a century by approving funding passed on to Chinese scientists they accuse of manufacturing the SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus that causes Covid-19.</p>

<p>Among its headline conclusions, the report said the National Institutes of Health had indeed funded contentious "gain-of-function" research -- which seeks to enhance viruses as a way of finding ways to combat them -- at the Wuhan Institute of Virology.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fauci angrily denied covering up the origins of Covid-19 before the panel in June, arguing that it would be "molecularly impossible" for the bat viruses studied at the lab to be turned into the virus that caused the pandemic.</p>

<p>But the panel's report said SARS-CoV-2 "likely emerged because of a laboratory or research related accident."</p>

<p>The probe found that lockdowns "did more harm than good" and that mask mandates were "ineffective at controlling the spread of Covid-19," contradicting other research showing that masking in public does reduce transmission rates.</p>

<p>Social distancing guidelines also came under criticism, although travel restrictions were deemed to have saved lives.</p>

<p>Investigators found that Trump's Operation Warp Speed -- the publicly-funded project to develop Covid vaccines -- was a "tremendous success" but that school closures would have an "enduring impact" on US children.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/tadp2ib8_covid19-vaccine_625x300_06_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Most believe it to have spread from animals in China.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-aliya-fakhri-actor-nargis-fakhris-sister-arrested-for-killing-ex-boyfriend-7160117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Aliya Fakhri, Nargis Fakhri's Sister Arrested For Killing Ex Boyfriend]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-aliya-fakhri-actor-nargis-fakhris-sister-arrested-for-killing-ex-boyfriend-7160117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 10:48:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Aliya Fakhri, sister of actor Nargis Fakhri, was arrested for allegedly murdering her ex-boyfriend and his friend in Queens by setting a two-story garage on fire. The court has remanded her and her next appearance is scheduled for December 9.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Aliya Fakhri, 43, is the younger sister of actor&nbsp;Nargis Fakhri.</li>
	<li>She was born and raised in Queen, New York.</li>
	<li>Aliya and Nargis' father, Mohammed Fakhri, was a Pakistani, while their mother, Marie Fakhri, is Czech. Aliya's parents got divorced when she was a child, and shortly after, her father died.</li>
	<li>According to officials, Aliya arrived at the garage on the morning of November 2 and yelled "You are all going to die today" at Jacobs, who was sleeping at that time. Seconds later, the building was set on fire. Aliya has been charged with four counts of murder in the first degree and four counts of murder in the second degree, and has also been accused of arson by a grand jury.</li>
	<li>According to Aliya's mother, she struggled with opioid addiction after a dental mishap - which she believes may have led to her daughter's behaviour, several reports claimed.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/47k6chd8_aliya-fakhri_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Aliya Fakhri is the younger sister of actress Nargis Fakhri.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>