<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:45:48 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-envoy-bangladesh-home-adviser-meet-discuss-security-cooperation-safety-of-indians-6475816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Envoy, Bangladesh Home Adviser Meet, Discuss Security Cooperation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-envoy-bangladesh-home-adviser-meet-discuss-security-cooperation-safety-of-indians-6475816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:27:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma today met interim government's Home and Agriculture Adviser Lt Gen (Retd.) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury and discussed areas of engagement to advance security cooperation and safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma today met interim government's Home and Agriculture Adviser Lt Gen (Retd.) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury and discussed areas of engagement to advance security cooperation, exchanged views on border management, capacity building, and safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>During his meeting with Mr Chowdhury, Mr Verma also announced that Indian visa centres are now issuing a limited number of visas for Bangladeshi nationals, primarily for emergency medical needs and students pursuing studies abroad.</p>

<p>"HC Pranay Verma called on Bangladesh Home &amp; Agriculture Adviser Lt Gen (Retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today. Discussed areas of engagement to advance India-Bangladesh security cooperation, exchanged views on border management, capacity building, and safety &amp; security of India nationals &amp; students in Bangladesh," the High Commission of India in Bangladesh said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">HC Pranay Verma called on ??Home &amp; Agriculture Adviser H.E. Lt Gen (Retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today. Discussed areas of engagement to advance????security cooperation, exchanged views on border management, capacity building, and safety &amp; security of ??nationals &amp; students in?? <a href="https://t.co/oXLpi7F5MC">pic.twitter.com/oXLpi7F5MC</a></p>
— India in Bangladesh (@ihcdhaka) <a href="https://twitter.com/ihcdhaka/status/1830561362394919098?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>They also discussed areas of mutual interest in the agriculture sector, including possible collaboration between agricultural research institutions and exchanges in mechanized farming, post-harvest management etc, the mission said in another post.</p>

<p>According to the Daily Star newspaper, the meeting addressed a range of bilateral issues, including police reforms, border security, and the safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Our two countries should work together on flood warning and forecasting," the adviser was quoted as saying by the paper.</p>

<p>Mr Verma assured him of India's assistance with necessary data and information for flood warning and forecasting, the paper added.</p>

<p>The adviser assured the high commissioner that the Indian nationals residing in Bangladesh would be provided full security. He added that Indian students are welcome to continue their studies in Bangladesh, the paper said.</p>

<p>The interim government headed by 84-year-old Nobel laureate Yunus was installed days after prime minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled to India on August 5 following unprecedented anti-government student-led protests over a controversial quota system in government jobs.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g38ke30g_indian-envoy-pranay-verma-meets-bangladesh-home-adviser-jahangir-alam-chowdhury_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma met Bangladesh Home Adviser Lt Gen (Retd.) JA Chowdhury]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volkswagen-weighs-first-ever-germany-plant-closures-to-cut-costs-6475662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Volkswagen Weighs First-Ever Germany Plant Closures To Cut Costs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volkswagen-weighs-first-ever-germany-plant-closures-to-cut-costs-6475662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:43:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Volkswagen AG is considering unprecedented factory closures in Germany in a bid for deeper cutbacks, delivering another blow to Chancellor Olaf Scholz's government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Volkswagen AG is considering unprecedented factory closures in Germany in a bid for deeper cutbacks, delivering another blow to Chancellor Olaf Scholz's government.</p>

<p>The potential measures, targeting its main passenger car brand as well as other group operations, also include trying to end the company's pact with unions to keep jobs secure until 2029, the company said Monday. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Any shutdowns would mark the first closures in Germany during the company's 87-year history, setting VW up for a clash with powerful unions.</p>

<p>"The economic environment has become even tougher and new players are pushing into Europe," VW Chief Executive Officer Oliver Blume said in a statement. "Germany as a business location is falling further behind in terms of competitiveness."</p>

<p>A full-blown labor dispute would be a major test for the CEO - who also heads up the Porsche sports car brand - after union clashes felled a number of his VW predecessors. The company has struggled to cut costs at its namesake passenger brand where profit margins have long lagged, with efforts becoming harder amid a sputtering transition to EVs and a consumer spending slowdown.</p>

<p>Works council head Daniela Cavallo said VW's management had failed after meetings detailed that the company's core brand, making the Golf and Tiguan models, threatened to become loss-making, according to a separate statement. The company is plotting to close at least one larger carmaking factory and one component site in Germany, it said, alongside abolishing wage agreements.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4i8bid1o_volkswagen-germany-struggles-with-cost-cuts-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>VW employs about 650,000 workers globally, almost 300,000 of which are in Germany. Half the seats on the company's supervisory board are held by labor representatives, and the German state of Lower Saxony - which owns a 20% stake - often sides with trade union bodies.</p>

<p>Previous clashes ended or shortened the tenures of top executives including former CEO Bernd Pischetsrieder, ex-VW brand chief Wolfgang Bernhard and more Herbert Diess, Blume's predecessor as CEO. All three tried to push through efficiencies particularly at VW's domestic German operations.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/42bj4p6o_volkswagen-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volkswagen's headquarters in Wolfsburg, Germany. (Photo: Krisztian Bocsi / Bloomberg)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-immediately-suspends-30-of-its-350-arms-export-licenses-to-israel-6475594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Immediately Suspends 30 Of Its 350 Arms Export Licenses To Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-immediately-suspends-30-of-its-350-arms-export-licenses-to-israel-6475594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:33:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain will immediately suspend 30 of its 350 arms export licenses with Israel because there is a risk such equipment might be used to commit serious violations of international humanitarian law, foreign minister David Lammy said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain will immediately suspend 30 of its 350 arms export licenses with Israel because there is a risk such equipment might be used to commit serious violations of international humanitarian law, foreign minister David Lammy said on Monday.</p>

<p>Soon after the Labour Party won an election in July, Mr Lammy said he would update a review on arms sales to British ally Israel to ensure these complied with international law.</p>

<p>"It is with regret that I inform the House (of Commons, lower house of parliament) today that the assessment I have received leaves me unable to conclude anything other than that for certain UK arms exports to Israel, there does exist a clear risk that they might be used to commit or facilitate a serious violation of international humanitarian law," Lammy said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/repgssu8_keir-starmer-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The decision was made after a risk assessment of such equipment by the UK.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-13-wounded-in-suicide-bombing-in-afghanistans-kabul-cops-6475387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Killed, 13 Wounded In Suicide Bombing In Afghanistan's Kabul]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-13-wounded-in-suicide-bombing-in-afghanistans-kabul-cops-6475387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:04:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A suicide bomber detonated explosives in the Afghan capital on Monday, police said, killing six people and wounding 13 more.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A suicide bomber triggered explosives in the Afghan capital on Monday, police said, killing six people and wounding 13 more.</p>

<p>Violence has waned in Afghanistan since the 2021 Taliban takeover, however, several militant groups remain active including the regional chapter of Islamic State.</p>

<p>There was no immediate claim of responsibility for Monday afternoon's attack, which took place in the Qala-e-Bakhtiar area of Kabul's southern outskirts.</p>

<p>Kabul police spokesman Khalid Zadran said "a person wearing explosives on his body detonated", and one woman was among the fatalities.</p>

<p>"The injured were transferred to hospitals on time and investigations are ongoing," he posted on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Afghanistan's Taliban authorities have declared security their highest priority since surging back to power following the chaotic withdrawal of foreign forces three years ago.</p>

<p>While their sweeping security operations have led to a decline in militants challenging their rule, according to analysts, they also downplay or delay confirmation of attacks.</p>

<p>The last suicide attack in Afghanistan claimed by the regional chapter of Islamic State was in the southern city of Kandahar -- the Taliban's historic stronghold -- in March.</p>

<p>Taliban authorities said only three people were killed while a hospital source put the toll far higher at 20.</p>

<p>Taliban government spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid told AFP last month that Islamic State "existed here before but we suppressed them very hard".</p>

<p>"No such groups exist here that can pose a threat to anyone," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kfim27vg_kabul-blast-generic_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It took place in the southern Kabul area of Qala-e-Bakhtiar. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-researchers-find-probable-launch-site-of-russias-nuclear-powered-missile-9m370-burevestnik-6475004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia's "Invincible" Nuclear-Powered Nuke Launch Site Detected: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-researchers-find-probable-launch-site-of-russias-nuclear-powered-missile-9m370-burevestnik-6475004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 20:12:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two U.S. researchers say they have identified the probable deployment site in Russia of the 9M370 Burevestnik, a new nuclear-powered, nuclear-armed cruise missile touted by President Vladimir Putin as "invincible."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two U.S. researchers say they have identified the probable deployment site in Russia of the 9M370 Burevestnik, a new nuclear-powered, nuclear-armed cruise missile touted by President Vladimir Putin as "invincible."</p>

<p>Putin has said the weapon - dubbed the SSC-X-9 Skyfall by NATO - has an almost unlimited range and can evade U.S. missile defences. But some Western experts dispute his claims and the Burevestnik's strategic value, saying it will not add capabilities that Moscow does not already have and risks a radiation-spewing mishap.</p>

<p>Using images taken on July 26 by Planet Labs, a commercial satellite firm, the two researchers identified a construction project abutting a nuclear warhead storage facility known by two names - Vologda-20 and Chebsara - as the new missile's potential deployment site. The facility is 295 miles (475 km) north of Moscow.</p>

<p>Reuters is the first to report this development.</p>

<p>Decker Eveleth, an analyst with the CNA research and analysis organization, found the satellite imagery and identified what he assessed are nine horizontal launch pads under construction. They are located in three groups inside high berms to shield them from attack or to prevent an accidental blast in one from detonating missiles in the others, he said.</p>

<p>The berms are linked by roads to what Eveleth concluded are likely buildings where the missiles and their components would be serviced, and to the existing complex of five nuclear warhead storage bunkers.</p>

<p>The site is "for a large, fixed missile system and the only large, fixed missile system that they're (Russia) currently developing is the Skyfall," said Eveleth.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry and Washington embassy did not respond to a request to comment on his assessment, Burevestnik's strategic value, its test record and the risks it poses.</p>

<p>A Kremlin spokesman said these were questions for the defence ministry and declined further comment.</p>

<p>The U.S. State Department, the CIA, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence and the U.S. Air Force National Air and Space Intelligence Center declined to comment.</p>

<p>The identification of the missile's probable launch site suggests that Russia is proceeding with its deployment after a series of tests in recent years marred by problems, said Eveleth and the second researcher, Jeffery Lewis, of the Middlebury Institute of International Studies at Monterey.</p>

<p>Lewis agreed with Eveleth's assessment after reviewing the imagery at his request. The imagery "suggests something very unique, very different. And obviously, we know that Russia is developing this nuclear-powered missile," he said.</p>

<p>Hans Kristensen of the Federation of American Scientists, who also studied the Vologda imagery at Eveleth's request, said that it appears to show launch pads and other features "possibly" related to Burevestnik. But he said he could not make a definitive assessment because Moscow does not typically place missile launchers next to nuclear warhead storage.</p>

<p>Eveleth, Lewis, Kristensen and three other experts said Moscow's normal practice has been stockpiling nuclear payloads for land-based missiles far from launch sites - except for those on its deployed Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) force.</p>

<p>But deploying the Burevestnik at Vologda would allow the Russian military to stockpile the nuclear-armed missiles in its bunkers, making them available to launch quickly, said Lewis and Eveleth.</p>

<p>Deputy Foreign Minister Sergei Ryabkov said Russia will make changes to its guidelines on the use of nuclear weapons in response to what it regards as Western escalation in the war in Ukraine, state news agency TASS reported on Sunday.</p>

<p><strong>POOR TEST RECORD</strong></p>

<p>A 2020 report by the United States Air Force's National Air and Space Intelligence Center said that if Russia successfully brought the Burevestnik into service, it would give Moscow a "unique weapon with intercontinental-range capability".</p>

<p>But the weapon's checkered past and design limitations raised doubts among eight experts interviewed by Reuters about whether its deployment would change the nuclear stakes for the West and other Russian foes.</p>

<p>The Burevestnik has a poor test record of at least 13 known tests, with only two partial successes, since 2016, according to the Nuclear Threat Initiative (NTI), an advocacy group focused on reducing nuclear, biological and emergent technology risks.</p>

<p>The setbacks include a 2019 blast during the botched recovery of an unshielded nuclear reactor allowed to "smoulder" on the White Sea floor for a year following a prototype crash, according to State Department reports.</p>

<p>Russia's state nuclear agency Rosatom said five staff members died during the testing of a rocket on August 8. Putin presented their widows with top state awards, saying the weapon they were developing was without equal in the world, without naming the Burevestnik.</p>

<p>Pavel Podvig, a Geneva-based expert on Russia's nuclear forces, Lewis, Eveleth, and other experts said it will not add capabilities that Moscow's nuclear forces already do not have, including the ability to overwhelm U.S. missile defences.</p>

<p>Moreover, its nuclear-powered engine threatens to disgorge radiation along its flight path and its deployment risks an accident that could contaminate the surrounding region, said Cheryl Rofer, a former U.S. nuclear weapons scientist and other experts.</p>

<p>"The Skyfall is a uniquely stupid weapon system, a flying Chernobyl that poses more threat to Russia than it does to other countries," agreed Thomas Countryman, a former top State Department official with the Arms Control Association, referring to the 1986 nuclear plant disaster.</p>

<p>NATO did not respond to questions about how the alliance would respond to the weapon's deployment.</p>

<p>Little publicly is known about the Burevestnik's technical details.</p>

<p>Experts assess that it would be sent aloft by a small solid-fuel rocket to drive air into an engine containing a miniature nuclear reactor. Superheated and possibly radioactive air would be blasted out, providing forward thrust.</p>

<p>Putin unveiled it in March 2018, saying the missile would be "low flying," with nearly unlimited range, an unpredictable flight path and "invincible" to current and future defences.</p>

<p>Many experts are sceptical of Putin's claims.</p>

<p>The Burevestnik, they say, could have a range of some 15,000 miles (23,000 km) - compared to more than 11,000 miles (17,700 km) for the Sarmat, Russia's newest ICBM - while its subsonic speed would make it detectable.</p>

<p>"It's going to be as vulnerable as any cruise missile," said Kristensen. "The longer it flies, the more vulnerable it becomes because there is more time to track it. I don't understand Putin's motive here."</p>

<p>The Burevestnik's deployment is not banned by New START, the last U.S.-Russian accord limiting strategic nuclear weapon deployments, which expires in February 2026.</p>

<p>A provision allows Washington to request negotiations with Moscow on bringing the Burevestnik under the caps but a State Department spokesperson said no such talks had been sought.</p>

<p>Citing the war in Ukraine, Russia has spurned U.S. calls for unconditional talks on replacing New START, stoking fears of an all-out nuclear arms race when it expires.</p>

<p>Podvig said Moscow might use the missile as a bargaining chip if talks ever resume.</p>

<p>He called the Burevestnik a "political weapon" that Putin used to bolster his strongman image before his 2018 re-election and to telegraph to Washington that it cannot dismiss his concerns over U.S. missile defences and other issues.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cadomeog_9m370-burevestnik-launch-site_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reuters is the first to report this development.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-navys-p8i-poseidon-aircraft-reaches-france-1st-ever-deployment-in-europe-6472691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Navy's P8i Poseidon Aircraft Reaches France, 1st-Ever Deployment In Europe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-navys-p8i-poseidon-aircraft-reaches-france-1st-ever-deployment-in-europe-6472691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 19:55:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a first-ever such deployment by India in Europe, an Indian Navy P8i aircraft has landed in France at the Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a first-ever such deployment by India in Europe, an Indian Navy P8i Poseidon aircraft has landed in France at the Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube. The purpose of the deployment is to participate in the joint naval exercise 'Varuna' in which France is also participating.</p>

<p>"A P8i aircraft of the Indian Navy has reached France to participate in a joint naval exercise with the French Navy," a senior navy official said.</p>

<p>The 2024 edition of Indo-French bilateral naval 'Exercise Varuna', is scheduled from September 2 to September 4 in the Mediterranean Sea.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="2024 edition of Indo-French naval Exercise Varuna is scheduled from Sept 2-4 in the Mediterranean Sea" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lg7ok3to_indian-navy-maritime-exercise-ians_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="2024 edition of Indo-French naval Exercise Varuna is scheduled from Sept 2-4 in the Mediterranean Sea" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">2024 edition of Indo-French naval 'Exercise Varuna' is scheduled from Sept 2-4 in the Mediterranean Sea</p>
</div>

<p>"The drill will include advanced tactical exercises underscoring the deepening synergy and interoperability between the two navies," a spokesperson of the Indian Navy said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This deployment comes 63 years after the Indian Navy's Alize aircraft, operating from the erstwhile INS Vikrant, last flew at Hyeres Airbase," the spokesperson said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Indian Navy personnel of the P-8I aircraft upon touch down at Frances Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k82h0878_indian-navy-p8i-poseidon-aircraft-with-2-sukhoi-su30-mki_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="Indian Navy personnel of the P-8I aircraft upon touch down at Frances Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">An Indian Navy P8i Poseidon aircraft has landed in France at the Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube</p>
</div>

<p>INS Tabar, which had earlier arrived in Toulon will also be participating in the exercise.</p>

<p><strong>THE INDIAN NAVY P8i AIRCRAFT</strong></p>

<p>The P-8 Poseidon is a maritime patrol and reconnaissance aircraft developed and produced by United States' Boeing Defense. It is derived from the civilian Boeing 737-800 airliner. The P8i is a variant of the P-8 Poseidon specially designed for the Indian Navy.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Indian Navys fleet of P8i has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7ttse4b4_indian-navy-p8i-fleet_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="Indian Navys fleet of P8i has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Indian Navy's fleet of P8i Poseidon has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013.</p>
</div>

<p>The Indian Navy's P8i fleet aims to replace the aging Tupolev Tu-142M maritime surveillance turboprops.</p>

<p>Indian Navy's fleet of P8i Poseidon has surpassed 35,000 flight-hours, since their induction in 2013. The Indian Navy has twelve P8i aircraft in total. The P8i is not just responsible for coastal patrolling but is also used for other critical missions like maritime surveillance, anti-submarine and anti-surface warfare, search-and-rescue, anti-piracy, and supporting operations of other arms of the military.</p>

<p><strong>THE VARUNA NAVAL EXERCISE</strong></p>

<p>The Varuna Naval Exercise is a bilateral maritime drill between the Indian and French navies. The drill usually sees participation of guided missile frigates, tanker, Maritime Patrol Aircraft and integral helicopters from the two sides.</p>

<p>Indian &amp; French Navy bilateral naval exercise was initiated in 1993. The exercise was later christened as 'Varuna' in 2001 and has since become a hallmark of robust India-France strategic bilateral relationship. Having grown in scope and complexity over the years, this exercise provides an opportunity to learn from each other's best practices and procedures.</p>

<p>According to the Ministry of Defence, the exercise also facilitates operational level interaction between the two navies to foster mutual cooperation for good order at sea, underscoring the shared commitment to ensuring security, safety and freedom of the global maritime commons.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t637rkmc_indian-navy-p8i-poseidon-1st-deployment-in-europe-pti_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian Navy personnel of the P-8I aircraft upon touch down at France's Air Base 125 Istres-Le Tube]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/at-global-meet-s-jaishankar-shares-indian-perspective-of-global-situation-at-ambassadors-conference-of-austrian-foreign-ministry-6474707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Global Meet, S Jaishankar Shares "Indian Perspective Of Global Situation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/at-global-meet-s-jaishankar-shares-indian-perspective-of-global-situation-at-ambassadors-conference-of-austrian-foreign-ministry-6474707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 19:34:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Monday virtually addressed the Ambassadors Conference of Austrian Foreign Ministry at the invitation of Austrian Foreign Minister Alexander Schallenberg.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Monday virtually addressed the Ambassadors Conference of Austrian Foreign Ministry at the invitation of Austrian Foreign Minister Alexander Schallenberg.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar shared Indian perspective on global situation and the prospects of bilateral relationship and European Union.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Mr Jaishankar said, "Pleased to address the Ambassadors Conference of Austrian Foreign Ministry today. Thank FM Alexander Schallenberg for the invitation. Shared with them Indian perspective of the global situation, as well as the prospects for our own bilateral relationship and that with the European Union."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Pleased to address the Ambassadors Conference of <a href="https://twitter.com/MFA_Austria?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MFA_Austria</a> today. Thank FM <a href="https://twitter.com/a_schallenberg?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@a_schallenberg</a> for the invitation.<br />
<br />
Shared with them Indian perspective of the global situation, as well as the prospects for our own bilateral relationship and that with the European Union.<br />
<br />
?? ?? <a href="https://t.co/qcS3VU019i">pic.twitter.com/qcS3VU019i</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1830546101725736999?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, Schallenberg lauded Mr Jaishankar and emphasised that during such challenging times, effective foreign policy relies on continuous engagement with key partners outside of Europe more than ever.</p>

<p>"On the occasion of our annual ambassadors conference, great to hear from my good friend @DrSJaishankar. In these challenging times, effective foreign policy relies on continuous engagement with key partners outside of Europe more than ever," posted the Austrian Foreign Minister on X.</p>

<p>Notably, Prime Minister Narendra Modi paid an official visit to Austria on July 9-10, 2024, this was the first visit by an Indian Prime Minister to Austria in 41 years, marking the 75th year of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p>

<p>The visit aimed to elevate bilateral relations to new heights through enhanced cooperation in various sectors, including technology, economy, and global security.</p>

<p>PM Modi and Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer emphasised that the shared values of democracy, freedom, international peace and security, a rules-based international order with the UN Charter at its core, the shared historical linkages, and the long-standing ties between the two countries are at the centre of the growing enhanced partnership.</p>

<p>They reiterated their commitment to continue their efforts towards deepening and widening bilateral, regional and international cooperation for a more stable, prosperous and sustainable world.</p>

<p>Both nations reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific region, ensuring maritime security and adhering to international laws such as United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS).</p>

<p>Discussions included assessments of developments in Europe and West Asia, with a shared focus on restoring peace and adherence to international law, notably concerning the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>The leaders welcomed the launch of the India-Middle East-Europe Corridor (IMEC) and Austria's interest to engage with this initiative.</p>

<p>The leaders agreed on a future-oriented economic partnership focusing on green and digital technologies, infrastructure, renewable energy, and smart cities.The first high-level bilateral Business Forum was convened, promoting partnerships across sectors and encouraging CEO-level interactions to explore new opportunities.</p>

<p>Recognizing their commitments under the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), both countries pledged to collaborate on renewable energy, with a specific focus on Austria's Hydrogen Strategy and India's Green Hydrogen Mission. As parties to the UNFCCC and committed to limiting the global temperature increase to below 2°C, leaders acknowledged the importance of reducing climate change risks.</p>

<p>They noted the EU's target for climate neutrality by 2050, Austria's goal for 2040, and India's aim for net zero emissions by 2070.</p>

<p>Initiatives such as the Start-Up Bridge and exchanges under Austria's Global Incubator Network and India's Start-Up India were highlighted as crucial for fostering innovation and entrepreneurship.</p>

<p>They also acknowledged the increasing importance of digital technologies in industrial processes (Industry 4.0), including in the sustainable economy.</p>

<p>Both leaders reiterated their commitment to multilateralism and supported comprehensive reforms of the United Nations. India reiterated its support for Austria's UNSC candidature for the term 2027-28, while Austria expressed its support for India's candidature for the period 2028-29.</p>

<p>India invited Austria to join the International Solar Alliance (ISA), highlighting collaboration in renewable energy and sustainable development.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iltj1phg_s-jaishankar-_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar shared the prospects of bilateral relationship and European Union.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-urges-countries-to-accelerate-measures-to-reduce-road-traffic-deaths-6473910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Urges Countries To Accelerate Measures To Reduce Road Traffic Deaths]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-urges-countries-to-accelerate-measures-to-reduce-road-traffic-deaths-6473910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 17:58:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization on Monday called on countries in the WHO South-East Asia Region to accelerate measures to reduce road traffic deaths, a leading cause of mortality among young people aged 15-29.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization on Monday called on countries in the WHO South-East Asia Region to accelerate measures to reduce road traffic deaths, a leading cause of mortality among young people aged 15-29.</p>

<p>"Vulnerable road users, including pedestrians, bicyclists and two or three-wheelers constitute 66 per cent of all reported road traffic deaths in our region," said Saima Wazed, Regional Director, WHO South-East Asia, in her address at the 15th World Conference on Injury Prevention and Safety Promotion (Safety 2024) which began here today.</p>

<p>She emphasised that the roads and their networks need to be designed prioritising those most at risk -- children and adolescents, people with disabilities, pedestrians and other vulnerable groups.</p>

<p>The WHO South-East Asia Region accounted for 330,223 of the 1.19 million estimated global road traffic deaths in 2021, representing 28 pc of the global burden, the WHO said in a statement.</p>

<p>With 70 per cent of the global population projected to live in urban areas by 2030, demand for public transport will surge. The WHO South-East Asia Region, amid rapid urbanisation, faces shared challenges -- a high prevalence of motorised two and three-wheelers, inadequate traffic injury data, poor pedestrian and cyclist infrastructure, and limited emergency services, it said.</p>

<p>Unlike high-income countries, where road safety measures often focus on car occupants, low and middle-income countries need to prioritise the safety of vulnerable road users, such as pedestrians, cyclists and riders of two and three-wheelers who are disproportionately at higher risk.</p>

<p>Strengthening trauma and emergency care systems, enhancing road safety data, strong leadership and promoting collaboration among all stakeholders are essential for improving road safety, the statement said.</p>

<p>"I am a great believer in collaborations and partnerships -- and expanding these to non-traditional stakeholders," said the regional director.</p>

<p>"This can be our moment to rethink and redo mobility for healthy cities. A holistic approach requires a cross-cutting, multi-sectoral approach, requiring collaboration with local governments, urban planners, traffic policing, law enforcement and others," she added.</p>

<p>Road safety, a public health and development priority, is crucial to achieving the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). In September 2020, the UN General Assembly launched the Decade of Action for Road Safety 2021-2030 which aims to reduce road traffic deaths and injuries by at least 50 per cent by 2030, Wazed said.</p>

<p>While the WHO South-East Asia Region saw a 2 per cent decrease in road fatalities in 2021, contributing to a global 5 per cent reduction, further efforts are needed to meet global targets.</p>

<p>At the World Conference, the regional director launched the 'WHO South-East Asia Regional Status Report on Road Safety: Towards Safer and Sustainable Mobility.' "This report outlines road traffic injury patterns in our countries and highlights best practices and country-specific interventions. It is both timely and essential for assessing our current position, and for guiding necessary actions to achieve global targets," she stated.</p>

<p>Addressing these challenges and implementing recommended strategies will be key to advancing road safety and reaching the 2030 targets, Wazed stated.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j2om9ag8_saima-wajid_625x300_02_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vulnerable road users constitute 66% of all reported road traffic deaths in our region, said Saima Wajid]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-bids-to-join-brics-in-push-to-build-alliances-beyond-west-6473870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkey Bids To Join BRICS In Push To Build Alliances Beyond West]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-bids-to-join-brics-in-push-to-build-alliances-beyond-west-6473870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 17:53:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Turkey has formally asked to join the BRICS group of emerging-market nations as it seeks to bolster its global influence and forge new ties beyond its traditional Western allies, according to people familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Turkey has formally asked to join the BRICS group of emerging-market nations as it seeks to bolster its global influence and forge new ties beyond its traditional Western allies, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The view of President Recep Tayyip Erdogan's administration is that the geopolitical center of gravity is shifting away from developed economies, according to the people, who spoke on condition of anonymity because they aren't authorized to comment.</p>

<p>The country's new diplomatic push reflects its aspirations to cultivate ties with all sides in a multipolar world, while still fulfilling its obligations as a key member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, they said.</p>

<p>Straddling Europe and Asia, Turkey submitted an application to join BRICS some months ago amid frustration over a lack of progress in its decades-old bid to join the European Union, the people added. The bid is also partly a result of rifts with fellow NATO members after Turkey maintained close links with Russia following its invasion of Ukraine in 2022, the people added. Turkey's foreign ministry and presidency declined to comment.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Bosphorus strait in Istanbul. (Photo Credit: Moe Zoyari / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qinv9hto_bosphorus-strait-istanbul-turkey-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpg" title="The Bosphorus strait in Istanbul. (Photo Credit: Moe Zoyari / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The Bosphorus strait in Istanbul. (Photo Credit: Moe Zoyari / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p>"Turkey can become a strong, prosperous, prestigious and effective country if it improves its relations with the East and the West simultaneously," Erdogan said in Istanbul over the weekend. "Any method other than this will not benefit Turkey, but will harm it."</p>

<p>The BRICS grouping, named after Brazil, Russia, India and China and South Africa, includes some of the biggest emerging economies. It got four new members at the start of this year when Iran, the United Arab Emirates, Ethiopia and Egypt joined its ranks. Saudi Arabia was invited to join, though the kingdom is yet to do that.</p>

<p>The group's further enlargement could be discussed during a summit in Kazan, Russia, from Oct. 22-24, said the people. Malaysia, Thailand and Turkey's close ally Azerbaijan are among other countries looking to join.</p>

<p>The BRICS touts itself as an alternative to what its members see as Western-dominated institutions such as the World Bank and International Monetary Fund. New members can potentially get access to financing through its development bank as well as broaden their political and trading relationships.</p>

<p>Erdogan's ruling Justice and Development Party has long accused Western nations of thwarting Turkish aspirations for a self-sufficient defense industry and strong economy. The president has repeatedly called for an overhaul of the United Nations Security Council to broaden its five permanent members, and expressed interest in joining the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, set up by Russia and China as a rival to NATO.</p>

<p>"We do not have to choose between the European Union and the Shanghai Cooperation Organization as some people claim," Erdogan said. "On the contrary, we have to develop our relations with both these and other organizations on a win-win basis."</p>

<p>BRICS expansion has largely been driven by China, which is trying to boost its global clout by courting nations traditionally allied with the US.</p>

<p>Turkey has been in talks to join the EU since 2005, but has encountered a series of obstacles, including what that bloc describes as the country's democratic shortcomings.</p>

<p>Turkey believes joining the BRICS could help the country improve economic cooperation with Russia and China, and become a trade conduit between the EU and Asia. It wants to be a hub for gas exports out of Russia and Central Asia, the people said.</p>

<p>Erdogan's administration has been trying to lure investment from Chinese electric carmakers, which could potentially take advantage of Turkey's customs union with the EU to boost their market access.</p>

<p>"BRICS is an organization that increases the diversity of approaches, identities and politics in the global economic system," Turkey's Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan said after attending a BRICS foreign ministers meeting in June.</p>

<p>Still, Turkey is making parallel efforts to rejuvenate membership talks with the EU. That remains "a strategic target," Fidan said last week after attending informal talks with EU counterparts for the first time in five years.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t6dduh54_recep-tayyip-erdogan-bloomberg_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Straddling Europe and Asia, Turkey submitted an application to join BRICS some months ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/firing-outside-ap-dhillons-canada-house-gangster-claims-responsibility-6473453]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Firing Outside AP Dhillon's Canada House, Gangster Claims Responsibility]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/firing-outside-ap-dhillons-canada-house-gangster-claims-responsibility-6473453]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 17:05:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shots were reportedly fired outside Punjabi singer AP Dhillon's house on Victoria Island in Canada's Vancouver.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shots were reportedly fired outside Punjabi singer AP Dhillon's house on Victoria Island in Canada's Vancouver. The incident took place yesterday and a man named Rohit Godara, a member of the Lawrence Bishnoi gang, has reportedly taken responsibility for the incident.</p>

<p>A video, which can not be independently verified, shows a man standing outside a house firing multiple shots at night. The video is being circulated on the internet but the location remains unverified.</p>

<p>AP Dhillon lives on Victoria Island in British Columbia.</p>

<p>A purported post is being circulated where the gangster, Rohit Godara, is claiming that the firing took place at two locations in Canada - Victoria Island and Woodbridge Toronto. According to the post, he fired outside the singer's house after he featured Salman Khan in a music video. He also gave death threats to the singer in the purported post. The gangster claims he is associated with Lawrence Bishnoi.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Shots being fired outside a house in Canada" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s7r8t488_firing-canada_625x300_02_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Shots being fired outside a house in Canada" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Shots being fired outside a house in Canada</p>
</div>

<p>Security agencies are verifying the claims made in the post and analysing the video. The singer is yet to respond to the incident. The police in Canada have not responded to the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>AP Dhillon is known for blending the 80s-style synth-pop with Punjabi music. His rise on the global canvas has been meteoric owing to songs like 'Brown Munde', 'Excuses', 'Summer High', 'With You', 'Dil Nu', and 'Insane', among others.</p>

<p>In November last year, gangster Lawrence Bishnoi claimed responsibility for a purported shooting at singer Gippy Grewal's house in Canada. The alleged incident took place in the White Rock neighbourhood in Vancouver.</p>

<p>In April, two motorcycle-borne persons opened fire outside Khan's residence at the Galaxy Apartment in Mumbai's Bandra area and fled the spot. The Mumbai police declared jailed gangster Lawrence Bishnoi and his younger brother Anmol Bishnoi as "wanted accused" in connection with the incident.</p>

<p>Last year, the National Investigation Agency (NIA) said that Mr Khan topped the list of 10 main targets that jailed gangster Lawrence Bishnoi planned to eliminate, citing the actor's infamous 1998 black buck hunting incident, which according to the gangster, offended the Bishnoi community.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3ek8af9_-old-money_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-tv-or-screen-for-toddlers-at-all-sweden-recommends-parents-6473141]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No TV Or Screen For Toddlers At All, Sweden Recommends Parents]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-tv-or-screen-for-toddlers-at-all-sweden-recommends-parents-6473141]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 16:27:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Children under the age of two should be kept away from digital media and television completely, Sweden's Public Health Agency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Toddlers should not be allowed to watch screens at all, Sweden told parents on Monday.</p>

<p>Children under the age of two should be kept away from digital media and television completely, the country's Public Health Agency said.</p>

<p>Kids between the ages of two and five should be limited to a maximum of one hour of screen time a day, it said in new recommendations, while those aged six to 12 should spend no more than an hour or two a day in front of a screen.</p>

<p>Teenagers aged 13 to 18 should be limited to two to three hours per day, the agency said.</p>

<p>"For too long, smartphones and other screens have been allowed to enter every aspect of our children's lives," Public Health Minister Jakob Forssmed told reporters.</p>

<p>The minister said that Swedish teens aged 13 to 16 spend six and a half hours a day on average in front of their screens, outside of school hours.</p>

<p>Forssmed said that didn't leave "a lot of time for communal activities, physical activity or adequate sleep", and lamented a Swedish "sleep crisis" noting that more than half of 15-year-olds did not get enough sleep.</p>

<p>The health agency also recommended that kids not use screens before going to bed and that phones and tablets be kept out of bedroom at night.</p>

<p>It cited research showing that excessive screen use can lead to poor sleep, depression and body dissatisfaction.</p>

<p>Sweden's government has previously said it is looking at a ban on smartphones in primary schools.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/1rfldvag_tv-generic_625x300_28_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The health agency also recommended that kids not use screens before going to bed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-hates-donald-trump-wants-kamala-harris-to-win-ex-aides-stunning-claim-6472810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Melania Trump Hates Donald Trump, Wants Kamala Harris To Win": Ex-Aide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-hates-donald-trump-wants-kamala-harris-to-win-ex-aides-stunning-claim-6472810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 15:40:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The former White House Communications Director Anthony Scaramucci has made a stunning claim - that Donald Trump's wife Melania is secretly rooting for Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The former White House Communications Director Anthony Scaramucci has made a stunning claim - that Donald Trump's wife Melania is secretly rooting for Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris. He went on to claim that Melania Trump is supporting Kamala Harris because "she hates Donald Trump".</p>

<p>Mr Scaramucci, in his recent interview on the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iOCyN9nXXIE" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">MediasTouch podcast</a>, claimed Melania Trump is even more enthusiastic about a Kamala Harris victory than he is.</p>

<p>Interestingly, Mr Scaramucci's remarks come at a time when the former First Lady has been absent at husband Donald Trump's political campaign rallies. She was seen only at a few fundraising events and the rally in which there was an assassination attempt on Trump.</p>

<p>Speaking with host Ben Meiselas, Mr Scaramucci claimed Melania Trump is far more keener than him to see Kamala Harris take over the White House. In a response to a question, he said "Maybe Melania Trump. That could be the only person I think of. Because she hates (Trump)," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Scaramucci went on to say that his wife hates Donald Trump too. "My wife hates Trump as much as Melania does," adding jokingly that even the host of the interview is "nicer to Trump than Melania is".</p>

<p><strong>WHO IS ANTHONY SCARAMUCCI?</strong></p>

<p>Anthony Scaramucci was responsible for all communications at the White House for a mere eleven days in 2017 - from July 21 to July 31, following which he was fired by Donald Trump. According to UK news website <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-4718658/Sean-Spicer-resigns-White-House-Press-Secretary.html" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Daily Mail</a>, Mr Scaramucci's appointment led to White House Press Secretary Sean Spicer's resignation the very next day. Mr Spicer had voiced his displeasure about Mr Scaramucci being hired.</p>

<p>Within a few days of his appointment Mr Scaramucci found himself in a major PR mess, soon after which then President Donald Trump fired him. John Kelly, the Chief of Staff at the time also questioned his credibility.</p>

<p><strong>DONALD TRUMP TRASHES CLAIMS</strong></p>

<p>Donald Trump has rubbished Mr Scaramucci's comments about him and his wife Melania. Mr Trump dismisses his allegations saying his former aide is a bitter man who holds a grudge.</p>

<p><strong>MELANIA TRUMP'S LOW ATTENDANCE AT TRUMP RALLIES</strong></p>

<p>Melania Trump has been keeping a low profile and has hardly attended husband Donald Trump's rallies. She is reportedly occupied with her son Barron Trump's college education and spends most of her time in New York, where her son is planning to attend college. She has also expressed her fondness for New York.</p>

<p>Melania Trump is reportedly focusing more on family and personal milestones, than on Donald Trump's 2024 Presidential campaign. On October 1 this year, she will release her memoir, Melania. Her office describes the book as "a powerful and inspiring story of a woman who has forged her own path, overcome challenges, and defined personal excellence."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/ccijet1o_donald-trump-melania-trump_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A former Trump aide has claimed that Melania Trump is rooting for Kamala Harris over Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-report-strange-noises-from-boeing-starliner-spacecraft-6472674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams, Butch Wilmore Report Strange Noises From Spacecraft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-report-strange-noises-from-boeing-starliner-spacecraft-6472674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 15:24:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA astronauts on board the International Space Station (ISS) have reported strange, unexplained noises coming from the Boeing Starliner spacecraft. This unexpected incident comes just days before Starliner's scheduled undocking and return to Earth]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA astronauts on board the International Space Station (ISS) have reported strange, unexplained noises coming from the Boeing Starliner spacecraft. This unexpected incident comes just days before Starliner's scheduled undocking and return to Earth without a crew on September 6.<br />
<br />
Astronaut Butch Wilmore, currently stranded on the ISS alongside Sunita Williams, contacted NASA's Mission Control in Houston to report the unusual sounds. In a recorded conversation, Wilmore noted the noise sounded almost like a sonar ping.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
NASA's Mission Control confirmed the noise as a "pulsing" sound but has yet to determine its origin. The sound has been a source of concern and speculation among both the crew and NASA engineers.<br />
<br />
Experts propose mundane possibilities, such as electromagnetic interference or audio system feedback.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Starliner crew reports hearing strange "sonar like noises" emanating from their craft. This is the real audio of it: <a href="https://t.co/xzHTMvB7uq">pic.twitter.com/xzHTMvB7uq</a></p>
— SpaceBasedFox ????????????????????????????????????????????.???????????? (@SpaceBasedFox) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceBasedFox/status/1830180273130242223?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Chris Hadfield, astronaut and former commander of the ISS, said, “There are several noises I'd prefer not to hear inside my spaceship, including this one that Boeing Starliner is now making.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">There are several noises I'd prefer not to hear inside my spaceship, including this one that <a href="https://twitter.com/Boeing?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Boeing</a> Starliner is now making. <a href="https://t.co/NMMPMo5dtt">pic.twitter.com/NMMPMo5dtt</a></p>
— Chris Hadfield (@Cmdr_Hadfield) <a href="https://twitter.com/Cmdr_Hadfield/status/1830380090569494973?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“You saying this hits a lot differently than nearly anyone else saying this,” a user commented.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">You saying this hits a lot differently than nearly anyone else saying this</p>
— Cbo (@cbo_mlb) <a href="https://twitter.com/cbo_mlb/status/1830383944237265387?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another asked if it was “some sort of pressure or temperature change.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">any guesses, chris? some sort of pressure or temperature change?</p>
— sam mcallister (@sammcallister) <a href="https://twitter.com/sammcallister/status/1830381455266005397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, someone speculated, “This sounds like a feedback loop between a ground station and the spacecraft that is being modulated by an AGC (automatic gain control) circuit. The approximately one second cycle time would be a combination of transmission distance, buffering and the cycling of the AGC circuit.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My personal speculation:<br />
<br />
These comm systems are complex and robust, however; This sounds like a feedback loop between a ground station and the spacecraft that is being modulated by an AGC (automatic gain control) circuit. The approximately one second cycle time would be a…</p>
— DGM (@DGMJK) <a href="https://twitter.com/DGMJK/status/1830410916992516440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Starliner mission, initially planned for an eight-day duration, has faced numerous delays and technical challenges. Wilmore and Williams have been aboard the ISS for nearly three months due to issues, including thruster failures and helium leaks.<br />
<br />
With the Starliner now set for an unmanned return, NASA has decided to bring Wilmore and Williams back to Earth in February 2025 aboard a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/720ksnho_sunita-williams_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a recorded conversation, Wilmore noted the noise sounded almost like a sonar ping.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-says-kursk-incursion-will-not-halt-russian-advance-in-eastern-ukraine-6472539]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Says Kursk Incursion Will Not Halt Russian Advance In Eastern Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-says-kursk-incursion-will-not-halt-russian-advance-in-eastern-ukraine-6472539]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 15:06:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin said Monday that Kyiv's incursion into Russia's Kursk region will not stop Moscow's advance in east Ukraine and vowed to deal with Ukrainian "bandits" there.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin said Monday that Kyiv's incursion into Russia's Kursk region will not stop Moscow's advance in east Ukraine and vowed to deal with Ukrainian "bandits" there.</p>

<p>Ukraine's surprise August 6 incursion into Russia has displaced around 130,000 people and seen Kyiv hold on to parts of the border Kursk region.</p>

<p>Moscow has since continued to press into east Ukraine, resisting pulling troops from occupied Ukraine towards Kursk.</p>

<p>"Their calculation was to stop our offensive actions in key parts of the Donbas. The result is known... They did not achieve stopping our advance in the Donbas," Putin told schoolchildren in Siberia.</p>

<p>"The result is clear. Yes, people are going through difficult experiences, especially in the Kursk region. But the main aim that the enemy had -- to stop our offensive in Donbas -- it did not achieve," Putin said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He added Moscow is seeing advances at a "rate that we did not have for a long time."</p>

<p>Kyiv has said one of its aims of going into Kursk was to stretch the Russian army and force it to pull reserves from east Ukraine.</p>

<p>"We have to of course deal with these bandits that entered the territory of the Russian Federation, specifically the Kursk region, attempting to destabilise the situation in the border areas," Putin said.</p>

<p>The Russian leader's language was a break from previous statements on the incursion, which he had described as "the situation that has evolved".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pqsvmrc_vladimir-putin-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin said Moscow is seeing advances at a rate that they did not see for a long time (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isis-is-no-longer-a-threat-says-iraq-pm-6472447]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[ISIS Is No Longer A Threat, Says Iraq PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isis-is-no-longer-a-threat-says-iraq-pm-6472447]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 14:55:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iraqi Prime Minister Mohammed Shia al-Sudani said that the Islamic State (IS) militant group no longer poses a threat to Iraq and dialogue to end the US-led international coalition to fight the IS group continues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iraqi Prime Minister Mohammed Shia al-Sudani said that the Islamic State (ISIS) terrorist group no longer poses a threat to Iraq and dialogue to end the US-led international coalition to fight the IS group continues.</p>

<p>Al-Sudani made the remarks during talks with Major General Kevin C. Leahy, commander of the US-led coalition against ISIS in Iraq, in the presence of US ambassador to Iraq Alina L. Romanowski, said al-Sudani's media office in a statement, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>The remnants of ISIS terrorists have turned into gangs that are being hunted by Iraqi forces in remote areas of the country, the statement said.</p>

<p>The meeting focused on "the progress of the technical dialogue between Iraq and the US-led international coalition about ending the coalition's mission in the country and transferring the mission to bilateral relations between Iraq and the coalition member states," it said.</p>

<p>The discussions also covered ongoing cooperation in training, sharing expertise, and intelligence collaboration with Iraqi security forces, it added.</p>

<p>On January 25, the Iraqi foreign ministry announced that Iraq and the United States had agreed to establish the High-Level Military Committee to oversee the end of the international coalition mission in Iraq and that the focus would shift to developing comprehensive bilateral relations with coalition countries across political, economic, cultural, security, and military dimensions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/7h2cf25_us-iraq_625x300_10_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iraq's PM made the remarks during talks with the commander of the US-led coalition against ISIS in Iraq.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-singapore-visit-to-bilateral-take-ties-to-an-entirely-new-level-foreign-ministry-6472135]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM's Singapore Visit To Take Ties To "Entirely New Level": Foreign Ministry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-singapore-visit-to-bilateral-take-ties-to-an-entirely-new-level-foreign-ministry-6472135]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 14:09:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi will be on an official visit to Singapore on September 4, 5 to further strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will be on an official visit to Singapore on September 4, 5 to further strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations. The prime minister's visit comes a fortnight after the high-level roundtable between top ministers of both countries.</p>

<p>"Ties between India and Singapore are poised to take-off to an entirely new level of cooperation," the Ministry of External Affairs said at the special briefing about the Prime Minister's visit.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi's visit to Singapore comes after six years, said Secretary East, Ministry of External Affairs, Jaideep Mazumdar. India and Singapore are looking to significantly enhance their cooperation in the semiconductor sector, he added.</p>

<p>He also said that the PM's visit to Singapore is "important for trade and investment".</p>

<p>Singapore is India's largest trade partner in ASEAN. It is also a leading source of Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) in the last financial year with an investment of $11.77 billion in 2023 alone," he said, adding that Singapore is India's sixth largest trade partner worldwide.</p>

<p>During his two-day visit, Prime Minister Modi will also address CEOs, he said.</p>

<p>"Investments have also been very large. Since 2000 till now, we have an accumulative FDI of USD 160 billion dollars. There will be an interaction with business leaders in the PM's visit. This will be an important element of the visit as Prime Minister will address the CEOs in his visit, where they will hear India's growth story first hand," Mr Mazumdar said.</p>

<p>"His [PM Modi's] first visit to Singapore was in his first term as the Prime Minister. This visit is of great significance as it's his visit early in his term, and also as the new Prime Minister Lawrence Wong has taken oath recently and Singaporeans are excited to welcome PM Modi. This is an opportune time to set the stage for India-Singapore's vibrant bilateral relations for the next stage of India-Singapore bilateral relations. Our ties have evolved and we have a dynamic strategic partnership encompassing diverse areas from our shared history and people-to-people ties, which form an important link between us," he added.</p>

<p>Speaking about the special roundtable framework shared by the two nations, he said "We have identified new anchors of our partnership under the India-Singapore ministerial roundtable framework. The visit will also take place in the light of our 60th anniversary of diplomatic relations which we're celebrating in 2025 and 10th year of our strategic partnership with Singapore."</p>

<p>"During the recently concluded India-Singapore Ministerial Roundtable, which is a unique forum between ministers on both sides on diverse areas, a number of new forward-looking futuristic areas were identified in digitization, skill, sustainability, health, advanced manufacturing and connectivity. We are likely to exchange a number of MoUs in these areas in the forthcoming visit of the PM," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cektlbho_narendra-modi-singapore-pm-lawrence-wong_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi will be on visit Singapore on September 4, 5 to further strengthen bilateral ties.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-kamala-harris-to-meet-us-negotiating-team-on-gaza-hostage-deal-6471985]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden, Kamala Harris To Meet US Negotiating Team On Gaza Hostage Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-kamala-harris-to-meet-us-negotiating-team-on-gaza-hostage-deal-6471985]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 13:47:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden will sit down on Monday with US negotiators pushing for a hostage-release deal in the Israel-Hamas war, the White House said, after the deaths of six captives in Gaza, including an American citizen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden will sit down on Monday with US negotiators pushing for a hostage-release deal in the Israel-Hamas war, the White House said, after the deaths of six captives in Gaza, including an American citizen.</p>

<p>Biden's official schedule was revised to make time for the White House meeting, which will also be attended by Vice President Kamala Harris, who is running to succeed him in November's presidential election.</p>

<p>A statement announcing Biden's updated schedule said he and Harris would meet Monday "with the US hostage deal negotiating team following the murder of American citizen Hersh Goldberg-Polin and five other hostages by Hamas on Saturday, and discuss efforts to drive towards a deal that secures the release of the remaining hostages."</p>

<p>The United States, along with fellow mediators Egypt and Qatar, has spent months pushing for a hostage-prisoner exchange and ceasefire in the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Militants seized 251 hostages during the October 7 attack on Israel that sparked the war, 97 of whom remain in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Scores of hostages were released during a one-week truce in November, with campaigners and family members believing another deal is the best option to ensure the rest return.</p>

<p>A nationwide strike in Israel aimed at ramping up pressure on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government to secure the release of the remaining captives was set to begin Monday.</p>

<p>Hostage relatives and advocates have accused Netanyahu's administration of not doing enough to bring the captives back alive, and have called for an immediate ceasefire to rescue the rest.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1n7j43c_kamala-harris-joe-biden-afp-_625x300_16_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A statement announcing Joe Biden's updated schedule said he and Kamala Harris would meet Monday (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-refers-to-x-by-its-old-name-twitter-internet-reacts-6471839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Refers To X By Its Old Name "Twitter", Internet Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-refers-to-x-by-its-old-name-twitter-internet-reacts-6471839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 13:27:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk shared a meme which showed a person lying on a pile of money, with the caption "POV: VPN companies after Brazil banned Twitter."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, who rechristened Twitter X, seemed to have momentarily forgotten the new name of his social media platform. The billionaire entrepreneur, on Monday, referred to X as "Twitter" in a post after the platform was banned in Brazil.<br />
<br />
Mr Musk shared a meme that showed a person lying on a pile of money, with the caption "POV: VPN companies after Brazil banned Twitter." The use of the original name did not go unnoticed, with many users joking that the "rebranding is going well."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/OYpEJy1Kct">pic.twitter.com/OYpEJy1Kct</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1830147680468607423?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“He's still calling it Twitter LOL,” a user commented under the post.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">He's still calling it Twitter LOL</p>
— Bedard glazer (@DibbleTiki) <a href="https://twitter.com/DibbleTiki/status/1830380057082155121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another wrote, “I'm glad you recognize that the app is still called Twitter.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm glad you recognize that the app is still called Twitter</p>
— Matthew Oneill (@Matthew_ONeill5) <a href="https://twitter.com/Matthew_ONeill5/status/1830387366252474400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone wrote, “Why are you excited about sharing this? I thought your company was called X? This meme is about Twitter.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Why are you excited sharing this? I thought your company was called X? This meme is about Twitter.</p>
— Fentuo Tahiru Fentuo (@Fentuo_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Fentuo_/status/1830266810933166171?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Elon Musk's social media platform <a href="http://https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-alexandre-de-moraes-controversy-explained-why-brazil-supreme-court-judge-banned-x-6457462">X was banned in Brazil</a> on Saturday following the suspension order by Brazilian Supreme Court judge Alexandre de Moraes, citing non-compliance with court orders and the spread of disinformation. Mr Musk has responded by calling the judge an "evil dictator cosplaying as a judge" and accusing him of trying to destroy democracy in Brazil.<br />
<br />
The ban comes after a months-long standoff between Mr Musk and the Brazilian authorities investigating the spread of disinformation on the platform. The judge previously ordered the suspension of several accounts belonging to supporters of former President Jair Bolsonaro, who tried to discredit the voting system in the 2022 election.<br />
<br />
Mr Musk's platform has over 22 million users in Brazil and has been accused of allowing the spread of disinformation and hate speech. The judge's order also includes a fine of 50,000 reais (Rs 7.5 lakhs) for anyone who tries to bypass the ban using VPNs or other technological means.<br />
<br />
Mr Musk has expressed outrage, calling the ban an attack on free speech and democracy.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ufkiriag_musk-_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-ex-childcare-worker-pleads-guilty-to-sexually-abusing-60-girls-6471519]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian Ex-Childcare Worker Pleads Guilty To Sexually Abusing 60 Girls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-ex-childcare-worker-pleads-guilty-to-sexually-abusing-60-girls-6471519]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 12:40:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former childcare worker Ashley Paul Griffith on Monday pleaded guilty to raping, sexually abusing and exploiting dozens of girls under his care in Australia and Italy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former childcare worker Ashley Paul Griffith on Monday pleaded guilty to raping, sexually abusing and exploiting dozens of girls under his care in Australia and Italy.</p>

<p>It took Judge Anthony Rafter more than two hours to read out the 307 charges against Griffith in the Brisbane courtroom where several victims and their families had gathered, according to state broadcast ABC.</p>

<p>Police accused the 46-year-old of being one of Australia's worst-ever paedophiles after the charges against him were made public last year.</p>

<p>Griffith was first arrested in 2022 for making child sexual abuse content. A year later he was charged with 1,623 offences against 91 children.</p>

<p>However, some charges were dropped and the ABC reported that Monday's charges related to roughly 60 children. Many of the victims were under the age of 12.</p>

<p>The offences happened between 2003 and 2022 in twelve different locations across Australia as well as Pisa, Italy.</p>

<p>Griffith is in custody and will be sentenced at a later date. The court heard sentencing could take more than two days to give time to read victim impact statements, the ABC reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mep1k2co_child-abuser-australia-_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ashley Paul Griffith was first arrested in 2022 for making child sexual abuse content.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/27-years-after-the-great-lego-spill-toy-pieces-still-washing-up-on-beaches-6471433]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[27 Years After The Great Lego Spill, Toy Pieces Still Washing Up On Beaches]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/27-years-after-the-great-lego-spill-toy-pieces-still-washing-up-on-beaches-6471433]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Sep 2024 12:31:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nearly five million Lego pieces were lost at sea when a cargo ship nearly capsized off the coast of England in 1997.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On a gloomy drizzly day in late June, Hayley Hardstaff, a marine biologist from Cornwall, England, took her routine walk along Portwrinkle Beach. What began as an ordinary stroll turned extraordinary when she stumbled upon a black, plastic dragon with a missing upper jaw. To her surprise, it was a piece of Lego, not just any piece, but a remnant of one of history's most curious maritime mishaps.</p>

<p>In 1997, an accident involving a cargo ship and a rogue wave led to one of the most bizarre environmental disasters in history - the Great Lego Spill. Nearly five million Lego pieces, including 33,427 black dragons, were lost at sea when the Tokio Express, a cargo ship en route from Rotterdam to New York, nearly capsized off the coast of England. The incident resulted in the loss of all 62 of its shipping containers, causing one of the largest toy-related environmental disasters.</p>

<p>Twenty-seven years later, people are still finding these tiny plastic artefacts on beaches across Europe.</p>

<p>Tracey Williams, who started the "Lego Lost at Sea" Facebook page, has been documenting these Lego finds for years. The spill included nautically themed pieces like dragons, octopuses, seaweed, scuba tanks and life rafts. Some pieces, like black dragons and green octopuses, have become prized finds for beachcombers.<br />
<br />
<iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="497" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FLegoLostAtSea%2Fposts%2Fpfbid08byNCC4YRvYYjcK6LZJAkBuaqECp6Se5ofEKVfNnCqa1Pdhz7u1gvmH8wpA8eBxtl&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe><br />
<br />
Oceanographer Curtis Ebbesmeyer, known for tracking the 1992 Friendly Floatees Spill, pointed out that ocean currents can carry debris to far-off places, making the extent of such pollution hard to track. While some pieces have been found in the Netherlands, France and Belgium, many remain lost, possibly sunk to the ocean floor.<br />
<br />
Mr Ebbesmeyer's curiosity about the Cornwall spill led him to investigate further. He contacted Lego and received an inventory of the container's contents, along with samples of the pieces. Testing them in his bathtub revealed that half of the pieces floated, which could explain why many remain missing.<br />
<br />
In the years since, pieces have sporadically appeared, often found by fishermen trawling the ocean floor. One of the rarest finds, a Lego shark, was recently caught 20 miles off the Cornish coast, marking the first sighting of this specific piece in 27 years. This leaves 51,799 more of these sharks still unaccounted for, according to the "Lego Lost at Sea" account.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">CATCH OF THE DAY!<br />
Oh my goodness – our very first Lego shark from the Great Lego Spill of 1997 has just been hauled up from the deep! Caught in a fisherman's net and somewhat battered and bruised after 27 years at the bottom of the ocean, this Lego shark is one of 51,800 lost… <a href="https://t.co/EFbuGU6NGU">pic.twitter.com/EFbuGU6NGU</a></p>
— Lego Lost At Sea (@LegoLostAtSea) <a href="https://twitter.com/LegoLostAtSea/status/1819450030249365667?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Professor Andrew Turner considers the incident an interesting case study due to public awareness. Unlike most container spills, the Great Lego Spill was made public, and it represents just a small part of the vast plastic pollution in the ocean.<br />
<br />
Mr Turner says it is just the "tip of the iceberg" when it comes to plastic pollution in the ocean. He pointed out the vast amounts of plastic that remain on the ocean floor, much of which is unaccounted for and whose potential impact is still largely unknown.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c1blmf58_lego_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[People are still finding these tiny plastic artefacts on beaches across Europe.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>