<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:01:14 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jealous-husband-in-japan-makes-100-calls-daily-to-wife-from-private-number-arrested-6594051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Jealous' Husband In Japan Makes 100 Blank Calls To Wife Daily, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jealous-husband-in-japan-makes-100-calls-daily-to-wife-from-private-number-arrested-6594051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 17:25:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While his sentencing remains pending, the incident has ignited a national conversation in Japan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a strange incident in Japan, a man was arrested for making over 100 silent phone calls daily to his wife for several weeks. The disturbing event unfolded between July and August, captivating public attention due to the husband's bizarre behaviour.&nbsp;According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3278699/japan-wife-discovers-jealous-husband-made-100-nuisance-calls-day-entire-month">South China Morning Post</a></em>, a 31-year-old woman from Hyogo prefecture reported to police that she received unsettling blank calls every day in July and August. However, upon answering, the caller remained silent. Initially, she brought her concerns to her husband, but his nonchalance and lack of concern frustrated her.</p>

<p>A turning point came when she observed the calls stopped when her husband was asleep, gaming, or spending time with her. Her suspicion was piqued, and she devised a test. While shopping together, she closely monitored his actions, noticing he didn't touch his phone, and that's when the calls stopped.</p>

<p>She then reported her concerns to the police, who investigated the couple's phone records.&nbsp;Investigations revealed that the husband was indeed the mastermind behind the mysterious silent calls, leaving his wife distressed. Further probe revealed that he had been using private numbers to conceal his identity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The couple had no known relationship issues and appeared to live harmoniously. According to reports, his motives stemmed from jealousy and possessiveness. A specific incident in the past triggered his insecurity when he discovered his wife engaging in a conversation with another man. Feeling threatened, he began making silent calls as a form of punishment.&nbsp;However, he also claimed that he ''loved her so much.''</p>

<p>In Japan, causing significant emotional distress through nuisance phone calls is considered a criminal offence. Violators may face up to one year in prison or a fine of up to 1 million yen (US$7,000), and a prohibition order will be issued.</p>

<p>On September 4, authorities apprehended the husband, taking him into custody. While his sentencing remains pending, the incident has ignited a national conversation in Japan. Many called for greater awareness and action against emotional harassment and domestic abuse.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One user wrote, ''The husband's control over his wife is too much. This kind of love is suffocating.''</p>

<p>Another commented, ''Communication is the best way for a couple to resolve issues, not harassment or violence.''</p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f9dm735o_man-on-phone_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Japan, causing emotional distress through nuisance phone calls is considered a criminal offence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-youtuber-sydney-watson-sparks-outrage-after-calling-indian-spices-dirt-in-viral-post-6593746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian YouTuber Sparks Outrage After Calling Indian Spices "Dirt"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-youtuber-sydney-watson-sparks-outrage-after-calling-indian-spices-dirt-in-viral-post-6593746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:51:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian YouTuber has found herself in the middle of a social media storm after criticising Indian cuisine for its "dirt spices". Sydney Watson's remarks have drawn severe backlash, with users quickly jumping to defend Indian food.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian YouTuber has found herself in the middle of a social media storm after criticising Indian cuisine for its "dirt spices". Sydney Watson's remarks have drawn severe backlash, with users quickly jumping to defend the historical and cultural significance of Indian food.</p>

<p>The controversy began when an X user shared a post praising Indian cuisine, saying, "Indian food is the best on earth. Fight me." Accompanying the post was a colourful photo of various curries and rice. While the post was meant to celebrate Indian food, the conversation quickly took a different turn when Sydney Watson responded with, "It really, really isn't."</p>

<p>However, it was her follow-up comments that ignited outrage. Watson added, "If your food requires you to put dirt spices all over it in order for it to be palatable, your food is not good."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">If your food requires you to put dirt spices all over it in order for it to be palatable, your food is not good.</p>
— Dr. Sydney Watson (@SydneyLWatson) <a href="https://twitter.com/SydneyLWatson/status/1835771598768402529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In another comment, she wrote, "It all tastes like burning. People who like this are masochistic."</p>

<p>Her remarks did not sit well with social media users.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">yep.<br />
It all tastes like burning. People who like this are masochistic.</p>
— Dr. Sydney Watson (@SydneyLWatson) <a href="https://twitter.com/SydneyLWatson/status/1835771926360248352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A user commented under the post, "Sydney, as far back as the Romans people have been importing spices from India in quantities so great, Ptolemy complained 'There is no year in which India does not drain the Roman Empire of fifty million sesterces'. The point is spice goes on nearly all food."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sydney , as far back the as the Romans people have been importing spices from India in quantities so great, Ptolemy complained "There is no year in which India does not drain the Roman Empire of fifty million sesterces". Point is spice goes on nearly all food.</p>
— anu mathimugan (@deedeewhiteshep) <a href="https://twitter.com/deedeewhiteshep/status/1836289247931994216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another taunted, "It's okay to like bland food without projecting."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's okay to like bland food without projecting.</p>
— Aaron Binder (@theaaronbinder) <a href="https://twitter.com/theaaronbinder/status/1835807081955574076?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"This of course, coming from the country that brought us true delicacies like 'pineapple beetroot hamburger' and 'vegemite on toast'," a comment read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This of course, coming from the country that brought us true delicacies like "pineapple beetroot hamburger" and "vegemite on toast"</p>
— Chairman Birb Bernanke (@Bonecondor) <a href="https://twitter.com/Bonecondor/status/1835827234365460575?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone said, "It's okay if you don't like spicy but condemning is where we draw the line please."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's okay if you don't like spicy but condemning is where we draw the line please. <a href="https://t.co/SKailtFyam">pic.twitter.com/SKailtFyam</a></p>
— Duchess_Beeyah???????? (@KhadijaGarba19) <a href="https://twitter.com/KhadijaGarba19/status/1835827788806328585?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Who cares! You stick with your boiled potatoes while we savour our flavorful delicacy," read a comment.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Who cares!<br />
You stick with your boiled potatoes while we savor our flavorful delicacy.</p>
— Smile&amp;Shine ???????????????? (@smileandshine20) <a href="https://twitter.com/smileandshine20/status/1835882971410382924?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Indian cuisine continues to make its mark on the global stage, with four dishes featured in Taste Atlas' prestigious list of the "100 Best Dishes in the World" this year. Leading is the ever-popular Butter Garlic Naan, which secured an impressive 7th place. Following closely behind were Murgh Makhani (Butter Chicken) at 43, Tikki at 47, and Tandoori Chicken at 48.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/genp568o_sydney-watson_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sydney Watson's remarks did not sit well with social media users.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/lebanons-pager-attacks-whats-next-for-hezbollah-6593630]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Pager Attacks: What Next For Hezbollah?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/lebanons-pager-attacks-whats-next-for-hezbollah-6593630]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:37:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the short term, if not tactically, Israel has been managing to secure at least psychological victories against Hezbollah and its ilk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3egae548_lebanon-hospital_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>One could easily dismiss it as a spy film plot if it weren't so real: a highly sophisticated 'pager attack' purportedly by Israeli agencies has left dozens dead and opened a new front in the ongoing Gaza crisis. Nine people were reported killed and over 2,700, including civilians, were injured when a series of text pagers supposedly used by Hezbollah members exploded in various parts of the country. Iran's ambassador to Lebanon, Mojtaba Amani, was also injured in the explosions.</p>

<p>Reports suggest Israel had intercepted the group's supply chains and laced more than 5,000 of these devices with explosives. A Taiwanese company, Gold Apollo, has denied charges that it was the provider of the consignment. Earlier, in February, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah had warned his group against the use of mobile phones.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>More Complexity To Deal With</strong></h2>

<p>Israel has not officially taken credit for the attack. However, the incident adds one more layer to an intricate and clandestine face-off between Israeli agencies and the Lebanese militia group as both try to avoid a full-scale confrontation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The intent behind such an audacious attack appears to be to inflict a psychological and strategic blow rather than a tactical one. The attack would be added to a not-too-long but notable list of Israeli operations in the recent past that have primarily been designed to highlight the state's intrusions within its enemy's infrastructure, whether political, military, or technological. Examples include the use of automated AI-assisted weapons to assassinate Iranian scientist Mohsen Fakhrizadeh on the outskirts of Tehran in 2021, the elimination of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh in central Tehran a few months ago, and various other clandestine operations aimed at disrupting Iran's nuclear programme. The basic idea behind these operations, including ones now involving low-grade tech like pagers, is optics, to show that the Israeli state can target its detractors at the time and place of its choosing.</p>

<p>The cat-and-mouse game between Hezbollah and Israel has been on the brink of turning into a full conflict for months now. Recently, Israel flew fighter jets over Beirut just before a sermon by Nasrallah, to show force and awareness. It has also been on a mission to eliminate his immediate deputies, such as Fuad Shukr. Recent reports have once again suggested that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu may look to remove Defense Minister Yoav Gallant, who has criticised the way decisions have been taken on the war in Gaza. Despite the political fault lines within Israel on these issues - including the far too public discrepancies between civil and military leaderships - there is a consensus to target both Hamas and Hezbollah in order to secure long-term security narratives, which were deemed lost after the October 7 terror attack.</p>

<h2><strong>Will Iran Intervene?</strong></h2>

<p>As a critical part of the 'Axis of Resistance', Hezbollah, backed by Iran, remains strong compared to Hamas, which has seen its fighting strength deplete significantly in recent months. Also, in choosing not to join Hamas in the aftermath of the October 2023 attack in Israel, Hezbollah managed to buy some time. The reason for this approach could be attributed to two lines of thinking. First, direct aggression against Israel in the country's north would in all likelihood not only invite a response of Israeli air power but that of the US as well, causing mass casualties on the ground in Lebanon, for which Hezbollah would have to be answerable. Second, there seems to be a lack of clarity on whether Iran would directly intervene in support of the said axis. For instance, Tehran hasn't yet directly responded to the killing of Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Hezbollah thus seemingly prefers a more protracted response, causing nuisance and displacement in Israel's north instead of going for a traditional, full-scale border conflict that it very well will not be able to afford.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, the growing tensions between Israel and Hezbollah are threatening to jeopardise diplomatic tracks being promoted by the likes of the US to put a ceasefire in place. Israeli hostages remain under Hamas captivity in Gaza, and Israeli military operations in response are set to continue. Netanyahu has made no qualms in admitting that such warfare will prevail till Hamas is eliminated.</p>

<h2><strong>A Psychological Strike</strong></h2>

<p>Ultimately, both Hamas and Netanyahu have, in their own way, obstructed ceasefire efforts. A political settlement today will require a prolonged secession of hostilities. While Nasrallah claims that his group does not want total war, both sides are sliding towards tactical exchanges. But even these tactical attacks can very well lead to a broader conflict.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With the latest explosions, Hezbollah's 'low-tech' pager communication network has already been busted, making it harder for the group to operate, debate, and deploy forces. In the short term, if not tactically, Israel has been managing to secure at least psychological victories against Hezbollah and its ilk. In the long term, things remain as uncertain as before. It won't be surprising if the Gaza crisis and accompanying regional tensions spill well into 2025.</p>

<p><em>[Kabir Taneja is a Fellow with the Strategic Studies Programme at the Observer Research Foundation. He is the author of 'The ISIS Peril: The World's Most Feared Terror Group and its Shadow on South Asia' (Penguin Viking, 2019)]</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3egae548_lebanon-hospital_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukrainian-strike-triggers-earthquake-sized-blast-at-russian-arsenal-report-6593249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Strike Triggers Earthquake-Sized Blast At Russian Arsenal: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukrainian-strike-triggers-earthquake-sized-blast-at-russian-arsenal-report-6593249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:49:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A large-scale Ukrainian drone attack on Russia triggered an earthquake-sized blast at a major arsenal in the Tver region on Wednesday, forcing the evacuation of a nearby town, war bloggers and some media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A large-scale Ukrainian drone attack on Russia triggered an earthquake-sized blast at a major arsenal in the Tver region on Wednesday, forcing the evacuation of a nearby town, war bloggers and some media reported.</p>

<p>Unverified video and images on social media showed a huge ball of flame blasting high into the night sky and multiple detonations thundering across a lake about 380 km (240 miles) west of Moscow.</p>

<p>NASA satellites picked up intense heat sources emanating from an area of about 14 square kilometres (5 square miles) at the site in the early hours and earthquake monitoring stations picked up what sensors thought was a small earthquake in the area.</p>

<p>"The enemy hit an ammunition depot in the area of Toropets," said Yuri Podolyaka, an Ukrainian-born, pro-Russian military blogger.</p>

<p>"Everything that can burn is already burning there (and exploding)."</p>

<p>There was no information about casualties.</p>

<p>Russian state media have in the past reported that a major arsenal for conventional weapons was located at the site of the blasts. State media, which is now subject to military censorship laws, was muted in its reporting on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Igor Rudenya, the governor of the Tver region, said that Ukrainian drones had been shot down, that a fire had broken out and that some residents were being evacuated. He did not say what was burning.</p>

<p>One woman told Reuters that members of her family had been evacuated from Toropets.</p>

<p>"A fire started with explosions," the woman said, giving only a first name, Irina.</p>

<p>A source in Ukraine's SBU state security service told Reuters the drone attack destroyed a warehouse storing missiles, guided bombs and artillery ammunition. There was no immediate comment from the Ukrainian government.</p>

<p>Russia and Ukraine each reported dozens of enemy drone attacks on their territory overnight, with Russian forces advancing in eastern Ukraine.</p>

<p><strong>MAJOR EXPLOSION</strong></p>

<p>The size of the main blast shown in the unverified social media video was consistent with 200-240 tons of high explosives detonating, according to George William Herbert of the Middlebury Institute of International Studies at Monterey in California.</p>

<p>A Toropets chatroom on the Russian social media site VK was flooded with messages of support from other parts of the country and offers of help to people fleeing the town.</p>

<p>Some people were asking whether buildings at specific addresses were still standing.</p>

<p>"People, does anyone know what's happened to Kudino village??? They told me nothing is left of our house," posted one woman.</p>

<p>Another woman replied: "It's horror there." Kudino is a village 4.5 km (2.8 miles) northeast of Toropets.</p>

<p>Some war bloggers questioned how drones could trigger such large explosions at what was thought to be a highly fortified facility.</p>

<p>According to an RIA state news agency report from 2018, Russia was building an arsenal for the storage of missiles, ammunition and explosives in Toropets, a 1,000-year-old town, which has a population of just over 11,000.</p>

<p>Dmitry Bulgakov, then a deputy defence minister, told RIA in 2018 that the facility could defend weapons from missiles and even a small nuclear attack. Bulgakov was arrested earlier this year on corruption charges. He denies the charges.</p>

<p>"It (the concrete facilities) ensures their reliable and safe storage, protects them from air and missile strikes and even from the damaging factors of a nuclear explosion," RIA quoted Bulgakov as saying at the time.</p>

<p>Some Russians on chat groups expressed anger.</p>

<p>"Why wasn't the ammunition underground?! What are you doing???? In Kudino, houses were blown away! Why is the forest burning and no one is there... what kind of negligence is this!!!!" one woman posted.</p>

<p>Russia reported that its air defence units had destroyed 54 drones launched against five Russian regions overnight, without mentioning Tver. Ukraine said it had shot down 46 of 52 drones launched by Moscow overnight and that Russia had used three guided air missiles which did not reach their targets.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4l3l8cto_tver-russia_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia and Ukraine each reported dozens of enemy drone attacks on their territory overnight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/are-smartphones-safe-lebanons-hezbollah-pager-explosions-raise-concerns-6593213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Are Smartphones Safe? Lebanon Pager Explosions Raise Concerns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/are-smartphones-safe-lebanons-hezbollah-pager-explosions-raise-concerns-6593213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:43:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The explosions occurred in various public places, with reports flooding in from grocery stores, street markets, and other busy locations. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon witnessed a series of explosions on Tuesday after thousands of pagers, allegedly used by the militant group Hezbollah, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100 ">detonated simultaneously across the country</a>. The coordinated blasts killed at least nine people and left over 3,000 injured.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The explosions occurred in various public places, with reports flooding in from grocery stores, street markets, and other busy locations. Video footage from a grocery store showed a man shopping when the pager attached to his waist suddenly exploded, throwing him to the ground. Bystanders fled in terror as chaos erupted around them.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hundreds of Hezbollah fighters injured after mass explosions — Reuters<br />
<br />
Hospitals in Lebanon are overflowing with mostly Hezbollah terror group members being taken to hospitals. A mass pager blast has killed and injured thousands of militants and ordinary Lebanese.<br />
<br />
There are… <a href="https://t.co/1bUC5FcJf1">pic.twitter.com/1bUC5FcJf1</a></p>
— Insider News (@Ins1der_News) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ins1der_News/status/1836263406321479901?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>With pagers being outdated technology, attention has shifted to more modern devices like smartphones, which are widely used by billions worldwide. Could a similar malfunction happen with smartphones?</p>

<p>The notion of hackers turning smartphones into bombs is frightening but unlikely. Smartphone technology's complexity and safeguards minimise risks.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's use of pagers stemmed from security concerns. Simpler and less connected, pagers are harder to track and hack. However, reports suggest explosives may have been embedded in pagers. A New York Times report speculated that Israeli intelligence had inserted explosives into pagers ordered from a Taiwanese manufacturer, although the company denied the claims. If true, this suggests that the explosion was triggered remotely through advanced means.</p>

<p>When it comes to smartphones, they are more complex, with software systems and network connections. In theory, hackers could exploit vulnerabilities in smartphone firmware to cause overheating or malfunction, but mass-scale attacks would be far more difficult to execute compared to pagers. This is because smartphones have multiple security layers and safety measures to prevent battery overheating.</p>

<p>Modern smartphones are equipped with built-in safety mechanisms like temperature regulation circuits, which automatically cut off charging when the device overheats. Advanced cooling systems such as vapour chambers and graphite layers are also present, to ensure that any excess heat is dissipated.</p>

<p>As a result, while smartphones can occasionally malfunction and overheat, they rarely explode. In the rare cases where a smartphone catches fire, it is often due to physical damage or manufacturing defects rather than malicious interference.</p>

<p>Even if hackers could remotely manipulate a smartphone's battery to generate heat, the chances of causing a mass explosion are slim. In most instances, the phone would overheat and possibly swell, leak or catch a small fire, but an explosion on the scale of the Hezbollah pager incident is unlikely.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7dffoi9_phone-generic_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Modern smartphones are equipped with built-in safety mechanisms like temperature regulation circuits.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-bound-easyjet-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-bag-of-vapes-explode-6593117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EasyJet Flight Makes Emergency Landing After Bag Of Vapes Explode]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-bound-easyjet-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-bag-of-vapes-explode-6593117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:31:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eyewitnesses described a terrifying scene, with one passenger recounting a "very large red flash and flame followed by thick black smoke."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chaos erupted on an EasyJet flight carrying 236 passengers when a suspected bag of vapes exploded. The London Gatwick-bound plane, which had taken off from Heraklion, Greece, was forced to evacuate passengers on the runway after reports of "popping noises and smoke" filled the aircraft, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/09/18/easyjet-passengers-bag-vapes-explodes-plane-forcing-evacuation-21624573/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Metro</em></a> reported.&nbsp;Eyewitnesses described a terrifying scene, with one passenger recounting a "very large red flash and flame followed by thick black smoke." Panic spread quickly, with some shouting "bomb" and others rushing to exit the plane.</p>

<p>A witness said, ''Fire and acrid smoke billowed from the bag, popping exploding noises, smoke filled the cabin around the bag.'' Another witness claimed that a British woman carrying a vape in her bag was seen waving it around as smoke began to emanate from it, sparking widespread alarm.</p>

<p>Authorities believe a power bank and e-cigarettes inside a passenger's bag caused the explosion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fortunately, none of the 236 passengers suffered burn injuries from the blast, which occurred shortly after takeoff. However, one passenger sustained a minor friction burn while exiting the plane via the evacuation slide.</p>

<p>Emergency services swiftly responded to the incident, ensuring passenger safety. Following a thorough investigation, authorities cleared the aircraft for re-entry, allowing passengers to retrieve their belongings. Police forces also rushed to the scene to investigate the incident.</p>

<p>After the incident,&nbsp;EasyJet said: "EasyJet can confirm that flight EZY8216 from Heraklion to London Gatwick was evacuated during boarding prior to departure, due to a fire in a passenger's cabin bag. Fire services attended the aircraft and cabin crew evacuated the aircraft in line with procedures. Customers are currently being looked after in the terminal and a replacement aircraft and crew have been arranged to fly customers home later today. Safety is our highest priority.''</p>

<p>The incident highlights the potential risks of carrying lithium-ion batteries and electronic devices on commercial flights.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/nt2dgg3g_-easyjet-_625x300_20_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Panicked passengers evacuated the plane after the explosion]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-seeks-review-of-indus-water-treaty-serves-notice-to-pakistan-6592974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Seeks Review Of Indus Water Treaty, Serves Notice To Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-seeks-review-of-indus-water-treaty-serves-notice-to-pakistan-6592974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:18:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has served a formal notice to Pakistan seeking a review of the Indus Water Treaty, arguing that "fundamental and unforeseen" changes in the circumstances require a reassessment of the pact.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has served a formal notice to Pakistan seeking a review of the Indus Water Treaty, arguing that "fundamental and unforeseen" changes in the circumstances require a reassessment of the pact.</p>

<p>The notice was issued to Pakistan on August 30 under Article XII(3) of the Indus Water Treaty (IWT), government sources said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>India and Pakistan signed the IWT on September 19, 1960, after nine years of negotiations, with the World Bank being a signatory to the pact, which sets out a mechanism for cooperation and information exchange between the two sides on the use of the waters of a number of cross-border rivers.</p>

<p>India's notification highlights fundamental and unforeseen changes in circumstances that require a reassessment of obligations under various articles of the treaty, the sources said.</p>

<p>Among various concerns, the important ones include a change in population demographics, environmental issues and the need to accelerate the development of clean energy to meet India's emission targets, they said.</p>

<p>India has also cited the impact of persistent cross-border terrorism as one of the reasons for demanding the review.</p>

<p>"The notification was issued in the background of a separate prolonged controversy with respect to the Kishanganga and Ratle hydro projects," a source said.</p>

<p>"In this regard, the World Bank has simultaneously activated both the neutral-expert mechanism and the Court of Arbitration on the same set of issues," the source added.</p>

<p>"The Indian side has, therefore, also called for a reconsideration of the dispute-resolution mechanism under the treaty," the source said.</p>

<p>India has not cooperated with the Court of Arbitration process to resolve the dispute.</p>

<p>New Delhi considers that the start of the two concurrent processes to resolve the dispute violates the provision of the three-step graded mechanism prescribed in the IWT.</p>

<p>India has been pushing for the resolution of the dispute through the neutral-expert proceedings.</p>

<p>With this notification, India has called on Pakistan to begin government-to-government negotiations in order to review the treaty under the provisions of Article XII(3), the sources said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/india-pakistan-flags-afp_650x400_41521105457.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has not cooperated with the Court of Arbitration process to resolve the dispute.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-pager-attack-on-hezbollah-could-mean-for-volatile-middle-east-6592973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Pager Attack On Hezbollah Could Mean For Volatile Middle-East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-pager-attack-on-hezbollah-could-mean-for-volatile-middle-east-6592973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:17:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The alleged Israeli attack on members of Hezbollah via their pagers is another ominous development propelling the Middle East towards a full-scale regional war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>The alleged Israeli attack on members of Hezbollah via their pagers is another ominous development propelling the Middle East towards a full-scale regional war. It leaves Hezbollah with little option but to retaliate with the full support of the Iran-led “axis of resistance”.</p>

<p>The sophistication and impact of targeting the pagers is unprecedented. The attack resulted in at least <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/17/world/middleeast/israel-hezbollah-pagers-explosives.html">11 deaths</a>, including some of Hezbollah's fighters, and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/sep/17/hundreds-of-hezbollah-members-hurt-in-lebanon-after-pagers-explode">up to 3,000 people</a> wounded.</p>

<p>The main aim of the attack, which US officials <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/17/world/middleeast/israel-hezbollah-pagers-explosives.html">have reportedly said</a> was carried out by Israel, was intended to disrupt Hezbollah's means of communication and its command and control system in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Since Hezbollah has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/pagers-drones-how-hezbollah-aims-counter-israels-high-tech-surveillance-2024-07-09/">reduced the use of mobile phones</a> by its forces because Israel can easily detect and target them, pagers have increasingly become the preferred messaging device within the group.</p>

<p>The attack may have also been designed to cause panic within the group and among the Lebanese public, many of whom <a href="https://www.newarab.com/news/support-hezbollah-growing-lebanon">do not support Hezbollah</a>, given the political divisions in the country.</p>

<p>Since Hamas' October 7 attacks on southern Israel, the Israeli leadership under Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has repeatedly said it is <a href="https://www.afr.com/world/middle-east/israel-approves-battle-plans-for-hezbollah-edging-closer-to-war-20240619-p5jn3v">determined</a> to remove the threat of Hezbollah, which has operated in solidarity with Hamas.</p>

<p>Hours before the pager attack, Netanyahu's government <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/sep/17/israel-war-goals-netanyahu-hamas-gaza-palestine">clarified</a> that Israel's war goals would expand to include a return of the tens of thousands of residents to their homes in northern Israel, which they have fled due to constant rocket fire from Hezbollah. Israel's defence minister, Yoav Gallant, said the only way to do this was through military action.</p>

<p>The simultaneous pager explosions on Tuesday, then, may be a prelude to an all-out Israeli offensive against Hezbollah.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BREAKING via Reuters<br />
<br />
Hundreds of members of Hezbollah were seriously wounded on Tuesday when the pagers they use to communicate exploded.<br />
<br />
Here is one video of one of the pager explosions. <a href="https://t.co/UDepHvkkEe">pic.twitter.com/UDepHvkkEe</a></p>
— Yashar Ali ? (@yashar) <a href="https://twitter.com/yashar/status/1836038437264368078?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<h2>The consequences of war with Hezbollah</h2>

<p>Hezbollah has already declared it will retaliate. What form this will take remains to be seen. The group has a massive military capability to not only to pound northern Israel with drones and missiles, but also attack other parts of the Jewish state, including heavily populated cities such as Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>Hezbollah showed this capability in its 2006 war with Israel. The war lasted 34 days, during which <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/hezbollah-to-air-new-footage-on-raid-that-sparked-2006-lebanon-war/">165 Israelis were killed</a> (121 IDF soldiers and 44 civilians) and Israel's economy and tourist industry were markedly damaged. Hezbollah and Lebanese losses were far greater, with at least 1,100 deaths. However, the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2006/08/15/opinion/15iht-edsaikal.2491556.html">failed to destroy or incapacitate</a> the group.</p>

<p>Any successful retaliatory attack on Israel's cities could result in serious civilian casualties, giving Israel a further pretext to pursue its long-held aim of destroying Hezbollah and punishing its main backer, the Islamic Republic of Iran.</p>

<p>In a wider conflict, the United States is committed to defending Israel, while Iran would support Hezbollah in whatever way necessary. If Israeli and US leaders think Iran will continue to refrain from any action that could propel it into war with Israel and the US, they are mistaken.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is a central piece in the regime's national and regional security paradigm. Tehran has invested heavily in the group, along with other regional affiliates – Iraqi militias, the Yemeni Houthis and the Syrian regime of Bashar al-Assad, in particular. The aim of this “axis of resistance” has been to build a strong deterrent against Israel and the US.</p>

<p>Ever since its foundation 45 years ago, the Iranian regime has viewed Israel and its main backer, the US, as an existential threat, just as Israel has regarded Iran in the same way. For this, the regime has reoriented its foreign relations towards America's major adversaries, especially Russia and China. <a href="https://carnegieendowment.org/russia-eurasia/politika/2024/02/united-against-america-russia-iran-military-cooperation-is-a-looming-threat?lang=en">Russo-Iranian military cooperation</a> has grown so strong, in fact, that Moscow will have little hesitation in backing Iran and its affiliates in any war.</p>

<p>Tehran is fully cognisant of Israel's nuclear prowess. To guard against it, Iran has developed its own nuclear program to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/27/us/politics/iran-president-nuclear-bomb.html">threshold level</a> of developing a weapon. Iranian leaders may have also gained Russia's assurances it would help defend Iran should Israel resort to the use of its nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, it is important to remember that after nearly a year of demolishing Gaza and devastating its inhabitants, Israel has not been able to wipe out Hamas.</p>

<p>Its own actions speak to this. It has constantly forced Gazans to relocate so IDF soldiers can operate in areas they had previously declared to be cleared of fighters.</p>

<p>The task of defeating Hezbollah and its backers would be a far greater objective to achieve. It carries the serious risk of a war that all parties have been saying that they do not want, yet all are preparing for.</p>

<p>The pager attack is just the latest in a string of operations that keeps imperilling any chances of a permanent Gaza ceasefire that could stabilise the region and contribute to the causes of peace rather than war.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/239302/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amin-saikal-1413547">Amin Saikal</a>, Emeritus professor of Middle Eastern and Central Asian Studies, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/australian-national-university-877">Australian National University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/will-the-exploding-pager-attack-be-the-spark-that-ignites-an-israel-hezbollah-war-239302">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qcrllkug_israel-hezbollah-attack-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bruised-by-fresh-election-loss-justin-trudeau-shows-no-sign-of-stepping-down-6592944]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bruised By Election Loss, Justin Trudeau Shows No Sign Of Stepping Down]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bruised-by-fresh-election-loss-justin-trudeau-shows-no-sign-of-stepping-down-6592944]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:11:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Doubts about the leadership Justin Trudeau intensified after his ruling Liberal Party suffered a second humiliating loss in a special election, but the unpopular leader is determined to cling to office ahead of a looming national vote.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Doubts about the leadership of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau intensified after his ruling Liberal Party suffered a second humiliating loss in a special election, but the unpopular leader is determined to cling to office ahead of a looming national vote.</p>

<p>The Liberals, who have governed for almost nine years, suffered a narrow defeat on Monday in a Montreal constituency that had been one of the party's safest seats.</p>

<p>The loss, following a defeat in Toronto in late June, reinforced the perception that Liberal prospects in the next national election are dim. The mandate for Trudeau's minority government expires at the end of October 2025, but an early election has become increasingly likely after the smaller New Democratic Party dropped its support.</p>

<p>Even so, Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign. And the party's mechanisms to force him out are limited.</p>

<p>Andrew McDougall, an assistant professor of political science at the University of Toronto, said the Liberals were losing "the crown jewels" in urban strongholds, not marginal seats, highlighting the party's bleak prospects.</p>

<p>"This is obviously a very difficult moment for Justin Trudeau," McDougall said. "It seems to reinforce the narrative that he's yesterday's man, and that if the Liberals are going to win the next election, they're going to have to do it with somebody else."</p>

<p>Although polls indicate the Liberals will lose badly to the official opposition right-of-center Conservatives in the next election amid unhappiness over inflation and a housing crisis, Trudeau and his closest aides say he is going nowhere and has time to help the party recover.</p>

<p>"Obviously, it would have been nicer to be able to win ... but there is more work to do and we're going to stay focused on doing it," Trudeau told reporters on Tuesday.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Justin Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vr64s064_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Justin Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Justin Trudeau showed no sign on Tuesday that he may step down before the next election campaign.</p>
</div>

<p>His main immediate challenge is that he has lost control of the House of Commons, where the Liberals hold only a minority of seats. The left-leaning NDP signed a deal in 2022 to keep the Liberals in power but tore up the agreement this month.</p>

<p>The NDP increased its share of the vote in Montreal while retaining a seat in the western province of Manitoba, fending off a strong Conservative challenge.</p>

<p>The Liberals face a number of confidence votes by legislators in the next few months and a defeat would trigger an election, although the NDP may choose to keep the government afloat until it can buoy its own popularity.</p>

<p>"The Liberals gave both opposition parties a reason to believe that they can defeat Trudeau," said Darrell Bricker, CEO of polling firm Ipsos-Reid. "The potential they can trigger (an election) sooner is definitely there."</p>

<p>Keeping a minority government alive can be difficult and how much Trudeau can press ahead with his legislative agenda remains unclear.</p>

<p>The Liberals said on Monday they would focus on legislation regarding defense and citizenship.</p>

<h2><strong>SPECIAL CONVENTION</strong></h2>

<p>Unlike in the United States, where President Joe Biden stepped down as Democratic presidential candidate in favor of Vice President Kamala Harris, there is no smooth way for Trudeau to hand over power.</p>

<p>In Australia and the UK, prime ministers are chosen by legislators and can be quickly overthrown. Trudeau was selected by a special convention of party members and cannot be forced out if he wants to stay.</p>

<p>One senior Liberal said if the polls continued to look miserable, senior ministers could urge Trudeau to leave.</p>

<p>But the Liberal, who requested anonymity given the sensitivity of the situation, said there was no guarantee Trudeau - a stubborn man according to insiders - would listen.</p>

<p>Bricker said those in charge of Liberal fundraising could make the same pitch to Trudeau.</p>

<p>"If the money dries up, they are not in a position to fight," he said.</p>

<p>If Trudeau steps down, an interim leader would be chosen while the party set up another convention.</p>

<p>Tradition dictates a stand-in must come from the ranks of legislators, ruling out former Bank of Canada governor Mark Carney, often mentioned as a potential Trudeau replacement.</p>

<p>The interim leader does not run to be the permanent replacement, according to party custom. That could deter cabinet heavyweights such as Finance Minister Chrystia Freeland and Innovation Minister Francois-Philippe Champagne from seeking to replace Trudeau in the short term.</p>

<p>Regardless, changing leaders might not boost Liberal prospects, said Frank Graves, president of the Ekos polling firm.</p>

<p>"The difficulties Mr. Trudeau and the Liberals are experiencing are pretty similar to those progressive incumbents are experiencing in other advanced western democracies," he said by email, citing rising populism and economic uncertainty.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/eqti80h4_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canadas Prime Minister Justin Trudeau shows no signs of stepping down despite recent setbacks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-how-cancer-cells-may-be-using-lipids-to-hide-from-immune-system-6592758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Shows How Cancer Cells May Be Using Lipids To Hide From Immune System]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-how-cancer-cells-may-be-using-lipids-to-hide-from-immune-system-6592758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:51:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have long known that cancer cells alter lipid metabolism, but it was generally assumed that cancer cells were gobbling up these lipids for energy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cancer cells rarely begin stealthily. Quite the contrary, they alert the immune system to their presence by displaying chemical red flags on their membranes. When detected, the body's defences can swoop in and destroy renegade cells before they can do significant damage. Lipids, fatty molecules traditionally thought to be largely a fuel supply for developing tumours, are at the heart of this early detection system.</p>

<p>However, a new study in Nature shows that one specific lipid type is essential for cancer immune evasion -- so much so that certain cancer cells cannot reproduce without it. The findings validate long-held assumptions that not only is this lipid a crucial factor in cancer biology (and thus a key therapeutic target).</p>

<p>"Cancer cells are altering how this lipid is metabolized, which in turn distorts the 'eat me' signals that malignant cells usually produce," says first author Mariluz Soula, a former graduate student in the laboratory of Kivanc Birsoy, and now a scientist Lime Therapeutics. "This paints a very different picture of the role lipids play in cancer growth."</p>

<p>Scientists have long known that cancer cells alter lipid metabolism, but it was generally assumed that cancer cells were gobbling up these lipids for energy--consuming the fatty molecules to help the tumor grow and spread far beyond that of healthy cells.</p>

<p>"We knew from the literature that elevated lipid levels correlate with severity of cancer growth and metastasis, but it was unclear how," Soula says. The Birsoy lab, in conjunction with the laboratory of Gabriel D. Victoria, set out to answer this question by screening the genes involved in this process. They then implanted a series of cancer cells, each missing a different such gene, into mice with and without immune systems--thereby revealing which lipids a cancer cannot live without.</p>

<p>The result: so-called "sphingolipids." Discovered in the late 1800s by German chemist Johann Ludwig Wilhelm Thudichum, sphingolipids were named after the enigmatic Sphinx of Greek lore because of their puzzling structure and function. Two centuries later, sphingolipids are less of a mystery. "We know that sphingolipids aren't really used for energy," Soula says. "They're mainly in the cell membrane to create scaffolding for signaling proteins."</p>

<p>This finding raised an intriguing possibility. Was lipid metabolism in cancer cells really just the story of hungry cells trying to consume more energy? Or was it a key part of the cancer cell's efforts to subtly manipulate cell signaling and dodge the immune system?</p>

<p>To test how sphingolipids were driving cancer growth, the team turned to an FDA-approved drug used to treat Gaucher disease--a genetic disorder characterized by an impaired ability to break down lipids. The drug essentially blocks glycosphingolipid synthesis, and the team found that this impaired tumor growth in pancreatic, lung, and colorectal cancer models.</p>

<p>They also found that depleting glycosphingolipids prevented the formation of the "lipid nanodomains" that bunch signalizing molecules together on the membrane, impacting the cell's surface receptors on the cell surface in a way that made them more sensitive to an immune response. These findings suggest that cancer cells hoard glycosphingolipids in order to obscure inflammatory signals, and that disrupting glycosphingolipid production can leave cancer cells vulnerable to the immune system.</p>

<p>"Everyone thought of elevated lipid levels as an energy source for cancer cells to consume," Soula says. "We discovered that it's far more nuanced. Lipids are not just fuel, but a protection mechanism for cancer cells that modulates how they communicate with the immune system."</p>

<p>Future work will determine whether this holds true for multiple cancers. The team tested a variety of types, but found this mechanism at work in KRAS-dependent cancers (so named for the mutated oncogene that drives them). Still, the initial results could have significant clinical impact, given how aggressive many KRAS-dependent cancers, such as pancreatic cancer, tend to be. Based on their findings, the team suggests that drug and dietary interventions that stunt sphingolipid production may help increase the efficacy of existing immunotherapies.</p>

<p>"Diets may impact many aspects of cancer biology," Birsoy says. "We believe modulating dietary lipids may be an interesting avenue to target cancer cells' ability to evade immune cells."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tlop50jo_surgery_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pager-attacks-hezbollah-mass-murder-iran-slams-israel-after-9-killed-envoy-injured-in-lebanon-6592621]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Mass Murder": Iran Slams Israel After 9 Killed In Pager Attack In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pager-attacks-hezbollah-mass-murder-iran-slams-israel-after-9-killed-envoy-injured-in-lebanon-6592621]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:35:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Among those wounded in the pager attacks on Tuesday was Iran's ambassador to Lebanon Mojtaba Amani, with Iranian media reporting he suffered injuries "to the hand and the face."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran accused Israel on Wednesday of "mass murder" after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">pager devices</a> belonging to the Tehran-aligned Hezbollah group in Lebanon exploded, killing nine people and wounding nearly 3,000 others.&nbsp;Foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani said in a statement he "condemned the terrorist act of the Zionist regime... as an example of mass murder".</p>

<p>Among those wounded in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-pager-attacks-what-is-a-pager-and-why-hezbollah-still-relies-on-this-outdated-device-6590890#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories">pager blasts</a> on Tuesday was Iran's ambassador to Lebanon Mojtaba Amani, with Iranian media reporting he suffered injuries "to the hand and the face."&nbsp;</p>

<p>State television said that Amani was only lightly injured.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Iranian Red Crescent said on Wednesday it had dispatched "rescue teams and eye surgeons" to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Lebanon</a> to treat the wounded.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Israel on the wave of explosions that killed nine people, including the 10-year-old daughter of a Hezbollah member, and wounded around 2,800 others.</p>

<p>The blasts came just hours after Israel announced it was broadening the aims of the war sparked by Hamas's October 7 attacks to include its fight against the group's ally <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Hezbollah</a> along the country's border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>In his statement, Kanani expressed solidarity with the families of those killed and wounded in the explosions including the Iranian ambassador.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Combating the terrorist acts of the (Israeli) regime and the threats arising from them is an obvious necessity," said Kanani.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is necessary for the international community to act quickly in order to counter the impunity of the Zionist criminal authorities."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4s1csfh8_pager-attack_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pager attacks in Lebanon also injured nearly 3,000 others.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-cups-of-coffee-a-day-may-lower-risk-of-developing-heart-condition-study-6592540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Cups Of Coffee A Day May Lower Risk Of Developing Heart Condition: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-cups-of-coffee-a-day-may-lower-risk-of-developing-heart-condition-study-6592540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:28:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three cups of coffee a day could lower one's risk of developing multiple metabolic conditions, including diabetes, and those related to heart, by 40 per cent to almost 50 per cent, a new research has found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three cups of coffee a day could lower one's risk of developing multiple metabolic conditions, including diabetes, and those related to heart, by 40 per cent to almost 50 per cent, a new research has found.</p>

<p>Researchers said that as populations age globally, there is an increase in number of people with at least two cardiometabolic diseases -- referred to as 'cardiometabolic multimorbidity' -- which is becoming a public health concern.</p>

<p>Using data from the UK Biobank, the researchers from Suzhou Medical College of Soochow University, China, analysed information of over 1.72 lakh people taking caffeine with that of 1.88 lakh people consuming coffee and tea. The participants were free of cardiometabolic conditions at the study's start.</p>

<p>While coffee and tea are well-known to contain caffeine, the stimulant is also present in chocolates, aerated and energy drinks, and snack bars, all of which count as caffeine intake.</p>

<p>The authors found that people consuming moderate amounts -- three cups of coffee or 200-300 milligrams of caffeine a day -- had a 40-48 per cent lower risk of developing cardiometablic comorbidity, compared to those not consuming or taking under 100 milligrams of caffeine a day. The results are published in the Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism.</p>

<p>"Consuming three cups of coffee, or 200-300 mg caffeine, per day might help to reduce the risk of developing cardiometabolic multimorbidity in individuals without any cardiometabolic disease," lead author Chaofu Ke from the School of Public Health at Suzhou Medical College of Soochow University said.</p>

<p>While the protective effects of coffee and tea beverages in people having one cardiometabolic disease have been detailed in numerous studies, the researchers said the potential effects of these beverages in the onset of more than one such condition is largely unknown.</p>

<p>Even though all levels of coffee and caffeine intake were found to be conversely related with the risk of onset of more than one cardiometabolic disorder -- higher the intake, lower the risk -- those reporting moderate levels of coffee or caffeine intake were found to have the lowest risk.</p>

<p>"The findings highlight that promoting moderate amounts of coffee or caffeine intake as a dietary habit to healthy people might have far-reaching benefits for the prevention of cardiometabolic comorbidity," Ke said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/480ih3a8_coffee-generic-istock_625x300_12_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-makes-tentative-return-to-work-week-after-finishing-chemotherapy-6592564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton Makes Tentative Return To Work After Finishing Chemotherapy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-makes-tentative-return-to-work-week-after-finishing-chemotherapy-6592564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:27:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kate Middleton held a meeting at Windsor Castle, west of London, with staff from the Royal Foundation Centre for Early Childhood.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Princess of Wales has taken a first step towards returning to her work on the early-years development of children, a week after announcing she had completed chemotherapy. Catherine, 42, also known as <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-finishes-chemotherapy-course-says-cant-tell-what-a-relief-6527477">Kate Middleton</a>, held a meeting at Windsor Castle, west of London, with staff from the Royal Foundation Centre for Early Childhood, the organisation she established, on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The meeting was listed in the Court Circular, the official record of engagements carried out by members of the royal family, which was published in The Times newspaper on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The issue of childrens' early development has been described as mother-of-three Catherine's life's work by aides.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/groundbreaking-how-people-reacted-to-kate-middletons-chemo-announcement-6535556">Catherine</a>, a future queen who is married to heir to the throne Prince William, has appeared in public on only a few occasions since the start of the year, when it was announced that she was due to have abdominal surgery.</p>

<p>That announcement was followed in March with the shock revelation that she was undergoing a course of "preventative chemotherapy" for an undisclosed cancer.</p>

<p>She said last week she had finished the treatment and was "looking forward to being back at work and undertaking a few more public engagements in the coming months when I can".</p>

<p>The announcement in a highly emotional video came after her father-in-law, King Charles III, 75, was given the light to resume public duties in April after his own cancer treatment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/jj55v3mo_kate-middleton_625x300_14_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-wins-challenge-against-brussels-1-66-billion-antitrust-fine-6592492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Wins Challenge Against Brussels' $1.66 Billion Antitrust Fine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-wins-challenge-against-brussels-1-66-billion-antitrust-fine-6592492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:16:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ruling will be a relief for Google after the EU's highest court last week upheld a 2017 fine worth 2.42 billion euros for abusing its dominance by favouring its own comparison shopping service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An EU court on Wednesday scrapped a 1.49-billion euro ($1.65 billion) fine imposed by Brussels against Google for an abuse of dominance over online advertising. "The General Court annuls the (European) Commission's decision in its entirety," the Luxembourg-based court said in a statement, adding that the "institution committed errors in its assessment".</p>

<p>Brussels "failed to take into consideration all the relevant circumstances in its assessment of the duration of the contract clauses that the commission had deemed abusive", the court said.</p>

<p>The commission, the EU's influential competition regulator, said it "takes note" and would "carefully study the judgment and reflect on possible next steps" -- which could include an appeal.</p>

<p>The ruling will be a relief for Google after the EU's highest court last week upheld a 2017 fine worth 2.42 billion euros for abusing its dominance by favouring its own comparison shopping service.</p>

<p>As part of a major push to target big tech abuses, the EU slapped Google with fines worth a total of 8.2 billion euros between 2017 and 2019 over antitrust violations.</p>

<p>The 1.49-billion euro fine is the third of those penalties, focused on Google's AdSense service.</p>

<p>But the long-running legal battles between Google and the EU do not end there.</p>

<p>Google is also challenging a 4.3-billion-euro penalty Brussels levied on it for putting restrictions on Android smartphones to boost its internet search business.</p>

<p>The 2018 fine remains the EU's largest-ever antitrust penalty.</p>

<p>The General Court in 2022 slightly reduced the fine to 4.1 billion euros, but mainly supported the commission's argument that Google had imposed illegal restrictions.</p>

<p>The legal saga continues in that case after Google appealed the latest decision before the higher European Court of Justice.</p>

<p>The EU has since armed itself with a more powerful legal weapon known as the Digital Markets Act (DMA), to rein in tech giants including Google.</p>

<p>Rather than regulators discovering egregious antitrust violations after probes lasting many years, the DMA gives businesses a list of what they can and cannot do online.</p>

<p>The aim is that tech titans change their ways before the need for deterrent fines.</p>

<p>Google is already the subject of one investigation under the DMA alongside Facebook owner Meta and Apple.</p>

<p>Google is in the US regulators' crosshairs as well.</p>

<p>Last week, the tech titan faced its second major antitrust trial in less than a year with the US government accusing Google of a monopoly in ad technology -- the complex system determining which online ads people see and their cost.</p>

<p>It comes after a US judge in August found Google's search business to be an illegal monopoly, a ruling which threatens a possible break-up for the tech behemoth.</p>

<p>Ad tech is at the centre of multiple probes by regulators around the world.</p>

<p>British regulators earlier this month said in provisional findings that Google abused its dominance in the market.</p>

<p>The EU similarly concluded last year that Google is distorting competition in the market and recommended that the company be forced to divest its ad tech business.</p>

<p>Google has the right to respond in the British and EU cases before the regulators reach final conclusions.</p>

<p>Parent company Alphabet in July said revenue from online ad searches climbed to $48.5 billion in the second quarter of this year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/subjtm5_google_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stone-age-people-drove-dwarf-hippos-elephants-to-extinction-on-cyprus-study-says-6592447]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stone Age People Drove Dwarf Hippos To Extinction On Cyprus? Study Says...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stone-age-people-drove-dwarf-hippos-elephants-to-extinction-on-cyprus-study-says-6592447]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:10:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cyprus wasnt the only Mediterranean island with dwarf wildlife. In fact, Crete, Malta, Sicily, Sardinia and many other islands had their own dwarf elephants and hippos.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine growing up beside the eastern Mediterranean Sea 14,000 years ago. You're an accomplished sailor of the small watercraft you and your fellow villagers make, and you live off both the sea and the land. But times have been difficult — there just isn't the same amount of game or fish around as when you were a child. Maybe it's time to look elsewhere for food.</p>

<p>Now imagine <a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/heritage5040160">going farther</a> than ever before in your <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0299765">little boat</a>, accompanied maybe by a few others, when suddenly you spot something on the horizon. Is that an island?</p>

<h2><strong>An island of tiny elephants and hippos</strong></h2>

<p>Welcome to <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/D6LAmqHQic4oNJjz7">Cyprus</a> as the world emerges from the <a href="https://www.livescience.com/40311-pleistocene-epoch.html">last ice age</a>. You are the first human to set your eyes on this huge, <a href="http://doi.org/10.4000/paleorient.2565">heavily forested island</a> teeming with food.</p>

<p>When you beach your boat to have a look around, you can't believe what you're seeing — tiny boar-sized hippos and horse-sized elephants that look like babies to your eyes. There are so many of them, and you're hungry after the long journey.</p>

<p>The diminutive beasts don't seem to show any fear. You easily kill a few and preserve the meat as best you can for the long journey back.</p>

<p>When you get home, you are excited to let everyone in the village know what you've found. Soon enough, you organise a major expedition back to the island.</p>

<p>Of course, we'll never know if this kind of scenario took place, but it's a plausible story of how and when the <a href="https://cosmosmagazine.com/history/archaeology/cyprus-stone-age-settlement/">first humans managed to get to Cyprus</a>. It also illustrates how they might have quickly brought about the demise of the <a href="https://uchytel.com/Hippopotamus-minor">tiny hippopotamus</a> <em>Phanourios minor</em>, as well as the <a href="https://uchytel.com/Palaeoloxodon-cypriotes">dwarf elephant</a> <em>Palaeoloxodon cypriotes</em>.</p>

<h2><strong>Dwarf ‘giants'</strong></h2>

<p>Cyprus wasn't the only Mediterranean island with dwarf wildlife. In fact, Crete, Malta, Sicily, Sardinia and many other islands had their own <a href="https://www.theextinctions.com/articles-1/elephants-of-the-aegean-dwarfs-and-giants-of-the-ancient-sea">dwarf elephants</a> and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2017/jan/25/sun-sea-and-fossils-the-mediterranean-is-a-surprising-palaeontological-paradise">hippos</a>.</p>

<p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="tWIqa" scrolling="no" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/tWIqa/2/" style="border: 0;" width="100%"></iframe></p>

<p><a href="https://www.sapiens.org/biology/island-dwarfism/">Island dwarfism</a> — the process in which a once large, mainland species evolves to become smaller in response to fewer resources and predators — is in fact quite common. Unfortunately, the process also makes such species <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.add8606">more vulnerable to rapid environmental change</a>, including the arrival of new predators such as humans.</p>

<figure class="align-right zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="Photo of a museum display of the skeleton of a dwarf hippo and an illustration of what it may have looked like in life." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=237&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=825&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=825&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=825&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1037&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1037&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1037&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Skeleton of a dwarf hippo (<em>Phanourios minor</em>) and artist's reconstruction of the animal displayed at the Akamas Geology and Palaeontology Information Centre in Pano Arodes, western Cyprus.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://panoarodes.com/akamas-geology-and-paleontology-information-center/">CJA Bradshaw / Flinders University</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The Cypriot dwarf hippopotamus was the <a href="http://doi.org/10.1016/j.palaeo.2019.05.032">smallest dwarf hippo</a> in the Mediterranean region. Genetic data suggest <a href="http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab089">it diverged</a> from the <a href="https://www.awf.org/wildlife-conservation/hippopotamus">common hippopotamus</a> (<em>Hippopotamus amphibius</em>) roughly 1.5 million years ago.</p>

<p>The Cypriot dwarf elephant was less than 10% of the size of its mainland ancestor, <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/237394736_Palaeloxodon_cypriotes_the_dwarf_elephant_of_Cyprus_Size_and_scaling_comparisons_with_P_falconeri_Sicily-Malta_and_mainland_P_antiquus">the straight-tusked elephant</a> (<em>Palaeoloxodon antiquus</em>) that inhabited Europe and Western Asia during the Middle and Late Pleistocene.</p>

<h2><strong>An extinction controversy</strong></h2>

<p>For a long time, many <a href="https://ibdigital.uib.es/greenstone/collect/monografiesHistoriaNatural/index/assoc/Monograf/iesSHNB_/2005vol0/12p193.dir/MonografiesSHNB_2005vol012p193.pdf">archaeologists</a> and <a href="https://doi.org/10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0134429">palaeontologists</a> didn't believe humans had anything to do with the extinction of these two “<a href="https://rewilding.academy/what-is-megafauna-2/">megafauna</a>” species on Cyprus.</p>

<p>The doubters assumed that either people arrived well after the extinctions, or the earliest humans were too few to be able to kill off entire species.</p>

<p>Earlier this year we showed that <a href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2318293121">people came to Cyprus between 14,000 and 13,000 years ago</a>, well before hippos and elephants went extinct. We also showed that the human population likely grew to several thousand within a few hundred years of arrival. But we didn't know whether this human population was large enough to drive the dwarf hippos and elephants to extinction.</p>

<p>Our new <a href="https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2024.0967">research published today</a> answers this question with a combination of several different types of mathematical models.</p>

<h2><strong>Could a small human population cause extinction?</strong></h2>

<p>Even though these animals are long extinct, we can draw some conclusions about their likely population because we can estimate their weights from palaeontological information. The dwarf hippo weighed around 130kg, and the dwarf elephant came in at just over 500kg.</p>

<p>We also know how to translate weights to estimates of population size, longevity, survival and fertility. We can even use data collected from related species still living today, such as the <a href="https://taronga.org.au/animals/pygmy-hippopotamus">pygmy hippo</a> and the <a href="https://www.worldwildlife.org/species/african-elephant">African elephant</a>, to estimate how fast they would have grown.</p>

<p>With this information, we built computer models of what would have happened to the two mini-megafauna species on Cyprus when human hunters arrived. We estimated how efficient human hunters would be, how long it would take them to process each carcass, and how much energy hunter-gatherers need to survive.</p>

<p>We also estimated how much of the human diet included these species, and how this proportion might have changed as the dwarf hippo and elephant numbers dwindled.</p>

<p>We found that even a small human population, numbering between 3,000 and 7,000, could have easily driven first dwarf hippos, and then dwarf elephants, to extinction. Our model showed the process would have taken less than 1,000 years. This prediction matches the sequence of extinction inferred from the palaeontological record.</p>

<p>Our results provide strong evidence that palaeolithic peoples in Cyprus were at least partially, if not entirely, responsible for megafauna extinctions during the Late Pleistocene and early Holocene.</p>

<p>Cyprus was the perfect place to test our models because the island offers an ideal set of conditions to examine whether the arrival of humans ultimately led to the extinction of its megafauna. This is because Cyprus was a relatively simple test case – a small island of around 11,000 square kilometres at the time, with only two species of megafauna.</p>

<p>Our research therefore improves our understanding of how even small human populations can disrupt ecosystems and cause major extinctions, particularly in times of rapid environmental change.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238999/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><span>(<strong>Authors:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/corey-j-a-bradshaw-9183">Corey J. A. Bradshaw</a>, Matthew Flinders Professor of Global Ecology and Node Leader in the ARC Centre of Excellence for Indigenous and Environmental Histories and Futures, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a></em>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/christian-reepmeyer-1527424">Christian Reepmeyer</a>, Deputy Director - Oceania, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/deutsches-archaologisches-institut-german-archaeological-institute-6198">Deutsches Archäologisches Institut - German Archaeological Institute</a></em>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/theodora-moutsiou-1527770">Theodora Moutsiou</a>, Special Scientist, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-cyprus-1426">University of Cyprus</a>)</em></span></p>

<p>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/small-populations-of-stone-age-people-drove-dwarf-hippos-and-elephants-to-extinction-on-cyprus-238999">original article</a>.)</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/924tc87g_dwarf-hippos_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-plan-continue-golf-comes-as-a-bogey-for-the-us-secret-sevice-6592416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Plan To Continue Golf Comes As A 'Bogey' For The US Secret Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-plan-continue-golf-comes-as-a-bogey-for-the-us-secret-sevice-6592416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:04:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of the Secret Service told Donald Trump in a private meeting that significant new security arrangements will be needed if he wants to keep playing golf, The New York Times reported on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of the Secret Service told Donald Trump in a private meeting that significant new security arrangements will be needed if he wants to keep playing golf, The New York Times reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump asked Ronald Rowe, the Secret Service's acting director, in a meeting on Monday whether it was safe for him to continue playing, the newspaper said. Rowe said the Secret Service views the golf course at Joint Base Andrews in Maryland as easier to secure because it is a military course.</p>

<p>That meeting occurred a day after the Secret Service thwarted a second apparent assassination attempt on Trump in less than two months. On Sunday, Secret Service agents fired on Ryan Wesley Routh, the apparent would-be assassin, when they saw the barrel of his gun poking through the fenceline at Trump's golf course in West Palm Beach, Florida, and local police officers later arrested him.</p>

<p>The incident has raised questions within Trump's orbit and among lawmakers about whether Trump's protection is sufficient.</p>

<p>"Former President Trump is receiving the highest level of protection that the U.S. Secret Service can provide, and we will continue to evaluate and adjust our specific protective measures and methodology based on each location and situation," Secret Service spokesperson Melissa McKenzie said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump on Tuesday told Fox News "we've long requested more people" and that additional Secret Service protection was forthcoming.</p>

<p>"I think we are getting it now. Somebody told me that they will be providing more people now," Trump told interviewer Sean Hannity by telephone.</p>

<p>Still, West Palm Beach Sheriff Ric Bradshaw told reporters on Sunday that Trump's security detail was not as tight as that of a sitting president.</p>

<p>Since the incident, both Democrats and Republicans have accused each other of using overheated rhetoric that is inspiring political violence.</p>

<p>White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said in a press briefing on Tuesday that Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance's comments about Vice President Kamala Harris not having faced an assassination attempt are dangerous.</p>

<p>"The big difference between conservatives and liberals is that ... no one has tried to kill Kamala Harris in the last couple of months," Vance said on Monday.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre said that language could put Harris in danger.</p>

<p>"When you make comments like that, all it does is ... opens an opportunity for people to listen to you and potentially take you very seriously, and so it's dangerous to have that type of rhetoric out there," she said.</p>

<p>Trump was due to speak at a campaign event in Michigan on Tuesday evening in his first public political event since the apparent assassination attempt over the weekend.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/rl6jcufk_donald-trump-golf-ndtv-file-photo_625x300_18_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Significant new security arrangements will be needed if Donald Trump wants to keep playing golf]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/opinion-a-smartphone-epidemic-is-destroying-europes-new-generation-6592345]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: 'We Lost Her': A Smartphone Epidemic Is Ruining Europe's New Generation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/opinion-a-smartphone-epidemic-is-destroying-europes-new-generation-6592345]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:55:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Parent-led movements are pushing for stricter screen time regulations, and even bans in schools, calling for comprehensive policies to protect the next generation's future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/mobile-phone_650x400_81501483347.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"We lost her, and she lost her childhood." These were the words of Amanda Miller, the mother of a 15-year-old girl who has been in the hospital for a year, undergoing treatment for acute mental health problems. Smartphone addiction has torn the teenager's world apart. Amanda now campaigns to ban the device for children in British schools. The Labour government is currently considering a ban on smartphones for children under 16 in schools.</p>

<p>In an interview with a TV channel, Amanda revealed that she reluctantly bought her daughter a smartphone for her 10th birthday, a decision she now regrets. Her daughter quickly became obsessed with the device. "She would come home from school and lock herself in her room with her phone. We completely lost her. Her mental health deteriorated-she started self-harming, became depressed, and suicidal to the point where she stopped eating. Eventually, she ended up in the hospital."</p>

<p>Amanda pleads with the UK Government to pass a law to help parents "bring their children back".</p>

<h2><strong>A Continental Epidemic&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Like Amanda, millions of parents across Europe are increasingly vocal about the damaging effects of smartphones on their children. Parent-led movements are pushing for stricter screen time regulations, and even bans in schools, calling for comprehensive policies to protect the next generation's future. More than 10,000 mothers with young children in Spain have created a WhatsApp group to inform one another of the state of their children's mental health and exchange tips on dealing with smartphone addiction. They want help from their government and demand legislation to ban smartphone use in schools.</p>

<p>This growing concern has sparked intense debates across Europe about how to address screen addiction among children. Movements advocating for phone-free schools are gaining momentum. In the absence of any legislation, some schools have started implementing smartphone-free classes and some others have completely banned phones in schools.</p>

<h2><strong>A Crisis In India</strong></h2>

<p>India's smartphone market has exploded in recent years, with no signs of slowing down. The youth, in particular, spend countless hours on their devices. Deloitte predicts that by 2026, India will be the second-largest smartphone market, surpassing one billion users, with rural areas driving sales<br />
Indian youth are consumed by social media and smartphones, which have been linked to mental health problems like depression, anxiety, and social isolation. A Boston Consulting Group (BCG) study reveals that half of Indian consumers pick up their phones out of habit, often without purpose.</p>

<p>Researchers in India warn that more comprehensive studies are needed to understand the full impact of smartphones on children.</p>

<p>In response, both central and state governments have set up de-addiction and research centres focused on phone addiction. While the Indian government has taken steps to encourage responsible usage, more action is needed. In 2015, the Modi government introduced the Prevention of Addiction of Technological Gadgets Bill in the Rajya Sabha, but it's unclear whether it was ever passed into law.<br />
Can we expect teenagers to resist what adults cannot?</p>

<p>Like millions of others, I rely on my smartphone for nearly every aspect of life-reading, writing, social media, internet browsing, and communication. I use it for payments, watching TV, and listening to music. With multiple OTT subscriptions, I have more content at my fingertips than I could ever use.<br />
So, is it fair to expect teenagers to limit their screen time and curb their dependence on smartphones? Some experts argue that banning smartphones in schools is ineffective and anti-technology. Instead, they believe students should be educated on responsible usage. Others warn that a ban might lead to covert smartphone use or smuggling of devices into classrooms. The focus, they say, should be on teaching children the benefits of responsible use and the dangers of overuse.</p>

<h2><strong>The Scale Of The Problem</strong></h2>

<p>Amanda Miller believes smartphones are "killing our children, killing their youth, destroying their mental health". According to a study by the UK's broadcasting and telecommunications regulatory authority, Ofcom, "by the age of 12, 97% of children have their own mobile phones". Studies have shown that increased screen time negatively impacts mental health, academic performance, and social skills. Adolescents, in particular, are at risk of anxiety, depression, and sleep problems due to excessive smartphone use.</p>

<p>By 2022, as much as 68% of the global population used smartphones, and over 60% of people in many countries admitted to being addicted to their devices.</p>

<p>Smartphones have fuelled the rise of social media platforms, allowing celebrities to connect with their young fans. Cristiano Ronaldo, for instance, reached one billion followers across social media platforms in September, with a large portion of his fanbase being young adults. Other youth icons, such as Selena Gomez, Justin Bieber, and Taylor Swift, also have millions of followers, reinforcing the hold smartphones have over young people.</p>

<p>While smartphones offer practical benefits like communication and education, those opposing a ban argue that implementing it could brand Europe as anti-technology. However, the device's addictive nature, similar to gaming addiction, raises concerns. Last year, UNESCO called for a ban on smartphones in schools, and France has already enforced one. The UK is seriously considering banning smartphones for children aged five to 16 in schools, in addition to guidelines issued earlier this year supporting head teachers who prohibit mobile phones.</p>

<p>Some British schools have already banned smartphones with great success, seeing improvements in academic performance and reduced distractions.</p>

<h2><strong>An Experiment That Gives Hope</strong></h2>

<p>Recently, 10 teenagers from a Manchester school participated in a five-day experiment, swapping their smartphones for basic mobile phones that only allowed calls and texts. These boys and girls, aged 14 to 16, previously spent over 12 hours a day on their devices. While one participant demanded his smartphone back, the other nine completed the experiment. One boy reported better sleep and another girl shared that her relationship with her father improved as they spent more time talking. Though a small sample, the experiment suggested that life without smartphones is possible for even the most dependent teens.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the British government contemplates the ban a school trust in England with 35,000 pupils has just announced it is banning smartphones in all its 42 schools in England. The trust hopes that the ban will lead to higher academic achievement and improve the mental health of its pupils.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/mobile-phone_650x400_81501483347.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-2011-hit-and-run-is-fake-news-spread-by-russia-microsoft-6592237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' '2011 Hit-And-Run' Is Fake News Spread By Russia: Microsoft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-2011-hit-and-run-is-fake-news-spread-by-russia-microsoft-6592237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:35:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A false claim circulating on social media that Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralysed after an alleged hit-and-run in San Francisco in 2011 is the work of a covert Russian disinformation operation, according to new research by Microsoft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A false claim circulating on social media that Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralysed after an alleged hit-and-run in San Francisco in 2011 is the work of a covert Russian disinformation operation, according to new research by Microsoft.</p>

<p>Researchers found that the operation created a video, paid an actor to appear as the alleged victim, and spread the claim through a fake website for a non-existent San Francisco news outlet named "KBSF-TV". The Russian group responsible, which Microsoft dubs Storm-1516, is described as a Kremlin-aligned troll farm.</p>

<p>The discovery is a sign of Russia ramping up its foreign influence efforts ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election, Microsoft said.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the Russian embassy in Washington did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>"Russian influence operations initially struggled to pivot operations aimed at the Democratic campaign following President Biden's departure from the U.S. 2024 presidential race," a blog published on Tuesday by Microsoft said.</p>

<p>"In late August, however, elements of prolific Russian actor Storm-1516 began producing content implicating Vice President Harris and Governor Walz in outlandish fake conspiracy theories," Microsoft said, referring to Harris' running mate, Tim Walz.</p>

<p>Storm-1516 is known for producing misleading videos featuring on-screen or voice actors who impersonate whistleblowers or journalists that share false, scandalous information, experts say.</p>

<p>A website for KBSF-TV was created shortly before publishing its first related article about the alleged driving incident, according to online registration records. The claim was circulated on social media platforms, including X.com, using the hashtag #HitAndRunKamala.</p>

<p>The video was also shared on Sept. 3 on X.com by Aussie Cossack, who describes himself as a "Registered foreign agent for Sputnik News," with the message "make this go viral MAGA folks." In total, it is estimated the video has been viewed more than 2.7 million times.</p>

<p>"Many entities within the pro-Russian ecosystem advanced the video and its claims," said Microsoft's Threat Analysis Center. "Storm-1516 relies on some of these personalities, such as Aussie Cossack, to drive amplification of its videos."</p>

<p>Cossack did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Earlier this month the U.S. Justice Department filed money-laundering charges against two employees of Russian state media network RT for what officials said was a scheme to hire an American company to produce online content to influence the election.</p>

<p>US officials say Russia's goal is to exacerbate US political divisions and weaken public support for American military aid to Ukraine. Harris says if elected she will continue supporting Ukraine in its defence against Russia's invasion.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Social media claims about Kamala Harris' "hit-and-run" is fake news, a Microsoft research shows.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-3-600-food-packaging-chemicals-found-in-human-bodies-in-new-study-6592181]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 3,600 Food Packaging Chemicals Found In Human Bodies In New Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-3-600-food-packaging-chemicals-found-in-human-bodies-in-new-study-6592181]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:30:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Around 100 of these chemicals are considered to be of "high concern" to human health, said lead study author Birgit Geueke.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 3,600 chemicals used in food packaging or preparation have been detected in human bodies, some of which are hazardous to health, while little is known about others, a study published on Tuesday said. Around 100 of these chemicals are considered to be of "high concern" to human health, said lead study author Birgit Geueke from the Food Packaging Forum Foundation, a Zurich-based NGO.</p>

<p>Some of these chemicals are relatively well-studied and have already been found in human bodies, such as PFAS and bisphenol A -- both of which are the target of bans.</p>

<p>But little is known about the health effects of others, Geueke told AFP, calling for more research into how chemicals used in packaging end up being swallowed along with food.</p>

<p>The researchers had previously catalogued around 14,000 food contact chemicals (FCCs), which are capable of "migrating" into food from packaging made of plastic, paper, glass, metal or other materials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They can also come from other parts of the food-making process, such as from conveyer belts or kitchen utensils.</p>

<p>The researchers then searched for these chemicals in existing biomonitoring databases, which track chemicals in human samples.</p>

<p>The team was expecting to find a few hundred FCCs, Geueke said. Instead, they were surprised to find 3,601 -- a quarter of all the known FCCs.</p>

<p>Geueke emphasised that this study could not show that all these chemicals necessarily ended up in bodies from food packaging, as "other exposure sources are possible".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the "high concern" chemicals were numerous PFAS, also known as forever chemicals, which have been detected in many parts of the human body in recent years and linked to a range of health problems.</p>

<p>Also detected was bisphenol A, a hormone-disrupting chemical used to make plastics that has already been banned from baby bottles in many countries.</p>

<p>Another hormone-disrupting chemical was phthalates, which has been linked to infertility.</p>

<p>Less is known about oligomers, which are also byproducts of plastic production.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There is almost no evidence on the health effects of these chemicals," Geueke said.</p>

<p>When it comes to toxicology, an old saying is that "the dose makes the poison".</p>

<p>A limitation of the study was that it could not say whether there were particularly high concentrations of any of the chemicals, Geueke acknowledged.</p>

<p>But she warned that these chemicals can interact with each other, pointing to a single sample that had up to 30 different PFAS.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Geueke recommended that people reduce their contact time with packaging -- and to avoid heating up food in the packaging it came in.</p>

<p>Duane Mellor, an expert in evidence-based medicine at the UK's Aston University and not involved in the research, praised the "very thorough piece of work".</p>

<p>"However, it does not cover how much of these chemicals we are exposed to and hints at other sources of these chemicals in our environment," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Rather than being "unduly alarmed", Mellor suggested that people "demand better data and minimise unnecessary exposure to chemicals which may ultimately impact our health".</p>

<p>Some of the chemicals are also already facing bans.</p>

<p>The European Union is in the final stages of banning the use of PFAS in food packaging. The EU has also proposed a similar ban for bisphenol A from the end of this year.</p>

<p>The study was published in the Journal of Exposure Science and Environmental Epidemiology.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/55a8ckv_food-packaging-chemicals-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Pagers Turned Bombs And Why Israel Is Being Blamed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:19:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of pagers exploded within seconds across the Lebanon yesterday in a synchronized attack targeting the US-designated terror group Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of pagers exploded within seconds across the Lebanon yesterday in a synchronized attack targeting the US-designated terror group Hezbollah. The explosions killed at least nine and injured 2,800 individuals in the country that has been caught up in the Israel-Palestine tensions in its backyard.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, the political force running Lebanon, has blamed Israel for the attack. Throughout Gaza war, it supported Hamas and exchanged fire across its southern border with Israel in support for its Palestinian group.</p>

<p>No country or group has claimed responsibility for the attack yet. But fingers pointing at Israel raise a big question over the capabilities of Mossad, the Israeli spy agency known for carrying out targeted attacks on foreign soils.</p>

<h2><strong>Pager bombs - a reality?</strong></h2>

<p>Pagers are wireless low-tech means of communication that lost popularity in the nineties with the emergence of mobile phones. They can display text messages but not relay voice calls. Hezbollah uses pagers to avoid location-tracking by Israel.</p>

<p>The ones used that exploded yesterday came fitted with explosives from Taiwan, reported the New York Times. Gold Apollo, a Taiwanese firm, had placed the order and the pagers were tampered by Israeli agents before they arrived in Lebanon, the US-based newspaper said citing unnamed officials.</p>

<p>Some 3,000 pagers were part of a recent order for Gold Apollo that included mostly its AR-924 model, reported the NYT.</p>

<p>Israeli intelligence infiltrated the production process of the pagers and fitted the explosives that could be triggered remotely without any suspicion, said news agency AFP citing a Brussel-based security analyst.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884">Inside Lebanon Politics: Hezbollah, Iran And A Larger Battle For Hegemony</a></p>

<p>Mossad had been planning the attack for months, according to Reuters. They fitted the Taiwan-made devices with up to 3 grams of explosives that went unnoticed by Hezbollah, it reported cited Lebanese sources.</p>

<p>The trigger was activated and about 3,000 pagers exploded when a codeword was sent to them, the news agency reported.</p>

<p>Gold Apollo founder Hsu Ching-Kuang has denied making the pagers. He said a Hungarian firm named BAC that had the right to use his company's brand name were the original makers.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Israel Is Being Blamed</strong></h2>

<p>Early Tuesday morning, Israeli PMO released a statement that the safe return of residents evacuated from northern Israel - which borders southern Lebanon - was among its war goals.</p>

<p>Hours later, blasts rocked Lebanon.</p>

<p>Mossad, which has a long history of carrying out sophisticated remote attacks on foreign soil, came under question though Israel never claims responsibility for such covert operations.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229">3 Grams Of Explosives Per Pager: Israel's Complex Op To Hurt Hezbollah</a></p>

<p>The latest such incident that was linked to Israel was the killing of a top Hamas commander in Iran. Ismail Haniyeh's assassination in a blast at a high-security VIP compound in a posh Tehran locality was carried out by Mossad, The Telegraph (UK) reported. The bomb was smuggled in months ago, the NYT had said, and was triggered remotely after Haniyeh entered that particular room.</p>

<p>Mossad also played a big role in the 'Operation Wrath of God', codenamed Bayonet, which was activated to avenge the murders of 11 Israeli athletes by Palestinian operatives at the 1972 Olympics in Munich.</p>

<p>During the operation, they used telephones not only to track their enemies but to kill them. A top leader of the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) was killed in Paris in a blast that occurred after he answered a telephone call. This marked the emergence of what came to be known as telephone bombs.</p>

<p>Mobile phones were the next target as technology evolved. A bomb-making expert of the Hamas was killed in 1996 after his mobile phone blasted when he answered a call.</p>

<p>Linked or not, attacks on Palestinians and their allies using telephone, mobile phone, and now pagers complete a cycle of using communication means as weapons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iuermu3_pagers-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pagers are wireless low-tech means of communication that lost popularity in the nineties. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>