<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 11:38:25 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-canada-row-when-fiction-is-as-important-as-facts-6808464]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India-Canada Row: When Fiction Is As Important As Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-canada-row-when-fiction-is-as-important-as-facts-6808464]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 11:32:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[What has compelled Canada to make public its investigations in the Nijjar assassination case and hold India responsible? Has there been a slight or a breach of trust, intended or otherwise, behind the scenes that a public show is to be put up?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/cbi4u6gg_justin_625x300_17_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"We're not so different, you and I. We've both spent our lives looking for the weakness in one another's systems. Don't you think it's time to recognize there is as little worth on your side as there is on mine?"</p>

<p>Those who've been rooting for Gary Oldman playing Jackson Lamb, the instantly unlikeable boss of the good-for-nothings of MI5, the British intelligence agency, in Apple's <em>Slow Horses</em>, may not even remember this line the actor delivered playing another spy boss in another spy thriller: as George Smiley in<em> Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy,</em> a 2011 film based on John la Carre's book.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Addressed to Smiley's Russian counterpart, Karla, this line, emblematic of the film's politics, was celebrated and decried in equal measure for creating an equivalence between the US and the USSR during the Cold War. Going by the recent media stories and diplomatic activity, George Smiley could have very well said it about India and Canada today.</p>

<h2><strong>Blow Hot, Blow Cold</strong></h2>

<p>New Delhi and Ottawa have expelled each other's top diplomats, following the Canadian Prime Minister's latest accusation of the Indian establishment being directly involved in the assassination of a Sikh separatist on Canadian soil. India, on the other hand, has not only denied it but also mounted a counterattack on Canada for nurturing anti-India groups within its territory.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fall is not fair weather for India-Canada relations. Exactly one year ago, the two countries were engaged in similar diplomatic acrimony over the same assassination. Khalistan, after nuclear proliferation, has been their proverbial bee in the bonnet for several decades. With the exception of the lull during the turn of the millennium, the issue has stayed alive and volatile. It is not going anywhere in a hurry.</p>

<p>Canada's soft approach towards anti-India outfits was once attributed solely to its domestic politics: the country is home to the largest Sikh diaspora, with around 7,70,000 of them living there. The current strain in the relationship, however, may not just be about Canada's vote bank politics or India's internal affairs involving resistance from a sect of Sikhs. There is, quite clearly, an emergence of bilateral antagonism now. Are the rapprochement personnel doing their job well? Or, more provocatively, are the spies doing theirs?</p>

<h2><strong>Flashbacks From 1975</strong></h2>

<p>Realistically speaking, assassinations on foreign soil are not a no-go zone, even with declared enemies, if the assassins are smart. The morality and legality of such actions is another story. What, then, has compelled Canada, a limited ally, to make public its investigations in the Nijjar assassination case and hold India responsible? Has there been a slight or a breach of trust, intended or otherwise, behind the scenes that a public show is to be put up? Are there bad-faith actors at work on either side, or is it sheer incompetence? It could be either or both, but as venerable Canadian writer Margaret Atwood reminds us, "Stupidity is the same as evil if you judge by the results". Therefore, it's the breakdown of bilateral ties that matters, much more than the nitty-gritty of what caused it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This escalation of diplomatic tensions between India and Canada is beginning to loosely resemble another controversial diplomatic event that occurred half a century ago: the breakdown of the then newly forged Australia-North Korea relations. On October 30, 1975, Pyongyang recalled its diplomats from Canberra, citing the host country's 'unfriendly attitude' and 'intolerable provocative acts' in a communication sent via commercial mail. Less than ten days later, Australian diplomats were ousted from Pyongyang on November 8 on account of 'unfriendly behaviour' and 'abuse of diplomatic immunity'.</p>

<p>The actors and the times are different, but the problem is the same. This inability to smoothen out the rough edges time and again reflects poorly on the political and diplomatic leaders of India and Canada. What are long bilateral ties worth if they cannot withstand such events? Both Ottawa and New Delhi have engaged in the game of provocation and reconciliation. The classic blow-hot, blow-cold approach. To what end, though?&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Lesson From<em> Bridge Of Spies</em></strong></h2>

<p>Coming back to George Smiley's wisdom, looking for weaknesses in the other is a zero-sum game. This isn't the Cold War yet, but as India grows in stature, the chances of this game intensifying will increase correspondingly. India and Canada are not directly engaged in any military-territorial jostling, so these flare-ups have an even more limited scope. Both are citing long-term national security concerns, and other countries like the UK and the US are trying to broker 'peace' by urging India to cooperate in the investigation.</p>

<p>Diplomacy is an exercise in sifting fact from fiction but addressing both because both matter, even if unequally. Another popular culture reference to demonstrate it comes from <em>Bridge of Spies</em>, a 2014 film about the famous spy exchange between the US and USSR. James Donovan (Tom Hanks), a lawyer representing a Russian spy called Rudolf Abel (Mark Rylance), tells him, "The case against you matters. Making them prove it matters. The fiction is: whether you did it or not doesn't matter. The state has to prove it, that you're a spy".</p>

<p>Before anyone condescends about taking lessons from fiction, remember, apart from John la Carre, celebrated writers like Ian Fleming and Graham Greene once served in MI6.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Nishtha Gautam is a Delhi-based author and academic.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kkm9j03o_justin_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/menendez-brothers-killed-parents-to-avoid-abuse-relatives-urge-their-release-6808424]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Menendez Brothers Killed Parents To Avoid Abuse, Relatives Urge Their Release]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/menendez-brothers-killed-parents-to-avoid-abuse-relatives-urge-their-release-6808424]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 11:26:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Relatives of Lyle and Erik Menendez on Wednesday pleaded for the release of the long-imprisoned brothers as US prosecutors review new evidence concerning the infamous 1989 murder of their parents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Relatives of Lyle and Erik Menendez on Wednesday pleaded for the release of the long-imprisoned brothers as US prosecutors review new evidence concerning the infamous 1989 murder of their parents.</p>

<p>The grisly shotgun slayings of wealthy music mogul Jose Menendez and his wife Kitty in their Beverly Hills home -- and their sons' subsequent, televised murder trials -- became the subject of a media frenzy. A hit Netflix series has recently sparked fresh interest in the case.</p>

<p>The brothers, aged 21 and 18 at the time of the murders, tearfully testified they killed their parents for fear of their own lives after years of sexual abuse by their father.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They were convicted of first-degree murder and have been serving life sentences in prison without possibility of parole since their sentencing in 1996.</p>

<p>"As details of Lyle and Eric's abuse came to light, it became clear that their actions, while tragic, were the desperate response of two boys trying to survive the unspeakable cruel(ty) of their father," their 92-year-old aunt Joan VanderMolen said Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Lyle and Erik have already paid a heavy price, discarded by a system that failed to recognize their pain," she told a news conference attended by some 30 relatives.</p>

<p>Their initial trial, starting in 1993, was one of the first televised murder cases to make daily headlines around the world. It ended in a mistrial due to a deadlocked jury, but they were found guilty in a second trial.</p>

<p>Prosecutors argued they conspired to murder their parents in order to inherit their $14 million fortune.</p>

<p>Last year, the brothers' attorneys filed a court petition setting out new evidence which they said demonstrates Jose Menendez's history of sexual abuse.</p>

<p>Among the new evidence is a letter Erik wrote to a cousin months before the murders, saying "I've been trying to avoid dad. It's still happening... Every night I stay up thinking he might come in."</p>

<p>Former Latino boy band member Roy Rossello said in a documentary series released last year that he was drugged and raped by Jose Menendez in the 1980s.</p>

<p>The brothers' attorneys have called for a resentencing, which could see their clients released from prison given the lengthy time already spent behind bars.</p>

<p>Prosecutors said in a statement Wednesday that Los Angeles's criminal justice system "has developed a more modern understanding of sexual violence since the Menendez brothers first faced prosecution."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Today, our office acknowledges that sexual violence is a pervasive issue affecting countless individuals -- of all gender identities," they wrote, confirming the case is being reviewed on multiple fronts.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Los Angeles district attorney George Gascon told reporters he had "a moral and an ethical obligation to review what is being presented to us."</p>

<p>His comments came two weeks after the release on Netflix of the crime drama "Monsters: The Lyle and Erik Menendez Story." The streaming giant also put out a documentary film, "The Menendez Brothers," last week.</p>

<p>Gascon, who is running for re-election on a criminal reform platform, acknowledged the initial Netflix show resulted in a large number of calls to his office about the case.</p>

<p>A hearing is scheduled for November 26.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aqk3mbmg_menendez-brothers-x_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Their initial trial, starting in 1993, made headlines across the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-many-australians-arent-looking-forward-to-king-charles-visit-6808225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Many Australians Aren't Looking Forward To King Charles' Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-many-australians-arent-looking-forward-to-king-charles-visit-6808225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 10:52:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On the eve of King Charles III's landmark tour Down Under, many of his antipodean subjects are unaware or uninterested -- a sign, experts say, of a more diverse and less Anglo-centric Australia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the eve of King Charles III's landmark tour Down Under, many of his antipodean subjects are unaware or uninterested -- a sign, experts say, of a more diverse and less Anglo-centric Australia.</p>

<p>There is no red-white-and-blue bunting around Sydney Harbour, no posters on the city's streets and aside from cries from ardent monarchists and republicans, little chatter about the first visit of a sitting Australian monarch in 13 years.</p>

<p>"I'd forgotten they were even coming," said 73-year-old Sydneysider Trevor Reeves summing up the mood in Australia's largest city.</p>

<p>This six-day royal visit to Sydney and Canberra will undoubtedly bring pomp, ceremony and plenty of media coverage.</p>

<p>Even with the schedule skimmed back because of Charles' cancer diagnosis, there will be extravagant mass gatherings, including an event in front of the Opera House and a sprawling community barbecue.</p>

<p>But few expect Charles and Camilla's visit to match the buzz of nation-stopping royal visits past -- including Charles and his first wife Diana's trip in 1983.</p>

<p>Today Aussies appear more preoccupied with war in the Middle East, the US election, or another group of British visitors -- rock group Oasis -- who will tour next year.</p>

<p>"I'm not excited, but I don't begrudge them coming out," said 72-year-old Susanne Lowire. "They don't have much impact over here."</p>

<p>"Some people just love it as they love movie stars," said Lowire, likening the royals to musical brothers Liam and Noel Gallagher.</p>

<p>"Are they going to fight again? Do they sound terrible? It's the same with the king and the queen coming over," she said.</p>

<p>University of Sydney historian Cindy McCreery believes the lack of attention being paid to the royal visit is understandable amid worries about war, climate change and the cost of living.</p>

<p>"We live in a complex moment with all the global issues," she said. It is "natural to expect a more varied response to the monarchy".&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, decades-long demographic trends are also shaping perceptions.</p>

<h3><strong>A changing nation</strong>&nbsp;</h3>

<p>About 36 per cent of Australians still identify as "English", the country's largest ancestry, according to a 2021 census.</p>

<p>That figure was 10 points higher when the census first asked that question in 1986.</p>

<p>About a third of Australians today were born overseas, and the population is steadily becoming more Italian, Greek, Lebanese, Indian or Chinese.</p>

<p>"That impacts how Australians connect or do not connect," McCreery said.</p>

<p>"In previous royal visits, people may have had a stronger connection to Britain, but a growing number of people may not necessarily have that immediate connection."</p>

<p>Polls show about a third of Australians would like to ditch the monarchy, a third would keep it, and a third are ambivalent.</p>

<p>So no sweeping constitutional change is on the cards, and the issue is a political dead rubber.</p>

<p>While Australia voted against becoming a republic in 1999, the movement remains active, but in political purgatory.</p>

<p>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is a lifelong Republican and even created a minister for the republic when he came to office.</p>

<p>The post was quietly scrapped earlier this year and Albanese, having heavily lost a referendum on Indigenous rights, has ruled out going back to the voters about the royals.</p>

<h3><strong>Royal collectors&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The royals are not without Australian fans.</p>

<p>Still, even Jan Hugo, one of the largest royal memorabilia collectors in the Southern Hemisphere, will not travel two hours to Sydney to see the king and queen, when they visit.</p>

<p>Her home in rural New South Wales could be mistaken for a museum. Every corner is bursting with more than 10,000 pieces of royal memorabilia.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5cjajee8_king-charles-memorabilia-afp-_625x300_17_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Jan Hugo is one of the largest royal memorabilia collectors in Australia.&nbsp;<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>Hugo admits she has given up counting how many items she has.</p>

<p>"It's probably worth a fortune to me and nothing to somebody else," she said.</p>

<p>It all started 40 years ago when she was given a commemorative coin for the engagement of Charles and Diana.</p>

<p>Now, most of Hugo's home is dedicated to the royal family, with unusual trinkets lining the walls.</p>

<p>A large statue of Queen Elizabeth II sits on a throne surrounded by her beloved corgis.</p>

<p>Hugo said the republic debate rears its head every time the royals visit, but whatever Australia decides she just hopes to get her hands on some memorabilia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/nu3et0i_king-charles-iii-afp_625x300_01_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Britain's King Charles and Queen Camilla will visit Australia from October 18 to 23. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vistara-frankfurt-mumbai-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-bomb-threat-6808170]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vistara Frankfurt-Mumbai Flight Makes Emergency Landing After Bomb Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vistara-frankfurt-mumbai-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-bomb-threat-6808170]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 10:47:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Mumbai-bound Vistara flight with 147 persons on board made an emergency landing here on Wednesday upon its arrival from Frankfurt in Germany following a bomb threat to the aircraft, a source said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Mumbai-bound Vistara flight with 147 persons on board made an emergency landing here on Wednesday upon its arrival from Frankfurt in Germany following a bomb threat to the aircraft, a source said.</p>

<p>The Boeing 787 aircraft was immediately taken to the isolation bay for mandatory security checks, according to the source.</p>

<p>The flight landed safely at 7.45 am.</p>

<p>There were 134 passengers and 13 crew on board the aircraft, as per sources.</p>

<p>"Vistara Frankfurt flight, which had departed for Mumbai from Frankfurt on Tuesday at 8.20 pm (local time) made an emergency landing here at around 7.45 am on Wednesday," a source said.</p>

<p>Vistara, in a statement, said that its Frankfurt-Mumbai flight received a security alert but landed safely here.</p>

<p>"The Vistara flight UK 028 operating from Frankfurt to Mumbai on October 16, 2024 was subject to a security threat received on social media," the airline said.</p>

<p>As per the protocol, all relevant authorities were immediately informed, it said, adding the aircraft safely landed at the Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport, Mumbai.</p>

<p>"It was taken to the isolation bay where all customers were disembarked. We are fully cooperating with the security agencies to complete the mandatory security checks," Vistara said in the statement.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jnf5p9mo_vistara-_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vistara flight UK 028 operating from Frankfurt to Mumbai was subject to a security threat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-tar-balls-the-mystery-debris-that-is-closing-beaches-in-sydney-6808009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Are Tar Balls, The Mystery Debris That Is Closing Beaches In Sydney]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-tar-balls-the-mystery-debris-that-is-closing-beaches-in-sydney-6808009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 10:14:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lifeguards declared Sydney's famed Bondi beach and several other strands closed Thursday, as more mysterious black "tar ball" globules washed up along the city's shores.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lifeguards declared Sydney's famed Bondi beach and several other strands closed Thursday, as more mysterious black "tar ball" globules washed up along the city's shores.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For days, thousands of black spheres -- ranging from the size of peas to tennis balls -- have appeared on the sand, puzzling locals and tourists alike.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Chemical testing has identified them as hydrocarbon-based tar balls, local officials said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tar balls can form when slicks of spilled oil are battered by wind and waves, mixing to form a sticky seawater emulsion that eventually breaks into smaller pieces or "balls". &nbsp;</p>

<p>The source is still unknown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"As a precaution, all Waverley Beaches will be closed until further investigation has been carried out," a local council that includes Bondi said.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBIus4cSf_U/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBIus4cSf_U/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBIus4cSf_U/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBIus4cSf_U/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Randwick City Council (@randwickcouncil)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The mayor of another beachside council, Dylan Parker, said three other beaches were also closed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our beaches will remain closed and we are investigating," he said. "We are still waiting for the tides to come in."&nbsp;</p>

<p>While formally closed, access to the beaches has not been forcibly restricted, so some brave surfers and swimmers could still be seen in the water.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It is common for authorities to declare beaches closed during large swells.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rki4nmio_tar-ball-generic-x-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tar balls can form when slicks of spilled oil are battered by wind and waves. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/69-year-old-man-killed-in-brooklyn-apartment-fire-caused-by-e-scooter-battery-6807958]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[69-Year-Old Man Killed In Brooklyn Home Fire Caused By E-Scooter Battery]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/69-year-old-man-killed-in-brooklyn-apartment-fire-caused-by-e-scooter-battery-6807958]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 10:05:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A tragic fire in a Brooklyn apartment, caused by a faulty lithium-ion battery in an e-scooter, claimed the life of a 69-year-old man and left two others injured.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 69-year-old American man died when his home was destroyed by fire. According to <em>The New York Post,</em> an e-scooter in the Brooklyn apartment caught fire due to a faulty lithium-ion battery.</p>

<p>The massive fire that killed the old man and injured two others broke out inside the second-floor apartment on Brighton 3rd Street near Brightwater Court in Brighton Beach. The flames and the heat created by it were so intense that it blocked the exit from the house, resulting in the death of the 69-year-old, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/16/us-news/e-scooter-sparks-deadly-nyc-fire-killing-69-year-old-resident-trapped-in-his-apartment-fdny/?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=nypost&amp;utm_source=twitter"><em>as per the news report.</em></a></p>

<p>A 32-year-old woman and 35-year-old man who were also home at the time were hospitalised after they tried to douse the flames-aa risky move when dealing with a battery fire, according to Flynn and police.</p>

<p>"So they attempted to extinguish the fire [and] they were able to escape with minor injuries," FDNY Chief Fire Marshal Daniel Flynn said. "There were two children as well that self-evacuated and did not sustain injuries.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBMYn7POKyQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBMYn7POKyQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBMYn7POKyQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBMYn7POKyQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by FDNY (@fdny)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>"I strongly recommend you do not attempt to extinguish these on your own," the FDNY official added. "Your conventional fire extinguishers will really not be as effective as they would be in other fires."</p>

<p>A dozen FDNY units, including 60 firefighters and EMS workers, responded to the scene.</p>

<p>"When lithium-ion batteries ignite, it's a much more serious, much more involved fire," FDNY Chief of Department John Esposito said. "Thankfully, our firefighters were quickly able to stretch hose lines and extinguish the fire before it spread to additional apartments and throughout."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0h2956v_fire_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The blaze broke out in a second-floor apartment, trapping the man inside. (Representative Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swiss-industrialist-pankaj-oswal-files-un-appeal-against-daughters-detention-in-uganda-6807747]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Swiss-Indian Billionaire's Daughter Detained In Uganda, He Moves UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swiss-industrialist-pankaj-oswal-files-un-appeal-against-daughters-detention-in-uganda-6807747]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:45:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Swiss industrialist Pankaj Oswal filed an appeal with the United Nations against the alleged illegal detention of his 26-year-old daughter in Uganda.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swiss industrialist Pankaj Oswal filed an appeal with the United Nations against the alleged illegal detention of his 26-year-old daughter in Uganda.</p>

<p>Vasundhara Oswal was seized by around 20 armed men, who did not produce an identification or warrant, from Oswal's&nbsp;extra-neutral alcohol (ENA) plant in Uganda. While she was detained on October 1, purportedly in a missing man's case, an&nbsp;urgent appeal to the United Nations Working Group on Arbitrary Detention (WGAD) was filed earlier this week.</p>

<p>A post on Vasundhara's Instagram handle detailed her "unlawful detainment and arrest", showing a toilet with blood and faeces on the floor. The post claimed that she forced to sit in a room full of shoes for over 90 hours, and not allowed to bathe or change her clothes for nearly five days.&nbsp;&nbsp;The woman was denied basic necessities, like clean water and proper food,&nbsp;given a small bench to sleep on, and made to participate in a suspect parade.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBBZnrfI4YD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBBZnrfI4YD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBBZnrfI4YD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBBZnrfI4YD/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Vasundhara Oswal (@vasundharaoswal)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.eureporter.co/world/uganda/2024/10/11/un-appeal-filed-after-26-year-old-daughter-of-industrialist-imprisoned-in-uganda-in-suspicious-circumstances/"><em>EU Reporter</em></a> said Vasundhara was denied vegetarian food&nbsp;and denying access to her family and lawyers.</p>

<p>Another <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.instagram.com/vasundharaoswal/p/DA57taIoULM/?img_index=1">post on her Instagram handle quoted her brother</a> as describing Vasundhara as a "workaholic", who developed the $110 million ENA plant in Uganda's Luwero from "a small tent on a bare land in 2021". He said her detention was a result of corporate jealousy of an unnamed 68-year-old man, whom he charged with an attempt to extort the Oswal money and drown her reputation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vasundhara's brother further claimed that the authorities did not release her despite a court order, and instead took her to a look court where she was charged with murder.</p>

<p>The WGAD is an expert body of international human rights specialists appointed by the Human Rights Council to investigate the&nbsp;misuse of the police powers, to shine a light on abuse and to intervene with the governments responsible.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Vasundhara's mother Radhika Oswal,&nbsp;in an appeal to the Ugandan government, said, "My young daughter has been thrown into a foreign jail. She has been stripped of her basic human rights and her dignity. Vasundhara is an innocent bystander. All I want is her safety.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.monitor.co.ug/uganda/video/oswal-family-members-remanded-in-chef-kidnapping-case-4787412"><em>The Monitor</em></a>, on the other hand, claimed that Vasundhara, also the executive director of PRO Industries, and the company's lawyer were&nbsp;remanded to prison on charges of kidnapping with intent to kill chef Mukesh Kumar Menaria, who has worked for the family for seven years.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bm2gdovo_vasundhara-oswal_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Industrialist Pankaj Oswal filed an appeal with the UN against the alleged detention of his daughter]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-justin-trudeau-admits-canada-has-only-intel-no-evidence-in-nijjar-killing-6807798]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau's Big Admission Amid India-Canada Diplomatic Showdown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-justin-trudeau-admits-canada-has-only-intel-no-evidence-in-nijjar-killing-6807798]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:33:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a startling admission during a public inquiry, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau admitted that Canada had no "hard evidentiary proof" to support allegations linking Indian government agents to the killing of  Hardeep Singh Nijjar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a startling admission during a public inquiry on Wednesday, Canadian Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-we-had-said-no-evidence-whatsoever-india-on-justin-trudeaus-deposition-6806506">Justin Trudeau</a> admitted that Canada had no "hard evidentiary proof" to support allegations linking Indian government agents to the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar last year. Mr Trudeau's testimony came amid heightened diplomatic tensions between India and Canada, which escalated following these accusations in 2023.</p>

<p>Speaking during a public inquiry into alleged foreign interference in Canada's federal electoral processes and democratic institutions, Mr Trudeau revealed that his claims about India's involvement were based on intelligence rather than conclusive evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was briefed on the fact that there was intelligence from Canada, and possibly from Five Eyes allies that made it fairly clear, incredibly clear, that India was involved in this... Agents of the government of India were involved in the killing of a Canadian on Canadian soil," he said.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-ties-hit-new-low-timeline-of-how-relations-soured-after-justin-trudeau-remark-on-khalistani-terrorist-hardeep-singhnijjar-6793267">India-Canada Ties Hit New Low: Timeline Of How Relations Soured</a></p>

<p>The Five Eyes network, comprising Canada, the United States, the United Kingdom, Australia, and New Zealand, focuses on surveillance and signals intelligence (SIGINT). According to Mr Trudeau, the information presented was alarming enough for the Canadian government to take seriously.</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau alleged that Indian diplomats were engaged in gathering information on Canadians who were critical of the Modi government, with this data reportedly being passed to senior Indian officials and criminal organizations, including the Lawrence Bishnoi gang. The Bishnoi gang, notorious for its involvement in organised crime, has been linked by Canadian authorities to violence targeting the South Asian community, specifically pro-Khalistani activists in Canada.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/lawrence-bishnoi-baba-siddique-roster-of-700-shooters-parallels-to-d-company-how-lawrence-bishnoi-operates-6786815">Lawrence Bishnoi Has 700 Shooters On Call. How He Operates From Jail</a></p>

<p>Nijjar, a designated terrorist by India's National Investigation Agency in 2020, was shot dead outside a gurdwara in Surrey, British Columbia, in June 2023. The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) later stated that six Indian diplomats were allegedly part of a plot to murder Nijjar. The Canadian Police also suggested that the Bishnoi gang was connected to Indian government agents.</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau explained that Canada had the option to go public with the allegations during the G20 summit held in New Delhi in September 2023 but chose not to.</p>

<p>"Our response was, well, it's within your security agencies," Mr Trudeau said, recounting Canada's exchanges with India. "At that point, it was primarily intelligence, not hard evidentiary proof. So we said, let's work together and look into your security services."</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau added that he confronted Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the G20 summit, claiming that Canada was aware of India's alleged involvement. According to Mr Trudeau, PM Modi's response was to express concern about individuals in Canada critical of the Indian government, requesting that they be arrested.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Canada's Response, India's Retaliation</strong></h2>

<p>The diplomatic fallout between the two countries worsened when India expelled six Canadian diplomats following Mr Trudeau's allegations. India also recalled its High Commissioner to Canada, Sanjay Kumar Verma, as part of the escalating diplomatic row. Mr Trudeau accused India of not cooperating with Canada's investigation, while India dismissed the claims as unfounded.</p>

<p>India responded with rejection of the accusations, stating that the Canadian government had failed to provide any evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660">"Preposterous Imputations": Trudeau's Escalation, India's Strong Rebuttal</a></p>

<p>"What we have heard today only confirms what we have been saying consistently all along - Canada has presented us (India) no evidence whatsoever in support of the serious allegations that it has chosen to level against India and Indian diplomats," the MEA said in a statement.&nbsp;"The responsibility for the damage that this cavalier behaviour has caused to India-Canada relations lies with Prime Minister Trudeau alone."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Our response to media queries regarding PM of Canada's deposition at the Commission of Inquiry: <a href="https://t.co/JI4qE3YK39">https://t.co/JI4qE3YK39</a> <a href="https://t.co/1W8mel5DJe">pic.twitter.com/1W8mel5DJe</a></p>
 Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1846644034393055519?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>This follows India's sharp rebuttal to Canada on Monday, rejecting allegations Mr Verma being a 'person of interest' in a murder investigation, describing them as "preposterous imputations."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Canada reportedly named &nbsp;High Commissioner Verma as a 'person of interest' in its investigation into Nijjar's death. India swiftly hit back, accusing Canada of maligning its officials without evidence and using "preposterous" claims to justify its failure to curb Khalistani extremism on its soil.</p>

<p><strong>Opinion </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/nijjar-row-why-exactly-is-a-beleaguered-trudeau-challenging-india-6800434">Nijjar Row: How US Backing Has Emboldened A Beleaguered Trudeau</a></p>

<p>In a strongly worded statement, New Delhi condemned Canada's diplomatic communication suggesting that the Indian High Commissioner and other Indian diplomats were implicated in a sensitive investigation. An MEA response stated, "The Government of India strongly rejects these preposterous imputations and ascribes them to the political agenda of the Mr Trudeau Government that is centred around vote bank politics."</p>

<p>The Indian government has consistently argued that Canada provides a safe haven for pro-Khalistani extremists and separatists who pose a threat to India's security. New Delhi also highlighted that it had requested action against these elements, which Canada had failed to take seriously.</p>

<h2><strong>'Major Win' For India&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Canadian journalist Daniel Bordman has described Mr Trudeau's admission as a "major win for the Indian narrative." Speaking with news agency ANI, Mr Bordman noted that Canada's initially aggressive stance, including the expulsion of Indian diplomats and accusations targeting India, has now been tempered by Mr Trudeau's clarification.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is a pretty big win for the Indian narrative... We had gone pretty hard. We had kicked out a diplomat and named the Indian High Commission," Mr Bordman said.</p>

<p>The heart of the diplomatic row remains unresolved, according to Mr Bordman, centring around perspectives on Nijjar's identity - whether he was a Khalistani terrorist, as India claims, or a community activist, as many in Canada believe.</p>

<p>"On the geopolitical technicality aspect, India wins here because you never said you had evidence. But what does it change from the grand structures of things? Ultimately, the diplomatic spat is really about the unanswered question, was Hardeep Singh Nijjar a Khalistani terrorist or a community activist? And that general disagreement has not moved," Bordman added.</p>

<p>Mr Bordman also criticised Mr Trudeau's claim that Canada supports India's territorial integrity. "Trudeau says things and then does things that don't align with what he says... He might claim to be against Khalistani separatism, but his actions tell a different story," Mr Bordman remarked.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/33o00gkg_justin-trudeau-afp-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau revealed that his claims about India's involvement were based on intelligence]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-hackers-steal-3-bn-in-crypto-to-fund-nuclear-programme-6807752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korean Hackers Steal $3 Billion In Crypto To Fund Nuclear Programme]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-hackers-steal-3-bn-in-crypto-to-fund-nuclear-programme-6807752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:24:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korean hackers have stolen an estimated $3 billion worth of cryptocurrency since 2017, using the funds to support the regime's nuclear and missile programmes, a Microsoft report showed on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean hackers have stolen an estimated $3 billion worth of cryptocurrency since 2017, using the funds to support the regime's nuclear and missile programmes, a Microsoft report showed on Thursday.</p>

<p>Of that amount, between $600 million and $1 billion was stolen just last year, based on Microsoft's Digital Defence Report for 2024'.</p>

<p>The report highlights that these stolen funds have financed over half of Pyongyang's nuclear development efforts, reports Yonhap news agency.</p>

<p>Since last year, Microsoft has identified several new North Korean hacking groups -- Moonstone Sleet, Jade Sleet, Sapphire Sleet and Citrine Sleet, which have been targeting cryptocurrency organisations.</p>

<p>In particular, Moonstone Sleet has developed a custom ransomware variant and deployed it against unidentified entities in the aerospace and defence sectors for both intelligence gathering and financial gain.</p>

<p>Microsoft analysts said the emergence of new hacking groups suggests that the North Korean regime is expanding its involvement in ransomware activities, increasing the use of cybercriminal tools to bolster the regime's financial resources and advance its strategic interests.</p>

<p>"Nation-states are becoming more aggressive in the cyber domain, with ever-growing levels of technical sophistication that reflect increased investment in resources and training," said Tom Burt, Microsoft's vice president of customer security and trust.</p>

<p>Microsoft also warned of rising cyber threats by state-backed actors, especially those related to Russia, China and Iran, ahead of the U.S. presidential election and amid persistent geopolitical conflicts in Europe and the Middle East.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, South Korea, the US and Japan recently agreed to bolster joint efforts to combat North Korea's illegal cyber activities, which are increasingly targeting the virtual currency industry.</p>

<p>The three sides stressed the importance of strengthening partnerships with the private sector, particularly with cryptocurrency service providers, to raise awareness of Pyongyang's cyber threats.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/9305ufv_crypto_625x300_16_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Between $600 million and $1 billion were stolen last year: Microsoft's Digital Defence Report 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-lays-off-employees-across-units-at-whatsapp-and-instagram-report-6807713]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Lays Off Employees Across Units, At WhatsApp And Instagram: Report Meta layoffs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-lays-off-employees-across-units-at-whatsapp-and-instagram-report-6807713]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:17:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta is laying off employees across units including Instagram, WhatsApp and Reality Labs, the Verge reported on Wednesday, citing people familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta is laying off employees across units including Instagram, WhatsApp and Reality Labs, the Verge reported on Wednesday, citing people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>A Meta spokesperson told Reuters in a statement that a few of its teams were making changes to align with their long-term strategic goals and location strategy.</p>

<p>"This includes moving some teams to different locations and moving some employees to different roles. In situations like these when a role is eliminated, we work hard to find other opportunities for impacted employees," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The Verge report did not specify the exact number of job cuts but mentioned that they were small. Meta also did not comment on the numbers.</p>

<p>Separately, the Financial Times reported that Meta fired another two dozen staff in Los Angeles for allegedly using their daily $25 meal credits to instead buy household items including acne pads, wine glasses and laundry detergent.</p>

<p>These terminations are separate from the team restructurings and took place last week, the FT report said.</p>

<p>Meta declined to comment on the FT report.</p>

<p>Meta has slashed around 21,000 jobs since November 2022 to keep costs low with CEO Mark Zuckerberg calling 2023 the "Year of Efficiency".</p>

<p>Meta shares have jumped more than 60% this year.</p>

<p>In its most recent second-quarter results, Meta beat market expectations for revenue and issued a rosy sales forecast for the third quarter, signalling that robust digital-ad spending on its social media platforms can cover the cost of its artificial intelligence investments.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c99ca29o_meta-generic_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta shares have jumped more than 60% this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-stray-dogs-eating-dead-on-gaza-streets-as-death-count-mounts-to-42-400-6807705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stray Dogs Eat Bodies On Gaza Streets As Death Count Mounts To 42,400]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-stray-dogs-eating-dead-on-gaza-streets-as-death-count-mounts-to-42-400-6807705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:15:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel launched a military campaign in Gaza after Hamas attacked Israeli towns on October 7 last year, resulting in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stray dogs have been eating the people killed in Israeli strikes in Gaza, CNN reported Wednesday. Fares Afana, the head of emergency services in the northern part of the war-torn enclave, told CNN that he and his colleagues had received the bodies of Palestinians killed in northern Gaza, with some showing signs of scavenging by animals.</p>

<p>"Stray dogs who are hungry are eating these bodies in the street... It makes it difficult for us to identify the bodies," he said.</p>

<p>He said that the Israeli forces are "destroying everything that represents life or signs of life", referring to the air and ground assaults in northern <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-tunnels-nothing-like-we-saw-in-gaza-israel-shares-video-of-hezbollah-tunnel-6799411" target="_blank">Gaza</a> and the Jabalia area, where Israel claims that Hamas members have been regrouping.</p>

<p>Israel launched a military campaign in Gaza after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-iran-hamas-sought-irans-help-for-israel-attack-planned-9-11-style-bombing-report-6779663" target="_blank">Hamas</a> attacked Israeli towns on October 7 last year, resulting in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-mother-mourns-son-killed-in-israeli-strike-before-second-polio-vaccine-6803871" target="_blank">Israel's assault</a> has since then killed 42,409 people, the majority civilians, and injured 99,153 others in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>In its daily update on Wednesday, the Gaza health ministry said Israeli military strikes had killed 65 Palestinians across the enclave in the past 24 hours.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-released-dogs-on-palestinian-detainees-un-report-flags-torture-6229598" target="_blank">Israel Used Dogs, Waterboarding On Palestinian Detainees: UN Flags "Torture"</a></strong></p>

<p>Mr Afana said that on Monday Israeli troops had fired on hungry residents searching for food at a warehouse aid center run by the UN's agency for Palestine refugees (UNRWA).</p>

<p>"The situation is getting worse," he said, adding that they "can't do their jobs normally".</p>

<p>"What is happening in northern Gaza is a real genocide," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>UNRWA Warns Of 'Real Risk' Of Gaza Famine</strong></h3>

<p>The UNRWA warned Wednesday of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-gaza-hungry-families-forced-to-slaughter-horses-eat-animal-fodder-5141815" target="_blank">risk of famine in Gaza</a> as Israel intensified its operations in the north of the besieged Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>At a press conference, UNRWA chief Philippe Lazzarini said that "there is a real risk today... that we enter a situation where famine or acute malnutrition is unfortunately again a likelihood," pointing to the upcoming winter and the weakened immune systems of Gaza's population.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-israel-of-potential-aid-cuts-over-gaza-assistance-delays-6797954" target="_blank">US Warns Israel Of Potential Aid Cuts Over Gaza Assistance Delays</a></strong></p>

<p>Speaking on the humanitarian situation in Gaza, he said it had "become a kind of wasteland, which I would say is almost unliveable".</p>

<p>Mr Lazzarini said that with appropriate action, a hunger crisis in Gaza "can be avoided" if convoys and food are allowed to enter.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hrgighl_gaza-dogs_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's assault has killed 42,409 people, the majority civilians, in Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-constitution-changed-it-now-calls-south-korea-hostile-state-6807525]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea's Constitution Changed, It Now Calls South Korea 'Hostile State']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-constitution-changed-it-now-calls-south-korea-hostile-state-6807525]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:38:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea said Thursday that its constitution now defines the South as a "hostile" state, the first time Pyongyang has confirmed legal changes called for by leader Kim Jong Un earlier this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea said Thursday that its constitution now defines the South as a "hostile" state, the first time Pyongyang has confirmed legal changes called for by leader Kim Jong Un earlier this year.</p>

<p>The country <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-is-kim-jong-uns-north-korea-blowing-up-roads-railways-to-the-south-6802312">blew up roads</a> and railways linking it to the South this week as "an inevitable and legitimate measure taken in keeping with the requirement of the DPRK Constitution which clearly defines the ROK as a hostile state," the official Korean Central News Agency said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>South Korea's military on Tuesday released video footage of North Korean soldiers dynamiting deeply symbolic roads and railways connecting the two Koreas, days after Pyongyang's military had vowed to "permanently" seal the border with the South.</p>

<p>Relations between the two Koreas are at one of the lowest points in years, after Kim in January defined Seoul as his country's "principal enemy" and said they were no longer interested in reunification.</p>

<p>KCNA said Thursday that the army had taken "a measure to physically cut off the DPRK's roads and railways which lead to the ROK (South Korea)".</p>

<p>The move was "part of the phased complete separation of its territory, where its sovereignty is exercised, from the ROK's territory".</p>

<p>North Korea said that sections of the key inter-Korean roads and railways had "been completely blocked through blasting."</p>

<p>"This is an inevitable and legitimate measure taken in keeping with the requirement of the DPRK Constitution which clearly defines the ROK as a hostile state," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The North held a key meeting of its rubber-stamp parliament last week, and this is the first confirmation that the country's basic law was amended in line with Kim's demands.</p>

<p>The report did not provide further details about the constitutional changes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Previously, under a 1991 inter-Korean accord, relations between the North and South were defined as a "special relationship" as part of a process aimed at eventual reunification, not as state-to-state relations.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-army-ready-to-shoot-amid-friction-with-south-korea-over-drones-6781818">Kim</a> called for the constitutional change in a speech in January, during which he threatened war if the South were to violate "even 0.001 mm of our territorial land, air and waters."</p>

<h3><strong>Drones&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Seoul has said the North Korean military had been clearing land and laying fresh mines along the border for months, as part of a drive to reinforce the border, which the South claims is largely to prevent defections by Pyongyang's own citizens.</p>

<p>North Korea also recently accused Seoul of using drones to drop anti-regime propaganda leaflets on the capital Pyongyang, with Kim convening a security meeting to direct a plan of "immediate military action" in response, state media reported Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Seoul's military initially denied sending drones north but has subsequently declined to comment, even as Pyongyang has warned it would consider it "a declaration of war" if another drone was detected.</p>

<p>Activist groups in the South have long sent propaganda northwards, typically carried by balloons, but enthusiasts are also known to have flown small, hard-to-detect drones into the North.</p>

<p>Unlike conventional drones made of metal, the devices they used were constructed from expanded polypropylene, similar to Styrofoam, allowing them to go undetected by both South and North Korean authorities, according to enthusiasts who spoke to local media.</p>

<p>North Korea has itself sent drones southwards -- in 2022, five of Pyongyang's drones crossed the border, prompting the South Korean military to fire warning shots and deploy fighter jets.</p>

<p>The jets failed to shoot down any of the drones.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/398hjiko_north-korea-flag-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea accused Seoul of using drones to drop anti-regime propaganda leaflets. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-elon-musk-donates-nearly-75-million-for-donald-trumps-presidential-cause-6807420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Donates Nearly $75 million For Donald Trump's Presidential Cause]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-elon-musk-donates-nearly-75-million-for-donald-trumps-presidential-cause-6807420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:12:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has donated almost $75 million to the political action committee he created to support Donald Trump's US presidential campaign, according to filings made late Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has donated almost $75 million to the political action committee he created to support Donald Trump's US presidential campaign, according to filings made late Tuesday, illustrating the Tesla founder's growing commitment to the Republican's cause.</p>

<p>Musk, estimated to be the world's richest man, has taken an increasingly visible role in Trump's campaign, accompanying him on stage at a recent rally in Pennsylvania and frequently lambasting his opponent, Democrat Kamala Harris, on social media.</p>

<p>Trump frequently name-checks Musk at rallies and has promised to appoint him to a committee tasked with slashing government bureaucracy.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are locked in a too-close-to-call race for the White House, according to polls.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-elon-musk-says-he-is-all-in-for-donald-trump-as-the-next-us-president-6740162">Musk</a>'s America PAC raised $74.95 million for Trump's cause between July 1 and September 30, according to filings with the Federal Election Commission.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The PAC has focused on launching grassroots get-out-the-vote efforts, including in battleground states such as Pennsylvania that tip the overall national election result.</p>

<p>On its website, America PAC offers those who sign up to help with voter turnout "$30 per hour, with bonuses for performance."</p>

<p>Musk earlier said he would<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-secretly-funded-right-wing-group-long-before-donald-trump-endorsement-sources-6706711"> pay </a>$47 to anyone who gets a registered swing-state voter to sign a petition supporting free speech and the right to bear arms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The billionaire endorsed Trump after the Republican survived an assassination attempt in July.</p>

<p>In the same reporting period, Harris's primary Harris Victory Fund PAC hauled in $633 million, according to its FEC filing.</p>

<p>Harris dramatically entered the race for the presidency after the withdrawal of incumbent President Joe Biden, following a disastrous debate performance against Trump in July.</p>

<p>Since then, the current vice president has reinvigorated the party's base and carried out a barnstorming campaign across the country, with a particular focus on battleground states.</p>

<p>Her political action committee's year-to-date receipts were nearing a billion dollars, the filing said, standing at $931.2 million.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d89c4me8_elon-musk-donald-trump-_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump frequently name-checks Elon Musk at rallies. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/china-to-build-lunar-space-station-explore-habitable-planets-under-new-plan-6807390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China To Build Lunar Space Station, Explore Habitable Planets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/china-to-build-lunar-space-station-explore-habitable-planets-under-new-plan-6807390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:09:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China announced plans to launch a manned lunar mission, construct a lunar space station and explore habitable planets and extra-terrestrial life to expand its space programme in the next few decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China on Tuesday announced plans to launch a manned lunar mission, construct a lunar space station and explore habitable planets and extra-terrestrial life to expand its space programme in the next few decades.</p>

<p>China's top space bodies unveiled a national mid- and long-term development programme for space science, which will guide the country's planning of space science missions and space research from 2024 to 2050.</p>

<p>An established space power, China in recent years built its own space station which is currently in operation besides launching several space missions, including a lunar probe that collected samples for the first time from the far side of the Moon and brought them back to Earth for scientific studies.</p>

<p>The programme released by the China Academy of Sciences (CAS), China National Space Administration and the China Manned Space Agency to the media here outlined the goals of China's space science, including 17 priority areas under five key scientific themes, and a three-phase roadmap.</p>

<p>The international lunar research station initiated by China will be constructed during the second phase from 2028 to 2035, Ding Chibiao, vice president of the CAS, told the media here.</p>

<p>The programme also outlines a roadmap for the development of space science in China through 2050.</p>

<p>In the first phase, leading up to 2027, China will focus on the space station operation, implementing the manned lunar exploration project, the fourth phase of its lunar exploration programme and the planetary exploration project.</p>

<p>Under the new plan, scientists will also explore the habitability of celestial bodies in the solar system and exoplanets and search for extraterrestrial life, he said.</p>

<p>Key areas of space development in the coming years will be the origin and evolution of the solar system, characterisation of planetary atmospheres, the search for extraterrestrial life, and exoplanet detection, Ding said.</p>

<p>The theme of the extreme universe focuses on exploring the origin and evolution of the universe, revealing the physical laws under extreme cosmic conditions, dark matter and the universe's origin and evolution, as well as the detection of cosmic baryonic matter, according to the programme.</p>

<p>Studies will be conducted on detecting medium to low-frequency gravitational waves and primordial gravitational waves, with the goal of uncovering the nature of gravity and space-time, and the exploration of the Sun and the Earth.</p>

<p>Priority areas include Earth's cycle systems, comprehensive observations of the Earth-Moon, space weather observation, three-dimensional solar exploration, and heliosphere exploration, according to the programme.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i0ibf4k_china-space-station_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The launch of China's Zhongxing-11 satellite]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/the-astronaut-wears-prada-as-axiom-unveils-new-spacesuit-6807386]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Astronaut Wears Prada As Axiom Unveils New Spacesuit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/the-astronaut-wears-prada-as-axiom-unveils-new-spacesuit-6807386]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:03:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Astronauts walking on the moon as part of NASA's first human mission to the lunar South Pole will be wearing Prada, as part of a new venture unveiled.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Astronauts walking on the moon as part of NASA's first human mission to the lunar South Pole will be wearing Prada, as part of a new venture unveiled on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Private space company Axiom Space teamed up with the Italian luxury brand to provide the surface suits and spacewalk systems for NASA's Artemis 3 mission, which is planned for September 2026.</p>

<p>The external layer of the space suit, designed to reflect heat, is largely white, as it was on the suits worn by the Apollo astronauts who last walked on the moon more than 50 years ago.But the update will have a few touches of grey and some red stripes similar to those seen on Italy's Luna Rossa America's Cup boat, which was also sponsored by Prada.</p>

<p>Matt Ondler, president of Axiom Space, told a press launch in Milan that making the suit had required "extreme engineering" and "fantastic manufacturing capability".</p>

<p>"They will go in places that are incredibly hazardous, extreme environments," he said.</p>

<p>"One of the missions that NASA wants to do is to try to find water craters at the South Pole. These are some of the coldest places in the universe. And so this suit has to be designed very cleverly."</p>

<p>At the lunar South Pole, a land of mountains and deep craters, the sun hovers below or just above the horizon.</p>

<p>As a result, temperatures vary from upwards of 54 degrees Celsius (130 degrees Fahrenheit) in sunlit periods to minus 203 degrees Celsius (minus 334 degrees Fahrenheit) in shadowed areas that have never see the sun, NASA says.</p>

<p>The suit aims to provide maximum comfort to the astronauts, the team said, while also protecting them against radiation, external pressure and provide the power and oxygen they need for up to eight hours of moonwalks.</p>

<p>With the mission set to see the first woman on the moon, the suits are also unisex and can be adapted to different sizes.</p>

<p>"We've blended engineering, science and art to produce the ultimate garments for future moonwalkers, ensuring that astronauts can perform their tasks and missions in safety and comfort," said Russell Ralston, Axiom spacesuit programme manager.</p>

<p>The design of the boots was a particular challenge, in terms of insulation and to make them robust enough for the terrain.</p>

<p>But the materials used are "confidential", said Lorenzo Bertelli, marketing manager for Prada and the son of the fashion house's founder, Miuccia Prada.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8ke7m9k_axiom-prada-spacesuit_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The external layer of the space suit, designed to reflect heat, is largely white.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-donald-trump-unstable-in-fox-news-interview-ahead-of-2024-us-presidential-elections-6807340]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Calls Donald Trump "Unstable" In Feisty Fox News Interview]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-donald-trump-unstable-in-fox-news-interview-ahead-of-2024-us-presidential-elections-6807340]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 07:51:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, 79, is the oldest major-party presidential candidate ever in the US history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat's US presidential nominee Kamala Harris attacked her Republican rival Donald Trump on Thursday, calling him "unstable" and questioning the 78-year-old former president's fitness for office. In an interview with right-wing Fox News, Harris, 59, blasted Trump - the oldest major-party presidential candidate ever - for threatening to use the military against internal enemies.</p>

<p>"He has talked about turning the American military on the American people. He has talked about going after the people who are engaged in peaceful protest. He has talked about locking people up because they disagree with him," she said.</p>

<p>"He is unstable, and we should all be concerned," she told the interviewer Bret Baier.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://special.ndtv.com/ndtv-world-summit-2024-167/" target="_blank"><strong>WATCH NDTV World Summit on October 21-22. Get All The Details Here</strong></a></p>

<p>During the half-hour sit-down interview, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-her-presidency-would-not-be-a-continuation-of-joe-biden-6806793" target="_blank">Harris</a> clashed with Baier on several issues and repeatedly asked "may I finish" when he talked over her answers.</p>

<p>She was also pressed on comments she made last week when she said she could not think of anything she would have done differently from US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-will-cut-her-own-path-says-president-joe-biden-6799780" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> during his four years in the White House.</p>

<p>"My presidency will not be a continuation of Joe Biden's presidency," Harris, who became her party's nominee after 81-year-old Biden dropped out in July.</p>

<p>She said she would bring "fresh and new ideas".</p>

<p>"I represent a new generation of leadership," she added.</p>

<p>Asked when she had first noticed that Biden's mental acuity had "diminished" before he quit the race following a disastrous debate with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hope-hes-okay-kamala-harris-as-trump-dances-during-town-hall-6799707" target="_blank">Trump</a>, the Democrat turned the subject back to the Republican.</p>

<p>"Bret, Joe Biden is not on the ballot. And Donald Trump is," she said.</p>

<p>After her interview, the Trump campaign released a statement calling it a "train wreck."</p>

<h3><strong>Harris Asks Trump To Release Medical Report</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-donald-trump-release-your-medical-records-6784346" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> this week challenged Donald Trump to release his medical records, days after she was found in "excellent health" and fit for the presidency.</p>

<p>According to a medical report published by the White House on Saturday, Harris "possesses the physical and mental resiliency required to successfully execute the duties of the presidency."</p>

<p>"Yesterday, I released my medical records. Donald Trump should do the same," she wrote on X on Monday.</p>

<p>"I invite the public to watch his rallies and be the decision maker on his acuity," she said in a video attached to the tweet.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yesterday, I released my medical records. Donald Trump should do the same. <a href="https://t.co/GWXn7CPaTM">pic.twitter.com/GWXn7CPaTM</a></p>
 Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1845648263166259347?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>As Harris ramped up pressure for details on the physical health and mental acuity of Trump ahead of the US Presidential elections in November, Trump's campaign issued a statement saying he was also "in perfect and excellent health to be Commander in Chief".</p>

<p>A journalist had asked Trump in August whether he would release his medical records and he replied, "Oh sure, I would do that very gladly, sure."</p>

<p>He, however, has not released any detailed medical records since then.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qnq9s648_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris this week challenged Donald Trump to release his medical records]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-dies-from-rare-mosquito-virus-caught-in-backyard-cases-rising-6807278]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Dies From Rare Mosquito Virus Caught In Backyard, Cases Rising]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-dies-from-rare-mosquito-virus-caught-in-backyard-cases-rising-6807278]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 07:38:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Contracted in 2019 while working in his backyard, Pawulski's condition caused severe migraines and vomiting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An American man died last week following a five-year fight with a mosquito-borne virus that kills almost 30% of patients. The rare disease is also making a comeback in the tri-state area on the East Coast.</p>

<p>Richard Pawulski, 49, of Colchester, Connecticut, contracted Eastern equine encephalitis (EEE) while performing garden work on his woods property in August 2019, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/16/us-news/conn-dad-dies-from-mosquito-borne-virus-eee-as-cases-rise/"><em>New York Post.</em></a> Even those who survive the virus's first outbreak, which attacks the brain, are often left with lasting impairments and neurologic issues. When Pawulski first developed the condition, he had severe migraines and was vomiting yellow bile, but doctors were confused.</p>

<p>"I'm not joking when I say your life can change in the blink of an eye, because that was what happened to us," his grieving daughter of Richard, Amellia Pawulski, 18, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/16/us-news/conn-dad-dies-from-mosquito-borne-virus-eee-as-cases-rise/"><em>The Post.</em></a></p>

<p>Richard died at 2:30 am Monday, one week after he was admitted into hospice when doctors determined that "there wasn't much else" that could be done for him, Amellia said.</p>

<p><strong>What is Eastern equine encephalitis (EEE)?</strong></p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/eastern-equine-encephalitis/about/index.html"><em>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), </em></a>Eastern equine encephalitis is caused by a virus spread to people through the bite of an infected mosquito. It is a rare but serious disease. Approximately 30% of people who develop severe eastern equine encephalitis die, and many survivors have ongoing neurologic problems. Symptoms of eastern equine encephalitis can include fever, headache, vomiting, diarrhoea, seizures, behavioural changes, and drowsiness.</p>

<p>There are no vaccines to prevent or medicines to treat eastern equine encephalitis. People living in areas where eastern equine encephalitis virus circulates should protect themselves by preventing mosquito bites.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6bm3t5kg_mosquitoes_625x300_07_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The virus kills nearly 30% of patients.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bts-member-j-hope-finishes-mandatory-south-korean-military-service-6807269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BTS Member J-hope Finishes Mandatory South Korean Military Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bts-member-j-hope-finishes-mandatory-south-korean-military-service-6807269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 07:33:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[K-pop megastar J-hope from BTS ended eighteen months of South Korean military service Thursday, with his bandmate embracing him and dozens of fans turning up to celebrate his return to the industry.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>K-pop megastar J-hope from BTS ended eighteen months of South Korean military service Thursday, with his bandmate embracing him and dozens of fans turning up to celebrate his return to the industry.</p>

<p>The seven members of the world's most popular boy band have been on a self-described "hiatus" since 2022 due to their military service, which South Korea requires of all men under 30 due to tensions with the nuclear-armed North.</p>

<p>J-hope, the main dancer of the group, emerged from the gates of his army base in South Korea's central Wonju city, where he was met by fellow band member Jin, who<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bts-star-jin-finishes-south-korean-military-service-greeted-by-bandmates-5871639"> finished his service</a> in June.</p>

<p>Outside the base fans had hung up colourful banners to welcome the star back to civilian life saying: "The sun is finally shining upon ARMY" referring to the group's official fandom, and: "My bank account! It's ready to go straight to J-hope!"</p>

<p>Fans had put a life-size cut out of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/bts-j-hope-purchased-2-luxury-apartments-for-rs-125-crore-in-seoul-report-6498346">J-hope</a> dancing outside the base, with a giant balloon congratulating him on his military discharge flying overhead.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fans had been urged not to show up for safety reasons, but early Thursday there were around 50 admirers present -- including international fans from China and Brazil -- outside the base.</p>

<p>A group of Japanese fans rented a bus to get to the military unit, which is located about 100 km (62 miles) from Seoul.</p>

<p>The latest BTS military discharge is likely to be good for the K-pop industry as a whole, analysts said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"J-Hope's comeback is certainly like a refreshing downpour for HYBE during a long, dry spell," Yoo Sung-man, an analyst at Leading Investment and Securities, told AFP.</p>

<p>BTS' agency HBYE is struggling with a legal battle with K-pop girl group NewJeans' superproducer Min Hee-jin, which has been causing a headache for investors, he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In addition, another BTS member, SUGA, was investigated over a drunk e-scooter incident in Seoul earlier this year, which led to HYBE's share price dropping to a record low.</p>

<p>"Even putting aside the 'Suga' issue, the 'Min Hee-jin and NewJeans' issue needs to be resolved first," said Yoo.</p>

<p>"Unless all BTS members complete their military service and make a full-group comeback, J-Hope's solo return might not be enough to overshadow the conflict completely," he added.</p>

<p>HYBE's share price was up 2.9 per cent in early trading Thursday.</p>

<p>The rest of the band will complete their service in June 2025.</p>

<p>Jin announced Monday that he will release his first solo album in November.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tuo1qu2o_j-hope-x_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[J-hope, the main dancer of the group, emerged from the gates of his army base in South Korea's Wonju city]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lions-maul-zookeeper-to-death-at-crimea-safari-park-6806998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lions Maul Zookeeper To Death At Crimea Safari Park]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lions-maul-zookeeper-to-death-at-crimea-safari-park-6806998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 06:10:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of lions mauled a zookeeper to death at one of Europe's largest big-cat parks on Wednesday after a door inside their enclosure was left unlocked, investigators said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of lions mauled a zookeeper to death at one of Europe's largest big-cat parks on Wednesday after a door inside their enclosure was left unlocked, investigators said.</p>

<p>The mauling occurred at the Taigan safari park on the Russian-annexed Crimean peninsula, one of the largest breeding grounds for lions in Europe and home to around 60 of the predators.</p>

<p>"A criminal case has been opened over the death of an employee at the Taigan lion park as a result of a predator attack," the Moscow-installed Investigative Committee of Crimea and Sevastopol said in a statement.</p>

<p>The employee who had worked at the park for almost 17 years died after she "went to clean a cage with three lions, without shutting the bolt of a door between two rooms of the enclosure", investigators said.</p>

<p>The park's owner Oleg Zubkov identified the victim as chief zookeeper Leokadia Perevalova, calling the incident a "tragic" mistake.</p>

<p>"It is unclear how and why this happened, as the animals could not have done such a thing on their own, and apparently there were no people around," he said in a statement on his blog.</p>

<p>"The employees who discovered the body, unfortunately, could no longer provide any assistance, since she had simply been torn to pieces," he said.</p>

<p>On his Telegram channel, Zubkov praised Perevalova as a "valuable employee" who was the "soul of our park", adding that "the human factor of forgetfulness played a role".</p>

<p>"Unfortunately when I arrived there was nothing I could do to help. (They are) top predators and they do not forgive mistakes, he said.</p>

<p>A criminal case has been opened into the death of a person by workplace negligence, investigators said.</p>

<p>The sprawling 70-acre park was opened to visitors in 2012 on the site of a former military base.</p>

<p>Authorities closed the zoo for a month in December 2019 after they accused Zubkov of giving the animals expired feed, an allegation he denied.</p>

<p>He accused Crimea's Russian-installed authorities of tyring to "bankrupt" his business and of deliberately freezing his projects after they seized power in 2014.</p>

<p>Crimea was annexed by Russia in 2014 but is internationally recognised as part of Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/v6jhe844_lion_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Crimea's Taigan safari park is one of the largest breeding grounds for lions in Europe.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-stands-by-false-claims-of-haitian-immigrants-eating-pets-6806938]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Stands By False Claims Of Haitian Immigrants Eating Pets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-stands-by-false-claims-of-haitian-immigrants-eating-pets-6806938]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 05:47:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Wednesday stood by debunked claims that immigrants in Ohio were eating pets, telling Latino voters during a town hall he was "just saying what was reported."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Wednesday stood by debunked claims that immigrants in Ohio were eating pets, telling Latino voters during a town hall he was "just saying what was reported."</p>

<p>Trump in recent weeks has amplified a false claim that has gone viral that Haitian immigrants in Springfield, Ohio, were stealing residents' pets or taking wildlife from parks for food.</p>

<p>There have been no credible reports of Haitians eating pets, and officials in Ohio - including Republicans - have repeatedly said the story is untrue.</p>

<p>At a town hall hosted by Univision, an undecided Latino Republican voter from Arizona, a battleground state, asked Trump whether he truly believed that immigrants were eating pets.</p>

<p>"I was just saying what was reported. All I do is report," Trump replied during the event held in Miami. "I was there, I'm going to be there and we're going to take a look."</p>

<p>Trump added that "newspapers" had also reported on the claim, without naming any or providing any details.</p>

<p>Trump, who has not yet traveled to Springfield, has previously said he would conduct mass deportations of Haitian immigrants from the Ohio city, even though the majority of them are in the U.S. legally.</p>

<p>The city has faced bomb threats since Trump began repeating the false accusations about Haitians.</p>

<p>In the final weeks before the Nov. 5 election, Trump is increasingly resorting to darker and more violent language about illegal immigration, an issue that opinion polls show resonates with many voters, especially Republicans.</p>

<p>He is competing against Democrat Kamala Harris for key votes from the growing Latino population. Latino voters have typically backed Democrats, but the Trump campaign is hoping to win over more Latino voters, especially men, on the back of economic discontent.</p>

<p>Harris led Trump by eight percentage points - 47% to 39% - among Hispanic voters in Reuters/Ipsos polling conducted between Sept. 11 and Oct. 7.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ajjnau2g_donald-trump-_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump in recent weeks has amplified a false claim that Haitian immigrants were stealing and eating pets.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>