<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 02:42:26 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-governor-kathy-hochuls-former-aide-charged-with-acting-as-chinese-agent-6484278]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York Governor's Former Aide Charged With Acting As Chinese Agent]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-governor-kathy-hochuls-former-aide-charged-with-acting-as-chinese-agent-6484278]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:51:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former aide to New York Governor Kathy Hochul has been arrested today and charged with acting as an undisclosed agent of China, federal prosecutors in Brooklyn said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former aide to New York Governor Kathy Hochul has been arrested today and charged with acting as an undisclosed agent of China, federal prosecutors in Brooklyn said.</p>

<p>Linda Sun had served as the deputy chief of staff to Ms Hochul for a year. The 41-year-old has also been accused of visa fraud, alien smuggling and money laundering conspiracy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It is alleged that while working in the state government, Ms Sun blocked Taiwanese government's representatives from meeting officials and sought to organise a high-level New York state official's visit to China.</p>

<p>"In return for these and other actions, Ms Sun received substantial economic and other benefits from representatives of the People's Republic of China (PRC) government and the Chinese Communist Party," the US Attorney's Office said in a press release.</p>

<p>Her husband Chris Hu has also been arrested. The prosecutors said the Chinese government facilitated millions of dollars in transactions for Mr Hu, who carried out business activities in China.</p>

<p>Ms Sun also received several gifts, including Nanjing-style salted ducks prepared by a Chinese government official's chef, prosecutors added.</p>

<p>Ms Sun and Mr Hu laundered the proceeds of their scheme to purchase a $4.1 million property in New York, a $2.1 million condominium in Hawaii and various luxury automobiles, including a 2024 Ferrari, the US Attorney's Office said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9d3enok8_kathy-hochul-reuters_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Linda Sun had served as the deputy chief of staff to New York Governor Kathy Hochul for a year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-minister-plans-spending-cuts-in-2025-budget-to-fund-gaza-war-6484124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Minister Plans Spending Cuts In 2025 Budget To Fund Gaza War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-minister-plans-spending-cuts-in-2025-budget-to-fund-gaza-war-6484124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:26:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich said on Tuesday the 2025 state budget will feature steep spending cuts as the government tries to balance fiscal responsibility with a need to finance Israel's ongoing war with Hamas in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich said on Tuesday the 2025 state budget will feature steep spending cuts as the government tries to balance fiscal responsibility with a need to finance Israel's ongoing war with Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>The minister has been under pressure from the Bank of Israel and investors seeking clarity on fiscal policy for next year. The central bank has been calling for spending cuts and tax hikes or other ways to bring in more revenue. But Smotrich has said that during a war it was wrong to raise taxes.</p>

<p>Speaking at a news conference, Smotrich outlined only his main focus points while formulating the budget, which he said would be ready for a cabinet vote in early October and an initial parliamentary vote in mid-November. Full approval by lawmakers would be at the end of December, he said.</p>

<p>"We are in the longest and most expensive war in Israel's history with expenses of 200 to 250 billion shekels ($54-$68 billion)," Smotrich said.</p>

<p>"We are not limiting war spending and we will support the war effort until victory," he said. "Without victory, there will not be security and without security, there will be no economy."</p>

<p>The war, triggered by Hamas attacks on Israel, has raged since October 7 with little signs of a near-term ceasefire.</p>

<p>To finance the war, Smotrich plans broad spending reductions of 35 billion shekels in 2025, along with a freeze in tax rates, benefits and wages. He sees a budget deficit of 4% of gross domestic product, down from a 6.6% of GDP target in 2024.</p>

<p>The deficit reached 8.1% in July and is expected to grow further in August but Smotrich said it will come back to its target by year end.</p>

<p>Three credit rating agencies lowered Israel's credit rating this year and Smotrich has also been accused of not managing the economy well with scant growth of 1.2% in the second quarter.</p>

<p>Smotrich said the shekel was far stronger than prior to the war, the stock market was doing well and high tech investments have recovered, with the jobless rate at 2.8%.</p>

<p>A rise in inflation to 3.2% was temporary, and mainly due to supply factors stemming from the war, he said.</p>

<p>An economic plan accompanying the budget will include support for the high-tech sector, a streamlining of the public sector, measures to fight tax evasion and a diversification of capital sources.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ub5u123g_israel-gaza-war_625x300_01_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The war, triggered by Hamas attacks on Israel, has raged since October 7, 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-man-seeks-to-revoke-home-gift-to-colleague-after-remarrying-at-93-6484038]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Man Seeks To Revoke Home Gift To Colleague After Remarrying at 93]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-man-seeks-to-revoke-home-gift-to-colleague-after-remarrying-at-93-6484038]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:10:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite Tan's dissatisfaction with his children and his belief that Gu and his family provided better support, his request to reclaim the property was denied by the court.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After remarrying at the age of 93, a man from Shanghai regretted his decision to sign a contract giving his flat to a coworker in exchange for care and companionship. The man, whose last name is Tan, went to court with his former care giver and coworker, Gu, but his request to get his property restored was denied, according to the <em>South China Morning Post.</em></p>

<p>Tan and Gu's family formed a support arrangement in 2005, when Tan promised to give them his flat in return for their company and attention. His demands included regular phone calls from Gu and his family, a weekly visit, grocery and clothing purchases, and taking care of him while he was ill. In return, Tan wrote in his will that he would bequeath his flat and its contents to Gu instead of his children, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3276830/china-man-agreed-gift-home-colleague-companionship-changes-mind-after-remarriage-93?module=top_story&amp;pgtype=section"><em>SCMP reported.</em></a></p>

<p>"They cared about me more than my family. They helped me get through illness and pain and made my life rich and happy," Tan wrote.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/outcry-in-china-after-women-lock-crying-child-in-plane-toilet-to-educate-her-6450292"><strong>Also Read | Outcry In China After Women Lock Crying Child In Plane Toilet To "Educate Her"</strong></a><br />
<br />
Tan said he was not on good terms with his children, who he felt had not fulfilled the duty of support.</p>

<p>Tan also signed a purchase contract with Gu in 2005, selling his flat to Gu for 200,000 yuan (US$28,000). The size of the unit was not revealed in the report.</p>

<p>The average housing price in Shanghai in 2005 was 6,700 yuan per square meter, according to the Shanghai Statistics Bureau.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dmndvpn8_chinese-man_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The agreement had included a sale of the flat and specified various caregiving duties.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/islamic-state-group-claims-afghanistan-suicide-attack-in-which-6-died-6484000]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Islamic State Group Claims Afghanistan Suicide Attack In Which 6 Died]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/islamic-state-group-claims-afghanistan-suicide-attack-in-which-6-died-6484000]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:03:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Islamic State group claimed on Tuesday a suicide attack in the Afghan capital that killed six people a day earlier, saying it had targeted the Taliban government's prosecution service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Islamic State group claimed on Tuesday a suicide attack in the Afghan capital that killed six people a day earlier, saying it had targeted the Taliban government's prosecution service.</p>

<p>The explosion in Kabul's southern outskirts on Monday afternoon killed at least six people and wounded 13 more, according to the city's police.</p>

<p>The IS group's Amaq media wing said in a statement on the Telegram messaging app that "the suicide bomber waited until the time when the prosecutor's employees were leaving their shifts" before detonating in the middle of a crowd.</p>

<p>It put the combined figure of dead and wounded at "more than 45" and said the bombing was committed "to avenge Muslims held in Taliban prisons".</p>

<p>Afghanistan's Taliban authorities have declared security their highest priority since surging back to power following the chaotic withdrawal of US-led foreign forces three years ago.</p>

<p>While their sweeping security operations have led to a decline in militants challenging their rule, according to analysts, the regional IS chapter known as Islamic State Khorasan (IS-K) remains a threat.</p>

<p>The group has targeted Taliban government ministries, foreign embassies and religious minorities.</p>

<p>The previous suicide attack in Afghanistan claimed by IS-K was in the southern city of Kandahar -- the Taliban's historic stronghold -- in March.</p>

<p>Taliban authorities said only three people were killed in that attack, while a hospital source put the toll at 20. Such discrepancies are not uncommon.</p>

<p>Taliban government spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid told AFP last month that IS "existed here before but we suppressed them very hard".</p>

<p>"No such groups exist here that can pose a threat to anyone," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/e9dcdp5g_kabul-attack_625x300_12_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Afghanistan's Taliban authorities have declared security their highest priority. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-man-who-invited-over-50-to-rape-wife-also-clicked-daughters-nudes-6483943]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Man Who Invited Over 50 To Rape Wife Also Clicked Daughter's Nudes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-man-who-invited-over-50-to-rape-wife-also-clicked-daughters-nudes-6483943]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 22:53:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a case that has outraged people across France, the man who drugged his wife and invited more than 50 strangers to rape her, also photographed his daughter naked after she was drugged, according to the Daily Mail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a case that has outraged people across France, the man who drugged his wife and invited more than 50 strangers to rape her, also photographed his daughter naked after she was drugged, according to the Daily Mail.</p>

<p>While going through Dominique P's computer, the police found a folder titled 'My Daughter Naked', Judge Roger Arata revealed in court.</p>

<p>As the judge made the revelation, the daughter broke down, started shaking uncontrollably, and had to be helped out of the courtroom in Avignon, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-13807687/Daughter-man-let-50-men-rape-unconscious-wife-breaks-flees-court-trial-hears-photographed-drugged-file-computer-named-Daughter-Naked.html" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Daily Mail.</a></p>

<p>Just as he did with his wife, Dominique gave his daughter tranquilisers and after she fell unconscious, he partially dressed her in her mother's clothes and photographed her. The pictures were taken at their family home near Paris in 2013.</p>

<p>The shocking revelation comes after the trial of the 71-year-old accused, along with 50 other men began on Monday. He is accused of drugging his 72-year-old wife and getting her raped when she passed out. This happened on multiple occasions for over a decade. He also film the abuse when the strangers raped her. They each face up to 20 years in prison if found guilty.</p>

<p>He has also been charged in a 1991 rape and murder case as well as for attempted rape in 1999.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qfoedhm8_france-protest-afp-_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The pictures were taken at their family home near Paris in 2013]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-approving-fewer-visas-turning-away-more-foreigners-amid-border-crackdown-6480788]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Approving Fewer Visas, Turning Away More Foreigners Amid Crackdown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-approving-fewer-visas-turning-away-more-foreigners-amid-border-crackdown-6480788]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 22:46:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canada is closing its doors to more visitors and temporary residents by approving fewer visas and turning away more people who reach its borders with official documents, according to government data obtained by Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada is closing its doors to more visitors and temporary residents by approving fewer visas and turning away more people who reach its borders with official documents, according to government data obtained by Reuters.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>The spike in rejections of foreign travellers comes as Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's Liberal government, trailing in polls ahead of an election expected next year, tries to lower the numbers of temporary residents - and possibly permanent immigrants. Migrants have been blamed for the shortage and high prices of housing.</p>

<p>Canadians have prided themselves on embracing newcomers but polls show a growing number say Canada is admitting too many immigrants. That stance is filtering down to border and immigration officers, observers say.</p>

<p>In July, Canada refused entry to 5,853 foreign travellers, who were "allowed to leave," as Canada puts it, and who include students, workers and tourists, the most since at least January 2019, according to border agency data that has not been previously reported.</p>

<p>Border officers turned away 3,727 foreign travellers per month on average through the first seven months of 2024, an increase of 633 people or 20% from a year earlier.</p>

<p>Separately, officers deemed 285 visa-holders inadmissible in July, also the most in any month since at least January 2019, the data showed.</p>

<p>A Canada Border Services Agency spokesperson said changes in findings of inadmissibility can be caused by migration patterns or policy changes and are decided case by case. CBSA did not identify any specific policy changes.</p>

<p>"The CBSA's role, policy, and practice has always been to assess the admissibility of persons coming to Canada. This has not changed," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>At the same time, Canada's immigration department is approving fewer visas.</p>

<p>The ratio of refused visitor visa applications to approved ones was higher in June than at any point since the height of the pandemic. In January, February, May and June 2024, more applications were refused than approved, according to immigration department data.</p>

<p>The number of approved study and work permits also dropped from multi-year highs in 2023 and 2022, respectively.</p>

<p>"Canadians want a system that is not out of control," Immigration Minister Marc Miller said in August.</p>

<p>Miller's spokesperson said the immigration department was "committed to a fair and non-discriminatory application of immigration policy and procedures" and attributed the drop in study-permit approvals to a cap announced in January. The decline appears to have begun last year, however.</p>

<p>Eight lawyers told Reuters they have heard from clients of greater scrutiny of visa-holders at airports and land border crossings.</p>

<p>British Columbia lawyer Will Tao said he has represented half a dozen visa-holders who border officials disbelieved about the nature of their plans in Canada and suggested they turn back voluntarily or risk deportation. Some did so, not knowing the implications this could have for their visa or travel authorization, including potential cancellation.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>Tao sees increased border officer skepticism stemming from a "180-degree" attitude shift on immigration from the government. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The idea that foreigners are entering Canada without meeting requirements, or are causing the country harm, is trickling down from politicians to front-line officials, he added.</p>

<p><strong>'YOUR TEMPORARY RESIDENT VISA IS NO LONGER VALID'</strong></p>

<p>Mohammed Kamil Shaibu was paged while waiting to board a connecting flight from Paris to Toronto last September on his way to a conference in Edmonton.</p>

<p>The Ghanaian was told a Canadian immigration officer wanted to talk to him. He was then quizzed over the phone about his employment, the purpose of his trip and any assistance he had received in filing his tourist visa application.</p>

<p>"I had trouble answering," he said in an interview. "I was so terrified. I don't even know what I said."</p>

<p>Shaibu was told he would not be going to Canada. Instead, he was asked to return to Accra.</p>

<p>"Your temporary-resident visa is no longer valid for travel to Canada," reads an email reviewed by Reuters that Shaibu received that day from the immigration department.</p>

<p>Canada should not grant visas it does not plan to honor, said University of Calgary assistant law professor Gideon Christian.</p>

<p>"Why accept people if, when they come, you're not going to admit them?"</p>

<p>Shaibu says his experience has not soured him on Canada.</p>

<p>"I know Canada is a very nice place made up of very nice and accommodating and hospitable people."</p>

<p>He says he may even try again to visit one day.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/82fg42h4_canada-immigration-generic-istock_625x300_03_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canada is closing its doors to more visitors and temporary residents by approving fewer visas]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-cathay-pacifics-a350-problems-could-affect-rolls-royce-6483889]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Cathay Pacific's A350 Problems Could Affect Rolls-Royce]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-cathay-pacifics-a350-problems-could-affect-rolls-royce-6483889]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 22:44:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An engine failure on Cathay Pacific's A350 flight has raised concerns about Rolls-Royce, the manufacturer responsible for the aircraft's engines.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British manufacturer Rolls-Royce, which makes and maintains the engines for the Airbus A350, has come under scrutiny following an engine failure on Hong Kong's Cathay Pacific Airways aircraft from Hong Kong on Monday.</p>

<p>Investors are trying to determine whether this incident could have larger implications for Rolls-Royce as airlines that operate the twin-aisle A350 start conducting fleet inspections. The A350 is mostly used for long-haul flights and can accommodate up to 410 passengers.</p>

<p><strong>What Went Wrong on the Flight?</strong></p>

<p>According to a <em>Reuters</em> report, a problem unfolded several minutes after take-off on flight CX383 from Hong Kong to Zurich on Monday, according to flight tracking service FlightRadar24. The five-year-old A350-1000 plane performed two wide circles and dumped fuel over the sea before returning to Hong Kong, where it landed safely about 75 minutes after its departure. Cathay Pacific said it identified an engine component failure after the aircraft returned to Hong Kong.</p>

<p>Cathay Pacific has not specified which engine component failed, but the carrier said it was the "first of its type to suffer such failure on any A350 aircraft worldwide." A person familiar with the matter told Reuters the incident involved a problem with a fuel nozzle inside a XWB-97 engine, the Rolls-Royce model used on the A350-1000. Now 15 jets need a replacement part. The airline has already had to cancel 34 return flights.</p>

<p><strong>What Could The Implications Be For Rolls-Royce?</strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/article/2024/sep/03/what-happened-to-cathay-pacifics-a350-and-how-will-it-affect-rolls-royce"><em>The Guardian</em></a>, the key question for Rolls-Royce is: how widespread is the problem? The company that makes the engines in Derby earns much of its money from fees related to engine flying hours, so groundings can be costly.</p>

<p>Tufan Erginbilgic, Rolls-Royce's chief executive, has overseen an astonishing appreciation in the company's market value - up nearly fivefold to 39 billion pounds - since taking over at the start of 2023. As well as cutting management jobs, he has achieved this increase in part by charging airline customers more. However, these customers might baulk at the rising charges if their engines are out of service for long periods. The company highlighted the Cathay statements that it had secured the spare parts and that repairs could be completed quickly, without needing to remove the engines entirely.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r4u5uioo_cathay-pacifics-a350-flight_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The issue could have financial implications for Rolls-Royce.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-on-historic-visit-brunei-goes-to-iconic-mosque-meets-families-6482551]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi, On Historic Visit To Brunei, Goes To Iconic Mosque, Meets Families]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-on-historic-visit-brunei-goes-to-iconic-mosque-meets-families-6482551]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 21:08:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi today visited the renowned Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque in Brunei, during his two-day visit to the nation. His visit to Brunei is aimed at bolstering bilateral ties between the two countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today visited the renowned Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque in Brunei, during his two-day visit to the nation. His visit to Brunei is aimed at bolstering bilateral ties between the two countries.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit to the mosque, considered one of the most iconic structures in the region, came shortly after the inauguration of a new Chancery of the Indian High Commission.</p>

<p>The Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque is named after the 28th Sultan of Brunei - the father of the current Sultan, Haji Hassanal Bolkiah, and is considered as the Architect of Modern Brunei.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9b7p0624_pm-narendra-modi-visits-omar-ali-saifuddien-mosque-in-brunei-pti_625x300_03_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>PM Modi also interacted with the local officials, scholars and members of the Indian community who had gathered in large numbers.</p>

<p>The new Chancery of the Indian High Commission in Brunei was launched by Prime Minister Modi to a rousing welcome by members of the Indian community. The new facility, which has come up at the Jalan Duta Diplomatic Enclave, is adjacent to the US Embassy in Bandar Seri Begawan.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and National Security Adviser (NSA) Ajit Doval were present on the occasion as the PM lit a lamp and unveiled a plaque at the launch.</p>

<p>After the launch, The Prime Minister's Office said in a statement that "The chancery complex embodies a profound sense of Indianness, masterfully integrating traditional motifs and lush tree plantations. The use of elegant claddings and durable Kota stones further enhances its aesthetic appeal, harmoniously blending classic and contemporary elements. The design not only pays homage to India's rich cultural heritage but also creates a tranquil and inviting atmosphere."</p>

<p>PM Modi arrived at the Bandar Seri Begawan Airport Tuesday afternoon as he began his two-day visit to Brunei Darussalam - the first-ever bilateral trip by an Indian PM to the southeast Asian nation - at the invitation of Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah.</p>

<p>The historic visit of the Prime Minister coincides with the 40th anniversary of establishment of diplomatic ties between India and Brunei.</p>

<p><em><strong>(Inputs from IANS)</strong></em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/id8pj2u4_narendra-modi-visits-omar-ali-saifuddien-mosque-brunei-pti_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi today visited the renowned Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque in Brunei.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mobile-phones-and-brain-cancer-are-not-linked-says-who-led-study-6483100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mobile Phones And Brain Cancer Are Not Linked, Says WHO-Led Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mobile-phones-and-brain-cancer-are-not-linked-says-who-led-study-6483100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 20:42:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There is no link between mobile phone use and increased brain cancer risk, according to a new World Health Organization-commissioned review of the available published evidence worldwide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is no link between mobile phone use and increased brain cancer risk, according to a new World Health Organization-commissioned review of the available published evidence worldwide.</p>

<p>Despite the huge rise in the use of wireless technology, there has not been a corresponding rise in the incidence of brain cancers, the review, published on Tuesday, found. That applies even to people who make long phone calls or those who have used mobile phones for more than a decade.</p>

<p>The final analysis included 63 studies from 1994-2022, assessed by 11 investigators from 10 countries, including the Australian government's radiation protection authority.</p>

<p>The work assessed the effects of radiofrequency, used in mobile phones as well as TV, baby monitors and radar, co-author Mark Elwood, professor of cancer epidemiology at the University of Auckland, New Zealand, said.</p>

<p>"None of the major questions studied showed increased risks," he said. The review looked at cancers of the brain in adults and children, as well as cancer of the pituitary gland, salivary glands and leukemias, and risks linked to mobile phone use, base stations, or transmitters, as well as occupational exposure. Other cancer types will be reported separately.</p>

<p>The review follows other similar work. The WHO and other international health bodies have said previously there is no definitive evidence of adverse health effects from the radiation used by mobile phones, but called for more research. It is currently classified as "possibly carcinogenic", or class 2B, by the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC), a category used when the agency cannot rule out a potential link.</p>

<p>The agency's advisory group has called for the classification to be re-evaluated as soon as possible given the new data since its last assessment in 2011.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/14adp23g_crowd-generic_625x300_03_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The final analysis included 63 studies from 1994-2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/listeria-outbreak-claims-9-lives-in-us-health-authorities-advise-checking-refrigerated-foods-6483064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Listeria Outbreak Kills 9 In US, Experts Advise Checking Refrigerated Food]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/listeria-outbreak-claims-9-lives-in-us-health-authorities-advise-checking-refrigerated-foods-6483064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 20:39:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Deadly Listeria outbreak linked to deli meats, first reported in July, has resulted in at least 57 hospitalizations and nine deaths across 18 US states, according to the CDC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Deadly listeria outbreak in deli meats, which was first reported in July and, as of Tuesday, has been linked to several hospitalisations across many US states, could bring more illness, according to the Centres for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>

<p>The outbreak has led to at least 57 hospitalisations and nine deaths in 18 states since the CDC initially reported it on July 19. Those cases now include nine deaths across South Carolina, Illinois, New Jersey, Virginia, Florida, Tennessee, New Mexico, and New York.</p>

<p>The<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2024/s0828-listeria-outbreak-deli-meats.html"> national public health agency</a> of the United States has confirmed that this is the largest listeriosis outbreak since the 2011 outbreak linked to cantaloupe.</p>

<p>The agency has urged citizens to exercise extreme caution regarding the outbreak, saying, "Everyone should check their homes for any remaining recalled Boar's Head products since they can have a long shelf life." Look for "EST. 12612" or "P-12612" inside the USDA mark of inspection on the product labels. Some of the products have sold by dates into October 2024."</p>

<p><strong>Listeria infection: Symptoms, source</strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2024/s0828-listeria-outbreak-deli-meats.html">CDC,</a> Listeria is a hardy germ that can remain on surfaces, like meat slicers, and foods, even at refrigerated temperatures. It can also take up to 10 weeks for some people to have symptoms of listeriosis.</p>

<p>Listeria can cause severe illness (known as invasive listeriosis) when the bacteria spread beyond the gut to other parts of the body.</p>

<p>Pregnant people typically experience only fever, fatigue, and muscle aches. However, Listeria infection during pregnancy can lead to miscarriage, stillbirth, premature delivery, or life-threating infection of the newborn.</p>

<p>People who are not pregnant may experience headaches, stiff necks, confusion, loss of balance, and convulsions, in addition to fever and muscle aches.</p>

<p>Symptoms of severe illness usually start 1 to 4 weeks after eating contaminated food with Listeria but may start as early as the same day or as late as 70 days after.</p>

<p><strong>Prevention:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Do not eat recalled deli products. Throw them away or contact stores about returns.</li>
	<li>People who are at higher risk for getting sick with Listeria, such as those who are pregnant, are aged 65 or older, or have a weakened immune system, should always avoid eating meats sliced at deli counters, unless heated to an internal temperature of 165°F or until steaming hot just before serving.</li>
	<li>Clean your refrigerator, containers, and surfaces that may have touched sliced deli meats.</li>
	<li>Call your healthcare provider if you have symptoms of Listeria and recently ate meat sliced at deli counters.</li>
	<li>Businesses that received recalled meats should take extra precautions like cleaning and sanitising and throwing away opened sliced meats and cheeses at delis. Businesses should also follow USDA-FSIS best practices for controlling Listeria contamination in deli areas.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m5dr73l_deli-meat_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The CDC advises thorough cleaning of refrigerators and surfaces to prevent contamination.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/watch-pm-modi-interacts-with-indians-in-brunei-during-bilateral-visit-6482685]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: PM Modi Interacts With Indians In Brunei During Bilateral Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/watch-pm-modi-interacts-with-indians-in-brunei-during-bilateral-visit-6482685]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 19:48:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi received a warm welcome by the members of the Indian community in Brunei Darussalam today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi received a warm welcome by the members of the Indian community in Brunei Darussalam today.</p>

<p>The PM arrived in Brunei Darussalam this afternoon at the invitation of Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah, for the first-ever bilateral trip by an Indian PM to the southeast Asian nation.</p>

<p>Upon his arrival, PM Modi was received by Crown Prince Haji Al-Muhtadee Billah at the Bandar Seri Begawan Airport and was given a ceremonial welcome.</p>

<p>After the guard of honour, the PM was welcomed by members of the Indian community who had come to see him. During his interactions, PM Modi could be seen signing a drawing of him made by a child as onlookers cheered the moment.</p>

<p>During the visit, the Prime Minister will engage in bilateral discussions that focus on multiple areas such as defence, trade and investment, energy, space technology, health, culture and people-to-people exchanges.</p>

<p>"This visit is special as it is the first ever bilateral visit by an Indian PM and is taking place as the two countries are celebrating 40 years of the establishment of diplomatic ties this year," Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said in a post on X.</p>

<p>The trip is part of a three-day bilateral visit to Brunei and Singapore. According to the MEA, the government of Brunei has been supportive of India's 'Look East' and 'Act East' policies for deepening cooperation with ASEAN.</p>

<p>"Brunei is an important partner for India's Act East Policy and our vision for the Indo-Pacific, and as we mark a decade of our 'Act East' Policy this year, the visit assumes additional significance. Brunei has been our country coordinator in ASEAN from 2012 to 2015 and played a key role in our further engagements with ASEAN and continues to do so today," MEA Secretary (East) Jaideep Mazumdar told news agency IANS.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f96vk2_modi-brunei_625x300_03_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[After the guard of honour, the PM was welcomed by members of the Indian community]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/larry-the-10-downing-street-cat-in-uk-gets-a-russian-rival-jojo-6482312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Larry, The 10 Downing Street Cat In UK, Gets A 'Russian' Rival 'JoJo']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/larry-the-10-downing-street-cat-in-uk-gets-a-russian-rival-jojo-6482312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 18:57:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Larry the Downing Street cat is facing a challenge to his position as the British government's chief mouser -- a cute "Russian" kitten.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Larry the Downing Street cat is facing a challenge to his position as the British government's chief mouser -- a cute "Russian" kitten.</p>

<p>New prime minister Keir Starmer and his family, who moved into Number 10 after the Labour leader's thumping general election win in July, brought their family cat JoJo with them.</p>

<p>Now after "negotiations" with the Starmer children -- who had wanted a German Shepherd dog -- it has been agreed that Jojo will also be joined by a "Siberian kitten".</p>

<p>"There's been a long summer of negotiations, back and forth, different options," Starmer told BBC radio in an interview broadcast on Monday.</p>

<p>"But now we've gone for... a kitten instead of a dog," he added.</p>

<p>But Larry has been top cat at the British prime ministerial residence in central London for the last 13 years.</p>

<p>The 17-year-old tabby was adopted from a cat rescue charity in 2011 to keep the Downing Street mice at bay, although then premier David Cameron revealed his performance left something to be desired.</p>

<p>Despite that, Larry has become a media star -- particularly popular with journalists -- and even has his own social media account @Number10cat.</p>

<p>Starmer -- Larry's sixth prime minister -- revealed that feline rivalry was not the only issue with having pets in Downing Street.</p>

<p>"The problem we've got, which is the same for JoJo the cat, is that the only door out of our new flat is bomb proof," he said.</p>

<p>"Therefore, getting a cat flap is proving a little bit difficult," he added.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Larry Bridges' -</strong></p>

<p>Given Larry's celebrity status as the greatest survivor of the political upheaval of recent years, officials have even drawn up a detailed plan in the event of his death.</p>

<p>Like that for the late Queen Elizabeth II, which was codenamed "London Bridge", Larry's plan has been dubbed "Larry Bridges".</p>

<p>The arrival of the Starmers' new pet was welcomed by Sarah Elliott, central veterinary officer for the charity Cats Protection.</p>

<p>But she added a few words of advice for the Starmers as they try to integrate the new addition.</p>

<p>"As the junior member of the growing cat coalition at Downing Street, the prime minister and his family will need to take plenty of time to slowly introduce the new addition to JoJo and Larry.</p>

<p>And she added: "Young kittens can be exhausting for older statesmen like Larry, so he'll also need a safe, quiet area to retreat to when the energy of a younger member of the team gets a bit too much," she added.</p>

<p>Larry himself on Tuesday made it clear he was very still very much in charge.</p>

<p>"The kitten will REPORT to Larry the Cat," he said on X, via the human running his social media account.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jl6dfvu8_larry-the-cat_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Larry has been top cat at the British prime ministerial residence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shameful-of-uk-to-halt-some-arms-export-licenses-to-israel-netanyahu-6482262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Shameful" Of UK To Halt Some Arms Export Licenses To Israel: Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shameful-of-uk-to-halt-some-arms-export-licenses-to-israel-netanyahu-6482262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 18:51:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Tuesday that the British government made a "shameful decision" when it suspended some arms export licences to Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Tuesday that the British government made a "shameful decision" when it suspended some arms export licences to Israel.</p>

<p>Britain's foreign minister David Lammy said on Monday that the government had suspended 30 of 350 arms export licences with Israel due to a risk the equipment could be used to commit serious violations of international humanitarian law.</p>

<p>The decision, which came a day after Israeli forces recovered the bodies of six hostages from a tunnel in Gaza, was quickly denounced by a number of Israeli ministers.</p>

<p>"This shameful decision will not change Israel's determination to defeat Hamas, a genocidal terrorist organization that savagely murdered 1,200 people on October 7, including 14 British citizens," Netanyahu said in a social media post.</p>

<p>"Hamas is still holding over 100 hostages, including 5 British citizens. Instead of standing with Israel, a fellow democracy defending itself against barbarism, Britain's misguided decision will only embolden Hamas," Netanyahu said.</p>

<p>"With or without British arms, Israel will win this war and secure our common future."</p>

<p>Soon after Britain's Labour Party won an election in July, Lammy said he would update a review on arms sales to ally Israel to ensure these complied with international law.</p>

<p>British exports amount to less than 1% of the total arms Israel receives, and the minister said the suspension would not have a material impact on Israel's security and Britain continued to support its right to self-defence.</p>

<p>Both Israeli and Palestinian leaders are being investigated for alleged war crimes and crimes against humanity in the wake of the Oct. 7 attacks by Hamas in southern Israel which killed 1,200 people, by Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The Israeli response in Gaza has killed more than 40,700 people, according to Palestinian health authorities.</p>

<p>Lammy said Monday's decision was not a judgment on whether Israel had breached international law or not. Israel and Palestinian leaders have dismissed allegations of war crimes.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The decision, which came a day after Israeli forces recovered the bodies of six hostages.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-and-partner-jailed-after-planning-to-drug-rape-her-six-year-old-daughter-6482017]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Woman And Partner Jailed After Planning To Drug, Rape Her Daughter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-and-partner-jailed-after-planning-to-drug-rape-her-six-year-old-daughter-6482017]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 18:15:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The woman, from East Cornwall, received a 17-year prison sentence, while the man, from North Cornwall, was sentenced to 13 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman and her partner from Cornwall have been sentenced to prison for plotting to drug and rape her six-year-old daughter. The couple, whose identities are being withheld to protect the victim, were sentenced at Plymouth Crown Court on Friday, August 30.</p>

<p>The woman, from East Cornwall, received a 17-year prison sentence, while the man, from North Cornwall, was sentenced to 13 years. Both were also given a 20-year Sexual Harm Prevention Order, reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.itv.com/news/westcountry/2024-09-03/mum-and-partner-planned-to-drug-and-rape-her-daughter-6" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>ITV News</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The investigation began in 2021 when the man accidentally left his phone with someone at a pub, who then discovered disturbing messages related to the sexual abuse of a young girl. Police seized the phone as evidence and subsequently arrested both individuals.</p>

<p>Detectives uncovered text messages revealing that the woman had planned to drug her six-year-old daughter to allow the man to rape her. They also found sexually explicit images of the child, which the woman had taken and sent to him.</p>

<p>The woman faced five charges and pleaded not guilty to all. However, at a trial held at Truro Crown Court in May 2024, she was found unanimously guilty by the jury and sentenced to 17 years for the following offences:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Conspiracy to rape a child under 13</li>
	<li>Conspiracy to assault by penetration of a child under 13</li>
	<li>Administering a substance with intent to stupefy to allow sexual activity</li>
	<li>Distributing indecent images of a child</li>
	<li>Possession of indecent images of a child</li>
</ul>

<p>The man pleaded guilty to charges of conspiracy to rape a child under 13 and possessing indecent images of a child. He was sentenced to 13 years in prison.</p>

<p>Detective Inspector Sara Ward, the Senior Investigating Officer, said, "This is an extremely harrowing case, and we welcome the sentences handed down by the judge today. I want to thank everyone who supported the police investigation through what has been a long and challenging process due to the nature of these crimes. My sincere thanks also go to the investigation team, who have acted with the utmost professionalism and commitment in bringing these offenders to justice for their depraved acts. The young victim was betrayed by the person who should have been protecting her. All of our thoughts remain with the victim."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/iof8givc_arrest-generic_625x300_30_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man pleaded guilty to charges of conspiracy to rape a child under 13]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/41-killed-in-ukraines-poltava-after-russia-launches-two-ballistic-missiles-6481491]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[49 Killed In Ukraine's Poltava After Russia Launches 2 Ballistic Missiles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/41-killed-in-ukraines-poltava-after-russia-launches-two-ballistic-missiles-6481491]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 17:11:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 49 people have been killed and more than 219 injured in Ukraine's Poltava after two Russian ballistic missiles hit a military education facility today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 49 people have been killed and more than 219 injured in Ukraine's Poltava after two Russian ballistic missiles hit a military education facility today.</p>

<p>Two Russian ballistic missiles hit a hospital and an educational institution, partially destroying one of the institute's buildings, Ukraine's Ministry of Defence said.</p>

<p>"The time interval between the alarm and the arrival of the deadly missiles was so short that it caught people in the middle of evacuating to the bomb shelter," the Ukraine's Defence Ministry added.</p>

<p>Writing on social media website X, President Zelenskyy said, "I received preliminary reports on the Russian strike in Poltava. According to available information, two ballistic missiles hit the area. They targeted an educational institution and a nearby hospital, partially destroying one of the telecommunications institute's buildings."</p>

<p>He went on to write that many are feared trapped in the debris. While 41 people were killed, more than 180 others were injured in the attack. He also said that search and rescue operation are being carried out and several people have been rescued as well. The death count later reached 49 and the injury count mounted to 219.</p>

<p>"We know about 49 dead and 219 injured people. Search teams continue to dismantle the rubble at the site," Poltava Governor Philip Pronin said on Telegram.</p>

<p>President Zelenskyy also posted a video message for all Ukrainians.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I received preliminary reports on the Russian strike in Poltava. According to available information, two ballistic missiles hit the area. They targeted an educational institution and a nearby hospital, partially destroying one of the telecommunications institute's buildings.… <a href="https://t.co/TNppPr1OwF">pic.twitter.com/TNppPr1OwF</a></p>
— Volodymyr Zelenskyy / Володимир Зеленський (@ZelenskyyUa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1830933556832473177?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"People were trapped under the rubble. Many people were rescued, but more than 180 were injured. Unfortunately, there are many casualties. As of now, we know that 41 people were killed. My deepest condolences to all of their relatives and loved ones," President Zelenskyy wrote.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian President has ordered a full-scale investigation into the attack and its circumstances. He confirmed that "All necessary services are involved in the rescue operations." He also thanked the people who helped immediately after the attack. "I am grateful to everyone who has been helping and saving lives from the very first moments following the strike," he wrote.</p>

<p>President Zelenskyy vowed that Russia will "surely pay for this strike".</p>

<p>Calling it a "terror attack", Me Zelenskyy wrote, "We continue to urge everyone in the world who has the power to stop this terror: Ukraine needs air defense systems and missiles now, not sitting in storage. Long-range strikes that can protect us from Russian terror are needed now, not later. Every day of delay, unfortunately, means more lost lives."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-04/russia-missile_650x400_71524538446.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Two Russian ballistic missiles hit a hospital and an educational institution in Ukraine's Poltava.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/earthquake-play-a-vital-role-in-the-formation-of-gold-nuggets-study-6480997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earthquakes Play A Vital Role In The Formation Of Gold Nuggets: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/earthquake-play-a-vital-role-in-the-formation-of-gold-nuggets-study-6480997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 16:11:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent study suggests that earthquakes may significantly contribute to the formation of gold nuggets within quartz veins through a process known as piezoelectricity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gold has long been valued both for its rarity and aesthetic appeal, serving not only as a medium of exchange or a piece of jewellery but also as a catalyst in chemical reactions and an electrical conductor in modern technology. It is usually found as gold nuggets in quartz veins, crystallised silicon dioxide, and its formation process has been debated by scientists for many years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the recent research entitled <em>"Gold nugget formation from earthquake-induced piezoelectricity in quartz,"</em> which was published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-024-01514-1"><em>Nature Geoscience,</em></a> suggests that earthquakes may play a significant role in creating these valuable nuggets.</p>

<p>"The standard explanation is that gold precipitates from hot, water-rich fluids as they flow through cracks in the Earth's crust," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scimex.org/newsfeed/electricity-generated-by-earthquakes-might-be-the-secret-behind-giant-gold-nuggets">said Dr Chris Voisey</a>, the lead author of the study.</p>

<p>"As these fluids cool or undergo chemical changes, gold separates out and becomes trapped in quartz veins," he said.</p>

<p>Despite its widespread acceptance, this theory falls short in explaining the formation of large gold nuggets, particularly given the extremely low concentration of gold in these fluids.</p>

<p>"The stressed quartz not only electrochemically deposited gold onto its surface, but it also formed and accumulated gold nanoparticles," &nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scimex.org/newsfeed/electricity-generated-by-earthquakes-might-be-the-secret-behind-giant-gold-nuggets">said study co-author Professor Andy Tomkins</a>, from the Monash University School of Earth, Atmosphere and Environment..</p>

<p>"Remarkably, the gold had a tendency to deposit on existing gold grains rather than forming new ones."</p>

<p>This is because, while quartz is an electrical insulator, gold is a conductor.</p>

<p>Once some gold is deposited, it becomes a focal point for further growth, effectively "plating" the gold grains with more gold.</p>

<p>"Our discovery provides a plausible explanation for the formation of large gold nuggets in quartz veins," said Dr Voisey.</p>

<p>These findings open up new avenues of possibility in understanding the formation of gold nuggets, showing probable linkage between seismic activities and generation of these precious metals within quartz veins. This might cast a new light on the geological processes that generate one of the world's most treasured materials.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q4rk0fig_gold-formation_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This discovery challenges the traditional understanding of gold formation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-arrives-in-brunei-on-historic-2-day-visit-heres-what-is-planned-6480318]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Arrives In Brunei On Historic 2-Day Visit. Here's What Is Planned]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-arrives-in-brunei-on-historic-2-day-visit-heres-what-is-planned-6480318]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 15:33:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi arrived at the Bandar Seri Begawan Airport this afternoon as he began a two-day visit to Brunei Darussalam - the first ever bilateral trip by an Indian PM to the southeast Asian nation - at the invitation of Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi arrived at the Bandar Seri Begawan Airport this afternoon as he began a two-day visit to Brunei Darussalam - the first ever bilateral trip by an Indian PM to the southeast Asian nation - at the invitation of Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah.</p>

<p>"As we celebrate the 40 years of our diplomatic relations, I look forward to my meetings with His Majesty Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah and other esteemed members of the Royal family to advance our historical relationship to new heights," said PM Modi in his departure statement ahead of his visit to Brunei Darussalam and Singapore.</p>

<p>During his visit, the Prime Minister will engage in bilateral discussions focusing on exploring new areas for cooperation in multiple areas like defence, trade and investment, energy, space technology, health, capacity building, culture and vibrant people-to-people exchanges.</p>

<p>Last month, External Affairs Minister (EAM) S Jaishankar had met Erywan Pehin Yusof, Foreign Minister of Brunei on the sidelines of ASEAN meetings in Vientiane and jointly launched the logo celebrating 40 years of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the Brunei Sultan met for the first time on the sidelines of 25th ASEAN Summit at Nay Pyi Taw in November 2014. They met once again during the 2017 East Asia Summit held in Manila.</p>

<p>In January 2018, the Brunei Sultan, along with the 10 ASEAN Heads of State and Government, visited India for the ASEAN-India Commemorative Summit. The leaders were also 'Guests of Honour' at India's 69th Republic Day celebrations on January 26, 2018.</p>

<p>In 2013, then Prime Minister Manmohan Singh visited Brunei Darussalam to participate in the 11th ASEAN-India Summit and the 8th EAS Summit.</p>

<p>Crowned as the 29th Sultan and Yang Di-Pertuan of Brunei Darussalam in August 1968, Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah undertook his first State Visit to India in September, 1992. His second State Visit to India came in May, 2008.</p>

<p>According to the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA), Brunei Darussalam government has been supportive of India's 'Look East' and 'Act East' policies for expansion and deepening of cooperation with ASEAN.</p>

<p>"Brunei is an important partner for India's Act East Policy and our vision for the Indo-Pacific, and as we mark a decade of our 'Act East' Policy this year, the visit assumes additional significance. Brunei has been our country coordinator in ASEAN from 2012 to 2015 and played a key role in our further engagements with ASEAN and continues to do so today," Jaideep Mazumdar, MEA Secretary (East), said ahead of the PM's landmark visit.</p>

<p>Indian naval and coast guard ships have also regularly visited Brunei and two Indian defence companies - Bharat Electronics Ltd and MKU Limited - participated in the Defence Industry Exposition organised by Brunei Armed Forces in June 2024 for the first time. Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah and Crown Prince Al-Muhtadee Billah visited the Indian stalls during the expo and appreciated the Indian companies' participation.</p>

<p>There are currently around 14,500 Indians living in Brunei Darussalam out of the total population of about 450,500 with more than half of the Indian expatriates being semi and unskilled workers, who work in oil and gas industries construction, retail businesses, etc. There is also a substantial number of Indian doctors and teachers working in Brunei.</p>

<p>After Brunei, PM Modi will travel to Singapore - a country with which India is exploring enhanced cooperation in digital, skill development, sustainability, healthcare, connectivity and advanced manufacturing areas.</p>

<p>In his departure statement on Tuesday, PM Modi said that he is looking forward to meeting Singapore President Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Prime Minister Lawrence Wong, Senior Minister Lee Hsien Loong and Emeritus Senior Minister Goh Chok Tong besides the leaders of Singapore's vibrant business community.</p>

<p>"I look forward to my discussions to deepen our Strategic Partnership with Singapore, particularly in new and emerging areas of advanced manufacturing, digitalization, and sustainable development. Both countries are important partners in our Act East Policy and the Indo-Pacific Vision. I am confident that my visits would further strengthen our partnership with Brunei, Singapore and the larger ASEAN region," said Prime Minister Modi.</p>

<p>Last week, External Affairs Minister (EAM) S Jaishankar, Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman, Commerce and Industry Minister Piyush Goyal and Railways Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw led the Indian delegation at the second India-Singapore Ministerial Roundtable (ISMR) held in Singapore on Monday.</p>

<p>During their visit, the Indian ministerial delegation also jointly called on Singapore Prime Minister and Minister for Finance Lawrence Wong who had led the Singapore delegation for the first ISMR held in New Delhi in September 2022.</p>

<p>"Glad that progress has been made on several fronts since our last meeting. And new ideas for cooperation are being pursued, including in advanced manufacturing and connectivity. These initiatives will pave the way for closer strategic cooperation and partnership between India and Singapore," the Singapore PM said after his meeting with the visiting Indian ministers on Monday.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/arkc2bfk_narendra-modi-brunei-visit_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi was given a ceremonial welcome on his arrival in Brunei Darussalam.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-makes-1st-aircraft-deployment-in-india-for-tarang-shakti-ii-6480569]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia Makes 1st Aircraft Deployment In India For 'Tarang Shakti'- II]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-makes-1st-aircraft-deployment-in-india-for-tarang-shakti-ii-6480569]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 15:14:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Royal Australian Air Force has made its first deployment of combat aircraft in India for participation in exercise 'Tarang Shakti', Australia's Defence department said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Royal Australian Air Force has made its first deployment of combat aircraft in India for participation in exercise 'Tarang Shakti', Australia's Defence department said in a statement.</p>

<p>The second leg of India's largest multilateral air exercise, 'Exercise Tarang Shakti 24' is being held at Air Force Station Jodhpur from 30 August to 13 September. Australia, Greece, Sri Lanka, UAE, Japan, Singapore and the United States are participating in it.</p>

<p>Three EA-18G Growler aircraft from No 6 Squadron, and up to 120 personnel have been sent by Australia.</p>

<p>"This is the first time India has conducted Exercise Tarang Shakti, with 11 participating nations and 18 observer nations attending," the statement read.</p>

<p>Chief of Air Force, Air Marshal Stephen Chappell said Australia's participation in Exercise Tarang Shakti demonstrated a commitment to supporting regional partners and fostering international cooperation to address shared security challenges.</p>

<p>"India is a top-tier security partner for Australia, and through the Comprehensive Strategic Partnership between Australia and India, the Government is continuing to prioritise practical and tangible cooperation that directly contributes to Indo-Pacific stability," Air Marshal Chappell said.</p>

<p>He said Australia's participation in such an exercise showcases its advanced capabilities. The Chief of Air Force said the exercise will provide aviators with the opportunity to develop interoperability with foreign militaries.</p>

<p>"Participation in international exercises such as Tarang Shakti 24, showcases our advanced capabilities that ensure rapid response and adaptability to emerging threats and security challenges in the Indo-Pacific region," Chappell said.</p>

<p>"Exercise Tarang Shakti 24 will provide our aviators with the opportunity to develop interoperability with foreign militaries, develop a mutual understanding of tactical operations, and foster international relations," he added.</p>

<p>Australia and India have enjoyed increased air defence cooperation in recent years, including hosting Indian Air Force Flankers at Exercise Pitch Black in 2018, 2022, and 2024, the Australian Defence Department said.</p>

<p>Air Force also conducts a number of training and engagement activities with Indian Navy P-8I Neptune surveillance aircraft.</p>

<p>Australia will continue to support India's key role in the region by increasing the depth and complexity of our defence cooperation, the statement added.</p>

<p>The first phase of Exercise Tarang Shakti concluded in Tamil Nadu in August.</p>

<p>The first phase of India's largest multilateral air exercise 'Tarang Shakti' involved the air forces of Germany, France, Spain, and the UK.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8e30ss7g_tarang-shakti-ani-_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is the first time India has conducted Exercise Tarang Shakti, the statement said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/geologists-say-quartz-and-few-earthquakes-can-make-a-giant-gold-nugget-6480444]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Geologists Say Quartz And Few Earthquakes Can Make A Giant Gold Nugget]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/geologists-say-quartz-and-few-earthquakes-can-make-a-giant-gold-nugget-6480444]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:58:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Humanitys fascination with gold stretches back thousands of years. Gold mining is described in ancient Greek and Roman sources, and gold rushes  especially in the 19th century played a powerful role in shaping the modern world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Humanity's fascination with gold stretches back thousands of years. Gold mining is described in ancient Greek and Roman sources, and gold rushes – especially in the 19th century – played a powerful role in shaping the modern world.</p>

<p>The dense, yellow metal is often found in the veins of the rocky mineral quartz. This is because the two condense together from hot fluids underground as a result of changes in temperature, pressure and chemistry.</p>

<p>Geologists understand this process quite well, but large gold nuggets have been a bit of a mystery. Gold is only dissolved in natural fluids at around one part per million, so how does it concentrate into lumps that weigh tens or even hundreds of kilograms?</p>

<p>As we report today in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-024-01514-1">Nature Geoscience</a>, the answer likely has to do with the unusual electrical properties of quartz – and what happens when an earthquake puts it under pressure.</p>

<h3><strong>Quartz under pressure</strong></h3>

<p>Quartz is what is called a piezoelectric material. There aren't many minerals like this on Earth, and quartz is by far the most abundant.</p>

<p>Piezoelectric materials generate an instantaneous electric charge when put under stress – when there is a physical force compressing or stretching them. The bigger the force, the bigger the charge.</p>

<p>Not only did we see gold deposited onto the quartz surface, we also saw it clumping together into nanoparticles. What's more, once the process began, gold was more likely to be deposited onto existing grains of gold than on quartz.</p>

<p>This actually makes a lot of sense, as quartz is an electrical insulator and gold conducts electricity. The existing gold grains adopt the electric potential from the nearby quartz and become the focus of reactions that deposit gold.</p>

<p>Industrial gold-plating works in much the same way, only here we are gold-plating other gold.</p>

<h3><strong>Back to nuggets</strong></h3>

<p>Now we know how quartz and gold behave this way in the lab, we can think about geology again.</p>

<p>Some of the most impressive gold nuggets ever found have been in quartz veins where gold-bearing fluids flow through faults in earthquake-prone rock.</p>

<p>During seismic activity, the stress on quartz can generate piezoelectric voltages capable of drawing gold from these fluids. Once deposited, gold becomes the focus of further piezoelectric plating as fluid infiltration continues – so the gold deposits grow bigger over time.</p>

<p>Over millions and millions of years, this process will be repeated again and again. Is this the reason we see such large gold nuggets in this kind of quartz vein? We think it must be at least part of the picture.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/236694/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/christopher-voisey-1549579">Christopher Voisey</a>, Research Fellow in the School of Earth, Atmosphere, &amp; Environment, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/monash-university-1065">Monash University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-do-you-make-a-giant-gold-nugget-take-a-vein-of-quartz-add-a-few-thousand-earthquakes-236694">original article</a>.</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/u5ue8fj_gold-generic_625x300_18_January_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gold is only dissolved in natural fluids at around one part per million (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-national-gets-14-year-jail-term-in-singapore-for-sexually-harassing-girl-6480417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Gets 14-Month Jail Term In Singapore For Sexually Harassing Girl]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-national-gets-14-year-jail-term-in-singapore-for-sexually-harassing-girl-6480417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:52:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 52-year-old Indian national has been sentenced to 14 months of jail for molesting a teenage girl from a known family.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 52-year-old Indian national has been sentenced to 14 months of jail for molesting a teenage girl from a known family.</p>

<p>For molesting a child below 14 years old, an offender can be jailed for up to five years, fined, caned, or receive any combination of such punishments. The man cannot be caned as he is over 50.</p>

<p>The man, who cannot be named due to a gag order to protect the girl's identity, pleaded guilty to a molestation charge, The Straits Times newspaper said.</p>

<p>The 13-year-old girl trusted him enough to go on a motorcycle ride with him one evening in October 2022 when he molested her near a playground in Sembawang, northern Singapore, Deputy Public Prosecutor Suriya Prakash told the court.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/otndq408_jail-generic_625x300_24_December_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man pleaded guilty to a molestation charge (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>