<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 03:56:55 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-what-if-biden-leaves-2024-presidential-race-5993373]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Election: What If Biden Leaves 2024 Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-what-if-biden-leaves-2024-presidential-race-5993373]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 03:56:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden's woeful performance in the presidential debate against challenger Donald Trump has re-ignited questions about what would happen should the veteran Democrat step down as party flagbearer at the last minute.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden's woeful performance in the presidential debate against challenger Donald Trump has re-ignited questions about what would happen should the veteran Democrat step down as party flagbearer at the last minute.</p>

<p>Such a high-risk political U-turn would be unprecedented in modern American election history. Here's a look into how replacing the 81-year-old could be possible.</p>

<p><strong>- If a candidate leaves -</strong></p>

<p>To designate a formal nominee, delegates from all 50 states attend their party's summer nominating convention to officially anoint a candidate based on primary voting.</p>

<p>Biden overwhelmingly won the primary votes, and the party's roughly 3,900 delegates heading to the convention in Chicago this August are beholden to him.</p>

<p>If Biden exits, the delegates would have to find a replacement. That would mean bringing US politics back to the old days, when party bosses jostled to pick a nominee through deal-making in smoke-filled back rooms and endless rounds of voting.</p>

<p>On March 31, 1968 president Lyndon Johnson made the shock announcement in the middle of the Vietnam War that he would not seek reelection.</p>

<p>The move turned that year's convention, also in Chicago, into a political crisis with protesters in the street and left-leaning delegates angry at the pro-war stance of party-picked candidate Hubert Humphrey.</p>

<p>Following the debacle, states more widely embraced the primary process and conventions have become well-oiled affairs, whose outcomes have been known in advance since they are determined by the primaries.</p>

<p>If a candidate must step down after being officially nominated at the convention, a party's formal governing body, either the Democratic National Committee or Republican National Committee, would nominate a new candidate in an extraordinary session.</p>

<p><strong>- Who might fill in? -</strong></p>

<p>So far, the Democrats have circled the wagons around their designated nominee, at least when speaking on the record, with former president Barack Obama coming out to defend Biden.</p>

<p>When asked about Biden potentially stepping aside, campaign communication director Michael Tyler told reporters aboard Air Force One there were "no conversations about that whatsoever."</p>

<p>A natural -- but not automatic -- pick to take Biden's place would be his running mate on the 2020 ticket, Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Sent in Thursday night to put out the fire after the Democratic president's lackluster performance, the 59-year-old conceded Biden had been "slow to start" the debate but had "finished strong."</p>

<p>Otherwise, any of a number of strong Democratic politicians -- Governors Gavin Newsom of California, Gretchen Whitmer of Michigan and Josh Shapiro of Pennsylvania are mentioned -- might be called on.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, could a strong third-party hopeful emerge? So far, no independent candidate is posing any danger to America's dominant two-party system.</p>

<p>In 1992, Texas billionaire Ross Perot, running as an independent, managed to win nearly 19 percent of the popular vote.</p>

<p>But in the end, because of the vagaries of the American electoral system, he did not receive a single one of the votes that matter most: those of the 538 members of the Electoral College that ultimately decide the winner.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/h13tfc7_joe-biden_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If Biden exits, the delegates would have to find a replacement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-does-not-think-joe-biden-will-quit-white-house-race-5993312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says Does Not Think Biden Will Quit White House Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-does-not-think-joe-biden-will-quit-white-house-race-5993312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 03:33:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican Donald Trump said Friday he does not believe US President Joe Biden will exit the 2024 White House race, after the incumbent's lackluster debate performance sparked alarm within the Democratic Party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican Donald Trump said Friday he does not believe US President Joe Biden will exit the 2024 White House race, after the incumbent's lackluster debate performance sparked alarm within the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>"Many people are saying that after last night's performance that Joe Biden is leaving the race. But the fact is, I don't really believe that because he does better in polls than any of the Democrats they're talking about," Trump told a campaign rally in Virginia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/dmc10gkg_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump said Friday he does not believe US President Joe Biden will exit the 2024 White House race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-has-sent-israel-thousands-of-2-000-pound-bombs-since-october-7-5993168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Has Sent Israel Thousands Of 2,000-Pound Bombs Since October 7]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-has-sent-israel-thousands-of-2-000-pound-bombs-since-october-7-5993168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 02:43:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden administration has sent to Israel large numbers of munitions, including more than 10,000 highly destructive 2,000-pound bombs and thousands of Hellfire missiles, since the start of the war in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The Biden administration has sent to Israel large numbers of munitions, including more than 10,000 highly destructive 2,000-pound bombs and thousands of Hellfire missiles, since the start of the war in Gaza, said two U.S. officials briefed on an updated list of weapons shipments.</p>

<p>Between the war's start last October and recent days, the United States has transferred at least 14,000 of the MK-84 2,000-pound bombs, 6,500 500-pound bombs, 3,000 Hellfire precision-guided air-to-ground missiles, 1,000 bunker-buster bombs, 2,600 air-dropped small-diameter bombs, and other munitions, according to the officials, who were not authorized to speak publicly.</p>

<p>While the officials didn't give a timeline for the shipments, the totals suggest there has been no significant drop-off in U.S. military support for its ally, despite international calls to limit weapons supplies and a recent administration decision to pause a shipment of powerful bombs.</p>

<p>Experts said the contents of the shipments appear consistent with what Israel would need to replenish supplies used in this eight-month intense military campaign in Gaza, which it launched after the Oct. 7 attack by Palestinian Hamas who killed 1,200 people and took 250 others hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>"While these numbers could be expended relatively quickly in a major conflict, this list clearly reflects a substantial level of support from the United States for our Israeli allies," said Tom Karako, a weapons expert at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, adding that the listed munitions were the type Israel would use in its fight against Hamas or in a potential conflict with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The delivery numbers, which have not been previously reported, provide the most up-to-date and extensive tally of munitions shipped to Israel since the Gaza war began.</p>

<p>Israel and Iran-backed Hezbollah have been trading fire since the start of the Gaza war, and concern is rising that an all-out war could break out between the two sides.</p>

<p>The White House declined to comment. Israel's Embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The shipments are part of a bigger list of weapons sent to Israel since the Gaza conflict began, one of the U.S. officials said. A senior Biden administration official on Wednesday told reporters that Washington has since Oct. 7 sent $6.5 billion worth of weapons to Israel.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu in recent weeks claimed that Washington was withholding weapons, a suggestion U.S. officials have repeatedly denied even though they acknowledged some "bottlenecks".</p>

<p>The Biden administration has paused one shipment of the 2,000-pound bomb, citing concern over the impact it could have in densely populated areas in Gaza, but U.S. officials insist that all other arms deliveries continue as normal. One 2,000-pound bomb can rip through thick concrete and metal, creating a wide blast radius.</p>

<p>Reuters reported on Thursday that the United States is discussing with Israel the release of a shipment of large bombs that was suspended in May over worries about the military operation in Rafah.</p>

<p>International scrutiny of Israel's military operation in Gaza has intensified as the Palestinian death count from the war has exceeded 37,000, according to the Gaza health ministry, and has left the coastal enclave in ruins.</p>

<p>Washington gives $3.8 billion in annual military assistance to its longtime ally. While Biden has warned that he would place conditions on military aid if Israel fails to protect civilians and allow more humanitarian aid into Gaza, he has not done so beyond delaying the May shipment.</p>

<p>Biden's support for Israel in its war against Hamas has emerged as a political liability, particularly among young Democrats, as he runs for re-election this year. It fueled a wave of "uncommitted" protest votes in primaries and has driven pro-Palestinian protests at U.S. universities.</p>

<p>While the United States provides detailed descriptions and quantities of military aid sent to Ukraine as it fights a full-scale invasion of Russia, the administration has revealed few details about the full extent of U.S. weapons and munitions sent to Israel.</p>

<p>The shipments are also hard to track because some of the weapons are shipped as part of arms sales approved by Congress years ago but only now being fulfilled.</p>

<p>One of the U.S. officials said the Pentagon has sufficient quantities of weapons in its own stocks and had been liaising with U.S. industry partners who make the weapons, such as Boeing Co and General Dynamics, as the companies work to manufacture more.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/86i1skog_israel-military-_625x300_11_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US has transferred at least 14,000 of the MK-84 2,000-pound bombs to Israel since Gaza war began.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-releases-10-ukrainian-civilian-prisoners-volodymyr-zelensky-5992966]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Releases 10 Ukrainian Civilian Prisoners: Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-releases-10-ukrainian-civilian-prisoners-volodymyr-zelensky-5992966]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 01:45:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Friday 10 civilians, including a politician and two priests, taken prisoner in Russia and Belarus had been freed in a deal mediated by the Vatican.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Friday 10 civilians, including a politician and two priests, taken prisoner in Russia and Belarus had been freed in a deal mediated by the Vatican.</p>

<p>Russia and Ukraine have exchanged hundreds of prisoners throughout their two-year conflict, typically in one-for-one swaps, but the release of civilian prisoners is rarer.</p>

<p>"We managed to return 10 more of our people from Russian captivity," Zelensky said in a post on Telegram. It was not immediately clear if the release was part of an exchange deal involving Russian prisoners held in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Some of those released have been in prison since 2017, he said, arrested in Russian-controlled parts of eastern Ukraine that at the time were run by Moscow-backed separatists.</p>

<p>Russia has since annexed four Ukrainian regions -- Donetsk, Kherson, Lugansk and Zaporizhzhia -- alongside the Crimea peninsula which it seized in 2014.</p>

<p>The list of those freed included Nariman Dzhelal, a senior Crimean Tatar politician and two priests from the Ukrainian Greek Catholic Church.</p>

<p>Five of them were originally arrested in Belarus, Russia's close ally, including on charges of aiding Kyiv's army by providing information on Russian military movements.</p>

<p>Russia invaded Ukraine through Belarus at the start of the war and although Minsk has not joined Russia's offensive, the two countries' militaries are closely linked.</p>

<p>"They have all been released and are now back home in Ukraine," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>"I would also like to note the Vatican's efforts to bring these people home," he added, without elaborating.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/j1qeblo8_russia-ukraine-war_625x300_20_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some of those released have been in prison since 2017.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-imposes-asset-freezes-visa-bans-on-hamas-financiers-5992666]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EU Imposes Asset Freezes, Visa Bans On Hamas Financiers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-imposes-asset-freezes-visa-bans-on-hamas-financiers-5992666]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:14:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The European Union on Friday imposed asset freezes and visa bans on several firms and individuals accused of helping to finance Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, Brussels said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The European Union on Friday imposed asset freezes and visa bans on several firms and individuals accused of helping to finance Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, Brussels said.</p>

<p>The sanctions were the second round to be imposed by the EU on the Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad groups after their attack on Israel on October 7.</p>

<p>Overall the bloc has so far blacklisted 12 individuals and three entities linked to the operatives.</p>

<p>Among the latest targets were three front companies used by key financier Hamza Abdelbasit to funnel funds to the group, including Spanish real estate firm Al Zawaya Group, and two others based in Sudan, an EU statement said.</p>

<p>Also hit were the head of Hamas' "foreign investment activities", a money changer enabling transfers from backer Iran and the official in charge of the groups "Charitable Institutions Association", it said.</p>

<p>The EU said in addition it was imposing sanctions on Ali Morshed Shirazi, a senior Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corp official overseeing Tehran's links to Palestinian groups from Lebanon.</p>

<p>Top Hamas official Maher Rebhi Obeid "responsible for directing Hamas' terrorist operatives in the West Bank" was also put on the list.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The operatives also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 42 are dead.</p>

<p>In response Israel unleashed a devastating military campaign in Hamas' stronghold Gaza that has killed at least 37,765 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza.</p>

<p>EU diplomats said that following the latest sanctions on Hamas the bloc should now impose a second round of measures targeting violent Israeli extremists in the West Bank.</p>

<p>The 27-nation EU -- which has struggled for a united position on the Gaza war -- in April imposed sanctions on four "extremist" Israeli settlers and two groups over violence against Palestinians in the West Bank.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/6op53pqo_european-union-generic_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Overall the bloc has so far blacklisted 12 individuals linked to operatives. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-aid-pier-removed-from-gaza-due-to-high-sea-states-pentagon-5992560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Aid Pier Removed From Gaza "Due To High Sea States": Pentagon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-aid-pier-removed-from-gaza-due-to-high-sea-states-pentagon-5992560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 23:52:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A temporary US aid pier has again been removed from the Gaza coast due to high seas and will be towed to an Israeli port, the Pentagon said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A temporary US aid pier has again been removed from the Gaza coast due to high seas and will be towed to an Israeli port, the Pentagon said on Friday.</p>

<p>It is the third time the pier has been detached from the shore because of weather conditions since its initial installation in mid-May, and the effort is also facing difficulties with distribution of assistance once it reaches Gaza.</p>

<p>"Due to high sea states expected this weekend, Central Command has removed the temporary pier from its anchored position in Gaza and will tow it back to Ashdod, Israel," Deputy Pentagon Press Secretary Sabrina Singh told journalists, referring to the military command responsible for the Middle East.</p>

<p>She said she does not have a date for the pier's reinstallation, and that "the commander will continue to assess the sea states over the weekend."</p>

<p>The pier was first anchored to the Gaza coast in mid-May, but was damaged by bad weather later in the month and had to be removed for repairs.</p>

<p>It was then reattached on June 7, but was moved to Ashdod on June 14 to protect it from anticipated high seas -- a situation that is now being repeated.</p>

<p>When the pier has been operational, it has been used to deliver a large amount of aid to the shore.</p>

<p>"Since May 17, Central Command has assisted in the delivery of more than 8,831 metric tons, or approximately 19.4 million pounds, of humanitarian aid to the shore for onward distribution by humanitarian organizations," Singh said.</p>

<p>But distribution has been a problem, with the UN World Food Program suspending its deliveries of assistance that arrive via the pier earlier this month to assess the security situation.</p>

<p>The move came after Israel conducted a military operation nearby that freed four hostages, but which Hamas-run Gaza's health ministry said killed more than 270 Palestinians.</p>

<p>As a result, aid is piling up in the marshalling yard where it is delivered onshore.</p>

<p>"There's still some room there, but it's, I would say majority is pretty full right now," Singh said.</p>

<p>Gaza is suffering through a war which broke out after Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The operatives also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 42 are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,765 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/ivh5hgco_gaza-coast_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gaza is suffering through a war which broke out after Hamas's unprecedented October 7. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-should-resume-intermediate-short-range-missile-production-putin-5992213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Should Resume Intermediate, Short-Range Missile Production: Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-should-resume-intermediate-short-range-missile-production-putin-5992213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 22:58:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin said on Friday that Russia should resume production of intermediate and shorter-range nuclear-capable missiles and then consider where to deploy them after the United States brought similar missiles to Europe and Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said on Friday that Russia should resume production of intermediate and shorter-range nuclear-capable missiles and then consider where to deploy them after the United States brought similar missiles to Europe and Asia.</p>

<p>Putin's move finally kills off all that remains from one of the most significant arms controls treaties of the Cold War amid fears that the world's two biggest nuclear powers could be entering a new arms race together with China.</p>

<p>The Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty, signed by Mikhail Gorbachev and Ronald Reagan in 1987, marked the first time the superpowers had agreed to reduce their nuclear arsenals and eliminated a whole category of nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>The United States under former President Donald Trump formally withdrew from the INF Treaty in 2019 after saying that Moscow was violating the accord, an accusation the Kremlin repeatedly denied and dismissed as a pretext.</p>

<p>Russia then imposed a moratorium on its own development of missiles previously banned by the INF treaty - ground-based ballistic and cruise missiles with ranges of 500 km to 5,500 km.</p>

<p>Putin said Russia had pledged not to deploy such missiles but that the United States had resumed their production, brought them to Denmark for exercises and also taken them to the Philippines.</p>

<p>"We need to respond to this and make decisions about what we will have to do in this direction next," Putin was shown on state television telling Russia's Security Council.</p>

<p>"Apparently, we need to start manufacturing these strike systems and then, based on the actual situation, make decisions about where - if necessary to ensure our safety - to place them," he said.</p>

<p><strong>DISINTEGRATION</strong></p>

<p>Russia and the United States, by far the biggest nuclear powers, have both expressed regret about the disintegration of the tangle of arms control treaties which sought to slow the Cold War arms race and reduce the risk of nuclear war.</p>

<p>Trump in 2018 said he wanted to terminate the INF Treaty because of what he said were years of Russian violations and his concerns about China's intermediate-range missile arsenal.</p>

<p>Putin has said in the past that the U.S. withdrawal would trigger a new arms race.</p>

<p>The United States publicly blamed Russia's development of the 9M729 ground-launched cruise missile, known in NATO as the SSC-8, as the reason for it leaving the INF Treaty.</p>

<p>In his moratorium proposal, Putin suggested Russia could agree not to deploy the missiles in its Baltic coast exclave of Kaliningrad. Since leaving the pact, the United States has tested missiles with a similar profile.</p>

<p>Putin said earlier this month he could deploy conventional missiles within striking distance of the United States and its European allies if they allowed Ukraine to strike deeper into Russia with long-range Western weapons.</p>

<p>In his comments on Friday, Putin gave no indication of where the missiles could be deployed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/1lam6j78_putin-reuters_625x300_13_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin said Russia had pledged not to deploy such missiles but US had resumed their production (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/employer-of-indian-man-who-died-while-working-in-italy-farm-arrested-centre-5992143]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Employer Of Indian Man Who Died While Working In Italy Farm Arrested: Centre]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/employer-of-indian-man-who-died-while-working-in-italy-farm-arrested-centre-5992143]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 22:47:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) on Friday condemned the negligence in the treatment of Satnam Singh, an Indian worker who died in north Italy, stating that his employer, responsible for his medical care, has been arrested.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) on Friday condemned the negligence in the treatment of Satnam Singh, an Indian worker who died in north Italy, stating that his employer, responsible for his medical care, has been arrested.</p>

<p>MEA official spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal called for humane treatment of workers, adding that all possible assistance was being provided to the family of Satnam Singh.</p>

<p>"His employer who was supposed to provide him medical care has been arrested and the investigation goes on. We condemn such treatment. We call for the human treatment of workers. We are providing all possible assistance to his family," said Jaiswal during a weekly briefing.</p>

<p>India has also raised this issue with Italy and has called for prompt action against those responsible for his demise.</p>

<p>The secretary (Consular Passport and Visa Division and Overseas Indian Affairs) in the Ministry of External Affairs, Muktesh Pardeshi raised the matter with Luigi Maria Vignali, Director General for Migratory Policies and Italians Abroad, Italian Minister of Foreign Affairs.</p>

<p>Muktesh Pardeshi further said that the Indian Embassy in Italy is in contact with the family of Satnam Singh for consular help and transportation of body to India.</p>

<p>"@SecretaryCPVOIA Muktesh Pardeshi conveyed to @LuigiVignali Italian DG our deep concern about death of Satnam Singh &amp; called for prompt action against those responsible. Embassy is in contact with family of Satnam Singh for consular help &amp;transportation of mortal remains @MEAIndia," the Indian embassy in Italy posted on X on June 26.</p>

<p>Indian national Satnam Singh lost his life after being abandoned on the street following an accident, according to the Flai CGIL trade union.</p>

<p>The accident, which resulted in the severing of his arm, happened while he was working at the farm.</p>

<p>According to the Flai CGIL trade union, instead of receiving help from the employer, "Singh was dumped like a bag of rubbish near his home."</p>

<p>Earlier last week, the Embassy said that it is in contact with local authorities and that efforts are being made to contact the family and provide consular assistance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/q006l43g_indian-national-in-italy-satnam-singh-twitter_625x300_20_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has called for prompt action against those responsible for Satnam Singh's death (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/europe-satellite-operator-cancels-ariane-6-plans-to-go-with-spacex-report-5991788]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Europe Satellite Operator Cancels Ariane 6 Plans, To Go With SpaceX: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/europe-satellite-operator-cancels-ariane-6-plans-to-go-with-spacex-report-5991788]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 21:47:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Europe's weather satellite operator has cancelled plans to use the European rocket Ariane 6 less than two weeks before its first-ever launch, opting to go with US firm SpaceX instead, the French newspaper Le Monde has reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Europe's weather satellite operator has cancelled plans to use the European rocket Ariane 6 less than two weeks before its first-ever launch, opting to go with US firm SpaceX instead, the French newspaper Le Monde has reported.</p>

<p>The latest blow to European space efforts comes after four years of delays to the Ariane 6, which is scheduled to finally blast off for the first time on July 9.</p>

<p>Contacted by AFP on Friday, the European Organisation for the Exploitation of Meteorological Satellites (EUMETSAT) could not immediately be reached, while the French company Arianespace, which developed and operates the Ariane 6 rocket, did not comment.</p>

<p>According to the Le Monde report, EUMETSAT's executive committee asked the board of directors representing the organisation's 30 member states to launch the MTG-S1 weather satellite on SpaceX's Falcon 9 rocket.</p>

<p>That would mean cancelling the contract EUMETSAT signed with Arianespace four years ago.</p>

<p>The MTG-S1 satellite had been planned to be the third launch on an Ariane 6 rocket, scheduled to blast off sometime early next year.</p>

<p>The Le Monde report did not specify exactly why EUMETSAT ditched the European rocket for US billionaire Elon Musk's SpaceX.</p>

<p>The CEO of France's CNES space agency Philippe Baptiste said it was "quite a brutal change as the flight was supposed to take place very soon."</p>

<p>"Clearly, today is a very disappointing day for European space efforts," he wrote in a LinkedIn post.</p>

<p>"I am impatiently waiting to understand what reasons could have led EUMETSAT to such a decision, at a time where all major European space countries as well as the European Commission are calling for launching European satellites on European launchers!</p>

<p>"How far will we, Europeans, go in our naivety?"</p>

<p>Baptiste called on the European Commission to "take the necessary measures so that all European institutional satellites are launched on small and large European launchers."</p>

<p>Ariane 6's long-awaited inaugural flight comes at a difficult time for European space efforts.</p>

<p>The years of Ariane 6 delays, setbacks for the lighter Vega-C launcher and Russia's withdrawal of its Soyuz rockets has left Europe without an independent way to blast its missions into space.</p>

<p>Before the latest setback, Ariane 6 rockets had an order book of 30 missions, and planned to launch nine times a year.</p>

<p>SpaceX's Falcon 9 rocket -- which is reusable, unlike Ariane 6 -- is planning 144 launches this year alone.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/iic38r2g_spacex-generic_625x300_16_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The MTG-S1 satellite had been planned to be the third launch on an Ariane 6 rocket. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-cinema-agency-chief-gets-3-year-jail-over-sexual-assault-of-godson-5991727]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Cinema Agency Chief Gets 3 Year Jail Over Sexual Assault Of Godson]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-cinema-agency-chief-gets-3-year-jail-over-sexual-assault-of-godson-5991727]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 21:38:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of France's top cinema institution, Dominique Boutonnat, was on Friday given a three-year prison sentence, including two years suspended, after being convicted of sexually assaulting his godson in 2020.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of France's top cinema institution, Dominique Boutonnat, was on Friday given a three-year prison sentence, including two years suspended, after being convicted of sexually assaulting his godson in 2020.</p>

<p>In a statement released immediately after the ruling, Boutonnat announced he was stepping down as head of the National Centre of Cinema (CNC), whose role includes overseeing measures to curb sexual violence in the industry.</p>

<p>He will be able to serve his one-year jail term at home wearing an electronic bracelet, said the Nanterre criminal court outside Paris. Boutonnat, 54, was also banned from having any contact with the victim for three years.</p>

<p>In its verdict, the court ruled that the "plaintiff's version was more credible" than that of Boutonnat who, according to the court, always exercised "a real influence" over his godson.</p>

<p>In the statement released by the CNC, Boutonnat "reaffirmed his innocence" and said he would appeal.</p>

<p>Boutonnat's godson has accused him of trying to masturbate him during a holiday in Greece in 2020 when he was 19.</p>

<p>In court, the young man has described Boutonnat as "more than a godfather."</p>

<p>"It's someone using me to masturbate," he said.</p>

<p>Boutonnat denies any sexual assault has taken place. He has said in court that it was his godson who had initiated the situation and kissed him on the mouth.</p>

<p>"I feel bad about leaving an ambiguous situation, but to say there was a sexual assault is false," he has told the court.</p>

<p>He was placed under investigation in February 2021 but still reappointed by the government as head of the CNC in July 2022.</p>

<p>"This case is a perfect demonstration of what sexual assault is," said Caroline Toby, the victim's lawyer, adding that "the abuse of authority" had been recognised in court.</p>

<p>On June 14, the public prosecutor had requested a three-year suspended prison sentence for Boutonnat.</p>

<p>The trial came as French cinema reels from a renewed #MeToo reckoning that has seen several big names, including acting legend Gerard Depardieu, accused of sexual abuse.</p>

<p>Activists had denounced Boutonnat's leadership of the National Centre of Cinema (CNC).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/5utui0u_dominique-boutonnat_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dominique Boutonnat denies any sexual assault has taken place. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-year-old-boy-jailed-for-4-years-over-german-christmas-market-attack-plot-5991666]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[15-Year-Old Boy Jailed For 4 Years Over German Christmas Market Attack Plot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-year-old-boy-jailed-for-4-years-over-german-christmas-market-attack-plot-5991666]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 21:30:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A German court on Friday sentenced a 15-year-old boy to four years in jail for planning an Islamist attack on a Christmas market in the western city of Leverkusen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A German court on Friday sentenced a 15-year-old boy to four years in jail for planning an Islamist attack on a Christmas market in the western city of Leverkusen.</p>

<p>The teenager wanted to rent a truck and "kill as many people as possible" by ramming it into the traditional market, the court in Cologne said in a statement.</p>

<p>The boy had started to become "radicalised" in autumn 2023, the court said.</p>

<p>The evidence against him included a video in a chat group announcing his plans for an attack on "infidels" with a recognisable Islamist symbol in the background.</p>

<p>The boy had planned the attack along with another teenager who was supposed to film it and share the video, the court said.</p>

<p>The 16-year-old from Brandenburg, the state that surrounds Berlin, will stand trial in a different court from July.</p>

<p>The 15-year-old made a "comprehensive confession" during his trial, a court spokesman told AFP.</p>

<p>Islamist extremists have carried out several attacks in Germany in recent years, the deadliest being a truck rampage at a Berlin Christmas market in December 2016 that killed 12 people.</p>

<p>More recently, an Islamist motive is suspected in the killing of a police officer in a knife attack on the market square in the city of Mannheim in late May.</p>

<p>The number of people considered Islamist extremists in Germany fell slightly from 27,480 in 2022 to 27,200 last year, according to a report from the federal domestic intelligence agency.</p>

<p>However, in presenting the report, Interior Minister Nancy Faeser said Germany would be "continuing to step up the fight against Islamist terrorism".</p>

<p>In another case involving teenagers, two boys and two girls aged 15 to 16 were arrested at Easter this year on suspicion of planning an Islamist attack in the same region of western Germany.</p>

<p>Herbert Reul, interior minister of North Rhine-Westphalia state, said the young age of the suspects left him "speechless", adding that it posed a "huge challenge for society as a whole".</p>

<p>Germany's biggest-selling daily Bild reported that the four youths were allegedly planning to carry out Molotov cocktail and knife attacks in the name of the Islamic State group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-02/jail-generic_650x400_61517932452.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boy had started to become "radicalised" in autumn 2023, the court said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vatican-urged-to-stop-displaying-art-by-priest-accused-of-abusing-women-5991645]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vatican Urged To Stop Displaying Art By Priest Accused Of Abusing Women]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vatican-urged-to-stop-displaying-art-by-priest-accused-of-abusing-women-5991645]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 21:24:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A prominent cardinal has asked Vatican authorities to stop displaying the artwork of a Jesuit priest accused of abusing nuns and other women, to avoid a suggestion of indifference to the victims' suffering.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A prominent cardinal has asked Vatican authorities to stop displaying the artwork of a Jesuit priest accused of abusing nuns and other women, to avoid a suggestion of indifference to the victims' suffering.</p>

<p>Father Marko Ivan Rupnik, whose mosaics adorn about 200 churches and chapels around world as well as the Vatican, was expelled from the Jesuit order last year.</p>

<p>About 20 people, mostly former nuns, have accused him of various types of abuse, either when he was a spiritual director of a community of nuns in Slovenia about 30 years ago or after he moved to Rome to pursue his career as an artist.</p>

<p>He has not commented on the allegations, which the Jesuit Order said last year were "very highly" credible.</p>

<p>Five women who accused Rupnik of sexual and psychological violence had asked bishops around the world to remove his mosaics from churches to avoid offending the feelings of the faithful.</p>

<p>"Pastoral prudence would prevent displaying artwork in a way that could imply either exoneration or a subtle defence" of alleged perpetrators of abuse, the president of the Pontifical Commission for the Protection of Minors, Cardinal Sean O'Malley, said in a letter to Vatican officials.</p>

<p>"We must avoid sending a message that the Holy See is oblivious to the psychological distress that so many are suffering."</p>

<p>The letter dates from Wednesday but was published on Friday after the lawyer of some of Rupnik's alleged victims questioned the appropriateness of keeping his artworks in places of worship, causing possible disturb to the faithful.</p>

<p>The lawyer said in a letter addressed to more than 80 bishops from various dioceses that some women were abused during the creation of the mosaics, when posing as models or participating in the installation of the artworks.</p>

<p>The head of the Vatican's Dicastery for Communication, Paolo Ruffini, opposed the removal of the artist's works, considering that was not the right way to help the victims.</p>

<p>"I don't think we have to throw stones, thinking it is the way of healing someone," Ruffini said last week at a Catholic media conference, whose video footage was obtained by The Pillar. "The Christian faith is saying other things."</p>

<p>Still, some dioceses are considering the possible removal of the Jesuit priest's paintings, including Lourdes, where a mosaic by Father Rupnik adorns the facade of the Basilica of Our Lady of the Rosary. A decision is expected shortly.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/qfm9eon_pope-francis-poses-with-cardinal-sean-patrick_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Head of Vatican's Dicastery for Communication opposed removal of the artist's works. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fake-free-wi-fi-scam-targets-australian-airports-flights-report-5991352]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fake Free Wi-Fi Scam Targets Australian Airports, Flights: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fake-free-wi-fi-scam-targets-australian-airports-flights-report-5991352]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 20:38:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 42-year-old man from Western Australia faces charges for allegedly setting up fake Wi-Fi networks at airports and on domestic flights across Perth, Melbourne, and Adelaide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 42-year-old man from Western Australia has been charged by Australian police for allegedly setting up fraudulent Wi-Fi networks at airports and on domestic flights. The Australian Federal Police (AFP) claims that these fraudulent networks pretended to be real ones in order to obtain personal information from unwary tourists. The man was supposed to appear in court in Perth on Friday in relation to nine allegations related to cybercrime.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/man-charged-with-evil-twin-wifi-scam-at-airports-and-on-flights/news-story/a6143f56b0b060f34003bb6968e92588"><em>News Corp Australia</em></a>, police allege the man, 42, used a device in a number of locations, including airports in Perth, Melbourne, and Adelaide, and on domestic flights, to create "evil twin" copies of legitimate wi-fi networks.</p>

<p>When users tried to connect their devices to the networks, they were allegedly taken to a fake web page and required to sign in using their email or social media logins.</p>

<p>Those details were then allegedly saved to the man's devices and could be used to access more personal information, including a victim's online communications, stored images and videos, or bank details, police said.</p>

<p>The alleged scam was reported to police by an airline in April after its employees identified a suspicious wi-fi network during a domestic flight.</p>

<p>As per the news portal, AFP Western Command Cybercrime Detective Inspector Andrea Coleman said internet users should always be cautious when logging on to any public wi-fi networks.</p>

<p>"To connect to a free wi-fi network, you shouldn't have to enter any personal details - such as logging in through an email or social media account," she said.</p>

<p>Inspector Coleman said those using public hotspots should install a reputable VPN on their devices to encrypt and secure their data.</p>

<p>"When using a public network, disable file sharing, don't do anything sensitive - such as banking -while connected to it and once you finish using it, change your device settings to 'forget network'," she said.</p>

<p>"We also recommend turning off the wi-fi on your phone or other electronic devices before going out in public, to prevent your device from automatically connecting to a hotspot."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/kc9auu5_rajasthan-cyber-crime_625x300_15_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The scam was uncovered by an airline.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-ruling-curbs-federal-agencies-powers-5991350]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Supreme Court Ruling Curbs Federal Agencies Powers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-ruling-curbs-federal-agencies-powers-5991350]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 20:38:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The conservative-majority US Supreme Court on Friday overturned 40 years of legal precedent to weaken the power of federal agencies, which regulate myriad issues affecting the everyday lives of Americans, from air pollution to food and drugs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The conservative-majority US Supreme Court on Friday overturned 40 years of legal precedent to weaken the power of federal agencies, which regulate myriad issues affecting the everyday lives of Americans, from air pollution to food and drugs.</p>

<p>"Courts may not defer to an agency interpretation of the law simply because a statute is ambiguous," said the majority opinion written by Chief Justice John Roberts.</p>

<p>At the heart of the matter is a 1984 ruling in Chevron v Natural Resources Defense Council, which said judges should defer to government agencies in determining a "reasonable" interpretation of the law if the language is ambiguous.</p>

<p>At the time, the case was a win for the administration of Republican president Ronald Reagan, who accused the country's progressive federal judges of burying corporate America under masses of unnecessary and restrictive red tape.</p>

<p>But the political right has since decried the ruling, saying it unfairly empowers the central government over the judiciary and means agencies can alter the meaning of statutes, depending on who is in charge.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/hc435au8_us-supreme-court-bloomberg_625x300_24_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At the heart of the matter is a 1984 ruling in Chevron v Natural Resources Defense Council. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-expand-deportation-relief-work-permits-to-309-000-more-haitians-5991236]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US To Expand Deportation Relief, Work Permits To 309,000 More Haitians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-expand-deportation-relief-work-permits-to-309-000-more-haitians-5991236]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 20:18:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden administration will expand deportation relief and work permits to an estimated 309,000 Haitians in the country already, the U.S. Department of Homeland Security said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden administration will expand deportation relief and work permits to an estimated 309,000 Haitians in the country already, the US Department of Homeland Security said on Friday.</p>

<p>The administration will expand access to the Temporary Protected Status program to Haitians through February 2026 due to violence and security issues in Haiti that limit access to safety, healthcare, food and water, the department said.</p>

<p>About 264,000 Haitians in the U.S. were already covered by the program, according to the U.S. government.</p>

<p>U.S. President Joe Biden, a Democrat seeking another term in Nov. 5 elections, has walked a political tightrope when it comes to immigration, trying to step up security at the U.S.-Mexico border while also taking a more humane approach to immigrants in the U.S. illegally.</p>

<p>In a presidential debate on Thursday, Biden's Republican challenger, former President Donald Trump, criticized Biden for failing to stem high levels of illegal immigration.</p>

<p>Gang wars in Haiti have displaced over half a million people and nearly five million are facing severe food insecurity. Armed groups, which now control most of the capital, have formed a broad alliance while carrying out widespread killings, ransom kidnappings and sexual violence.</p>

<p>Under the latest move, TPS will now be available to Haitians who were in the U.S. on or before June 3.</p>

<p>The TPS program offers deportation relief and work permits to people in the U.S. whose home countries face armed conflict, natural disasters and other extraordinary events. The designations last six to 18 months but frequently are renewed.</p>

<p>As president, Trump tried to end most TPS enrollment but was blocked in federal courts.</p>

<p>Thousands of Haitian migrants crossed the U.S.-Mexico border into Del Rio, Texas, in September 2021 as part of a rise in illegal crossings after Biden took office. In recent years, the number of Haitians caught crossing illegally has plummeted as many have used new legal pathways to the U.S.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/5t1qk6f8_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_11_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 264,000 Haitians in US were already covered by the program: US government. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-becomes-part-of-global-bond-index-effective-today-5987809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Becomes Part Of Global Bond Index Effective Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-becomes-part-of-global-bond-index-effective-today-5987809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 20:07:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India government bonds or government securities are set for inclusion in the global bond index from today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India government bonds or government securities are set for inclusion in the global bond index from today.</p>

<p>JP Morgan will add Indian government bonds to its Government Bond Index-Emerging Markets (GBI-EM) from June 28. It is the first time ever that Indian government bonds would be included in this index.</p>

<p>Government securities inclusion in the global bond index will have a positive impact on the Indian economy.</p>

<p>Indian bonds will have a 10 per cent weightage in the JP Morgan Emerging Markets Bond Index. The weightage of India's government bonds will be gradually increased in this index in a phased manner from June 28, 2024, to March 31, 2025, by one per cent each in the next 10 months.</p>

<p>JP Morgan announced the inclusion of Indian bonds in GBI-EM in September 2023, since then there has been an inflow of more than $10 billion into Indian bonds.</p>

<p>The move will enable foreign inflow to accelerate into Indian bonds. Demand for Indian government bonds will increase due to the inflow of foreign investment. This will increase the size of the Indian bond market. Besides, liquidity and efficiency will also increase.</p>

<p>Till now, only banks, insurance companies, and mutual funds have been major investors in government bonds. Now, a large number of global investors will be able to invest in Indian bonds. This will reduce the bond yield and will also reduce the cost of borrowing for the government which is expected to reduce the fiscal deficit.</p>

<p>Demand for the rupee will increase due to foreign inflow and hence it may remain strong in the coming months.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/uaf1rn2s_bonds-generic-bond-index-generic-unsplash_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India's inclusion in global bond index effective today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/60-indian-nationals-arrested-in-sri-lanka-for-cyber-crime-operations-5987734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[60 Indian Nationals Arrested In Sri Lanka For Cyber Crime Operations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/60-indian-nationals-arrested-in-sri-lanka-for-cyber-crime-operations-5987734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:52:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 60 Indian nationals part of a group engaged in online financial scams have been arrested by Sri Lanka's Criminal Investigations Department.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 60 Indian nationals part of a group engaged in online financial scams have been arrested by Sri Lanka's Criminal Investigations Department.</p>

<p>They were arrested on Thursday from the Colombo suburbs of Madiwela and Battaramulla and from the western coastal town of Negombo.</p>

<p>According to Police Spokesman SSP Nihal Thalduwa, the CID conducted simultaneous raids in these mentioned areas, leading to the seizure of 135 mobile phones and 57 laptops.</p>

<p>The crackdown follows a complaint from a victim who was lured into a WhatsApp group promising cash for social media interactions.</p>

<p>Further investigation revealed a scheme where victims were coerced into making deposits after initial payments. In Peradeniya, a father-son duo admitted to aiding the fraudsters, Daily Mirror Lanka newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Key evidence uncovered during a luxury house raid in Negombo led to the initial arrest of 13 suspects and the seizure of 57 phones and computers.</p>

<p>Subsequent operations in Negombo yielded 19 additional arrests, exposing international links in Dubai and Afghanistan. Victims included both locals and foreigners, the report added.</p>

<p>It is suspected that they were involved in financial fraud, illegal betting and various activities of gambling.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/fh1k7t2o_jail-generic-getty_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 60 Indians part of a group engaged in online scams have been arrested in Sri Lanka]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/137-indian-nationals-arrested-in-sri-lanka-for-cybercrime-operations-cops-5990839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[137 Indian Nationals Arrested In Sri Lanka For Cybercrime Operations: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/137-indian-nationals-arrested-in-sri-lanka-for-cybercrime-operations-cops-5990839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:15:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As many as 137 Indian nationals who were allegedly involved in a large-scale online financial scam across multiple locations in Sri Lanka have been arrested by police, according to a media report on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As many as 137 Indian nationals who were allegedly involved in a large-scale online financial scam across multiple locations in Sri Lanka have been arrested by police, according to a media report on Friday.</p>

<p>They were arrested on Thursday from the Colombo suburbs of Madiwela and Battaramulla and the western coastal town of Negombo, said Police Spokesman SSP Nihal Thalduwa was quoted as saying by Daily Mirror newspaper.</p>

<p>He said the Criminal Investigations Department (CID) conducted simultaneous raids in these areas, leading to the seizure of 158 mobile phones, 16 laptops, and 60 desktop computers.</p>

<p>In Negombo, 55 suspects were detained along with 55 mobile phones and 29 laptops.</p>

<p>Similarly, in Kochchikade, authorities apprehended 53 individuals and confiscated 31 laptops and 58 mobile phones.</p>

<p>The operation in Madiwela led to the arrest of 13 suspects and recovery of eight laptops and 38 mobile phones, while in Thalangama, 16 suspects were taken into custody with eight laptops and 38 mobile phones.</p>

<p>The SSP said that all the arrested suspects were males.</p>

<p>The crackdown follows a complaint from a victim who was lured into a WhatsApp group promising cash for social media interactions.</p>

<p>Further investigation revealed a scheme where victims were coerced into making deposits after initial payments. In Peradeniya, a father-son duo admitted to aiding the fraudsters, the newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Key evidence uncovered during a luxury house raid in Negombo led to the initial arrest of 13 suspects and the seizure of 57 phones and computers.</p>

<p>Subsequent operations in Negombo yielded 19 additional arrests, exposing international links in Dubai and Afghanistan. Victims included both locals and foreigners, the report added.</p>

<p>It is suspected that they were involved in financial fraud, illegal betting and various activities of gambling.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/iof8givc_arrest-generic_625x300_30_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The SSP said that all the arrested suspects were males (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-extend-digital-tax-on-e-commerce-supplies-till-june-30-5990736]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, US Extend Digital Tax On E-Commerce Supplies Till June 30]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-extend-digital-tax-on-e-commerce-supplies-till-june-30-5990736]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:00:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and the US have decided to extend a 2 per cent equalisation levy or digital tax on e-commerce supplies until June 30, the finance ministry said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and the US have decided to extend a 2 per cent equalisation levy or digital tax on e-commerce supplies until June 30, the finance ministry said on Friday.</p>

<p>In a major reform of the international tax system, India and the US have joined 134 other members of the OECD/G20 Inclusive Framework (including Austria, France, Italy, Spain, and the UK) in reaching an agreement on October 8, 2021, on the statement on a two-pillar solution to address the tax challenges arising from the digitalisation of the economy.</p>

<p>On October 21, 2021, the US and Austria, France, Italy, Spain, and the UK reached a political compromise on the transitional approach to the unilateral measures in force while Pillar 1 is implemented.</p>

<p>On November 24, 2021, India and the US agreed that the same terms that apply under the October 2021 Joint Statement shall apply between India and the US with respect to India's charge of 2 per cent equalisation levy on e-commerce supply of services and the US' trade action regarding the said Equalisation Levy.</p>

<p>The validity of this agreement was from April 1, 2022, till implementation of Pillar 1 or March 31, 2024, whichever is earlier.</p>

<p>On December 18, 2023, the Inclusive Framework issued a statement calling for a finalisation of the text of the Pillar 1 multilateral convention by the end of March 2024 with a view to holding a signing ceremony by the end of June 2024.</p>

<p>On February 15, 2024, the US and Austria, France, Italy, Spain, and the UK decided to extend the political compromise set forth in the October 21 Joint Statement until June 30, 2024.</p>

<p>"In light of above developments, India and the United States have decided to extend the validity of the agreement reflected in November 24 Statements until June 30, 2024. All other terms of the transitional approach remain the same," the finance ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>India and the US will remain in close contact to ensure that there is common understanding of the respective commitment and endeavour to resolve all issues on this matter through constructive dialogue, it added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-09/q35u6gic_india-us-flags-reuters_625x300_18_September_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/azerbaijan-to-hold-snap-parliamentary-election-on-september-1-5990692]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan To Hold Snap Parliamentary Election On September 1]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/azerbaijan-to-hold-snap-parliamentary-election-on-september-1-5990692]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:55:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Ilham Aliyev of Azerbaijan scheduled snap parliamentary elections for Sept. 1 in a decree published on Friday in a widely expected move that appears unlikely to radically change the parliament's make-up.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Ilham Aliyev of Azerbaijan scheduled snap parliamentary elections for Sept. 1 in a decree published on Friday in a widely expected move that appears unlikely to radically change the parliament's make-up.</p>

<p>Aliyev, in power since 2003, won a snap presidential election in February, and his New Azerbaijan Party, which holds 69 of 125 seats in the outgoing parliament, is expected to win a fresh majority in the oil-rich country, which has been courted by the West, Russia and Turkey.</p>

<p>Opposition deputies in parliament are loyal to Aliyev, but some opponents outside parliament say they have faced persecution after a string of independent journalists and political activists were arrested ahead of this year's presidential election, which Aliyev won with more by 92% of the vote.</p>

<p>Some of those detained faced charges for what they said were politically-motivated crimes, including smuggling. The authorities said the arrests were not political.</p>

<p>Aliyev has touted the success of a September lightning offensive which retook the former breakaway region of Nagorno-Karabakh from what Baku said were its illegitimate ethnic Armenian leaders.</p>

<p>Almost all of the region's more than 100,000 ethnic Armenians fled and Baku is now rebuilding the region amid plans to resettle it with Azerbaijanis.</p>

<p>Western energy firms such as BP operate in Azerbaijan, which is party to the "OPEC+" pact between the OPEC oil producers' club and other key exporters such as Russia to restrict output in order to support world prices.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/p124tbe8_-azerbaijan-ilham-aliyev_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Ilham Aliyev has been in power since 2003. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>