<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 06:56:58 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-us-president-elections-2024-tracker-trump-speaks-to-germanys-scholz-agrees-to-work-for-return-of-peace-in-europe-6990156]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Speaks To Germany's Scholz, Discusses "Return Of Peace In Europe"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-us-president-elections-2024-tracker-trump-speaks-to-germanys-scholz-agrees-to-work-for-return-of-peace-in-europe-6990156]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 06:54:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has so far won 312 electoral votes, well past the 270 needed for victory, while Kamala Harris is lagging behind at 226.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump is set to return to the White House after his emphatic victory over Kamala Harris in the November 5 US presidential elections. While the final results have not yet been declared, Trump has so far won 312 electoral votes, well past the 270 needed for victory. His Democratic rival, Harris, is lagging behind at 226.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old leader also sealed his sweep of all seven swing states, including Arizona, Georgia, Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin, all of which voted Democratic in the last election. He also won the swing states of North Carolina and Nevada.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He has now started to assemble his second administration and has named campaign manager Susie Wiles to serve as his White House chief of staff. She is the first woman to be named to the high-profile role. All eyes are now on the Republican's other appointments for his incoming administration.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are live updates on Donald Trump's return to White House:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/or1krfkg_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has sealed his sweep of all seven swing states]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-urges-fans-to-skip-soccer-match-with-france-after-amsterdam-violence-6989993]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Urges Fans To Skip Soccer Match With France After Amsterdam Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-urges-fans-to-skip-soccer-match-with-france-after-amsterdam-violence-6989993]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 06:06:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has urged fans to avoid Thursday's France-Israel football tie, which authorities fear could become a flashpoint following violence in Amsterdam following a match involving an Israeli team.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has urged fans to avoid Thursday's France-Israel football tie, which authorities fear could become a flashpoint following violence in Amsterdam following a match involving an Israeli team.</p>

<p>Despite a high police presence and the attendance of French President Emmanuel Macron, Israeli officials on Sunday warned fans to stay away because of fears they could be targeted.</p>

<p>A right-wing Jewish group has nevertheless announced a rally ahead of the Nations League tie.</p>

<p>The Paris fixture will take place one week after clashes, which followed a game between Israeli club Maccabi Tel Aviv and Dutch team Ajax.</p>

<p>The violence was condemned as "anti-Semitic" by Israeli, US, Dutch and European leaders. About two dozen people were injured, while police said they had made more than 60 arrests.</p>

<p>Describing the France-Israel fixture as high risk, Paris police chief Laurent Nunez said 4,000 gendarmes would be deployed around the Stade de France, on public transport and across the French capital.</p>

<p>Such a massive deployment was "highly unusual" for an international match, Nunez told BFMTV, while the national police force's elite unit would be tasked with protecting Israel's footballers.</p>

<p>"We will not tolerate any overspill or disturbances to public order," he added.</p>

<p><strong>'Intolerable anti-Semitism'</strong></p>

<p>In Jerusalem, the National Security Council on Sunday urged Israeli fans to "avoid attending sports games/cultural events involving Israelis, with an emphasis on the upcoming match of the Israeli national team in Paris".</p>

<p>Organisations wishing to attack Israel had been identified in a number of European cities, including Paris, it warned, advising its nationals not to have recognisable Israeli or Jewish signs on display.</p>

<p>The match comes amid a tide of rising anti-Jewish and anti-Muslim abuse since the start of Israel's war with Hamas in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Macron's office on Sunday said the French president would attend the upcoming tie to "send a message of fraternity and solidarity after the intolerable acts of anti-Semitism that followed the match in Amsterdam this week".</p>

<p>The scenes in Amsterdam last week sparked widespread international condemnation, with US President Joe Biden and European leaders denouncing the "anti-semitic" violence against Jews.</p>

<p>The Palestinian foreign ministry reported "anti-Arab chanting".</p>

<p>Following rising tensions in the run-up to the Europa League game, groups of men on scooters launched "hit-and-run" attacks on Maccabi Tel Aviv supporters.</p>

<p>This came after sporadic incidents linked to both Maccabi supporters -- accused of chanting and singing anti-Palestinian slogans and songs -- and opposing groups of youths.</p>

<p>Amsterdam police said some Maccabi supporters had burned a Palestinian flag on the Dam central square, and vandalised a taxi.</p>

<p>Police said the attackers were mobilised by calls on social media to target Jewish people.</p>

<p>The authorities have already arrested 63 people in connection with Thursday's violence and more detentions are expected.</p>

<p><strong>Protest planned</strong></p>

<p>Right-wing Jewish movement Betar on Sunday said it would organise a protest against anti-Semitism ahead of the tie.</p>

<p>World Betar, a pro-Israel youth movement, was also planning to host Israel's far-right Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich on the sidelines of a gala on Wednesday in support of Israel organised by far-right individuals.</p>

<p>Several associations, unions and French leftist parties had denounced the "Israel is Forever" event, and in particular Smotrich's planned appearance.</p>

<p>But police chief Nunez -- who gave his approval for the gala to be held -- said that Smotrich might not in fact attend. "I understand that in the end, he won't be there," he said.</p>

<p>Betar is active worldwide and has links to the Israeli right.</p>

<p>The group's CEO Yigal Brand said in a statement on Sunday that the movement was "outraged at what has happened in Amsterdam.</p>

<p>"We are proud Zionists and have nothing to apologise for," he added.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities had warned fans against attending a Maccabi Tel Aviv basketball match in the Italian city of Bologna on Friday, which ended without incident.</p>

<p>Following the violence in Amsterdam, Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said he had ordered the Mossad spy agency to draw up a plan to prevent unrest at events abroad.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4j25e8r_amsterdam-clashes_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Amsterdam violence was condemned as "anti-Semitic" by Israeli, US, Dutch and European leaders (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gazans-dig-through-rubble-by-hand-for-bodies-survivors-amid-fresh-israeli-attack-6989962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gazans Dig Through Rubble For Bodies, Survivors Amid Fresh Israeli Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gazans-dig-through-rubble-by-hand-for-bodies-survivors-amid-fresh-israeli-attack-6989962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 05:51:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Much rattled, Mohammed Alloush, a Palestinian man from Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip, rushed to his relatives' house on Sunday to see what had happened after it was attacked by the Israeli army.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Much rattled, Mohammed Alloush, a Palestinian man from Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip, rushed to his relatives' house on Sunday to see what had happened after it was attacked by the Israeli army.</p>

<p>Upon his arrival with dozens of his neighbours, Alloush was shocked to find the house, once alive with more than 50 residents, completely destroyed, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"We heard cries for help from beneath the rubble. Some were still alive. I must help and rescue them," Alloush told Xinhua with a breaking voice.</p>

<p>However, neither Alloush nor any other responders have any tools in hand.</p>

<p>"We are forced to dig with our bare hands to help the injured and pull out the dead as possible as we can," said the 35-year-old father of four, holding the body of a child in his arms.</p>

<p>"The situation is very dangerous here, as the Israeli army may strike the house again, but we have to race against time to rescue as many as we can," he said.</p>

<p>Alloush said he and his neighbors have to bury the dead in place, and transfer the injured to the Kamal Adwan and Indonesian hospitals, which have been out of service, with donkey carts.</p>

<p>Earlier on Sunday, the Israeli army killed at least 36 members of Alloush's family in an attack on their house in Jabalia refugee camp, according to locals and medical sources.</p>

<p>The attack was part of Israel's ongoing large-scale military offensive in the area starting from Oct. 5, which aims to kill the remnants of Hamas and prevent it from regrouping in the territory, the Israeli military has claimed.</p>

<p>Mahmoud Basal, spokesperson for the Palestinian Civil Defense in Gaza, said the Israeli military forced the Civil Defense teams to leave the area and sieged many locals inside their houses.</p>

<p>Israel has been conducting a large-scale offensive against Hamas in the Gaza Strip to retaliate against a Hamas rampage through the southern Israeli border on Oct. 7, 2023, during which about 1,200 people were killed and about 250 taken hostage.</p>

<p>The Palestinian death count from ongoing Israeli attacks in Gaza has risen to 43,603, with injuries up to 102,929, Gaza-based health authorities said in a statement on Sunday.</p>

<p>In northern Gaza, the Israeli offensive has killed more than 1,800 people, wounded about 4,000 others, and left hundreds missing, apart from destroying all local hospitals, the Hamas-run government media office said Monday in a press statement.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, rescue operations are difficult in Gaza City, even with the presence of the Civil Defense services.</p>

<p>On Saturday night, the Israeli army killed at least five Palestinians in an attack on a house of the al-Khour family in the Tal al-Hawa neighbourhood west of Gaza City.</p>

<p>"It was very hard for the ambulances and Civil Defense to reach the area quickly, so I decided to use my hands to rescue the survivors and pull out the dead to bury them in the early morning," 25-year-old Palestinian Mohammed Doghmosh told Xinhua.</p>

<p>Doghmosh said he and his friends used the flashlights on their mobile phones to see clearly through the rubble so that they could pull out the casualties as soon as possible.</p>

<p>"All the time, we are in a race against death, war, and time. So, we have to take the mission into our own hands and help each other as best we can," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/82cb0je_alloush-family-home-gaza_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Sunday, the Israeli army killed at least 36 members of Mohammed Alloush's family in Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strike-kills-hezbollah-commander-8-others-in-syria-war-monitor-6989932]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Strike Kills Hezbollah Commander, 8 Others In Syria: War Monitor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strike-kills-hezbollah-commander-8-others-in-syria-war-monitor-6989932]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 05:41:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel struck an apartment belonging to Hezbollah in a stronghold of pro-Iran groups south of Damascus on Sunday, killing nine people including a commander, a war monitor said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel struck an apartment belonging to Hezbollah in a stronghold of pro-Iran groups south of Damascus on Sunday, killing nine people including a commander, a war monitor said.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said one of the dead was a Lebanese commander of the Iran-backed Hezbollah group in Syria.</p>

<p>Israel has increased strikes on Syria since an all-out war with Hezbollah in Lebanon erupted on September 23.</p>

<p>Rami Abdel Rahman, who heads the Britain-based monitor, told AFP that the commander "was active in Syria and held Lebanese nationality". The man's name is not yet known.</p>

<p>The monitor, which has a network of sources inside Syria, said that "nine people lost their lives -- four civilians (a woman and her three children) of Syrian nationality, and five others, including a Hezbollah commander."</p>

<p>It said the strike hit "an apartment in a building in the Sayyida Zeinab area" south of the Syrian capital.</p>

<p>According to the monitor, 14 others were wounded in the strike which "targeted individuals in an apartment inhabited by Lebanese families and Hezbollah members".</p>

<p>Some of thos killed in the strike "remain unidentified", the Observatory said.</p>

<p>Syria's official SANA news agency reported an "Israeli aggression targeting a residential building in the Sayyida Zeinab" area, home to a major Shiite shrine.</p>

<p>It later reported a death count of "seven civilians, including children and women", and 20 wounded.</p>

<p>On Saturday, four pro-Iran fighters were among five people killed in Israeli strikes in north and northwest Syria, the Observatory reported.</p>

<p>Since Syria's civil war broke out in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes in Syria, mainly targeting army positions and fighters including from Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities rarely comment on the strikes, but have repeatedly said they will not allow arch-enemy Iran to expand its presence in Syria.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some of those killed in the strike "remain unidentified", the Observatory said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunmen-kill-10-in-bar-shooting-in-mexico-6989845]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunmen Kill 10 In Bar Shooting In Mexico]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunmen-kill-10-in-bar-shooting-in-mexico-6989845]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 05:10:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gunmen killed 10 people in a bar in the central Mexican state of Queretaro late Saturday, authorities said, adding to a wave of violent crime that is gripping several areas of the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gunmen killed 10 people in a bar in the central Mexican state of Queretaro late Saturday, authorities said, adding to a wave of violent crime that is gripping several areas of the country.</p>

<p>The incident took place in a bar in the downtown area of the state's capital, also known as Queretaro, where four gunmen entered, killing seven men and three women, according to the state attorney general and Queretaro city's security chief.</p>

<p>Seven other people were injured. One person was so far in police custody, authorities said. Investigators were at the scene and also looking into a vehicle believed to be linked to the incident.</p>

<p>Queretaro is not commonly prone to high levels of violent crime, such as homicide, and is considered relatively safer than many other areas of Mexico.</p>

<p>"I reiterate to the people of Queretaro that there will be punishment for those responsible for this brutal act, we will continue to seal our borders and maintain the security of our state," Queretaro governor Mauricio Kuri said on X.</p>

<p>Mexico is dealing with a security crisis linked to organized crime and warring factions of drug cartels that is one of the most pressing challenges for new Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum.</p>

<p>There have been 2,788 homicides in the country since her inauguration on Oct 1., according to pollster TResearch's analysis of government data.</p>

<p>Sheinbaum has vowed to crack down on violent crime and unveiled a security plan aimed at increasing opportunities for vulnerable young people, improving intelligence sharing among government institutions and beefing up the country's National Guard.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c0dp84i8_mexico-bar-shooting_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Seven people were injured in the shooting]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/many-killed-in-strikes-on-gaza-lebanon-as-israel-faces-us-aid-deadline-6989819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Many Killed In Strikes On Gaza, Lebanon As Israel Faces US' Aid Deadline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/many-killed-in-strikes-on-gaza-lebanon-as-israel-faces-us-aid-deadline-6989819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 05:04:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli air strikes killed dozens of people in Lebanon and Gaza Sunday, rescuers and authorities said, ahead of a US deadline for improved aid delivery to the Palestinian territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli air strikes killed dozens of people in Lebanon and Gaza Sunday, rescuers and authorities said, ahead of a US deadline for improved aid delivery to the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>Another strike south of the Syrian capital Damascus killed nine people including a Hezbollah commander, a war monitor said.</p>

<p>Rescuers in the Gaza Strip said 13 children were among 30 people killed by Israeli strikes in the territory's north.</p>

<p>The first hit a house in Jabalia, killing at least 25 people including 13 children and injuring more than 30, Gaza's civil defence agency said.</p>

<p>At around 6:00 am, "there was a very huge explosion" at the Alloush family home, said relative Abdullah al-Najjar.</p>

<p>"When we arrived here, all the bodies were torn apart."</p>

<p>Vowing to stop Hamas militants from regrouping in already ravaged north Gaza, Israel on October 6 began a major air and ground assault.</p>

<p>The United Nations has described the area as "under siege", and Washington set a deadline of this coming week for Israel to get more aid in or face possible cuts to military assistance.</p>

<p>After the Jabalia strike, Israel's military said it hit "infrastructure" in which militants were operating and "posed a threat" to troops.</p>

<p>Another strike on Gaza City's Sabra neighbourhood killed five people, the civil defence agency said.</p>

<p>- Israel claims pager blasts -</p>

<p>In Lebanon, the health ministry said an Israeli strike on Almat village north of Beirut killed 23 people including seven children.</p>

<p>"Under the rubble, there are only children, elderly men and women," Hezbollah lawmaker Raed Berro said, denying Israeli allegations that Hezbollah and weapons were embedded among civilians.</p>

<p>The ministry reported at least another 15 dead in strikes in the east as well as three Hezbollah-affiliated rescuers killed in the south, both areas where the Iran-backed group has a strong presence.</p>

<p>War monitor the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported that an Israeli strike on an apartment belonging to Hezbollah south of Damascus killed nine people, including a Hezbollah commander.</p>

<p>Iran's foreign ministry condemned the strike, calling for "an arms embargo" on Israel and its "expulsion from the United Nations".</p>

<p>Since late September Israel has been engaged in a two-front war after turning its focus north towards Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel admitted for the first time Sunday it was behind a wave of deadly attacks on Hezbollah communications devices in September.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu "greenlighted the pager operation in Lebanon" in which hundreds of devices exploded, killing nearly 40 people and wounding around 3,000, his spokesman said.</p>

<p>The operation preceded Israel's ongoing air and ground campaign in Lebanon, after almost a year of tit-for-tat exchanges of fire with Hezbollah, which said it was acting in support of Hamas.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza erupted with Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack on southern Israel which resulted in 1,206 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed 43,603 people in Gaza, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Israel's military said it intercepted two drones approaching from the east. Pro-Iran groups in Iraq have previously said they launched attack drones at Israel.</p>

<p>- Aid surge 'must happen' -</p>

<p>Israel's main military backer the United States on October 15 warned that it could withhold some of its billions of dollars in assistance unless Israel improves aid delivery to the Gaza Strip within 30 days -- a deadline that expires on Wednesday.</p>

<p>State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said at the time top US officials made "clear" to Israel's government that changes need to be made "to see that the level of assistance making it into Gaza comes back up from the very, very low levels that it is at today".</p>

<p>The demand came before Tuesday's vote for President-elect Donald Trump, who has suggested he would give freer rein to Israel.</p>

<p>On Saturday, a UN-backed assessment warned that famine is imminent in northern Gaza.</p>

<p>Fewer aid shipments were allowed into Gaza than at any time since October 2023, according to the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) report.</p>

<p>The alert from the Famine Review Committee warned of "an imminent and substantial likelihood of famine occurring, due to the rapidly deteriorating situation".</p>

<p>Israel's military questioned the report's credibility, denouncing "partial, biased data and superficial sources with vested interests".</p>

<p>German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock said that "humanitarian access must be granted at all times and must never become a means of warfare".</p>

<p>She said that "time and again" promises of aid were not kept, and that an Israeli pledge to flood Gaza with aid "must happen, without excuses".</p>

<p>The heads of UN agencies in early November described north Gaza as "under siege" and denied "basic aid and life-saving supplies".</p>

<p>Arab and Muslim leaders are gathering in Saudi Arabia for a summit Monday that will focus on the wars in Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Gaza mediator Qatar said it had suspended its role in trying to broker a deal.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/iacgtm08_gaza_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since late September, Israel has been engaged in a two-front wa]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-launch-biggest-drone-attacks-yet-on-each-other-6989762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia, Ukraine Launch Biggest Drone Attacks Yet On Each Other]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-launch-biggest-drone-attacks-yet-on-each-other-6989762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 04:49:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia and Ukraine both launched record drone attacks on each other overnight, despite a phone call reported by the Washington Post from US president-elect Donald Trump urging Russian President Vladimir Putin not to escalate the conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia and Ukraine both launched record drone attacks on each other overnight, despite a phone call reported by the Washington Post from US president-elect Donald Trump urging Russian President Vladimir Putin not to escalate the conflict.</p>

<p>Trump's election to the White House has the potential to upend the almost three-year conflict and has thrown into question Washington's multi-billion dollar support for Kyiv, crucial to its defence.</p>

<p>The Republican said on the campaign trail that he could end the fighting within hours and has indicated he will talk directly with Russian President Vladimir Putin -- a major break from the approach adopted by President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the Washington Post reported that Trump had had a phone call on Thursday with the Russian strongman in which he told Putin not to inflame the attritional war.</p>

<p>Just days after his stunning election victory over Democratic rival Kamala Harris, Trump reminded Putin of Washington's sizeable military foothold in Europe from his Mar-a-Lago estate in Florida, according to the Post.</p>

<p>The Kremlin had earlier said it saw "positive signals" from Trump's willingness to strike a deal, and several people speaking to the US paper said Trump had expressed the desire for more conversations on "the resolution of Ukraine's war soon".</p>

<p>Trump will not be inaugurated until January and for the moment on the battlefield and in the skies, the conflict shows no signs of subsiding.</p>

<p><strong>'Positive signals'</strong></p>

<p>Russia fired 145 drones at Ukraine overnight, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said -- more than in any single night-time attack of the conflict so far.</p>

<p>"Last night, Russia launched a record 145 Shaheds and other strike drones against Ukraine," Zelensky said on social media, urging Kyiv's Western allies to do more to help Ukraine's defence.</p>

<p>Russia also said it had downed 34 Ukrainian attack drones targeting Moscow on Sunday, the largest attempted attack on the capital since the start of the offensive in 2022.</p>

<p>US National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said Sunday that the White House was to spend its remaining $6 billion of funding for Ukraine before Trump takes office, warning of the risks of ending US support for Kyiv.</p>

<p>While having publicly claimed to be backing Harris in the US election, the Kremlin is widely believed to have actually wanted to see Trump return to the White House, welcoming his scepticism over American aid to Ukraine and his chaotic leadership style.</p>

<p>"The signals are positive," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said in an interview with state media published Sunday.</p>

<p>"Trump during his election campaign talked about how he perceives everything through deals, that he can make a deal that can lead to peace.</p>

<p>"At least he's talking about peace, and not about confrontation. He isn't talking about his wish to inflict a strategic defeat on Russia -- that distinguishes him from the current administration," Peskov added.</p>

<p>"What will happen next, it's hard to say," Peskov said, adding that Trump was "less predictable" than Harris and Biden.</p>

<p>"It's also less predictable to what extent he will stick to the statements that he made on the campaign trail," Peskov added.</p>

<p>Trump has not said how he intends to strike a peace deal or what terms he is proposing.</p>

<p>Russia's President Putin has demanded Ukraine withdraw from swathes of its eastern and southern territory as a precondition to peace talks.</p>

<p>People familiar with Thursday's call said Trump had briefly raised the question of land with Putin.</p>

<p>Following Trump's election, Zelensky warned there should be "no concessions" to Putin. Ceding land or giving in to any of his other hardline demands would only embolden the Kremlin and lead to more aggression, he said.</p>

<p>Zelensky has also previously warned that without US aid Kyiv would lose the conflict.</p>

<p><strong>'Massive' attack</strong></p>

<p>Talk of a US-brokered deal comes as Russia advances on the battlefield.</p>

<p>Moscow's troops made their largest territorial gains in October since March 2022, according to AFP analysis of data from the Washington-based Institute for the Study of War (ISW).</p>

<p>Moscow's defence ministry claimed Sunday to have captured another village in Ukraine's east.</p>

<p>In his evening address, Zelensky alluded to Ukraine's attempted barrage of Moscow, the largest attack targeting the Russian capital since the start of the conflict.</p>

<p>Thanking his forces responsible for drone combat he said: "Russian military objects are becoming more and more accessible to our soldiers."</p>

<p>Moscow region governor Andrei Vorobyov called it a "massive" attempted strike.</p>

<p>It forced the temporary closure of three airports, wounded a 52-year-old woman and set two homes on fire in the village of Stanovoye in the Moscow region, officials said.</p>

<p>While the Ukrainian capital Kyiv is frequently targeted by massive Russian drone and missile strikes, attacks on Moscow are far less frequent.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mmkif8oo_drone-attack-on-ukraine_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia fired 145 drones at Ukraine overnight, Zelensky said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-speaks-to-putin-urges-him-to-not-escalate-war-in-ukraine-report-6989684]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Speaks To Putin, Urges Him To Not Escalate War In Ukraine: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-speaks-to-putin-urges-him-to-not-escalate-war-in-ukraine-report-6989684]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Nov 2024 04:18:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has spoken to Russian President Vladimir Putin and urged him not to escalate the war in Ukraine, the Washington Post reported Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has spoken to Russian President Vladimir Putin and urged him not to escalate the war in Ukraine, the Washington Post reported Sunday.</p>

<p>Trump held the call from his Mar-a-Lago estate in Florida on Thursday, just days after his stunning election victory over Democratic rival Kamala Harris, the report said.</p>

<p>The president-elect's representatives did not immediately respond when asked by AFP for comment.</p>

<p>The Post, citing several people familiar with the call who spoke on the basis of anonymity, reported that Trump had reminded Putin of America's sizable military presence in Europe.</p>

<p>They said he also expressed an interest in further conversations to discuss "the resolution of Ukraine's war soon."</p>

<p>Trump's election is seen as carrying the potential to upend the almost three-year Ukraine conflict, as he insists on a quick end to the fighting and casts doubt on Washington's multi-billion dollar support for Kyiv.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky spoke with Trump on Wednesday, with the Republican's billionaire backer Elon Musk also notably joining them on the call.</p>

<p>Zelensky described the call as "excellent," saying that he and Trump had agreed to "maintain close dialogue and advance our cooperation."</p>

<p>The outgoing Democratic administration of President Joe Biden has confirmed that it will send as much aid as possible to Ukraine before Trump's inauguration on January 20.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Biden's National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said the White House aims "to put Ukraine in the strongest possible position on the battlefield so that it is ultimately in the strongest possible position at the negotiating table."</p>

<p>This would include using the remaining $6 billion of funding for Ukraine available, Sullivan said.</p>

<p><strong>'Losing your allowance'</strong></p>

<p>The Russian government has given a cautious but mostly positive response to Trump's return, with Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov saying Sunday: "The signals are positive... At least he's talking about peace, and not about confrontation."</p>

<p>During his campaign, Trump repeatedly vowed to quickly end the Ukraine war -- even before he is sworn into office -- but without detailing his thinking.</p>

<p>Trump and his allies have railed against US funding for Ukraine, while insinuating that it helps fund a corrupt pro-war nexus of defense companies and foreign policy hawks.</p>

<p>Trump's eldest son, Donald Trump Jr., shared a clip Saturday on Instagram which showed Zelensky standing next to the president-elect with a caption reading: "POV (point of view): You're 38 days from losing your allowance."</p>

<p>Any quick deal in Ukraine is expected to require Kyiv to cede some of the territory it has lost to Russian invaders in Ukraine's south and east.</p>

<p>A former adviser to Trump, Bryanb Lanza, told the BBC on Saturday that Ukraine had to give up any ambition on regaining Crimea, for instance, which was occupied by Russia in 2014.</p>

<p>He said the US priority was for "peace and to stop the killing", although the Trump transition team clarified that he was not speaking on behalf of the president-elect.</p>

<p>Kyiv, though facing a manpower shortage and uncertainty over US support, has steadfastly opposed giving up territory and its European allies and weapons suppliers such as Britain and France are known to be nervous about unilateral moves by Trump.</p>

<p>Zelensky has said that giving up land or meeting other demands from the Kremlin would only embolden the Kremlin and provoke more aggression, a view shared by many European allies.</p>

<p>Trump "briefly raised the issue of land" in his call with Putin, the Post reported, without further details.</p>

<p>In recent months, both sides in the war have made moves seen as possible efforts to gain leverage ahead of eventual negotiations, with Ukraine seizing a chunk of Russian territory and Moscow's troops making advances in Ukraine.</p>

<p>This weekend brought the biggest drone attacks yet from both sides.</p>

<p>Russia fired 145 drones at Ukraine overnight, Zelensky said, while Russia said it had downed 34 Ukrainian drones targeting Moscow on Sunday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sal4bm5g_donald-trump-putin_625x300_09_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump reportedly had reminded Putin of US' sizable military presence in Europe (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-powerful-earthquakes-hit-cuba-within-an-hour-6988795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Two Powerful Earthquakes Hit Cuba Within An Hour]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-powerful-earthquakes-hit-cuba-within-an-hour-6988795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 23:28:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A second, more powerful quake rocked southern Cuba on Sunday, US geologists said, shortly after a first shallow tremor that did not prompt a tsunami alert.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two powerful earthquakes rocked southern Cuba in quick succession on Sunday, US geologists said, as authorities said no tsunami alert was issued and no deaths immediately reported.</p>

<p>The US Geological Survey put the second, more powerful tremor at a magnitude of 6.8 and 14.6 miles (23.5 kilometers) deep, some 25 miles off the coast of Bartolome Maso, in southern Granma province.</p>

<p>It came just an hour after a first tremor, which the USGS put at a magnitude of 5.9, with the epicenter some nine miles beneath the ocean roughly 22 miles off Bartolome Maso.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The state-run newspaper Granma said no deaths had been immediately reported, but that the quake had been felt throughout the Caribbean island nation.</p>

<p>"Here people quickly took to the streets because the ground moved very strongly," Andres Perez, a 65-year-old retiree who lives in downtown Santiago de Cuba, told AFP via telephone of the first quake.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It felt very strong really, my wife is a bundle of nerves," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US tsunami warning system said no tsunami warning had been issued.</p>

<p>The tremor shook the island as it recovers from Hurricane Rafael, which hit the country's west as a Category 3 storm, leaving residents without power for two days.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A 5.1 magnitude earthquake was recorded in October 2023 in Santiago de Cuba, without causing any damage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another strong earthquake of magnitude 7.7 was recorded in January 2020 in the Caribbean Sea and was felt in several Cuban provinces, causing the evacuation of buildings in the capital Havana, with no damage reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b9blons8_earthquake_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The second earthquake was at a magnitude of 6.8. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-okayed-deadly-lebanon-pager-attacks-says-his-office-6988315]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Confirms He Okayed Pager Attacks That Killed Nearly 40 In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-okayed-deadly-lebanon-pager-attacks-says-his-office-6988315]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 21:52:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Sunday accepted that he had "okayed" the pager attacks in Lebanon, which had killed nearly 40 Iran-backed Hezbollah members in September.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has accepted that he had "okayed" the pager attacks in Lebanon, which had killed nearly 40 and wounded 3,000 Iran-backed Hezbollah members in September.</p>

<p>"Netanyahu confirmed Sunday that he greenlighted the pager operation in Lebanon," his spokesperson Omer Dostri told news agency AFP.</p>

<p>Thousands of pagers exploded in Hezbollah strongholds on September 17 and 18 - which Iran and Hezbollah blamed on Israel. Some of the Hezbollah members who were injured reportedly lost their fingers, while some lost their eyesight.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had called the blasts an "Israeli breach" of its communications network and vowed to avenge the attack.</p>

<p>The pagers were used by Hezbollah members as a low-tech means of communication to evade Israeli location-tracking.</p>

<p>The blasts came just hours after Israel announced it was broadening the aims of the war sparked by Hamas' October 7 attacks to include its fight against the group's ally Hezbollah along the country's border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>This week, Lebanon had filed a complaint with the United Nations Labour Agency over the deadly attack, calling it an "egregious war against humanity".</p>

<p>Israel and Hezbollah have been fighting across the Lebanese border since the war in Gaza erupted after Hamas attacked Israeli towns on October 7 last year. Since then, several Hezbollah fighters, including former chief of the Iran-backed group Hassan Nasrallah, have been killed. Last month, Israel's army also confirmed that it "eliminated" Hezbollah's Hashem Safieddine, an apparent successor of Nasrallah, in a strike in southern Beirut.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Israel conducted airstrikes on Hezbollah's main bastion in south Beirut, with one raid hitting an area near Lebanon's only international airport - causing minor damage to some of the airport's buildings, including flag carrier Middle East Airlines' premises.</p>

<p>Since October last year, more than 3,000 people have been killed in Israeli strikes on Lebanon.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h903pudo_netanyahu_625x300_10_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On September 17, thousands of pagers exploded in Hezbollah strongholds.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bitcoin-hits-80-000-for-first-time-as-trump-set-to-return-to-white-house-6988187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bitcoin Hits $80,000 For First Time As Trump Set To Return To White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bitcoin-hits-80-000-for-first-time-as-trump-set-to-return-to-white-house-6988187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 21:25:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bitcoin soared to a new record high on Sunday, as traders bet that Donald Trump's return to the White House will be good for the cryptocurrency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin soared to a new record high on Sunday, as traders bet that Donald Trump's return to the White House will be good for the cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>The digital currency passed $80,000 for the first time in its history shortly after 12:00 pm (1200 GMT).</p>

<p>It has been rising since Republican candidate Trump won last Tuesday's US presidential election over sentiment that he will ease regulations on digital currencies.</p>

<p>"The odds that Bitcoin and crypto will become a significantly larger asset class have risen markedly," Charles Morris, an analyst at investment company ByteTree told AFP.</p>

<p>Bitcoin reached $75,000 on Wednesday, topping its previous all-time peak of $73,797.98 achieved in March.</p>

<p>"We shouldn't expect this bullish trend to be interrupted for a long time -- about a year. The next level for me is $100,000," Stephane Ifrah, of French crypto asset management company Coinhouse, told AFP.</p>

<p>Trump was seen as the pro-crypto candidate in his battle with the Democratic Party's candidate Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>During his first presidency Trump referred to cryptocurrencies as a scam, but has since radically changed his position, even launching his own platform for the unit.</p>

<p>He has pledged to make the United States the "bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world," and to put tech billionaire and right-wing conspiracy theorist Elon Musk in charge of a wide-ranging audit of governmental waste.</p>

<p>The previous Trump term saw corporate tax cuts that brought more liquidity to markets, encouraging investment into high-growth assets such as cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Trump announced in September that he, along with his sons and entrepreneurs, would launch a digital currency platform named World Liberty Financial.</p>

<p>But it had a faltering sales launch earlier this month, with only a fraction of its tokens that went on the market finding a buyer.</p>

<p>Cryptocurrencies have made headlines since their creation, from their extreme volatility to the collapse of several industry giants, foremost among them the FTX exchange platform.</p>

<p>In the run-up to the election, Trump apparently became the first former president to use bitcoin in a purchase, as he bought burgers at a New York City restaurant, which hailed it as a "historic transaction".</p>

<p>Bitcoin is listed continuously, including on Sundays.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/78nudmn_bitcoin_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bitcoin passed $80,000 for the first time in its history. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/english-channel-nightmare-survivors-search-for-missing-father-i-live-in-hope-6988018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Live In Hope": A Channel Nightmare Survivor's Search For Missing Father]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/english-channel-nightmare-survivors-search-for-missing-father-i-live-in-hope-6988018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 20:58:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Osama Ahmed's life took a dramatic turn one night in October when the small boat that was to carry him and his father to the English coast sank shortly after setting out from France.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Osama Ahmed's life took a dramatic turn one night in October when the small boat that was to carry him and his father to the English coast sank shortly after setting out from France.</p>

<p>The 20-year-old Syrian was rescued but when he woke up in hospital and asked about his dad nobody knew anything.</p>

<p>Since that moment, Osama has been looking frantically for his father with whom he had hoped to start a new life in Britain.</p>

<p>Beyond the tragically long list of deaths in the Channel of migrants trying to cross, another statistic is also growing fast: Missing people.</p>

<p>"I live in hope of finding him," Osama told AFP in a house in Calais on the French coast where an association, La Margella, put him up. He rejected any idea that his dad may not have survived. "God willing, I will find him," he said.</p>

<p>On the night between October 22 and 23 father and son tried to make it across the water, like 30,000 other migrants this year alone. It was their third attempt.</p>

<p>They were part of a group of around 60 people hiding in the dunes who, at the signal of the people smugglers, rushed to the small boat waiting for them in the water.</p>

<p>But barely one kilometre (1,000 yards) into the journey, water began to seep in.</p>

<p>The group turned the boat around, but the smugglers on the beach pushed them back out to sea, Osama said.</p>

<p>He said they had been promised lifejackets that failed to materialise because, the smugglers claimed, they had been damaged.</p>

<p>The boat's air chambers became completely deflated soon after departure, and everyone on board tumbled into the sea.</p>

<p>For half an hour Osama and his father managed to cling to each other, but when the boat began to disintegrate amid the panic and darkness they were separated.</p>

<p>Two ferries passed without stopping, and eventually, rescue services arrived.</p>

<p>French maritime authorities reported finding three bodies, one woman and two men, after the drama that occurred two kilometres (1.2 miles) off the French coast.</p>

<p>Forty-five people were rescued but survivors reported that there had been more people on board, suggesting that a number had gone missing.</p>

<p>'World's nicest man'</p>

<p>The drama was followed by other, similar incidents, in the Channel and authorities have since found nine bodies floating in the sea or washed up on northern French beaches, none of them the young Syrian's dad.</p>

<p>Osama, who was treated in hospital for burns caused by saltwater and fuel, has been to every police station, hospital and Red Cross office in the area in search of his father, in vain.</p>

<p>He told officials what clothes his dad wore last, and about the ring in which his name is engraved. Police took a sample of Osama's DNA.</p>

<p>Every time a body is found along the coast, Osama fears it could be his father. As the excruciating wait lingers, his life plans are on hold.</p>

<p>His family fled from Syria 13 years ago, to settle in Turkey. Two of Osama's brothers are already in England, having made the journey also in small boats.</p>

<p>He flashed a big smile as he described his dad, "the world's nicest man" and his "role model".</p>

<p>On his phone he has a picture of him, a man in his 50s wearing a white shirt and a jacket, and sporting a grey moustache.</p>

<p>French associations say the authorities should do more to help survivors locate their loved ones after failed crossings.</p>

<p>"People go missing and their families find it very hard to access services that might assist them in their search," said Jeanne Bonnet, co-founder of La Margelle which tries to help migrants navigate French officialdom.</p>

<p>"We sometimes get the feeling that we're being given the runaround," she said.</p>

<p>Osama, she said, was offered no accommodation when he left hospital, injured and traumatised, so he went back to the same camp he had stayed in previously. That's where La Margella took charge of him.</p>

<p>Braving cold temperatures and fog, close to 1,200 migrants have reached England onboard small boats since the beginning of November, according to British official figures.</p>

<p>Sixty people have been confirmed dead this year -- not counting the most recently-discovered bodies and missing people -- a record number since such Channel crossings started in 2018.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/95bikgt_osama-ahmed-afp_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Osama Ahemed has been looking for his father with whom he had hoped to start a new life in Britain.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/adani-jkh-terminal-at-colombo-port-likely-to-be-operational-from-q1-2025-6987661]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Adani-JKH Terminal At Colombo Port Likely To Be Operational From Q1 2025]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/adani-jkh-terminal-at-colombo-port-likely-to-be-operational-from-q1-2025-6987661]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 19:53:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The first cargo ship is likely to reach Sri Lanka's Adani-John Keells Holding (JKH) West Container Terminal (WCT) in Colombo Port in the first quarter of 2025, Srilankan news website The Morning Online reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first cargo ship is likely to reach Sri Lanka's Adani-John Keells Holding (JKH) West Container Terminal (WCT) in Colombo Port in the first quarter of 2025, Srilankan news website The Morning Online reported quoting JKH chairperson Krishan Balendra.</p>

<p>The vessel's arrival will add 1.5 million 20-foot equivalent units (TEUs) to the port capacity, Mr Balendra said.</p>

<p>The first phase of the WCT is likely to be operational in Q1 of 2025, which will add 1.5 million TEUs to the 8 million TEU capacity at Colombo Port, he said at the JKH investor webinar for Q2 of fiscal 2025.</p>

<p>The first batch of quay and yard cranes for WCT arrived in September, and the cranes' commissioning is expected to be completed by Q4 of 2024, he added.</p>

<p>The JKH quarterly report said the quay length in the first phase will enable simultaneous servicing of two large vessels, which will enable a higher throughput once the first phase is complete.</p>

<p>"The remainder of the terminal is expected to be completed by mid-2026," the report said.</p>

<p>Mr Balendra said the timeframe for operationalising the Sri Lanka Port Authority-run East Container Terminal (ECT) is unclear. Even if ECT becomes operational, only a part of the terminal will become operational, of which the capacity addition to the Colombo Port would not be material, he added.</p>

<p>The ECT project is expected to add a maximum of 2.4 million TEUs capacity to the Colombo Port once fully operationalised.</p><br />
<br />
<p><i>(Disclaimer: New Delhi Television is a subsidiary of AMG Media Networks Limited, an Adani Group Company.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mfpe23ag_colombo-port_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The first batch of quay and yard cranes for WCT arrived in September]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidias-jensen-huang-reveals-why-he-doesnt-wear-a-watch-i-dont-aspire-6987626]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Nvidia's Jensen Huang Reveals Why He Doesn't Wear A Watch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidias-jensen-huang-reveals-why-he-doesnt-wear-a-watch-i-dont-aspire-6987626]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 19:49:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Huang, whose company Nvidia has seen its valuation skyrocket in recent years, emphasized the value of living in the moment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang has a distinct approach to time and explained why he chooses not to wear a watch. Speaking at a tech event, Mr Huang, whose company Nvidia has seen its valuation skyrocket in recent years, emphasized the value of living in the present moment.</p>

<p>"Very few people know this, but I don't wear a watch. The reason I don't is that now is the most important time. You might be surprised, but I'm not particularly ambitious. I don't aspire to do more; I want to do better at what I'm currently doing. I'm not striving for more-I wait for the world to come to me. Those who know me are aware that Nvidia doesn't have a long-term strategy. We have no grand plan. Our definition of a long-term plan is simply: What are we doing today?"</p>

<p>An Instagram account, @entrepreneursonig, shared a video of Huang discussing his philosophy at the event, with the caption: "Doing more is easy; doing less is hard. Jensen Huang, CEO and co-founder of NVIDIA, shares how he and his company focus on the present, ultimately shaping their future."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCKmRBSqjTs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCKmRBSqjTs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCKmRBSqjTs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCKmRBSqjTs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Entrepreneurs On IG (@entrepreneursonig)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>In 2023, Huang shared a story from a conversation with a Japanese gardener, which shaped his perspective on the subject. The billionaire recounted meeting a gardener who "lovingly tended to a temple in Kyoto" and managed to maintain the garden's mossy perfection despite the heat, the garden's size, and his small tools. When asked how he did it, the gardener replied, "I have plenty of time."</p>

<p>Huang reflected, "This is the best career advice I can give: Now is the most important time-just focus on the present. I'm rarely chasing things... I'm focused on now. I'm enjoying my job."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1ui3qqfg_jensen-huang_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Huang discussed his philosophy at the event]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-sees-positive-signs-on-donald-trumps-position-on-ukraine-6987345]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Sees "Positive Signs" On Donald Trump's Position On Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-sees-positive-signs-on-donald-trumps-position-on-ukraine-6987345]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 18:51:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin said Sunday that it saw "positive signals" from US president-elect Donald Trump's position on Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin said Sunday that it saw "positive signals" from US president-elect Donald Trump's position on Ukraine, while warning it was hard to predict how he would behave in office.</p>

<p>"The signals are positive. Trump during his election talked about how he perceives everything through deals, that he can make a deal that can lead to peace," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said in an interview with state media published Sunday.</p>

<p>But Peskov said it was hard to predict "to what extent he's going to stick to statements that he made on the campaign trail".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/r4op1p3_trump-putin-trump-ians_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia warned it was hard to predict how Trump would behave in office.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-resumes-free-coffee-tea-to-boost-morale-after-laying-off-15-000-employees-6987304]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Intel Resumes Free Coffee And Tea To Boost Morale Amid Layoffs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-resumes-free-coffee-tea-to-boost-morale-after-laying-off-15-000-employees-6987304]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 18:46:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In August, it announced plans to reduce its workforce by 15,000 through voluntary separations and layoffs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Intel is set to resume free coffee and tea for employees following substantial layoffs as part of broader cost-cutting measures. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.oregonlive.com/silicon-forest/2024/11/intel-brings-back-workers-free-coffee-seeking-to-stem-declining-morale.html" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Oregonian</em></a>, the chip giant shared in an internal message that in-office beverages would return to boost employee morale.</p>

<p>"Although Intel still faces cost challenges, we understand that small comforts play a significant role in our daily routines," the message, seen by <em>The Oregonian</em>, stated. "We know this is a small step, but we hope it is a meaningful one in supporting our workplace culture."</p>

<p>However, free fruit, a perk employees had come to expect, will not be returning, the report noted.</p>

<p>Intel, once a leader in the tech industry, has faced several setbacks that have affected its position. While it played a major role in the PC boom of the 1990s, its focus on personal computers left it trailing in the mobile chip market, enabling Apple to take the lead with the iPhone.</p>

<p>In 2013, former Intel CEO Paul Otellini admitted to regretting his decision to pass on a deal with Apple to produce chips for the iPhone, as Intel had assumed the volume wouldn't justify the costs.</p>

<p>Another missed opportunity came in 2017 and 2018, when Intel declined to invest in OpenAI, now a front-runner in artificial intelligence. OpenAI had sought Intel's backing to reduce dependence on Nvidia's chips and create its own infrastructure. Former CEO Bob Swan reportedly doubted the market viability of generative AI models, contributing to Intel's decision to forgo the investment.</p>

<p>Intel has also faced delays in manufacturing, such as setbacks in 2020 with its 7-nanometer chips, which allowed competitors like Samsung and TSMC to pull ahead.</p>

<p>As its valuation dropped, Intel ramped up cost-cutting measures. In August, it announced plans to reduce its workforce by 15,000 through voluntary separations and layoffs. That month, the company shared a presentation detailing cuts to employee benefits, including reductions in reimbursements for internet, phone, and commuting costs.</p>

<p>In September, Intel informed employees in at least one Oregon office that free beverages and fruits would be discontinued.</p>

<p>"That's petty, right? How much does one piece of fruit per day cost?" a former Intel employee told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.businessinsider.in/tech/news/intel-says-its-bringing-back-free-office-coffee-to-boost-morale-after-a-rough-year/articleshow/115064835.cms" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Business Insider</em></a>.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rj3nfas_intel-reuters_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Intel, once a leader in the tech industry, has faced several setbacks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-kills-each-other-in-violent-fight-as-son-plays-video-game-in-another-room-6986951]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Couple Kills Each Other While Son Plays Video Game In Another Room]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-kills-each-other-in-violent-fight-as-son-plays-video-game-in-another-room-6986951]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 17:39:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident occurred on October 31 in Longview, Washington, about 50 miles north of Portland, Oregon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a tragic incident last week, a married couple in Washington State fatally wounded each other during a violent confrontation in their home while their 11-year-old son played video games in another room, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/09/us-news/parents-brutally-killed-each-other-as-son-11-played-video-games-in-another-room-officials/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to officials, the boy, wearing earbuds, was unaware of the argument unfolding on Halloween night as his parents fought in the home. He only realized what had happened when he later found their bodies.</p>

<p>The incident occurred on October 31 in Longview, Washington, about 50 miles north of Portland, Oregon. Investigators have been unable to determine which of the two was the primary aggressor, the media outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The victims, identified as Juan Antonio Alvarado Saenz, 38, and Cecilia Robles Ochoa, 39, both suffered fatal injuries. Police reported that Alvarado Saenz died from multiple stab wounds to the chest, while Robles Ochoa had both stab and gunshot wounds, according to the Cowlitz County Sheriff's Office.</p>

<p>After discovering his parents in the kitchen, the boy called 911. Emergency responders arrived but were unable to revive the couple. Authorities confirmed that the boy was the only other person present in the home at the time.</p>

<p>Detectives have since uncovered that Alvarado Saenz and Robles Ochoa had ongoing relationship issues and were planning to separate, according to statements from the sheriff's office.</p>

<p>A knife and a gun were recovered at the scene. The firearm was later confirmed to have been stolen from Alvarado Saenz's employer and had not been reported missing until after the incident.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1neck6oo_us-police-generic_625x300_30_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boy, wearing earbuds, was unaware of the fight unfolding on Halloween night]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-1-500-russian-troops-killed-or-injured-every-day-in-october-in-ukraine-uk-6986827]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1,500 Russian Troops Killed Or Injured Every Day In October In Ukraine: UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-1-500-russian-troops-killed-or-injured-every-day-in-october-in-ukraine-uk-6986827]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 17:15:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian troops recently suffered their worst month for casualties since the country's war with Ukraine began almost three years ago, the head of Britain's armed forces said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian troops recently suffered their worst month for casualties since the country's war with Ukraine began almost three years ago, the head of Britain's armed forces said on Sunday.</p>

<p>An average of around 1,500 Russian soldiers were killed or injured per day in October, UK Chief of the Defence Staff Tony Radakin told the BBC.</p>

<p>Russia does not reveal the number of its war dead, but Radakin said last month's toll was the heaviest since Moscow launched the full-scale invasion of its neighbour in February 2022.</p>

<p>"Russia is about to suffer 700,000 people killed or wounded -- the enormous pain and suffering that the Russian nation is having to bear because of (President Vladimir) Putin's ambition," he added.</p>

<p>The armed forces chief acknowledged that Russia was territorial making gains, but said the losses were "for tiny increments of land".</p>

<p>He said the Russian government was spending more than 40 per cent of public expenditure on defence and security, putting "an enormous strain" on the state.</p>

<p>The UK has been one of Ukraine's strongest backers in its fight against Russian aggression, providing Kyiv with billions of pounds in military aid, as well as weapons and troop training.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer has reiterated Britain's "ironclad" support for Ukraine, after Donald Trump's US presidential election win raised concerns about western countries' future commitment to backing Kyiv's war effort.</p>

<p>Radakin repeated that the UK would support Ukraine for "as long as it takes".</p>

<p>"That's the message President Putin has to absorb and the reassurance for (Ukrainian) President (Volodymyr) Zelensky," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-03/2mej6kl_russian-troops-reuters_625x300_02_March_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UK has been one of Ukraine's strongest backers. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-forces-capture-new-village-in-ukraines-donetsk-amid-raging-war-6986600]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Forces Capture New Village In Ukraine's Donetsk Amid Raging War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-forces-capture-new-village-in-ukraines-donetsk-amid-raging-war-6986600]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 16:39:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Russian defence ministry said Sunday that its forces had captured a new village in Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Russian defence ministry said Sunday that its forces had captured a new village in Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region where the army has been making advances in recent weeks.</p>

<p>"Units of the Centre armed group have liberated the town of Voltchenka," the ministry said, using the Russian spelling of the Ukraine village Vovchenko, around five kilometres (three miles) from the industrial city of Kurakhove.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/50a9boq_donetsk-ukraine_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian army has been making advances in the region since recent weeks. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violence-outside-sheikh-hasina-party-office-after-rally-call-dhaka-tense-6986068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Violence Outside Sheikh Hasina Party Office After Rally Call, Dhaka Tense]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violence-outside-sheikh-hasina-party-office-after-rally-call-dhaka-tense-6986068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 15:43:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's capital Dhaka remains tense on Sunday as several Awami League supporters were reportedly beaten following the party's decision to hold a protest march at Shaheed Noor Hossain Square in commemoration of Noor Hossain Day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's capital Dhaka remains tense on Sunday as several Awami League supporters were reportedly beaten following the party's decision to hold a protest march at Shaheed Noor Hossain Square in commemoration of Noor Hossain Day.</p>

<p>The incident took place in front of Sheikh Hasina's party's central office on Bangabandhu Avenue, local media reported.</p>

<p>A political activist and leader of Awami League's youth front, the Jubo League, Noor Hossain was killed on November 10, 1987 during the anti-Ershad movement.</p>

<p>The Awami League's announcement to hold a rally on Sunday afternoon to mark the occasion was its first significant decision since the government led by former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina was brought down by an uprising on August 5.</p>

<p>In a social media post, the party invited common people and activists, who believe in the "values of the Liberation War and democratic principles", to join the march at Noor Hossain Chattar (Zero Point). It also called for removal of anti-democratic forces and the reestablishment of democratic governance under the leadership of the Bangladesh Awami League.</p>

<p>Immediately after the announcement, Bangladesh's interim government led by Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus made it clear that it will not grant permission to hold the protest rally.</p>

<p>"The Awami League in its current form is a fascist party. There is no way this fascist party will be allowed to hold protests in Bangladesh," said Yunus' Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam.</p>

<p>The anti-discrimination student movement is also holding a counter-gathering at the same venue, demanding trial of the Awami League leaders.</p>

<p>Anticipating violence, the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) said that 191 platoons of the border security forces have been deployed in the country's capital and across the country to maintain law and order on Noor Hossain Day.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3t9m083o_bangladesh-violence_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>