<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 03:46:08 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-destroys-1-000-hezbollah-rocket-launcher-barrels-says-military-6605651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Destroys 1,000 Hezbollah Rocket Launcher Barrels, Says Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-destroys-1-000-hezbollah-rocket-launcher-barrels-says-military-6605651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 03:46:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli fighter jets pounded Hezbollah targets in southern Lebanon late on Thursday, striking hundreds of rocket launcher barrels that were set to be used to immediately fire toward Israeli territory, the military said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Israeli fighter jets pounded Hezbollah targets in southern Lebanon late on Thursday, striking hundreds of rocket launcher barrels that were set to be used to immediately fire toward Israeli territory, the military said.</p>

<p>It said that since the afternoon, fighter jets struck some 100 rocket launchers consisting of about 1,000 barrels.</p>

<p>"The IDF (Israel Defense Forces) will continue to operate to degrade the Hezbollah terrorist organization's infrastructure and capabilities in order to defend the State of Israel," the IDF said.</p>

<p>The intense barrage followed attacks earlier in the week attributed by Lebanon and Hezbollah to Israel that blew up Hezbollah radios and pagers, killing 37 people and wounding about 3,000 in Lebanon.</p>

<p>In Thursday's late operation, Israel launched dozens of bombs across southern Lebanon, three Lebanese security sources said. There were no immediate reports of casualties.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said that Israel will keep up military action against Hezbollah.</p>

<p>British Foreign Secretary David Lammy called for an immediate ceasefire between Israel and Lebanon's Hezbollah after a week of escalation. The U.S. has also expressed fears of further escalation.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed to return tens of thousands of residents evacuated from northern border areas to their homes. Hezbollah</p>

<p>In a show of support with Hamas after the Oct. 7 attacks, Iran-backed Hezbollah began firing rockets into northern Israel, forcing many residents to flee to the center of the country. Israel and Hezbollah have been trading fire daily since.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/g7dminco_yoav-gallant-_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said that Israel will keep up military action against Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airlines-suspend-flights-as-middle-east-tensions-rise-6605511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Airlines Suspend Flights As Middle East Tensions Rise]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airlines-suspend-flights-as-middle-east-tensions-rise-6605511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 02:51:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Concerns over a wider conflict in the Middle East have prompted international airlines to suspend flights to the region or to avoid affected air space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Concerns over a wider conflict in the Middle East have prompted international airlines to suspend flights to the region or to avoid affected air space.</p>

<p>Below are some of the airlines that have adjusted services to and from the region:</p>

<p><strong>AIR ALGERIE</strong></p>

<p>The Algerian airline suspended flights to and from Lebanon until further notice.</p>

<p><strong>AIRBALTIC</strong></p>

<p>Latvia's airBaltic plans to resume flights between Riga and Tel Aviv on Sept. 17, it said via email on Sept. 16.</p>

<p><strong>AIR FRANCE-KLM</strong></p>

<p>Air France said on Sept. 17 it was suspending services to Beirut and Tel Aviv up to and including Sept. 19.</p>

<p>KLM cancelled all flights to and from Tel Aviv until Oct. 26. The Franco-Dutch group's low-cost unit Transavia cancelled flights to and from Tel Aviv until March 31, 2025, and flights to Amman and Beirut until Nov. 3.</p>

<p><strong>AIR INDIA</strong></p>

<p>The Indian flag carrier suspended scheduled flights to and from Tel Aviv until further notice.</p>

<p><strong>CATHAY PACIFIC</strong></p>

<p>Hong Kong-based Cathay Pacific cancelled all flights to Tel Aviv until March 27, 2025.</p>

<p><strong>DELTA AIR LINES</strong></p>

<p>The U.S. carrier said it will pause its flights between New York and Tel Aviv through Dec. 31.</p>

<p><strong>EASYJET</strong></p>

<p>The UK budget airline stopped flying to and from Tel Aviv in April and will resume flights on March 30, 2025, a spokesperson said.</p>

<p>IAG</p>

<p>IAG-owned Spanish low-cost carrier Vueling cancelled its operations to Tel Aviv until Jan. 12, 2025, it said in an e-mailed comment. Flights to Amman have been cancelled until further notice, the airline added.</p>

<p>LOT</p>

<p>The Polish flag carrier suspended flights to Lebanon until further notice, while flights to Tel Aviv are now operating regularly, it said in an emailed comment on Sept. 10.</p>

<p><strong>LUFTHANSA GROUP</strong></p>

<p>The German airline group said on Sept. 17 it was suspending all connections to and from Tel Aviv and Tehran up to and including Sept. 19. The airline had resumed flights to Tel Aviv on Sept. 5, while flights to Beirut will remain suspended through Sept. 30.</p>

<p>Swiss International Air Lines, also a part of the Lufthansa Group, separately said it had suspended flights to Beirut until the end of October.</p>

<p><strong>RYANAIR</strong></p>

<p>Europe's biggest budget airline cancelled flights to and from Tel Aviv until Oct. 26, citing "operational restrictions."</p>

<p><strong>SUNDAIR</strong></p>

<p>The German airline cancelled all flights between Bremen and Beirut until Oct. 23.</p>

<p><strong>SUNEXPRESS</strong></p>

<p>SunExpress, a joint venture between Turkish Airlines and Lufthansa, suspended flights to Beirut through Dec. 17.</p>

<p><strong>UNITED AIRLINES</strong></p>

<p>The Chicago-based airline suspended flights to Tel Aviv for the foreseeable future due to security reasons.</p>

<p><strong>LEBANESE AIRSPACE ALERTS</strong></p>

<p>Britain advised UK airlines not to enter Lebanese airspace from Aug. 8 until Nov. 4 citing "potential risk to aviation from military activity".</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/t1hcc7rg_airplane-generic_625x300_21_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Algerian airline suspended flights to and from Lebanon until further notice.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-2024-key-candidates-ranil-wickremesinghe-sajith-premadasa-anura-kumara-dissanayake-namal-rajapaksa-nuwan-bopage-6605432]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Elections: A Look At The 5 Key Candidates And What They Stand For]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-2024-key-candidates-ranil-wickremesinghe-sajith-premadasa-anura-kumara-dissanayake-namal-rajapaksa-nuwan-bopage-6605432]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 02:23:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka, which is slowly recovering from its worst-ever economic crisis, will vote to elect the next President on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka, which is slowly recovering from its worst-ever economic crisis, will vote to elect the next President on Saturday. The cash-strapped island nation is currently being led by President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who is seeking a re-election to continue with bold reforms to help revive the economy.</p>

<p>President Ranil Wickremesinghe, 75, is seeking a fresh mandate after claiming credit for stabilising the economy and bringing an end to months of food, fuel and medicine shortages.</p>

<p>In 2022, when Ranil Wickremesinghe took charge as President, Sri Lanka was dealing with civil unrest spurred by the economic crisis. There were protests across the nation which led to thousands storming the Presidential palace which was then occupied by Mr Wickremesinghe's predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who fled the country. Mr Wickremesinghe took charge and restored calm and helped revived the economy by taking some tough decisions.</p>

<p>The 2024 election is key to deciding the future of reforms in the economically fragile nation.</p>

<p>Speaking with NDTV, Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe said on Thursday that his vision for future ties with India holds a stronger economic relationship. "We want to encourage more investments from India and more tourists from India. We are working together with India on infrastructure projects like the Trincomalee Harbour," he said.</p>

<p>"I took over as President when the country was in utter chaos and no one thought we could stabilise this fast. But I knew from experience that we could go ahead provided we had the support of the International Monetary Fund and our creditors," the President said, adding that "I have ensured we come back to normalcy. Law and order is functioning, democracy is functioning and although we have stabilised the economy, now we have to decide our path. Are we going to get into the same old ways or are we working towards (building) a strong export economy? I have asked for a mandate to go ahead."</p>

<p>However, Mr Wickremesinghe faces a tough electoral battle from two contenders. In total, President Wickremesinghe is among 38 candidates contesting Sri Lanka's presidential election.</p>

<p>This year's election is dominated by two major alliances, the SJB (Samagi Jana Balawegaya) and the NPP (National People's Power), apart from various smaller parties and independent candidates.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the 5 main contenders in the 2024 Sri Lanka Elections:</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>RANIL WICKREMESINGHE</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/092fhub8_ranil-wickremesinghe-afp-650_625x300_13_July_22.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>75-year-old Ranil Wickremesinghe is a lawyer who has served as prime minister for a record six times. His party holds only one seat in parliament and will need to drum up support from key parties to bolster his chances.</p>

<p>As the leader of the United National Party or UNP, he took office in July 2022 after widespread protests unleashed by the debilitating financial crisis forced his predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa to flee Sri Lanka and later resign.</p>

<p>The Sri Lankan Parliament elected Ranil Wickremesinghe to serve out the rest of the five-year term of Mr Rajapaksa, who took office in 2019.</p>

<p>Ranil Wickremesinghe's re-election bid failed to get formal backing from the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), the party with the most seats in the 225-member parliament, but the support of more than 90 lawmakers puts him in strong position. He is contesting as an independent candidate.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>SAJITH PREMADASA</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1vco5cjs_sajith-premadasa_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The 57 year-old Opposition leader and son of former President Ranasinghe Premadasa, he leads the Samagi Jana Balawegaya or SJB that separated from Mr Wickremesinghe's UNP in 2020.</p>

<p>His centrist, more left-leaning party has called for changes to the $2.9 billion bailout programme with the International Monetary Fund and outlined plans to adjust some targets, such as changing taxes to reduce the cost of living.</p>

<p>Premadasa favours a mix of interventionist and free-market economic policies.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>ANURA KUMARA DISSANAYAKE</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vu6mofi4_anura-kumara-dissanayake_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The 55-year-old leader, who holds just three seats in parliament, stands for tough anti-corruption measures and pro-poor policies have given a popular boost to his candidacy.</p>

<p>He will contest under the National People's Power or NPP coalition, which includes his Marxist-leaning party People's Liberation Front or PLF. His party has traditionally backed stronger state intervention and more closed market economic policies.</p>

<p>A pre-election opinion survey showed Mr Dissanayake was leading in voting preferences at 36%, followed by Mr Premadasa and Mr Wickremesinghe at third.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>NAMAL RAJAPAKSA</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o1meeqe8_namal-rajapaksa_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The 38-year-old leader is a scion of the powerful Rajapaksa family that produced two presidents - his father Mahinda and uncle Gotabaya - Namal is a surprise entrant, as the candidate of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna or SLPP, founded by another uncle, Basil.</p>

<p>He faces the daunting task of keeping the party unified to counter Mr Wickremesinghe's chances of winning.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<h3><strong>NUWAN BOPAGE</strong></h3>
	</li>
</ul>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k6podgso_nuwan-bopage_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>40-year-old Nuwan Bopage is the presidential candidate of the Peoples' Struggle Alliance or PSA. He hopes to tap into the remnants of the massive people's uprising that deposed Gotabaya Rajapaksa two years ago.</p>

<p>He has taken a strong anti-corruption stance, backs more pro-poor policies and opposes Sri Lanka's alignment with the IMF programme.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sj6lisg4_ranil-wickremesinghe-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Supporters of Sri Lanka's president Ranil Wickremesinghe attend his final election campaign rally.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-believes-diplomatic-solution-to-israel-hezbollah-conflict-achievable-6605278]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Diplomatic Solution To Israel-Hezbollah Conflict "Achievable": Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-believes-diplomatic-solution-to-israel-hezbollah-conflict-achievable-6605278]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 01:36:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden believes there can still be a diplomatic resolution to escalating tensions between Israel and Hezbollah following a series of pager and walkie-talkie bombings, his spokeswoman said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden believes there can still be a diplomatic resolution to escalating tensions between Israel and Hezbollah following a series of pager and walkie-talkie bombings, his spokeswoman said Thursday.</p>

<p>"He believes it's achievable," Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre told a briefing. "The president continues to believe that we have to be optimistic and a diplomatic resolution is the best way."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/81g72018_joe-biden_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden believes there can still be a diplomatic resolution between Israel and Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-votes-for-new-president-on-saturday-all-you-need-to-know-6604947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Votes For New President On Saturday. All You Need To Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-votes-for-new-president-on-saturday-all-you-need-to-know-6604947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:02:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The people of Sri Lanka are set to vote for a new president on Saturday in an election that will be key in deciding the future reforms in the country that is reeling under an unprecedented economic crisis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The people of Sri Lanka are set to vote for a new president on Saturday in an election that will be key in deciding the future reforms in the country that is reeling under an unprecedented economic crisis.&nbsp;</p>

<p>More than 17 million Sri Lankans are eligible to vote for their next president, who will serve a five-year term.</p>

<h3><strong>Who all are nominated?</strong></h3>

<p>The Sri Lankan elections panel approved the nominations of 39 candidates, including the incumbent President Ranil Wickremesinghe. One candidate died later. Among the frontrunners are Anura Kumara Dissanayaka, leader of the National People's Power party, and leader of opposition Sajith Premadasa from the Samagi Jana Balawegaya party.</p>

<h3><strong>How did the candidates campaign?</strong></h3>

<p>The current president, Mr Wickremesinghe, held his first rally on August 17 in the historic city of Anuradhapura. It was the first out of nearly a 100 of his rallies. His key rivals also held about a dozen rallies each.</p>

<p>The campaigning ended at midnight on Wednesday, 48 hours before election day.</p>

<h3><strong>What is the election process?</strong></h3>

<p>Sri Lanka follows the first-past-the-post system, allowing voters to choose three candidates. The candidate securing at least 50% or more of the overall vote is declared the winner.</p>

<p>In case no candidate gets 50% votes in the first round, there is a legal provision for a run-off between the two frontrunners. Given the close race, Sri Lanka could see a second count for the first time in four decades since the introduction of the voting system.</p>

<h3><strong>How will the votes be counted?</strong></h3>

<p>Sri Lankans will cast their votes at thousands of polling stations amid tight security. Government employees will count them afterwards under the supervision of Election Commission officials, election monitors and representatives of candidates.</p>

<p>Voting will begin at 7 AM local time and end at 4 PM. Counting will start shortly after.</p>

<h3><strong>When will the results be declared?</strong></h3>

<p>The winner will formally be announced by the Election Commission, probably on Sunday. The oath taking ceremony usually takes place on the same day.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nh2g8u68_sri-lanka-elections-reuters_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The campaigning ended at midnight on Wednesday, 48 hours before election day.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/workers-at-musks-tesla-spacex-and-x-donate-to-harris-while-he-backs-trump-6604944]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Workers At Musk's Tesla, SpaceX And X Donate To Harris While He Backs Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/workers-at-musks-tesla-spacex-and-x-donate-to-harris-while-he-backs-trump-6604944]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:01:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has endorsed Republican former President Donald Trump in the race for the White House, but employees at his collection of companies are largely donating to Trump's Democratic rival Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has endorsed Republican former President Donald Trump in the race for the White House, but employees at his collection of companies are largely donating to Trump's Democratic rival Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Workers at Tesla have contributed $42,824 to Harris' presidential campaign versus $24,840 to Trump's campaign, according to OpenSecrets, a nonpartisan nonprofit that tracks US campaign contributions and lobbying data.</p>

<p>Employees at Elon Musk's rocket company SpaceX have donated $34,526 to Harris versus $7,652 to Trump. Employees at the social media platform X, formerly known as Twitter, have donated $13,213 to Harris versus less than $500 to Trump.</p>

<p>While the figures are relatively small for campaign fundraising, they indicate political leanings at odds with Elon Musk's own. The world's richest man, Elon Musk has boosted Trump on X and dismissed left-leaning ideas as a "woke-mind virus."</p>

<p>Elon Musk did not immediately respond to a request for comment. He backed President Joe Biden in 2020 but has tacked rightward since then. Trump has said that if he wins the Nov. 5 election, he will appoint Elon Musk to lead a government efficiency commission.</p>

<p>The OpenSecrets data includes donations from company employees and owners and those individuals' immediate family members. Campaign finance laws prohibit companies themselves from donating to federal campaigns.</p>

<p>Many of Elon Musk's employees are based in California, a Democratic stronghold, said Ross Gerber, CEO of Gerber Kawasaki Wealth and Investment Management, which is a Tesla shareholder. Gerber is also an investor in X.</p>

<p>In July, Elon Musk said he would move X and SpaceX headquarters to Texas from California because of a California gender-identity law he called the "last straw." Gerber said such a move would mean "losing out on a lot of potential talent" in California.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nvneif7g_elon-musk_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In July, Elon Musk said he would move X and SpaceX headquarters to Texas from California (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sincere-gratitude-maldives-as-india-extends-50-million-budgetary-support-6604888]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Sends "Crucial Budgetary Support" To Maldives Amid Strained Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sincere-gratitude-maldives-as-india-extends-50-million-budgetary-support-6604888]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:55:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a goodwill gesture, India on Thursday said it has decided to rollover a USD 50 million Treasury Bill for an additional year upon the request of the Maldives government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a goodwill gesture, India on Thursday said it has decided to rollover a USD 50 million Treasury Bill for an additional year upon the request of the Maldives government.</p>

<p>"At the request of the Government of Maldives, the State Bank of India (SBI) has subscribed the USD 50 mn Government Treasury Bill (T-bills) issued by the Ministry of Finance of Maldives, for a period of one more year from the date of maturity of the previous subscription, September 19, 2024," the High Commission of India in Maldives said in a press release.</p>

<p>SBI bought the Treasury Bill under an agreement signed by the previous government. SBI has bought a total of USD 200 million in Treasury Bills for USD 50 million for each one, the Adhadhu news portal reported.</p>

<p>The Treasury Bills were previously rolled over annually with interest paid by the Indian government. However, the government of President Mohamed Muizzu repaid USD 50 million in January this year, it said.</p>

<p>Maldives had requested the Indian government to extend the deadline for repayment of the remaining USD 150 million. India agreed to rollover USD 50 million in May and a second USD 50 million payment was due today.</p>

<p>"Sincere gratitude to External Affairs Minister @DrSJaishankar and the Government of #India for extending crucial budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of USD 50 million Treasury Bill. This generous gesture reflects the enduring bonds of friendship between #Maldives and #India," Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer said in a post on X on Thursday.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sincere gratitude to External Affairs Minister <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DrSJaishankar</a> and the Government of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/India?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#India</a> for extending crucial budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of USD 50 million Treasury Bill.<br />
<br />
This generous gesture reflects the enduring bonds of friendship between…</p>
— Moosa Zameer (@MoosaZameer) <a href="https://twitter.com/MoosaZameer/status/1836768732972224735?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Earlier in May 2024, the SBI had similarly subscribed a USD 50 mn T-bills under the same mechanism, again on the request of the Government of Maldives.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Foreign Ministry Thursday thanked the "generous support that the Government of India has been providing to the Maldives in the form of budgetary support." "This extension comes at a pivotal moment as the Government of Maldives is implementing a strong fiscal consolidation program to address the pressing economic challenges," the ministry said.</p>

<p>The development comes days after Foreign Minister Zameer acknowledged that the Maldives-India ties witnessed rough patches in the initial days of President Mohamed Muizzu-led government but insisted that the two countries have resolved the "misunderstandings".</p>

<p>India's relationship with the Maldives came under strain since Mohamed Muizzu, known for his pro-China leanings, took charge as the President. Within hours of his oath, he had demanded the withdrawal of Indian military personnel manning three aviation platforms gifted by India to the Maldives. After talks between the two sides, the Indian military personnel were replaced by civilians.</p>

<p>Unlike his predecessors, who made the first port of call to New Delhi after assuming office, Mohamed Muizzu travelled to Turkiye first and to China for his first state visit in January. He visited New Delhi on June 9 to attend Prime Minister Modi's swearing-in ceremony.</p>

<p>Mohamed Muizzu will travel to India on an official visit "very soon", his spokesperson said last week.</p>

<p>The Maldivian government is also working to defer repayment of loans taken from other countries including China.</p>

<p>The Maldives owes much of its external debt to China and India. The government's debt servicing commitments amount to USD 409 million this year, placing additional stress on its already limited foreign currency reserves.</p>

<p>Maldives reserves currently stand at USD 444 million, with usable reserves at USD 61 million.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/fgprr38_s-jaishankar-moosa-zameer_625x300_13_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mohamed Muizzu will travel to India on an official visit "very soon", his spokesperson said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-year-old-japanese-schoolboy-stabbed-to-death-in-china-6604881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10-Year-Old Japanese Schoolboy Stabbed To Death In China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-year-old-japanese-schoolboy-stabbed-to-death-in-china-6604881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:55:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A child enrolled in a Japanese school in the Chinese city of Shenzhen has died after being stabbed on Wednesday, officials confirmed on Thursday, the second such attack near Japanese educational centres in China in recent months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A child enrolled in a Japanese school in the Chinese city of Shenzhen has died after being stabbed on Wednesday, officials confirmed on Thursday, the second such attack near Japanese educational centres in China in recent months.</p>

<p>Chinese authorities said the 10-year-old boy was a Japanese national born to a Japanese father and a Chinese mother, and he had been stabbed on his way to school at about 8 a.m. (0000 GMT) on Wednesday by a 44-year-old assailant surnamed Zhong.</p>

<p>He died in the early hours of Thursday, Japanese foreign minister Yoko Kamikawa told reporters in Tokyo.</p>

<p>"Medical experts made every effort to save his life, and the Chinese side will provide the necessary assistance to his family to take care of his affairs," Lin Jian, a Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson, told a regular news conference in Beijing.</p>

<p>"According to the information currently available, this is an individual case and such incidents could occur in any country," he added.</p>

<p>On Thursday afternoon, people laid wreaths at the gates of the school in Shenzhen's affluent Shekou area, which is home to most of the city's foreign community and international schools.</p>

<p>"As Chinese people, we oppose this behaviour, we oppose teachings of hatred," said one man who identified himself as an ordinary Shenzhen resident.</p>

<p>"Many of us have been under such teachings of hate for a long time, leading to such evil consequences," he added.</p>

<p>The attack took place on the anniversary of an incident in 1931 that triggered war between China and Japan, a sensitive date at a time when diplomatic relations are in danger of deteriorating.</p>

<p>"I actually did not know 18th September was this day for Chinese people to take revenge for things in the Second World War," said a Japanese father of two children in Shenzhen, who asked to only be identified by his surname, Suzuki, out of safety concerns.</p>

<p>"I have lived here for seven years and did not know we need to be cautious for being Japanese while living in China."</p>

<p>Japan has asked China to provide a detailed explanation of the facts and to take strong safety measures, Kamikawa told reporters earlier in the day.</p>

<p>"I take the incident extremely seriously," she added.</p>

<p>"This should never happen in any country. Particularly, I sincerely regret that this despicable act was committed against a child on their way to school."</p>

<p>The local Japanese chamber of commerce has asked the Japanese government to ensure the safety of its nationals in the area, the organisation said in a statement.</p>

<p>It was the second such attack near a Japanese educational facility in China in recent months. In June, a man attacked a bus used by a Japanese school in the eastern city of Suzhou, resulting in the death of a Chinese national who tried to shield a Japanese mother and her child from the assailant.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3fr947h_china-stabbing_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boy died in the early hours of Thursday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-partys-student-leader-beaten-to-death-on-campus-6604862]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's Party's Student Leader Beaten To Death On Campus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-partys-student-leader-beaten-to-death-on-campus-6604862]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:50:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Bangladeshi student leader was beaten to death at his university campus in an apparent reprisal for attacks on protesters during the uprising that ousted ex-premier Sheikh Hasina last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Bangladeshi student leader was beaten to death at his university campus in an apparent reprisal for attacks on protesters during the uprising that ousted ex-premier Sheikh Hasina last month.</p>

<p>Shamim Ahmed was enrolled at Jahangirnagar University in the capital Dhaka, and was a top member of the student wing of Sheikh Hasina's Awami League party, police officer Abu Bakkar told AFP.</p>

<p>Bakkar said Ahmed was beaten by unknown assailants on Wednesday night for leading an attack on student demonstrators at the campus in mid-July, when protests demanding Sheikh Hasina's removal from office were gaining momentum.</p>

<p>"We took him to the Gonoshasthaya Hospital, where he later died," the officer added.</p>

<p>Staff at the hospital confirmed to AFP that Ahmed had died after being brought in with multiple injuries.</p>

<p>Ahmed is at least the second leader of the Awami League's student wing to be killed this month.</p>

<p>Fellow leader Abdullah Al Masud died hours after being beaten by a mob in the northern city of Rajshahi on September 8, according to local media reports.</p>

<p>He had also been accused of marshalling counter-demonstrations against the student-led uprising against Sheikh Hasina, who fled the country in early August moments before protesters stormed her Dhaka palace.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina's government was accused of widespread abuses, including the mass detention and extrajudicial killing of political rivals.</p>

<p>More than 450 people were killed in the weeks of violence leading up to the autocratic leader's toppling.</p>

<p>Since her departure for exile in neighbouring India, cabinet ministers and other senior members of Sheikh Hasina's party have been arrested, and her government's appointees have been purged from courts and the central bank.</p>

<p>At least 25 journalists seen as close to Sheikh Hasina's regime have also been taken into custody since her ouster and replacement with an interim government led by Nobel Peace Prize laureate Mohammed Yunus.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/v92affb_jahangirnagar-university_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shamim Ahmed was enrolled at Jahangirnagar University in Dhaka (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modis-us-visit-ukraine-war-israels-offensive-in-gaza-on-agenda-6604834]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi's US Visit: Ukraine War, Israel's Offensive In Gaza On Agenda]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modis-us-visit-ukraine-war-israels-offensive-in-gaza-on-agenda-6604834]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:46:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New initiatives to boost cooperation to ensure stability in the Indo-Pacific, ways to find peaceful solutions to the conflicts in Ukraine and Gaza and addressing concerns of the global South will be the focus of PM Modi's three-day US visit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New initiatives to boost cooperation to ensure stability in the Indo-Pacific, ways to find peaceful solutions to the conflicts in Ukraine and Gaza and addressing concerns of the global South will be the focus of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's three-day visit to the US beginning Saturday.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi will attend the annual Quad summit at Wilmington in Delaware, address the Summit of the Future at the UN General Assembly in New York, hold a roundtable with CEOs of top American firms working in the technology sector and hold bilateral talks with US President Joe Biden and several other global leaders.</p>

<p>The prime minister's first destination will be Wilmington, the hometown of Biden where he will join the US president, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and his Japanese counterpart Fumio Kishida at the Quad summit on September 21.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi will hold separate bilateral talks with all three Quad leaders.</p>

<p>The Quad summit is expected to discuss ways to expand cooperation among the member nations to ensure peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific besides deliberating on the conflicts in Gaza and Ukraine.</p>

<p>"We expect new initiatives to be announced," Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said.</p>

<p>The Quad leaders will unveil a "milestone" initiative to prevent, detect, treat and alleviate the impact of cancer on patients and their families.</p>

<p>Mr Misri said there will be a strong focus on peace, progress and stability in the Indo-Pacific at the Quad summit, adding the leaders will discuss health security, climate change, emerging technologies, infrastructure, connectivity, counterterrorism and humanitarian assistance.</p>

<p>To a question on India's possible role as a peace-maker to resolve the Ukraine conflict, Mr Misri told a media briefing that New Delhi is involved in a set of several conversations with important partners and leaders on it.</p>

<p>"We are involved in a set of several conversations with several important partners and leaders at this point. These conversations are a work in progress and we will update you on the results of this conversation at the right time," he said.</p>

<p>"At the present moment, we remain engaged with our interlocutors on these very important issues," Mr Misri said.</p>

<p>From Wilmington, Prime Minister Modi will travel to New York to attend an Indian community event at Long Island on September 22 and address the Summit of the Future at the UN General Assembly the next day. In New York, The prime minister will also attend a roundtable with CEOs of American firms working in areas of AI, quantum computing and semiconductors.</p>

<p>Asked whether Prime Minister Modi will put forward any proposal at the Summit of the Future to bring peace to Ukraine, Misri did not give a direct reply.</p>

<p>"As you know, the prime minister recently visited Russia and Ukraine, and after those visits, he also held discussions with leaders, including President Biden and President (Vladimir) Putin.</p>

<p>"Our National Security Advisor also had discussions with President Putin during his visit to Russia. So, I can only say at this point that these talks are ongoing between the leaders," Mr Misri said.</p>

<p>"As for putting forward any proposal, we'll have to see how much consensus is reached and whether we can reach a stage where a proposal can be put before a larger audience. So, I think we need to wait a little, and at the right time, we will be able to update you on this," he added.</p>

<p>Asked about India's priorities at the Summit of the Future, Mr Misri said a host of issues including concerns of the Global South are expected to figure.</p>

<p>"I won't be able to preview or pre-empt the prime minister's remarks at this very important event. But I would underline that the summit is being held at a time of conflict, tensions and divisions in the world," he said.</p>

<p>"There is an obvious deficit of development in the world at large and the Global South is at the risk of being left behind on account of current developments," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Misri said the world is also "playing catch-up" in so far as the fulfilment of the very important Sustainable Development Goals is concerned.</p>

<p>"There are a host of issues related to climate, to education, to youth, gender, energy, infrastructure and the digital divide. So I would imagine that the prime minister's message and India's message will take many of these issues into consideration and highlight India's approaches on all of these issues," he said.</p>

<p>The 'Summit of the Future' will bring leaders from various countries to forge a new international consensus on how to deliver a "better present and safeguard the future", according to the UN. On the conflict in Gaza, Mr Misri reiterated India's long-held position.</p>

<p>"We have always stood for a ceasefire in so far as the immediate events are concerned, the need to ensure a humanitarian corridor and the delivery of humanitarian aid in Gaza, and for the immediate release of the hostages so that we can work towards a more sustainable and broad-based settlement in the area," he said.</p>

<p>"Our long-term approach towards this issue has also long been clear. We are in favour of a two-state solution, States of Israel and Palestine living at peace with each other within stable borders and secure borders for both of them," he added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/87lertu8_pm-modi_625x300_16_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Modi will hold separate bilateral talks with all three Quad leaders.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/china-india-are-not-competitors-but-cooperators-says-chinese-envoy-6604833]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["China, India Are Not Competitors But Cooperators," Says Chinese Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/china-india-are-not-competitors-but-cooperators-says-chinese-envoy-6604833]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:46:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's Ambassador to India Xu Feihong said on Thursday that President Xi Jinping and PM Modi have reached many important consensus which means that the two countries are not competitors but co-operators and are development partners, not threats.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Noting that China and India are the two biggest developing countries in the world and both have the responsibility of improving the livelihood of people, China's Ambassador to India Xu Feihong said on Thursday that President Xi Jinping and PM Modi have reached many important consensus which means that the two countries are not competitors but co-operators and are development partners, not threats.</p>

<p>"China and India are the two biggest and developing countries in the world. Both of us have the important responsibilities of developing the economy and improving the livelihood of people. China is determined to build itself into a great modern socialist country by the middle of this century and India has a vision of Vikasit Bharat by 2047... For a long time, China and India had a very close cooperation - in 1950s, China and India put forth the five principles of peaceful coexistence, which have become basic norms of international relations and also fundamental principles of international law, which have made historical contributions for greater cause of human progress," Xu Feihong told reporters.</p>

<p>"In the new era, President Xi Jinping and PM Modi have reached many important consensus - that means China and India are not competitors but cooperators. We are developmental partners, not threats. This consensus provides guidelines for our bilateral relations... We have enough wisdom and capabilities for the right path and to get along with each other," he added.</p>

<p>Earlier, speaking at an event here, the Chinese Ambassador said that India is implementing initiatives such as "Atmanirbhar Bharat (Self-Reliant India)" and "Make in India" and is committed to becoming a global manufacturing hub.</p>

<p>"China is advancing Chinese modernization on all fronts and promoting high-standard opening up, which will provide new cooperation opportunities to all countries including India. We are willing to strengthen exchanges of modernization experience with India, jointly make the cake of cooperation bigger, and better benefit the two countries and two peoples. The economic and trade structures of China and India are highly complementary. We welcome more Indian commodities to enter the Chinese market, and more Indian enterprises to invest in China. It is hoped that the Indian side could provide a sound business environment for the Chinese enterprises in India. The foundation of China-India people-to-people friendship is profound," he said.</p>

<p>The Chinese envoy said that since 1990s, India has actively promoted economic and social reforms.</p>

<p>"Under the leadership of Prime Minister Modi, the Indian government put forward the policy of 'Reform, Perform and Transform', and India's economy maintains rapid development and people's living standards improve continuously. I would congratulate on the achievements India has made through reforms. Only China and India can understand how many efforts should be made to promote reform in a country with a population of 1.4 billion. We are willing to enhance experience-sharing on reforms with the Indian side, synergize our development strategies, learn from each other's strengths and make progress together," he said.</p>

<p>Xu Feihong said that at the conference marking the 70th anniversary of the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence, President Xi Jinping reiterated that China's resolve to stay on the path of peaceful development will not change.</p>

<p>"The leaders of China and India reached important consensuses such as 'China and India are partners rather than rivals, and are not threats to each other but opportunities for each other's development'. They not only point out the direction for the development of bilateral relations but also provide important guidelines for the two countries to promote modernization," he said.</p>

<p>The Chinese envoy said that at present, China-India relations are at a crucial stage of improvement and development.</p>

<p>"Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with Indian External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar twice in the past two months and met with Indian National Security Advisor Mr Ajit Doval a few days ago. They had in-depth communication and reached an important consensus on the improvement of bilateral relations," he said.</p>

<p>India and China held the 31st meeting of the Working Mechanism for Consultation &amp; Coordination on India-China Border Affairs (WMCC) on August 29 in Beijing.</p>

<p>The two sides had a frank, constructive and forward-looking exchange of views on the situation along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) to narrow down the differences and find early resolution of the outstanding issues and they agreed for intensified contact through diplomatic and military channels.</p>

<p>The two sides decided to jointly uphold peace and tranquillity on the ground in border areas in accordance with relevant bilateral agreements, protocols and understandings reached between the two Governments.</p>

<p>It was reiterated that restoration of peace and tranquility, and respect for LAC are the essential basis for restoration of normalcy in bilateral relations.</p>

<p>During an interaction in Geneva recently, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar had said that 75 per cent of disengagement problems with Beijing had been sorted out and the two nations "still have some things to do."</p>

<p>Jaishankar also underlined how India and China never had an easy relationship in the past.</p>

<p>"We did not have an easy relationship in the past. What happened in 2020 was in violation of multiple agreements, the Chinese moved a large number of troops to the Line of Actual Control. We, in response, moved our troops up.. Some progress on border talks with China. 75 per cent of disengagement problems are sorted out. We still have some things to do," Jaishankar said during his conversation with Ambassador Jean-David Levitte at the Geneva Centre for Security Policy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/6fh10mvo_india-china_625x300_04_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Chinese envoy said that China-India ties are at a crucial stage of improvement. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-fined-900-000-a-day-for-restoring-services-in-brazil-despite-ban-6604765]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[X Fined $900,000 A Day For Restoring Services In Brazil Despite Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-fined-900-000-a-day-for-restoring-services-in-brazil-despite-ban-6604765]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:36:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazil's Supreme Court on Thursday ordered Elon Musk's X to suspend access to the social network, after service was restored despite a ban, or face a daily fine of over $900,000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil's Supreme Court on Thursday ordered Elon Musk's X to suspend access to the social network, after service was restored despite a ban, or face a daily fine of over $900,000.</p>

<p>The former Twitter was banned last month in Latin America's largest nation, but access to the phone app returned on Wednesday in what the government slammed as a deliberate violation of the suspension order.</p>

<p>X said the return of its service was "inadvertent and temporary."</p>

<p>Judge Alexandre de Moraes said in a court order that a "recalcitrant" X had "unlawfully, persistently and intentionally" failed to respect judicial orders, and would face a daily fine of 5 million reais ($913,000 USD) until it again suspends its service.</p>

<p>Moraes also ordered state telecommunications agency Anatel to take all necessary measures to once again block access to the social network.</p>

<p>The high-profile judge has been engaged in a long feud with South African-born billionaire Musk, as part of his drive to crack down on disinformation in Brazil.</p>

<p>Last month he ordered the suspension of X after Musk refused to remove dozens of right-wing accounts accused of spreading fake news, and then failed to name a new legal representative in the country as ordered.</p>

<p><strong>Musk assets frozen</strong></p>

<p>The suspension infuriated Musk and the far-right, and has fueled a fierce debate on freedom of expression and the limits of social networks, both inside and outside the country.</p>

<p>The social media platform has more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<p>Moraes also froze the assets of X and Musk's satellite internet operator Starlink -- which has been operating in Brazil since 2022, especially in remote communities in the Amazon -- to ensure payment of fines imposed on the social network for flouting court orders.</p>

<p>Last week, Moraes ordered the transfer of about $3 million from Musk's companies to pay fines incurred by X.</p>

<p>Musk has repeatedly hit out at Moraes in social media posts, calling him an "evil dictator" and dubbing him "Voldemort" after the villain from the Harry Potter series.</p>

<p>Internet providers explained that X had been accessible again after an automatic update to the phone application.</p>

<p>New software allows the app to use constantly changing identifying IP addresses, which makes it much harder to block.</p>

<p>While X said the restoration of service was unintentional, Anatel said the company acted with "deliberate intention" to skirt the Supreme Court order.</p>

<p>Anatel said Thursday it had "identified a mechanism which, we hope" will block the service again.</p>

<p>When banning X, Moraes also ruled that those using "technological subterfuges" such as virtual private networks (VPNs) to access the blocked site could be fined up to $9,000.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5g0r9d7_x-generic_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[X said the return of its service was "inadvertent and temporary." (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-sri-lankan-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-seeks-re-election-outlines-vision-for-india-sri-lanka-ties-6604764]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lankan President Seeks Re-Election, Outlines Vision For India-Sri Lanka Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-sri-lankan-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-seeks-re-election-outlines-vision-for-india-sri-lanka-ties-6604764]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:35:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe has said his vision for future ties with India holds a stronger economic relationship.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe has said his vision for future ties with India holds a stronger economic relationship. Sri Lanka will vote to elect its next President in two days and Mr Wickremesinghe is seeking another term in office. The elections will be key in deciding the future reforms in the country, currently reeling under an unprecedented economic crisis.</p>

<p>"We need to have a stronger economic relationship. Our social and cultural relationship has been going on for 1,000 years," Mr Wickremesinghe told NDTV in an exclusive interview.</p>

<p>"We want to encourage more investments from India and more tourists from India. We are working together with India on infrastructure projects like the Trincomalee Harbour," he added.</p>

<p>He further said, his priority areas of focus with regards to ties with India includes, renewable energy, for which there is a big demand in India. "When the Singapore-India cables come we can get on to that," he said. It is understood that India and Singapore have planned to connect their power grids through an undersea cable via Andaman and Nicobar, which will allow India to sell renewable energy to Singapore.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka's economy suffered a near total collapse in 2022 after a severe shortage of foreign currency reserves. The island country was unable to finance even the most essential imports, causing massive social unrest. Then president Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country, which led to then Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe being elected as president.</p>

<p>"I took over as President when the country was in utter chaos and no one thought we could stabilise this fast. But I knew from experience that we could go ahead provided we had the support of the International Monetary Fund and our creditors," the President said.</p>

<p>"I have ensured we come back to normalcy. Law and order is functioning, democracy is functioning and although we have stabilised the economy, now we have to decide our path. Are we going to get into the same old ways or are we working towards (building) a strong export economy? I have asked for a mandate to go ahead," Mr Wickremesinghe said.</p>

<p>The leader also talked about his key rivals. "I find my two main opponents are not aware about the economy. One claims to be a market economy, he's giving everything virtually away for free. Where is the money for that? We don't have the money for that."</p>

<p>One of his key rivals is Anura Kumara Dissanayaka, who is the leader of a once-marginal Marxist party tarnished by its violent past. The party led two failed uprisings in the 1970s and 1980s that left more than 80,000 people dead, and won less than four per cent of the vote in the last parliamentary elections.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sri Lanka's crisis has proven an opportunity for Mr Dissanayaka, who has seen a surge of support.</p>

<p>According to news agency AFP, fellow opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, once dismissed as the princeling dynast of a former president assassinated in 1993 during the country's decades-long civil war, is also favoured to make a strong showing. He has campaigned on a pledge to secure concessions from the IMF.</p>

<p>"The Samagi Jana Balawegaya wants to give everything away for free. Only a headache is left for them to give away for free. The National People's Power doesn't know which way to go, their economic policies are a mismatch. They are playing on the difficulties of the people but they don't give an answer about how they will get out of it," he said.</p>

<p>In light of Saturday's elections, the president also outlined his own agenda. "I want to make our economy export oriented. That will bring prosperity to the people. I've already brought in the economic transformation act in parliament. We have set benchmarks for the country to achieve. If we achieve those, we will become an export oriented economy. When we restructure it, we have to look at the areas in which we can take off, like modernising agriculture and renewable energy."</p>

<p>He said he has also envisioned a "better educated and trained workforce to become part of supply chains and bring manufacturing to Sri Lanka".<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7ihqc79g_ranil-wickremesinghe-ndtv_625x300_20_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We need to have a stronger economic relationship," Ranil Wickremesinghe told NDTV.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unknown-mozart-composition-from-his-teens-discoverd-in-germany-6604671]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Unknown Mozart Composition From His Teens Discovered In Germany]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unknown-mozart-composition-from-his-teens-discoverd-in-germany-6604671]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:15:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A previously unknown piece of music composed by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart when he was probably in his early teens has been uncovered at a library in Germany, researchers said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A previously unknown piece of music composed by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart when he was probably in his early teens has been uncovered at a library in Germany, researchers said Thursday.</p>

<p>The piece dates to the mid- to late-1760s and consists of seven miniature movements for a string trio lasting around 12 minutes, the Leipzig Municipal Libraries said in a statement.</p>

<p>Born in 1756, Mozart was a child prodigy and began composing at a very early age under his father's guidance.</p>

<p>Researchers discovered the work at the city's music library while compiling the latest edition of the so-called Koechel catalogue, the definitive archive of Mozart's musical works.</p>

<p>The newly discovered manuscript was not penned by Mozart himself but is believed to be a copy made in around 1780, the researchers said.</p>

<p>The piece was performed by a string trio at the unveiling of the new Koechel catalogue in the Austrian city of Salzburg on Thursday.</p>

<p>It will receive its German premiere at the Leipzig Opera on Saturday.</p>

<p>The piece is referred to as "Ganz kleine Nachtmusik" in the new Koechel catalogue, according to the Leipzig libraries.</p>

<p>The manuscript consists of dark brown ink on medium-white handmade paper and the parts are individually bound, they said.</p>

<p>The Koechel catalogue describes the piece as "preserved in a single source, in which the attribution of the author suggests that the work was written before Mozart's first trip to Italy", according to the municipal libraries.</p>

<p>The young Mozart had been known to researchers up until now "mainly as a composer of piano music, arias and symphonies", Ulrich Leisinger of the International Mozarteum Foundation in Salzburg said in a statement.</p>

<p>A list by Mozart's father had alerted academics to the existence of "many other chamber music compositions" by the young artist, which were all thought to have been lost until the emergence of the string trio, Leisinger said.</p>

<p>"Since the inspiration for this apparently came from Mozart's sister, it is tempting to imagine that she kept the work as a memento of her brother," Leisinger said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lotfneog_mozart-pixabay_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The newly discovered piece is referred to as "Ganz kleine Nachtmusik"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-holds-phone-call-with-newly-appointed-ukrainian-counterpart-6604669]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar Holds Phone Call With Newly Appointed Ukrainian Counterpart]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-holds-phone-call-with-newly-appointed-ukrainian-counterpart-6604669]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:14:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Thursday held a phone conversation with newly-appointed Ukrainian Foreign Minister Andrii Sybiha with a focus on boosting bilateral ties and finding a solution to the conflict in Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Thursday held a phone conversation with newly-appointed Ukrainian Foreign Minister Andrii Sybiha with a focus on boosting bilateral ties and finding a solution to the conflict in Ukraine.</p>

<p>The conversation came nearly a month after Prime Minister Narendra Modi's high-profile trip to Kyiv.</p>

<p>"I spoke with Subrahmanyam Jaishankar to build on Narendra Modi's historic visit to Kyiv and talks with Zelenskyy," Sybiha said.</p>

<p>"We agreed to take our bilateral relations forward in all promising areas of cooperation. We exchanged views ahead of UNGA and coordinated next steps in political dialogue," he said after the talks.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Mr Jaishankar said he was looking forward to working with the Ukrainian foreign minister.</p>

<p>"Spoke with the new Ukrainian FM @andrii_sybiha today. Congratulated him on his appointment. Look forward to working with him," he said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Spoke with the new Ukrainian FM <a href="https://twitter.com/andrii_sybiha?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@andrii_sybiha</a> today.<br />
<br />
Congratulated him on his appointment. Look forward to working with him.<br />
<br />
?? ??</p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1836717854449660212?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>It is learnt that the Russia-Ukraine conflict figured in the talks.</p>

<p>In his talks with Zelenskyy, Modi said both Ukraine and Russia should sit together without wasting time to end the ongoing war and that India was ready to play an "active role" to restore peace in the region.</p>

<p>The prime minister said India was on the side of peace since the beginning of the conflict and he would even like to contribute personally for a peaceful resolution of the crisis.</p>

<p>Modi's nearly nine-hour visit to Ukraine, the first by an Indian prime minister since its independence in 1991, came six weeks after he held summit talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin in Moscow.</p>

<p>India has been maintaining that the conflict in Ukraine must be resolved through dialogue and diplomacy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/oc10krbk_s-jaishankar_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bilateral-and-multilateral-aspects-foreign-secretary-vikram-misri-on-pm-modis-us-visit-6604599]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bilateral And Multilateral Aspects": Foreign Secretary On PM Modi's US Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bilateral-and-multilateral-aspects-foreign-secretary-vikram-misri-on-pm-modis-us-visit-6604599]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 23:01:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri on Thursday said that the upcoming visit by Prime Minister Narendra Modi for the Quad summit emphasises several important aspects, including bilateral, plurilateral and multilateral.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri on Thursday said that the upcoming visit by Prime Minister Narendra Modi for the Quad summit emphasises several important aspects, including bilateral, plurilateral and multilateral, and asserted that the agenda of the summit includes developing Indo-Pacific region, and implementing Sustainable Development Goals.</p>

<p>The remarks by Mr Misri came during a briefing by the Ministry of External Affairs on Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to the United States for the upcoming Quad summit.</p>

<p>Elaborating on the events which will be taking place in the US during PM Modi's visit, Mr Misri said, "PM Modi will be visiting the US from September 21-23. This visit combines very important aspects. It has very important bilateral aspect to it, very important plurilateral aspects to it and equally important multilateral aspect to it. There will be interaction with a variety of foreign partners at the level of the Prime Minister. There will be interaction with the large Indian community in the US. And there will be engagement with a host of business and industry leaders, amongst others."</p>

<p>He added, "PM's first talk will be in Wilmington, Delaware, which is the hometown of President Joe Biden. That is also the venue of this sixth Quad summit..."</p>

<p>Mr Misri further informed that from Wilmington, the PM will travel to New York, to attend the Summit of the Future. He said, "He (PM Modi) will also have a number of engagements throughout these three days. On September 21, there will be Quad summit; the bilateral meetings on the sidelines of the Quad summit. A special event on the sidelines of Quad summit will be Cancer Moonshot event. On September 22, PM will have an interaction with the Indian community. This is being organised by the community in Long Island, New York..."</p>

<p>Speaking on the objective of the Cancer Moonshot initiative, Mr Misri said, "Through the Cancer Moonshot initiative, the Quad aims to implement innovative strategies to prevent, detect, treat, and alleviate the impact of cancer on patients and their families, and to begin with, we intend to collaborate to reduce the burden of cervical cancer in the Indo-Pacific region."</p>

<p>The Foreign Secretary also said that PM Modi will engage with several tech CEOs during his three day visit. "There will be a technology roundtable with a number of tech CEOs where we will have the opportunity to discuss the tech investment landscape and the opportunities that are available here," Mr Misri said. "There will be several other meetings with stakeholders and bilateral meetings with head of states," he added.</p>

<p>"On September 23, PM will address the Summit of the Future in the United Nations General Assembly. There are a few more bilateral meetings that are being fixed up on that day," Mr Misri informed.</p>

<p>Elaborating on the agenda of Quad, Mr Misri said that the Quad's constructive agenda continues to "develop the Indo-Pacific, implementing Sustainable Development Goals, delivering public goods, and having a strong focus on peace, prosperity and stability in the Indo-Pacific region."</p>

<p>He added, "Our agenda includes covering health security, climate change, critical and emerging technology, HADR, connectivity, maritime security, and counter-terrorism."</p>

<p>The Foreign Secretary also noted that the upcoming visit offers the Quad leaders, the opportunity to view progress achieved in the last one year and set the agenda for the next year.</p>

<p>Elaborating on the bilateral meetings with President Biden, Mr Misri said that the India and US will exchange agreements. "At the bilarteral meeting with President Joe Biden, there will be an opportunity for both sides to exchange a few agreements -- Indo-Pacific economy related framework agreements, and India-US drug framework," Mr Misri said.</p>

<p>On the possibility of meeting with former US President Donald Trump, Mr Misri said, "There are many meetings with the Prime Minister right now which we are trying to fix. Right now, I will not be able to tell you about any specific meeting, whether the meeting has been fixed or not. We are looking from all angles as to how much time we have and with whom we can hold meetings. We will keep updating you about the meetings."</p>

<p>Notably, Prime Minister Narendra Modi will visit the United States from September 21 to 23 during which he will take part in the Quad Summit and address the 'Summit of the Future' at the United Nations General Assembly in New York.</p>

<p>PM Modi will take part in the fourth Quad Leaders' Summit in Wilmington, Delaware, which is being hosted by US President Joe Biden on September 21. Following the request of the US side to host the Quad Summit this year, India has agreed to host the next Quad Summit in 2025.</p>

<p>At the Quad Summit, the leaders will review the progress achieved by the Quad over the last one year and set the agenda for the year ahead to assist the countries of the Indo-Pacific region in meeting their development goals and aspirations, a Ministry of External Affairs release said.</p>

<p>PM Modi will address 'Summit of the Future' at the United Nations General Assembly in New York on September 23. The theme of the Summit is 'Multilateral Solutions for a Better Tomorrow'.</p>

<p>Quad is a diplomatic partnership between four countries--Australia, India, Japan, and the United States. It is pertinent to note that in recent years, Quad Foreign Ministers have met eight times, and Quad governments continue to meet and coordinate at all levels.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bivua0gg_vikram-misri_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollahs-hassan-nasrallah-the-most-powerful-man-in-lebanon-6604424]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah's Hassan Nasrallah: The Most Powerful Man In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollahs-hassan-nasrallah-the-most-powerful-man-in-lebanon-6604424]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 22:33:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Backed by Iran and hated by Israel, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah is Lebanon's most powerful man. He enjoys cult status among his Shiite supporters and holds sway over the country's institutions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Backed by Iran and hated by Israel, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah is Lebanon's most powerful man.</p>

<p>He enjoys cult status among his Shiite supporters, is equipped with a formidable arsenal far bigger and more modern than the national army's, and holds sway over the country's institutions.</p>

<p>Nasrallah has rarely been seen in public since his Shiite movement fought a devastating 2006 war pitting his fighters against Israeli troops.</p>

<p>No one knows where he lives, and the vast majority of his speeches in the past two decades have been televised from a secret location.</p>

<p>The 64-year-old delivered his latest such speech on Thursday, after the communications devices of hundreds of Hezbollah's operatives exploded in an unprecedented attack that the group blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>A gifted public speaker, Nasrallah is a master of cadence, swinging from humour to belittle his enemies to rage to fire up his 100,000-man militia.</p>

<p>The bearded, bespectacled cleric is never seen without traditional robes and the black turban that marks him out as a descendant of the prophet Mohammed.</p>

<p>He is married and has four surviving children. His eldest son Hadi was killed during a military operation against Israeli troops in south Lebanon in 1997.</p>

<p>He was elected secretary general of Hezbollah in 1992, aged just 32, after an Israeli helicopter gunship killed his predecessor Abbas al-Musawi.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is the only group that refused to give up its weapons after Lebanon's 15-year civil war ended in 1990, and Nasrallah insists that Israel remains an existential threat.</p>

<p>Since Hezbollah's Palestinian ally Hamas attacked Israel on October 7, Hezbollah has battled Israeli troops almost daily along the Lebanon-Israel border.</p>

<p>The unprecedented attacks that this week saw hundreds of Hezbollah members' pagers and walkie-talkies explode across Lebanon on Tuesday and Wednesday have put Nasrallah under huge pressure to respond.</p>

<p><strong>'Divine victory'</strong></p>

<p>Born in Beirut's impoverished northern suburb of Burj Hammud on August 31, 1960, he was one of nine children of a poor grocer hailing from the tiny southern village of Bazuriyeh.</p>

<p>Nasrallah studied both politics and the Koran for three years at a seminary in the Iraqi Shiite holy city of Najaf, before being expelled in 1978 when the Sunni-dominated government turned on Shiite activists.</p>

<p>He then became heavily involved in Lebanese politics and gained much of his early experience in the Shiite Amal militia during the civil war.</p>

<p>But he broke away from Amal when Israeli troops marched on Beirut in 1982 to become one of the founders of Hezbollah.</p>

<p>He acquired his cult status in Lebanon and across the Arab world after Israel withdrew its troops from south Lebanon under relentless Hezbollah attack in May 2000, ending 22 years of occupation of the border strip.</p>

<p>Nasrallah's years at the helm of Hezbollah, or Party of God, have seen the group expand from guerrilla faction into the country's most powerful political force.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is admired by many Shiites in Lebanon for supporting local charities, building up health and education services in its strongholds and assisting the needy among its supporters.</p>

<p>Nasrallah's personal popularity soared across the Arab world after a UN-brokered ceasefire ended the 2006 conflict with Israel, with supporters handing out posters bearing his photograph and declaring "divine victory."</p>

<p>But in divided Lebanon, the movement is also widely hated, including by those who dream of a nation free from sectarianism and where the rule of law prevails.</p>

<p>His reputation in the Arab world took a major blow during the Arab Spring protests of 2011, when he sent fighters to neighbouring Syria to prop up President Bashar al-Assad's regime.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q8ehs648_nasrallah_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nasrallah was elected secretary general of Hezbollah in 1992, aged just 32 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallahs-punishment-warning-to-israel-and-fear-of-all-out-war-6604351]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Israel Won't Be Able To...": Hezbollah Chief's Vow After Lebanon Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallahs-punishment-warning-to-israel-and-fear-of-all-out-war-6604351]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 22:21:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah warned Israel of "just punishment" after 32 were killed and over 3,000 were injured in a series of explosions on two consecutive days. Israel has not commented on the attacks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li>The attacks were a "massacre" that "could be a war crime or a declaration of war," he said, accusing Israel of having wanted to "kill no less than 5,000 people in two minutes".</li>
	<li>Lebanon lies north of Israel and daily fighting has resulted in the displacement of thousands of residents from its northern region and Israeli officials promised people to return to their homes.</li>
	<li>Israeli Defence Minister, Yoav Gallant, said, "The centre of gravity is moving northward -- resources are being allocated." Hezbollah is fighting Tel Aviv over its war in Gaza which has killed over 40,000.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah chief said, "They will not stop until the aggression on Gaza stops". It comes along with a warning to Israel that they will not be "able to return the people of the north to the north" unless they "stop the war in Gaza".</li>
	<li>Hezbollah is an ally of the Palestinian militant group Hamas, which has been fighting a war in Gaza since its October 7 attack on Israel.</li>
	<li>Today, Lebanese state media reported that Israeli fighters broke the sound barrier over the capital Beirut, i.e., fighter jets went supersonic at the same time when the Hezbollah chief was speaking.</li>
	<li>Israel said two of its soldiers were killed near the border with Lebanon today, while Hezbollah claimed that 25 of its members were killed following explosions, news agency AFP reported. Lebanese media reported Israeli strikes and shelling on towns in its south.</li>
	<li>While Israel's war drags to its 11th month, pager and walkie-talkie explosions in its "enemy" in the north have opened another front triggering concerns of an all-out war.</li>
	<li>The New York Times spoke to three Israeli intelligence officers who said BAC Consulting, a Hungary-based manufacturer of pagers, was a shell company set up by Mossad to rig the devices at the source before shipping them to Lebanon.</li>
	<li>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken has warned against any escalation of the war in the Middle East. "France and the United States are united in calling for restraint and urging de-escalation when it comes to the Middle East in general and when it comes to Lebanon in particular," he said.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c6n7ucoo_hezbollah-chief_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel said two of its soldiers were killed near the border with Lebanon today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/how-indias-krishna-bull-revolutionised-brazils-dairy-industry-6604187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How India's 'Krishna' Bull Revolutionised Brazil's Dairy Industry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/how-indias-krishna-bull-revolutionised-brazils-dairy-industry-6604187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 21:59:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In 1960, Brazilian cattle baron Celso Garcia Sid imported a bull named Krishna from India, a gift from the Maharaja of Bhavnagar, to improve Brazil's cattle breeding.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 1958, Brazilian cattle baron Celso Garcia Sid sent cowboy Ildefonso dos Santos to India to find a bull that could enhance Brazilian livestock, according to <em>the BBC.</em> Cid was browsing through photographs when he fell in love with a calf named Krishna: his coats were reddish white and his horns hung downward. Cid immediately ordered the purchase of this wonder bull. That was in 1960 when the wonder bull from India arrived in Brazil.</p>

<p>During that time the cowboy had described him as "colossus". "Nothing that is said about this animal can reveal anything-it is a colossus," he had said.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/portuguese/brasil-44730087"><em>BBC</em></a>, Krishna, gifted by the Maharaja of Bhavnagar, proved to be a genetic revolution in Brazil cattle market, with an elevated value to the Gir breed that is now counted as one of the most valuable breeds in the bovine embryo market. His lineage forms 80% of Brazil's milk production. The government of India has even approached Brazil seeking help to import the breed back into India, from where the breed nearly vanished due to failed crossbreeding attempts.</p>

<p>According to Guilherme Sachetim, grandson of Cid, Krishna is the turning point in the history of livestock farming in Brazil. "He renewed the national dairy cattle's blood at the time when inbreeding was restraining productivity," he said.</p>

<p>In fact, the advancement of genetic improvement techniques enabled Krishna's high-performance DNA to spread in all directions throughout Brazil. "Millions of people have enjoyed this import," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/portuguese/brasil-44730087"><em>BBC</em></a>.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Preserved Legacy of Gir Bull Krishna and Celso Garcia Cid." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8hjii1i_the-preserved-legacy-of-gir-bull-krishna-and-celso-garcia-cid_625x300_19_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="The Preserved Legacy of Gir Bull Krishna and Celso Garcia Cid." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The Preserved Legacy of Gir Bull Krishna and Celso Garcia Cid.</p>
</div>

<p>The tale of Krishna links Brazil to India's glorious heritage of cattle breeding during the Maharajas' regime who came up with such breeds that are resistant to lion attacks. The legacy of Krishna continues to shape Brazil's dairy industry, however, for the betterment of millions across Americas.</p>

<p>This friendship with the Maharaja of Bhavnagar, because of his state and philanthropic gesture, helped change the landscape of dairy industry in Brazil for good. He paid a visit in the early 1960s to Celso's farm in Sertanopolis, and before his death, he left all his cows to him. This not only deepened the friendship but also placed the start for huge progress in Brazilian livestock.</p>

<p>Legendary bull Krishna, which played such an important role in this process, left a legacy of his own. After his death, Cid embalmed Krishna's body in a glass coffin and preserved it in the farmhouse, where it remains even to this day. A sign on which someone heaved between Krishna's paws reads: "Want to meet Gir? Watch me!"-testament to the monumental influence of the bull on the breed.</p>

<p>Today, an excellent Brazilian Gir can produce as much as 20 litres of milk per day. Ten times more than the original cattle brought to Brazil nearly one century ago, this indicates a significant leap in productivity. But these leaps in productivity reflect the spectacular impact Krishna and following breeding programs made on the dairy sector and really improved many farmers' lives across Brazil.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t55cs8l8_krishnagirbull_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Krishna revolutionized Brazil's dairy industry.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-sri-lankan-elections-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-tells-ndtv-about-chinas-growing-presence-6604052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ahead Of Lankan Polls, President Tells NDTV About China's Growing Presence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-sri-lankan-elections-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-tells-ndtv-about-chinas-growing-presence-6604052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 21:34:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The south Asian and Indian Ocean region is going through a "difficult time", Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe said on Thursday in an exclusive interview to NDTV. Sri Lanka will hold elections on September 21 to elect the next President.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The south Asian and Indian Ocean region is going through a "difficult time", Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe said on Thursday in an exclusive interview to NDTV. Sri Lanka will hold elections on September 21 to elect the next President.</p>

<p>Mr Wickremesinghe, who took over as President when Sri Lanka was going through its worst-ever economic crisis, has steered the economy back towards normalcy. His re-election will prove to be an effective referendum on an unpopular International Monetary Fund austerity plan enacted by his government after the island nation's unprecedented financial crisis.</p>

<p>Ranil Wickremesinghe, 75, is seeking a fresh mandate after claiming credit for stabilising the economy and bringing an end to months of food, fuel and medicine shortages.</p>

<p>In an exclusive interview to NDTV's Gaurie Dwivedi, Mr Wickremesinghe spoke not just about the domestic challenges Sri Lanka faces, but also the challenges faced by the entire south Asian region, where India plays a leading part.</p>

<h2><strong>CRISES IN MALDIVES AND BANGLADESH</strong></h2>

<p>"It is a difficult time for the region. Maldives is going through an economic crisis and needs all the help they can get. Bangladesh too is facing a political crisis and we (as neighbours) should ensure that stability returns as soon as possible, after which elections can be held where a new parliament can then decide on a new prime minister," the Sri Lankan President said, while speaking about the most recent and immediate regional challenges.</p>

<p>He went on to say that of all the others neighbours, "the issue of Bangladesh has the greatest impact on India", adding that Sri Lanka too has significant investments in Bangladesh, which it views as a "friendly country". He said he is concerned that if the crisis in Bangladesh is "not resolved in the short-to-medium term, it can have an impact on India."</p>

<h3><strong>SRI LANKA'S CHALLENGES AND ANTI-INDIA REMARKS</strong></h3>

<p>In 2022, when Ranil Wickremesinghe took charge as President, Sri Lanka was dealing with civil unrest spurred by the economic crisis. There were protests across the nation which led to thousands storming the Presidential palace which was then occupied by Mr Wickremesinghe's predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who fled the country. Mr Wickremesinghe took charge and restored calm and helped revived the economy by taking some tough decisions.</p>

<p>"Think of the time when all hope was lost... we didn't have food, gas, medicine, or any hopes. Now you have a choice. Decide if you want to go back to that period of terror, or progress," Mr Wickremesinghe had said in the closing days of his election campaign. India had stood by Sri Lanka during the crisis and helped revive its economy.</p>

<p>Mr Wickremesinghe told NDTV that it will be his priority to deepen economic ties, especially in infrastructure projects, adding that the two nations have shared cultural and economic ties for "thousands of years".</p>

<p>His rivals in the elections however have made some strong anti-India remarks, and should they win the election, it may prove to be a challenge for New Delhi and perhaps even a complete reset in ties.</p>

<p>"Let us first watch the elections," said the Sri Lankan President, hinting at his rivals' remarks being amplified due to political rhetoric. But he went on to say that "There will be some groups which will make anti-India remarks. That can't be stopped, but the aim is to minimise it."</p>

<p>"As far as India-Sri Lanka friendship is concerned, it is decided by the people of both nations and they have already decided it," he told NDTV.</p>

<p>Ranil Wickremesinghe faces two formidable challengers including Anura Kumara Dissanayaka, the leader of a once-marginal Marxist party tarnished by its violent past. The party led two failed uprisings in the 1970s and 1980s that left more than 80,000 people dead, and won less than four per cent of the vote in the last parliamentary elections.</p>

<p>But Sri Lanka's crisis has proven an opportunity for Mr Dissanayaka, who has seen a surge of support.</p>

<p>According to news agency AFP, fellow opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, once dismissed as the princeling dynast of a former president assassinated in 1993 during the country's decades-long civil war, is also favoured to make a strong showing. He has campaigned on a pledge to secure concessions from the IMF.</p>

<p>Speaking to NDTV about China, the Sri Lankan President said that "We've had good relations with China and we will continue to do so. But we will look at our interest first," adding that "We will ensure that nothing (about China ties) will affect the security of India. Our dealings with China will work within the framework" of India's national security.</p>

<h3><strong>GROWING CHINESE PRESENCE IN INDIAN OCEAN</strong></h3>

<p>Describing China as a "leading global power", Mr Wickremesinghe said that "China is going to have an extended influence in the Indian Ocean region. They are already working with a number of countries."</p>

<p>China is looking to grow its presence in the Indian Ocean and it is already working to build up its presence around the Suez Canal, said Mr Wickremesinghe, adding that China is looking to be a "leading global power after the United States."</p>

<p>"Sri Lanka will keep working with China, but we will work on our own terms, keeping India's interests in mind, after all India is just twenty miles away from us and we have shared historic ties" he told NDTV.</p>

<p>With an "all-weather ally" in Pakistan, a "pro-Beijing regime" in Maldives, an increasing presence in Nepal and deepening ties with Bangladesh's new regime, China has been mounting its presence across south Asia and the Indian Ocean. Sri Lanka votes on Saturday to elect their next President, one of the candidates reportedly being openly "pro-China and anti-India".<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/rcgunci_sri-lanka-ranil-reuters-_625x300_16_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[South Asia and Indian Ocean region is going through a "difficult time", Sri Lankan President told NDTV.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>