<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 20:38:09 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-tried-to-hire-hitman-to-kill-wife-of-man-she-met-online-jailed-for-8-years-6632396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Tried To Hire Hitman To Kill Wife Of Man She Met Online, Jailed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-tried-to-hire-hitman-to-kill-wife-of-man-she-met-online-jailed-for-8-years-6632396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 19:42:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to court documents, Sasser met David Wallace on Match.com and became obsessed after he revealed his engagement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Melody Sasser, a 48-year-old Tennessee woman, was sentenced to 100 months in prison for attempting to hire a hitman to kill the wife of a man she met on a dating website. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/woman-tried-hire-hitman-kill-wife-man-met-match-seem-random-8715907">People,</a></em> Sasser used the dark website "Online Killers Market" to seek a hitman, offering $9,750 in Bitcoin for a "random" or "accident" killing.&nbsp;According to court documents, Sasser met David Wallace on Match.com and became obsessed after he revealed his engagement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Wallace told investigators that their relationship was limited to hiking companionship.&nbsp;Sasser had assisted him on an Appalachian Trail hike and they had also explored trails together in the Knoxville area before he relocated to Alabama&nbsp;and married his now-wife.</p>

<p>However, Sasser's interest evolved into an unhealthy obsession.&nbsp;After learning of his engagement, she showed up at his Alabama home, making disturbing threats and beginning a campaign of harassment against his now-wife.&nbsp;Sasser monitored the couple's activities using a fitness app and harassed the wife with six phone calls in one day.</p>

<p>''It needs to seem random or accident. or plant drugs, do not want a long investigation. She recently moved in with her new husband,” she wrote on the website, including details such as the couple's license plate numbers and the wife's workplace.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sasser also notified the website administrator when he left her home for a mere two-mile walk.</p>

<p>"I have waited for two months and 11 days and the job is not completed. 2 weeks ago you said it has been worked on and would be done in a week. The job is still not done. Does it need to be assigned to someone else? Will it be done? What is the delay? When will it be done," Sasser wrote in a follow-up message to the website's administrator.</p>

<p>Ultimately, the plan was unsuccessful. During the search of her home, law enforcement uncovered incriminating evidence, including a journal detailing multiple hitman websites and a handwritten account of her communications with the notorious "Online Killers Market". Additionally, investigators found a stash of cash hidden beneath a sticky note bearing a Bitcoin address.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a result, a federal grand jury indicted Sasser in June last year for utilising interstate commerce facilities to facilitate murder-for-hire. Sasser ultimately accepted responsibility for her crimes through a plea deal. On Wednesday, she received her sentence: 100 months in prison, accompanied by an order to pay over $5,300 in restitution to the victim.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vdha9hq_melody-sasser_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sasser used the dark website "Online Killers Market" to seek a hitman]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankas-new-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-and-what-is-at-stake-for-india-6632199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's New President And What Is At Stake For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankas-new-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-and-what-is-at-stake-for-india-6632199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 19:14:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka has made history by voting leftist Anura Kumara Dissanayake to power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka has made history by voting leftist Anura Kumara Dissanayake to power. The people rejected all the known and tested political leaders and dynasts - Rajapaksa, Wickremesinghe and Premadasa - who, according to them, contributed to the island nation's economic collapse.</p>

<p>The Election Commission declared AKD, as Dissanayake is popularly known, as the winner after the second round of counting. Dissanayake won 5.7 million (42.3%) votes after two rounds of counting in the nation's first-ever second preference vote count - defeating Sajith Premadasa of the SJB (Samagi Jana Balawegaya), who got 4.5 million (32.8%). It was a big defeat for incumbent President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who fought as an independent and was a distant third with 17.3% votes. Namal Rajapaksa, the son of former President Mahinda Rajapaksa, managed only 2.4% of the total votes.</p>

<p>It is a robust victory for Dissanayake, the leader of the Marxist JVP (Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna) and also the broader front NPP (National Peoples Power), which had won just over 3% of votes in the previous presidential election in 2019. It also reflects the extent of Sri Lankans' distrust of the old regime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Soon after his win, Dissanayake wrote on X: "This achievement is not the result of any single person's work, but the collective effort of hundreds of thousands of you. Your commitment has brought us this far, and for that, I am deeply grateful. This victory belongs to all of us."</p>

<p><strong>Pragmatic leader</strong></p>

<p>An analysis of Dissanayake's political career reveals that he is a pragmatic leader who knows how to deal with global political realities despite his ideological moorings rooted in Marxism.</p>

<p>Dissanayake's political activism began when he was a university leader in the early 1990s, and it brought him close to the JVP (Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna), a left-wing Marxist-Leninist party mainly consisting of Sinhalese rural youth and known for its armed uprisings in 1971 and 1987-89. It is interesting to note that JVP's origins are linked to a faction within the Communist Party of Sri Lanka (CPSL) in the 1960s, mostly in its pro-China bloc.</p>

<p>However, ground-level electoral politics forced JVP to temper its stand, which had a positive impact on leaders like Dissanayake, who became the party's national organiser in 1997. In 2000, he became an MP. His elevation as JVP chief came after a long wait, in 2014. Dissanayake's flexibility and willingness to learn enabled him to grasp Sri Lanka's economic issues and relate to the rural and working-class citizens, especially through the country's worst economic crises in the late 2010s and early 2020s. His brief stint as Agriculture Minister also helped him connect with Sri Lanka's rural agricultural sector, setting him apart from the political elite.</p>

<p>Incandescent anger against the political elite over an economic mess saw Sri Lankans overthrow the Rajapaksa family in 2022. To voters fed up with steep inflation, food, fuel and medicine shortages and swelling debt, Dissanayake's anti-corruption stance and promise of political reforms appealed to the masses, especially the youth.</p>

<p>The victory will be overwhelming both for Dissanayake and JVP. This is their first time in power, and the lack of experience could be a worry domestically as well as internationally.</p>

<p>India is closely observing the developments in its neighbourhood, just a couple of hours away by speed boat from its southern tip Rameswaram. So is China, which is striving to increase its influence over the island nation.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka has undeniably moved towards China in the past 15 years, handing many lucrative projects to the country. Among other projects, China snagged one to develop an airport in Colombo. Earlier, the strategically important Hambantota Port, situated along the world's busiest shipping lane linking Asia and Europe was given to China, which gave it an upper hand in the region.</p>

<p><strong>India's stakes</strong><br />
&nbsp;<br />
India has splurged millions of dollars in the form of aid and loans to ensure stability in Sri Lanka, its closest neighbour.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi congratulated Dissanayake on his victory and said he looks forward to working closely with him to further strengthen the Indo-Lanka multifaceted cooperation.</p>

<p>In his response on Monday (Sept 23), Dissanayake thanked PM Modi for his 'kind' words and support and said he shared his commitment to strengthening ties.</p>

<p>Historically, JVP has been anti-India, especially during the late 1980s, when the party held agitations against Indian imports, including medicines and drugs.</p>

<p>India will also be concerned about the Tamil population in Sri Lanka, as Dissanayake's party has had a complex and antagonistic relationship with Tamil nationalism and LTTE. The JVP opposed the Indo-Sri Lanka Peace Accord in 1987, and did not support the implementation of the 13th amendment of the Sri Lankan Constitution, which delegates powers to the country's Tamil minority.</p>

<p>A majority of Tamils did not vote for Dissanayake, given what they believe is the apathy of his alliance NPP towards Tamils' political demands. Whether Dissanayake, after taking office, will reach out to the country's Tamil minority will be watched.</p>

<p>Experts believe that the rigid stance may not hold up against the strategic geopolitical realities. Dissanayake displayed his eagerness to engage with India as early as February 2024 and met with Foreign Minister S Jaishankar and National Security Adviser Ajit Doval.</p>

<p>Sri Lankans have reposed their faith in Dissanayake as their last hope. They are yet to experience his rule or his policies. His recent speeches do suggest a more nuanced approach, moderating his Left-leaning position. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>Dissanayake has a lot on his plate on the domestic front, and fixing the economy will be his priority. He is expected to dissolve parliament and call parliamentary elections soon. Some of his public statements and decisions didn't seem to favour India's interests in the recent past.</p>

<p>India needs to use its diplomatic channels to ensure that Indian investments like the wind power project in the northern part of Sri Lanka are not jeopardised. Given the project's strategic location in northern Sri Lanka, any setback could mean a Chinese company or its proxy taking over, which would be a concern given the significance of the region and the presence of the Tamil minority.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kmdflmg8_sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake_625x300_23_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An analysis of Dissanayake's political career reveals that he is a pragmatic leader.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/sundar-pichai-says-google-will-fund-global-ai-education-at-the-cost-of-120m-dollars-6631961]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Will Fund Global AI Education At The Cost Of 120M Dollars: Sundar Pichai]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/sundar-pichai-says-google-will-fund-global-ai-education-at-the-cost-of-120m-dollars-6631961]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 18:43:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pichai announced "Global AI Opportunity Fund" at the event and said that the AI education will be done in local languages, in partnerships with nonprofits and NGOs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Speaking at the "UN Summit of the Future" on Saturday, Google CEO Sundar Pichai has said that he wants to close the "AI Divide" and pledged 120 million USD for AI training and education around the world, according to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://blog.google/inside-google/message-ceo/united-nations-keynote-2024/">blog</a> on Google.</p>

<p>Pichai addressed the United Nations General assembly (UNGA) at the very first "UN Summit of the Future," delivering the keynote speech. Pichai announced "Global AI Opportunity Fund" at the event and said that the AI education will be done in local languages, in partnerships with nonprofits and NGOs.</p>

<p>Pichai expressed his confidence in AI being the most transformative technology yet, and shared his personal experience as to how technology changed his life, being born and brought up in Chennai. He mentioned four ways through which AI technology has potential for transformative change: access to information in one's own language, AI driven scientific discoveries, AI's climate-related disaster management systems, and AI's contribution to the world economy.</p>

<p>However, Pichai also cautioned regarding AI's potential for harm as well. He expressed concerns of accuracy, biasness as well as misapplication of AI like in case of deep fakes. Pichai also called for regulations that do not give into protectionist impulses, enabling wider reach of AI technologies for equal opportunity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/d24jdpj_sundar-pichai_625x300_14_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sundar Pichai gave the keynote speech at the first "UN Summit of the Future"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/colombia-woman-awarded-rs-23-crore-after-millionaire-boss-recorded-her-nude-videos-on-hidden-camera-6631876]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Millionaire Boss Caught Filming Nude Videos Of Nanny On Hidden Camera]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/colombia-woman-awarded-rs-23-crore-after-millionaire-boss-recorded-her-nude-videos-on-hidden-camera-6631876]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 18:34:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Her job abruptly ended when she found a hidden camera in a smoke detector in her bedroom.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kelly Andrade, a 25-year-old live-in nanny, has been awarded a $2.78 million payout after discovering she was secretly videotaped by her millionaire boss, Michael Esposito, at his New York home. Ms Andrade, from Colombia, cared for Esposito's four children while living with the family, the <em><u><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/22/us-news/nyc-jury-awards-au-pair-who-was-secretly-filmed-by-creepy-chicken-mogul-employer-2-78m/" rel="nofollow, noindex">New York Post</a></u></em> reported.&nbsp; However, her job abruptly ended when she found a hidden camera in a smoke detector in her bedroom.&nbsp;The twisted episode unfolded in 2021.</p>

<aside>
<p>Ms Andrade's suspicions arose after noticing Esposito frequently adjusting the smoke detector, which was constantly repositioned. Her worst fears were confirmed when she discovered a hidden camera inside, containing a memory card filled with hundreds of recordings – many of which captured intimate moments of her nude or dressing/undressing. Within minutes of her finding the device, Esposito showed up at the house.&nbsp;Fearing for her safety, she escaped through a window when he arrived home and started banging on her door.</p>

<p>''He seemed very nervous and he seemed very worried when he arrived at the house,'' she recalled.</p>

<p>Esposito was arrested on suspicion of illegal surveillance, which carries a maximum four-year prison sentence. However, he was allowed to walk free after agreeing to two years of probation and counselling. A Manhattan jury awarded Ms Andrade $780,000 in emotional distress damages against Esposito and his wife Danielle, plus $2 million in punitive damages against him.</p>
</aside>

<p>Speaking to the <em>Post</em>, the nanny said, ''It's not enough for the whole situation I've been through these three years. It's not enough. I was angry because the damage that he caused me was irreversible.''</p>

<p>After enduring a traumatic experience, she is now devoted to healing and moving forward. The Colombian native, residing in New Jersey with her husband, reflected on the gruelling trial process, stating that it forced her to "relive" painful memories she had sought to forget.&nbsp;By sharing her story, she seeks to ensure that no one else suffers in silence and that perpetrators are held accountable for their actions.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6rcopj3_man-working-on-laptop_625x300_23_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Michael Esposito was arrested on suspicion of illegal surveillance.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-protests-airspace-violation-by-russian-patrol-plane-6631580]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Protests Airspace "Violation" By Russian Patrol Plane]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-protests-airspace-violation-by-russian-patrol-plane-6631580]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 18:00:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan lodged a "very serious protest" with Moscow after a Russian patrol plane entered its airspace three times, the defence minister said Monday, calling it the first confirmed incursion since 2019.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan lodged a "very serious protest" with Moscow after a Russian patrol plane entered its airspace three times, the defence minister said Monday, calling it the first confirmed incursion since 2019.</p>

<p>The military responded by scrambling fighter jets and issuing radio and flare warnings, Japan's Defense Minister Minoru Kihara told reporters.</p>

<p>"We confirmed today that a Russian Il-38 patrol aircraft has violated our airspace over our territorial waters north of Rebun Island, Hokkaido, on three occasions," he said.</p>

<p>"The airspace violation is extremely regrettable and today we lodged a very serious protest with the Russian government via diplomatic channels and strongly urged them to prevent a recurrence."</p>

<p>Japan has supported the Western position on Ukraine, providing Kyiv with financial and material support and sanctioning Russian individuals and organisations after Moscow's invasion of its neighbour.</p>

<p>Mr Kihara said it was "the first publicly announced airspace incursion by a Russian aircraft since June 2019", when a Tu-95 bomber entered Japanese airspace in southern Okinawa and around the Izu Islands south of Tokyo.</p>

<p>In 2023, an aircraft believed but not confirmed to be Russian entered Japanese airspace, according to the defence ministry.</p>

<p>Top government spokesman Yoshimasa Hayashi also said on Monday that "we will refrain from giving any definitive information on the intent and purpose of this action, but the Russian military has been active in the vicinity of our country since the invasion of Ukraine".</p>

<p>Japan also scrambled fighter jets this month when Russian aircraft flew around the archipelago for the first time since 2019.</p>

<p>The Tu-142 planes did not enter Japanese airspace but flew over an area subject to a territorial dispute between Japan and Russia, Tokyo said.</p>

<p>Russian and Chinese warships recently held joint drills in the Sea of Japan, part of a major naval exercise that President Vladimir Putin said was the largest of its kind for three decades.</p>

<p>Japan scrambled fighter jets in August after the first confirmed incursion by a Chinese military aircraft into its airspace, with Tokyo calling it a "serious violation" of its sovereignty.</p>

<p>Then last week, a Chinese aircraft carrier sailed between two Japanese islands near Taiwan for the first time. Japan called that incident "totally unacceptable from the perspective of the security environment of Japan and the region".</p>

<p>China said the passage complied with international law.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q3je0h5g_japan-flag-generic-_625x300_12_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The airspace violation is extremely regrettable," said Japan's Defense Minister (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thailand-government-official-collects-salary-and-bonuses-for-10-years-without-working-heres-how-6631470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thailand Official Collects Salary And Bonuses For 10 Years Without Working]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thailand-government-official-collects-salary-and-bonuses-for-10-years-without-working-heres-how-6631470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 17:44:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite his decade-long absence, the government official remarkably escaped termination or penalties, continuing to collect his salary and bonuses without interruption.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A shocking scandal has rocked Thailand, exposing the country's deep-seated corruption issues. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3279397/thai-official-inactive-10-years-continues-receive-salary-while-working-nightclub" rel="nofollow, noindex">South China Morning Post</a></em>, a government official from the Disaster Prevention and Mitigation Department in Ang Thong province allegedly received a salary and bonuses for 10 years without ever showing up to work. The reason? He was too busy singing at a nightclub to bother with his day job. The official was constantly exhausted from working at night, which led him to skip work during the day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite his decade-long absence, the government official remarkably escaped termination or penalties, continuing to collect his salary and bonuses without interruption. To maintain a facade of accountability, he would periodically receive a summons to the office to receive reprimands or sign documents at the mayor's behest - a strategic move seemingly designed to dodge scrutiny.</p>

<p>The shocking case of misconduct was only revealed thanks to a Facebook page called Watchdog, dedicated to exposing government wrongdoing. The page has garnered 1.1 million followers, highlighting the widespread concern over corruption in Thailand. According to Transparency International's 2023 Corruption Perceptions Index, Thailand scored a dismal 35 out of 100, ranking 108th out of 180 countries. A staggering 88% of Thai respondents view government corruption as a significant problem, with 24% admitting to paying bribes in the past year.</p>

<p>This incident has sparked outrage, with many questioning the government's lack of accountability. Under Thai law, corrupt officials can face one to 10 years in prison and fines ranging from 2,000 to 20,000 baht ($60 to $600).&nbsp;The local government has maintained silence regarding the case,&nbsp;and it remains unclear whether or how the official will be punished.</p>

<p>Notably, this isn't an isolated incident. Another case involves a family in Nakhon Ratchasima province, who endured six years of bullying by their neighbour – a government official and son of a high-ranking police officer. Despite reporting the abuse, the family faced legal threats, and the perpetrator remains uncharged.</p>

<p>Thailand's public sector employs approximately 1.68 million workers, including 421,000 civil servants. Once coveted for their financial security and benefits, these jobs are now losing appeal among young people, who increasingly opt for riskier careers to pursue their passions.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vel22l98_thai-official_625x300_23_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The official was constantly exhausted from working at night, which led him to skip work during the day.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-killed-over-400-injured-in-israeli-strikes-says-lebanon-6631423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[182 Killed, Over 700 Injured In Israeli Strikes, Says Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-killed-over-400-injured-in-israeli-strikes-says-lebanon-6631423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 17:38:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli air strikes on Hezbollah strongholds in Lebanon on Monday killed 182 people, according to the Lebanese health ministry, in by far the deadliest cross-border escalation since war erupted in Gaza on October 7.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli air strikes on Hezbollah strongholds in Lebanon on Monday killed 182 people, according to the Lebanese health ministry, in by far the deadliest cross-border escalation since war erupted in Gaza on October 7.</p>

<p>War began when Palestinian group Hamas carried out the worst-ever attack on Israel, with Hezbollah and other Iran-backed groups around the region drawn into the violence.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israel said it had hit more than 300 Hezbollah sites with dozens of strikes, while Hezbollah said it had targeted three sites in northern Israel.</p>

<p>"Israeli enemy strikes on southern towns and villages since this morning" have killed "182 people and wounded 727 others", the health ministry said, with children, women and health workers among the casualties.</p>

<p>World powers have implored Israel and Hezbollah to pull back from the brink of all-out war, with the focus of violence shifting sharply in recent days from Israel's southern front with Gaza to its northern border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>"We sleep and wake up to bombardment... that's what our life has become," said Wafaa Ismail, 60, a housewife from the southern Lebanese village of Zawtar.</p>

<p><strong>More to come</strong></p>

<p>Israeli military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari told people in Lebanon to avoid potential targets linked to Hezbollah as strikes would "go on for the near future".</p>

<p>Hagari said Israel's military "will engage in (more) extensive and precise strikes against terror targets which have been embedded widely throughout Lebanon".</p>

<p>He told civilians to "immediately move out of harm's way for their own safety".</p>

<p>The strikes sent hundreds of people fleeing their homes, according to Bilal Kachmar, an official in Tyre.</p>

<p>"Hundreds of displaced people rushed" to a school-turned-shelter in the southern city, he said, with many others "camping out in the streets".</p>

<p>AFP correspondents saw rows of cars leaving the nearby city of Sidon.</p>

<p>The Israeli military also warned people living in the Bekaa valley, in eastern Lebanon, to flee their homes, as it announced it was "broadening" the scope of its strikes.</p>

<p>Explosions around the ancient city of Baalbek in eastern Lebanon triggered flashes of fire and sent smoke billowing into the sky.</p>

<p>In divided Lebanon, large parts of the south and east of the country, as well as the southern suburbs of capital city Beirut, are seen as strongholds of Hezbollah, where the group has historically wielded influence and built up services for its Shiite Muslim support base.</p>

<p>The education minister said schools in targeted areas would close for two days.</p>

<p>The official National News Agency said Lebanese had received phone messages from Israel telling them to "quickly evacuate".</p>

<p>Hezbollah, a powerful political and military force in Lebanon, says it is acting in its near-daily battle with Israeli troops along Lebanon's border in support of its Palestinian ally Hamas, which is also backed by Iran.</p>

<p><strong>Israel changing 'security balance'</strong></p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Monday that Israel was not waiting threats to emerge but was preempting them and was acting to change the "security balance" in the north.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's deputy chief, Naim Qassem, said the group was in a "new phase, namely an open reckoning" with Israel, and ready for "all military possibilities".</p>

<p>They spoke after Hezbollah rocket attacks on northern Israel caused damage in the area of Haifa, a major city on Israel's north coast.</p>

<p>On Sunday morning, hundreds of thousands of people in northern Israel fled to their bomb shelters as Hezbollah fired a barrage of rockets across the border.</p>

<p>The attack came after an Israeli air strike in Hezbollah's southern Beirut stronghold on Friday killed its elite Radwan Force commander, Ibrahim Aqil, along with other commanders and civilians.</p>

<p>Last Tuesday and Wednesday, coordinated communications device blasts that Hezbollah blamed on Israel killed 39 people and wounded almost 3,000.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Hezbollah said it targeted Israeli military production facilities and an air base in the Haifa area with rockets as "an initial response".</p>

<p>On Monday the group said it had again fired rockets at military sites near Haifa.</p>

<p>"No country can live like this," said Ofer Levy, 56, a customs officer, who lives on the edge of Haifa.</p>

<p>Since the cross-border exchanges between Israel and Hezbollah began in October, tens of thousands of people on both sides have fled their homes.</p>

<p>An Israeli military official, who cannot be further identified under military rules, on Monday outlined the goals of the military operation.</p>

<p>It seeks to "degrade threats" from Hezbollah, push them back from the border, and then to destroy infrastructure built near the frontier by Hezbollah's Radwan Force, the official said.</p>

<p>Lebanese Prime Minister Najib Mikati urged the United Nation and world powers to deter what he called Israel's "plan that aims to destroy Lebanese villages and towns".</p>

<p><strong>Another Gaza?</strong></p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, whose country is Israel's main ally and weapons supplier, said his administration was "going to do everything we can to keep a wider war from breaking out".</p>

<p>Ahead of the annual General Assembly in New York, UN chief Antonio Guterres warned of Lebanon becoming "another Gaza" and said it was "clear that both sides are not interested in a ceasefire" there.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Of the 251 hostages also seized by militants, 97 are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,431 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/frc12br_israel-strikes-lebanon_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lebanon said that "children, women and paramedics" were among the casualties.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/with-ai-dead-celebrities-are-working-again-and-making-millions-6630844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[With AI, Dead Celebrities Are Working Again And Making Millions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/with-ai-dead-celebrities-are-working-again-and-making-millions-6630844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 16:22:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The dead-celebrity industry has proved lucrative. Despite Michael Jackson being about $500 million in debt at the time of his death, his estate has amassed a fortune of $2 billion, according to People.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can you think of a better way to get into the spirit of Halloween than listening to The Legend of Sleepy Hollow read by the ghost of James Dean?</p>

<p>The actor's career may have ended tragically in 1955, but his estate is keeping his paycheck alive through artificial intelligence. Alongside the estates of Judy Garland, Laurence Olivier and Burt Reynolds, it signed with AI voice-cloning startup ElevenLabs in July as part of the company's "iconic voices" project. The actors now narrate books, articles and other text material put into ElevenLabs' Reader app; essentially, Garland can now read you The Wonderful Wizard of Oz or your tax return-the choice is yours.</p>

<p>The dead-celebrity industry has proved lucrative. Despite Michael Jackson being about $500 million in debt at the time of his death, his estate has amassed a fortune of $2 billion, according to People, thanks to projects such as a jukebox musical and even featuring work made while he was alive. Yet advances in AI mean a late artist like Jackson can still generate new art.</p>

<p>Mark Roesler, an intellectual-property lawyer, has represented more than 3,000 celebrities, most of whom are dead, and has made some 30,000 deals on their behalf since founding his company CMG Worldwide Inc. more than four decades ago. Among current clients including Rosa Parks and Malcolm X, he's negotiated Jerry Garcia his own ElevenLabs deal.</p>

<p>There are two key ways a living celebrity makes money, Roesler says. The first is personal services, which, for a musician like Prince, would have been income from his concerts and songs. The second is intellectual property, which is independent of those services and could be anything from the copyright of music to pictures.</p>

<p>When a celebrity dies, their personal services revenue expires immediately, leaving to their estate just the intellectual-property revenue, which, Roesler found, used to decline on average by 10% annually, but now can rise. "I've been assisted by all the technological changes, like AI," he says. "With intellectual property, there are so many different uses of it."</p>

<p>For instance, Travis Cloyd, founder and chief executive officer of Worldwide XR (where Roesler is chairman), has cast Dean in the movie Return to Eden, currently in production. With dead celebrities, there are now two pathways for filmmakers, Cloyd says: "You could either hire an actor, or now, because of the technology, you can create a digital human of James Dean."</p>

<p>The latter process begins with a base of source material, so-called legacy assets that even include family videos. These are put through machine learning to create a digital model of the actor. From there, other elements are created by using body doubles for skin texture and movement, and vocals get layered on top.</p>

<p>It's similar to how Paul Walker (Furious 7) and Peter Cushing (Rogue One: A Star Wars Story) made their controversial CGI appearances almost a decade ago. A large role by Ian Holm, who died in 2020, in this summer's Alien: Romulusinflamed critics and did little to quell the ethical debate around AI, even though his widow, kids and estate signed off.</p>

<p>Hollywood is slowly getting on board after last year's actors' and writers' strikes brought the industry to a standstill over a number of issues, chief among them AI. In August, SAG-Aftra reached a deal allowing brands to replicate living actors' voices in AI audio ads on a job-by-job basis.</p>

<p>For dead ones, Cloyd says, enormous demand will dictate the terms. The potential for AI projects to become the main driver of income for celebrities' estates in the next five years is massive, he says: "With the rise of digital platforms, streaming services and virtual experiences, there are ample opportunities for celebrities to monetize their legacies in new and exciting ways."</p>

<p>Consider ABBA Voyage, which opened in London in May 2022 and has been making more than $2 million a week with concerts featuring de-aged, virtual-reality avatars of the Swedish pop stars. Although the foursome collaborated on the show and were all still alive as of press time, these CGI renderings could theoretically keep minting money for their estates long after their deaths.</p>

<p>Not everyone is convinced. Jeff Jampol, who manages "inactive artists" including Janis Joplin and the Doors, sees AI as a "nonstarter." He's turned down offers to replicate Jim Morrison's voice and casts the technology as a fad akin to nonfungible tokens, or NFTs. "There'll be something else next," he says, noting his decades in the industry seeing "waves come and go." But mostly, "I can't put anything in Jim Morrison's mouth that he didn't say ever. That would be a travesty."</p>

<p>Jampol compares handling the legacy of an artist to having six matches on a fireplace. Each venture they sign on to is like striking a match. "They hold it into the fireplace, and the fireplace glows, and then nine seconds later the match goes out. You're left with an empty, cold, dark fireplace and one burnt match. Just repeat that five times, and it's the end of a legacy for 25 years," he says. "How they lived, what they said and what they created is their legacy. I can't change that."</p>

<p>Svana Gisla, the Emmy- and Grammy-nominated co-producer behind ABBA Voyage, which didn't use AI in cloning the singers, thinks there's one key place the new technology falls short. "We will always be seeking that emotional connection that lies within that communication that art brings," she says, "and AI will never provide that communication or replace artistry in any form."</p>

<p>Perhaps the biggest test of AI will arrive next spring, when Elvis Evolution premieres at ExCeL London and sees the King of Rock 'n' Roll performing for the first time in more than 45 years. For the almost two-hour immersive biopic-think piped-in scents of earthy cotton fields and cranked-up humidity to evoke rural Mississippi-capturing the icon's stage presence in hologram form has been no easy task, says Andrew McGuinness, founder and CEO of Layered Reality, the show's producer.</p>

<p>"It's not a kind of fabrication or the work of a digital artist," he says. "It actually comes from his real-life performances, his real-life facial movements, his real-life voice structure," and it takes hundreds of hours of performance and home videos fed into AI software to create his digital double. Layered Reality had access to the full archive of his home-turned-museum Graceland.</p>

<p>"If you wish to, you can see what he had for lunch on a certain day 45 years ago," says McGuinness. Elvis' favorite dishes might even be available to fans in the bar that keeps the 1960s atmosphere going as they exit the show.</p>

<p>Will the infamous peanut butter, banana and bacon sandwich be on the menu? McGuinness won't say.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/u8dk2gi_ai-michael-jackson-_625x300_23_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Advances in AI mean a late artist like Michael Jackson can still generate new art. (AI Generated Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/biggest-takeaway-from-quad-summit-is-that-its-here-to-stay-6630288]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Biggest Takeaway From Quad Summit Is That It's Here To Stay]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/biggest-takeaway-from-quad-summit-is-that-its-here-to-stay-6630288]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 15:14:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With enduring wars in Europe and the Middle East, China's belligerent activities in the Indo-Pacific region and emerging non-traditional security challenges in the region, the Quad had its task cut out.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/33b0679o_esfsr_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>US President Joe Biden hosted the Prime Ministers of India, Australia, and Japan for the fourth in-person Quad Leaders' Summit at his hometown, Wilmington, last week. This summit was seen as crucial for multiple reasons. First, it was the last one to be attended by Biden, a key architect of the grouping's institutionalisation, and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida, who played a pivotal role in adding political heft to the forum. Second, 2024 marks 20 years since the formation of the grouping. Third, and most importantly, the Wilmington summit further consolidated the grouping by expanding key areas of cooperation in the Indo-Pacific. Indeed, this summit has been successful in signalling - 'The Quad is here to stay'.</p>

<p>At a time of highly complex global crises playing out in different parts of the world, the Quad leaders' summit took place in the context of critical challenges and vital opportunities. With enduring wars in Europe and the Middle East, China's belligerent activities in the Indo-Pacific region and emerging non-traditional security challenges in the region, the Quad had its task cut out. The Wilmington Declaration - the joint statement of the Quad leaders - amply addressed these critical questions.</p>

<h2><strong>The Wilmington Statement</strong></h2>

<p>The joint statement issued by the leaders of the Quad grouping in Wilmington exhibits continuity in responding to the war in Ukraine, reiterating the urgent need to put an end to the conflict and uphold the spirit of international law. Similarly, this year's statement expressed concerns over ballistic missile launches conducted by North Korea and the need to prevent the proliferation of nuclear missiles and technologies. Additionally, the Wilmington Declaration focused on the ongoing conflict in Gaza as well.</p>

<p>The group shared its concerns over the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Gaza advocating for a sovereign, viable, and independent state of Palestine while remaining sensitive to the concerns of Israel. Apart from these, the statement further reiterated concerns over the worsening political and humanitarian situation in Myanmar, as well as attacks by the Houthis in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden.<br />
However, China remained the big-ticket question for the Quad in the Indo-Pacific context. On the China question, Quad's response this year seems sharper than the previous years. Earlier, at the Quad Foreign Ministers' meet, the grouping called Beijing out - albeit without naming it - for disregarding international law and unilaterally acting in the East and South China Sea region. Similarly, the Quad leaders expressed their concern over increasing militarisation in disputed pockets of the Indo-Pacific. Responding to the tensions in the region, the grouping condemned the use of coastguards and maritime militia vessels, which serve as China's tactics for coercive and intimidating manoeuvres.</p>

<h2><strong>A Slew Of Announcements</strong></h2>

<p>Quad's synergy on issues of maritime safety and security in the Indo-Pacific has also gained vital momentum at this summit. A joint coastguard-level cooperation among the four Quad countries - Quad-at-Sea Ship Observer Mission - proposed at the summit seeks to improve interoperability among the coastguard services of the four countries, advancing cooperation in the domain of maritime safety and security. Similarly, responding to the imminent challenges posed by natural calamities and disasters in the Indo-Pacific, the grouping announced the launch of the 'Quad Indo-Pacific Logistics Network', which is meant to pursue shared airlift capacities in a bid to improve cooperation in the domain of Humanitarian Assistance and Disaster Relief (HADR) activities.</p>

<p>Additionally, Quad's efforts to bolster Maritime Domain Awareness through the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness (IPMDA) received a significant push with Australia committing to involve the Pacific Islands Forum Fisheries Agency to enhance cooperation, as well as by the grouping proposing a new Maritime Initiative for Training in the Indo-Pacific (MAITRI). This summit further consolidated its regional partnerships through continued cooperation with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), the Indian Ocean Rim Association (IORA), and the Pacific Islands Forum (PIF). Notably, the Quad Fellowship programme has been expanded to include students from ASEAN countries demonstrating the grouping's inclusion of regional partners in fostering people-to-people ties.</p>

<p>The slew of announcements made at this year's Quad summit, and the resultant Wilmington Declaration, underscore the enduring promise and relevance of the grouping. While Quad continues to respond to critical geopolitical challenges in the world - specifically in the Indo-Pacific - it has also demonstrated a robust positive agenda to harness shared opportunities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Indeed, the Quad is here to stay, in pursuit of a free and open Indo-Pacific - one that is inclusive and resilient.</p>

<p><em>(Harsh V Pant is Vice President for Studies at ORF. Sayantan Haldar works with the Maritime Initiative at ORF)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/33b0679o_esfsr_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stranded-sunita-williams-now-commands-international-space-station-6630143]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Stranded' Sunita Williams Now Commands International Space Station]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stranded-sunita-williams-now-commands-international-space-station-6630143]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 14:57:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams is now commander of the International Space Station. She was in space on an eight-day mission that had to be extended to over eight months because the spacecraft she travelled in faced glitches]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams is now commander of the International Space Station. She was in space on an eight-day mission that had to be extended to over eight months because the Boeing Starliner spacecraft she travelled in faced technical glitches.</p>

<p>NASA has announced that Russian cosmonaut Oleg Kononenko handed over the command of the space station to Sunita Williams at a ceremony onboard the space station.</p>

<p>Kononenko is completing a year-long mission on the station and is among three astronauts, along with Tracy C Dyson and Nikolai Chub, who are set to return to Earth.</p>

<p>Williams has been working aboard the microgravity laboratory to advance scientific knowledge and demonstrate new technologies for future human and robotic exploration missions.</p>

<p>This is the second time Sunita Williams is taking command of the ISS. She last took charge 12 years back. As commander of the International Space Station, her key responsibility will be to maintain safety onboard the space station.</p>

<p>Speaking at the formal handover event, Sunita Williams said. "This Expedition 71 has taught all of us a lot, the ability to adapt, you adopted Butch and me even though that was not part of the plan, you welcomed us as family."</p>

<p>Oleg Kononenko formally handed over a golden key to Sunita Williams -- a part used in the Soyuz spacecraft's docking port. An elated Sunita Williams was seen swirling and playing with the key in the near zero gravity environment of the ISS. In all, she has spent 431 days in space and is likely to return to Earth on the SpaceX Crew Dragon in February.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Sunita Williams shared her thoughts on the unexpected delay and described the International Space Station as her "happy place". She mentioned how life in space has not been a difficult adjustment due to her previous experience -- this is her third sojourn into space.</p>

<p>The International Space Station is like a mini-city in space that has been flying for 25 years. The ISS weighs 419 tonnes, and costs over $150 billion. It is the size of a football field -- about 109 metres long. Astronauts see 16 sunrises daily in its orbit.</p>

<p>On June 6, after she reached the International Space Station, Sunita Williams hugged the crew members. "A big thanks to family and friends who lived this [moment] for a long time. I think you are glad we are not with you anymore and we have another family up here which is just awesome," she said.</p>

<p>Born to Dr Deepak Pandya and Bonnie Pandya, 59-year-old Sunita Williams is also a Navy-trained pilot. She is also a marathon runner and ran one while on the International Space Station.</p>

<p>A lover of Indian cuisine, Sunita Williams will have fish curry during her space flight, NASA has confirmed. During her earlier flights, she has enjoyed samosas in space.</p>

<p>Before her flight, Sunita Williams had told NDTV that she would carry an idol of Lord Ganesh with her as it was her good luck charm.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hpp478o8_sunita-williams_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams has been working aboard the microgravity laboratory]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-images-expose-crater-after-russias-sarmat-missile-test-failure-6629967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Satellite Images Expose Crater After Russia's Sarmat Missile Test Failure]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-images-expose-crater-after-russias-sarmat-missile-test-failure-6629967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 14:31:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian RS-28 Sarmat intercontinental ballistic missile likely failed during a test earlier this month, according to arms experts and satellite imagery from the launch site.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian RS-28 Sarmat intercontinental ballistic missile likely failed during a test earlier this month, according to arms experts and satellite imagery from the launch site.</p>

<p>Maxar satellite images from Sept. 21 show a crater about 60 metres (200 feet) wide at the launch silo at the Plesetsk Cosmodrome in northern Russia and damage around the area that was not visible in imagery from earlier in the month.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">??<br />
<br />
Russia Testing of the new RS-28 Sarmat (Satan II) Nuclear ICBM reportedly failed yet again in Archangelsk, with the giant missile apparently exploding in the silo at launch, leaving a massive crater. <a href="https://t.co/HcogAfV9ad">pic.twitter.com/HcogAfV9ad</a></p>
— Eliyahu Cohen ?️ (@LetJewsLive) <a href="https://twitter.com/LetJewsLive/status/1838046511495618570?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It was not clear from the imagery if the liquid-fuelled Sarmat failed during a launch or if there was an accident during defuelling.</p>

<p>"By all indications, it was a failed test. It's a big hole in the ground," said Pavel Podvig, an analyst based in Geneva, who runs the Russian Nuclear Forces project.</p>

<p>"There was a serious incident with the missile and the silo."</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry did not respond to a request for comment and has made no announcements about planned Sarmat tests in recent days.</p>

<p>The 35-metre RS-28 Sarmat, known as Satan II, has a range of 18,000 km (11,000 miles) and a launch weight of over 208 tonnes and can carry up to 16 multiple independently targetable re-entry vehicle nuclear warheads as well as some Avangard hypersonic glide vehicles, according to Russian media.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pl6si1qg_crater-from-maxar-satellite-x-_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maxar satellite images from Sept. 21 show a crater about 60 metres (200 feet) wide at the launch silo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xiaomi-seeks-recall-of-controversial-antitrust-report-on-flipkart-from-india-6629773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Seeks Recall Of Controversial Antitrust Report On Flipkart From India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xiaomi-seeks-recall-of-controversial-antitrust-report-on-flipkart-from-india-6629773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 14:08:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's Xiaomi has asked India's antitrust body to recall its report that found the company and Walmart's Flipkart breached competition laws, arguing it contains commercial secrets, two people familiar with the matter said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's Xiaomi has asked India's antitrust body to recall its report that found the company and Walmart's Flipkart breached competition laws, arguing it contains commercial secrets, two people familiar with the matter said.</p>

<p>Any recall of the Competition Commission of India (CCI) report could delay its antitrust investigation, which began in 2021. In a rare move in August, the commission recalled an antitrust report on Apple after the company similarly complained commercial secrets were disclosed.</p>

<p>Xiaomi has told the commission in an application the investigation report on Flipkart contains sensitive business data on the smartphone company which was supposed to be redacted when the document was shared with parties in the case, said the two sources familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>One of Xiaomi's concerns with the Flipkart report is that it contains its model-wise sales which is sensitive information, one of the sources said.</p>

<p>Xiaomi, Flipkart and the competition watchdog did not immediately respond to Reuters queries.</p>

<p>The commission does not make investigation reports public and they are only shared with parties to the case. A recall requires parties to return the report which then undergoes further review for redactions.</p>

<p>The watchdog has found that e-commerce giants Amazon and Flipkart gave preference to select sellers and prioritised certain listings, and also colluded with companies like Xiaomi to launch phones exclusively on their websites, Reuters reported this month citing the August reports on Flipkart and Amazon.</p>

<p>Counterpoint Research data shows that South Korea's Samsung and China's Xiaomi are two of India's biggest smartphone players, together holding an almost 36% market share, with China's Vivo on 19%.</p>

<p>Xiaomi is not concerned with data in the report made on Amazon, in which the investigators also said the two companies colluded on online sales in breach of antitrust laws, said both the sources, who declined to be named as the matter is confidential.</p>

<p>It wants the commission to ask parties to return the report and destroy any copies, allowing the watchdog to further redact the sensitive information and reshare the reports, said the first source.</p>

<p>The watchdog took a similar step with its Apple report, which found the U.S. company exploited its dominant position in the market for app stores on its iOS operating system. The company denies wrongdoing.</p>

<p>The commission's Flipkart report said the Indian units of Samsung, Xiaomi, Motorola, Vivo, Lenovo and Realme indulged in the practice of exclusive product launches on Flipkart's shopping website, saying this was "against free and fair competition" and "against the interest of consumers".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3oncjjjg_flipkart-generic_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One of Xiaomi's concerns with the Flipkart report is that it has sensitive info such as model-wise sales.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-africa-to-add-incentives-improve-black-empowerment-system-6629673]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Africa To Add Incentives, Improve Black Empowerment System]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-africa-to-add-incentives-improve-black-empowerment-system-6629673]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 13:55:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of South Africa's flagship Black economic empowerment programme plans to introduce additional incentives and potential fines to improve corporate participation and curb exploitation of the system meant to tackle the country's gross inequalit]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of South Africa's flagship Black economic empowerment programme plans to introduce additional incentives and potential fines to improve corporate participation and curb exploitation of the system meant to tackle the country's gross inequality, he said.</p>

<p>The African National Congress, which had ruled unchallenged for 30 years until it lost its parliamentary majority in the May elections, is under intense pressure to improve the lives of Black people left disadvantaged by decades of white minority rule.</p>

<p>The empowerment law enacted in 2003 created a scorecard system that encourages companies to hire and promote Black people by offering them tax breaks and access to government contracts.</p>

<p>Two decades later, unemployment is five times higher for Black people than for white people and income inequality is the worst in the world, according to the World Bank, and critics say the empowerment policy has not worked. &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There's no society that can be viable with (this) level of inequality," Tshediso Matona, head of the Broad-based Black Economic Empowerment Commission told Reuters.</p>

<p>Under the voluntary programme, companies earn points in categories such as Black ownership, management control and skills development.</p>

<p>However, Matona says some companies inflate their scores by falsely listing Black people as managers, a practice commonly known in South Africa as "fronting", a crime under the law.</p>

<p>The commission, which refers cases of infringement to state prosecutors, has received 1,348 complaints of fronting since 2017, said Matona. He added, without saying how many cases had been sent to trial, that no one had yet been convicted of fronting largely because the criminal justice system was "still figuring out how to work with the B-BBEE regulation".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Listed companies are required to disclose their Black empowerment status in annual reports, but fewer and fewer are doing so. In 2022, only 141 of about 400 listed companies submitted a report.</p>

<p>Matona said he hoped to enhance company incentives for compliance while "naming and shaming" and possibly fining those who fail to submit the reports. &nbsp;</p>

<p>President Cyril Ramaphosa has said he wants to focus on showing companies the advantages of Black empowerment, but that if they refuse to comply then penalties would be needed.</p>

<p>"On this one (Black empowerment), we are unequivocal," Ramaphosa told reporters over a week ago, describing racial inequality as an "existential challenge" for South Africa.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It must be done, and it will be done."</p>

<p>Matona would not be drawn on the specifics of the proposals but said incentives could focus on increasing recognition for companies that invest in skills and enterprise development and should not be "too obsessed about ownership in existing businesses".</p>

<p>He said he hoped to have amendments to the law tabled in parliament within 12 months.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Any inclusion of punitive measures could set the ANC on a collision course with its coalition partner, the pro-business Democratic Alliance party, which has said it would resist them.</p>

<p>"Businesses don't exist for altruistic purposes, we must accept that," said DA labour spokesperson Michael Bagraim.</p>

<h3><strong>'BLACKWASHING' AND TRAINING LOOPHOLES&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>A common criticism of the affirmative action system is that it made a small number of political insiders extremely wealthy through shareholding deals, especially in its early years.</p>

<p>Economist Duma Gqubule said his research - based on an analysis of companies' annual reports and shareholding plans - found Black ownership of the 50 biggest firms listed on the Johannesburg bourse was barely 1%, far below the official average figure of about 30%.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This was because legal loopholes allowed firms to count Black shareholders even after they sold their stake, or to use shareholding structures that artificially increase Black ownership, a practice Gqubule described as "Blackwashing".</p>

<p>Matona blamed a lack of oversight of independent agencies which issue Black empowerment scorecards and said the industry needed regulation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His attempt to shift the focus away from ownership to skills development and training also has loopholes, consultants and trainees Reuters spoke to said.</p>

<p>To get skills points companies must pay for training courses for Black people, but they don't have to hire them. Some engage a consultancy to find them disabled people to train, because these earn more points, the head of one such consultancy said.</p>

<p>This often leaves Black job seekers in a cycle of training.</p>

<p>"They keep on promising us that they will hire us but they've never done that," said Nonhle Mnguni, a 22-year-old woman in Soweto who has done such courses in business administration, banking, freight forwarding and call centre work since leaving high school.</p>

<p>Giles Von Broembsen, CEO of property management company Pretor Group, said his company ran training programmes for employees, more than half of whom are Black, but that he could only earn points by sending them on a training course elsewhere.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The points and the scoring and the system is all very laudable, but it's not practical," he said.</p>

<p>While some political and economic analysts agree with Matona's approach to push for more compliance, others want the law repealed, saying it adds unnecessary bureaucracy which increases business costs and deters foreign investment.</p>

<p>"I think the whole thing should be repealed," said political analyst Moeletsi Mbeki. "(The state) should help entrepreneurs to develop new businesses, irrespective of their race."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sbe9sqn8_south-africa-black-empowering-system-_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Under the voluntary programme, companies earn points in categories such as Black ownership.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-reportedly-incommunicado-israel-investigates-possible-death-reports-6629380]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Hamas Chief Yahya Sinwar Goes Missing, Israel Probes If He Is Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-reportedly-incommunicado-israel-investigates-possible-death-reports-6629380]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 13:41:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas's Gaza-based leader Yahya Sinwar has been incommunicado for a long time, making Israel look for evidence of his possible death.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas's Gaza-based leader Yahya Sinwar has been incommunicado for a long time, making Israel look for evidence of his possible death. Reports by Israel's public broadcaster Kan, news outlets such as Haaretz, Maariv and Walla, and the IDF Military Intelligence Directorate suggested that Sinwar may have been killed in recent Israeli strikes in Gaza. However, there is no concrete evidence to support this claim. Meanwhile, the Shin Bet agency reportedly believes that he is still alive.</p>

<p>According to The Times Of Israel, some reports quoted sources stating that the elusive Hamas chief, who has been hiding in tunnels in Gaza since Hamas's October 7 attack, has a history of going off the radar before reemerging to deliver messages related to the ceasefire negotiations or other issues. Security officials, cited by multiple outlets, noted that any assertion of Sinwar's death was currently speculative and lacked a solid basis.</p>

<p>Haaretz, quoting sources, reported that Israel bombed tunnels in areas where Sinwar was thought to be hiding, but there was no definitive evidence that he was harmed or killed. He may be deliberately maintaining a low profile. The military's response to inquiries was succinct: “We have no information confirming or refuting the matter.”</p>

<p>Since the October 7 attack on Southern Israel -- believed to have been orchestrated by Sinwar -- Israel has targeted key figures within Hamas, including the group's military wing chief, Muhammad Deif, and Khan Younis Brigade chief, Rafa'a Salameh. Hamas chief&nbsp;Ismail Haniyeh and deputy chief Saleh al-Arouri were&nbsp;also killed in drone strikes in Iran and Beirut, respectively,&nbsp;earlier this year. Reports said that&nbsp;Yahya Sinwar and his brother Muhammad remained high-value targets for Israeli forces, yet attempts to locate them have proven unsuccessful.</p>

<p>Reports have also explored the intricate and secretive methods of communication that Sinwar allegedly employs from his hideouts, involving intermediaries and handwritten notes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3d9jl3c8_yahya-sinwar_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas chiefIsmail Haniyeh and deputy chief Saleh al-Arouri werealso killed in drone strikes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jai-hanuman-pm-narendra-modi-greets-rapper-hanumankind-at-new-york-event-6629086]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Jai Hanuman": PM Modi Greets Rapper HanuMankind At New York Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jai-hanuman-pm-narendra-modi-greets-rapper-hanumankind-at-new-york-event-6629086]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 13:01:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi met rapper HanuMankind at the 'Modi and US' event in Long Island, New York, on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi met rapper HanuMankind at the 'Modi and US' event in Long Island, New York, on Sunday. The event, held at the Nassau Coliseum, was part of PM&nbsp;Modi's three-day visit to the US aimed at strengthening ties between the two nations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>HanuMankind, whose real name is Sooraj Cherukat, captivated the audience with his high-energy performance. Several videos of his performance have been shared online.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Viral Singer Hanumankind wows Indian Crowd at PM Modi's community event in NYC<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ModiInUSA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ModiInUSA</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ModiAndUS?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ModiAndUS</a> <a href="https://t.co/1e0rpP7QUO">pic.twitter.com/1e0rpP7QUO</a></p>
— PoliticsSolitics (@IamPolSol) <a href="https://twitter.com/IamPolSol/status/1837893051420688568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Following his set, PM Modi greeted the Kerala-born rapper with a handshake and a hug and praised his performance. The Prime Minister even chanted "Jai Hanuman" before embracing the artist.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">VIDEO | PM Modi (<a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a>) welcomed by music artists Hanumankind, Aditya Gadhvi and Devi Sri Prasad (<a href="https://twitter.com/ThisIsDSP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ThisIsDSP</a>) onstage at the Community Event at Nassau Coliseum in New York earlier today. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PMModiUSVisit?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PMModiUSVisit</a><br />
<br />
(Source: Third Party) <a href="https://t.co/thZKkxDEw2">pic.twitter.com/thZKkxDEw2</a></p>
— Press Trust of India (@PTI_News) <a href="https://twitter.com/PTI_News/status/1837894943391498441?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>HanuMankind, known for tracks like Big Dawgs, Rush Hour, Genghis, and Go To Sleep, is rapidly emerging as a prominent figure in mainstream hip-hop.<br />
<br />
The event also featured performances from other artists, including singer Aditya Gadhvi and composer Devi Sri Prasad. Aditya, known for his viral hit Khalasi, performed in front of a 13,500-strong crowd. Devi Sri Prasad, famous for his work in blockbusters Pushpa: The Rise and Waltair Veerayya, also had the opportunity to meet PM Modi.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAOqbO4PyxT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAOqbO4PyxT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAOqbO4PyxT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAOqbO4PyxT/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Aditya Gadhvi (@adityagadhviofficial)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Members of the Indian expatriates from Tamil Nadu also showcased the traditional musical instrument 'Parai' during the event. Earlier, a group performed Mallakhamb, an acrobatic art form from Maharashtra, outside Nassau Coliseum.</p>

<p>On September 22, the Prime Minister addressed tens of thousands of Indian-Americans at the '<a href="http://https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-us-visit-live-updates-narendra-modi-joe-biden-pm-modi-diaspora-event-modi-and-us-pm-modi-ceo-roundtable-pm-modi-unga-modi-summit-of-the-future-6617764">Modi &amp; US' event</a>. During his speech, he spoke about India's rapid progress and discussed various topics significant to both India and the Indian expatriates.&nbsp;</p>

<p>PM Modi referred to the Indian community in the US as "brand ambassadors" of India. "You are the bridge that connects our two great democracies," he stated, acknowledging the significant contributions of Indian-Americans to both nations.</p>

<p>After the event, PM Modi met the CEOs of several American tech companies at a roundtable in New York. He will attend the United Nations General Assembly in New York today, where he will address the 'Summit of the Future'.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/v9353rq8_hanumankind-modi_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi greeted Kerala-born rapper HanuMankind with a handshake and a hug.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-rise-of-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sri-lankas-new-president-6628769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Rise Of Lanka's Anura Kumara Dissanayake From Grassroots To President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-rise-of-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sri-lankas-new-president-6628769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 12:37:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake has been elected as Sri Lanka’s next president, securing victory in the country’s first election since its economic collapse in 2022.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anura Kumara Dissanayake, a left-leaning leader, has been elected Sri Lanka's next president in the country's first election since its economy collapsed in 2022. Mr Dissanayake, popularly known as “AKD,” was born into a small farming family in Anuradhapura. His political journey began with his involvement in the student wing of the Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP), a Marxist-Leninist party.</p>

<p>Born on November 24, 1968, he comes from a modest background - his father was a government office help and his mother a homemaker. Politics wasn't initially a family pursuit, but Dissanayake's early life experiences, including the loss of his cousin to political violence, drew him to activism.</p>

<p>One of Mr Dissanayake's cousin was killed during the government's crackdown on the JVP's second insurrection in 1988. This period also saw his family home destroyed, deepening his resolve to remain loyal to the JVP's cause.</p>

<h2><strong>Tryst With Politics</strong></h2>

<p>Dissanayaka, a physics graduate, entered politics during the Indo-Sri Lanka agreement of 1987, which aimed to end the Sri Lankan civil war and saw the induction of Indian Peacekeeping Forces (IPKF) in the island nation. From 1987-1989, the JVP - a Marxist political party - led an armed revolt against the Government of Sri Lanka. His association with the party came at a crucial juncture in Sri Lanka's history.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The JVP insurrection saw low-scale violence inflicted on armed forces which was later intensified. In 1997, Dissanayaka was elected to the party's central committee and in 2008 when he became the leader, he apologised for the group's violence during this "season of terror".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A lot of things happened during the armed conflict that should not have happened," he said in a 2014 interview with the BBC.</p>

<h2><strong>Political evolution and leadership</strong></h2>

<p>Initially, the JVP maintained a staunch anti-imperialist and socialist position, but by the 1980s, it shifted towards Sinhala nationalism. The party fiercely opposed Tamil political claims and external intervention in Sri Lanka's ethnic conflict. After being banned in the 1980s and later legalised, the JVP entered mainstream politics, winning seats in parliament. Mr Dissanayake himself became a Member of Parliament in 2000 and briefly served as the Minister of Agriculture under President Chandrika Kumaratunga Bandaranaike between 2004 and 2005.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jkv96n4o_anura-kumara-dissanayaka-afp_625x300_23_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>In 2014, he was appointed leader of the JVP, succeeding Somawansa Amarasinghe. Under his leadership, the party underwent significant changes, focusing on expanding its political base. Recognising that the JVP's traditional appeal was limited, Mr Dissanayeke formed the National People's Power (NPP) Alliance, bringing together over two dozen political groups, professionals, academics, and activists. This move aimed to position the NPP as an alternative to the two traditional political camps — led by the Sri Lanka Freedom Party and the United National Party.</p>

<h2><strong>Leadership and ideology</strong></h2>

<p>Colleagues describe Mr Dissanayake as a clear-headed decision-maker who values collective input, a hallmark of his leadership style. Vijitha Herath, a fellow JVP MP, said that Mr Dissanayake is very good at factoring in multiple views and making the best decision quickly, in real-time.</p>

<p>His calm, composed demeanour and ability to build compelling narratives against Sri Lanka's ruling class have made him a magnetic figure in public life. Known for his powerful speeches in parliament, Sri Lanka's new President has been a vocal critic of government excesses and mismanagement, often stacking his arguments with facts and figures that resonate with the public.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4p78iruo_anura-kumara-dissanayaka-afp_625x300_23_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Under his leadership, the NPP shifted its focus from purely socialist principles to a broader political message, seeking to address corruption and economic mismanagement. This ideological evolution has drawn criticism from some traditional leftists, but Mr Dissanayake remains unapologetic, emphasising that his party's goal is to serve the majority of the people rather than adhere strictly to labels of left-wing politics.</p>

<h2><strong>Presidential run and political campaigns</strong></h2>

<p>In 2019, Mr Dissanayake contested the presidential election against Gotabaya Rajapaksa. While some liberals and leftists feared that his candidacy would split the opposition vote and enable Rajapaksa's victory, Mr Dissanayake's NPP went ahead with the campaign, drawing large crowds but securing only 3.16 per cent&nbsp;of the vote. In the 2020 parliamentary elections, the NPP won just three seats, down from six in the previous term, earning the derisive label of the “3% party” from rivals. Despite these setbacks, Mr Dissanayake and his party doubled down on grassroots mobilisation, expanding their reach through relentless political organizing and engaging with the Sinhala expatriates in Europe, Asia, and North America.</p>

<h2><strong>The 2022 people's uprising</strong></h2>

<p>The turning point came in 2022, during the Janatha Aragalaya, or the people's struggle, resulting in the ouster of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa. Although the movement was decentralised and comprised a wide array of voices, Mr Dissanayake's NPP played a key role in sympathising with the people's demand for “system change” and maintaining its grassroots activism.</p>

<p>As political disillusionment deepened, particularly among the youth, the NPP began to be seen as a viable alternative to Sri Lanka's traditional political elites. Mr Dissanayake's rallies drew large crowds, and his oratory style, which combined calm analysis with impassioned calls for reform, resonated with many.</p>

<p>As Sri Lanka continues to grapple with significant economic challenges and political uncertainty, Mr Dissanayake has emerged as a symbol of hope for many citizens seeking change. At 55, Anura Kumara Dissanayake now stands as a prominent leader who embodies the aspirations of those disillusioned by the country's long-entrenched political elite.</p>

<h2><strong>China Xi Congratulates Him</strong></h2>

<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping congratulated the Marxist leader and said "he looks forward to working together "to jointly carry forward our traditional friendship." Xi Jinping said he hoped to broaden cooperation with Sri Lanka under the so-called Belt and Road initiative. Concerns were being raised about whether Sri Lanka's first Leftist President would incline towards China.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The National People's Power leader, Harini Amarasuriya, told NDTV that Anura Kumara Dissanayake "had a very successful visit to India a few months ago and is conscious of India's position in the world," adding he is "Sensitive to India's concerns about maintaining regional stability and positioning itself as a global leader. Look forward to working closely with India."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6gafankg_anura-kumara-dissanayake_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Colleagues describe Anura Kumara Dissanayake as a clear-headed decision-maker. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankas-first-leftist-president-sworn-in-after-landslide-election-win-6629140]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's First Leftist President Sworn In After Landslide Election Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankas-first-leftist-president-sworn-in-after-landslide-election-win-6629140]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 12:36:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's first leftist president was sworn into office Monday vowing to restore public faith in politics after anger over the island nation's unprecedented economic crisis propelled him to a landslide poll win.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka's first leftist president was sworn into office Monday vowing to restore public faith in politics after anger over the island nation's unprecedented economic crisis propelled him to a landslide poll win.</p>

<p>Self-avowed Marxist Anura Kumara Dissanayaka of the People's Liberation Front (JVP) took his oath at the colonial-era Presidential Secretariat in Colombo after trouncing his nearest rivals in Saturday's vote.</p>

<p>The previously fringe politician -- whose party led two failed uprisings that left tens of thousands dead -- saw a surge of support after the country's 2022 economic meltdown forced painful hardships on ordinary Sri Lankans.</p>

<p>Dissanayaka, 55, was sworn in by the chief justice in a ceremony attended by lawmakers, members of the Buddhist clergy and the military who sang the national anthem after the ceremony.</p>

<p>"I will do my best to fully restore the people's confidence in politicians," Dissanayaka said after taking the oath.</p>

<p>"I am not a conjurer, I am not a magician," he added. "There are things I know and things I don't know, but I will seek the best advice and do my best. For that, I need the support of everyone."</p>

<p>Dissanayaka succeeds outgoing president Ranil Wickremesinghe, who took office at the peak of the financial crisis following the government's first-ever foreign debt default and months of punishing food, fuel and medicine shortages.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Wickremesinghe, 75, imposed steep tax hikes and other austerity measures per the terms of an International Monetary Fund bailout.</p>

<p>His policies ended the shortages and returned the economy to growth but left millions struggling to make ends meet.</p>

<p>"I can confidently say that I did my best to stabilise the country during one of its darkest periods," he said in a statement after placing a distant third in Saturday's poll.</p>

<p>Shortly before the ceremony, Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena resigned, clearing the way for Dissanayaka to appoint his own cabinet.</p>

<p>Dissanayaka's party has said he wants to have his own cabinet until a fresh parliament is elected later this year. His JVP party has only three members in the 225-member parliament.</p>

<p>He has vowed to press ahead with the IMF rescue package negotiated by his predecessor last year but modify its terms in order to deliver tax cuts.</p>

<p>"It is a binding document, but there is a provision to renegotiate," Bimal Ratnayake, a senior member of Dissanayaka's party, told AFP.</p>

<h3><strong>Legacy of violence&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Dissanayaka's party led two rebellions in the 1970s and 1980s that left more than 80,000 people dead before renouncing violence.</p>

<p>It had been a peripheral player in Sri Lankan politics in the decades since, winning less than four per cent of the vote during the most recent parliamentary elections in 2020.</p>

<p>But Sri Lanka's crisis proved an opportunity for Dissanayaka, who saw his popularity rise after pledging to change the island's "corrupt" political culture.</p>

<p>The 55-year-old labourer's son was a JVP student leader during the second insurrection and has described how one of his teachers sheltered him to save him from government-backed death squads that killed party activists.</p>

<p>He counts famous Marxist revolutionary Che Guevara among his heroes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since his rise to popularity, he has softened some policies, saying he believes in an open economy and is not totally opposed to privatisation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fk1nuj6_-anura-kumara-dissanayaka_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayaka of the People's Liberation Front (JVP) was sworn in by the chief justice.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/googles-sundar-pichai-shares-highlights-of-pm-modis-roundtable-with-ceos-6628828]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google's Sundar Pichai Shares Highlights Of PM Modi's Roundtable With CEOs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/googles-sundar-pichai-shares-highlights-of-pm-modis-roundtable-with-ceos-6628828]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 11:47:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi wants to ensure that Artificial Intelligence (AI) technology benefits the people of India and is challenging tech giants to do more in this direction, Google CEO Sundar Pichai has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi wants to ensure that Artificial Intelligence (AI) technology benefits the people of India and is challenging tech giants to do more in this direction, Google CEO Sundar Pichai has said.</p>

<p>"The Prime Minister has been focused on transforming India with his Digital India vision. He pushed us to continue making in India, designing in India. We are proud to now make our Pixel phones manufactured in India. He is thinking about how AI can transform India in a way that benefits the people. He challenged us to think about applications in healthcare, education, and agriculture," the Indian-born industry leader said following his meeting with Prime Minister Modi during his US trip.</p>

<p>"He is also thinking about the infrastructure of India, be it data centres, power, energy, and investing to make sure India can transition. We are proud to be partnering with India. We are robustly investing in AI in India. We look forward to doing more. We have several programmes and partnerships with MeitY, agriculture and health ministries, and central and state governments," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Pichai said the Prime Minister has always challenged them to do more for India. "He is asking to do the same with AI. He has a clear vision, both in terms of the opportunity AI will create, but he wants to make sure that ultimately AI is there to benefit the people of India."</p>

<p>Mr Pichai was among CEOs of tech giants who met Prime Minister Modi for a roundtable in New York today. Hosted by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) School of Engineering, the roundtable was attended by Nvidia's Jensen Huang, Adobe's Shantanu Narayen,&nbsp;Accenture's Julie Sweet, AMD's Lisa Su, Biogen's Chris Viehbacher, HP's Enrique Lores, and IBM's Arvind Krishna, among others.</p>

<p>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang called Prime Minister Modi an "incredible student". "Every time I meet him, he wants to learn more about the technology. Artificial intelligence is a new industry and I am looking forward to partnering with India. We are partnering with many companies, start-ups and IITs in India," he said.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said in a post on X that he had a&nbsp;fruitful roundtable with the tech CEOs and they discussed aspects relating to technology and innovation and more. "Also highlighted the strides made by India in this field. I am glad to see immense optimism towards India," he said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Ministry of External Affairs, the roundtable focused on artificial intelligence and quantum; biotechnology and life sciences; computing, IT and communication; and semiconductor technologies.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister highlighted the economic transformation happening in India, particularly in electronics and information technology manufacturing, semiconductors, biotech and green development. He stated that his government was committed to making India a global hub of semiconductor manufacturing. He also dwelt on India's BIO E3 policy to develop India into a biotech powerhouse. On AI, he noted that India's policy is to promote AI for All, underpinned by its ethical and responsible use," the MEA said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The CEOs expressed their strong interest in investing and collaborating with India. India's growing prominence as a global technology hub, driven by its innovation-friendly policies and flourishing market opportunities, got much appreciation from the tech-leaders," it added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/91b2bcm_modi-ceo-meet_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi shared a picture with the CEOs of tech giants he met in New York]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drugs-baby-oil-video-tools-what-went-on-at-rapper-sean-combs-diddys-freak-offs-6628356]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drugs, Baby Oil, Video Tools: Rapper Diddy's "Freak Off" Sexual Encounters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drugs-baby-oil-video-tools-what-went-on-at-rapper-sean-combs-diddys-freak-offs-6628356]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 11:18:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US government has launched a high-profile sex trafficking and racketeering case against music mogul Sean Combs, aka Diddy, accusing him of orchestrating coercive and abusive sexual encounters at luxury hotels.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US government has launched a high-profile sex trafficking and racketeering case against music mogul Sean Combs, aka Diddy, accusing him of orchestrating coercive and abusive sexual encounters at luxury hotels. The indictment, which includes accusations of arson, bribery, kidnapping and obstruction of justice, centres on what prosecutors refer to as&nbsp;“freak-offs”&nbsp;-&nbsp;“elaborate and produced sex&nbsp;performances,”&nbsp;involving drugs, prostitutes, and recordings - according to a report in the New York Times.&nbsp;Combs'&nbsp;legal team, however, insists these encounters were consensual.</p>

<p>According to the 14-page federal criminal indictment, these&nbsp;“freak-offs”&nbsp;were organised by Combs and his associates in hotel suites filled with baby oil, drugs and video equipment. Prosecutors allege that participants were coerced, with some requiring intravenous fluids to recover from the multi-day ordeals. The government claims Combs filmed the sessions and used the footage to blackmail participants into silence.</p>

<p>“Freak-off activity is the core of this case, and freak-offs are inherently dangerous,”&nbsp;said Emily A Johnson, one of the prosecutors. This depiction&nbsp;is echoed&nbsp;in the civil lawsuit filed by singer Cassie, whose real name is Casandra Ventura, against Combs last year. Cassie claimed that Combs directed frequent freak-offs, where she&nbsp;was coerced&nbsp;into performing sexual acts, which he filmed.</p>

<p>Combs, who has pleaded not guilty, faces a vastly different narrative presented by his defence team. His lawyer, Marc Agnifilo, argued the events were consensual, part of an unconventional but voluntary relationship between Combs and Ventura. Agnifilo pointed out that several men involved denied being coerced or viewing themselves as sex workers.</p>

<p>The racketeering charges stem from allegations that Combs coordinated these events through a network of enablers who managed logistics such as securing prostitutes, booking hotel rooms, and cleaning up after the sessions. Prosecutors argue that violence often accompanied these encounters, a claim the defence denies.</p>

<p>In addition to&nbsp;Ventura's&nbsp;lawsuit, Combs faces a series of other civil suits from women who accuse him of drug-fuelled sexual abuse. One complainant, Adria English, alleged that Combs demanded she has sex with guests at his famous&nbsp;“white parties.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Combs's&nbsp;lawyers have dismissed the lawsuits as opportunistic.</p>

<p>Combs, who remains in federal custody after being denied bail, is accused of attempting to cover up evidence of the abuse. Prosecutors claim he offered hotel staff bribes and&nbsp;attempted&nbsp;to destroy surveillance footage after an alleged assault on Ventura in 2016.The investigation is underway, and&nbsp;Combs's&nbsp;legal battle is far from over.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations against Combs go back to the 1990s when he founded Bad Boy Records, his label, according to Forbes.&nbsp;In 2022, he was in the&nbsp;14the&nbsp;spot among&nbsp;Forbes'&nbsp;list of the highest-paid entertainers after he made an estimated $90 million that year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vgmfpskg_sean-combs_625x300_17_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sean Combs's lawyers have dismissed the lawsuits as opportunistic. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-spits-outside-his-home-dna-match-later-leads-to-his-arrest-in-36-year-old-murder-case-6628436]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Spits Outside His Home, DNA Match Leads To Arrest In Murder Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-spits-outside-his-home-dna-match-later-leads-to-his-arrest-in-36-year-old-murder-case-6628436]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Sep 2024 10:38:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Holloman, who has no prior criminal record, was taken into custody on September 19.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A decades-old cold case has been solved with the arrest of a man accused of murdering a young mother in Boston. James Holloman has been charged with the 1988 stabbing death of Karen Taylor after DNA evidence linked him to the crime scene, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/mans-spit-leads-to-his-arrest-in-1988-cold-case-murder-boston-woman-8716440" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>People</em></a> reported.</p>

<p>Although a check made out to Holloman was found near Taylor's body, authorities had been unable to definitively connect him to the murder until recently. A breakthrough came when Holloman's DNA was collected after he spat on the sidewalk last year.</p>

<p>Investigators compared the DNA to samples found under Taylor's fingernails, on a bloody sweatshirt, and a cigarette discovered near her body. The results confirmed a match, leading to Holloman's arrest.</p>

<p>Holloman, who has no prior criminal record, was taken into custody on September 19. His attorney has expressed scepticism about the DNA evidence, suggesting that it might not be conclusive after so many years.</p>

<p>Suffolk County District Attorney Kevin Hayden told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/boston/news/karen-taylor-1988-murder-boston-james-holloman-dna/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>CBS News</em></a> that this case exemplifies "superb investigative work by detectives and prosecutors utilizing modern criminological science."&nbsp;</p>

<p>He added, "Most importantly, it provides an opportunity for Karen Taylor's loved ones to see someone held accountable for her death after so many years of unanswered questions."</p>

<p>Taylor was found dead on May 27, 1988, in her apartment in Boston's Roxbury neighbourhood at the age of 25.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her body was discovered after her mother called the apartment, and Taylor's 3-year-old daughter answered, saying her mom "was sleeping and she couldn't wake her up," according to a statement from the Suffolk County District Attorney's office, reported by WHDH.</p>

<p>The statement further explained, "The mother went to Taylor's apartment at 37 Williams Street in Roxbury but couldn't access the building. She went around to the back and crawled through the window of her daughter's bedroom, where she found her lying face down in a pool of blood."</p>

<p>An autopsy revealed that Taylor had been stabbed 15 times in her chest, head, and neck.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aek4ib5o_us-police-generic_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[His attorney has expressed scepticism about the DNA evidence]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>