<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:26:35 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-probing-trump-rally-shooting-as-potential-domestic-terrorism-act-6107541]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Probing Trump Rally Shooting As Potential "Domestic Terrorism" Act]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-probing-trump-rally-shooting-as-potential-domestic-terrorism-act-6107541]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:26:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman who shot at former president Donald Trump during an election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday appears to have acted alone, said the FBI, which is probing the incident as a potential "domestic terrorism" act.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman who shot at former president Donald Trump during an election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday appears to have acted alone, said the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), which is probing the incident as a potential "domestic terrorism" act.</p>

<p>The gunman, shot dead by a sniper, has been identified as Thomas Matthew Crooks (20).</p>

<p>"At this point in the investigation, it appears that he was a lone actor, but we still have more investigation to go," said Robert Wells, the executive assistant director of the FBI's National Security Branch.</p>

<p>The FBI, he said, is investigating this as an assassination attempt and also as a "potential domestic terrorism act". The counterterrorism division and criminal divisions are working together to determine the motive, he added.</p>

<p>Trump was left with a bloodied face after a bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear. He is now safe and continuing with his schedule that includes travelling to Milwaukee to attend the Republican National Convention, which would formally nominate him as the party's presidential nominee against incumbent Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The FBI is leading the investigation into the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>"The shooter may be deceased, but the investigation is very much ongoing. And, because of that, we are limited in what we say at this point," FBI Director Christopher Wray said.</p>

<p>"What we witnessed yesterday was nothing short of an attack on democracy and our democratic process," he told reporters at a news conference in Washington DC.</p>

<p>According to an FBI official, the investigation into the gunman at Donald Trump's rally Saturday has not yet turned up any mental health issues, threatening posts, or other motives, but cautioned it was still early.</p>

<p>The shooter, as per FBI, used an AR-style rifle chambered in 5.56mm, a common calibre for such weapons.</p>

<p>The New York Times said authorities were scouring the gunman's social media and other property as they sought to determine a motive for the attack.</p>

<p>Biden is likely to address the nation at 8 pm from the Oval Office. He will give "a forceful and needed address to update the nation on the horrifying attack on Donald Trump and the need for every American to come together to not just condemn, but put to an end political violence in this country once and for all," a campaign official told the daily.</p>

<p>Crooks graduated from the Community College of Allegheny County two months ago, earning an associate degree in engineering science, school officials said in a statement, adding that they were "shocked and saddened by the horrific turn of events."</p>

<p>Kimberly Cheatle, the director of the Secret Service, in a memo to her agents, said "The attempted assassination of former President Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania, is a moment that will forever be remembered in history."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qaseqkio_trump-assassination_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump was left with a bloodied face after a bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/something-triggered-that-what-trump-attackers-former-teacher-said-6107846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Something Triggered That...": What Trump Attacker's Former Teacher Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/something-triggered-that-what-trump-attackers-former-teacher-said-6107846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:15:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The portrait pieced together so far of the 20-year-old nursing home aide who allegedly tried to assassinate Donald Trump at an election rally reveals frustratingly little about why he would make such an attempt - or how he managed to come so close.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The portrait pieced together so far of the 20-year-old nursing home aide who allegedly tried to assassinate Donald Trump at an election rally reveals frustratingly little about why he would make such an attempt - or how he managed to come so close to killing the former president.</p>

<p>The early details that have emerged about Thomas Matthew Crooks, who was shot dead by law enforcement, show a young man working an entry-level job near his hometown in Pennsylvania, where he graduated from high school in 2022 with a reputation as a bright but quiet classmate. His high school counselor described him as "respectful" and said he never knew Crooks to be political.</p>

<p>The FBI said on Sunday that Crooks' social media profile does not contain threatening language, nor have they found any history of mental health issues. They said he acted alone and have not identified a motive.</p>

<p>What is unique about Crooks - when compared to other recent shooters who opened fire at schools, churches, malls and parades - is that he came within inches of killing a presidential candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Saturday afternoon, Crooks slipped onto a rooftop location 140 meters from the stage where Trump was speaking in Butler, Pennsylvania. He then began firing an AR-15-style semiautomatic rifle, purchased by his father, officials said.</p>

<p>The gunfire killed a 50-year-old man, critically wounded two other spectators, and struck Trump's ear - an assassination attempt that has further inflamed an already bitter U.S. political divide.</p>

<p>A resident of Bethel Park, about an hour away from where the shooting occurred, Crooks was a registered Republican who would have been eligible to cast his first presidential vote in the Nov. 5 election in which Trump is challenging President Joe Biden. Public records show his father is a registered Republican and his mother a registered Democrat, and that as a 17-year-old Crooks made a $15 donation to a Democratic Party cause.</p>

<p>Crooks was employed as a dietary aide at a nursing home at the time of the shooting, the home's administrator said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We are shocked and saddened to learn of his involvement as Thomas Matthew Crooks performed his job without concern and his background check was clean," said Marcie Grimm, administrator of the Bethel Park Skilled Nursing and Rehabilitation Center.</p>

<p>NEVER KNOWN TO BE POLITICAL</p>

<p>Two years ago, Crooks graduated from the local high school, where he showed no particular interest in politics, according to one classmate who asked not to be identified. Crooks' interests centered on building computers and playing games, the classmate said in an interview.</p>

<p>"He was super smart. That's what really kind of threw me off was, this was, like, a really, really smart kid, like he excelled," the classmate said. "Nothing crazy ever came up in any conversation."</p>

<p>Jim Knapp, who retired from his job as the school counselor at Bethel Park High School in 2022, said Crooks had always been "quiet as a churchmouse," "respectful" and kept to himself, although he did have a few friends.</p>

<p>He rarely came across Crooks because "he wasn't a needy type kid," Knapp said. Crooks was content to occasionally eat lunch by himself in the school cafeteria, said Knapp, who would engage such students to see if they wanted company.</p>

<p>"Kids weren't calling him names, kids weren't bullying him," Knapp said.</p>

<p>Knapp said he never knew Crooks to be political in any way, even as other kids would sometimes wear Trump or Biden attire. He added that he couldn't recall Crooks ever being disciplined in school.</p>

<p>"Anybody could snap, anybody could have issues," he said. "Something triggered that young man and drove him to drive up to Butler yesterday and do what he did."</p>

<p>Residents near the Crooks' home described feeling shocked and unsettled that an assassination attempt has been linked to a person from the sedate city of 33,000 people.</p>

<p>"Bethel Park is a pretty blue-collar type of area, and to think that somebody was that close is a little insane," said Wes Morgan, a 42-year-old who works at an investment management company and bikes with his children on the same street as the Crooks' residence.</p>

<p>A couple standing on the porch of their nearby brick ranch-style home was left processing the events and spotlight on their neighborhood.</p>

<p>"There's never been a gun issue. There's never been the police being called," Mary Priselac, 67, said alongside her husband. "You kind of have to wonder what didn't he get in life? What led to this extreme?"</p>

<p>Crooks' gun — an AR-style 556 rifle — had been legally bought, the FBI officials said, adding that the FBI believed it had been purchased by the suspect's father. The officials said "a suspicious device" was found in the suspect's vehicle, which was inspected by bomb technicians and rendered safe.</p>

<p>Bruce Piendl, owner of Allegheny Arms and Gunworks in Bethel Park, said guns were part of the culture in the area. "You have to understand in western Pennsylvania we have a rich tradition of hunting and fishing and outdoor stuff," he said. "Within 10 miles (16 km) of here, there are a ton of gun clubs."</p>

<p>Piendl said his record show he did not sell any firearms to the shooter but declined to say whether he sold any to his family.</p>

<p>"That's between me and God," Piendl said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Crooks slipped onto a rooftop near where Trump was speaking and began firing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/so-frightening-photographer-who-captured-bullet-that-hit-trumps-ear-6107808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["So Frightening": Photographer Who Captured Bullet That Hit Trump's Ear]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/so-frightening-photographer-who-captured-bullet-that-hit-trumps-ear-6107808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:07:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The moment a bullet grazed the ear of former US president Donald Trump during an assassination attempt on him at a rally in US's Pennsylvania was captured by a New York Times photographer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The moment a bullet grazed the ear of former US president Donald Trump during an assassination attempt on him at a rally in US's Pennsylvania was captured by a New York Times photographer. The image clicked by Doug Mills, a veteran photographer who was standing just a few feet away from Trump, shows the bullet behind the 78-year-old leader's face after it clipped his right ear.</p>

<p>Mr Mills, who has been covering the US presidents since 1983, said he did not know he had captured the bullet in one of his photographs.</p>

<p>"It happened so fast but now I can see it all in slow-motion. I was taking pictures when the pops started happening. I just happened to have my finger on the shutter and I heard the pops and kept shooting. I didn't know what I had captured but when I got to my laptop I could see that bullet flying behind his head because it is definitely not in the frames right before it and it's not in afterwards. It's only that one frame. I was shooting in 1/1,800 of a second. It captured that streak behind him," he said.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Photo by New York Times photographer Doug Mills shows bullet flying just behind Trump's head. <a href="https://t.co/0ncIBC0i1v">pic.twitter.com/0ncIBC0i1v</a></p>
— The Spectator Index (@spectatorindex) <a href="https://twitter.com/spectatorindex/status/1812293722832318726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The photo he captured shows a long white streak behind Trump's head, showing the apparent path of a bullet used in the assassination attempt against the former president. "I never thought I'd ever see an assassination attempt on a president and be there to photograph it," Mr Mills said.</p>

<p>According to Mills, he was at the right place at the right time and his long experience of covering presidents helped him capture the crucial moments after the attack</p>

<p>"I've covered the president for 40+ years and I've always known which way they come onstage and which way they go off. And the closest stairs were to my right so I ran over to that side and witnessed him being helped up to his feet, and my immediate reaction was "Oh my god! He is alive", he said</p>

<p>The photographer also described the president's initial reaction after he realised that he survived an attempted assassination. "All of a sudden, he got near the edge of the stage and raised up his fist in defiance. And I could see the blood on his face and that defiance went away like in a split second. He became very serious. I thought he looked very pale," Mr Mill said.</p>

<p>"Two very different moments happened, you know, in a matter of seconds. It is a moment unlike any in my lifetime, my history, my job of covering the White House since 1983. You never think about something like this ever happening because it is so frightening," he added.</p>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks. The investigation agency also now released a photo of the young attacker.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Crooks was shot down by Secret Service snipers after he fired multiple shots at the former US president in the rally from a nearby rooftop. Witnesses claimed they tried to warn the security officials about a man moving from roof to roof nearby and laying on his stomach with a gun pointed at the rally.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/os20isd8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The FBI identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-had-appeared-in-ad-for-worlds-largest-money-manager-blackrock-6107796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooter Had Appeared In Ad For World's Largest Money Manager]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-had-appeared-in-ad-for-worlds-largest-money-manager-blackrock-6107796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:03:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks, the 20-year-old who shot at former president Donald Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania, had briefly appeared in a 2022 advertisement for BlackRock Inc, the world's largest money manager.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thomas Matthew Crooks, the 20-year-old who shot at former president Donald Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania, had briefly appeared in a 2022 advertisement for BlackRock Inc, the world's largest money manager.</p>

<p>The ad, filmed at the Bethel Park High School in Pennsylvania, featured Crooks and several other unpaid students in the background, said the investment giant in a statement. Crooks graduated from the school in 2022.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?Trumps Shooter “Thomas Mathew Crooks” was featured in a BLACKROCK COMMERCIAL in 2023!!! <a href="https://t.co/fdbkfHOS04">pic.twitter.com/fdbkfHOS04</a></p>
— The Real World Fan Page (@BeOutTheMatrix) <a href="https://twitter.com/BeOutTheMatrix/status/1812654532352180615?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>BlackRock said it has pulled the ad but the video will be available to authorities. The ad, however, is being widely shared by social media users.</p>

<p>"The assassination attempt on former President Trump is abhorrent. We're thankful former President Trump wasn't seriously injured, and thinking about all the innocent bystanders and victims of this awful act, especially the person who was killed," the company added in its statement.</p>

<p>BlackRock, whose earnings figures are expected today, has faced scrutiny after shooting incidents since some of its index funds own shares in gunmakers.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump Assassination Attempt</strong></h2>

<p>Trump survived an assassination attempt on Saturday after a gunman opened fire at him at a rally in Pennsylvania ahead of the Presidential elections. The attack left him with a bloodied face as the former president said the bullet pierced his "upper part of right ear".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gjebfnog_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A bystander died in the attack while shielding his family and Crooks - a registered Republican - was shot dead by a Secret Service sniper.</p>

<p>Trump, whose Republican candidature will be finalised today, shared a message of unity after the attack and said Americans must not allow "evil to win". "It was God alone who prevented the unthinkable from happening," he said on social media.</p>

<p>Biden, too, appealed to the nation to "lower the political temperature" in a rare Oval Office address. "Politics must never be a literal battlefield, God forbid a killing field," he said.</p>

<p>The US markets are expecting Trump trades to gain momentum after the attack. It has already been pinning hopes for the return of Republicans, especially after Biden's poor performance in last month's debate. Those trades are likely to take deeper hold as the attack sparks a wave of sympathy and support for Trump.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hv9t3jhg_thomas-crooks-_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A screengrab of Thomas Crooks from the BlackRock ad that aired in 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-markets-ramp-up-the-trump-trade-after-assassination-attempt-6107581]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Global Markets Ramp Up The 'Trump Trade' After Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-markets-ramp-up-the-trump-trade-after-assassination-attempt-6107581]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 08:04:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As world financial markets started to reopen after the attempted assassination of Donald Trump, one thing seemed likely: The Trump trade will get even more momentum.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As world financial markets started to reopen after the attempted assassination of Donald Trump, one thing seemed likely: The Trump trade will get even more momentum.</p>

<p>The series of wagers - based on anticipation that the Republican's return to the White House would usher in tax cuts, higher tariffs, and looser regulations - had already been gaining ground since President Joe Biden's poor performance in last month's debate imperiled his re-election campaign.</p>

<p>But the trades were expected to take deeper hold, with Trump galvanizing supporters and drawing sympathy by exhibiting defiant resilience after being shot in the ear on stage at a Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>The dollar - which would gain if loose fiscal policy kept bond yields elevated - started to move higher against most peers early in Asia trading, with the Mexico peso leading the slide, weakening 0.3%. Bitcoin rose above $60,000, potentially reflecting Trump's crypto-friendly stance, while futures on the S&amp;P 500 Index for September rose 0.2% at 08:47 p.m. in New York.</p>

<p>"For us, the news does reinforce that Trump's the frontrunner," said Mark McCormick, global head of foreign-exchange and emerging-market strategy at Toronto Dominion Bank. "We remain US dollar bulls for the second half and early 2025."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9thpq1vo_gfx1_625x300_15_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>To be sure, there's still plenty of room for surprises with almost four months to go in the US election campaign. The emergence of political violence may deepen concern about instability in the US and push investors into haven assets, potentially overshadowing some of the market positioning that has already taken place in the run-up to the election.</p>

<p>While future contracts on 10-year Treasury notes for September showed declines in early Asia trading, US government bonds tend to rally when investors seek temporary safety, so that may distort the Trump trade in the Treasuries market, which hinges on wagering that the yield curve will steepen as long-term bonds underperform on anticipation that Trump's fiscal and trade policies will fan inflation pressures.</p>

<p>Moreover, some investors may want to book early gains or be wary of getting deeper into an already crowded position.</p>

<p>"Political risk is binary and hard to hedge, and uncertainty was high as it is with the close nature of the race," said Priya Misra, a portfolio manager at JPMorgan Investment Management.</p>

<p>"This adds to volatility. I think it further increases the chance of a Republican sweep," she said, adding that "could put steepening pressure on the curve."</p>

<p>Equity investors are preparing for at least a near-term jump in volatility when S&amp;P 500 futures start trading at 6 p.m. in New York.</p>

<p>While traders generally don't expect Trump's assassination attempt to derail the stock-market trajectory in the long run, a pick-up in near-term price swings is likely. The market has already been contending with speculation that valuations have become too stretched, given the boom in artificial-intelligence stocks and the risks posed by elevated interest rates and political uncertainty.</p>

<p>But investors have also been anticipating that bank, health-care and oil-industry stocks would benefit from a Trump victory.</p>

<p>"The attack will boost volatility," said David Mazza, CEO at Roundhill Investments, predicting investors could seek temporary safety in defensive stocks like mega-cap companies. He said it "also adds support for stocks that do well in a steepening yield curve, especially financials."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/sqh9hou_gfx2_625x300_15_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The early reaction echoes what was seen after the first presidential debate in late June, when Biden's weak performance was seen as fueling Trump's election odds.</p>

<p>The dollar advanced during that event, and investors soon began embracing a wager that involves buying shorter-maturity notes and selling longer-term ones - known as a steepener trade. That trade has been paying off, with the 30-year Treasury yields jumping to nearly 5 basis points below 2-year ones from around 37 basis points below ahead of the debate.</p>

<p>"If the market sense that Trump's chances to win are higher than they were on Friday - then we would expect the back end of the bond market to sell off in the manner we saw in the immediate aftermath of the debate," Michael Purves, CEO and founder of Tallbacken Capital Advisors, wrote in an email.</p>

<p>While bond traders have been pricing in at least two interest-rate reductions in 2024, a major boost in Trump's election odds could push the Federal Reserve toward staying on hold for longer, according to Purves.</p>

<p>"Trump's stated policies are (at least now) more inflationary than Biden's," he wrote, "and we think the Fed will want to accumulate as much dry power as possible."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/i307oeg8_wall-street-generic-bloomberg_625x300_12_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The emergence of political violence may deepen concern about instability in the US. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooting-changes-bidens-plan-to-revive-presidential-campaign-6107578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooting Changes Biden's Plan To Revive Presidential Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooting-changes-bidens-plan-to-revive-presidential-campaign-6107578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 08:03:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden had just begun to turn the tables in his reelection bid when the attempt on Donald Trump's life took away his most powerful tool: drawing attention to his opponent's behavior and second-term agenda.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden had just begun to turn the tables in his reelection bid when the attempt on Donald Trump's life took away his most powerful tool: drawing attention to his opponent's behavior and second-term agenda.</p>

<p>Battered by doubts about his mental fitness and pressure to step aside, Biden fought back on Friday with an energetic speech in Detroit vowing to "shine a spotlight" on Trump - an argument he planned to drive home until Election Day in November.</p>

<p>About 24 hours later, and just under 200 miles away, shots rang out at Trump's rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, the chilling apex of an era in American politics defined by radicalized views and heated rhetoric.</p>

<p>Biden's beleaguered campaign is now limited in how it can push forward. The outburst of political violence stymies his efforts to argue his case. It also threatens to undercut a core premise of his presidency - that he would restore decency and normalcy to national politics.</p>

<p>Instead, the president will hope that a unifying message in a time of crisis resonates with voters. Biden announced he would deliver a rare Oval Office address at 8 p.m. local time. He plans to call on Americans to come together and end political violence, a campaign official said.</p>

<p>"There's no place in America for this kind of violence," Biden told reporters on Sunday at the White House. "Unity is the most elusive goal of all, but nothing is as important than that right now."</p>

<p>The intense focus on the attempted assassination does offer Biden a reprieve from the conversation that had dominated headlines for weeks: whether he should withdraw after his disastrous debate. One Democratic donor, speaking on the condition of anonymity, said that they previously believed the party would be best served by replacing Biden, but there's no way that could happen now without contributing to a sense of chaos.</p>

<p>The shooting - and Trump's iconic, bloodied, fist-pumping response - seems certain to rally voters and donors behind the Republican candidate.</p>

<p>Business leaders Elon Musk and Bill Ackman, who previously resisted endorsing the former president, came out with public statements backing Trump within minutes of his being struck.</p>

<p>It will be days or weeks before public opinion surveys are released assessing the aftermath. But former President Ronald Reagan saw a substantial increase in support when he was shot and wounded in 1981. Many presidential historians say that attack cemented his status in the conservative movement.</p>

<p>By contrast, Biden must balance how to push forward without seeming insensitive.</p>

<p>The president plans to reiterate his condemnation of violence in politics on Monday in a prime-time interview with NBC News, then his political operation will pivot back to drawing contrasts between Biden's vision and Trump's, the campaign official said. Biden will not shy away from talking about the stakes of the election, and his campaign sees the tragedy in Pennsylvania as reinforcing the central thesis of his campaign, the official added.</p>

<p>The president expressed sympathy for Trump on Sunday while vowing a "thorough and swift" federal investigation, a Secret Service probe into its security measures and an independent review of the shooting that he pledged to release to the American people.</p>

<p>Biden urged people not to "make assumptions" about the gunman's "motives or his affiliations," imploring the public to "let the FBI do their job, and their partner agencies do their job."</p>

<p>With Election Day less than four months away, Biden badly needs to reverse his standing. He trails Trump by nearly 3 percentage points, according to the RealClearPolitics polling average.</p>

<p>Figures on both sides of the aisle have called for leaders to rise above the political fray and attempt to heal national divisions. The shooting confirmed the fears of half of swing-state voters, who said in a Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll in May that they were worried about violence surrounding the election.</p>

<p>Already, the president's campaign said it would pause messaging and television ads. Biden postponed a Monday speech in Austin to mark the 60th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act. His campaign canceled a Monday event counter-programming the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee. Vice President Kamala Harris delayed political travel originally scheduled for Tuesday in Florida, according to a campaign official.</p>

<p>Biden will not be off the road for long. He plans to travel to Las Vegas to address Black and Latino advocacy groups on Tuesday and Wednesday and sit for another interview with BET, the White House said.</p>

<p><strong>Republican Criticism</strong></p>

<p>While law enforcement officials, and Trump himself, have not ascribed a motive to the shooter, some Republicans have already made unsubstantiated claims blaming Biden for motivating the would-be assassin.</p>

<p>"The central premise of the Biden campaign is that President Donald Trump is an authoritarian fascist who must be stopped at all costs," Ohio Senator J.D. Vance, a possible Trump running mate, posted on X. "That rhetoric led directly to President Trump's attempted assassination."</p>

<p>Supporters of the president pointed to his call for unity after the shooting. Biden said he had a "short but good" call with Trump.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign official denounced the criticism from some GOP lawmakers, calling politicization of the tragedy an unacceptable abdication of leadership.</p>

<p>Still, the failed assassination attempt shifts the dynamics of the race in Trump's favor.</p>

<p>It's a remarkable twist of fate for Trump, who has glorified violence throughout his political career, from encouraging rally attendees in 2016 to "knock the crap" out of protesters to telling supporters to "fight like hell" on Jan. 6, 2021, just before they stormed the US Capitol.</p>

<p>"Biden's inevitable ritual condemnation of political violence today (when it comes) will be insufficient and irrelevant," posted Vivek Ramaswamy, who ran against Trump in the 2024 GOP primaries.</p>

<p><strong>Defiant Images</strong></p>

<p>Republican pollster Frank Luntz said the shooting guarantees "every Trump voter will actually vote," while Biden won't be able to count on that certainty. The biggest effect is likely to be in battleground Pennsylvania - a must-win for Biden - because that is where the shooting occurred, he said.</p>

<p>"The long and winding road for Joe Biden just became even longer and windier," Luntz posted on X. "The shooting of Donald Trump will be significantly consequential in a way the shooter never intended."</p>

<p>With Trump dominating the national conversation, there's little Biden can do in the near term to push his anti-Trump message, mend Democratic divisions and shift the dynamics of the race in a way that reassures skeptics.</p>

<p>"This has got to help Donald Trump, at least for a while, with independents," said Matthew Wilson, a Southern Methodist University political science professor. "Those images showing a defiant Donald Trump with blood on his face and his fist in the air are better advertising than anything money can buy."</p>

<p>Others urged caution in overstating the impact of the moment. They pointed to a minimal shift in polls after other seismic events, including Biden's debate catastrophe and Trump's conviction in the New York hush-money trial.</p>

<p>Senator Bernie Sanders, a progressive stalwart, expressed confidence in Biden's chances as long as he focuses on his plans for a second term to bolster the social safety net, slash drug prices and expand workers' rights.</p>

<p>"If he continues to talk about that, I think he gets reelected," Sanders said on NBC's Meet the Press.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pg7gshog_gunfire-at-trump-rally_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's beleaguered campaign is now limited in how it can push forward]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-photo-of-thomas-matthew-crooks-20-year-old-loner-who-shot-at-trump-6107465]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1st Photo Of Thomas Matthew Crooks, 20-Year-Old "Loner" Who Shot At Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-photo-of-thomas-matthew-crooks-20-year-old-loner-who-shot-at-trump-6107465]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 07:30:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hours after a bullet grazed former US president Donald Trump' ear at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania on Sunday sending shockwaves throughout the country, the FBI identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hours after a bullet grazed former US president Donald Trump' ear at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania on Sunday sending shockwaves throughout the country, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.</p>

<p>"The FBI has identified Thomas Matthew Crooks, 20, of Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, as the subject involved in the assassination attempt of former President Donald Trump on July 13, in Butler, Pennsylvania," the FBI said in a statement.</p>

<p>The investigation agency has now released a photo of the young attacker. The image shows the 20-year-old wearing glasses and smiling into the camera.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Crooks was shot down by Secret Service snipers after he fired multiple shots at the former US president in the rally from a nearby rooftop. Witnesses claimed they tried to warn the security officials about a man moving from roof to roof nearby and laying on his stomach with a gun pointed at the rally.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An assault rifle, AR-15, was found near his body.</p>

<p>Described as a "quiet" student and a "loner", Crooks had graduated in 2022 from Bethel Park High School, and received a $500 "star award" from the National Math and Science Initiative.</p>

<p>A registered Republican, the upcoming November 5 election would have been the first time he would have voted in a presidential election.</p>

<p>His schoolmates labelled him as "socially reserved" and did not recall him ever discussing politics or Trump but mentioned that he was often bullied at school. "He was quiet but he was just bullied. He was bullied so much," a student told local US media.</p>

<p>After graduating, he had been working at a nursing home.</p>

<p>Following the attack, a "suspicious device" was found inside his car, which is now being inspected by bomb technicians. Officials are now searching through his phone.</p>

<p>The Sunday attack was a close call for Trump, who is currently in the middle of a bid to be re-elected as the President of the United States. Videos show that a last second tilt of his head saved the leader's life as the bullet clipped his ear.</p>

<p>A video showed the 78-year-old Republican leader, with blood smeared on his face, raising his fist and muttering "Fight! Fight!" as Secret Service agents whisked him off the stage after the attack.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7bpe1ibo_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks-afp_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Crooks was shot down by Secret Service snipers after he fired multiple shots.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-us-president-donald-trump-reaches-milwaukee-for-republican-convention-after-assassination-attempt-6107449]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Reaches Milwaukee For Republican Convention After Assassination Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-us-president-donald-trump-reaches-milwaukee-for-republican-convention-after-assassination-attempt-6107449]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 07:23:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump arrived on Sunday in Milwaukee, where he will be formally nominated as the Republican presidential candidate later this week after surviving an assassination attempt that aggravated an already bitter U.S. political divide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump arrived on Sunday in Milwaukee, where he will be formally nominated as the Republican presidential candidate later this week after surviving an assassination attempt that aggravated an already bitter U.S. political divide.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, a Democrat, ordered a review of how a 20-year-old man with an AR-15-style rifle got close enough to shoot at Trump from a rooftop on Saturday. As a former president, Trump has lifetime protection by the U.S. Secret Service.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was holding a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania - a key state in the Nov. 5 election - when shots rang out, hitting his right ear and leaving his face streaked with blood. His campaign said he was doing well.</p>

<p>One person in the crowd was killed and two others were wounded. Secret Service agents fatally shot the suspect, the agency said.</p>

<p>Biden sought to calm the country on Sunday, delivering a brief televised address from the Oval Office in the White House.</p>

<p>"There is no place in America for this kind of violence, for any violence ever. Period. No exceptions. We can't allow this violence to be normalized," he said. "The political rhetoric in this country has gotten very heated. It's time to cool it down."</p>

<p>Trump and Biden are locked in a close election rematch, according to most opinion polls including Reuters/Ipsos. The shooting on Saturday whipsawed discussion around the campaign, which had been focused on whether Biden, 81, should drop out following a halting June 27 debate performance.</p>

<p>Trump is due to receive his party's formal nomination at the Republican National Convention, which kicks off in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, on Monday. The FBI said there were no known threats to the convention or anyone attending, while the Secret Service said they do not anticipate any changes to the security plan.</p>

<p>"I was going to delay my trip to Wisconsin, and The Republican National Convention, by two days, but have just decided that I cannot allow a 'shooter,' or potential assassin, to force change to scheduling, or anything else," Trump wrote on his Truth Social site on Sunday.</p>

<p>The convention will feature televised speeches by rising Republican stars and Trump's choice for a yet-to-be-announced vice presidential running mate while highlighting the party's stance on such topics as abortion, immigration and the economy.</p>

<h3><strong>SUSPECT A NURSING HOME AIDE</strong></h3>

<p>The FBI identified Thomas Matthew Crooks of Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, as the suspect and said the shooting was being investigated as an attempted assassination.</p>

<p>FBI officials said on Sunday that the shooter acted alone. The agency said it had yet to identify an ideology linked to the suspect or any indications of mental health issues or found any threatening language on the suspect's social media accounts.</p>

<p>Crooks was a registered Republican, according to state voter records, and donated $15 to a Democratic political action committee when he was 17. At the time of the shooting, he was employed as a dietary aide at a nursing home. The Bethel Park Skilled Nursing and Rehabilitation Center said Crooks "performed his job without concern and his background check was clean."</p>

<p>The gun - an AR-style 556 rifle - had been legally bought, FBI officials said, adding they believed it had been purchased by the suspect's father. The officials said "a suspicious device" was found in the suspect's vehicle, which was inspected by bomb technicians and rendered safe.</p>

<h3><strong>SPECTATOR KILLED PROTECTING FAMILY</strong></h3>

<p>The rally attendee killed on Saturday was identified by authorities as Corey Comperatore, 50, of Sarver, Pennsylvania. He died trying to protect his family from the hail of bullets, said Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro.</p>

<p>"Corey was an avid supporter of the former president, and was so excited to be there," Shapiro said, adding, "Political disagreements can never, ever be addressed through violence."</p>

<p>Two people wounded in the shooting were in stable condition on Sunday. Pennsylvania State identified them as David Dutch, 57, of New Kensington, Pennsylvania and James Copenhaver, 74, of Moon Township, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The Secret Service denied accusations by some Trump supporters that it had rejected a campaign request for more security, saying that it recently "added protective resources and capabilities to the former President's security detail."</p>

<p>The shots on Saturday appeared to come from outside the area secured by the Secret Service, the agency said.</p>

<p>Hours after the assassination attempt, the Oversight Committee in the Republican-led U.S. House of Representatives summoned Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle to testify at a hearing scheduled for July 22.</p>

<p>Residents of Bethel Park, where the suspected shooter lived, expressed shock at the news on Sunday.</p>

<p>"It's a little crazy to think that somebody that did an assassination attempt is that close, but it just kind of shows the political dynamic that we're in right now with the craziness on each side," said resident Wes Morgan, 42, describing Bethel Park as "a pretty blue-collar type of area."</p>

<h3><strong>POLITICAL VIOLENCE FEARS</strong></h3>

<p>While mass shootings at schools, nightclubs and other public places are common in the United States, the attack was the first shooting of a U.S. president or major party presidential candidate since the 1981 attempted assassination of Republican President Ronald Reagan.</p>

<p>Americans fear rising political violence, Reuters/Ipsos polling shows, with two out of three respondents to a May survey saying they worried violence could follow the election.</p>

<p>After Biden defeated Trump in the 2020 election, Trump supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021, in a deadly riot fueled by Trump's false claims that his loss was the result of widespread fraud.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j63gcls_trump-shooting-reuters_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is due to receive his party's formal nomination at the Republican National Convention.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/were-not-enemies-joe-bidens-rare-address-after-trump-assassination-attempt-6107421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trump Rally Shooting Calls On Us To Take Step Back": Biden In Rare Address]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/were-not-enemies-joe-bidens-rare-address-after-trump-assassination-attempt-6107421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 07:19:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden sent out a message of unity a day after his rival-predecessor Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt, calling on the nation to lower the temperature of hostile politics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden sent out a message of unity a day after his rival-predecessor Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt, calling on the nation to lower the temperature of hostile politics.</p>

<p>In a rare Oval Office address on Sunday, Biden maintained that fellow Americans are not enemies, but friends and co-workers who must stand together despite disagreements.</p>

<p>"I want to speak to you tonight about the need for us to lower the temperature in our politics and to remember, when we disagree, we are not enemies, we are neighbours, we are friends, co-workers, citizens and&nbsp;most importantly, we are fellow Americans. We must stand together," he said.</p>

<p>Politics must never be a literal battlefield, God forbid a killing field, he added.</p>

<p>Trump, the 78-year-old Republican whose candidature in the Presidential elections is all but finalised, was left with a bloodied face after being hit in the ear at a rally in Pennsylvania while a bystander was killed in the attack.</p>

<p>The shooter, Thomas Matthew Crooks - a registered Republican, was shot dead at the spot.</p>

<p>After the attack, Trump too shared a message of unity and said Americans must not allow "evil to win". "It was God alone who prevented the unthinkable from happening," he said on social media.</p>

<p>Biden, in a televised address from behind the historic Resolute Desk, said it's time to "cool down" the country's political record.</p>

<p>"Yesterday's shooting at Donald Trump's rally in Pennsylvania calls on all of us to take a step back, take stock of where we are, how we go forward from here...Unity is the most elusive goal of all, but nothing is important than that right now - unity," he told the nation.</p>

<p>Both sides had a responsibility to ease the situation, said the 81-year-old Democrat.</p>

<p>"We debate and disagree, we compare and contrast...but in America, we resolve our differences at the ballot box," he added.</p>

<p>Biden had earlier denounced the shooting incident in an online post, asserting there's no place in America for any kind of violence. Earlier in the day, he said he had a "short but good conversation" after the attack with Trump.</p>

<p>"As assassination attempt is contrary to everything we stand for as a nation. It's not America, and we cannot allow this to happen," he said earlier in the day.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ldokppi8_joe-biden-oval-office-afp_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden said it's time to "cool down" the country's political record.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-melania-trump-said-on-assassination-attempt-on-husband-donald-trump-6107359]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Melania Trump Said On Assassination Attempt On Husband Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-melania-trump-said-on-assassination-attempt-on-husband-donald-trump-6107359]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 07:00:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former first lady Melania Trump said Sunday that a gunman who opened fire at a Donald Trump rally was a "monster," as she condemned the assassination attempt in which the Republican presidential candidate was injured.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former first lady Melania Trump said Sunday that a gunman who opened fire at a Donald Trump rally was a "monster," as she condemned the assassination attempt in which the Republican presidential candidate was injured.</p>

<p>"A monster who recognized my husband as an inhuman political machine attempted to ring out Donald's passion -- his laughter, ingenuity, love of music, and inspiration," Melania Trump said in a statement shared on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/IGIWzL6SMJ">pic.twitter.com/IGIWzL6SMJ</a></p>
— MELANIA TRUMP (@MELANIATRUMP) <a href="https://twitter.com/MELANIATRUMP/status/1812492817068945437?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"When I watched that violent bullet strike my husband, Donald, I realized my life, and Barron's life, was on the brink of devastating change," she said, referencing the couple's 18-year-old son.</p>

<p>"I am grateful to the brave Secret Service agents and law enforcement officials who risked their own lives to protect my husband," Melania Trump said.</p>

<p>Donald Trump said he was hit in the ear when a shooter targeted an election campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania on Saturday.</p>

<p>The shooter and a bystander were killed, while two spectators were critically injured.</p>

<p>Melania Trump said she offered her "sincerest sympathy" to the families of the victims, saying: "Your need to summon your inner strength for such a terrible reason saddens me."</p>

<p>Melania, 54, has barely engaged with her husband's White House campaign, failing to appear at a single Trump rally and rarely joining him in public.</p>

<p>She has also remained largely absent during the former president's multiple court appearances in recent months to fight legal cases against him and as he cranks up his 2024 election campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/bf125gfo_melania-trump-afp-photo_625x300_09_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Melania Trump said she offered her "sincerest sympathy" to the families of the victims.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-to-cool-it-down-biden-addresses-us-after-trump-assassination-bid-6107323]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Time To Cool It Down": Biden Addresses US After Trump Assassination Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-to-cool-it-down-biden-addresses-us-after-trump-assassination-bid-6107323]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 06:44:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden sought to calm a divided nation after his rival Donald Trump survived an assassination bid, saying in a rare Oval Office address Sunday it was time to lower the temperature of America's hostile politics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden sought to calm a divided nation after his rival Donald Trump survived an assassination bid, saying in a rare Oval Office address Sunday it was time to lower the temperature of America's hostile politics.</p>

<p>"You know, the political record in this country has gotten very heated. It's time to cool it down," Biden said in the televised speech, just the third he has given from behind the historic Resolute Desk during his presidency.</p>

<p>As the country reeled from images of a bloodied Trump waving his fist after a gunman opened fire at a rally in Pennsylvania, Biden added that US politics "must never be a literal battlefield, a God forbid, a killing field."</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Democrat said that both sides had a responsibility to ease the situation ahead of a deeply polarized election that would now be a "time of testing" for the United States.</p>

<p>The short but forceful speech went without any major hitches -- bar Biden twice referring to the ballot box as a "battle box" -- with the ageing president under close scrutiny following a disastrous debate performance against Trump recently.</p>

<p>Investigators said that they were still probing the motives of 20-year-old gunman Thomas Matthew Crooks, who was shot dead by snipers at the event in Butler, Pennsylvania, on Saturday after firing multiple shots with a legally-bought semi-automatic rifle.</p>

<p>Former President Trump said on social media Sunday that Americans should not allow "evil to win," adding it was "more important than ever that we stand United."</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Republican later added on social media that it was "God alone" who had saved him. Trump's wife Melania called the shooter a "monster."</p>

<h3><strong>Security questions&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Trump was hit in the ear and left with a bloodied face by the attack, which also killed a bystander while two other people were wounded, but he managed to raise a defiant fist to the crowd as Secret Service agents bundled him away.</p>

<p>He landed later Sunday in Milwaukee for the Republican National Convention, where he will be anointed as the party's presidential nominee, with supporters believing the attack will swing voters behind him in November.</p>

<p>The US Secret Service insisted the agency is "fully prepared" to maintain security at the huge Republican gathering, and that it was not changing its protocols even after the attempt to kill Trump.</p>

<p>But the agency faces searching questions about how the shooter was able to climb onto a rooftop around 150 meters (500 feet) from where Trump was speaking and fire multiple rounds.</p>

<p>Biden said earlier that he had a "short but good conversation" after the attack with Trump.</p>

<p>Investigators are now trying to figure out what drove the shooter, with the FBI saying it believed that Crooks acted alone and had no known ideology.</p>

<p>"We are investigating this as an assassination attempt, but also looking at it as a potential domestic terrorism act," Robert Wells, assistant director of the FBI counterterrorism division, told reporters.</p>

<p>The FBI said the AR-style 556 rifle was believed to have been bought by the shooter's father, but do not yet know how he accessed the weapon or whether he took it without his father's knowledge.</p>

<p>Investigators also found a "suspicious device" in the shooter's car.</p>

<h3><strong>'Bullied'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Crooks' former schoolmates described him as a quiet student who often came across as lonely.</p>

<p>"He was quiet but he was just bullied. He was bullied so much," Jason Kohler, who said he attended the same high school as Crooks, told reporters.</p>

<p>Biden meanwhile praised the bystander who was killed, named as firefighter Corey Comperatore, saying he "was protecting his family from the bullets."</p>

<p>The attempt on Trump's life sent shock waves around the world, but the effects on a tight US presidential race in a deeply divided country are uncertain.</p>

<p>US politics have become increasingly hostile, with Trump building his image around inflammatory verbal assaults, and many Democrats expressing fury and disgust at Trump's rise.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dkviueqo_joe-biden-afp-_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden said that both sides had a responsibility to ease the situation ahead of the elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-faces-scrutiny-after-trump-assassination-attempt-6107111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Secret Service Faces Scrutiny After Trump Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-faces-scrutiny-after-trump-assassination-attempt-6107111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 05:31:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Secret Service was under intense scrutiny on Sunday after a gunman managed to evade its agents and open fire on former President Donald Trump at a political rally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Secret Service was under intense scrutiny on Sunday after a gunman managed to evade its agents and open fire on former President Donald Trump at a political rally, with Republican leaders vowing swift investigations and President Joe Biden calling for an independent review.</p>

<p>The gunman, a 20-year-old Pennsylvania man, injured Trump and killed a rally attendee from a rooftop perch around 150 yards (140 m) from the stage where the former president was speaking in Butler, Pennsylvania, near Pittsburgh, officials said.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, who like other former presidents has lifetime protection by the Secret Service, was swarmed by agents who then rushed him away. Agents killed the shooter, identified by the FBI as Thomas Matthew Crooks of Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, and an AR-15-style semiautomatic was recovered near his body, officials said.</p>

<p>Trump says a bullet hit his upper right ear but that he is otherwise doing well and would travel to the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, where he will receive his party's presidential nomination.</p>

<p>Mike Johnson, speaker of the Republican-controlled US House of Representatives, said panels in the chamber will call officials from the Secret Service, the Department of Homeland Security and the FBI for hearings.</p>

<p>"The American people deserve to know the truth," Johnson said.</p>

<p>The House oversight panel called Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle to testify on July 22.</p>

<p>The Secret Service, tasked with protecting current and former presidents, is part of the Department of Homeland Security. The department's Office of the Inspector General is responsible for conducting oversight of Secret Service operations.</p>

<p>A spokesman for the inspector general's office did not respond to questions about whether it would launch its own inquiry. The FBI said in a statement following the shooting that it would be the lead federal law enforcement agency in the investigation into the shooting.</p>

<p>In a statement, Secret Service spokesman Anthony Guglielmi said the agency had "added protective resources (and) technology (and) capabilities as part of the increased campaign travel tempo."</p>

<p>Guglielmi denied accusations that the agency had rebuffed requests for more security resources from Trump's team.</p>

<p>In televised remarks, Biden, 81, said that Trump, as a former president who is the Republicans' nominee for president in the Nov. 5 election, already receives a heightened level of security.</p>

<p>"I've been consistent in my direction of the Secret Service to provide him with every resource, capability and protective measure necessary to ensure his continued safety," Biden, a Democrat, said.</p>

<p>He said he had "directed an independent review of the national security at yesterday's rally to assess exactly what happened," the results of which will be shared with the public.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Democratic Congressman Ritchie Torres said that he and Republican Congressman Mike Lawler are planning to introduce a bill that would call for enhanced security for all presidential candidates.</p>

<p><strong>'Full Rifle Kit'</strong></p>

<p>Paul Eckloff, a former Secret Service agent who retired in 2020, said agents would have surveyed all the rooftops with a line of sight ahead of time.</p>

<p>"This person either concealed themselves until they became a threat, or were not a threat until they revealed their weapons," said Eckloff.</p>

<p>In the moments after Trump was injured, the former president was quickly surrounded by Secret Service personnel who formed a human shield, while heavily armed agents in body armor and toting rifles also took to the stage and appeared to scan the area for threats.</p>

<p>Trump was whisked by the agents to a black SUV, and taken to a local hospital, according to the campaign.</p>

<p>Trump supporters blasted the Secret Service as having failed to protect the former president. Billionaire Elon Musk called for the agency's leadership to resign.</p>

<p>"How was a sniper with a full rifle kit allowed to bear crawl onto the closest roof to a presidential nominee," asked conservative activist Jack Posobiec on social media.</p>

<p>"There will be an intensive review" of the incident and "there's going to be a massive realignment," said Joseph LaSorsa, a former Secret Service agent who served on the presidential detail. "This cannot happen."</p>

<p><strong>Securing Trump Rallies</strong></p>

<p>During most of Trump's campaign stops, local police aid the Secret Service in securing the venue. Agents from other agencies within the Department of Homeland Security, such as the Transportation Security Administration, occasionally help.</p>

<p>Many Trump rallies feature thousands of audience members, take place in the open air and last for hours.</p>

<p>Before the event, agents scan the venue for bombs or other threats, and Trump invariably arrives in a fortified motorcade.</p>

<p>Law enforcement officials typically put up barriers as a perimeter, and require all attendees to go through a metal detector to enter the venue. Armed protective agents search all attendees' bags and even wallets. Many rallygoers are patted down by hand.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Secret Service is tasked with protecting current and former presidents]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-arrives-for-republican-national-convention-day-after-assassination-attempt-6107053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Arrives For Republican Convention Day After Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-arrives-for-republican-national-convention-day-after-assassination-attempt-6107053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 05:16:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump landed in Milwaukee on Sunday for the Republican National Convention, a little more than 24 hours after he was wounded in a failed assassination attempt, according to his son Eric Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump landed in Milwaukee on Sunday for the Republican National Convention, a little more than 24 hours after he was wounded in a failed assassination attempt, according to his son Eric Trump.</p>

<p>"Touchdown in Milwaukee with @realdonaldtrump," Eric Trump posted on social media platform X with a video peering through the cockpit as pilots landed the Republican presidential candidate's plane, dubbed "Trump Force One."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Touchdown in Milwaukee with <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realdonaldtrump</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TrumpForce1?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TrumpForce1</a> <a href="https://t.co/vkO5ZUPXG6">pic.twitter.com/vkO5ZUPXG6</a></p>
— Eric Trump (@EricTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/EricTrump/status/1812620356538040807?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>People could be seen disembarking from the plane at the airport in the Wisconsin city.</p>

<p>Trump had insisted he would stick to his schedule for the convention despite Saturday's shooting at a rally in Pennsylvania which left one bystander dead, two wounded, and Trump himself nicked in the ear by what he said was a "whizzing" bullet.</p>

<p>"I cannot allow a 'shooter,' or potential assassin, to force change to scheduling, or anything else," the presumptive Republican presidential nominee said earlier Sunday on Truth Social.</p>

<p>"Therefore, I will be leaving for Milwaukee, as scheduled, at 3:30 P.M. TODAY," he wrote, adding that he opted against delaying his trip to Wisconsin.</p>

<p>Republicans are expected to confirm Trump as their nominee to challenge Democrat incumbent Joe Biden for the White House in November.</p>

<p>Trump is also expected to announce his running mate as early as the opening day on Monday.</p>

<p>He formally accepts the nomination on Thursday in a speech that will be followed by millions, closing the convention by ushering in "a new golden age for America," according to his campaign.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/trbnmngo_donald-trump_625x300_02_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump is expected to announce his running mate as early as the opening day on Monday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-being-probed-as-domestic-terrorism-act-fbi-6106945]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Assassination Attempt Being Probed As Domestic Terrorism Act: FBI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-being-probed-as-domestic-terrorism-act-fbi-6106945]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:39:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman who shot at former president Donald Trump during an election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday appears to have acted alone, according to the FBI, which is investigating it as a potential "domestic terrorism" act.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman who shot at former president Donald Trump during an election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday appears to have acted alone, according to the FBI, which is investigating it as a potential "domestic terrorism" act.</p>

<p>The gunman has been identified as Thomas Matthew Crooks (20).</p>

<p>"At this point in the investigation, it appears that he was a lone actor, but we still have more investigation to go," said Robert Wells, the executive assistant director of the FBI's National Security Branch.</p>

<p>The FBI, he said, is investigating this as an assassination attempt," and also as a "potential domestic terrorism act." The counterterrorism division and criminal divisions are working jointly together to determine the motive, he added.</p>

<p>The FBI is leading the investigation into the assassination attempt of Trump at an election rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Trump was hit with a bullet that pierced the upper part of his right ear. He is now safe and is continuing with his schedule that includes travelling to Milwaukee to attend the Republican National Convention, which would formally nominate him as the party's presidential nominee against incumbent Joe Biden.</p>

<p>"The shooter may be deceased, but the investigation is very much ongoing. And, because of that, we are limited in what we say at this point," FBI Director Christopher Wray said.</p>

<p>"What we witnessed yesterday was nothing short of an attack on democracy and our democratic process," he told reporters at a news conference in Washington DC.</p>

<p>According to an FBI official, the investigation into the gunman at Donald Trump's rally Saturday has not yet turned up any mental health issues, threatening posts or other motives, but cautioned it was still early.</p>

<p>The shooter, as per FBI, used an AR-style rifle chambered in 5.56mm, a common calibre for such weapons.</p>

<p>The New York Times said authorities were scouring the gunman's social media and other property as they sought to determine a motive for the attack.</p>

<p>Biden is likely to address the nation at 8 pm from the Oval Office. He will give "a forceful and needed address to update the nation on the horrifying attack on Donald Trump and the need for every American to come together to not just condemn, but put to an end political violence in this country once and for all," a campaign official told the daily.</p>

<p>Crooks graduated from the Community College of Allegheny County two months ago, earning an associate degree in engineering science, school officials said in a statement, adding that they were "shocked and saddened by the horrific turn of events." Kimberly Cheatle, the director of the Secret Service, in a memo to her agents said "the attempted assassination of former President Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania, is a moment that will forever be remembered in history."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cppov9so_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The gunman has been identified as Thomas Matthew Crooks (20). (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-victim-corey-comperatore-was-a-firefighter-father-of-2-died-shielding-his-family-6106855]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Victim Was A Firefighter, Died Shielding His Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-victim-corey-comperatore-was-a-firefighter-father-of-2-died-shielding-his-family-6106855]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:02:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The spectator who died in the shooting that targeted Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania rally has been identified as Corey Comperatore, a 50-year-old firefighter and father of two.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The spectator who died in the shooting that targeted Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania rally has been identified as Corey Comperatore, a 50-year-old firefighter and father of two.</p>

<p>"We lost a fellow Pennsylvanian last night, Corey Comperatore," the state's governor, Josh Shapiro, told reporters. "I just spoke to his wife and his two daughters."</p>

<p>He said the victim was a churchgoing firefighter and an enthusiastic Trump supporter who "loved his community and most especially...his family."</p>

<p>Josh Shapiro called Saturday's shooting, in which two other spectators were wounded, "shocking, for this Commonwealth (state) and the country."</p>

<p>The other victims have yet to be identified, though NPR news affiliate WESA quoted hospital officials in Pittsburgh as saying both were local men and both remained in critical condition.</p>

<p>The shooter, identified as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks of nearby Bethel Park, was killed by a Secret Service sniper.</p>

<p>One of Corey Comperatore's daughters, Allyson, described her father in a Facebook post as "the best dad a girl could ever ask for," someone always ready to help and quick to "make friends with anyone."</p>

<p>"The media will not tell you that he died a real-life super hero," she said.</p>

<p>"He threw my mom and I to the ground... (and) shielded my body from the bullet that came at us."</p>

<p>Josh Shapiro also described Corey Comperatore as "a hero" who died protecting his family. He said state flags would be flown at half-staff to honor the victim.</p>

<p>"Corey was an avid supporter of the former president," Josh Shapiro added, "and was so excited to be there last night."</p>

<p>A GoFundMe page created to raise money for the Comperatore family had received donations of nearly $330,000 as of 3:00 pm.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b5q03l7g_corey-comperatore_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pennsylvanian Governor described Corey Comperatore as "a hero" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-school-sheltering-displaced-gazans-6106800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[15 Killed In Israeli Strike On School Sheltering Displaced Gazans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-school-sheltering-displaced-gazans-6106800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 03:49:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The civil defence agency in Hamas-run Gaza said Sunday that 15 people were killed in a strike on a school sheltering war displaced where the Israeli military said it had targeted "terrorists".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The civil defence agency in Hamas-run Gaza said Sunday that 15 people were killed in a strike on a school sheltering war displaced where the Israeli military said it had targeted "terrorists".</p>

<p>The strike on the UN-run Abu Araban site in central Gaza's Nuseirat camp was the fifth on a school-turned-shelter in eight days.</p>

<p>The Abu Araban school was housing "thousands of displaced people," civil defence agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP, adding that most of the dead were women and children.</p>

<p>Schools in Nuseirat were the target for two of the earlier school strikes as Israel keeps up its offensive against Hamas Palestinian militants who triggered the war with their October 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its air force "struck a number of terrorists who were operating in the area of UNRWA's Abu Araban school building in Nuseirat".</p>

<p>It said the building had "served as a hideout" and base for "attacks" on Israeli troops.</p>

<p>AFPTV images showed the three-storey complex standing, with clothes and bedding airing out over its railings. A wall bearing the UN logo had been blown out, and rooms inside were damaged.</p>

<p>On July 6, Israeli aircraft hit Al-Jawni school, also run by the United Nations relief agency for Palestinian refugees (UNRWA), in Nuseirat. UNRWA said about 2,000 people were sheltering there at the time.</p>

<p>The following day, four people died in a strike on the church-run Holy Family school in Gaza City, in the territory's north, according to the Civil Defence agency.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israel hit another Nuseirat school, again saying it was targeting "terrorists".</p>

<p>The next day, a hospital source said at least 29 people died in a strike at the entrance to Al-Awda school in the Khan Yunis area, southern Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel says Hamas uses schools, hospitals and other public infrastructure for military purposes. Hamas denies the accusation.</p>

<p>France and Germany on Wednesday called for an investigation into the school strikes.</p>

<p>After the Al-Jawni strike, UNRWA spokesperson Juliette Touma told AFP that when the war began "we closed the schools and they became shelters."</p>

<p>UNRWA is the main relief agency in Gaza but more than half, or 190, of its facilities have been hit -- "some more than once" -- in the military response to the October 7 Hamas attacks, she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dq0ri2g_gaza-school-strike_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Schools in Nuseirat were the target for two of the earlier school strikes]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-pulling-out-of-gaza-truce-talks-as-israel-keeps-up-strikes-6106799]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Says Pulling Out Of Gaza Truce Talks, As Israel Keeps Up Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-pulling-out-of-gaza-truce-talks-as-israel-keeps-up-strikes-6106799]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 03:43:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Hamas official said Sunday that the Palestinian group was withdrawing from Gaza truce talks, as Israeli bombardments hit a school a day after a deadly strike targeting the militant commander Mohammed Deif.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Hamas official said Sunday that the Palestinian group was withdrawing from Gaza truce talks, as Israeli bombardments hit a school a day after a deadly strike targeting the militant commander Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>Speaking after the strike on southern Gaza's Al-Mawasi, which the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory said killed at least 92 people, a senior official from Iran-backed Hamas cited Israeli "massacres" as a reason for suspending negotiations.</p>

<p>A second Hamas official said Deif, commander of the Islamist group's military wing, was "well and directly overseeing" operations despite the Israeli bombing raid that the military said was an attempt to kill him.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Israeli forces struck a UN-run school in the central Nuseirat refugee camp that the military said "served as a hideout" for militants.</p>

<p>The civil defence agency in Gaza said 15 people were killed in the strike, the fifth attack in just over a week to hit a school used as shelter by displaced Palestinians.</p>

<p>The first Hamas official, quoting the group's Qatar-based political chief Ismail Haniyeh, said Israel's "lack of seriousness, continued policy of procrastination and obstruction, and the ongoing massacres against unarmed civilians" were behind the "decision to halt negotiations".</p>

<p>But according to the official, Haniyeh told international mediators Hamas was "ready to resume negotiations" when Israel's government "demonstrates seriousness in reaching a ceasefire agreement and a prisoner exchange deal".</p>

<p>Talks mediated by Qatar and Egypt, with United States support, have for months tried but failed to bring a halt to the war.</p>

<p>Israeli demonstrators, sometimes in the tens of thousands, have stepped up their actions demanding the government reach a deal to free the captives taken by Hamas militants on October 7.</p>

<p>The military's chief of staff Herzi Halevi said in a video message that "continuous... military pressure" could help create "the conditions for an agreement to return the hostages".</p>

<p><strong>Schools turned shelters</strong></p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack that sparked the war, now in its 10th month, resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza including 42 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel responded with a military offensive that has killed at least 38,584 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to data provided by the Gaza health ministry.</p>

<p>In Nuseirat, an AFP photographer saw part of the bombarded school complex damaged. Crowds of Palestinians, some visibly shaken and in tears, gathered in the courtyard.</p>

<p>At the nearby Al-Awda hospital, the wounds of several children were bandaged.</p>

<p>With most of Gaza's 2.4 million people displaced at least once during the war, many have sought refuge in school buildings.</p>

<p>Four previous strikes on schools turned shelters since July 6 killed a total of at least 49 people, according to officials, medics and rescuers.</p>

<p>Israel says Hamas uses schools, hospitals and other public infrastructure for military purposes. Hamas denies the accusation.</p>

<p>Separately on Sunday, rescuers said at least 10 people were killed in strikes on different parts of Gaza City, where the Israeli military said its operations were ongoing in the territory's north.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist at the site of a strike in the city's Tal al-Hawa neighbourhood saw buildings reduced to rubble. The civil defence agency said rescuers had extracted the bodies of "two martyrs".</p>

<p>At the site of Saturday's strike in Al-Mawasi, on the Mediterranean coast, an AFP photographer saw the charred remains of tents as Palestinians searched through the wreckage for salvageable items.</p>

<p><strong>'Right to live'</strong></p>

<p>Al-Mawasi, near the cities of Khan Yunis and Rafah, had in May been declared a safe humanitarian zone by the Israeli military, which told civilians to evacuate to it. However, there have been multiple deadly incidents there blamed on Israeli strikes.</p>

<p>Israel's military on Sunday said one of Deif's associates, Rafa Salama, had been killed by the strike a day earlier "in the area of Khan Yunis".</p>

<p>Israel accused both Salama, commander of Hamas's Khan Yunis brigade, and Deif of helping to "mastermind" the October 7 attack.</p>

<p>Halevi, Israel's army chief, said that Deif was at the site targeted along with "other terrorists and accomplices", but that it was "too early to conclude the results of the strike".</p>

<p>"Very few" civilians "were harmed", he added.</p>

<p>Philippe Lazzarini, head of the UN agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA, said on social media that the Al-Mawasi "attack and the mass casualties are a stark reminder that no one is safe in Gaza, wherever they are".</p>

<p>"The people of Gaza are children, women and men who... have the right to live and hope for a better future."</p>

<p>The deaths drew condemnation from governments across the region.</p>

<p>Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan said Israel did not intend to end the war and committed "new massacres each time there is a positive atmosphere" towards a truce.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jrn4gko_gaza_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The civil defence agency in Gaza said 15 people were killed in a fresh strike]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-was-quiet-lonely-and-bullied-in-school-report-6106636]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooter Was "Quiet", "Lonely" And "Bullied" In School: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-was-quiet-lonely-and-bullied-in-school-report-6106636]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 02:45:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 20-year-old Pennsylvania man, Thomas Matthew Crooks, has been identified as the suspected shooter who tried to assassinate former president Donald Trump at a campaign rally this weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 20-year-old Pennsylvania man, Thomas Matthew Crooks, has been identified as the suspected shooter who tried to assassinate former president Donald Trump at a campaign rally this weekend.</p>

<p>Secret Service snipers killed Crooks on Saturday after he fired multiple shots at the rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, from a nearby rooftop.</p>

<p>As authorities seek to understand his motivations, here is what we know of the alleged gunman:</p>

<p><strong>'Quiet'</strong></p>

<p>Crooks' former schoolmates described him as a "quiet" student who often came across as "lonely," ABC News reported.</p>

<p>But although he seemed "socially reserved," a former schoolmate did not recall hearing him discuss politics or Trump, according to ABC.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was hit in the ear at the rally. A bystander was killed and two spectators critically injured in the worst act of US political violence in decades.</p>

<p>Jason Kohler, who said he attended the same high school as Crooks, said the alleged shooter had often been bullied.</p>

<p>"He was quiet but he was just bullied. He was bullied so much," Kohler told reporters.</p>

<p>He said Crooks had been made fun of for the way he dressed, noting that he would sometimes wear hunting outfits.</p>

<p><strong>No military ties</strong></p>

<p>Following the shooting, investigators found a "suspicious device" in Crooks' car, which was inspected by bomb technicians and is being analysed.</p>

<p>They noted that explosive devices have been collected as evidence.</p>

<p>Authorities are now in the process of searching Crooks' phone.</p>

<p>Kevin Rojek, special agent in charge of the FBI's Pittsburgh field office, told reporters Sunday that the gun used in the shooting was an AR-style semiautomatic rifle which was purchased legally.</p>

<p>Investigators believe the weapon used was purchased by Crooks' father, but it was unclear how he accessed the weapon.</p>

<p>Rojek added that there were no indications so far of any mental health issues.</p>

<p>Crooks also did not have military affiliations, according to Pentagon spokesman Major General Pat Ryder.</p>

<p>The FBI told reporters that they are investigating the incident as an assassination attempt and also potential domestic terrorism act.</p>

<p><strong>Acted alone</strong></p>

<p>The shooter was believed to be working alone, according to the FBI, and officials said they have not identified an ideology associated with him.</p>

<p>His political leanings were not instantly clear.</p>

<p>News reports indicated he was a registered Republican, but also noted that he previously gave money to a Democratic-aligned progressive political action committee.</p>

<p>While social media platform Discord said it had identified an account that appeared linked to the suspect, this was "rarely utilized."</p>

<p>A spokesperson added that "we have found no evidence that it was used to plan this incident, promote violence, or discuss his political views."</p>

<p>The suspect's father Matthew Crooks earlier told CNN that he was trying to establish "what the hell is going on" before speaking about his son.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/os20isd8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An ex schoolmate said Crooks had been made fun of for the way he dressed (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-call-for-unity-after-assassination-attempt-stuns-us-6106463]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Trump Call For Unity After Assassination Attempt Stuns US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-call-for-unity-after-assassination-attempt-stuns-us-6106463]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 01:50:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rivals Joe Biden and Donald Trump urged Americans to show unity Sunday after an assassination attempt on the Republican put the nation on edge in the run-up to the presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rivals Joe Biden and Donald Trump urged Americans to show unity Sunday after an assassination attempt on the Republican that the FBI said was carried out by a shooter with a legally-bought semi-automatic rifle.</p>

<p>The attack put the divided nation on edge in the run-up to the presidential election and was being investigated as a potential act of domestic terrorism, as well as a massive security failure.</p>

<p>President Biden said he would address the nation from the Oval Office later in the day, a step only taken at times of grave crisis, after his 78-year-old predecessor was hit in the ear at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"Unity is the most elusive goal of all, but nothing is more important than that right now," Biden said in brief remarks from the White House, flanked by Vice President Kamala Harris and his homeland security chief.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Democrat said he had a "short but good conversation" on Saturday with Trump, his political nemesis whom he regularly brands as a threat to democracy.</p>

<p>Biden said the motives of the shooter, 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks, remained unknown and urged people not to make assumptions about his "afflations."</p>

<p>A day after being rushed from the stage by Secret Service agents with blood streaked across his face, Trump made a similar call.</p>

<p>"In this moment, it is more important than ever that we stand United," Trump said in a statement on his Truth Social network, adding that Americans should not allow "Evil to win."</p>

<p>The tycoon added that it was "God alone who prevented the unthinkable from happening" and that he would "FEAR NOT."</p>

<p>Trump's wife Melania called the shooter a "monster."</p>

<p><strong>Suspected explosives</strong></p>

<p>Secret Service snipers killed Crooks after he fired multiple shots from a nearby rooftop. A bystander was killed and two spectators critically injured in one of the worst acts of US political violence in decades.</p>

<p>The FBI said that it believed that Crooks acted alone and had no known ideology.</p>

<p>"We located the weapon at the scene, immediately adjacent to the shooter," Kevin Rojek, special agent in charge of the FBI's Pittsburgh field office, told reporters.</p>

<p>"We searched the shooter's car, and we're in the process of searching his phone. During the search of the vehicle, we located a suspicious device, which was inspected by bomb technicians."</p>

<p>Biden said he had ordered a full review of security at the rally, as well as at this week's Republican National Convention in Milwaukee where Trump will be crowned the party's presidential nominee.</p>

<p>Biden praised the victim, named as Corey Comperatore, saying he "was protecting his family from the bullets."</p>

<p>Questions are swirling about shooter Crooks, whose body was seen in television images on a low roof of a building, near a weapon that investigators said was an AR-style semi-automatic rifle legally bought by his father.</p>

<p>Crooks' former schoolmates described him as a quiet student who often came across as lonely.</p>

<p>"He was quiet but he was just bullied. He was bullied so much," Jason Kohler, who said he attended the same high school as Crooks, told reporters.</p>

<p>The shocking incident drew immediate criticism of security, particularly about how a presidential candidate could be targeted by a gunman around 150 meters away despite a huge Secret Service detail.</p>

<p>US Secret Service spokesman Anthony Guglielmi rejected "absolutely false" claims that it had refused additional protection for Trump ahead of the rally.</p>

<p>Some phone footage suggested that people had seen the shooter on the roof before he opened fire.</p>

<p><strong>Political fallout</strong></p>

<p>The attempt on Trump's life sent shock waves around the world, but the effects on a tight US presidential race in a deeply divided country are uncertain.</p>

<p>Trump's family has already been promoting images of the president raising a defiant fist to the crowd after the shooting.</p>

<p>His narrow escape has sparked conspiracy theories and finger-pointing by Republicans.</p>

<p>Possible Trump vice presidential pick J.D. Vance claimed Biden's campaign "rhetoric" had "led directly" to the attack.</p>

<p>US politics have become increasingly hostile, with Trump building his image around inflammatory verbal assaults, and many Democrats expressing fury and disgust at Trump's rise.</p>

<p>World leaders expressed outrage over the assassination attempt, with UN chief Antonio Guterres saying he condemned it "unequivocally."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/svuvbrhc_trump-biden-split-reuters_625x300_06_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said he had a "short but good conversation" on Saturday with Trump (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-bullet-flew-by-his-ear-man-predicted-trump-rally-shooting-4-months-ago-6105912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bullet Flew By His Ear": Man Predicted Trump Rally Shooting 4 Months Ago]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-bullet-flew-by-his-ear-man-predicted-trump-rally-shooting-4-months-ago-6105912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 23:12:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt yesterday evening during a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt yesterday evening during a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. Multiple videos shot by bystanders and video journalists showed what happened before, after and the moment when Mr Trump was shot at. Now, a four-month-old video has resurfaced online that predicted the attack on the former US president.</p>

<p>In a video posted on YouTube on March 14, Bradon Biggs spoke about an alleged divine vision he had about the attempt at Trump's life. Biggs has a YouTube channel where he frequently posts videos on "visions and prophetic warnings".</p>

<p>"I saw an attempt on his (Donald Trump) life. This bullet flew by his ear and it came so close to his head that it busted his eardrum, and I saw he fell to his knees during this timeframe and started worshipping the lord," he said.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old had just begun his speech when shots rang out, hitting his right ear and streaking his face with blood. He dropped to his knees behind the podium. When he emerged about a minute later, he mouthed "Fight! Fight! Fight!" pumping his fist in the air.</p>

<p>Many X users are now posting the clip of Biggs in which he also claim that he saw Trump "winning the presidency".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Recorded on 3/14/24 (verified), Pastor Brandon Biggs recounts a prophecy he saw.<br />
<br />
"I saw an attempt on [Trump's] life that this bullet flew by his ear and it came so close to his head that it busted his ear drum. And I saw, he fell to his knees during this timeframe..." <a href="https://t.co/U9iGpNmN7j">pic.twitter.com/U9iGpNmN7j</a></p>
— John Greenewald, Jr. (@blackvaultcom) <a href="https://twitter.com/blackvaultcom/status/1812533859210461417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation has identified 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks as the "subject involved" in the attempted assassination.</p>

<p>One rally attendee was killed and two other spectators were injured in the shooting. The suspect was shot dead by a Security Services agent.</p>

<p>The shooting occurred less than four months before the November 5 election, when Trump faces an election rematch with Democratic President Joe Biden. Most opinion polls including those by Reuters/Ipsos show the two locked in a close contest.</p>

<p>It was the first shooting of a US president or major party candidate since the 1981 attempted assassination of Republican President Ronald Reagan.</p>

<p>The incident has raised immediate questions about security failures by the Secret Service, which provides former presidents including Trump with lifetime protection.</p>]]></content:encoded>
   </item>
</channel>
</rss>