<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 08:31:08 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-richest-lose-134-billion-in-stock-slump-led-by-jeff-bezos-6252506]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Richest Lose $134 Billion In Stock Slump, Led By Jeff Bezos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-richest-lose-134-billion-in-stock-slump-led-by-jeff-bezos-6252506]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 08:25:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jeff Bezos's net worth shrank by $15.2 billion on Friday, leading a wide-ranging slump that erased $134 billion from the fortunes of the 500 richest people in the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jeff Bezos's net worth shrank by $15.2 billion Friday, leading a wide-ranging slump that erased $134 billion from the fortunes of the 500 richest people in the world.</p>

<p>Shares of Amazon.com Inc. slid 8.8% amid a broader selloff in the market, dropping Bezos' net worth to $191.5 billion, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index. The one-day wipeout is his third-worst, trailing only April 4, 2019, when the Amazon co-founder's wealth tumbled $36 billion following his divorce settlement, and April 29, 2022, when Amazon shares plunged 14%.</p>

<p>The Nasdaq 100 Index fell 2.4%, dragging down the fortunes of other tech billionaires including Elon Musk and Oracle Corp.'s Larry Ellison, whose net worths were pared $6.6 billion and $4.4 billion, respectively. Uncertainty over possible Federal Reserve rate cuts, as well as some high-profile earnings disappointments, have helped plunge the tech-heavy index into correction territory, wiping out more than $2 trillion in value in just over three weeks.</p>

<p>Investors have also become jittery over fears that this year's AI-fueled gains are overdone or the market is too concentrated. The decline in Amazon shares - the biggest drop since April 2022 - came after the company said on an earnings call that it planned to continue spending big on AI even at the expense of short-term profits.</p>

<p>Technology billionaires Mark Zuckerberg, Sergey Brin and Larry Page also each lost more than $3 billion Friday as shares of Meta Platforms Inc. and Alphabet fell in New York trading. Tech tycoons in total saw $68 billion carved from their fortunes, according to Bloomberg's wealth index.</p>

<p>Bezos, 60, the world's second-richest person, has been steadily offloading Amazon shares this year. He sold stock worth about $8.5 billion over nine trading days in February. And on a day last month when Amazon hit a fresh record, he disclosed a plan to sell 25 million additional shares worth $5 billion.</p>

<p>The additional sales would bring his total this year to roughly $13.5 billion, according to Bloomberg's calculations. He would still hold almost 912 million shares, or about 8.8% of Amazon, once those sales are complete.</p>

<p>His wealth also derives from space-exploration company Blue Origin and the Washington Post.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5jp369v8_jeff-bezos_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jeff Bezos, 60, is the world's second-richest person]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-dead-5-critical-as-residential-building-collapses-in-russia-6252439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Dead, 5 Critical As Residential Building Collapses In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-dead-5-critical-as-residential-building-collapses-in-russia-6252439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 08:06:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The deathcount from the partial collapse of a residential building in the Russian city of Nizhny Tagil has risen to 10, said the Ministry of Emergency Situations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The death count from the partial collapse of a residential building in the Russian city of Nizhny Tagil has risen to 10, said the Ministry of Emergency Situations.</p>

<p>The Ministry said on Friday that rescuers have found 10 bodies and 15 people have been rescued from under the rubble, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Five people are reportedly in critical condition at a hospital.</p>

<p>Local authorities have declared August 3 as a mourning day for the victims of the tragedy.</p>

<p>According to the Ministry, search and rescue operations are ongoing.</p>

<p>The tragedy occurred on Thursday when two entrances of a five-storey gas-powered building in Nizhny Tagil, a city located in Russia's Sverdlovsk Oblast, caved in due to an explosion of a gas-air mixture, according to the Ministry of Emergency Situations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/moscow-police-reuters_625x300_1529212985362.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shocking-scenes-riots-in-uk-over-mass-stabbing-that-killed-three-girls-6252366]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Shocking Scenes": Riots In UK Over Mass Stabbing That Killed Three Girls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shocking-scenes-riots-in-uk-over-mass-stabbing-that-killed-three-girls-6252366]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 07:44:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rioting erupted Friday evening in Sunderland, northeast England, where police said officers faced "serious and sustained levels of violence", the latest unrest linked to a mass stabbing earlier this week that killed three young girls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rioting erupted Friday evening in Sunderland, northeast England, where police said officers faced "serious and sustained levels of violence", the latest unrest linked to a mass stabbing earlier this week that killed three young girls.</p>

<p>Eight people were arrested and three officers required hospital treatment following hours of "utterly deplorable" disturbances, Northumbria Police Chief Superintendent Helena Barron said.</p>

<p>Two officers remained in hospital early Saturday, she added.</p>

<p>Footage broadcast by the BBC showed a mob of several hundred rampaging in Sunderland's city centre, attacking police and setting fire to at least one car and a building next to a police office.</p>

<p>Other images shared on social media showed balaclava-clad youths throwing bricks and other missiles as fireworks and flares were let off.</p>

<p>"The shocking scenes we have witnessed in Sunderland this evening are completely unacceptable," Barron said, adding the "disorder, violence and damage" seen "will not be tolerated".</p>

<p>"A full investigation is now under way to identify anyone else responsible" in addition to the eight people arrested, she added.</p>

<p>The disorder came as police nationwide prepared for planned far-right rallies and other demonstrations this weekend, after two nights of unrest in several English towns and cities in the wake of Monday's knife attack.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police said it had a "proportionate and risk-based" plan for rival pro-Palestinian and anti-immigration protests Saturday. Its officers arrested 111 people as a rally in Westminster turned violent late Wednesday.</p>

<p>But Friday night's disturbances in Sunderland, after a calm night nationwide Thursday, were an ominous sign for the coming days.</p>

<p>'Deeply anxious'</p>

<p>Responding to events there, interior minister Yvette Cooper vowed rioters will "pay the price for their violence and thuggery". She gave police "the full backing of government to take the strongest possible action and ensure they face the full force of the law".</p>

<p>"They do not represent Britain," Cooper said.</p>

<p>Earlier, Merseyside Police said extra officers had been deployed in and around Liverpool city centre "to help prevent disorder or criminality" there. Despite a minor skirmish near a mosque, the evening passed off peacefully.</p>

<p>Liverpool lies close to the seaside town of Southport where Monday's knife attack occurred.</p>

<p>Far-right elements have been blamed for the disturbances in the aftermath of the stabbing spree targeting children at a Taylor Swift-themed dance party.</p>

<p>Officials have said online disinformation about the British-born 17-year-old suspect Axel Rudakubana helped fuel the unrest.</p>

<p>He faces murder and attempted murder charges over the stabbing rampage that also left five children and two adults critically wounded.</p>

<p>Police have said the case is not being treated as terror-related but have not revealed a motive.</p>

<p>Anger over the tragedy has fused with growing anti-immigration sentiment on the right of English politics, pushed by openly Islamophobic far-right figures.</p>

<p>After violence in Southport late Tuesday, unrest rocked the northern cities of Hartlepool and Manchester as well as London 24 hours later.</p>

<p>In Southport, the mob targeted a mosque, prompting hundreds of Muslim places of worship across the country to step up security amid fears of more anti-Islamic demonstrators.</p>

<p>Faith leaders say mosques have been hiring paid security staff and checking their CCTV cameras are working.</p>

<p>"The Muslim community is deeply anxious right now," Zara Mohammed, secretary-general of the Muslim Council of Britain, told AFP.</p>

<p>'Sow hatred'</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer has accused "thugs" of "hijacking" the nation's grief to "sow hatred" and pledged that anyone carrying out violent acts will "face the full force of the law".</p>

<p>In power for less than a month, Starmer met Friday with local leaders in Southport to discuss "a package of support for the local community", his Downing Street office said.</p>

<p>Starmer's visit came the day after he announced a new "national capability" to tackle disorder in the wake of the recent disturbances.</p>

<p>The new measures will allow the sharing of intelligence, wider deployment of facial-recognition technology and criminal behaviour orders to restrict troublemakers from travelling.</p>

<p>The police alert for the weekend comes after far-right social media channels advertised "enough is enough" anti-immigrant rallies, and anti-facism groups vowed to stage counter-protests.</p>

<p>"Enough is enough" has emerged as a rallying online slogan for the far-right and others following Monday's attack.</p>

<p>South Yorkshire police said Friday they knew of a planned protest in the town of Rotherham, while officers in south Wales said they were preparing for events being planned for Saturday in Cardiff.</p>

<p>Police in Northern Ireland noted social media posts calling for roadblocks "using women and children", as well as a march to an Islamic centre in Belfast on Saturday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/l5auit4_uk-riots-_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Two officers remained in hospital early Saturday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-allies-vow-revenge-after-top-hamas-hezbollah-leaders-killed-6252277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran, Allies Vow Revenge After Top Hamas, Hezbollah Leaders Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-allies-vow-revenge-after-top-hamas-hezbollah-leaders-killed-6252277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 07:14:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran and its regional allies vowed retaliation for the deaths of Hamas and Hezbollah leaders, raising regional tensions as mourners filled Tehran's city centre calling for revenge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran and its regional allies vowed retaliation for the deaths of Hamas and Hezbollah leaders, raising regional tensions as mourners filled Tehran's city centre calling for revenge.<br />
<br />
A public funeral was held for Hamas's political chief Ismail Haniyeh in the Iranian capital where he was killed early Wednesday in an attack on which Israel has not commented.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's body was then flown to Qatar, where he had resided and where he will be laid to rest on Friday, when his group called for a "day of furious rage" in the Palestinian territories and across the region.</p>

<p>Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, addressing the funeral of the Lebanese group's top military commander, said Israel and "those who are behind it must await our inevitable response" to Fuad Shukr's and Haniyeh's killings within hours of each other.</p>

<p>"You do not know what red lines you crossed," Nasrallah said, addressing Israel, a day after Shukr was killed in a strike in south Beirut.</p>

<p>Israel, which said Shukr's assassination was a response to deadly rocket fire last week on the annexed Golan Heights, warned its adversaries on Thursday they would "pay a very high price" for any "aggression".</p>

<p>"Israel is at a very high level of preparation for any scenario, both defensive and offensive," Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Those who attack us, we will attack in return."</p>

<p>A source close to Hezbollah told AFP that Iranian officials met in Tehran on Wednesday with representatives of the so-called "axis of resistance", a loose alliance of Tehran-backed groups hostile to Israel, to discuss their next steps.</p>

<p>"Two scenarios were discussed: a simultaneous response from Iran and its allies or a staggered response from each party," said the source who had been briefed on the meeting, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>The leader of Yemen's Iran-backed Huthi rebels vowed a "military response" to Israel's "major escalation".</p>

<p>Analysts told AFP that the retaliation would be measured to avoid a wider conflagration.</p>

<p>Iran and the groups it backs "will more than likely try to avert a war, while also strongly deterring Israel from continuing with this new policy, this targeted shock and awe," said Amal Saad, a Hezbollah researcher and lecturer at Britain's Cardiff University.</p>

<p>In Tehran, Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei led prayers for Haniyeh, having earlier threatened "harsh punishment" for his killing.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Roaring marches' -</strong></p>

<p>Crowds, including women shrouded in black, carried posters of Haniyeh and Palestinian flags in a procession and ceremony that began at Tehran University, an AFP correspondent reported.</p>

<p>Senior Iranian officials, including President Masoud Pezeshkian and Revolutionary Guards chief General Hossein Salami, attended the ceremony, state television images showed.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards announced the day before that Haniyeh and a bodyguard were killed in a pre-dawn strike Wednesday on their accommodation in Tehran.</p>

<p>The New York Times however reported, citing anonymous sources including two Iranian officials, that the blast was caused by an explosive device planted several months ago.</p>

<p>When asked about the report, Israeli military spokesman Daniel Hagari told reporters "there was no other Israeli aerial attack... in all the Middle East" on the night of Shukr's killing.</p>

<p>Qatar-based Haniyeh had been visiting Tehran for Pezeshkian's swearing-in on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian said Iran "will continue to support with firmer determination the axis of resistance", the official IRNA news agency said.</p>

<p>Qatar-based network Al Jazeera reported that the plane carrying Haniyeh's body had landed in Doha, where the Palestinian leader is to be buried following prayers at the Qatari capital's largest mosque.</p>

<p>Hamas called in a statement for a day of protests on Friday.</p>

<p>"Let roaring anger marches start from every mosque," it said.</p>

<p><strong>- Regional tensions -</strong></p>

<p>The international community has called for calm and a focus on securing a ceasefire in the Gaza Strip -- which Haniyeh had accused Israel of obstructing.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden said late Thursday he was "very concerned" about rising tensions in the region, adding that the killing of Haniyeh had "not helped" the situation.</p>

<p>The White House said Biden spoke with Netanyahu by phone on Thursday, promising to defend Israel's security "against all threats from Iran".</p>

<p>"We have the basis for a ceasefire. He should move on it and they should move on it now," Biden told reporters after the call.</p>

<p>The prime minister of key ceasefire broker Qatar said Haniyeh's assassination had thrown the whole Gaza war mediation process into doubt.</p>

<p>"How can mediation succeed when one party assassinates the negotiator on the other side?" Sheikh Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani said on social media site X.</p>

<p>The killings are the latest of several major incidents that have inflamed regional tensions during the Gaza war which has drawn in Iran-backed militant groups in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Israel has vowed to destroy Hamas in retaliation for its October 7 attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign against Hamas has killed at least 39,480 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3kregl9g_iran_625x300_03_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has vowed to destroy Hamas in retaliation for its October 7 attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-in-vietnam-puts-an-eel-up-his-anus-it-eats-through-his-intestines-6252274]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian In Vietnam Puts An Eel Up His Anus, It Eats Through His Intestines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-in-vietnam-puts-an-eel-up-his-anus-it-eats-through-his-intestines-6252274]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 07:12:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 31-year-old Indian national was rushed to a hospital in Vietnam's capital Hanoi after experiencing severe abdominal pain due to a live eel he had inserted into his anus, a report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 31-year-old Indian national was rushed to a hospital in Vietnam's capital Hanoi after experiencing severe abdominal pain due to a live eel he had inserted into his anus, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://vietnamnews.vn/society/1660152/expat-put-live-eel-into-anus-gets-colon-punctured.html">a report said</a>. &nbsp;</p>

<p>On July 27, The man <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/01/world-news/live-2-foot-eel-chews-through-mans-intestines-after-he-put-it-up-his-anus/">arrived at the hospital in excruciating pain</a>, prompting immediate medical attention. The doctors reported that the patient had inserted the eel earlier in the day, leading to a desperate attempt by the eel to escape. The creature bit through the patient's rectum and colon, entering the abdominal cavity.</p>

<p>Imaging tests, including an X-ray, revealed the eel's skeleton lodged within the patient's abdomen. Initial efforts to remove the eel through the anus were hindered by another foreign object - a lemon - that had been inserted and blocked the passage, prompting the medical team to initiate an emergency surgery.</p>

<p>During the surgery, doctors discovered the live eel, measuring over 25 inches in length and about 4 inches in diameter, inside the patient's abdominal cavity. Both the eel and the lemon were successfully removed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Due to the significant contamination and the presence of fecal matter in the abdominal cavity, a colostomy was performed, the report added.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9qhrgm4o_eel-vietnam-_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both the eel and the lemon were successfully removed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-scraps-plea-agreement-with-9-11-mastermind-khalid-sheikh-mohammed-6252185]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Scraps Plea Agreement With 9/11 Mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-scraps-plea-agreement-with-9-11-mastermind-khalid-sheikh-mohammed-6252185]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 06:49:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin on Friday scrapped a plea agreement with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed, just two days after the announcement of a deal that reportedly would have taken the death penalty off the table.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin on Friday scrapped a plea agreement with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed, just two days after the announcement of a deal that reportedly would have taken the death penalty off the table.</p>

<p>Agreements with Mohammed and two alleged accomplices announced Wednesday had appeared to have moved their long-running cases toward resolution -- but sparked anger among some relatives of those killed on September 11, 2001.</p>

<p>"I have determined that, in light of the significance of the decision to enter into pre-trial agreements with the accused... responsibility for such a decision should rest with me," Austin said in a memorandum addressed to Susan Escallier, who oversaw the case.</p>

<p>"I hereby withdraw from the three pre-trial agreements that you signed on July 31, 2024 in the above-referenced case," the memo said.</p>

<p>The cases against the 9/11 defendants have been bogged down in pre-trial maneuverings for years while the accused remained held at the Guantanamo Bay military base in Cuba.</p>

<p>The New York Times reported this week that Mohammed, Walid bin Attash and Mustafa al-Hawsawi had agreed to plead guilty to conspiracy in exchange for a life sentence, instead of facing a trial that could lead to their executions.</p>

<p>Much of the legal jousting surrounding the men's cases has focused on whether they could be tried fairly after having undergone methodical torture at the hands of the CIA in the years after 9/11.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1jmfn9g_khalid-sheikh-mohammed_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The accused remained held at the Guantanamo Bay military base in Cuba.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-threatens-google-6252123]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Google Close To Shut Down": Donald Trump On Censorship Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-threatens-google-6252123]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 06:23:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump has lashed out at Google over reports that was censoring news and photos of the Republican presidential candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump has lashed out at Google over reports that was censoring news and photos of the Republican presidential candidate.</p>

<p>"Google has been very bad. They've been very irresponsible and I have a feeling that Google is going to be close to shut down because I don't think Congress is going to take it. I really don't think so. Google has to be careful," Trump told Fox News in an interview.</p>

<p>Early this week, Trump alleged that it was virtually impossible to find pictures or anything about the failed assassination bid on him on July 13 on Google. Google, however, denied those allegations.</p>

<p>"Over the past few days, some people on X have posted claims that search is 'censoring' or 'banning' particular terms. That's not happening, and we want to set the record straight. The posts relate to our Autocomplete feature, which predicts queries to save you time. Autocomplete," it said in a social media post.</p>

<p>Google said autocomplete wasn't providing predictions for queries about the assassination attempt against former President Trump. That's because it has built-in protections related to political violence - and those systems were out of date. After the horrific events in Butler, Pennsylvania, those predicted queries should have appeared but didn't, it said.</p>

<p>"Once the issue was flagged, we started working on improvements, and they're already rolling out," it said.</p>

<p>"Secondly, people posted about how Autocomplete wasn't showing relevant predictions for 'President Donald'. This particular issue was a bug that spanned the political spectrum, also affecting queries for several past presidents, such as former President Obama, as you can see in the attached image. Typing 'vice president k' was also showing no predictions. We've made an update that has improved these predictions across the board," it said.</p>

<p>Some people, it said, also posted that searches for "Donald Trump" returned news stories related to "Kamala Harris." These labels are automatically generated based on related news topics, and they change over time.</p>

<p>"They span the political spectrum as well: For example, a search for 'Kamala Harris' showed Top Stories labelled with 'Donald Trump', because many articles cover the two of them together. You can see this happening across a range of topics, like the Olympics, other public figures, companies, and more. Our goal is to help people get relevant results for their query," Google said.</p>

<p>Overall, these types of prediction and labelling systems are algorithmic, it said.</p>

<p>"While our systems work very well most of the time, you can find predictions that may be unexpected or imperfect, and bugs will occur. Many platforms, including the one we're posting on now, will show strange or incomplete predictions at various times. For our part, when issues come up, we will make improvements so you can find what you're looking for, quickly and easily. We appreciate the feedback," it explained.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/3h5aud5g_donald-trump-afp-_625x300_11_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said that Google has been very irresponsible.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sending-more-warships-fighter-jets-to-middle-east-amid-rising-tensions-6251951]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sending More Warships, Fighter Jets To Middle East Amid Rising Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sending-more-warships-fighter-jets-to-middle-east-amid-rising-tensions-6251951]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 05:26:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States will bolster its military presence in the Middle East, deploying additional warships and fighter jets to protect US personnel and defend Israel amid soaring tensions in the region, the Pentagon said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States will bolster its military presence in the Middle East, deploying additional warships and fighter jets to protect US personnel and defend Israel amid soaring tensions in the region, the Pentagon said Friday.</p>

<p>The announcement comes after Iran and its regional allies vowed retaliation for the killings of a Hamas leader in Tehran and a Hezbollah commander in Beirut, fueling fears of a broader Middle East conflict.</p>

<p>"The Department of Defense continues to take steps to mitigate the possibility of regional escalation by Iran or Iran's partners and proxies," deputy Pentagon Press Secretary Sabrina Singh said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Since the horrific Hamas attack on Israel on October 7, the Secretary of Defense has reiterated that the United States will protect our personnel and interests in the region, including our ironclad commitment to the defense of Israel."</p>

<p>The aircraft carrier strike group led by the USS Abraham Lincoln will replace one helmed by the USS Theodore Roosevelt in the region, Singh said.</p>

<p>Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin has also ordered additional ballistic missile defense-capable cruisers and destroyers to the Middle East and areas under US European Command, as well as a new fighter squadron to the Middle East.</p>

<p>Israel killed Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut on Tuesday, a move it said was a response to deadly rocket fire last week on the annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Hours later, Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was killed in the Iranian capital -- an attack on which Israel has not yet commented.</p>

<p>A source close to Hezbollah told AFP that Iranian officials met in Tehran on Wednesday with representatives of the so-called "axis of resistance," a loose alliance of Tehran-backed groups hostile to Israel, to discuss their next steps.</p>

<p>"Two scenarios were discussed: a simultaneous response from Iran and its allies or a staggered response from each party," said the source, who had been briefed on the meeting, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>In April, Iran carried out its first direct attack on Israeli soil, firing a barrage of drones and missiles after a strike blamed on Israel killed Revolutionary Guards at Tehran's consulate in Damascus.</p>

<p>American forces helped defend Israel against the attack.</p>

<p>"As we have demonstrated since October and again in April, the United States' global defense is dynamic and the Department of Defense retains the capability to deploy on short notice to meet evolving national security threats," Singh said.</p>

<p>"The United States also remains intently focused on de-escalating tensions in the region and pushing for a ceasefire as part of a hostage deal to bring the hostages home and end the war in Gaza."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/orvtctjc_us-warship-uss-carney_625x300_13_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States said that it will bolster its military presence in the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mark-zuckerberg-apologised-to-me-and-said-he-wont-support-democrats-donald-trump-6251923]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Zuckerberg Called Me, Said He Won't Support A Democrat': Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mark-zuckerberg-apologised-to-me-and-said-he-wont-support-democrats-donald-trump-6251923]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 05:17:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that the Facebook founder and CEO Mark Zuckerberg recently called him to apologise for censoring him and assured that he would "not support a Democrat".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that the Facebook founder and CEO Mark Zuckerberg recently called him to apologise for censoring him and assured that he would "not support a Democrat".</p>

<p>"So, Mark Zuckerberg called me. First of all, he called me a few times. He called me after the event and he said, 'That was really amazing, it was very brave,'" Trump told Fox News in an interview.</p>

<p>"He actually announced he's not gonna support a Democrat because he can't because he respected me for what I did that day," Trump said.</p>

<p>"They are working on, and I think they fixed it. He's not doing what he did five years ago, with the 500 million dollars, I don't believe," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/324lssoo_trump-zuckerberg_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump said that Mark Zuckerberg pledged that he is not gonna support a Democrat. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/magnitude-6-8-earthquake-strikes-philippines-6251870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Magnitude 6.8 Earthquake Strikes Philippines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/magnitude-6-8-earthquake-strikes-philippines-6251870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 04:55:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 6.8-magnitude earthquake struck off the coast of the southern Philippines early Saturday, the United States Geological Survey said, with no tsunami warning issued.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 6.8-magnitude earthquake struck off the coast of the southern Philippines early Saturday, the United States Geological Survey said, with no tsunami warning issued.</p>

<p>The quake hit at a depth of 17 kilometres (10.5 miles) about 20 kilometres from the village of Barcelona on the east of Mindanao island, the USGS said.</p>

<p>The local seismological agency said no damage was expected, but it warned of aftershocks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earthquakes regularly strike the Philippines, which sits along the Pacific Ring of Fire, an arc of intense seismic and volcanic activity that stretches from Japan through Southeast Asia and across the Pacific basin.</p>

<p>Most are too weak to be felt by humans but strong and destructive quakes come at random with no technology available to predict when and where they will happen.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/earthquake-generic_650x400_71505899871.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 6.8-magnitude earthquake struck off the coast of the southern Philippines early Saturday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-accepts-responsibility-for-failure-to-protect-trump-6251674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Secret Service Accepts Responsibility For Failure To Protect Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-accepts-responsibility-for-failure-to-protect-trump-6251674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 03:48:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States Service has owned its failure to protect former president Donald Trump at an election rally in Pennsylvania on July 13.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States Service has owned its failure to protect former president Donald Trump at an election rally in Pennsylvania on July 13.</p>

<p>A young gunman shot at Trump, 78, when he was addressing an election rally in Butler. Trump escaped the assassination attempt, as a bullet flew within a millimetre of him and one of them hit his right ear.</p>

<p>“The Secret Service takes full responsibility for the tragic events of July 13th. This was a mission failure. The sole responsibility of our agency is to make sure our protectees are never put in danger. We fell short of that in Butler. And I'm working to make sure that this failure does not happen again,” Acting Director of the US Secret Service, Ronald Rowe, told reporters at a news conference here.</p>

<p>The main role of Secret Service is to protect the President, the former presidents and their family members. Presidential nominees also get protection of the secret service.</p>

<p>Rowe said that the Secret Service will continue to cooperate with pending oversight investigations of the July 13 failure being done now by Congress, the Department of Homeland Security's Office of the Inspector General, and the independent review directed by President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>“I am not waiting for the completion of those reports, and I've directed the Secret Service to take immediate steps to ensure our protectees are indeed safe. I am committed to pursuing accountability for the Secret Service's failure in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>“But let me be clear. If policy violations by Secret Service personnel are identified by the agency's Mission Assurance Review, those individuals will be held accountable. They will be held accountable to our fair and thorough disciplinary process,” he said.</p>

<p>Giving the sequence of events of July 13, Rowe said at 5.30 pm, Trump arrived at the campaign rally via Secret Service motorcade, and at that time, he met with supporters in a secure backstage area within the protective site.</p>

<p>At 5.45 pm, a local Butler County Emergency Services Unit counter sniper team member texted the Secret Service counter sniper team leader about a suspicious person and sent two photos of the individual, later identified as the assailant.</p>

<p>At 5.53 pm, the Secret Service counter sniper team leader texted the Secret Service counter sniper teams that local law enforcement was looking for a suspicious individual outside of the perimeter lurking around the AGR building.</p>

<p>At this time, Secret Service personnel were operating with the knowledge that local law enforcement was working on an issue of a suspicious individual.</p>

<p>At 6 pm, former President Trump took the stage to begin remarks.</p>

<p>“Based on what I know right now, neither the Secret Service counter-sniper teams nor members of the former president's security detail had any knowledge that there was a man on the roof of the AGR building with a firearm. It is my understanding that personnel were not aware the assailant had a firearm until they heard gunshots,” he said.</p>

<p>“At 6.11 pm, a member of the former President Trump's protective detail contacted their Pittsburgh field office counterpart to inquire about the radio update that there was an issue local law enforcement was looking into near the perimeter.</p>

<p>“At 6.11 pm, the assailant's first volley of three shots was fired, and within three seconds, the former president's detail rushed the stage and covered Trump, shielding him with their own bodies,” Rowe said giving the timeline of the failed assassination bid on July 13.</p>

<p>“The fourth-through-eight shots took place over the next several seconds. Fifteen and a half seconds after the assailant's first shot, a Secret Service counter sniper fired a single round that neutralised the assailant,” he said.</p>

<p>Rowe told reporters that this was a failure.</p>

<p>“We should have had better protection for the protectee. We should have had better coverage on that roof line. We should have had at least some other set of eyes from the Secret Service point of view covering that. That building was very close to that outer perimeter, and we should have had more of a presence,” he said.</p>

<p>“This was a Secret Service failure. That roof line should have been covered. We should have had better eyes on that,” he added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At 6 pm, former President Trump took the stage to begin remarks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-us-first-lady-jill-biden-extend-condolences-over-wayanad-landslides-6251501]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, US First Lady Jill Biden Extend Condolences Over Wayanad Landslides]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-us-first-lady-jill-biden-extend-condolences-over-wayanad-landslides-6251501]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 02:40:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and First Lady Jill Biden expressed condolences to India over the devastating landslides in Kerala's Wayanad that took the lives of over 300 people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and First Lady Jill Biden expressed condolences to India over the devastating landslides in Kerala's Wayanad that took the lives of over 300 people.</p>

<p>"Jill and I extend our deepest condolences to all those affected by the deadly landslides in the state of Kerala in India," the White House said in an official statement.</p>

<p>"Our prayers are with the victims of this tragic event, and we mourn with the families who have lost loved ones. We commend the bravery of the Indian service members and first responders supporting the complex recovery effort. We will continue to hold the people of India in our thoughts during this difficult time," said the White House.</p>

<p>The number of people who died in the landslides that struck the hilly areas of Meppadi in Wayanad district on July 30 following incessant rainfall has gone up to 210 while the people who have been discharged from the hospitals stood at 187, officials said on Friday.</p>

<p>As per the officials, 210 bodies and 134 body parts have been recovered till now which includes 96 males, 85 females and 29 children.</p>

<p>The number of bodies identified by relatives stood at 146. The administration has completed the post-mortem of 207 bodies and 134 body parts found from the incident site.</p>

<p>According to the officials, 84 people are undergoing treatment in various hospitals in Wayanad, Kozhikode and Malappuram districts while 187 have been discharged.</p>

<p>273 people have been brought to hospitals from the incident site.</p>

<p>Earlier today, Kerala Health Minister Veena George confirmed 308 deaths in the multiple landslides that hit Wayanad on July 30.</p>

<p>Two massive landslides hit Wayanad's Chooralmala and Mundakkai on July 30 creating widespread devastation, and loss of lives and property in the region.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/qs48mbso_joe-biden-jill-biden_625x300_28_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jill and I extend our deepest condolences to all those affected by the deadly landslides, Biden said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-missile-artillery-at-israel-after-killing-of-military-commander-6250999]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Strikes Israel After Killing Of Its Military Commander]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-missile-artillery-at-israel-after-killing-of-military-commander-6250999]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:09:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah forces on Friday resumed rocket and artillery attacks against Israel, ending the lull along the border following Israel's killing of the Lebanese group's military commander in Beirut.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah forces on Friday resumed rocket and artillery attacks against Israel, ending the lull along the border following Israel's killing of the Lebanese group's military commander in Beirut.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it had fired a surface-to-air missile at an Israeli warplane flying in Lebanese airspace overnight and forced it to turn back. Its forces also carried out two artillery attacks and two rocket strikes at military positions in northern Israel, it said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement it had successfully intercepted an aerial target coming from Lebanon into the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Israeli airstrikes and artillery fire hit several villages in southern Lebanon on Friday, according to Lebanese state media, a day after an Israeli strike killed at least five Syrian migrant workers in southern Lebanon, according to medics.</p>

<p>The Israeli military also said it had hit two Hezbollah fighters in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah said in an address on Thursday that he had ordered calm along the border following the Israeli airstrike in Beirut on Tuesday that killed military commander Fuad Shukr out of respect for the victims and to consider what the next steps should be.</p>

<p>The strike on the Hezbollah stronghold of Dahiyeh in Beirut's southern suburbs also killed an Iranian military adviser and five civilians.</p>

<p>Nasrallah said Hezbollah would retaliate but it would need to study what their response would be, and would otherwise resume its usual military operations against Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah and the Israeli military have been trading fire for nearly 10 months in parallel with the Gaza war, with exchanges mostly limited to the border area.</p>

<p>But strikes since last week have threatened to tip the conflict into a full-scale regional war.</p>

<p>Israel and the United States have accused Hezbollah of killing 12 youths in a July 27 rocket attack on the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights, a claim Hezbollah has denied.</p>

<p>The United Nations peacekeeping force in Lebanon, known as UNIFIL, told Reuters on Friday it had not investigated the incident as the Israeli-occupied Golan is outside its mandated area of operations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2caj1vvo_israel-lebanon-fight_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-kills-al-jazeera-journalist-claims-he-was-vital-part-of-hamas-military-activity-6250941]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Kills Al Jazeera Journalist, Alleges He Was Hamas Operative]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-kills-al-jazeera-journalist-claims-he-was-vital-part-of-hamas-military-activity-6250941]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 23:52:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military confirmed on Thursday it had killed Al Jazeera journalist Ismail Al-Ghoul in an airstrike in Gaza, saying he was a Hamas operative who had taken part in the October 7 attack on Israel, without offering proof for the assertion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military confirmed on Thursday it had killed Al Jazeera journalist Ismail Al-Ghoul in an airstrike in Gaza, saying he was a Hamas operative who had taken part in the October 7 attack on Israel, without offering proof for the assertion.</p>

<p>Al Jazeera dismissed what it said were "baseless allegations" which it said were an attempt to justify the deliberate killing of its journalists.</p>

<p>"The network condemns the accusations against its correspondent Ismail Al-Ghoul, without providing any proof, documentation or video," it said in a statement, adding that it reserved the right to take legal action against those responsible.</p>

<p>The Qatari broadcaster said on Wednesday that Al-Ghoul and cameraman Ramy El Rify were killed in an Israeli strike on Gaza City while on an assignment to film near the house of Ismail Haniyeh, the Hamas chief killed in Iran earlier on the same day.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Al-Ghoul was a member of the elite Nukhba unit who took part in the Oct. 7 attack and instructed Hamas operatives on how to record operations. It said he was involved in recording and publicizing attacks on Israeli troops.</p>

<p>"His activities in the field were a vital part of Hamas' military activity," the Israeli military said in a statement.</p>

<p>Al Jazeera said Al-Ghoul had worked for the network since November 2023 and his only profession was as a journalist.</p>

<p>It said he had been arrested and detained at Al-Shifa Hospital in the northern part of the Gaza Strip when it was taken by Israeli forces in March before being released, which it said "debunks and refutes their false claim of his affiliation with any organization."</p>

<p>The Israeli government has banned Al-Jazeera from operating in Israel, accusing it of posing a threat to national security.</p>

<p>Al Jazeera, which has been heavily critical of Israel's campaign in Gaza, has denied inciting violence.</p>

<p>The Hamas-run Gaza government media office said the deaths of the two Al Jazeera crew raised to 165 the number of Palestinian journalists killed by Israeli fire since Oct 7.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cpr1l5v8_al-jazeera-journalist-killed_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Al Jazeera said Al-Ghoul had worked for the network since November 2023]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sues-tiktok-over-massive-scale-privacy-violations-of-kids-under-13-6250866]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sues TikTok Over "Massive-Scale" Privacy Violations Of Kids Under 13]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sues-tiktok-over-massive-scale-privacy-violations-of-kids-under-13-6250866]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 23:38:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Justice Department filed a lawsuit Friday against TikTok and parent company ByteDance for failing to protect children's privacy on the social media app.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Justice Department filed a lawsuit Friday against TikTok and parent company ByteDance for failing to protect children's privacy on the social media app.</p>

<p>The US government said TikTok violated the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act that requires services aimed at children to obtain parental consent to collect personal information from users under age 13.</p>

<p>The lawsuit is the latest US action against TikTok and its Chinese parent over fears the company improperly collects vast amounts of data on Americans for the Chinese government, while influencing content in a way that potentially harms Americans.</p>

<p>The suit, also joined by the Federal Trade Commission, said it was aimed at putting an end "to TikTok's unlawful massive-scale invasions of children's privacy."</p>

<p>The DOJ said TikTok knowingly permitted children to create regular TikTok accounts, and then create and share short-form videos and messages with adults and others on the regular TikTok platform. TikTok collected personal information from these children without obtaining consent from their parents.</p>

<p>The US alleges that for years millions of American children under 13 have been using TikTok and the site "has been collecting and retaining children's personal information."</p>

<p>"TikTok knowingly and repeatedly violated kids' privacy, threatening the safety of millions of children across the country," said FTC Chair Lina Khan, whose agency in June referred the case to the Justice Department.</p>

<p>The FTC is seeking penalties of up to $51,744 per violation per day from TikTok for improperly collecting data.</p>

<p>TikTok did not immediately comment but said in June it had been working with the FTC for more than a year to address the agency's concerns and said it was "disappointed the agency is pursuing litigation instead of continuing to work with us on a reasonable solution."</p>

<p>Reuters in 2020 first reported the FTC and Justice Department were looking into allegations the popular social media app failed to live up to a 2019 agreement aimed at protecting children's privacy.</p>

<p>The Chinese-owned short-video platform boasts around 170 million US users, and is currently fighting a new law that would force ByteDance to divest TikTok's US assets by January 19 or face a ban.</p>

<p>The company last year faced fines from the European Union and UK over its handling of children's data.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, US Senate passed a bill that would extend COPPA to cover teenagers up to age 17, ban targeted advertising to kids and teens, and give parents and kids the option to delete their information from social media platforms.</p>

<p>The bill would need to pass in the Republican-controlled House, currently on recess until September, to become law.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/4sivso_tiktok_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The lawsuit is the latest US action against TikTok and its Chinese parent (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-seals-democratic-nomination-for-us-presidential-polls-6250754]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[It's Official, Kamala Harris Is Democratic Candidate For US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-seals-democratic-nomination-for-us-presidential-polls-6250754]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 23:18:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris effectively sealed the Democratic nomination Friday, confirming her remarkable rise to party standard bearer in November's showdown against Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris effectively secured the Democratic party's presidential nomination Friday, confirming her remarkable rise to party standard bearer in November's showdown against Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris was the sole candidate on the ballot for a five-day electronic vote of nearly 4,000 party convention delegates. She will be officially crowned at a Chicago convention later this month.</p>

<p>"I am honored to be the presumptive Democratic nominee for President of the United States," Kamala Harris, 59, said on a phone-in to a party celebration after securing enough votes by the second day of the marathon vote.</p>

<p>In the two weeks since President Joe Biden ended his reelection bid, Kamala Harris has gained full control of the party.</p>

<p>No other Democrats stepped forward to challenge her elevation to the top of the ticket, making her confirmation as the first Black and South Asian woman ever to secure a major party's nomination a formality.</p>

<p>The announcement came with Kamala Harris preparing to hit the campaign trail next week for a swing across seven crucial battleground states with her newly minted running mate -- who is expected to be revealed within days.</p>

<p>The Democratic Party decided on a virtual nomination process -- mirroring the pandemic-hit 2020 vote -- because of Ohio's August 7 deadline for major parties to submit the names of their certified candidates for the November election.</p>

<p>The virtual roll call marks the official beginning of the 2024 convention, although in practice the festivities really get going when thousands of party faithful descend on Chicago on August 19.</p>

<p>That will feature ceremonial votes for Kamala Harris and her running mate in what is expected to be a raucous celebration of her rise from state politics to the top of the ticket.</p>

<p>Trump's White House bid was thrown into chaos on July 21 when Biden, 81, withdrew his candidacy, backing Kamala Harris as the Democratic nominee.</p>

<p>The vice president has already smashed fundraising records, packed arenas and wiped out Trump's polling leads over Biden, creating momentum that she hopes she can ride through the convention to the White House.</p>

<p>She is set to make her first public appearance with her running mate Tuesday in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania -- a crucial swing state whose Democratic governor, Josh Shapiro, is among a handful candidates being vetted to potentially join the Kamala Harris ticket.</p>

<p>The swing will take Kamala Harris through all the "blue wall" states of Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin, where she will seek to rebuild the coalition that carried Biden to victory in 2020.</p>

<p>But she will extend the tour to the much more racially diverse Sun Belt and southern states of Georgia, North Carolina Arizona, North Carolina and Nevada as she seeks to shore up the Black and Hispanic vote that had been peeling away from the Democrats.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bqfnk8go_kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential elections are scheduled for November later this year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-buried-in-qatar-thousands-attend-funeral-6250748]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Chief Ismail Haniyeh Buried In Qatar, Thousands Attend Funeral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-buried-in-qatar-thousands-attend-funeral-6250748]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 23:15:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was buried in Qatar on Friday after his killing in Tehran, an attack blamed on Israel that has heightened regional tensions as the Gaza war dragged on.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was buried in Qatar on Friday after his killing in Tehran, an attack blamed on Israel that has heightened regional tensions as the Gaza war dragged on.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was laid to rest in Lusail, north of the capital Doha, following funeral prayers at the Gulf emirate's largest mosque attended by thousands of people.</p>

<p>Haniyeh, the Palestinian armed group's political chief, played a key role in mediated talks aimed at ending nearly 10 months of war between Hamas and Israel in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The burial was restricted to a small number of people including one of Haniyeh's daughters, Sara, who shared a video on social media showing her pouring holy water over a pebble-topped grave before lowering her head to kiss it.</p>

<p>"In this moment, I buried my soul under the dirt and I departed. I departed with all the pain of the world in my ribs," she captioned the video uploaded on X.</p>

<p>Mourners earlier on Friday lined up inside Imam Muhammad bin Abdul Wahhab Mosque, where Haniyeh's casket, draped in a Palestinian flag, was briefly carried in to the shouts of angry mourners.</p>

<p>Others prayed on mats outside in temperatures that reached 44 degrees Celsius (111 degrees Fahrenheit).</p>

<p>"He was a symbol, a resistance leader... people are angry," said Taher Adel, 25, a Jordanian student residing in the Qatari capital.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's predecessor Khaled Meshaal spoke at the ceremony, saying he had "served his cause, his people... and never abandoned them".</p>

<p>Turkey and Pakistan announced a day of mourning on Friday to honour Haniyeh, while Hamas called for a "day of furious rage".</p>

<p>Many mourners in Doha wore scarves that combined the Palestinian flag with a checkered keffiyeh pattern and the message in English: "Free Palestine".</p>

<p><strong>High-profile killings</strong></p>

<p>Haniyeh and a bodyguard were killed in a pre-dawn "hit" on their accommodation in Tehran Wednesday, Iran's Revolutionary Guards said. Haniyeh was in Iran to attend the swearing-in of President Masoud Pezeshkian a day earlier.</p>

<p>Israel, accused by Hamas, Iran and others of the attack, has not directly commented on it.</p>

<p>The killing of Qatar-based Haniyeh is among several incidents since April that have sent regional tensions soaring during the Gaza war, which has drawn in Iran-backed armed groups in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Iranian officials met with representatives of these groups on Wednesday to discuss the next steps, either "a simultaneous response from Iran and its allies or a staggered response from each party", a source close to Lebanon's Hezbollah movement told AFP.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant met with his visiting British counterpart John Healey on Friday and stressed "the importance of establishing a coalition" to support "Israel's defence against Iran and its proxies", Gallant's office said.</p>

<p>Military chief Herzi Halevi told troops Israel would respond "very strongly" to any attacks, an army statement said.</p>

<p>France urged its nationals visiting Iran to leave "due to the increased risk of a military escalation".</p>

<p>During the Gaza war, Hezbollah and Israeli forces have engaged in near-daily exchanges of fire, and did so again on Friday.</p>

<p>In Gaza, the civil defence agency reported several people killed in the territory's north, and Israel's military said it had killed around 30 operatives near Rafah, in the south.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's assassination came hours after Israel struck a southern suburb of Beirut, killing Fuad Shukr, the military commander of Lebanese Hamas ally Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's deputy, Saleh al-Aruri, was killed in Beirut early this year.</p>

<p>On Thursday Israel confirmed the death of Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif in a July strike in Gaza.</p>

<p><strong>Deal 'off the table'</strong></p>

<p>Israel has vowed to destroy Hamas in retaliation for its October 7 attack that ignited the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The attack on southern Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Hamas operatives also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign against Hamas has killed at least 39,480 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>The fighting has sparked a dire humanitarian crisis in the besieged territory. On Friday, the UN Satellite Centre said nearly two-thirds of the buildings in Gaza, or 151,265 structures, have been damaged or destroyed during the war.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei led prayers for Haniyeh in Tehran, having earlier threatened "harsh punishment" for his killing.</p>

<p>The New York Times, citing Middle Eastern officials, has reported that Haniyeh was killed by an explosive device planted weeks ago at a Tehran guesthouse.</p>

<p>Asked about the report, Israeli military spokesman Daniel Hagari told journalists "there was no other Israeli aerial attack... in all the Middle East" on the night of Shukr's killing in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel said Shukr's assassination -- for which Hezbollah said retaliation was "inevitable" -- was a response to rocket fire which killed 12 youths last week in the annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Iranian news agency Fars said the US report was a "lie", insisting that the Hamas leader was killed by a "projectile".</p>

<p>Analyst Hugh Lovatt said Haniyeh's killing "will mean that a ceasefire deal with Israel is now totally off of the table".</p>

<p>The White House said US President Joe Biden spoke with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Thursday and affirmed his commitment to defend Israel's security "against all threats from Iran".</p>

<p>"We have the basis for a ceasefire (in Gaza)... They should move on it now," Biden told reporters after the call.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6j87p5dg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Turkey and Pakistan announced a day of mourning on Friday to honour Ismail Haniyeh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-putin-might-gain-or-lose-from-prisoner-swap-with-west-6250676]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Putin Might Gain Or Lose From Prisoner Swap With West]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-putin-might-gain-or-lose-from-prisoner-swap-with-west-6250676]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 23:03:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When eight Russian citizens including a convicted hitman touched down in Moscow on Thursday in a historic prisoner swap with the West, President Vladimir Putin greeted them like heroes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When eight Russian citizens including a convicted hitman touched down in Moscow on Thursday in a historic prisoner swap with the West, President Vladimir Putin greeted them like heroes.</p>

<p>"I want to congratulate you all on your return to your Motherland," Putin beamed, assuring the group that also included cybercriminals and spies that Russia had not forgotten them for "even a minute".</p>

<p>Putin's message -- both to those released on Thursday and his agents across the world -- was clear: Even if you get caught, the Kremlin has your back.</p>

<p>A total of 24 people were freed in Thursday's exchange -- 16 headed to the West and eight to Russia -- in the biggest prisoner swap deal since the Cold War.</p>

<p>Russia released US journalists Evan Gershkovich and Alsu Kurmasheva, ex-marine Paul Whelan as well as high-profile domestic dissidents.</p>

<p>In return, it secured the largest number of alleged Russian spies freed in a single exchange for over a decade, as well as FSB security service assassin Vadim Krasikov.</p>

<p>"For the target audience, Putin brought back his soldiers, the heroes of a hybrid Third World War," said Russian political analyst Konstantin Kalachev.</p>

<p>"And the audience is not just special services, but millions who feel like citizens of a country at war with a stronger enemy," he added.</p>

<p>Among those returning to Russia were two sleeper agents living on false documents in Slovenia, a prolific hacker and an alleged Russian colonel posing as a Brazilian researcher in Norway.</p>

<p>For Putin, the main prize was Krasikov -- an elite FSB officer arrested in Germany in 2019 for murdering a former Chechen separatist on what Berlin said was Moscow's orders.</p>

<p>Putin, previously director of the FSB and an officer in its Soviet incarnation the KGB, had long pushed for Krasikov to be included in a prisoner swap deal, an idea that Germany had resisted.</p>

<p>The deal will have "strengthened loyalty" among other spies and assassins, said Abbas Gallyamov, an independent political analyst and former Kremlin speechwriter.</p>

<p>"Putin can count on them to work with greater dedication," he added.</p>

<p><strong>'Win-win'</strong></p>

<p>For the West, the exchange has raised fears Putin could become even more emboldened to take prisoners in what it blasts as "hostage diplomacy".</p>

<p>The Kremlin said Friday it was determined to see the release of more Russians it believes are wrongfully imprisoned in the West.</p>

<p>Over the last two years, Russia had been "blatantly" detaining Westerners for a possible swap "as negotiations with the West stalled" amid the Ukraine offensive, said Tatiana Stanovaya, a senior fellow at the Carnegie Russia Eurasia Center.</p>

<p>Russia and the West have a long history of swaps, including in 2022 when US basketball star Brittney Griner was exchanged with Russian arms dealer Viktor Bout.</p>

<p>But with Thursday's deal involving not just foreigners but Russian dissidents, Moscow reminded "the whole world of its repression, lawlessness and cruelty against critics of the authorities," Stanovaya said in an article.</p>

<p>Before the 2022 agreements to free first US Marine Trevor Reed and then Griner, deals had usually involved swapping spies for spies.</p>

<p>Moscow has tried to present this deal in similar terms.</p>

<p>Gershkovich and Whelan were both convicted of "espionage" -- charges rejected as baseless by the White House -- and the FSB said on Thursday that the Russians it released had "acted in the interests of foreign states to the detriment of Russia's security."</p>

<p>But to the West, the arrest of Gershkovich in particular -- the first "espionage" charges levelled at a US reporter in Russia since the cold War -- showed the Kremlin was willing to cross red lines.</p>

<p>Russia may see the exchange as a great success and "wonderful victory", political analyst Ekaterina Schulmann said in an interview with Russia's independent TV Rain.</p>

<p>But the reality was more nuanced.</p>

<p>"Russia is getting eight clumsy losers who couldn't do their job and got caught," she said.</p>

<p>"While it is giving away people who, if they want to and if they are able, will become significant political public figures."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/imbnpsc8_putin-met-freed-prisoners_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A total of 24 people were freed in Thursday's exchange (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-convinced-iran-will-attack-israel-in-few-days-report-6249881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Administration Convinced Iran Will Attack Israel In Few Days: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-convinced-iran-will-attack-israel-in-few-days-report-6249881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 21:05:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden administration is convinced that Iran will attack Israel in the coming days and is preparing to help it repel it , three American sources told Axios.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden administration is convinced that Iran will attack Israel in the coming days and is preparing to help it repel it , three American sources told Axios, according to which the Iranian attack - in retaliation for the killing of Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran - could follow the same pattern as the one conducted on April 13, but potentially larger, could involve the Lebanese Hezbollah.</p>

<p>But the administration fears that, unlike four months ago, it may be more difficult to mobilise the same regional and international coalition that helped Israel defend itself from the swarm of drones and missiles launched in April, reports Adnkronos news agency.</p>

<p>The killing of Ismail Haniyeh "does not help" efforts to reach a ceasefire in Gaza with Hamas, US President Joe Biden admitted, speaking to reporters at the Andrews air base where he went to welcome prisoners exchanged with Russia.</p>

<p>Biden - who yesterday had a telephone conversation with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu - said he was "very concerned" about the latest escalation of tensions in the Middle East.</p>

<p>"We have a ceasefire base, it has to go forward and they have to go forward," the president urged again, in a reference to the phone call with Netanyahu, which he called "very direct."</p>

<p>Ismail Haniyeh will be buried in Qatar today. The body of the Hamas political leader arrived in Doha yesterday from Iran, after thousands of people attended his funeral in Tehran.</p>

<p>According to Hamas and Qatari state media, the funeral prayer will be held after the Friday prayer at Qatar's national mosque, followed by burial in the city of Lusail.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/98jjcpo8_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said he was "very concerned" about the latest escalation of tensions in the Middle East (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/group-captain-shubhanshu-shukla-to-fly-to-space-station-5-facts-6249467]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Facts About Group Captain Shubhanshu Shukla, Set For Space Mission]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/group-captain-shubhanshu-shukla-to-fly-to-space-station-5-facts-6249467]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 02 Aug 2024 20:11:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Group Captain Shubhanshu Shukla has been chosen as the prime astronaut for the upcoming Indo-US mission to the International Space Station (ISS). He is the youngest of ISRO's astronaut-designates.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>He was born in Lucknow on October 10, 1985 and was a Wing Commander before being promoted to Group Captain recently.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>He is an alumnus of the National Defence Academy and was commissioned on June 17, 2006 in the fighter stream of the Indian Air Force.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>He will fly on Axiom-4 flight using the Space-X rocket and Crew Dragon.</li>
	<li>He has undergone a Fighter Combat Leader course from the prestigious Tactics and Combat Development Establishment (TACDE) school. He is also a Test Pilot with approximately 2000 hrs of flying experience.</li>
	<li>He has flown a variety of aircraft including Su-30 MKI, MiG-21, MiG-29, Jaguar, BAe Hawk, Domnier, and An-32.<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gq6mvatg_shubhanshu-shukla_625x300_02_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>