<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 13:37:09 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-thousands-of-ukrainians-to-graduate-amid-to-stay-or-leave-concerns-6184331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Of Ukrainians To Graduate Amid "To Stay Or Leave" Concerns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-thousands-of-ukrainians-to-graduate-amid-to-stay-or-leave-concerns-6184331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:33:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of teachers and professors have been fighting on the front lines and one-fifth of the sector's facilities have been damaged or destroyed by Russian bombardments]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anton Yushyn spent four years studying Italian at university in Kyiv but the outbreak of war taught him the most valuable lesson of his student life: to prioritise what matters most.</p>

<p>When he enrolled at Kyiv National Linguistic University, Russia had not yet invaded, and his main concerns were socialising and passing exams to placate his parents.</p>

<p>"Maybe it's not my goals that have changed but my values," Yushyn, 22, told AFP on graduation day in Kyiv last month.</p>

<p>"It all used to be about parties and having fun. Now you need to spend more time with family and friends because they could be gone at any moment," he said.</p>

<p>Thousands of Ukrainians graduating from around 300 universities this summer are entering into a society transformed by war -- their futures in doubt with no end in sight to the fighting.</p>

<p>As Ukraine mobilises young men to replenish the army's stretched ranks, male graduates face the prospect of being called up once they turn 25.</p>

<p>Higher education has not been immune from the conflict.</p>

<p>Dozens of teachers and professors have been fighting on the front lines and one-fifth of the sector's facilities have been damaged or destroyed by Russian bombardments.</p>

<p>In December 2022, a missile landed just a few hundred metres from Yushyn's campus.</p>

<h3><strong>To stay, or leave</strong></h3>

<p>But on graduation day, the mood at Yushyn's alma mater was festive. Perfume hung in the hot summer air and staff congratulated joyful students for completing their studies in the face of historic turbulence.</p>

<p>Student life was barely back to normal after the Covid pandemic when Russia invaded in February 2022.</p>

<p>Universities suspended classes and Korean language student Nikoletta Shova was sent by her parents to stay with relatives in Italy.</p>

<p>The 22-year-old compared the "emotional" time abroad to being in a "stupor", left wondering if she would ever be able to return.</p>

<p>Teaching restarted at most universities just a few weeks later -- online or in person -- when Russian forces were still on Kyiv's outskirts.</p>

<p>Shova returned after three months away and was able to finish her degree in person while raising money for the war effort with classmates.</p>

<p>Now, with her diploma in hand, uncertainty had returned.</p>

<p>She was considering studying abroad -- possibly marketing in the United States -- but she was also open to finding a creative job at home.</p>

<p>Building a future in Ukraine despite the war was possible, she said, borrowing a popular phrase to underscore that it would take perseverance: "he who doesn't take risks never drinks champagne".</p>

<h3><strong>Jokes, memes</strong></h3>

<p>"So I'm being realistic but with a bit of positivity," she said of her future.</p>

<p>Daryna Dekhtiar, 22, also a graduate of Kyiv National Linguistic University, went numb when Russia invaded.</p>

<p>"I didn't cry at all. I just went into autopilot," she said, but her friends had helped lift her spirits too, she added.</p>

<p>"We created our own memes, our jokes, it made it all much easier," she recalled.</p>

<p>Dana Andriichuk, who already had secured an office job by graduation, was rushing to meet friends after the ceremony.</p>

<p>She didn't want to dwell on the relative comfort of her student years or spend too much thinking about the prospect of a long war.</p>

<p>"I'm trying to avoid being a pessimist stuck in the past. I want to live now and not in the future, because we don't know what will happen next," she said.</p>

<p>"If the government encourages young people to stay and do everything possible to build a better future even in a state of war -- and society becomes nationally conscious -- then we can consider staying in the country," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>- 'Don't run and hide' -</strong></h3>

<p>Like thousands of other male graduates, Yushyn does not have as much freedom to choose. Authorities have barred men aged between 18 and 60 from leaving Ukraine.</p>

<p>Thousands have left illegally and dozens have died trying.</p>

<p>But Yushyn was resigned to life at home.</p>

<p>"Real men don't run and hide. If the time comes and I get a summons, I won't run from it," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"I can wind myself up, cry, sit here trembling all I want, it won't change the trajectory of the rocket," he said.</p>

<p>Whatever the future holds, he said he was unlikely to use Italian, but was resolved to spending his time as best he could.</p>

<p>"I need to use it to the fullest."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3fssseo_graduates_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Student life was barely back to normal after Covid-19 when Russia invaded Ukraine (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-court-clears-bayers-roundup-of-blood-cancer-risk-claims-6184258]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Can Bayer Weedkiller Cause Blood Cancer? What Australian Court Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-court-clears-bayers-roundup-of-blood-cancer-risk-claims-6184258]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:22:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian judge on Thursday dismissed a class action lawsuit claiming Bayer's Roundup weedkiller can cause a type of blood cancer, a boost for the company which is grappling with a slew of similar cases in the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian judge on Thursday dismissed a class action lawsuit claiming Bayer's Roundup weedkiller can cause a type of blood cancer, a boost for the company which is grappling with a slew of similar cases in the United States.</p>

<p>Justice Michael Lee of Australia's Federal Court ruled that on the balance of probabilities, there was insufficient evidence to conclude that Roundup can cause non-Hodgkins lymphoma (NHL).</p>

<p>"It is not proven in this proceeding on a balance of probabilities... that throughout the relevant period use of, and or exposure to Roundup products increased an individual's risk of developing NHL," Lee said.</p>

<p>The German pharmaceutical and chemicals company has maintained that Roundup, a glyphosate-based herbicide, is safe. It says it "fully stands behind its glyphosate-based products, which have been used around the world for almost 50 years."</p>

<p>The Australian class action against Bayer subsidiaries united more than 1,000 claimants and is one of some 40 cases filed outside the United States, all in either Canada or Australia.</p>

<p>Lead claimant, 41-year-old Kelvin McNickle, said he used Roundup to spray weeds for over two decades on his family's property and while working for a vegetation management company. He developed non-Hodgkins lymphoma at age 35.</p>

<p>In the United States, Bayer has prevailed in 14 of the last 20 Roundup trials, but it also racked up a string of losses in late 2023 and early 2024, resulting in more than $4 billion in damages awarded in verdicts.</p>

<p>Some of those verdicts have seen the amounts awarded reduced but the string of wins for plaintiffs shattered investor and company hopes that the worst of the Roundup litigation was over.</p>

<p>The company still faces more than 50,000 outstanding claims in the United States. A request for an agreement to prevent future cases was denied by a U.S. court.</p>

<p>Roundup was originally produced by U.S. agrochemical company Monsanto, which Bayer acquired for $63 billion in 2018.</p>

<p>The company has replaced glyphosate with new active ingredients in its products for household use in the United States to reduce the risk of litigation as most claims have come from home users.</p>

<p>It continues to sell glyphosate-based weedkillers to farmers, who rely on it heavily.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/uko0n4og_bayer-roundup_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company still faces more than 50,000 outstanding claims in the US]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-police-officer-filmed-kicking-and-stomping-on-mans-head-at-airport-probe-on-6184212]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Police Officer Filmed Stomping On Man's Head At Airport, Probe Launched]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-police-officer-filmed-kicking-and-stomping-on-mans-head-at-airport-probe-on-6184212]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 12:16:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disturbing videos showing a British police officer kicking and stomping on a man's head at Manchester Airport on Tuesday night have sparked outrage on social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disturbing videos showing a British police officer kicking and stomping on a man's head at Manchester Airport on Tuesday night have sparked outrage on social media. In one of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/doamuslims/status/1816111762057368046">clips</a>, the uniformed male officer is seen holding a Taser over the man, who is lying face down, before striking him twice while other officers shout at onlookers to stay back. The officer is also seen stomping his boots on the back of the man's head and slamming his knee into his back before sitting on top of him. Later in the same video, another man, whose hands were in the air while sitting nearby, is also taken to the ground after a police officer points a taser at him. Both men appeared to be handcuffed and taken into custody.</p>

<p>The second&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/doamuslims/status/1816206815404888228">video </a>shows another man being confronted, pepper-sprayed in the face and brought to the ground by a police officer who wrapped his arm around the man's neck as he wrestled him down. The clips appear to show the attacks taking place on the ground level of the airport outside of several elevators.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a statement on X (formerly Twitter), Greater Manchester Police (GMP) confirmed the incident, which took place in the airport's Terminal 2 on Tuesday. The cops said that footage on social media showed a confrontation that began after three officers were injured in a "violent assault", including one female officer who suffered a broken nose. However, they also added that the event seen in the videos was "truly shocking" and an "unusual occurrence". A male officer has been "removed from operational duties," the police said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We know that a film of an incident at Manchester Airport that is circulating widely shows an event that is truly shocking, and that people are rightly extremely concerned about," said Assistant Chief Constable Chaudhry.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We know that our communities are rightly concerned by video footage, which is being circulated online, that shows armed police officers responding to an incident at Manchester Airport .<br />
<br />
Assistant Chief Constable Wasim Chaudhry has issued a statement. <a href="https://t.co/xdHmUYeobL">pic.twitter.com/xdHmUYeobL</a></p>
— Greater Manchester Police (@gmpolice) <a href="https://twitter.com/gmpolice/status/1816195729527898134?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"The use of such force in an arrest is an unusual occurrence and one that we understand creates alarm. One male officer has been removed from operational duties and we are making a voluntary referral of our policing response to the Independent Office of Police Conduct (IOPC)," Mr Chaudhry added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The IOPC said it would assess GMP's referral "and decide what further action is required".</p>

<p>In its post, the Greater Manchester Police also outlined what it said were the events that led up to the videos. Cops said that they were called to Terminal 2 of the airport on Tuesday evening following reports of an assault. When they confronted the male suspect, three officers were injured in a "violent assault, where they were punched to the ground," with one female officer ending up with a broken nose, the force said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Four men have been arrested for assaulting an emergency worker, the statement added.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tatyana-ozolina-dubbed-russias-most-beautiful-biker-dies-in-motorbike-crash-in-turkey-6182895">Tatyana Ozolina, Dubbed "Russia's Most Beautiful Biker", Dies In Motorbike Crash In Turkey</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, on social media, the incident has sparked an outcry over whether violence used by police was proportionate or justified. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c7259wpl1x9o"><em>BBC</em></a>, protesters gathered outside the force's divisional headquarters in the town of Rochdale on Wednesday. Many British politicians also condemned the incident and called the videos "disturbing".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Andy Burnham, the mayor of Greater Manchester, called the videos "disturbing" in a post on X. UK Home Office Minister Diana Johnson said on X that she was "aware of the disturbing footage" and "understand(s) the public concern it has prompted. I have asked for a full update from Greater Manchester Police."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rpkbpo6_uk-police-video_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Four men have been arrested for assaulting an emergency worker.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/schools-shut-flights-cancelled-as-typhoon-gaemi-brings-rain-in-philippines-6184065]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Schools Shut, Flights Cancelled As Typhoon Gaemi Brings Rain In Philippines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/schools-shut-flights-cancelled-as-typhoon-gaemi-brings-rain-in-philippines-6184065]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Heavy rain from Typhoon Gaemi has flooded the Philippine capital Manila and nearby cities, forcing authorities to shut schools, and offices and cancel flights on Wednesday and declare a state of calamity in a region that is home to 13 million people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heavy rain from Typhoon Gaemi has flooded the Philippine capital Manila and nearby cities, forcing authorities to shut schools, and offices and cancel flights on Wednesday and declare a state of calamity in a region that is home to 13 million people.</p>

<p>The storm, which is strengthening as it gusts towards Taiwan, did not make landfall in the Philippines but has intensified seasonal monsoon rains, causing landslides and flooding over the past few days.</p>

<p>At least 12 people have died and more than 600,000 are displaced due to the storm, known locally as Typhoon Carina, the national disaster agency said. Water in some areas is neck-high.</p>

<p>The Philippine Coastguard said 260 passengers and 16 vessels were stranded in ports while airlines cancelled 114 flights out of Manila on Wednesday, the airport authority said.</p>

<p>The financial markets were also closed.</p>

<p>President Ferdinand Marcos Jr told the disaster relief agencies to provide assistance and prepare supplies for isolated communities during a briefing on Wednesday, and the mayors of 16 cities in the Greater Manila region have asked for emergency funding, officials said.</p>

<p>In the riverside city of Marikina, emergency workers waded through waist-deep waters and used rubber dinghies to rescue residents from their inundated homes.</p>

<p>Some people were sheltered in churches, among the statues of Catholic saints.</p>

<p>"The flood reached the second floor of our house, all our things are ruined, everything got wet, nothing was saved," Ladylyn Bernas, an evacuee at a nearby church, told Reuters.</p>

<p>Social media posts showed several vehicles stuck in water or floating down streets and highways.</p>

<p>The Philippines sees an average of 20 tropical storms annually, causing floods and deadly landslides.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4bstdkr_philippine-storm_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 12 people have died and more than 600,000 are displaced due to the storm.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paris-olympics-france-announces-major-operation-to-fight-cyber-spying-6183970]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Announces Major Operation To Fight Cyber-Spying Ahead Of Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paris-olympics-france-announces-major-operation-to-fight-cyber-spying-6183970]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:40:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Investigators were targeting a network of bots suspected of infecting computers with PlugX malware and of stealing data from them "notably for purposes of espionage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French authorities have launched a major operation to clean up computers infected by a cyber-espionage programme that has struck millions of users worldwide, a senior prosecutor said Thursday.</p>

<p>"On the eve of the Olympics, this operation demonstrates that different players in France and abroad are mobilised to fight against all forms of cybercrime," Paris chief prosecutor Laure Beccuau said in a statement.</p>

<p>She said investigators were targeting a network of bots suspected of infecting computers with PlugX malware and of stealing data from them "notably for purposes of espionage".</p>

<p>She said analysts and investigators had managed to take control of a server that was controlling millions of the infected computers and were administering a fix.</p>

<p>They launched the operation on July 18 and it is expected to last several months, having already aided victims in several European countries, the statement said.</p>

<p>It did not cite a specific threat to the Paris Olympics. But separately, the French government's cyber security agency warned last week that ransomware attacks will be "inevitable" during the Games, which officially open Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nodrs9mg_cyber_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-protesters-disrupt-germanys-frankfurt-airport-flights-suspended-6183878]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany's Busiest Airport Resume Operations After Climate Activist Protest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-protesters-disrupt-germanys-frankfurt-airport-flights-suspended-6183878]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:29:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Frankfurt airport, Germany's busiest, has resumed operations after suspending flights on Thursday morning when several climate activists blocked runways by gluing themselves to the tarmac.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Frankfurt airport, Germany's busiest, has resumed operations after suspending flights on Thursday morning when several climate activists blocked runways by gluing themselves to the tarmac.</p>

<p>Planes were able to take off and land again, the airport said on its website, but passengers were still advised to check on their flight status before setting off for the airport.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Frankfurt, a vital international transit hub and one of Europe's biggest airports, said around 140 flights had been cancelled out of 1,400 planned on Thursday.</p>

<p>Last Generation climate activists said in a statement that six protesters had cut through a fence and had reached various points around the Frankfurt airport runways with posters reading "Oil kills". Images released by the group showed protesters in orange safety vests with their hands glued to the tarmac.</p>

<p>A federal police spokesperson said several climate activists were on the airport grounds.</p>

<p>The group, which wants the German government to pursue a global agreement to exit oil, gas, and coal by 2030, has listed several countries across Europe and North America where similar disruptions are planned as part of a protest campaign that began on Wednesday.</p>

<p>In Norway, around a dozen activists blocked a part of the check-in area of the Oslo Airport, in a second day of actions, but there was no disruption of flights to and from the Norwegian capital, an airport official said.</p>

<p>Germany's Cologne-Bonn airport, the country's sixth-largest, suspended flights for several hours on Wednesday after climate activists glued themselves to a runway, while similar actions at other European airports had been foiled by authorities.</p>

<p>German Interior Minister Nancy Faeser, whose ministry wants to punish unauthorized airfield access with up to two years in jail, called the action "dangerous, dumb and criminal."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fj519m68_germany-airport-protest_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A spokesperson for Frankfurt said around 140 flights had been cancelled out of 1,400 planned on Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-mi-28-military-helicopter-crashes-due-to-malfunction-crew-dead-6183871]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Mi-28 Military Helicopter Crashes Due To Malfunction, Crew Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-mi-28-military-helicopter-crashes-due-to-malfunction-crew-dead-6183871]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:27:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Mi-28 military helicopter crashed in an uninhabited area of southwestern Russia, killing the crew, two Russian news agencies said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Mi-28 military helicopter crashed in an uninhabited area of southwestern Russia, killing the crew, two Russian news agencies said Thursday.</p>

<p>"An Mi-28 crashed in the Kaluga region... the crew died," the TASS news agency said, quoting a source in the defence ministry.</p>

<p>"According to preliminary information, a technical malfunction caused the disaster," the Interfax news agency said, citing a defence ministry statement.</p>

<p>It crashed in a forest about 150 kilometres (93 miles) from the Ukrainian border, a local official told TASS.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ki8fta78_mi28-military-helicopter_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/group-that-backed-nikki-hailey-over-donald-trump-now-supports-kamala-harris-6183870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Group That Backed Nikki Hailey Over Donald Trump Now Supports Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/group-that-backed-nikki-hailey-over-donald-trump-now-supports-kamala-harris-6183870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:27:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The group has raised nearly $400,000 from anti-Trump groups and encourages former Haley supporters to vote for Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of anti-Donald Trump voters,&nbsp;that previously backed Nikki Haley in the Republican primary, has now thrown its support behind the Democrat's likely US presidential nominee Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>The political action committee (PAC) in question, known as PIVOTPAC, rebranded from 'Haley Voters for Biden' to 'Haley Voters for Harris' after President Joe Biden quit the presidential race.</p>

<p>The PAC encourages Haley supporters to now support Kamala Harris for the race to the White House.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We stress that we proudly supported <a href="https://twitter.com/NikkiHaley?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NikkiHaley</a> over Trump. We have no regrets. We wish her well.<br />
<br />
It was always about what was best for our country.<br />
<br />
While we respect her personal decision to support the Republican nominee, we believe <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> is better for the country.</p>
— Haley Voters for Harris (@HaleyVte4Harris) <a href="https://twitter.com/HaleyVte4Harris/status/1816150751112278108?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This comes after Nikki Haley sent a cease and desist letter demanding the group stop using her name to support Harris. "Kamala Harris and I are total opposites on every issue. Any attempt to use my name to support her or her agenda is deceptive and wrong," Haley stated firmly.</p>

<p>Haley, a former Republican primary challenger, served as the US Ambassador to the United Nations in Donald Trump's first tenure as American President. She has now endorsed Trump for president and her lawyers argue the group's use of her name implies she supports Harris, which is false.</p>

<p>"I support Donald Trump because he understands we need to make America strong, safe and prosperous," Haley said, as per KTSM.</p>

<p>The 'Haley Voters for Harris' group, with nearly 7,000 followers, responded, "We will not be suppressed". The PAC has raised nearly $400,000 from anti-Trump groups and claims they don't speak on behalf of Haley and will continue to support Harris, calling her the "clear better choice" for the country.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We enthusiastically supported <a href="https://twitter.com/NikkiHaley?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NikkiHaley</a> over former President Trump in the primaries.<br />
<br />
Our rights to engage with likeminded voters and encourage them to vote for <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> - the clear better choice for the country - will not be suppressed.<br />
<br />
Statement below: <a href="https://t.co/o6gHlFkmyZ">https://t.co/o6gHlFkmyZ</a> <a href="https://t.co/EhW8FAipiv">pic.twitter.com/EhW8FAipiv</a></p>
— Haley Voters for Harris (@HaleyVte4Harris) <a href="https://twitter.com/HaleyVte4Harris/status/1815862099912057178?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Harris campaign has welcomed the group's support, with a spokesperson saying, "We're glad to have the support of voters who share our vision for a better America."</p>

<p>The director of Haley Voters for Harris, Craig Snyder, defended the group's name in an NPR interview, calling it a "factual statement" of how many people feel and plan to vote in November.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Harris campaign's National Republican Engagement Director, Austin Weatherford, welcomed "millions of Republicans" who rejected Trump's extremism, saying they "have a home in the Harris campaign's coalition".</p>

<p>Mr Weatherford said the campaign was focused on earning support from these voters, who prioritise democracy and national security.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bqfnk8go_kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/kamala-harris-the-woman-left-to-clean-up-us-president-joe-bidens-mess-6183840]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Kamala Harris, The Woman Left To Clean Up Joe Biden's Mess]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/kamala-harris-the-woman-left-to-clean-up-us-president-joe-bidens-mess-6183840]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:20:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Choosing Kamala Harris over Joe Biden is a tactical course-correction for Democrats, but it may have come a bit too late. Her strengths may not get optimised, her weaknesses are for all to see.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4r6407j8_kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>
</div>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2020-when-kamala-harris-called-president-elect-joe-biden-after-historic-win-says-we-did-it-joe-watch-2322207">"We did it, Joe,"</a> exclaimed the 49th Vice-President of the United States four years ago-the phrase becoming a war cry of sorts, coming from a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/kamala-harris-and-her-india-connection-818442">half-Black, half-Indian woman</a>, married to a Jewish-American man. This moment became a landmark in the sociopolitical history of the US. For all its celebratory moments, American democracy has a long way to go in terms of representation and inclusivity. When it comes to women, the gender schemas work as effectively in the oldest democracy of the world as it does in the emergent ones to keep women away from the high table.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Can <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/kamala-harris-to-rishi-sunak-indians-must-be-realistic-about-the-rise-of-indian-origin-leaders-6117384">Kamala Harris</a> be successful in the Holy Grail pursuit of occupying the Oval Office? The odds are stacked against her, starting from the delayed announcement of her candidature. With less than a month to go for the Democratic convention to secure her name on the ticket, Harris has a mountain to climb. The funding numbers are encouraging but the money can go only thus far in attitudinal and ideological battles.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Women And Politics</strong></h2>

<p>To begin with, there is a problem with the recall. Studies (J Hitchon &amp; C Chang, 1995) have revealed that voters recall women candidates in terms of their family and appearance and their men counterparts in terms of campaign activities. Harris understands that and has made this tendency work for her by highlighting her family background. However, in a deeply polarised American society which is in the throes of backlash against diversity, equity and inclusion (DEI), this strategy may not work as desired any longer.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/kamala-harris-says-number-of-indian-americans-in-elected-offices-not-reflective-of-their-population-5673477">Also Read |&nbsp;Indian Americans In Offices Not Reflective Of Their Population: Kamala Harris</a></strong></p>

<p>American women have been consistently voting at a higher rate than men for more than four decades now. They are certainly not less political than men. Yet, even they are not sending enough women to political offices. Women candidates continue to get penalised for expressing emotions, particularly anger. Harris has been trying to keep her 'anger' in check, often descending into banalities in her public speeches. She has become a constant fodder for the meme factory. Whether this is a carefully crafted strategy, only time will tell. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>"Too Coloured", "Not Coloured Enough"</strong></h2>

<p>Harris was only the second Black woman elected to the US Senate in the history of the country. This tells the world something that the Americans cannot be proud of. "The most disrespected person in America is the Black woman. The most unprotected person in America is the Black woman. The most neglected person in America is the Black woman," said Malcolm X in 1962. Per some critical indices like education, healthcare, wages et al, the observation holds even today. Harris has come a long way jumping over fiery hoops of racial and gender discrimination. Her win in the presidential polls will be a bigger moment than Barack Obama's presidency in terms of America's race issue. A decade after the 'Black Lives Matter' movement first made its appearance on social media, American society continues to struggle to find the golden equilibrium. The anti-DEI rabble-rousers have now found effective means to punish individuals and institutions that do not toe supremacist lines.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/us-presidential-election-she-s-experienced-tough-capable-joe-biden-praises-kamala-harris-818474">Watch |&nbsp;"She's Experienced, Tough, Capable": Joe Biden Praises Kamala Harris</a></strong></p>

<p>But Harris is not just Black, she's also half-Indian and the country celebrated her <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pride-of-our-village-kamala-harris-ancestral-village-in-tamil-nadu-celebrates-her-victory-2322250">from New Delhi to Chennai</a> as its prodigal daughter. With a steadily growing population in the US over the years, Indians have emerged as a group with political aspirations. Indian community's cultural, regional and religious associations have played an important role in increasing the political heft of Indian Americans. The flip side of this is the growing resentment among the fraudulently so-called originals-the Whites-against powerful immigrant communities. Ironically, even Black Americans harbour some resentment against immigrant communities that have reached the upper rungs of the socio-economic ladder. While this is sociologically 'natural', people like Harris are peculiarly affected. She's coloured but not adequately so for some.</p>

<h2><strong>A Course-Correction Too Late</strong></h2>

<p>2024 is no 2018, when a surge for Democrats in general and women candidates in particular, sent Democratic women politicians of different ethnicities like Debra Haaland and Sharice Davids (Native American); Ayanna Pressley and Jahana Hayes (Women of Colour); Veronica Escobar, Sylvia R. Garcia, Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (Latinas) to the Congress. The Republican campaign is bolstered by many a foreign policy faux pas of the Biden administration, the most important one being its role in the Israel-Palestine conflict. Even the captive Democratic voter is expressing dissent. The assassination attempt on Donald Trump has catapulted his already strong chances.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Choosing Harris over Biden is a tactical course-correction for Democrats, but it may have come a bit too late in the day. Her strengths may not get optimised, her weaknesses are for all to see. As her V-P tenure goes, she has all the blame to carry but no benefits to reap.</p>

<p>Harris has the unenviable position of being the woman who cleans up after a man. If she emerges triumphant, it will be her personal victory, not that of the party.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Nishtha Gautam is a Delhi-based author and academic.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mfoidgr8_kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-sanctions-israel-settlers-accused-of-sexual-assault-of-palestinians-6183746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia Sanctions Israel Settlers Accused Of Assault Of Palestinians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-sanctions-israel-settlers-accused-of-sexual-assault-of-palestinians-6183746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:05:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia on Thursday followed Europe and the United States by levying sanctions on Israeli settlers accused of "beatings, sexual assault and torture" of Palestinians in the occupied West Bank.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia on Thursday followed Europe and the United States by levying sanctions on Israeli settlers accused of "beatings, sexual assault and torture" of Palestinians in the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister Penny Wong announced financial sanctions and travel bans on seven individuals and the Hilltop Youth religious settler group.</p>

<p>"The individuals sanctioned today have been involved in violent attacks on Palestinians," Wong said.</p>

<p>"This includes beatings, sexual assault and torture of Palestinians resulting in serious injury and in some cases, death."</p>

<p>Settlement expansion has increased sharply since Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu returned to power in late 2022 at the helm of a hardline pro-settler coalition.</p>

<p>The West Bank -- occupied by Israel since 1967 -- has seen a significant spike in violence since the start of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.</p>

<p>At least 589 Palestinians have been killed in the West Bank by Israeli troops or settlers since the outbreak of the war on October 7, according to Palestinian authorities.</p>

<p>Over the same period at least 17 Israelis, including soldiers, have been killed in attacks in the territory involving Palestinians, according to Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Canberra's announcement echoes moves by the US, Britain, Canada and the European Union who have also blacklisted Israeli settlers.</p>

<p>"Israeli settlements in the Occupied Palestinian Territories are illegal under international law and a significant obstacle to peace," Wong added.</p>

<p>The International Court of Justice found Israel's occupation of the Palestinian territories illegal on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/evdgoskg_israeli-settlers_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Settlement expansion has increased sharply since PM Benjamin Netanyahu returned to power in 2022 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-recovers-bodies-of-5-hostages-held-in-gaza-6183650]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Recovers Bodies Of 5 Hostages Held In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-recovers-bodies-of-5-hostages-held-in-gaza-6183650]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:45:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces retrieved the bodies of five people taken hostage into the Gaza Strip during Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel, the military said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces retrieved the bodies of five people taken hostage in the Gaza Strip during Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel, the military said Thursday.</p>

<p>The army said the bodies of hostage Maya Goren as well as soldiers Ravid Aryeh Katz, Oren Goldin, Tomer Ahimas and Kiril Brodski had been returned to Israel.</p>

<p>The bodies were recovered on Wednesday during an operation in Khan Yunis, the main city in the south of the Gaza Strip, the military said.</p>

<p>The four soldiers were killed during the October 7 attack launched by Hamas militants, it added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">During an IDF operation led by ISA field analysts and coordinators, the bodies of the murdered hostage Maya Goren, and of the fallen soldiers held captive MSG (Res.) Oren Goldin, SSGT Tomer Ahimas, SGT Kiril Brodski and SGM (Res.) Ravid Aryeh Katz were rescued from the Khan Yunis… <a href="https://t.co/UEQ2B4WCPa">pic.twitter.com/UEQ2B4WCPa</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1816334755551666303?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In December, the military had announced the death of Goren, who was abducted and taken to Gaza on October 7.</p>

<p>Thursday's announcement comes after two Israeli kibbutzim, Nir Oz and Nir Yitzhak, said in separate statements that the army had recovered the bodies of Goren and Goldin.</p>

<p>"Last night, we were informed that in a military rescue operation, the body of the late Maya Goren was recovered," kibbutz Nir Oz said, adding that her family had been informed and more information would follow.</p>

<p>Later in a separate statement kibbutz Nir Yitzhak said the army had returned the body of Goldin.</p>

<p>"This evening, we were informed about the rescue operation for the late Oren Goldin, a member of the kibbutz emergency team, who fell on October 7" during the attack by Hamas militants, Nir Yitzhak said.</p>

<p>On October 7 Hamas militants attacked southern Israeli communities, which resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom remain in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,145 people, also mostly civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/af7e4i6o_israeli-hostage_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bodies were recovered on Wednesday during an operation in Khan Yunis]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-says-starlink-now-operational-on-more-than-1-000-aircraft-6183571]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Starlink Now Operational On More Than 1,000 Aircraft: Elon Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-says-starlink-now-operational-on-more-than-1-000-aircraft-6183571]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:37:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The affordable internet service Starlink is now operational on more than 1,000 aircraft, SpaceX and Tesla CEO Elon Musk said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The affordable internet service Starlink is now operational on more than 1,000 aircraft, SpaceX and Tesla CEO Elon Musk said on Thursday.</p>

<p>According to the company, Starlink keeps passengers connected with high-speed internet from the moment they step onboard their plane.</p>

<p>"Using Starlink on a plane feels like you're on a high-speed ground fibre connection," said the tech billionaire in a post on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Musk recently informed that Sierra Leone in Africa became the 100th country - and the 10th African nation - to be connected to Starlink.</p>

<p>In May, the company launched Starlink in Indonesia and Fiji. According to Musk, no long-term contract is required to order the high-speed internet service with Starlink.</p>

<p>The satellite-based internet service has also received preliminary approval from Sri Lanka to provide internet service in the island nation.</p>

<p>However, the internet service has yet to receive approval from the Indian government.</p>

<p>The commercial part has been examined on issues such as foreign investment and net worth, and the technical requirements have been examined in accordance with the licensing conditions in the country.</p>

<p>Once Starlink gets approval, it will be issued a Global Mobile Personal Communication by Satellite (GMPCS) services license, which is required to provide satellite communication services in the country.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/a945hc54_elon-musk_625x300_24_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starlink is now operational on more than 1,000 aircraft.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philippine-tanker-carrying-1-4-million-litres-of-oil-capsizes-in-manila-bay-6183540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Philippine Tanker Carrying 1.4 Million Litres Of Oil Capsizes In Manila Bay]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philippine-tanker-carrying-1-4-million-litres-of-oil-capsizes-in-manila-bay-6183540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:28:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Philippine-flagged tanker carrying 1.4 million litres of industrial fuel oil capsized and sank off Manila on Thursday, authorities said, as they raced against time to contain the spill.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Philippine-flagged tanker carrying 1.4 million litres of industrial fuel oil capsized and sank off Manila on Thursday, authorities said, as they raced against time to contain the spill.</p>

<p>The MT Terra Nova had been heading for the central city of Iloilo when it sank in Manila Bay, nearly seven kilometres (4.3 miles) off Limay municipality in Bataan province, near the capital, in the early hours.</p>

<p>An oil spill stretching several kilometres has been detected in the busy waterway.</p>

<p>"We are racing against time and we will try to do our best to contain it immediately and stop the fuel from leaking," Philippine Coast Guard spokesperson Rear Admiral Armando Balilo said at a briefing.</p>

<p>He warned that if all the oil in the tanker were to leak, it would be the biggest spill in Philippine history.</p>

<p>"There is a big danger that Manila will be affected, even the shoreline of Manila if the fuel will leak because it is within Manila Bay," Balilo said.</p>

<p>Transport Secretary Jaime Bautista said 16 of the 17 crew members had been rescued.</p>

<p>A search was underway for the missing crew member, but Bautista said strong winds and high waves were hampering response efforts.</p>

<p>Four of the crew were receiving medical treatment.</p>

<p>The Coast Guard said it was investigating "if there was an existing weather disturbance in the vicinity waters" when the MT Terra Nova capsized and sank.</p>

<p>The vessel sank as heavy rains fuelled by Typhoon Gaemi and the seasonal monsoon lashed Manila and surrounding regions in recent days.</p>

<p>An oil slick stretching about 3.7 kilometres was being carried by a "strong current" in an easterly, north-easterly direction, the Coast Guard said in a report.</p>

<p>Coast Guard Commandant Admiral Ronnie Gavan said he has ordered an investigation into the incident.</p>

<p>Marine environmental protection personnel have been mobilised to help contain the slick.</p>

<p>One of the worst oil spills in the Philippines was in February 2023, when a fuel tanker carrying 800,000 litres of industrial fuel oil sank in waters off the central island of Mindoro.</p>

<p>Diesel fuel and thick oil from that vessel contaminated the waters and beaches along the coast of Oriental Mindoro province, devastating the fishing and tourism industries.</p>

<p>The oil dispersed over hundreds of kilometres of waters famed for having some of the most diverse marine life in the world.</p>

<p>Thousands of fishermen were ordered to stay on shore until they could fish safely, and swimming was also banned.</p>

<p>In 2006, a tanker sank off the central island of Guimaras spilling tens of thousands of gallons of oil that destroyed a marine reserve, ruined local fishing grounds and covered stretches of coastline in black sludge.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h1lpdkb_philippine-oil-spill_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An oil spill stretching several kilometres has been detected in the busy waterway.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-doesnt-believe-kamala-harris-can-beat-donald-trump-in-2024-us-polls-report-6183175]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Report Reveals Why Barack Obama Hasn't Endorsed Kamala Harris In US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-doesnt-believe-kamala-harris-can-beat-donald-trump-in-2024-us-polls-report-6183175]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 09:15:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Many Democratic leaders have backed Kamala Harris as the party's new US Presidential candidate, but ex-president Barack Obama has held off so far.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many Democratic leaders have backed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-praises-kamala-harris-shes-experienced-shes-tough-shes-capable-6182671" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> as the party's new US Presidential candidate, but ex-president Barack Obama has held off so far.</p>

<p>According to the New York Post, Obama hasn't endorsed Harris - who US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-us-is-more-powerful-than-any-dictator-or-tyrant-6182537#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> supported after he dropped out of the race on Sunday, as he doesn't think she can beat Republican candidate <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-campaign-rally-donald-trump-calls-kamala-harris-a-radical-left-lunatic-6182225" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a>.</p>

<p>"Obama is very upset because he knows she can't win," a Biden family source told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/24/us-news/obama-doesnt-believe-kamala-harris-can-beat-trump-sources/" target="_blank">The New York Post</a>.</p>

<p>"Obama knows she's just incompetent - the border czar who never visited the border, saying that all migrants should have health insurance. She cannot navigate the landmines that are ahead of her," the source said. "When you are running for president there are things you can and can't say."</p>

<p>The source said that Obama's hope was to get Biden out of the way and an article written by actor <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-supporter-george-clooney-requests-him-to-leave-presidential-race-6077438" target="_blank">George Clooney</a>, asking him to step aside, was a part of that plan.</p>

<p>Obama wanted Arizona Senator Mark Kelly "at the top of the ticket" when the Democratic National Convention is held next month, the source told The New York Post.</p>

<p>"Obama is furious, things haven't gone his way, which is why he is not joining in the Democratic Party's support of Harris," the source added.</p>

<p>However, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/obama-plans-endorse-harris-president-soon-rcna163279" target="_blank">NBC News</a> reported on Thursday that Barack Obama plans to endorse Kamala Harris soon.</p>

<p>Obama privately has fully supported Harris' candidacy and has been in regular contact with her, the report said, citing people familiar with the discussions.</p>

<p>"Aides to Obama and Harris also have discussed arranging for the two of them to appear together on the campaign trail, though no date has been set," the report said.</p>

<h3><strong>Michelle Obama To Replace Joe Biden?</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier last month, before Joe Biden bowed out, US Senator Ted Cruz predicted that former First Lady <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michelle-obama-to-replace-joe-biden-us-senators-bold-prediction-5994892" target="_blank">Michelle Obama</a> would replace him.</p>

<p>His prediction came after Biden's presidential debate against Donald Trump, which was widely criticised by political analysts.</p>

<p>"The odds are north of 80% that the Democratic Party will remove Joe Biden from the ticket and replace him with Michelle Obama because Biden did so disastrously badly (in the debate) that Democrats across the country are in utter freefall and complete panic," he said.</p>

<p>Michelle Obama has so far not expressed any interest in joining the race to the White House.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/64kuvos8_kamala-harris-barack-obama_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama hasn't so far endorsed Kamala Harris]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-praises-joe-bidens-lifetime-of-service-following-oval-office-address-6183172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Obama Praises Biden's "Lifetime Of Service" Following Oval Office Address]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-praises-joe-bidens-lifetime-of-service-following-oval-office-address-6183172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 09:14:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Barack Obama commended President Joe Biden's dedication to the nation in light of Joe Biden's recent Oval Office address, marking a pivotal moment in American politics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Barack Obama commended President Joe Biden's dedication to the nation in light of Biden's recent Oval Office address, marking a pivotal moment in American politics.</p>

<p>Biden's first speech came since he announced his withdrawal from the 2024 election race and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the Democratic Party nominee for president.</p>

<p>"Joe Biden has stayed true to these words again and again over a lifetime of service to the American people," Obama remarked, reflecting on Biden's extensive career in public office.</p>

<p>The Oval Office address, traditionally reserved for moments of national significance or policy declarations, provided Biden with a platform to articulate his decision and rally support for Harris as the next leader of the country.</p>

<p>Returning to the White House after testing negative for COVID-19, Biden framed the upcoming election as a critical choice between progress and regression, hope and division. "I revere this office, but I love my country more," Biden affirmed, emphasising his commitment to defending democracy and the collective well-being of the American people.</p>

<p>In his address, Biden called upon Americans to unite and recognise their shared values, casting the election as pivotal in shaping the nation's trajectory for decades to come. He expressed optimism in the American spirit and underscored the importance of protecting democratic principles, urging unity over division.</p>

<p>While Biden did not directly mention former President Donald Trump, he contrasted his approach with Trump's contentious presidency, highlighting the imperative of safeguarding the integrity of democratic processes.</p>

<p>The upcoming US presidential election on November 5 will see Vice President Kamala Harris as the Democratic nominee, following Biden's endorsement. Harris, has garnered substantial support within the party and secured enough delegates for nomination, however, former US President Obama has not formally endorsed Harris.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5gmsqu1o_obamabiden_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama commended President Joe Biden's dedication to the nation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paris-olympics-2024-global-tensions-terror-threats-paris-olympics-to-be-held-amid-high-risk-6183100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Paris 2024 Will Be The Most High-Risk Olympics In History]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paris-olympics-2024-global-tensions-terror-threats-paris-olympics-to-be-held-amid-high-risk-6183100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 08:59:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Paris Olympic Games will be one of the most high-risk in history owing to a combination of internal strife within France and heightened global geopolitical tensions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Paris Olympic Games will be one of the most high-risk in history owing to a combination of internal strife within France and heightened global geopolitical tensions.</p>

<p>France is grappling with deep internal divisions: the country's volatile political climate and the potential for demonstrations or violence pose significant challenges for organisers.</p>

<p>The current global geopolitical landscape, marked by heightened tensions between major powers, further amplifies the security threats. These Olympics could serve as a potential target for state-sponsored actors seeking to exploit the event for their own agendas.</p>

<p>In response to these elevated threats, organisers are implementing unprecedented security measures, including deploying a record number of security personnel.</p>

<p>About 30,000 police, increasing to a record 45,000 at peak times, will work on the four-week Olympics and Paralympics across the Ile-de-France region covering Paris. They will be supplemented with police forces from across Europe to bolster security efforts.</p>

<p><strong>Islamist Terror</strong></p>

<p>A significant concern is the threat posed by Islamist terrorist networks.</p>

<p>Previous attacks on sporting and cultural events, combined with reports of foiled attempts by French authorities, underline this risk.</p>

<p>The escalation of the Israeli-Hamas conflict following the October 7, 2023, terror attack exacerbates this danger. Islamist terrorists may exploit the situation to position themselves as defenders of Palestinians and Muslims, targeting not just Israel but also Western countries that support Israel.</p>

<p>Daesh (ISIS) emerges as a primary suspect, especially since it operates as an umbrella network offering justification, inspiration and identity to lone actors and small cells operating in its name.</p>

<p>The possibility of Hamas conducting operations on European soil, as evidenced by arrests in Denmark and Germany, complicates the landscape.</p>

<p>Historically, Hamas has distanced itself from international Islamist terrorist networks such as Daesh and Al Qaeda, focusing on Israel. However, the dynamics have shifted post-October 7, with the conflict being framed as a broader Arab and Muslim cause against a morally corrupt West supporting Israel.</p>

<p>This alignment could potentially lead to cooperation between Hamas and Daesh.The Munich 1972 Olympics serve as a tragic reminder of the vulnerability of such events. The infiltration of the Olympic Village, the killing of Israeli athletes, and the taking of hostages by Black September highlight the dangers.</p>

<p>The anti-Semitic atmosphere in Europe, coupled with past rhetoric justifying attacks on Israelis, suggests Israeli athletes and fans could be at heightened risk during the Paris Games.</p>

<p><strong>Deadly Threats</strong></p>

<p>Hostage-taking, suicide bombings, and planted explosives are among the potential threats.</p>

<p>Although suicide bombings have become less common in Europe, they remain a possibility. The complexity of monitoring and gathering intelligence requires international cooperation to thwart such attacks.</p>

<p>The recent attacks by ISIS-affiliated militants in Moscow demonstrate the deadly potential of shooting sprees in crowded areas, while France's experience with knife and vehicle attacks adds another layer of concern.</p>

<p>The worst-case scenario involves multiple, simultaneous attacks across various locations, employing diverse methods and targets, extending beyond athletic venues to include churches and synagogues.</p>

<p><strong>What Motivates A Terrorist?</strong></p>

<p>The threat landscape is further complicated by the diverse pathways to radicalisation and the varied motivations that drive individuals to violence.</p>

<p>Extremists draw inspiration from a range of ideologies, and their motivations may be personal, social, or political. That's also because the Olympics provide an attractive high-profile platform for extremist groups and individuals seeking to carry out attacks.</p>

<p>Alt-right extremism is another significant threat. On July 17, French anti-terror police detained an alleged neo-Nazi sympathiser suspected of wanting to target the Olympic torch relay.</p>

<p><strong>Beyond Paris</strong></p>

<p>Social media plays a crucial role in amplifying extremist narratives and providing a platform for radicalisation.</p>

<p>The interconnectedness of the digital world means that even attacks far from Paris, such as at a public viewing event, could have a significant impact on the Games.</p>

<p>But security considerations extend beyond the immediate vicinity of Olympic venues, encompassing all media-related and public events associated with the games. The global reach of the Olympics means that any security breach, regardless of location, could have far-reaching consequences.</p>

<p>The spirit of the Olympics lies in peaceful competition, reminiscent of their ancient Greek origins. The 2024 Paris Olympics present a unique set of security challenges, requiring a comprehensive and multifaceted approach that addresses both internal and external threats.</p>

<p>International cooperation, intelligence gathering, and a thorough understanding of the evolving threat landscape are crucial for safeguarding athletes, spectators, and the public.</p>

<p>Marco Lombardi, director of ITSTIME research centre, is full professor at the Catholic University of Sacred Heart, where he teaches crisis management and risk communication, mass communication theory, sociology, intelligence and counter terrorism and security policies. He is member of the Governmental Commission on Counter Radicalisation and of the Strategic Policy Committee of the Italian Ministry of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation.</p>

<p>Maria Alvanou is a Criminologist (International Research Doctorate in Criminology-University of Trento) with the Italian Team for Security, Terroristic Issues &amp; Managing Emergencies (ITSTIME) at the Catholic University of Sacred Heart. Her doctoral research on Palestinian female suicide bombers during the second Intifada included fieldwork in Israel. She has been a member of the RAN and has taught at several law enforcement and military schools.</p>

<p><em>Originally published under Creative Commons by 360info.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g2v7ch6o_paris-riots_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 30,000 police will work on the Olympics over the next four weeks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-canada-intercept-china-russia-planes-near-alaska-air-defense-identification-zone-6183010]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US, Canada Intercept China, Russia Planes Near Alaska]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-canada-intercept-china-russia-planes-near-alaska-air-defense-identification-zone-6183010]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 08:35:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American and Canadian warplanes intercepted two Russian and two Chinese bombers in international airspace near the state of Alaska on Wednesday, the joint US-Canadian North American Aerospace Defense Command (NORAD) said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American and Canadian warplanes intercepted two Russian and two Chinese bombers in international airspace near the state of Alaska on Wednesday, the joint US-Canadian North American Aerospace Defense Command (NORAD) said.</p>

<p>"NORAD detected, tracked, and intercepted two Russian TU-95 and two PRC H-6 military aircraft operating in the Alaska Air Defense Identification Zone," it said.</p>

<p>The zone is a perimeter in which air traffic is monitored beyond the border of national airspace to provide additional reaction time in case of hostile actions.</p>

<p>Intercepts of Russian aircraft -- in which they are contacted visually or electronically by US or Canadian planes -- are relatively common in the area.</p>

<p>"Fighter jets from the United States and Canada conducted the intercept," NORAD said, adding that the bombers "remained in international airspace and did not enter American or Canadian sovereign airspace," and that their activity "is not seen as a threat."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rdrrqoso_us-air-force_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tatyana-ozolina-dubbed-russias-most-beautiful-biker-dies-in-motorbike-crash-in-turkey-6182895]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Russia's Most Beautiful Biker" Dies In Motorbike Crash In Turkey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tatyana-ozolina-dubbed-russias-most-beautiful-biker-dies-in-motorbike-crash-in-turkey-6182895]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 07:59:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A bike ride took a deadly turn for a 38-year-old Russian social media influencer in Turkey after she crashed into a truck while riding her red BMW motorcycle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A bike ride took a deadly turn for a 38-year-old Russian social media influencer in Turkey after she crashed into a truck while riding her red BMW motorcycle. According to Turkish media outlet <em>Turkiye Today</em>, Tatyana Ozolina, who goes by "MotoTanya" on social media, was travelling between Mugla and Bodrum when the fatal crash occurred. She lost control of her red BMW S1000RR 2015 and collided with a truck near Milas. Despite the immediate arrival of emergency services, Ms Ozolina was pronounced dead at the scene.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A Turkish biker accompanying her, Onur Obut, survived but suffered serious injuries and is in hospital. A third biker present at the scene was uninjured, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.turkiyetoday.com/lifestyle/russias-most-beautiful-biker-tatyana-dies-in-motorcycle-crash-in-turkiye-32287/">outlet </a>reported. The authorities are still investigating the circumstances surrounding the fatal accident that occurred.</p>

<p>Ms Ozolina, widely recognized as MotoTanya, was a popular Moto vlogger with over 1 million followers on Instagram and 2 million on YouTube. The influencer dubbed "Russia's most beautiful biker" is known for her global motorcycle adventures. In her last Instagram post, Ms Ozolina shared that she wasn't allowed to enter Europe.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"4000 km from home. Greece missed me but didn't miss my motorcycle. I was in Greece on foot. I bought a magnet and returned it to Turkey. I was upset that I didn't manage to ride around Europe, but not much because I knew that the situation could be like this... therefore, I moved on. Conquer beautiful, hot and hospitable Turkey," she wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9jxppvInIQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9jxppvInIQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9jxppvInIQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9jxppvInIQ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by #мотоТаня❤️?#motoTanya (@tanechkaozolina)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/29407600/influencer-russias-most-beautiful-biker-killed-horror-crash/amp/"><em>The Sun</em></a>, Ms Ozolina's bike was struck by another rider group, causing her to brake abruptly. She was unable to avoid a collision and ploughed into a truck, losing control and suffering fatal injuries. She died before the ambulance arrived. Her family including her son, 13, is "in a state of shock," the outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a tribute, Andrei Ivanov, head of the MotoMoscow Association, said, "MotoTanya is not with us anymore...she had a bright and beautiful life.... Millions of people followed her. Perhaps there is not a single motorcyclist in the country who was indifferent to Tatyana. She was adored, envied, admired, copied, awarded as a top blogger and, at the same time, discussed and slandered. Now all that remains is her memory. Sleep well."&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5hcpb2h_tatyana-ozolina_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The authorities are still investigating the accident.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-war-us-lawmaker-rashida-tlaib-hold-ups-war-criminal-sign-during-netanyahu-congress-speech-6182894]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Lawmaker Hold Ups "War Criminal" Sign During Netanyahu's Congress Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-war-us-lawmaker-rashida-tlaib-hold-ups-war-criminal-sign-during-netanyahu-congress-speech-6182894]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 07:58:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's address to a joint session of the US Congress on Wednesday sparked controversy and division among lawmakers and US citizens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's address to a joint session of the US Congress on Wednesday sparked controversy and division among lawmakers and US citizens. Representative Rashida Tlaib, the sole Palestinian-American member of Congress, held up a sign labeling Netanyahu a "war criminal" and "guilty of genocide" during his speech today.</p>

<p>Tlaib, a vocal critic of Israel's actions in Gaza, was joined by Hani Almadhoun, a Palestinian who has lost numerous family members in the conflict.</p>

<p>Tlaib was accompanied by an invited guest, Hani Almadhoun, a Palestinian who has lost more than 150 members of his extended family since Israel launched its war with the aim of destroying Hamas.</p>

<p>"After witnessing his sister forced to eat animal feed, he and his family were determined to start a soup kitchen to feed their starving neighbors,” Tlaib wrote in a post on X (formerly Twitter).</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I will never back down in speaking truth to power.<br />
<br />
The apartheid government of Israel is committing genocide against Palestinians. Palestinians will not be erased. Solidarity with all those outside of these walls in the streets protesting and exercising their right to dissent. <a href="https://t.co/TSbbXdv13U">pic.twitter.com/TSbbXdv13U</a></p>
— Rashida Tlaib (@RashidaTlaib) <a href="https://twitter.com/RashidaTlaib/status/1816200931848950184?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Outside the Capitol, thousands of protesters demonstrated against Netanyahu's visit, with some being kept back by police using pepper spray. Six protesters were arrested inside the House of Representatives before Netanyahu began speaking. While some lawmakers gave Netanyahu a standing ovation, others chose to stay away.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's US&nbsp; visit comes amid growing concerns over the humanitarian toll of Israel's nine-month ground invasion in Gaza, with Americans deeply divided on the issue. Netanyahu's speech highlighted the sharp divisions within the US Congress and the country at large on Israel's actions in the region.</p>

<p>In his address, Netanyahu said only military pressure can free the hostages and defeat Hamas, which launched a shock attack on October 7 that resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said he was "confident" in efforts to secure the release of the 114 hostages still in Gaza, where Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed at least 39,145 people, also mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>He also used his address to call for a global alliance against Iran, which he accuses of funding anti-Israel protests. He also slammed ceasefire demonstrators and praised President Joe Biden and former President Donald Trump for their efforts towards Middle East peace.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nbun3q38_rashida-tlaib_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-joe-bidens-speech-after-exiting-us-presidential-polls-barely-understandable-so-bad-6182893]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Donald Trump Said On Joe Biden's First Speech After Exiting US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-joe-bidens-speech-after-exiting-us-presidential-polls-barely-understandable-so-bad-6182893]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 25 Jul 2024 07:57:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden made his first televised address today since quitting the 2024 US presidential elections earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump today launched a scathing attack on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-us-is-more-powerful-than-any-dictator-or-tyrant-6182537#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> after the US President's first televised address since quitting the 2024 US presidential elections.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-campaign-rally-donald-trump-calls-kamala-harris-a-radical-left-lunatic-6182225#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Trump</a>, who recently survived an assassination attempt on July 13, said that Biden's speech was "barely understandable" and "so bad".</p>

<p>"Crooked Joe Biden's Oval Office speech was barely understandable, and sooo bad!" he posted on social media.</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/112844294440574656/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>In another post, he also called Biden and US Vice President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-praises-kamala-harris-shes-experienced-shes-tough-shes-capable-6182671" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a>, who is poised to be the new Democratic presidential nominee, a "great embarrassment to America".</p>

<p>"Crooked Joe Biden and lying Kamala Harris are a great embarrassment to America - there has never been a time like this," Trump said.</p>

<h3><strong>Joe Biden "Passes Torch To Next Generation"</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-rally-behind-kamala-harris-after-joe-biden-quits-presidential-race-6175715" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> today told Americans that he quit the 2024 US presidential election to unite the country, saying that it was time to pass the torch to "younger voices."</p>

<p>"I have decided the best way forward is to pass the torch to a new generation. That is the best way to unite our nation," the 81-year-old said in the 11-minute Oval Office speech.</p>

<p>"I revere this office. But I love my country more," he said.</p>

<p>"The defense of democracy, which is at stake, is more important than any title," Biden said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Join me as I deliver an address from the Oval Office. <a href="https://t.co/MPTTLv6nyn">https://t.co/MPTTLv6nyn</a></p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1816261097399410895?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In his address, he also praised his 59-year-old deputy Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>"She's experienced. She's tough. She's capable," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Joe Biden Bows Out</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-led-to-joe-bidens-sudden-exit-from-us-presidential-race-6168072" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> bowed out of the November 5 US election race on Sunday, giving in to weeks of pressure from his Democratic Party after a disastrous presidential debate performance against Donald Trump raised concerns about his age.</p>

<p>He is the first incumbent US president not to seek reelection since 1968 when Lyndon Johnson, under fire for his handling of the Vietnam War, abruptly pulled out of the campaign.</p>

<p>Biden has also joined James K Polk, James Buchanan, Rutherford B. Hayes, Calvin Coolidge, and Harry Truman as the US presidents who all decided not to stand for a second elected term.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cp4tp5lg_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's reaction came after Joe Biden made his first televised address since quitting the race]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>