<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 22:55:56 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-exit-shatters-irans-influence-but-risks-islamists-rise-in-syria-7210282]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Assad's Exit Shatters Iran's Influence But Risks Islamists' Rise In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-exit-shatters-irans-influence-but-risks-islamists-rise-in-syria-7210282]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 21:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ouster of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, after rebel forces swept into Damascus this weekend, shattered Iran's network of influence in the Middle East but Israel, the United States and Arab powers must now deal with the risk of instability.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ouster of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, after rebel forces swept into Damascus this weekend, shattered Iran's network of influence in the Middle East but Israel, the United States and Arab powers must now deal with the risk of instability and extremism from the mosaic of forces that replaces him.</p>

<p>Chief among the rebel forces that ended 50 years of brutal dynastic rule by Assad and his father was Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), a Sunni Muslim group previously affiliated with Al Qaeda that is designated as a terrorist organization by the US and the UN.</p>

<p>Western and Arab nations fear that the HTS-led rebel coalition may seek to replace Assad's regime with a hardline Islamist government, or one less able or inclined to prevent the resurgence of radical forces, three diplomats and three analysts told Reuters.</p>

<p>"There is strong fear inside and outside the region of the power vacuum that Assad's sudden collapse may cause," said Abdelaziz al-Sager, director of the Gulf Research Center, a think tank focused on the Middle East. He cited the civil wars that followed the toppling of Iraqi president Saddam Hussein in 2003 and Libyan dictator Muammar Gaddafi in 2011.</p>

<p>One senior Western diplomat in the region, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told Reuters that - with the rebel forces fragmented - there was no plan for how to rule Syria, a complex nation divided into various sects and ethnic groups, each with its own regional power base.</p>

<p>The senior diplomat expressed fears that lawlessness in Syria could allow the flourishing of extremist groups like Islamic State (IS), which in 2014 swept through large swathes of Syria and Iraq and established an Islamic Caliphate before it was driven out by a US-led coalition by 2019.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden on Sunday welcomed Assad's toppling and said he should be "held accountable" for his despotic rule but he warned that his departure was a moment of "risk and uncertainty". US forces on Sunday conducted dozens of strikes within Syria against IS to prevent it reasserting itself.</p>

<p>The speed of Assad's ouster, just two weeks since the rebel offensive began, took many in the White House by surprise. A senior US official said Washington was now seeking ways to communicate with all the rebel groups, not just HTS.</p>

<p>So far, Washington had mostly thrown its support behind Syrian Kurdish groups, such as the Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), whose areas of control are in northeast Syria. These groups, however, are in conflict with one of the main victorious rebels factions, the Syrian National Army (SNA), backed by regional power broker, Turkey, which opposes Kurdish influence.</p>

<p>Assad's allies, Tehran and Moscow, who propped up his rule for 13 years with military support, men and airpower, also face far-reaching implications from his precipitous downfall.</p>

<p>Moscow - which has given Assad and his family asylum - has two major military bases in Syria, its main footprint in the Middle East. Its naval base in Tartous on the Mediterranean has been a staging post to fly military contractors in and out of Africa.</p>

<p>For Tehran, its alliance with Assad - a member of the minority Alawite sect, an offshoot of Shi'ite Islam - was a cornerstone of its powerbase in a predominantly Sunni region wary of Shi'ite Iran.</p>

<p>Assad's departure shattered a pivotal axis of influence, eroding Tehran's ability to project power and sustain its network of militia groups across the Middle East, particularly to its ally Hezbollah in Lebanon. A senior Iranian official told Reuters on Monday it had opened a direct line of communication with the rebels in an attempt to "prevent a hostile trajectory".</p>

<p>Israel's year-long military campaign has already severely weakened the military power of Hezbollah and Palestinian group Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>Assad offered Iran a vital conduit for arms shipments to rebuild Hezbollah. Jonathan Panikoff, a former US deputy national intelligence officer for the Middle East, said his ouster could make it more difficult for Hezbollah to rearm, increasing the prospects that a ceasefire with Israel agreed last month would hold.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu hailed the ousting of Assad as an "historic day" that followed the blows delivered by Israel against Iran and Hezbollah. He said he had ordered Israeli forces to seize areas along the bordering buffer zone to ensure Israel's security.</p>

<p>Israeli forces carried out air strikes against suspected chemical weapons and missile sites on Monday to prevent them from falling into the hands of hostile actors, the foreign minister said.</p>

<p>Carmit Valensi, a senior researcher at the Institute for National Security Studies (INSS), a think tank for Israeli security policy based in Tel Aviv, said that - despite the risk of a prolonged period of chaos and violence in Syria - Assad's fall could benefit Israel.</p>

<p>"Despite concerns over the rise of extremist elements near the border and the lack of a clear authority in charge, the military capabilities of the rebels, in their various forms, aren't comparable to those of Iran and its proxies," she said.</p>

<p>CALLS FOR NEW CONSTITUTION, ELECTIONS</p>

<p>Marwan al-Muasher, vice president for studies at the US-based Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, said Assad's exit could provide an opportunity for Syrians to establish an inclusive political governance through an orderly transition that avoided a power vacuum that would allow extremist groups to gain ascendancy.</p>

<p>Hadi Al-Bahra, the head of Syria's main opposition abroad, told Reuters on the sidelines of the Doha Forum on Sunday that Syria should have an 18-month transition period to establish "a safe, neutral, and quiet environment" for free elections.</p>

<p>Al-Bahra, President of the Syrian National Coalition, said Syria should draft a constitution within six months, on which the first election would be a referendum. He said the opposition had asked state employees to report to work until the power transition, and assured them that they would not be harmed.</p>

<p>But Syria's political opposition has little influence on the ground in Damascus, where armed groups hold sway, and many Syria watchers remain skeptic.</p>

<p>HTS' leader, Abu Mohammed al-Golani, addressed huge crowds at the medieval Umayyad Mosque in central Damascus on Sunday, promising a new chapter for the region and that Syria would become "a beacon for the Islamic nation".</p>

<p>There are, however, questions about whether Golani's form of strict Islamist ideology would be accepted throughout Syria, a country where a moderate and liberal form of Islam prevails and with a mixed Christian, Alawite, Druze and Kurdish population.</p>

<p>Both Western and Middle Eastern officials expressed concern about the unity of Syria, with key territories, including those along borders with Iraq and Turkey, under the control of different sects and ethnic groups: these divisions, which were entrenched by a bloody 2011 uprising, present a growing threat to national stability.</p>

<p>The analysts and diplomats who spoke to Reuters warned of the risk of a free-for-all conflict - akin to the wake of the toppling of Gaddafi in Libya or Saddam in Iraq - in which armed groups from different Islamist, ethnic and ideological shades fight for supremacy over territory. Such a failed state in Syria would have a major impact on neighbors Lebanon, Turkey, Iraq and Jordan, they said.</p>

<p>RIVALRY AMONG REBELS</p>

<p>Syria's opposition comprises a broad spectrum from moderate groups such as the SNA to jihadi elements within the HTS, each with its own vision for Syria's future, ranging from secular democracy to Islamic governance.</p>

<p>"Each one of these rebel group is vying for supremacy; each one wants to be in charge. Each one thinks they can be Bashar al-Assad, and each one has allegiance to a foreign party funding his group," said al-Sager. "They will clash unless there is an effort by the UN and some regional countries with influence to unify them."</p>

<p>Turkish-backed forces dominate in the north, while US-aligned Kurdish groups, such as the Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), hold sway in northeastern Syria.</p>

<p>In a sign of the tensions between the groups, the Turkey-backed SNA seized swathes of territory, including the city of Tel Refaat, from US-backed Kurdish forces at the start of the recent offensive. On Sunday, a Turkish security source said the rebels entered the northern city of Manbij after pushing the Kurds back again.</p>

<p>Still, some analysts say that an orderly transition is possible, arguing that well-established government institutions in Damascus remain capable of carrying out duties.</p>

<p>They also point to the rebels' experience of governing in enclaves across Syria that they have managed in some cases for more than a decade. The rebel alliance, led by HTS, made a point of offering clemency for members of the security forces when it seized Aleppo, Syria's second-largest city, late last month and promised the sizeable minority populations that it would preserve their way of life.</p>

<p>But Hassan Hassan, an expert on Islamist groups in the Middle East based in Washington, said that concerns persisted among these minority groups now that the rebels had captured Damascus.</p>

<p>"There is uncertainty about what will happen next, particularly about religious influence and how (Islamic) laws may evolve," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hnlpk09g_bashar-al-assad_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Western and Arab nations fear that the HTS-led rebel coalition may seek to replace Assad's regime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fall-of-assad-breaks-key-link-in-irans-axis-of-resistance-7209638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fall Of Assad Breaks Key Link In Iran's "Axis Of Resistance"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fall-of-assad-breaks-key-link-in-irans-axis-of-resistance-7209638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 20:23:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fall of Syrian leader Bashar al-Assad shattered the key link in Iran's "axis of resistance", but Tehran will look for ways to adapt to the new reality, analysts say.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fall of Syrian leader Bashar al-Assad shattered the key link in Iran's "axis of resistance", but Tehran will look for ways to adapt to the new reality, analysts say.</p>

<p>After nearly 14 years of war in Syria, a lightning offensive launched by an Islamist-led rebel alliance brought Assad down.</p>

<p>The offensive began on November 27, just as a ceasefire took effect in the war between Iran's powerful proxy Hezbollah and Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had long used Syria as its key conduit for weapons and supplies from Iran.</p>

<p>With Assad gone, it is to be seen how Hezbollah will adapt, particularly after the staggering losses it suffered in its own recent war.</p>

<p><strong>'Frontline of resistance'</strong></p>

<p>In the past, Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who has the final say in his country's affairs, has said that "Syria is on the frontline of the resistance against Israel".</p>

<p>The axis of resistance, to use Tehran's term, comprises Iran itself and a smattering of proxy forces united by their opposition to Israel, including Lebanon's Hezbollah, Palestinian operator group Hamas and Yemen's Huthi rebels, as well as smaller groups in Iraq.</p>

<p>Until Sunday, Assad's government was a key component of the axis, and he would likely not have survived for as long as he did had it not been for Hezbollah and Iran's military backing.</p>

<p>But the fall of Assad on Sunday was a major blow to the loose alliance, and the latest in a string of setbacks for Iran in its fight against Israel.</p>

<p>In recent months Israel has killed Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar in Gaza and Hezbollah's secretary general Hassan Nasrallah in Lebanon, and decimated both groups' mid-level leadership.</p>

<p>Iran also blames Israel for the killing of former Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh in an attack in Tehran in July.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Islamic republic has lost hundreds of its Revolutionary Guards in Syria over more than a decade of the country's civil war, including in Israeli air strikes.</p>

<p><strong>'Destabilise'</strong></p>

<p>Within Iran, some believe the Syrian rebels' goal was to sever the link between Tehran and its allies.</p>

<p>With its influence now threatened in Syria, Iran "will no longer be able to support Hezbollah as it did before", Mehdi Zakerian, an expert on international relations in Tehran, told AFP.</p>

<p>In Tehran's official narrative, the revolt against Assad's rule was an American-Israeli plot to "destabilise" the Middle East and redraw its political map.</p>

<p>Syria's civil war was sparked by a crackdown on democracy protests inspired by the Arab Spring.</p>

<p>Iran sent to Syria what it presented as "military advisers" to support Assad's army, at his request.</p>

<p>Shiite Muslim militias close to Iran also deployed, allowing Tehran to gain influence in Syria, which borders not only Lebanon but also Israel.</p>

<p>After the fall of Damascus on Sunday, the Iranian embassy was ransacked, an act that would have been previously unimaginable.</p>

<p><strong>'He did not pay attention'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>And while Iran was a key backer of Assad, some official critiques of the former leader were emerging after his downfall.</p>

<p>"Bashar was an opportunity for Iran, but he did not pay enough attention to the recommendations of the Islamic Republic," Iranian news agency Fars said.</p>

<p>Following the rebels' declaration of victory, Iran's foreign ministry said its policy towards any new Syrian government would depend on "developments in Syria and the region, as well as the behaviour of the actors".</p>

<p>But the statement also said Iran expected to continue "friendly" relations with the country.</p>

<p>On Saturday, as rebels were swiftly advancing towards Damascus, Tehran had called on all sides in the conflict to engage in negotiations.</p>

<p>That statement by Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi was significant, not least because of its timing, and appeared to mark a change in tone.</p>

<p>Iran had long branded any form of opposition in Syria as "terrorism".</p>

<p>On Sunday, with that opposition now seemingly in charge, Araghchi said: "Syria played an important role in supporting the resistance, but it is not the case that the resistance will stop without Syria."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/o44h6kc8_bashar-al-assad_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran had long branded any form of opposition in Syria as "terrorism". (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-woman-stays-calm-without-phone-for-8-hours-in-unique-contest-wins-1-400-7209320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Unique Contest, China Woman Wins $1,400 For Ditching Phone For 8 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-woman-stays-calm-without-phone-for-8-hours-in-unique-contest-wins-1-400-7209320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:41:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The challenge was designed to highlight the growing dependence on technology and encourage people to embrace mindfulness and digital detox practices.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese woman,&nbsp;surnamed Dong, has made headlines for winning a unique competition where she abstained from using her mobile phone for eight hours without showing signs of anxiety.&nbsp;Dong, a sales manager at a finance firm, emerged victorious among ten contestants, taking home a prize of 10,000 yuan (approximately Rs 1,16,820),<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3289134/chinese-woman-wins-us1400-not-feeling-anxious-without-mobile-8-hours"> South China Morning Post </a></em>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The competition, sponsored by an undisclosed organization in Chongqing, southwestern China, required participants to surrender their electronic devices and adhere to strict rules while spending eight hours on a designated bed. The challenge was designed to highlight the growing dependence on technology and encourage people to embrace mindfulness and digital detox practices.</p>

<p>Contestants were allowed to leave their beds only for brief toilet breaks, limited to five minutes each. A quota was set for the total time spent away from their beds during the eight hours.&nbsp;Meals and drinks were provided, but participants had to consume them in bed. The rules also prohibited contestants from using their mobile phones, falling into a deep sleep, or exhibiting anxiety. To monitor their sleep quality and anxiety levels, contestants wore wrist straps throughout the competition. To pass the time, contestants were allowed to read books or rest with their eyes closed.</p>

<p>Dong reportedly managed this feat with ease, stating that she is accustomed to minimal phone usage in her daily life. She scored an impressive 88.99 out of 100, earning her a 10,000-yuan prize.&nbsp;Dong's strategy of wearing pyjamas and focusing on relaxation paid off, earning her the nickname "pyjama sister" on social media. Her everyday habits, which include tutoring her child instead of mindlessly browsing her phone, also contributed to her success.</p>

<p>The competition sparked widespread interest on Chinese social media, with many users expressing curiosity and amusement. One user wrote, "I want to join the competition. It seems so interesting and not challenging at all."</p>

<p>Another commented, "My grandma could win the top prize."</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/t0svc2m_china-woman_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[She scored an impressive 88.99 out of 100, earning her a 10,000-yuan prize]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-looking-back-at-2024-remembering-those-who-left-us-7209211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Pics: Looking Back At 2024 - Remembering Those Who Left Us]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-looking-back-at-2024-remembering-those-who-left-us-7209211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:29:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As we bid farewell to 2024 and recount the glories of the season, we remember there were tears too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we bid farewell to 2024 and recount the glories of the season, we remember there were tears too. The year was filled with wars and revolutions, trends and tragedies, with the world saying goodbye to some notable figures, including Russian President Vladimir Putin's staunchest critic Alexei Navalny, former One Direction member Liam Payne, famed producer Quincy Jones and industrialist Ratan Tata.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are some of the most famous people who have died in 2024.</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Glynis Johns | 5 October 1923 - 4 January 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: IMDB)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p45ear3o_glynis-johns-imdb_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: IMDB)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: IMDB)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A Tony Award-winning stage and screen star, Johns passed away at the age of 100. She is best remembered for playing the mother opposite Julie Andrews in the classic movie "Mary Poppins". She also introduced the world to the bittersweet standard-to-be "Send in the Clowns" by Stephen Sondheim.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Alexei Navalny | 4 June 1976 - 6 February 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@navalny)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/iuic3hp8_alexei-navalny-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: X/@navalny)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@navalny)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>One of the fiercest critics of Russian President Vladimir Putin, Navalny passed away in the Arctic penal colony where he was serving a 19-year sentence, Russia's prison agency said. He was 47. Before his arrest, Navalny campaigned against official corruption, organized major anti-Kremlin protests and ran for public office.</p>

<h3><strong>Jacob Rothschild | 29 April 1936 - 26 February 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Partners Capital website)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/a1a1a4p_jacob-rothschild-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: Partners Capital website)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Partners Capital website)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A financier and philanthropist, Rothschild passed away at the age of 87. He was part of the renowned Rothschild banking dynasty and began his career in the family bank, NM Rothschild &amp; Sons, in 1963. He later broke away to start businesses and charitable organizations.&nbsp;Rothschild was Chairman of RIT Capital Partners plc, one of the largest investment trusts quoted on the London Stock Exchange with a net asset value of about £2 billion. He played a prominent part in Arts philanthropy in Britain and was Chairman of Trustees of the National Gallery from 1985 to 1991, and from 1992 to 1998, chairman of the National Heritage Memorial Fund.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Peter Higgs | 29 May 1929 - 8 April 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@NobelPrize)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vf2geo8o_peter-higgs-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: X/@NobelPrize)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@NobelPrize)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>Nobel prize-winning physicist Peter Higgs died at age 94. Higgs is credited for proposing the existence of the so-called “God particle” that helped explain how matter formed after the Big Bang.&nbsp;Higgs predicted the existence of a new particle in 1964, which later came to be known as the Higgs boson. The physicist's work helped scientists in getting a better understanding of one of the most fundamental riddles of the universe: how the Big Bang created something out of nothing 13.8 billion years ago.</p>

<h3><strong>OJ Simpson | 9 July 1947 - 10 April 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: AFP)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/e9q1n84_oj-simpsons-afp_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: AFP)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: AFP)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A decorated football superstar and Hollywood actor, Simpson died aged 76. &nbsp;Simpson found fame and fortune through football and show business, but his legacy was forever changed by the June 1994 knife slayings of his ex-wife, Nicole Brown Simpson, and her friend Ronald Goldman in Los Angeles. His public trial captured America's attention and sparked debates on race, gender, domestic abuse, celebrity justice and police misconduct. &nbsp;He was acquitted in the murder case in 1995, but a separate civil trial jury found him liable in 1997 for the deaths and ordered him to pay $33.5 million to relatives of Brown and Goldman.</p>

<h3><strong>Ebrahim Raisi | 14 December 1960 - 19 May 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@raisi_com)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/08ritu8_ebrahim-raisi-_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: X/@raisi_com)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@raisi_com)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The Iranian president Raisi, a hard-line protege of the country's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Raisi died in a Helicopter crash aged 63. Raisi helped oversee the mass executions of thousands in Iran in 1988 and later led the country as it enriched uranium near weapons-grade levels, launched a major attack on Israel and experienced mass protests.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Maggie Smith | 28 December 1934 - 27 September 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Reuters)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ljvacj8g_maggie-smith-reuters_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: Reuters)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Reuters)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The masterful, scene-stealing actor, Smith won an Oscar for the 1969 film “The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie”. She gained new fans in the 21st century with her roles of dowager Countess of Grantham in "Downton Abbey" and Professor Minerva McGonagall in the Harry Potter films. Smith was often rated the preeminent British female performer of a generation along with Vanessa Redgrave and Judi Dench. The two-time Oscar winner died aged 89.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Quincy Jones | 14 March 1933 - &nbsp;3 November 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@DiscussingFilm)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ja7ck3a8_james-earl-jones-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="(Source: X/@DiscussingFilm)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@QuincyDJones)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>A multi-talented music titan, Jones' vast legacy ranged from producing Michael Jackson's historic "Thriller" album to writing prize-winning film and television scores. He collaborated with icons Frank Sinatra, and Ray Charles among hundreds of other recording artists to make chart-breaking music and earn honours and awards that fill 18 pages in his 2001 autobiography “Q". The 28-time Grammy winner and twice Academy Award awardee passed away aged 91.</p>

<h3><strong>Ratan Tata | 28 December 1937 - 9 October 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Tata.com)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/496pl1c_ratan-tata-tatacom_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: Tata.com)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Tata.com)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>One of India's most influential business leaders, Ratan Tata passed away aged 86. He joined the Tata Group in 1961 and succeeded his uncle J.R.D. Tata as chairman after the latter's retirement in 1991. Under his leadership, the company grew significantly to a sprawling collection of nearly 100 companies and expanded globally with revenue exceeding $100 billion on his retirement.</p>

<h3><strong>Liam Payne | 29 August 1993 - 16 October 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: X/@LiamPayne)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6kse7kd8_liam-payne-twitter_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: X/@LiamPayne)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: X/@LiamPayne)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>The former One Direction singer whose chart-topping British boy band generated a global following of swooning fans, died aged 31 after falling from a hotel balcony in Argentina.</p>

<h3><strong>Rohit Bal | 8 May 1961 - 1 November 2024</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Source: Rohit Bal  Facebook)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/v2fom42g_rohit-bal-facebook_625x300_09_December_24.jpg" title="(Source: Rohit Bal  Facebook)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em><small>(Source: Rohit Bal Facebook)</small></em></p>
</div>

<p>One of India's most celebrated fashion designers, Bal died aged 63 after a long period of illness. He popularised fashion designing as a viable, glamorous profession in the 1990s and many who came after him credit him for their success.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/lj2eud8g_year-ender-2024_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Peter Higgs , Liam Payne and Ebrahim Raisi died in 2024]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-voted-for-people-south-korean-mp-defies-party-to-impeach-president-7209125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Voted For People": South Korean MP Defies Party To Impeach President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-voted-for-people-south-korean-mp-defies-party-to-impeach-president-7209125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:14:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As South Korean lawmakers tried to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol for declaring martial law, ruling party MPs marched out of the chamber to thwart the effort -- except for Ahn Cheol-soo.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As South Korean lawmakers tried to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol for declaring martial law, ruling party MPs marched out of the chamber to thwart the effort -- except for Ahn Cheol-soo.</p>

<p>Ahn -- a self-made multi-millionaire, trained doctor and software designer -- sat alone in his party's bank of chairs in the National Assembly debating hall, one of just two members of the ruling People Power Party to vote to remove Yoon from office.</p>

<p>Despite tens of thousands of protesters outside, demanding the leader be removed after he sent soldiers in helicopters to parliament in a bid to overturn civilian rule, the impeachment motion failed by not meeting the quorum.</p>

<p>Days earlier, lawmakers from both parties had come together, jumping fences, barricading doors with office furniture, and battling special forces troops as they raced to vote down the martial law declaration.</p>

<p>But then the ruling party closed ranks -- saying Yoon had promised to resign and hand power to the prime minister and party chief, in what the opposition has called an unconstitutional power grab and "second coup".</p>

<p>Ahn said he was booed and heckled at a party meeting, when he tried to argue with other lawmakers that the president needed to be held to account.</p>

<p>"The idea that a president responsible for upholding the constitution of the world's 10th largest economy would stage an unconstitutional coup is beyond imagination," Ahn told AFP on Monday in his parliamentary office overlooking the National Assembly.</p>

<p>"Who could have foreseen he would commit such an unconstitutional act as president?"</p>

<p>Always unpopular, Yoon's approval rating has hit a record low of just 11 percent, a Gallup poll showed Monday, and further mass protests are expected this coming weekend, when the opposition will try again to impeach.</p>

<p>A "sense of duty" to uphold the constitutional order weighed heavily on him as he thought about how he should vote, Ahn told AFP.</p>

<p>"I have always believed that my role in politics is to represent the people's will, not my own personal interests. That is why I stayed to cast my vote."</p>

<p>"I didn't vote for the opposition party. I voted for the people"</p>

<p><strong>Presidential candidate&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Ahn himself had ambitions to be president: he ran in 2022, but dropped out and supported Yoon just a week before the election, with his support proving crucial in the neck-and-neck poll, which Yoon won by the narrowest margin in South Korean history.</p>

<p>His party merged with the PPP, but Ahn now finds himself at odds with his parliamentary colleagues, who are officially calling for an "orderly exit" for Yoon -- but in reality, experts say, trying to buy time ahead of an election they're likely to lose.</p>

<p>The PPP blocked impeachment, saying that Yoon had agreed to step down at some unspecified point in the future, with the country to be run by the prime minister and party chief in the interim.</p>

<p>But Ahn insists this is insufficient.</p>

<p>"I had expected Yoon to announce when and how he would resign and to detail plans for the formation of a joint governing body with ruling and opposition parties," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"Instead, he handed everything over to the ruling party," he said.</p>

<p>Without a clear roadmap from either the president or his party, "I concluded I had no choice but to support impeachment."</p>

<p>Ahn said he would vote for impeachment again.</p>

<p>"According to the constitution, each MP is a constitutional agent. Voting according to one's conscience, even if it goes against the party's official stance, takes precedence."</p>

<p>Yoon has lost the confidence of not only the South Korean public but also international allies, leaving him "incapable of continuing his duties as president," Ahn said.</p>

<p>"He must personally explain when and how he intends to resign."</p>

<p><strong>Household name&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Ahn is a household name in South Korea and was widely known even before entering politics in 2012 with his first presidential bid.</p>

<p>As a medical student in the 1980s, he wrote a programme to remove a virus from his computer and went on to pursue parallel careers as a software developer, doctor, and professor.</p>

<p>In 1995, he founded AhnLab, now the largest antivirus software company in South Korea, with a market capitalisation of nearly $635 million.</p>

<p>He has run as a presidential candidate multiple times, but it was his bid in 2022 that has proved most impactful.</p>

<p>Six days before the election, he endorsed Yoon -- a move analysts described as crucial to Yoon's razor-thin victory margin of less than one percentage point.</p>

<p>If he had known then what he knows now, Ahn said, he would not have done it.</p>

<p>"Not just me -- others would also have been unable to vote for him if we had known this information."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rgk9ntn_south-korea-mp_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A "sense of duty" to uphold the constitutional order weighed heavily, Ahn told AFP. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-the-mastermind-behind-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasina-7209051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus The "Mastermind" Behind Bangladesh Turmoil: Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-the-mastermind-behind-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasina-7209051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:04:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's former PM Sheikh Hasina has launched a fierce attack on the interim administration, accusing its Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus of running a "fascist regime" that allows terrorists and fundamentalists to act without restraint.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's former PM Sheikh Hasina has launched a fierce attack on the interim administration, accusing its Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus of running a "fascist regime" that allows terrorists and fundamentalists to act without restraint.</p>

<p>In a virtual address to a gathering of overseas Awami League supporters in London on Sunday, Ms Hasina accused Mr Yunus of being the "mastermind" behind the July-August turmoil that ousted her government and vowed to bring him and his allies to justice under Bangladeshi law.</p>

<p>She criticised Mr Yunus and his interim government for their alleged persecution of religious minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Since August 5, the attacks on minorities, places of worship of Hindus, Christians and Buddhists have been rampant. We condemn it. The Jamaat and terrorists are having a free run under the new regime," she said.</p>

<p>The audio recording of Hasina's address was shared on the Facebook page of the Bangladesh Students' League and Bangladesh Awami League.</p>

<p>Her remarks came as Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri is visiting to Dhaka today where he raised India's concerns over the safety of minorities, flagging "regrettable incidents of attacks on cultural, religious and diplomatic properties" in the country.</p>

<p>There have been a spate of incidents of violence against Hindus and other minorities, as well as attacks on temples in Bangladesh in the last few weeks that triggered strong concerns in New Delhi.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh is now under the grip of a fascist regime where people's democratic rights have been obliterated. Our government's achievements in poverty alleviation and infrastructure development, strengthening of democracy were being undone under Yunus's leadership," Ms Hasina said during her 37-minute virtual address over the phone.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina accused the Yunus government of providing clemency to terrorists and criminals, including those involved in arson and murders.</p>

<p>"The release of convicted criminals and terrorists, including those responsible for attacks on the Bangladesh Parliament and other atrocities, proves the complicity of this government," she alleged.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina vowed that those responsible for the alleged atrocities under the Yunus administration would be brought to justice.</p>

<p>"Md Yunus and his allies are the masterminds of the July-August unrest in the country. They are behind the killing of students and policemen, arson and atrocities. The murderers and conspirators who have harmed our nation will be held accountable under Bangladeshi law. Just as we took action against war criminals, justice will prevail for today's wrongdoers. No one will escape the law," she said.</p>

<p>On August 5, the student-led Monsoon Revolution under the banner of "Students Against Discrimination" succeeded in toppling Sheikh Hasina's 16-year regime, propelled by fervent demands for change and accountability.</p>

<p>After unprecedented anti-government protests, Ms Hasina resigned as Prime Minister and fled the country. She landed in India on August 5 and is currently staying here.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina criticised Mr Yunus and his government for their alleged persecution of religious minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Since August 5, the attacks on minorities, places of worship of Hindus, Christians and Buddhists have been rampant. We condemn it. The Jamaat and terrorists are having a free run under the new regime," she said.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina expressed outrage over the judicial and administrative repression under the current government, citing the case of Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das as an example.</p>

<p>"Chinmoy Krishna Das' lawyer was barred from contesting his case, a blatant violation of legal rights. This government is using every tool to suppress dissent and deny justice," she said.</p>

<p>Chinmay Krishna Das, a prominent spokesperson for Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote, was arrested at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday while en route to Chattogram for a rally. He was denied bail and remanded to jail on Tuesday. His arrest has further fueled concerns over the treatment of Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Condemning the ongoing oppression, Hasina declared, "This dark chapter of our nation's history will not last forever. Mohammed Yunus will be held accountable for his actions, and justice will prevail." Hasina further alleged that people are being subjected to brutal violence.</p>

<p>"Innocent people have been beaten to death under this fascist regime. The rule of law has been completely eroded," she said, calling for accountability and justice.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina claimed that the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has ignored allegations of financial irregularities involving Mr Yunus and his organization, Grameen Bank.</p>

<p>"They accuse my government of corruption but fail to provide evidence. Meanwhile, Yunus's activities remain unchecked by the ACC," she said, reiterating her challenge for the interim government to substantiate its allegations against her.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina claimed that since August, more than a thousand leaders and workers of the Awami League have been killed, their homes looted, and their businesses destroyed.</p>

<p>She claimed that members of her party were being systematically targeted and that these incidents were part of a broader conspiracy to eliminate the Awami League's influence.</p>

<p>"All units of the Awami League have been subjected to attacks. The homes and businesses of our leaders have been looted. Those who are reporting these atrocities face severe consequences under the current regime," she stated.</p>

<p>While concluding her virtual address, Ms Hasina expressed hope for a brighter future, assuring the people that "a new dawn will soon break, dispelling the darkness that has engulfed our country."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r5j153uk_sheikh-hasina-ians_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina slammed Muhammad Yunus's regime as "fascist", vows justice for atrocities]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-struck-chemical-weapons-in-syria-says-foreign-minister-7209002]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Struck "Chemical Weapons" In Syria, Says Foreign Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-struck-chemical-weapons-in-syria-says-foreign-minister-7209002]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:00:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar said Monday that his country had struck "chemical weapons" in neighbouring Syria, where rebel forces ousted president Bashar al-Assad over the weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar said Monday that his country had struck "chemical weapons" in neighbouring Syria, where rebel forces ousted president Bashar al-Assad over the weekend.</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference, Saar said "we attacked strategic weapon systems like, for example, remaining chemical weapons or long-range missiles and rockets in order that they will not fall in the hands of extremists".</p>

<p>Saar said Israel was monitoring the actions of the rebels, adding: "The steps we took, the only interest we have is the security of Israel and its citizens."</p>

<p>Israeli media reported on Friday that the military had struck a chemical weapons cache in Syria.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a Britain-based monitor, said on Monday the Israeli military conducted overnight strikes on multiple locations spanning coastal and southern Syria.</p>

<p>"Since the initial hours after the announcement of the fall of the former regime, Israel began launching intensive air strikes, deliberately destroying weapons and ammunitions depots," it said.</p>

<p>AFP photos on Monday showed damage at Mazzeh military airport on the outskirts of Damascus, including destroyed helicopters and jets, where the Israeli military struck nearby weapons depots.</p>

<p>Since Syria's civil war erupted in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes in the country, mainly targeting the army and Iran-backed groups.</p>

<p>Israel rarely comments on individual strikes in Syria but has repeatedly said it will not allow Iran to expand its presence in the country.</p>

<p>The country also moved troops into a demilitarised buffer zone in the Golan Heights region bordering Syria on Saturday.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel would "not allow any hostile force to establish itself on our border".</p>

<p>Saar said Monday that the takeover of the buffer was "a limited and temporary step we took for security reasons".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rooujejg_israel-strike-golan-heights-afp-_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since Syria's civil war erupted in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes in the country.(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/france-to-germany-to-belgium-the-eu-is-withering-away-7208998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: France To Germany To Belgium, EU Is Imploding]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/france-to-germany-to-belgium-the-eu-is-withering-away-7208998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:59:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The greatest threat to the EU doesn't come from Moscow or Beijing, but from within. Populist and nationalist movements are on the rise, fuelled by a toxic blend of economic anxiety, cultural insecurity, and distrust of Brussels.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-06/british-with-eu-flag-reuters_650x400_51466763676.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>France is without a government or an annual budget. Germany, the supposed anchor of European stability, is being run by a caretaker administration. Poland, meanwhile, has temporarily suspended the right to asylum, a cornerstone of European values, in a "bold new migration strategy" that looks more like a move that undermines the European Union ideals. Russia is firmly in the driver's seat in the Ukraine war. And as if that wasn't enough, the EU is staring down the barrel of a new American presidency—one that promises to hike import tariffs and bully Europe's NATO allies into coughing up more cash.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These aren't just random hiccups. France, Germany and Poland—the EU's big boys—are all in turmoil. Indeed when the pillars of a structure start to crack, how long can the roof hold up?&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Union In Crisis</strong></h2>

<p>The European Union, built on the lofty ideals of democracy, human rights and freedom of speech, now finds itself teetering on the edge of an existential crisis. The irony is as rich as it is tragic: a union founded on unity is fracturing under the weight of its contradictions.</p>

<p>Let's start with the obvious. Britain exited the Union, but it's not alone. In France, Marine Le Pen lurks menacingly in the political shadows, her far-right populism offering voters a seductive, anti-EU narrative. In Italy, Matteo Salvini champions a similar brand of nationalist fervour, while in Germany, the far-right AfD party is no longer a fringe player but a rising force to be reckoned with. The EU isn't just rotting from outside—it is under siege from within.</p>

<h2><strong>When Europhiles Play The Populist Card</strong></h2>

<p>Poland's Prime Minister, Donald Tusk, is a known Europhile. But it was shocking for many in the EU that he suspended the right to asylum in his country, putting aside the bloc's own principles. Tusk was a man who spent years championing European values, and now he undermines one of their cornerstones, all to save his own skin. Cynically, he justified his decision by saying that Russia and Belarus were diverting asylum seekers to his country and other EU member countries, a charge still unproven. But his critics point out that his real worries are a lot closer to home. His pro-EU Civic Platform coalition may have scraped through Poland's parliamentary elections last year, but it's been floundering ever since. Polls now show Tusk's party neck and neck with the Eurosceptic Law and Justice Party (PiS).</p>

<p>Tusk is not alone. Struggling Europhile leaders across the continent are suddenly discovering the political utility of "securing national borders". Take, for example, Olaf Scholz, Germany's embattled chancellor. His popularity is sinking fast. Recently, Scholz imposed border controls across all of Germany's land borders, citing an Islamist terror attack in Solingen as the trigger. But let's call it what it is: a calculated move for the February election to placate voters fed up with migration and to fend off rising populist parties like the AfD.</p>

<h2><strong>Double Standards</strong></h2>

<p>Then there is Brussels itself—the hallowed guardian of European unity, democracy and human rights. It has made a remarkable U-turn on migration. Recently, after one of its signature closed-door meetings, the European Commission threw its weight behind Tusk. In a statement backed by all 27 member states, Brussels claimed that Russia and Belarus are “abusing our values” and “undermining our democracies”. It justified its stance by saying that “exceptional situations require appropriate measures”.</p>

<p>Apparently, the EU has decided that border controls are acceptable so long as the justification is wrapped in anti-Russian rhetoric and presented by the right kind of leader. To understand the EU's hypocrisy, let's remind ourselves what it did to Viktor Orbán's Hungary—Orbán being a ‘bad boy' of Europe for supporting Russia. Recently, the EU's top court fined Hungary €200m for failing to follow the union's asylum policies. The court will also issue a penalty of €1m a day until it changes its policy. The European Court of Justice said Budapest was in breach of a 2020 judgement and had violated EU laws by forcing asylum seekers to travel to Belgrade or Kyiv to apply for a travel permit for entering Hungary.</p>

<p>These double standards are impossible to ignore. When Poland's PiS government previously clamped down on migration, Brussels was quick to condemn it as a betrayal of European values. But now that Tusk is doing the same, suddenly, the EU is all right with it.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>France Faces People's Mistrust</strong></h2>

<p>President Macron and France's so-called political class are facing a sea of public mistrust. A recent Le Monde survey paints a grim picture: only 22% of French people trust their MPs—a seven-point drop in just a year. Voters are sick of the endless political bickering. And who can blame them? With faith in the system evaporating, the odds that fresh parliamentary elections next summer will magically deliver a stable majority seem very slim.</p>

<p>The timing couldn't be worse. The war in Ukraine is at a potential turning point, and across the Atlantic, a new Trump administration looms, itching to kickstart a trade war that could send shockwaves through Europe's fragile economy. For now, Macron still holds the reins—at least on paper. But he has to convince France's allies that the nation isn't about to unravel completely. With domestic gridlock and global crises closing in, it's up to him to prove that France can still play ball on the world stage. The question is: does anyone still believe he can pull it off?</p>

<h2><strong>Ukraine Obsession: A Crisis Of Priorities</strong></h2>

<p>The European Union is pouring billions into Ukraine—defence aid, financial packages, reconstruction pledges—all in the name of standing up to Russian aggression. But its own citizens are buckling under the weight of spiralling costs. Energy bills are sky-high, inflation continues to bite and wages remain stagnant. Let's be blunt, I live and travel in the heart of Europe and I feel it: the EU's relentless commitment to Ukraine isn't just draining its coffers, it's bleeding its people dry.</p>

<p>The Biden administration, ever the puppet master, has pulled the EU deep into the Ukrainian quagmire. Washington's playbook is clear: keep Europe committed to Ukraine as a frontline bulwark against Russia. But what has Europe gained? Endless sanctions that hurt its own economies more than Moscow's, and a cold winter of discontent driven by an overreliance on expensive LNG imports from across the Atlantic. Meanwhile, Russia, as I have said in my previous columns, though battered, is far from broken. Its economy is adapting and its territorial grip in eastern Ukraine remains firm.</p>

<h2><strong>An Awkward Dance With Trump And Musk</strong></h2>

<p>Europe's love affair with the American tech and political elite has soured spectacularly. Donald Trump's triumphant return and his bromance with Elon Musk may spell trouble for the EU's ambitious tech crackdown.</p>

<p>Let's talk about X, Musk's digital playground, and its showdown with the EU's Digital Services Act (DSA). This isn't just another slap-on-the-wrist regulation. Passed in 2022, the DSA packs a punch, demanding platforms remove illegal content or face fines of up to 6% of their annual revenue. Musk's X is on the radar of the EU regulators, who have alleged multiple violations of the DSA rules. Now, they're mulling their next move—fine X, slap Musk with penalties, or go after both. But that was before Trump was in play. Now that he is, the EU's tech crusade is about to get a lot messier.</p>

<h2><strong>Digital Dinosaur In A World Of Tech Titans</strong></h2>

<p>One of the EU's biggest problems is that it's not disintegrating—it's badly stagnating. Former Italian Prime Minister Mario Draghi sounded the alarm in September. In his much-anticipated 328-page report, Draghi pulled no punches: "This is an existential challenge,” he said. Europe needs to raise its annual investment by a staggering €800 billion to keep pace with the US and China, with much of that going to tech. Without it, the continent risks being left in the dust.</p>

<p>Seattle-based, Indian-origin tech expert S. Aamir Aarfi says that Europe needs to act fast, as it currently lags behind all the top players. Says he, "Silicon Valley churns out innovation at warp speed, China dominates AI and 5G, and even India is emerging as a tech powerhouse. Unfortunately, Europe clings to regulations and bureaucracy, dangerously close to stagnation and irrelevance."</p>

<p>“Consider the cold, hard facts,” says Aarfi, “the US dominates Big Tech and is home to giants like Apple, Google and Microsoft. China has its state-backed juggernauts—Tencent, Alibaba, and Huawei. But Europe? It boasts only the SAP". Draghi notes that a mere four of the world's top 50 tech companies are European. He doesn't mince words: "Europe largely missed out on the digital revolution led by the internet and the productivity gains it brought.”</p>

<p>The EU appears to be spending more time regulating than innovating. Its flagship Digital Services and Markets Acts are more about policing foreign tech than fostering local growth. Meanwhile, European startups struggle to scale, stifled by red tape and a lack of venture capital. Europe dithers over ethics, while its brightest minds head to Silicon Valley or Shenzhen.</p>

<p>Draghi's diagnosis is clear: Europe isn't just falling behind—it's failing to show up. If it doesn't act boldly and invest massively, it risks becoming a digital backwater, sidelined in the industries defining the future. As Aarfi says, "Europe needs a tech revolution and it needs it now.”</p>

<p>The greatest threat to the EU doesn't come from Moscow or Beijing but from within. Populist and nationalist movements are on the rise, fuelled by a toxic blend of economic anxiety, cultural insecurity, and distrust of Brussels. Stuck in a web of noble intentions but shoddy execution, the EU risks becoming irrelevant—not through dramatic collapse, but through a slow, self-inflicted decline.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-06/british-with-eu-flag-reuters_650x400_51466763676.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-car-sized-drones-spotted-flying-over-new-jersey-fbi-begins-probe-7208816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mysterious Car-Sized Drones Spotted Over New Jersey, FBI Begins Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-car-sized-drones-spotted-flying-over-new-jersey-fbi-begins-probe-7208816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:38:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[These sightings, which began in late November, involve large, often car-sized drones flying in coordinated patterns.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unidentified drones have been reported flying over multiple counties in New Jersey, causing widespread concern among residents and prompting a federal investigation. These sightings, which began in late November 2024, involve large, often car-sized drones flying in coordinated patterns, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/07/nyregion/new-jersey-drones.html">New York Times</a></em> reported.&nbsp;They have been spotted hovering over critical infrastructure, including reservoirs, power lines, and railroads, as well as flying over residential backyards, highways, and often in groups.</p>

<p>A flurry of online images and videos have gone viral on social media in the US, sparking widespread curiosity and concern among locals.&nbsp;The drones were captured on camera by residents in multiple boroughs in the state, mostly at night.&nbsp;Witnesses described the drones as significantly larger than typical hobbyist models and emitting a loud, humming noise.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's kind of unsettling. They're not up for 15 minutes, they're up for hours," a resident told&nbsp;<em>WPIX. </em>"We saw one right up above us that was the size of our car, another resident said.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?Additional Footage of Drone Sighting's in New Jersey: Not Planes – Light Patterns Deviate from FAA Guidelines‼️ Suggesting Tech-Based or UAP Mimicry<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Uaphearing?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Uaphearing</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UAP?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UAP</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/uapdisclosure?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#uapdisclosure</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UAPs?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UAPs</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UAPTwitter?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UAPTwitter</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/uapX?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#uapX</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UFOTwitter?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UFOTwitter</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UFOSightings?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UFOSightings</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ufodisclosure?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ufodisclosure</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/njdrones?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#njdrones</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/newjerseydrones?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#newjerseydrones</a> <a href="https://t.co/L9JeIQ4POy">pic.twitter.com/L9JeIQ4POy</a></p>
— Ethical Truther ??️ (@EthicalTruther) <a href="https://twitter.com/EthicalTruther/status/1864780535769501877?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">These "drones" being seen over New Jersey are Galactic Federation crafts.<br />
<br />
They're partially disguised to give those who aren't ready time to adapt.<br />
<br />
Some look like planes. Some look like drones.<br />
<br />
The military already knows they can't stop them. Nothing can stop what's coming. <a href="https://t.co/CZ3A6VpxHW">https://t.co/CZ3A6VpxHW</a> <a href="https://t.co/gpihADUyVy">pic.twitter.com/gpihADUyVy</a></p>
— Kab (@Kabamur_Taygeta) <a href="https://twitter.com/Kabamur_Taygeta/status/1864619951144767783?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The FBI, along with local law enforcement and the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), is currently investigating the incidents. "We are working with several of our law enforcement partners to figure out what's going on. At the moment, we don't have any specifics to share," said bureau spokeswoman Amy J. Thoreson.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Authorities have emphasised there is no immediate threat but encouraged residents to report sightings and provide images to assist the investigation. FBI's Newark office and Morris County officials issued a<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.morriscountynj.gov/Morris-County-News/Law-Enforcement-Advises-Public-How-to-Report-Drones-Activity"> joint statement </a>asking the public to come forward with any information they might have over the mysterious "drone activity," including videos.&nbsp;"There continues to be no known threat to public safety," the statement reads.</p>

<p>However, the drones' consistent and organized activity has drawn public attention, with some fearing breaches of privacy or security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is making people anxious. It's kind of like a Peeping Tom, and it gets everybody's vigilance up − they become hypervigilant to it," said Richard Waldron, a Closter-based psychologist.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Following the reports, the Federal Aviation Administration has also banned drones from flying over President-elect Donald Trump's New Jersey golf course.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the mysterious drone sightings have captivated the online community, with the state's subreddit forum buzzing with theories and amateur investigations. Even UFO enthusiasts have joined the fray, speculating about the origins and purpose of the unmanned aerial vehicles.</p>

<p>Theories abound, ranging from suspicions of foreign surveillance drones, such as the Chinese spy balloon incident last year, to possibilities of US military tests or local law enforcement surveillance.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/t1ier34o_drones-in-new-jersey_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities have emphasised there is no immediate threat but encouraged residents to report sightings.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-much-microsoft-tesla-amazon-spend-protecting-their-ceos-7207126]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tesla, Google, Amazon: How Much They Are Spending For Their CEOs' Safety]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-much-microsoft-tesla-amazon-spend-protecting-their-ceos-7207126]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:28:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson has cast a spotlight on the extensive security measures employed by Wall Street's elite to ensure their safety.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson has cast a spotlight on the extensive security measures employed by Wall Street's elite to ensure their safety. With the increasing risks associated with high-profile roles, companies are shelling out significant amounts to protect their top executives. Big tech firms like Google, Amazon, and Tesla are among the many that prioritise personal security for their CEOs. These measures often include personal security details, private transportation, and state-of-the-art security systems, adding millions to operational costs annually.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">A prime example is Microsoft's CEO, Satya Nadella. Microsoft ramped up security for its CEO, allocating over $58,000 for his travel security this year. This figure was disclosed in the company's SEC filing on October 24. Mr Nadella, set to earn $79.1 million this year, had previously requested a pay reduction to offset rising security expenses after multiple incidents earlier in the year, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/24/microsoft-ceo-nadella-requested-pay-reduction-after-security-incidents.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNBC</a> first reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Tesla CEO Elon Musk</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">In the first two months of 2024, <a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/1318605/000110465924053333/tm2326076d15_def14a.htm " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Tesla spent $500,000</a> on Elon Musk's security, more than five times what was spent in the same period in 2019. This follows a significant increase in security costs, with Tesla disclosing $2.4 million spent on Mr Musk's protection in 2023. Between 2015 and 2018, Mr Musk's monthly security expenses averaged $145,000. His protection is managed by high-profile firms, including Gavin de Becker &amp; Associates and his own Foundation Security.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>BlackRock CEO Larry Fink</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">World's largest asset manager, BlackRock, doubled its security spending for CEO Larry Fink in 2023, as per <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1364742/000119312524087282/d577664ddef14a.htm" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">security filings</a>. The company spent $216,837 on personal security guards and $563,513 on upgrading Mr Fink's home security system.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Google CEO Sundar Pichai</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">Last year, Alphabet spent over $6.7 million on CEO Sundar Pichai for expenses, including security, retirement contributions, company vehicles, and other benefits, as per a Securities and Exchange Commission filing. These expenditures formed the bulk of his total compensation package, exceeding $6.8 million.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Amazon CEO Andy Jassy</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">In 2023, Andy Jassy's transportation costs totalled $986,164, covering business travel and security upgrades, as per a <a href="https://qz.com/google-amazon-apple-tesla-nvidia-ceo-security-costs-1851504917/slides/4 " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Quartz report</a>. His compensation dropped compared to 2022, largely due to a decline in Amazon's stock price and fewer restricted stock units. The stock price fell from $156.51 in 2022 to $143.90 in 2023, as per <a href="https://s2.q4cdn.com/299287126/files/doc_financials/2024/ar/Amazon-com-Inc-2024-Proxy-Statement.pdf " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">filings</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/p2hnndpo_elon-and-jeff_625x300_22_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Measures often include personal security details, private transportation, etc.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-fallout-because-of-huge-miscalculation-by-iran-israeli-envoy-reuven-azar-7208679]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syria Fallout Because Of "Huge Miscalculation By Iran": Israeli Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-fallout-because-of-huge-miscalculation-by-iran-israeli-envoy-reuven-azar-7208679]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:22:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel today said that it is not involved in the conflict in Syria, nor does it want to involve itself, but Tel Aviv is preparing to defend itself against any attack that may come from the Syrian side, Israel's envoy to India Reuven Azar said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel today said that it is not involved in the conflict in Syria, nor does it want to involve itself, but Tel Aviv is preparing to defend itself against any attack that may come from the Syrian side, Israel's envoy to India Reuven Azar said.</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV World, Mr Azar said that all that is happening in Syria is a series of events that are unfolding because of a "huge miscalculation" by Iran.</p>

<p>"All of Iran's tentacles in the region have been cut", Mr Azar said, explaining that "Iran and Hezbollah made a huge miscalculation. They didn't understand what the consequences would be of the attack against Israel."</p>

<p>He further added that "Hezbollah has been hit very hard. Nasrallah, as you remember, was taken out, along with many thousands of Hezbollah terrorists. Then Iran attacked Israel directly, and as you know, Israel defended itself and retaliated hard. So when you look at the picture today, you see that these tentacles of the Iranian regime have all been cut. And now, rebel forces in the region (Syria), which have been following all that (happened) and seeing the debilitation of the Iran axis took full advantage of it. And that is how you see the change in Syria."</p>

<p>Mr Azar said that the situation in Syria is a consequence of Iran messing with Israel, however, it is not engineered by Tel Aviv. "Israel is not involved in the Syrian conflict. We are not intending to involve ourselves in Syrian politics. That is a matter that the Syrian people have to sort out for themselves."</p>

<h2><strong>SITUATION AT THE ISRAEL-SYRIA BORDER</strong></h2>

<p>Mr Azar said that Tel Aviv is always prepared to defend itself against any and all threats, and that is what they are limiting themselves to when it comes to Syria.</p>

<p>"Israel is no doubt in a situation of alert. We are following very closely the events in Syria. The Israel Defence Forces have already taken defensive positions in the buffer zone in the border between Israel and Syria," Mr Azar said.</p>

<p>"There is a disengagement zone that was created in 1974 following the Yom Kippur War. That zone is a buffer zone from several hundred metres to a few kilometres. It is located in the north. In the past, that area has been attacked by different groups. It has been attacked now too. The UN forces there have come under attack and Israel has come to the rescue. So we are taking this temporary defensive positions in the buffer zone and following very closely what is going on on the other side, preparing to defend ourselves against any possible attack or development," he added.</p>

<h2><strong>SITUATION IN A GIST</strong></h2>

<p>Bashar Al-Assad's regime was backed by Russia, Iran, and Tehran-backed Hezbollah, while <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-civil-war-all-about-the-rebels-behind-the-fall-of-bashar-al-assad-7205678" target="_blank">the rebels</a> are led by Abu Mohammad Al-Jolani, a terrorist formerly associated with Al Qaeda and ISIS. While Turkey backs some of the rebel groups against the Al-Assads, Al-Jolani, who heads the Hayat Tahrir Al-Sham or HTS - the most prominent of all rebels factions - is not officially backed by anyone.</p>

<p>Bashar Al-Assad and his family, which ruled over Syria for more than five decades has fled to Russia. Moscow has officially granted them political asylum.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/c4afc028_syria34_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bashar Al-Assad's regime in Syria has been toppled by armed rebel groups.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-navy-inducts-russia-made-guided-missile-frigate-ins-tushil-7208450]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Navy Inducts Russia-Made Guided Missile Frigate INS Tushil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-navy-inducts-russia-made-guided-missile-frigate-ins-tushil-7208450]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:50:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian Navy's Russian-manufactured guided missile frigate INS Tushil was commissioned into the force at Russia's coastal city of Kaliningrad on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian Navy's Russian-manufactured guided missile frigate INS Tushil was commissioned into the force at Russia's coastal city of Kaliningrad on Monday.</p>

<p>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh, Chief of Naval Staff Admiral Dinesh K Tripathi and several other senior Indian officials were present at the commissioning ceremony.</p>

<p>INS Tushil is expected to significantly bolster the Indian Navy's operational capability in the Indian Ocean, a region that has witnessed increasing forays by China's PLA Navy in the last few years.</p>

<p>The warship has been constructed in Russia as part of an over USD 2.5-billion deal that New Delhi had inked with Moscow in 2016 for four stealth frigates for the Indian Navy.</p>

<p>Under the deal, two ships were to be built in Russia, while the other two were to be manufactured in India.</p>

<p>In his remarks at the ceremony, Mr Singh described the commissioning of the warship as a proud testament to India's growing maritime strength and a significant milestone in long-standing ties with Russia.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/u4eqkrd8_ins-tushil-ceremony_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"The ship is a big proof of the collaborative prowess of Russian and Indian industries. It exemplifies India's journey towards technological excellence through jointmanship," he said.</p>

<p>Singh said India and Russia will enter a "new era" of cooperation by taking advantage of each other's expertise in areas such as artificial intelligence, cyber security, space exploration and counter-terrorism.</p>

<p>The ship's construction was closely monitored by an Indian team of specialists from the 'Warship Overseeing Team' stationed at Kaliningrad.</p>

<p>The 3,900-tonne ship with a length of 125 metres packs a lethal punch and is an impressive blend of Russian and Indian cutting edge technologies and best practices in warship construction.</p>

<p>The ship's new design provides it with enhanced stealth features and better stability characteristics, officials said.</p>

<p>With the collaboration of Indian naval specialists and Severnoye Design Bureau, the indigenous content of the ship has been enhanced to an impressive 26 per cent, the officials said.</p>

<p>The major Indian defence firms involved in the project were BrahMos Aerospace Private Limited, Bharat Electronics Limited, Keltron, Nova Integrated Systems from Tata, Elcome Marine, Johnson Controls India and others.</p>

<p>INS Tushil is an upgraded Krivak III class frigate of Project 1135.6.</p>

<p>The warship is the result of the continuous toil of hundreds of shipyard workers along with multiple Russian and Indian Original Equipment Makers (OEMs), said one of the officials cited above.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hp6vc2b_ins-tushil_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The warship has been constructed in Russia as part of an over $2.5-billion deal]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/timeline-10-day-blitzkrieg-campaign-that-ended-assads-rule-in-syria-7208123]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Timeline: 10-Day Blitzkrieg Campaign That Ended Assad's Rule In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/timeline-10-day-blitzkrieg-campaign-that-ended-assads-rule-in-syria-7208123]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:12:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Syrian President Bashar al-Assad fled the country with his family and took asylum in Russia after rebels took control of the country in a 10-day blitzkrieg, seizing the capital Damascus and toppling the government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syrian President Bashar al-Assad fled the country with his family and reportedly took asylum in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bashar-al-assad-charging-rebels-fleeing-allies-how-syrian-president-reached-russia-7206198">Russia</a> after rebels took control of the country in a 10-day blitzkrieg, seizing the capital Damascus and toppling the government.</p>

<p>The blitzkrieg, German for "lightning war", started with a series of attacks that began on November 27 in northern Syria. The rapid offensive led by a group called Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), formerly known as the Al-Nusra Front affiliated with terror group Al-Qaeda, and allied factions, ended <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-damascus-bashar-al-assad-out-rebels-take-over-what-next-for-syria-and-its-people-7200024">Bashar al-Assad's 24-year-long rule</a> and the end of the Assad family's control over the country after 54 years.</p>

<h3><b>Day 1</b></h3>

<p>On November 27, the HTS, which controls much of the northwest Idlib area and slivers of neighbouring Aleppo, Hama and Latakia provinces, led a rapid offensive, attacking Syrian army outposts in the north, killing over 130 in the strikes.</p>

<p>The figures included 65 operatives from HTS", 18 from allied factions "and 49 members of regime forces", said the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, which relies on a network of sources inside Syria, AFP reported.</p>

<h3><b>Day 2</b></h3>

<p>The rebels take control of the highway linking Aleppo to the Syrian capital Damascus.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Image credit: maps.google.com" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/se9ot4kg_damascus_625x300_09_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Image credit: maps.google.com" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Image credit: maps.google.com</p>
</div>

<p>"Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS) and allied factions cut off the Damascus-Aleppo international M5 highway... in addition to controlling the junction between the M4 and M5 highways," said the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.</p>

<h3><b>Day 3 and 4</b></h3>

<p>On November 29 and 30, the clashes escalated after the rebels started shelling the government-held Aleppo city. The HTS and Turkey-backed factions launched artillery strikes on university residences, killing at least four people in the strikes.</p>

<p>The attack continued the following to take full control of Aleppo. Russian warplanes launched airstrikes on rebels, a first since 2016, the Observatory said.</p>

<p>The rebels seized control of most of Aleppo within a day and held more than 80 towns and villages in the north.</p>

<h3><b>Day 5</b></h3>

<p>On December 1, for the first time in more than a decade since the start of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-rebels-failed-for-13-years-how-they-beat-assad-regime-in-13-days-7205550">2011 civil war during the Arab Spring</a>, Aleppo was out of the Syrian army's control.</p>

<p>Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi travelled to Damascus to meet President Assad, saying that Tehran would "firmly support the Syrian government and army".</p>

<p>The US, France, Germany and Britain call for "de-escalation", urging for the protection of civilians and infrastructure in Syria.</p>

<h3><b>Day 6</b></h3>

<p>According to the Kremlin, Russian President Vladimir Putin and Iran's President Masoud Pezeshkian both pledged "unconditional support" for their ally.</p>

<h3><b>Day 7</b></h3>

<p>The rebels captured Hama, Syria's fourth largest city, after days of fierce fighting with Assad's forces. HTS chief Abu Mohammed al-Jolani says there would be "no revenge" after Hama's seizure.</p>

<h3><b>Day 8</b></h3>

<p>The rebels reach very close to Homs, the "city of revolution". HTS chief al-Jolani said the goal of the offensive was to overthrow Assad's rule, reiterating "our right to use all available means to achieve that goal". Syrian troops and Iran-backed paramilitaries pull out of eastern Deir Ezzor city -- the home to Iranian advisers brought in post-2011.</p>

<p>Over 820 people, including 111 civilians, were killed since the offensive began, the Observatory said.</p>

<h3><b>Day 9</b></h3>

<p>By December 7, HTS, the biggest of many rebel factions, took control of Homs and its chief Jolani said, "Damascus awaits you." The Syrian Defence Ministry denied any withdrawal of forces from the capital.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, who is funding anti-Kurdish fighters in northern Syria, said the country "is tired of war, blood and tears".</p>

<p>AFP reported that Hezbollah sent some 2,000 fighters to defend Syria.</p>

<h3><b>Day 10</b></h3>

<p>On December 8, the army pulled out of the capital and Syrian President Bashar al-Assad was forced to flee the country after rebels seized Damascus, ending his 24-year rule.</p>

<p>News agency AFP reported that according to a war monitor, the Army and security forces had abandoned Damascus International Airport.</p>

<p>The overthrow of the Bashar al-Assad regime follows the 13-year rebellion that started as a peaceful uprising against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-assad-family-damascus-the-al-assads-syrias-first-familys-rapid-rise-brutal-rule-abrupt-end-7198899">President Assad</a> and snowballed into a full-scale civil war that devastated Syria.</p>

<p>By the end of the day, reports from Russia emerged that Assad resigned and his family fled to Moscow, though the Kremlin did not confirm the reports.</p>

<h3><b>Day 11</b></h3>

<p>Celebrations continue in Syria marking the end of Assad's rule marred by brutality unleashed towards protesters during the 2011 protests. During the civil war, over half a million people have been killed, six million became refugees, and countless more are internally displaced.</p>

<p><em>-- with inputs from AFP</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/o71hn8s_syria_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The overthrow of the Bashar al-Assad regime follows the 13-year rebellion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-al-assad-turkey-russia-refugee-crisis-kurdistan-question-whats-turkeys-new-reality-in-syria-7208122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Refugee Crisis, Kurdistan Question: What's Turkey's "New Reality" In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-al-assad-turkey-russia-refugee-crisis-kurdistan-question-whats-turkeys-new-reality-in-syria-7208122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:12:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Syrian President Bashar al-Assad's regime collapsed in just 13 days of rebel offensive after 24 years of rule, leaving a political vacuum in its capital Damascus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syrian President Bashar al-Assad's regime collapsed in just 13 days of rebel offensive after 24 years of rule, leaving a political vacuum in its capital Damascus. While the rapid downfall was not entirely unexpected, its speed has left Turkey, along with other foreign actors, scrambling for power. Turkey, now the dominant external force in Syria, faces a "new reality", according to its president Recep Tayyip Erdogan.</p>

<p>"There is now a new reality in Syria, politically and diplomatically. And Syria belongs to Syrians with all its ethnic, sectarian and religious elements," Erdogan said as quoted by news agency Reuters. "The people of Syria are the ones who will decide the future of their own country."</p>

<h2><strong>The Collapse</strong></h2>

<p>The collapse of Assad's government was preceded by a coordinated offensive led by Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), an armed group with historical ties to al-Qaeda. What began as a limited campaign - backed implicitly by Turkey - quickly escalated into a full-scale assault. Within days, major cities like Aleppo and Hama fell to rebel forces, and the Syrian Army retreated to defensive positions around Damascus.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-bashar-al-assads-fall-means-for-historic-india-syria-relations-7206308#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Damascus' Nehru Street, Assad's Kashmir View: What Now For India-Syria Ties</a></p>

<p>Turkey, a long-time backer of Syrian opposition forces, had initially aimed for a smaller operation to ease pressure on its borders and counter Kurdish militias allied with the Kurdistan Workers' Party or PKK. According to reports, the sudden expansion of the offensive caught Ankara by surprise. Senior officials in President Erdogan's administration had anticipated Assad's eventual fall but not at this pace.</p>

<h2><strong>Turkey's Strategy</strong></h2>

<p>For years, Turkey has played a role in Syria's civil war, supporting opposition forces while conducting its own military operations against Kurdish militias in northern Syria. Erdogan's government has sought to create a buffer zone along its southern border and curb the ambitions of Kurdish groups seeking autonomy and creating a sovereign nation called Kurdistan.</p>

<p>The swift fall of Aleppo and Hama has created opportunities for Ankara to shape post-Assad Syria, but it also raises concerns about instability, refugee flows, and the growing influence of HTS.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kremlin-says-surprised-by-developments-in-syria-refuses-to-confirm-if-bashar-al-assad-in-russia-7207284">"Got Nothing To Tell You": Kremlin On Assad's Whereabouts</a></p>

<p>Turkey has sought to moderate HTS over the years. HTS leader Abu Mohammad al-Jolani has made overtures to minorities, pledged to preserve Syria's institutional structures, and expressed interest in dialogue with Russia. However, despite his assurances, the group's jihadist roots remain a point of contention.</p>

<h2><strong>Refugee Politics</strong></h2>

<p>One of Turkey's most immediate concerns is the return of Syrian refugees. Hosting over 3 million Syrians, Erdogan's government has faced domestic backlash over the prolonged presence of these displaced people. The fall of Assad has sparked hope among refugees for a return to their homeland.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-look-at-how-rebel-forces-overthrew-assad-and-how-it-mirrors-sheikh-hasinas-plight-7205876">Palace Looted, Portraits Torn: How Assad's Fall Echoes Sheikh Hasina's Fate</a></p>

<p>In Aleppo, factories and industrial centres are reportedly reopening. However, the return of refugees will depend on the establishment of security, economic stability, and basic infrastructure. Turkey is likely to play a central role in coordinating reconstruction efforts.</p>

<h2><strong>The Kurdish Question</strong></h2>

<p>The fate of Kurdish-controlled territories remains an issue for Turkey. The Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF) is dominated by the US-backed People's Defense Units or YPG militia. However, Ankara views the YPG as an extension of the PKK, a designated terrorist organisation under its laws. Turkey has conducted multiple military operations to push Kurdish forces away from its borders and consolidate control over northern Syria.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-rebels-failed-for-13-years-how-they-beat-assad-regime-in-13-days-7205550">Syrian Rebels Failed For 13 Years. How They Beat Assad Regime In 13 Days</a></p>

<p>The fall of Assad has complicated this dynamic. HTS, despite its Islamist background, has reportedly established a working relationship with the SDF in some areas. This development has raised concerns in Ankara, as it undermines Turkey's efforts to weaken Kurdish influence in Syria.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/oqichvo8_turkey-syria-afp-_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For years, Turkey has played a role in Syria's civil war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-envoys-big-warning-to-hamas-over-hostage-situationingaza-7207901]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Envoy's Big Warning To Hamas Over Hostage Situation In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-envoys-big-warning-to-hamas-over-hostage-situationingaza-7207901]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:45:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's Middle East envoy warned on Monday during a visit to the region it would "not be a pretty day" if the hostages held in Gaza were not released before the U.S. President-elect's inauguration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's Middle East envoy warned on Monday during a visit to the region it would "not be a pretty day" if the hostages held in Gaza were not released before the US President-elect's inauguration.</p>

<p>Steve Witkoff, who will formally take up the position when Mr Trump's administration starts, said he hoped and prayed there would be ceasefire in Gaza between Palestinian militant group Hamas and Israel before Trump takes office on Jan. 20.</p>

<p>"You heard what the president said, they better be released," he said, referring to Mr Trump.</p>

<p>"Listen to what the president has got to say. It's not a pretty day if they're not released," Mr Witkoff added, in response to Reuters questions on the sidelines of a bitcoin conference in UAE capital Abu Dhabi.</p>

<p>President-elect Mr Trump said on social media last week there would be "hell to pay" if the hostages were not released before his inauguration.</p>

<p>Hamas-led militants killed 1,200 people and captured more than 250, including Israeli-American dual nationals, during their Oct. 7, 2023 attack on Israel, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>More than 100 hostages have been freed through negotiations or Israeli military rescue operations. Of the 101 still held in Gaza, roughly half are believed to be alive.</p>

<p>More than 44,700 people have been killed in the assault that Israel launched on Gaza in response, authorities in the Hamas-run territory say. Thousands of others are feared dead under the rubble.</p>

<p>Mr Witkoff earlier spoke to an audience at the Bitcoin conference where those attending paid as much as $9,999 to access special sessions, which are closed to media.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pc76pvr_steve-witkoff-donald-trump-reuters_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Steve Witkoff will formally be the Middle East envoy when Donald Trump's administration starts]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-discuss-military-bases-with-syrias-new-rulers-says-kremlin-7207873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia To Discuss Military Bases With Syria's New Rulers, Says Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-discuss-military-bases-with-syrias-new-rulers-says-kremlin-7207873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:41:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin said on Monday that it was too early to say what the future would hold for Russia's military bases in Syria, adding that it would be the subject of discussion with the new rulers in Damascus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin said on Monday that it was too early to say what the future would hold for Russia's military bases in Syria, adding that it would be the subject of discussion with the new rulers in Damascus.</p>

<p>After a lightning advance of a militia alliance spearheaded by Hayat al-Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), a former al-Qaeda affiliate, Bashar al-Assad fled to Russia, raising questions about two strategically-important Russian military facilities in Syria.</p>

<p>Asked about the future of the bases, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said: "It's premature to talk about it yet."</p>

<p>"This is all a subject for discussion with those who will be in power in Syria," Peskov said, adding that there was "extreme instability" in the country.</p>

<p>"Of course, everything is being done now that is necessary and everything that is possible in order to get in touch with those who can deal with security. And, of course, our military is also taking all necessary precautions," Peskov said.</p>

<p>Russia's Hmeimim airbase in Syria's Latakia province a naval facility at Tartous on the coast.</p>

<p>The Tartous facility is Russia's only Mediterranean repair and replenishment hub, and Moscow has used Syria as a staging post to fly its military contractors in and out of Africa.</p>

<p>Peskov confirmed that Assad had been given asylum in Russia, saying the decision was made by President Vladimir Putin. Asked about a possible meeting between Putin and Assad, Peskov said none was currently in the official Kremlin schedule.</p>

<p>More broadly, Peskov said, the Kremlin saw a turbulent international situation with a high potential for conflict.</p>

<p>"We see the situation around Ukraine, we see many contradictory statements in this regard, we see a growing conflict potential in other regions, we can say the burning Middle East," Peskov said.</p>

<p>US President-elect Donald Trump called on Sunday for an immediate ceasefire and negotiations between Ukraine and Russia to end "the madness".</p>

<p>The Kremlin said on Sunday that Russia was open to talks, but that they had to be based on agreements reached in Istanbul in 2022 and on current realities on the battlefield where Russian forces have been pushing forward at their fastest rate since the early days of the war in 2022.</p>

<p>Putin has said that Ukraine must not join the NATO military alliance and that Russia should be left fully in control of four Ukrainian regions his troops partially control at the moment for a peace deal to be done.</p>

<p>Asked if there had been any contact with Trump or his team, Peskov said: "No, there have still been no contacts."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4do88uq_putin-syria-military-base_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia's Hmeimim airbase in Syria's Latakia province a naval facility at Tartous on the coast. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-military-on-high-alert-as-china-warships-sail-near-island-7207779]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taiwan Military On High Alert As China Warships Sail Near Island]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-military-on-high-alert-as-china-warships-sail-near-island-7207779]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:31:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwan's military was on high alert Monday after detecting Chinese warships near the island, Taipei said, as it prepared for likely drills by Beijing in response to President Lai Ching-te's US visits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan's military was on high alert Monday after detecting Chinese warships near the island, Taipei said, as it prepared for likely drills by Beijing in response to President Lai Ching-te's US visits.</p>

<p>The Taiwanese defence ministry said it also spotted Chinese coast guard vessels and that Beijing's People's Liberation Army (PLA) had restricted the airspace off the Chinese coast.</p>

<p>There has been intense speculation about the possibility of China launching military exercises in response to Lai's trip to the Pacific last week which included stopovers in Hawaii and Guam.</p>

<p>"In response to these actions by the PLA, the MND has initiated combat readiness drills, factoring in enemy threats, weather conditions, and tactical positioning," the Ministry of National Defense in Taipei said in a statement.</p>

<p>It added that military units were on "high" alert and those on outlying islands had "heightened their vigilance".</p>

<p>The ministry said its forces had "identified PLA Eastern, Northern, and Southern Theater Command naval formations, along with Coast Guard vessels, entering areas around the Taiwan Strait and the Western Pacific".</p>

<p>There was no immediate public announcement by the PLA or Chinese state media about increased military activity around Taiwan.</p>

<p>However, a Beijing foreign ministry spokeswoman said China would "firmly defend" its sovereignty, as Taiwan kicked off its drills.</p>

<p>Taiwan regards itself as a sovereign nation with its own government, military, and currency.</p>

<p>But Beijing insists the island is part of its territory and has not ruled out using force to bring it under its control.</p>

<p>Lai spoke with Republican US House Speaker Mike Johnson in Guam on Thursday -- the highest-level US contact the Taiwanese leader had during a week-long trip -- which drew a barrage of criticism from Beijing.</p>

<p>China's foreign ministry warned Taiwan on Friday that "seeking independence with the help of the United States will inevitably hit a wall", and called on Washington to "cease meddling in Taiwan-related affairs".</p>

<p>In response to a question about possible Chinese military drills around Taiwan following his trip, Lai told reporters on Friday that "raising your fists is not as good as opening your hands".</p>

<p>"No matter how many military exercises, warships and aircraft China sends to coerce neighbouring countries, it cannot win the respect of any country," Lai said.</p>

<p><strong>'Unusual movements'</strong></p>

<p>Taiwan's coast guard said on Monday it had detected "unusual movements" of seven Chinese coast guard ships since early Friday -- the day Lai returned to Taipei.</p>

<p>The Beijing army's airspace restrictions east of Zhejiang and Fujian provinces were expected to be in place until Wednesday, Taiwan's defence ministry said.</p>

<p>"Any unilateral, irrational acts of provocation could severely undermine peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and are unwelcome by the international community," the ministry said.</p>

<p>It added that the PLA's "recent activities near Japan, South Korea, the Philippines, and Taiwan have introduced risks and uncertainties to regional security".</p>

<p>Japan's defence ministry said Monday it had detected over the weekend a Chinese navy missile destroyer, frigate and "information-gathering ship" sailing southeast between Okinawa island and Miyako islands towards the Pacific Ocean.</p>

<p>"From the limited information available, the seven restricted airspaces are likely being used for two main purposes: missile testing and simulating no-fly zones, which represent a blocked airspace state," Su Tzu-yun, a military expert at the Institute for National Defense and Security Research in Taipei, told AFP.</p>

<p>Su said the drills "appear politically motivated" and would backfire on Beijing by reinforcing the "China threat theory".</p>

<p>Taiwan faces the constant threat of a military attack by China and relies heavily on US arms sales to boost its defences.</p>

<p>On the eve of Lai's Pacific tour, the United States approved a proposed sale to Taiwan of spare parts for F-16s and radar systems, as well as communications equipment, in deals valued at $385 million in total.</p>

<p>Lai said in the US state of Hawaii during his trip there was a need to "fight together to prevent war", warning there were "no winners" from conflict.</p>

<p>China has launched two large-scale military drills around Taiwan since Lai took office and regularly deploys fighter jets and navy ships to press its claims over the island.</p>

<p>Lai has been more outspoken than his predecessor Tsai Ing-wen in defending Taiwan's sovereignty, angering Beijing which calls him a "separatist".</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/84ucjcuo_china-warship-in-taiwanreuters_625x300_07_August_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Military units on outlying islands had "heightened their vigilance". (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thailand-police-bust-drug-fuelled-party-detain-120-in-underwear-7207711]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drug Party Busted, 120 People In Their Underwear Detained In Thailand]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thailand-police-bust-drug-fuelled-party-detain-120-in-underwear-7207711]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:21:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police in Thailand detained more than 120 people found in their underwear at a drug-fuelled party in Bangkok, officers told AFP Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police in Thailand detained more than 120 people found in their underwear at a drug-fuelled party in Bangkok, officers told AFP Monday.</p>

<p>Police Colonel Pansa Amarapitak told AFP that they were tipped off about a "drug party" in a room at a hotel in central Bangkok early on Sunday morning.</p>

<p>Police photos showed a room full of mostly male suspects in handcuffs and wearing nothing but underpants as officers searched them for drugs.</p>

<p>They found 31 of the 124 people arrested were in possession of illegal narcotics such as crystal methamphetamine, ecstasy and ketamine, Pansa said.</p>

<p>He added that all of them tested for the substances and 66 were found with traces in their system.</p>

<p>He said all except two were men, and around five were foreigners.</p>

<p>Police are seeking the courts' permission to hold those suspected of drug possession for questioning beyond the 48-hour window, Pansa told AFP Monday.</p>

<p>The rest have been released, Pansa told AFP.</p>

<p>Thailand is a major hub for illegal drug trafficking in Southeast Asia, and police raids and seizures of hard narcotics like heroin and methamphetamine are common.</p>

<p>The UN Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) said a record 190 tonnes of methamphetamine were seized in East and Southeast Asia last year.</p>

<p>Thailand has tough anti-drugs laws.</p>

<p>Possession of category one drugs, which include ecstasy and methamphetamine, can bring jail sentences of up to 10 years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/ojpk0nt8_bangkok-the-capital-of-thailand_625x300_23_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thailand is a major hub for illegal drug trafficking in Southeast Asia. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/war-cant-be-finished-zelensky-on-trumps-call-for-immediate-ceasefire-7207590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["War Can't Be Finished...": Zelensky On Trump's Call For Immediate Ceasefire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/war-cant-be-finished-zelensky-on-trumps-call-for-immediate-ceasefire-7207590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:05:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky has reportedly rejected his incoming US counterpart Donald Trump's call for an immediate ceasefire, saying Kyiv would not accept any peace agreement without security guarantees.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky has reportedly rejected his incoming US counterpart Donald Trump's call for an immediate ceasefire, saying Kyiv would not accept any peace agreement without security guarantees. The US President-elect had earlier called for an "immediate ceasefire" between Russian and Ukrainian forces and called for talks to begin.</p>

<p>However, In a post on Telegram, Mr Zelensky said the conflict with Moscow cannot be ended with "just a piece of paper and a few signatures". &nbsp;"War should not be endless," he wrote, adding "peace should be permanent and reliable."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Zelensky met the incoming US President in Paris on Saturday with French leader Emmanuel Macron at the Elysee. The meeting came amid concerns that Mr Trump could "probably" reduce aid to Ukraine.</p>

<h2><strong>What Trump Said?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>In an interview aired Sunday but recorded before the Saturday meeting, Mr Trump, said his incoming administration would reduce aid to Ukraine, which Washington has been steadfastly backing since its invasion by Russia nearly three years ago.</p>

<p>Mr Trump, in an interview aired Sunday but recorded before the Saturday meeting, said his incoming administration would reduce aid to Ukraine, which Washington has been steadfastly backing since its invasion by Russia nearly three years ago.</p>

<p>"Possibly. Yeah, probably, sure," Mr Trump told NBC's "Meet the Press". He also boasted that he could end the conflict swiftly without saying how.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Trump, earlier, called for an "immediate ceasefire" and called for talks to begin. "Too many lives are being so needlessly wasted, too many families destroyed, and if it keeps going, it can turn into something much bigger, and far worse," he wrote on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>He also said he has good relations with Putin. Meanwhile, Moscow and Kyiv are readying for his arrival in the White House, with an escalation in deadly attacks in recent weeks in the drawn-out conflict.</p>

<h2><strong>What&nbsp;Zelensky Said?</strong></h2>

<p>After the meeting, the Ukrainian leader on Sunday said Kyiv needed an "enduring" peace to protect it from Russia. Mr Zelensky, who had previously opposed any territorial concessions, has eased his position in recent months. His army is struggling on the front line and fears are mounting of dwindling Western aid. He has even floated the idea of temporarily forgoing Russian-controlled areas -- about one-fifth of Ukraine -- in exchange for NATO security guarantees and weapons deliveries from the West.</p>

<p>"I stated that we need a just and enduring peace -- one that the Russians will not be able to destroy in a few years, as they have done repeatedly in the past," Mr Zelensky said in a social media post.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Almost three years of war have ravaged Ukraine, killing thousands and leading millions to flee the country. &nbsp;"Ukrainians want peace more than anyone else," said Mr Zelensky. "Russia brought war to our land, and it is Russia that most seeks to disrupt the possibility of peace".</p>

<p>He called on Western allies not to "turn a blind eye to occupation" and said Kyiv would only agree to a deal that would bring long-term peace.</p>

<p>"War cannot be endless -- only peace must be permanent and reliable," he said.</p>

<p>In a rare admission of numbers, Mr Zelensky said 43,000 Ukrainian troops had been killed in combat, while some 370,000 were wounded.</p>

<p>"This is what this war is all about," Mr Zelensky wrote. "It cannot be finished with just a piece of paper and a few signatures...War should not be endless," he wrote, adding &nbsp;"peace should be permanent and reliable."</p>

<h2><strong>Russia's Stand</strong></h2>

<p>The Kremlin, meanwhile, accused Ukraine of "refusing" to negotiate an end to the war. It said its conditions to enter peace talks -- which include Kyiv giving up four regions -- remain unchanged.</p>

<p>"The Ukrainian side refused and is refusing negotiation," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said. He referred to a 2022 Ukrainian decree that ruled out talks with Putin, but not other Russian officials.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ap1umamo_donald-trump-volodymyr-zelensky-reuters_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump met Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky in Paris on Saturday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attacks-on-religious-places-regrettable-indian-foreign-secretary-after-high-level-meet-in-dhaka-7207489]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Attacks On Religious Places Regrettable": India's Plainspeak With Dhaka]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attacks-on-religious-places-regrettable-indian-foreign-secretary-after-high-level-meet-in-dhaka-7207489]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:51:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said today that he conveyed New Delhi's concerns to Dhaka over the attacks on minorities in Bangladesh.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said today that he conveyed New Delhi's concerns to Dhaka over the attacks on minorities in Bangladesh. In a meeting with Bangladeshi Foreign Adviser Mohammad Touhid Hossain, Mr Misri conveyed that the attacks on religious institutions and places of worship are "regrettable".</p>

<p>Mr Misri also conveyed to Bangladesh's interim government that India wishes to have a "positive, constructive, and mutually beneficial" relationship. Speaking to the media after his high-level meeting, Mr Misri said, "I have underlined today India's desire to work closely with the interim government of Bangladesh Authority."</p>

<p>Speaking about the issue of minorities, Mr Misri said, "We discussed recent developments and I conveyed our concerns including those related to the safety and welfare of minorities. We also discussed regrettable incidents of attacks on cultural and religious properties."</p>

<p>Calling the discussions "frank, candid, and constructive", Mr Misri said the discussions allowed both sides "the opportunity to take stock of our ties".</p>

<p>Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri arrived in Dhaka earlier today for a day-long visit. This was the first high-level meet between the two sides amid strained bilateral ties following the ouster of Bangladesh's Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in August.</p>

<p>Mr Misri first held a meeting with his counterpart - foreign secretary Jashim Uddin. The meeting was held at the state guest house Padma. The two foreign secretaries first held one-on-one talks and then a formal meeting was held where delegates from both sides were present.</p>

<p>Diplomatic ties between India and Bangladesh have faced testing times since the ouster of Sheikh Hasina after a massive anti-government protest in August. Nobel laureate Mohammad Yunus took over as Bangladesh's Chief Adviser days after Ms Hasina fled to India.</p>

<p>Ties between both countries worsened after multiple incidents of violence in Bangladesh targeting the Hindu minority citizens. There has been a sharp rise in incidents of mob violence, vandalism of property, and desecration at places of worship targeting the minorities. To add to this, there has even been a crackdown on Hindu priests by the interim government in Bangladesh. Two Hindu priests are being prosecuted and there are concerns over their captivity.</p>

<p>Dhaka has said that the sporadic violence in Bangladesh was a manifestation of an outburst of anger against the leaders and activists of the ousted Hasina regime and the Hindus who were harassed were related to her Awami League party and violence had nothing to do with their religious faith.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rjtlapjc_vikram-misri-bangladesh-foreign-adviser-md-touhid-hossain_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri today met Bangladesh Foreign Adviser Mohammad Touhid Hossain]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>