<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 10:35:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nancy-pelosi-says-us-should-add-joe-biden-to-mount-rushmore-consequential-president-6265638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nancy Pelosi Says Joe Biden's Face Should Be Added To Mount Rushmore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nancy-pelosi-says-us-should-add-joe-biden-to-mount-rushmore-consequential-president-6265638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 10:20:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["You have Teddy Roosevelt up there. And he's wonderful. I don't say take him down. But you can add Biden," the 84-year-old said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi has suggested that the country should add President Joe Biden's sculpture to Mount Rushmore, an iconic monument which features four former presidents including George Washington, Thomas Jefferson, Abraham Lincoln and Theodore Roosevelt. Ms Pelosi said that the 81-year-old is "such a consequential president of the United States, a Mount Rushmore kind of president," in a clip aired on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://youtu.be/nSFiel_2tvQ?si=8b5Zja-20DlesvD_">CBS Sunday Morning Show.</a></p>

<p>"You have Teddy Roosevelt up there. And he's wonderful. I don't say take him down. But you can add Biden," the 84-year-old said when asked if Mr Biden deserved to have his face permanently etched in rock at the renowned South Dakota national monument. Notably, the monument was completed in 1941, a year before Mr Biden was born.</p>

<p>This comes as Joe Biden quit the presidential race a few weeks ago after some reports claimed that Ms Pelosi told the US President that he could destroy the Democrats' chances of winning elections in November, due to his age. However, the politician defended the reports and said that Mr Biden "was in a good place to make whatever decision - the top of his game."</p>

<p>Notably, after Mr Biden's debate performance against Mr Trump, Ms Pelosi initially supported him, but she then publicly stated that he needed to decide whether to run for reelection, even though he had already declared he was still in. Later, she told MSNBC's 'Morning Joe' that "it is up to the president to decide if he is going to run," two days after Mr Biden even wrote a letter to Democratic members in early July restating that he was "firmly committed" to the race.</p>

<p>According to a report in CNN, the California Representative had reportedly asked Mr Biden's Senior Advisor Mike Donilon to connect her with the President on a call, which would mark the second conversation between the two since Mr Biden's poor performance in the debate with Donald Trump. However, Ms Pelosi denied any such claims. "No, I wasn't the leader of any pressure (campaign). Let me say things that I didn't do: I didn't call one person. I did not call one person. I could always say to him, 'I never called anybody.' "</p>

<p>"No. My whole point was whatever he decides, but we have to have a more aggressive campaign," she said. "What I'm saying is I had confidence the president would make the proper choice of a country, whatever that would be - and I said that - whatever that is, we'll go with," Ms Pelosi added.</p>

<p>According to reports, the US President seems to be enraged with Ms Pelosi over her alleged involvement in sabotaging his re-election campaign. Responding to the same, the American politician added that "he knows that I love him very much." The former Speaker also stated that she has "never shared any conversations with the president of the United States publicly."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/oft8phko_nancy-pelosi-suggests-biden-be-added-to-mount-rushmore-amid-rumours-of-rift_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The monument was completed in 1941, a year before Mr Biden was born.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-awami-league-explained-what-led-to-bangladesh-protests-that-has-seen-over-300-killed-6265524]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Led To Bangladesh Protests That Has Seen Over 300 Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-awami-league-explained-what-led-to-bangladesh-protests-that-has-seen-over-300-killed-6265524]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 09:55:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the two separate terms and 20 years that she has been the Prime Minister of Bangladesh, the ongoing protests that have seen over 300 people killed, is perhaps Sheikh Hasina's biggest test.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the two separate terms and 20 years that she has been the Prime Minister of Bangladesh, the ongoing protests that have seen over 300 people killed, is perhaps Sheikh Hasina's biggest test. At least 98 people were killed and hundreds injured in Bangladesh on Sunday as police used tear gas and rubber bullets to disperse tens of thousands demanding the resignation of PM Hasina. The violence marked one of the deadliest days in Bangladesh's recent history of civil unrest, surpassing the 67 deaths reported on July 19 when students protested against the quota system for government jobs.</p>

<p>But what has led to the deadly unrest across Bangladesh?</p>

<p>The protests, which began late last month, escalated dramatically when student activists at Dhaka University, the largest in the country, clashed violently with police and pro-government counter-protesters. The roots of these protests lie in a controversial quota system, which reserves up to 30 per cent of government jobs for family members of veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 war of independence against Pakistan.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Bangladesh Police uses tear gas against protesters. " id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fg055fbo_bangladesh-protests-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg" title="Bangladesh Police uses tear gas against protesters. " /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Bangladesh Police uses tear gas against protesters.<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>Protesters argue that this system is discriminatory and favours supporters of Prime Minister Hasina's Awami League party. They advocate for a merit-based system to replace the existing quota.</p>

<p>The quota system, established in 1972 and briefly abolished in 2018 before being reinstated, has been a persistent source of contention. Critics claim it unfairly benefits Awami League supporters and limits opportunities for other qualified candidates. Prime Minister Hasina's public remarks further inflamed the situation, leading to intensified protests.</p>

<p>The protests have evolved beyond the quota issue into a broader anti-government movement, drawing support from diverse sections of society, including film stars, musicians, and even garment manufacturers. Rap songs and social media campaigns have amplified the calls for Hasina's resignation.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Hasina, who has ruled since 2009 and secured a fourth consecutive term in January through elections boycotted by the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party, faces accusations of entrenching power through state institutions and suppressing dissent. The recent violence highlights the growing dissatisfaction and demands for change among the Bangladeshi populace.</p>

<h2><strong>Rapid Escalation</strong></h2>

<p>The protesting students have announced a "March To Dhaka" programme today.</p>

<p>Houses of public representatives, 20 Awami League offices, police stations and other government installations were attacked, vandalised and torched in 39 districts. Clashes between protesters and leaders of the Awami League and its associate organisations were reported in several districts.</p>

<p>Residences and offices of ruling party ministers, state ministers, parliamentarians and Awami League leaders were vandalised in at least 14 different locations.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Several buildings were set on fire during the ongoing protests. " id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8qd6fj9g_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg" title="Several buildings were set on fire during the ongoing protests. " /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Several buildings were set on fire during the ongoing protests.<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>In response to the unrest, the government declared an indefinite nationwide curfew starting at 6 pm on Sunday, the first such step during the current wave of protests. A three-day general holiday was also announced starting Monday. Additionally, the government shut down internet services.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Demonstrators blocked major highways and launched a non-cooperation program, escalating the violence nationwide. Police stations and ruling party offices became targets, with reports of severe clashes and significant casualties. Thirteen policemen were beaten to death in Sirajganj, and homes of two lawmakers were set on fire.</p>

<p>The unrest was not confined to Dhaka but spread across the country. In the central district of Munsiganj, two construction workers were killed, and 30 injured during a three-way clash involving protesters, police, and ruling party activists.</p>

<p>Further clashes in Pabna, Feni, Lakshmipur, Narsingdi, Rangpur, Magura, and other districts resulted in additional casualties. In Dhaka, a hospital was vandalised, and four garment factories were set on fire. The government's decision to shut down high-speed internet services, including social media platforms, added to the chaos.</p>

<h2><strong>Government Orders&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Bangladesh's telecom providers were instructed to shut down 4G services, effectively disabling internet access. The protests initially paused after the Supreme Court scrapped most quotas, but resumed sporadically, demanding justice for those killed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bangladesh's Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman directed officers to ensure the security of lives, properties, and state installations. Despite this, protesters continued to defy the curfew, leading to further clashes and casualties.</p>

<p>The international community, including India, has advised nationals against travelling to Bangladesh.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dt6m1368_bangladesh-protests-_625x300_21_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protests which began last month have escalated dramatically recently.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-airlines-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-passenger-spot-lice-in-womans-hair-6265317]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Flight Makes Emergency Landing After Lice Spotted In Woman's Hair]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-airlines-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-passenger-spot-lice-in-womans-hair-6265317]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 09:11:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Upon landing, passengers were informed of a 12-hour delay and were given hotel vouchers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Los Angeles-New York American Airlines flight made an emergency landing in Phoenix after passengers saw lice crawling in a woman's hair mid-air.&nbsp;A passenger on the flight, Ethan Judelson, shared his experience on TikTok, describing the confusion and uncertainty among passengers. He said that the crew provided minimal information about the diversion, leaving passengers puzzled. According to<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/plane-grounded-in-emergency-landing-after-passengers-see-lice-exclusive-8686592"> People</a></em>, the incident happened in June.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In his video, Mr Judelson described the scene: "I look around, no one's on the ground, no one's freaking out. I'm like, it can't be that dire. But we land, and as soon as we land, this woman across the aisle from me shoots up and rushes to the front of the plane."</p>

<p>After the plane made an emergency landing, Mr&nbsp;Judelson&nbsp;overheard hushed conversations among fellow passengers. According to eyewitnesses, two passengers had spotted lice crawling out of a woman's hair, prompting them to alert the flight attendants.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Apparently those two girls, they saw bugs crawling out of the woman's hair ... and alerted the flight attendant," Mr Judelson said in the TikTok video.</p>

<p>Upon landing, passengers were informed of a 12-hour delay and were given hotel vouchers.</p>

<p id="mntl-sc-block_23-0">"Right when we land in Phoenix we all get the email saying, 'Here's your voucher for the hotel.' And we're like, 'Hotel, are we staying here?' Mr Judelson, added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;American Airlines later issued a statement confirming that the flight was diverted due to a medical emergency.</p>

<p>In a statement issued to <em>People</em>, a spokesperson for American Airlines said, "On June 15, American Airlines flight 2201 with service from Los Angeles (LAX) to New York (JFK) diverted to Phoenix (PHX) due to the medical needs of a customer."</p>

<p>Fortunately, the passengers did eventually make it to Los Angeles.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/li80rstg_american-airlines_625x300_13_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The flight was delayed by 12 hours.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-once-dropped-a-dead-bear-in-new-yorks-central-park-6265237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Robert Kennedy Jr Once Dropped A Dead Bear In New York's Central Park]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-once-dropped-a-dead-bear-in-new-yorks-central-park-6265237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 08:53:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Independent US presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr said in a video posted online on Sunday that he dumped a dead bear in New York City's Central Park a decade ago and staged it to look like a bike had hit it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Independent US presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr said in a video posted online on Sunday that he dumped a dead bear in New York City's Central Park a decade ago and staged it to look like a bike had hit it.</p>

<p>Kennedy suggested in the video, which was posted on social media platform X, that he is trying to get ahead of a not-yet-published story from the New Yorker.</p>

<p>"Looking forward to seeing how you spin this one, @NewYorker..." Kennedy posted on his X account with a video of himself at a kitchen table talking to comedian Roseanne Barr.</p>

<p>Kennedy said in the video that he was driving to the Hudson Valley in New York state when a woman in a van in front of him hit a young bear and killed it. He put the bear's body into the back of his car because he was going to skin the bear and store its meat at his house, he said.</p>

<p>But after a late dinner in New York City at the Peter Luger Steak House, he had to go straight to the airport and did not want to leave the bear in his vehicle.</p>

<p>"I had an old bike in my car that somebody asked me to get rid of. I said, 'Let's go put the bear in Central Park and we'll make it look like he got hit by a bike,'" he said and then laughed, saying it would be "amusing" for whoever found it.</p>

<p>The Kennedy campaign did not immediately comment further on the incident.</p>

<p>In October 2014, the body of a black bear cub was found in the bushes of Central Park and police launched a criminal investigation into the death.</p>

<p>Foul play was suspected in the case, Reuters reported at the time, and state wildlife officials later concluded it was likely struck and killed by a vehicle.</p>

<p>Kennedy said in the video that the New Yorker had asked him about the incident and was planning on doing a "big article" about him.</p>

<p>The New Yorker did not immediately respond to an emailed request for comment.</p>

<p>In a recent Reuters/Ipsos poll, Kennedy was favored by 8% of voters. He has yet to qualify for the ballot in many states ahead of the Nov. 5 election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/h3r1nft8_robert-kennedy-jr_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Kennedy campaign did not immediately comment further on the incident.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-raises-terror-threat-level-from-possible-to-probable-6265030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia Raises Terror Threat Level From "Possible" To "Probable"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-raises-terror-threat-level-from-possible-to-probable-6265030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 07:59:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia on Monday raised its terror threat level to "probable" from "possible", citing an increase in extremist views in the country leading to a more than 50% chance of the planning of an onshore attack in the next 12 months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia on Monday raised its terror threat level to "probable" from "possible", citing an increase in extremist views in the country leading to a more than 50% chance of the planning of an onshore attack in the next 12 months.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said he had raised the country's threat level following advice from security services, but said there was no imminent threat of an attack.</p>

<p>"The advice that we have received is that more Australians are embracing a more diverse range of extreme ideologies and it is our responsibility to be vigilant," he told a news conference.</p>

<p>Australia lowered the threat level to "possible" in 2022, following eight years at "probable".</p>

<p>Mike Burgess, director general of the Australian Security Intelligence Organisation, the country's main intelligence agency, said tensions in the Middle East, including a conflict between Israel and Hamas that began on Oct. 7, were a contributing factor to raising the threat level.</p>

<p>"The conflict has fuelled grievances, promoted protests, undermined social cohesion and elevated intolerance," he said.</p>

<p>Australia has seen several violent attacks in recent months, some of which have been designated as motivated by extremism.</p>

<p>In April Australian police said a knife attack on an Assyrian church bishop and some of his followers in Sydney was a terrorist act motivated by suspected religious extremism.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-07/t8d2vrek_australia-generic-sydney-generic-sydney-opera-house-pixabay_625x300_29_July_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia lowered the threat level to "possible" in 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dostoevsky-to-proust-pope-francis-lists-his-favourite-authors-6265026]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dostoevsky To Proust, Pope Francis Lists His Favourite Authors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dostoevsky-to-proust-pope-francis-lists-his-favourite-authors-6265026]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 07:54:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pope Francis's bookish side emerged Sunday, after the Vatican published a letter in which the pontiff encouraged young priests to read --- while revealing that he himself likes the great tragedies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pope Francis's bookish side emerged Sunday, after the Vatican published a letter in which the pontiff encouraged young priests to read --- while revealing that he himself likes the great tragedies.</p>

<p>"How can we speak to the hearts of men and women if we ignore, set aside or fail to appreciate the 'stories' by which they sought to express and lay bare the drama of their lived experience in novels and poems," asked the pontiff in his July 17 letter to priests-to-be, published by the Vatican on Sunday in eight languages.</p>

<p>In the lengthy text -- peppered with references to literary greats like CS Lewis, Marcel Proust, TS Eliot and fellow Argentinian Jorge Luis Borges -- Francis argued that reading was "part of one's path to personal maturity" and therefore crucial not just for those joining the priesthood but all Christians in general.</p>

<p>Noting that Paul the Apostle was a reader, Francis plugged for time spent reading, noting that a good book can "(keep) us from other choices that are less wholesome" and open up minds "trapped by a few obsessive thoughts".</p>

<p>"In moments of weariness, anger, disappointment or failure, when prayer itself does not help us find inner serenity, a good book can help us weather the storm until we find peace of mind," wrote the 87-year-old Argentine Jesuit.</p>

<p>The pope -- whose tastes also run to jazz and soccer -- has sometimes dropped clues as to his preferred reading lists.</p>

<p>He has mentioned Dostoevsky as a favourite author and confessed to having read Italy's seminal 1827 novel "The Betrothed", three times, calling author Alessandro Manzoni the champion of "victims and those who come in last".</p>

<p>In a speech about artificial intelligence to the G7 in June, Francis cited Robert Hugh Benson's 1907 dystopian novel "Lord of the World": "It's nice to read it, it's interesting," he told the Group of Seven leaders.</p>

<p>In his letter to young priests, Francis pointed out that reading -- which he noted requires greater personal engagement than watching films or television -- improves one's vocabulary, develops intellectual capacity and reduces stress and anxiety.</p>

<p>He said he regretted that literature was considered non-essential in the training of priests.</p>

<h3><strong>An 'open mind'</strong></h3>

<p>"We desperately need to counterbalance this inevitable temptation to a frenetic and uncritical lifestyle by stepping back, slowing down, taking time to look and listen. This can happen when a person simply stops to read a book," wrote the pope.</p>

<p>In a personal aside, Francis recalled teaching high school literature at a Jesuit school at the age of 28, encountering resistance from students who did not want to read certain selections.</p>

<p>Arguing that even difficult or boring texts had value, the pope said people should approach reading with "an open mind" and "a willingness to be surprised."</p>

<p>"I, for my part, love the tragedians, because we can all embrace their works as our own, as expressions of our own personal drama," he said.</p>

<p>"In weeping for the fate of their characters, we are essentially weeping for ourselves, for our own emptiness, shortcomings and loneliness."</p>

<p>Seeing life through the eyes of others through literature leads to greater perspective and greater humanity as readers step out of their own lives to enter that of others, Francis wrote.</p>

<p>"We are caught up in the lives of the fruit seller, the prostitute, the orphaned child, the bricklayer's wife, the old crone who still believes she will someday find her prince charming," he said.</p>

<p>Immersing oneself in the thoughts and fears of characters facing daunting challenges has hidden benefits, wrote Francis.</p>

<p>"Perhaps too, in following a story to the end, we gain insights that will later prove helpful in our own lives."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/dpgb6ld_pope-francis_625x300_14_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pope Francis has mentioned Dostoevsky as a favourite author.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-sheikh-hasina-students-protest-over-job-quota-nearly-100-killed-in-fierce-clashes-in-bangladesh-curfew-imposed-10-facts-6264931]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh On The Boil Again, 98 Killed, Indefinite Curfew: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-sheikh-hasina-students-protest-over-job-quota-nearly-100-killed-in-fierce-clashes-in-bangladesh-curfew-imposed-10-facts-6264931]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 07:25:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The overall death count from fierce clashes in Bangladesh has risen to over 300, after 98 people died yesterday in the deadliest day in weeks of anti-government demonstrations. The violence-hit country is set for more protests today,]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Bangladesh braced for another tense day as protestors returned to the streets demanding the resignation of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, with analysts fearing violence could surpass what was seen yesterday.</li>
	<li>Dozens were also injured in fierce clashes yesterday.&nbsp;With 98 deaths yesterday, the count since protests began in July has climbed to about 300.</li>
	<li>The Bangladesh Home Ministry decided to impose an indefinite countrywide curfew amid fierce clashes and mobile internet was tightly restricted countrywide.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>A three-day general holiday has been declared on Monday, Tuesday and Wednesday to ensure public safety amid the ongoing violent protests across the country.</li>
	<li>Just days ago, over 200 people were killed in violent clashes between the police and mostly student protesters demanding an end to the controversial quota system that reserved 30 per cent of government jobs for relatives of veterans who fought in Bangladesh's War of Independence in 1971.</li>
	<li>India has strongly advised all its nationals in Bangladesh to exercise "extreme caution" and restrict their movements.&nbsp;"All Indian nationals including students living in the jurisdiction of the Assistant High Commission of India, Sylhet are requested to be in touch with this office and are advised to remain alert. In case of emergencies, please contact +88-01313076402," the Assistant High Commission said in a post on X.</li>
	<li>The United Nations' human rights chief Volker Turk said the "shocking violence" in Bangladesh must end, as he urged the government to stop targeting peaceful protesters.</li>
	<li>Rallies that began last month against civil service job quotas have escalated into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to step down.</li>
	<li>The demonstrations have grown into a wider anti-government movement across Bangladesh. It has attracted people from all strata of Bangladesh society, including film stars, musicians and singers. Songs calling for people's support have spread widely on social media.</li>
	<li>The protesters have dismissed Ms Hasina's invitation for dialogue aimed at quelling escalating violence and consolidated their demands into a unified call for the government's resignation.</li>
</ol>

<p><em><strong>(With inputs from PTI, AFP)</strong></em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0ktuobpg_bangladesh_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has strongly advised all its nationals in Bangladesh to exercise "extreme caution"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-hezbollah-hamas-iran-could-attack-israel-today-netanyahu-eyes-preemptive-strike-report-6264899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Could Attack Israel Today, Netanyahu Eyes Preemptive Strike: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-hezbollah-hamas-iran-could-attack-israel-today-netanyahu-eyes-preemptive-strike-report-6264899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 07:16:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken has warned his counterparts from the G7 countries that an attack by Iran and Hezbollah against Israel could commence as early as Monday, Axios reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken has warned his counterparts from the G7 countries that an attack by Iran and Hezbollah against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-mossad-hezbollah-abraham-alliance-vs-axis-of-resistance-players-in-israel-iran-shadow-war-6259187">Israel </a>could commence as early as Monday, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/05/iran-hezbollah-attack-israel-monday-blinken">Axios</a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In Israel, however, the leading daily <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/israel-could-preemptively-strike-iran-if-intelligence-shows-attack-is-imminent-report/">Times of Israel </a>reported that the Benjamin Netanyahu-led government could sanction a preemptive strike on Iran to prevent an attack on Israeli soil. According to the report, Israel's leading intelligence agencies Mossad and Shin Bet and their respective heads David Barnea and Ronen Bar, were part of a meeting called by Netanyahu that was also attended by Defence Minister Yoav Gallant and IDF Chief of Staff Herzi Halevi.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hezbollah, established in the early 1980s with Iranian support, represents Iran's first proxy in the Middle East. Funded and armed by the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), Hezbollah shares Tehran's core ideology and recruits primarily from <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/highly-volatile-situation-foreign-nationals-urged-to-leave-lebanon-6261722">Lebanon</a>'s Shiite Muslim population.</p>

<p>Iran on Saturday said that Hezbollah will escalate its attacks deeper into Israeli territory, potentially targeting more than just military installations. The rapid escalation of tensions follows Israel's recent assassination of a senior Hezbollah military commander, Fuad Shukr. On July 30, Israel struck a densely populated residential area in south Beirut, killing Shukr and five civilians.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The situation is further complicated by the assassination of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, a move attributed to Israel, although it has not been confirmed by Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>Concerns have heightened dramatically, as months of cross-border skirmishes risk devolving into a full-scale conflict between Hezbollah and Israel. The two adversaries last engaged in a devastating war in the summer of 2006, which saw Israel bombing Lebanon's only passenger airport in Beirut.</p>

<p>The intensity of the current situation has led various embassies, including India's, to urge their citizens to leave Lebanon while commercial flights remain available.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has maintained near-daily exchanges of fire with Israeli forces, targeting military positions since its Palestinian ally Hamas initiated an attack on Israel on October 7, triggering the ongoing war in Gaza.</p>

<p>In response to these developments, Antony Blinken convened a conference call with G7 foreign ministers to coordinate diplomatic efforts aimed at de-escalating the situation, the report added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n3orjc5g_khameini-netanyahu-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran-Israel conflict: Hezbollah has maintained near-daily exchanges of fire with Israeli forces.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-f-kennedy-jr-says-he-once-dumped-a-dead-bear-in-new-yorks-central-park-6264650]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Robert F Kennedy Jr Says He Once Dumped Dead Bear In New York Central Park]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-f-kennedy-jr-says-he-once-dumped-a-dead-bear-in-new-yorks-central-park-6264650]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 05:50:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The independent US presidential candidate said he and his friends were on a falconing excursion in New York state when a van ahead of him hit and killed a six-month-old black bear.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Robert F Kennedy Jr grossed people out this year with a story about a parasitic worm eating part of his brain. Now he's back with another doozy: about leaving a dead bear cub in New York's Central Park.</p>

<p>The independent US presidential candidate, conspiracy theorist and anti-vaccine activist made the disclosure in a three-minute video posted Sunday on social media as he apparently tried to get out ahead of a New Yorker magazine story that mentions the weird tale of roadkill and stealth from a decade ago.</p>

<p>In the video shot at what looked like a post-meal chat with people including sitcom actress Roseanne Barr, Kennedy recounts the saga:</p>

<p>He and friends were on a falconing excursion in New York state in 2014, Kennedy says, when a van ahead of him hit and killed a six-month-old black bear.</p>

<p>The scion of America's most prominent political family, eager to salvage the corpse for the meat, put it in the back of his own vehicle.</p>

<p>"And you can do that in New York state. You can get a bear tag for roadkill bear," Kennedy, 70, says in a gravelly voice.</p>

<p>But the falconing field trip ran late, so he could not get the remains back to his home in Westchester County.</p>

<p>So did a dinner he attended that evening in the Big Apple, and Kennedy realized he would have to go straight to the airport for a flight he was due to take.</p>

<p>"The bear was in my car, and I didn't want to leave the bear in the car because that would have been bad," he says.</p>

<p>After Kennedy and company brainstormed, they took the carcass to iconic Central Park and left it under an old bicycle Kennedy had in his car.</p>

<p>Kennedy said the plan was to make it look like a cyclist had killed the animal, an admission that drew laughter from people in the video.</p>

<p>"I wasn't drinking, of course, but people were drinking with me who thought this was a good idea," he says.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Then I thought, you know, at that time this was the little bit of the redneck in me," the son of the late Robert F. Kennedy adds.</p>

<p>When the animal's body was eventually found it became a huge news story.</p>

<p>"And I was like, 'Oh my God, what did I do?'" Kennedy says, adding: "I was worried because my prints were all over that bike."</p>

<p>He said the story remained dormant for a decade until a fact-checker from The New Yorker called to verify it for a feature on Kennedy. The piece has yet to be published.</p>

<p>"It's going to be a bad story," Kennedy forecasts with a laugh.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gakueia8_robert-f-kennedy-jr_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-warns-protesters-in-rotherham-you-will-regret-taking-part-in-this-6264460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Anti-Immigration Protests Rage In UK, "You Will Regret," Warns Starmer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-warns-protesters-in-rotherham-you-will-regret-taking-part-in-this-6264460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 04:49:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Unrest related to misinformation about the mass stabbing last Monday in the northwestern English seaside town of Southport has hit multiple towns and cities, with anti-immigration demonstrators clashing with police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer warned far-right protesters on Sunday they would "regret" participating in England's worst rioting in 13 years, as disturbances linked to the murder of three children earlier this week flared across the country.</p>

<p>Masked anti-immigration demonstrators smashed several windows at a hotel that has been used to house asylum seekers in Rotherham, South Yorkshire.</p>

<p>Unrest related to misinformation about the mass stabbing last Monday in the northwestern English seaside town of Southport has hit multiple towns and cities, with anti-immigration demonstrators clashing with police.</p>

<p>The violence is a major challenge for Starmer, elected only a month ago after leading Labour to a landslide win over the Conservatives.</p>

<p>"I guarantee you will regret taking part in this disorder. Whether directly or those whipping up this action online, and then running away themselves," Starmer said in a TV address.</p>

<p>There was "no justification" for what he called "far-right thuggery", he added, promising to bring the perpetrators "to justice".</p>

<h3><strong>Shops looted, burnt</strong></h3>

<p>Footage aired on the BBC showed rioters forcing their way into a Holiday Inn Express in Rotherham. They also pushed a burning bin into the building. It was not clear whether asylum seekers were inside.</p>

<p>Ten officers were injured there, but local police said none of the hotel staff or its clients had been hurt.</p>

<p>In the northeastern English city of Middlesbrough, hundreds of protesters squared up to riot police carrying shields. Some threw bricks, cans and pots at officers.</p>

<p>Protesters there seized a camera from an AFP crew and broke it. The journalists were not injured.</p>

<p>The fresh disturbances came after police said more than 150 people had been arrested since Saturday following skirmishes at far-right rallies in Liverpool, Manchester, Bristol, Blackpool and Hull, as well as Belfast in Northern Ireland.</p>

<p>Rioters threw bricks, bottles and flares at police -- injuring several officers -- and looted and burnt shops, while demonstrators shouted anti-Islamic slurs as they clashed with counter-protesters.</p>

<p>The violence is the worst England has seen since summer 2011, when widespread rioting followed the police killing of a mixed-race man in north London.</p>

<p>Christian, Muslim and Jewish religious leaders in Liverpool issued a joint appeal for calm.</p>

<p>"We're now seeing it (trouble) flooding across major cities and towns," said Tiffany Lynch of the Police Federation of England and Wales.</p>

<p>Late Sunday, Staffordshire police said another hotel known to have sheltered asylum seekers was targeted near Birmingham.</p>

<p>"A large group of individuals" have been "throwing projectiles, smashing windows, starting fires and targeting police" at the hotel in the town of Tamworth, with one officer injured, said the statement.</p>

<p>Riots first flared in Southport late Tuesday following Monday's frenzied knife attack at a Taylor Swift-themed dance party in the northwest coastal city, before spreading up and down England.</p>

<p>They were fuelled by false rumours on social media about the background of British-born 17-year-old suspect Axel Rudakubana, who is accused of killing a six, seven, and nine-year-old, and injuring another 10 people.</p>

<p>Police have blamed the violence on supporters and associated organisations of the English Defence League, an anti-Islam organisation founded 15 years ago whose supporters have been linked to football hooliganism.</p>

<p>Agitators have targeted at least two mosques, and the UK interior ministry announced Sunday it was offering new emergency security to Islamic places of worship.</p>

<p>The rallies have been advertised on far-right social media channels under the banner "Enough is enough".</p>

<p>Participants have waved English and British flags while chanting slogans like "Stop the boats" -- a reference to irregular migrants crossing the Channel to Britain from France.</p>

<p>Anti-fascist demonstrators have held counter-rallies in many cities, including Leeds where they shouted, "Nazi scum off our streets", as the far-right protesters chanted, "You're not English any more".</p>

<p>Not all the gatherings have turned violent. A peaceful one in Aldershot, southern England, on Sunday saw participants hold placards that read "Stop the invasion" and "We're not far right, we're just right".</p>

<p>"People are fed up with being told you should be ashamed if you're white and working class but I'm proud white working class," 41-year-old Karina, who did not give her surname, told AFP in Nottingham on Saturday.</p>

<p>At last month's election, the Reform UK party led by Brexit cheerleader Nigel Farage captured 14 percent of the vote -- one of the largest vote shares for a far-right British party.</p>

<p>Carla Denyer, co-leader of the left-wing Green party, said the unrest should be "a wake-up call to all politicians who have actively promoted or given in" to anti-immigration rhetoric.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t9g1dung_uk-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anti-immigration protest in Rotherham]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mali-cuts-ties-with-ukraine-over-alleged-involvement-in-rebel-attack-6264455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mali Cuts Ties With Ukraine Over Alleged Involvement In Rebel Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mali-cuts-ties-with-ukraine-over-alleged-involvement-in-rebel-attack-6264455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 04:40:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mali is immediately cutting diplomatic ties with Ukraine over comments by a spokesperson for Ukraine's military intelligence agency (GUR) about fighting in its north that killed Malian soldiers and Wagner fighters in late July, it said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mali is immediately cutting diplomatic ties with Ukraine over comments by a spokesperson for Ukraine's military intelligence agency (GUR) about fighting in its north that killed Malian soldiers and Wagner fighters in late July, it said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Mali's northern Tuareg rebels say they killed at least 84 Russian Wagner mercenaries and 47 Malian soldiers over days of fierce fighting in the north of the West African country in what appears to be Wagner's heaviest defeat since it stepped in two years ago to help Mali's military authorities fight insurgent groups.</p>

<p>GUR spokesperson Andriy Yusov has not confirmed Kyiv's involvement in the fighting, but in comments published on public broadcaster Suspilne's website on Monday, July 29, he said the Malian rebels had received the "necessary" information to conduct the attack.</p>

<p>"The rebels received all the necessary information they needed, and not just the information, which allowed (them) to conduct a successful military operation against Russian perpetrators of war crimes. We certainly won't go into details now - you will see more of this in the future," he said.</p>

<p>Mali said it had learned "with deep shock of the subversive remarks."</p>

<p>It said Yusov had "admitted Ukraine's involvement in a cowardly, treacherous and barbaric attack by armed terrorist groups that resulted in the death of members of the Malian Defence and Security Forces."</p>

<p>"The actions taken by the Ukrainian authorities violate the sovereignty of Mali, go beyond the scope of foreign interference, which is already condemnable in itself, and constitute a clear aggression by Mali and support for international terrorism," the Malian government said.</p>

<p>It also cited comments by Ukraine's ambassador to Senegal, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, Ivory Coast and Liberia.</p>

<p>Senegal's foreign minister summoned Ukrainian Ambassador Yurii Pyvovarov on Friday over a video it said the Ukrainian embassy had posted on its Facebook page in which Pyvovarov provided "unequivocal and unqualified support for the terrorist attack" in Mali.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-02/dv237uqo_malian-armed-force-650_625x300_15_February_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-rejects-donald-trumps-offer-to-shift-presidential-debate-6263809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Rejects Donald Trump's Offer To Shift Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-rejects-donald-trumps-offer-to-shift-presidential-debate-6263809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:57:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris has rejected her Republican rival Donald Trump's offer to shift the presidential debate to the Fox News channel, media reports said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris has rejected her Republican rival Donald Trump's offer to shift the presidential debate to the Fox News channel, media reports said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, and President Joe Biden -- who was then in the race to the White House -- agreed in May to participate in two presidential debates. The first was in June, hosted by CNN, and the second - to be hosted by ABC News - was scheduled for September 10.</p>

<p>Biden withdrew from the race last month, following which Vice-President Harris, who is of Indian and African heritage, was declared the 2024 presidential nominee of the ruling Democratic Party after she won enough votes from Democratic delegates in a virtual roll call.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Trump said that he has agreed to an offer from Fox News to hold a debate with Vice President Harris on September 4, shifting from the original plan, CBS News reported.</p>

<p>"I have agreed with FoxNews to debate Kamala Harris on Wednesday, September 4th. The debate was previously scheduled against Sleepy Joe Biden on ABC, but has been terminated in that Biden will no longer be a participant, and I am in litigation against ABC Network and George Slopadopoulos, thereby creating a conflict of interest," he said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Harris took to X to turn down Trump's debate offer on Fox News.</p>

<p>"It's interesting how "any time, any place" becomes "one specific time, one specific safe space." I'll be there on September 10th, like he agreed to. I hope to see him there," Harris said.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign also said it will stick to the original plan for an ABC News debate.</p>

<p>It said that "Donald Trump is running scared" hoping that Fox News will "bail him out" of the debate he had already agreed to with ABC News, according to the report.</p>

<p>"He needs to stop playing games and show up to the debate he already committed to on Sept. 10," the report quoted Michael Tyler, the Harris campaign communication director, as saying.</p>

<p>"The Vice President will be there one way or the other to take the opportunity to speak to a prime-time national audience," Tyler said, adding that the campaign is open to discussing further debates but only after the one both campaigns have already agreed to takes place.</p>

<p>Last month, Harris challenged Trump to a debate, provoking him to say whatever he had "to say to her face".</p>

<p>Harris would face Trump in the general elections on November 5.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris would face Donald Trump in the general elections on November 5.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/india-issues-advisory-for-nationals-in-bangladesh-after-fresh-violence-kills-90-6263773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Issues Advisory For Nationals In Bangladesh After Fresh Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/india-issues-advisory-for-nationals-in-bangladesh-after-fresh-violence-kills-90-6263773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:42:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 90 people, including 14 policemen, were killed on Sunday in fierce clashes between security forces personnel and anti-government protesters in different parts of Bangladesh, according to reports from Dhaka.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Sunday night strongly advised all its nationals presently residing in Bangladesh to exercise "extreme caution" and restrict their movements in the wake of fresh waves of violence in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>In its latest advisory, India also asked its citizens not to travel to Bangladesh till further notice.</p>

<p>At least 90 people, including 14 policemen, were killed on Sunday in fierce clashes between security forces personnel and anti-government protesters in different parts of Bangladesh, according to reports from Dhaka.</p>

<p>The protesters are demanding the resignation of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>"In view of ongoing developments, Indian nationals are strongly advised against travelling to Bangladesh till further notice," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said in the advisory.</p>

<p>"All Indian nationals presently in Bangladesh are advised to exercise extreme caution, restrict their movements and remain in contact with the High Commission of India in Dhaka," it said.</p>

<p>The student protests in Bangladesh started last month against a controversial job quota scheme. The protests now have turned into an anti-government agitation.</p>

<p>On July 25, the MEA said around 6,700 Indian students returned from Bangladesh in view of the situation in that country.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lo91fvag_bangladesh-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protesters are demanding the resignation of Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-claim-first-attack-on-shipping-lanes-in-2-weeks-6263601]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthis Claim First Attack On Shipping Lanes In 2 Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-claim-first-attack-on-shipping-lanes-in-2-weeks-6263601]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:59:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Iran-aligned Houthi movement said on Sunday that it targeted a Liberia-flagged container vessel in the Gulf of Aden, claiming its first attack on shipping lanes since Israel carried out a retaliatory airstrike in Hodeidah port on July 20.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Iran-aligned Houthi movement said on Sunday that it targeted a Liberia-flagged container vessel in the Gulf of Aden, claiming its first attack on shipping lanes since Israel carried out a retaliatory airstrike in Hodeidah port on July 20.</p>

<p>Houthi military spokesperson Yahya Saree said in a televised statement that the MV Groton was attacked by ballistic missiles.</p>

<p>British maritime agency UKMTO and British security firm Ambrey said on Saturday that the vessel was targeted by a missile 125 nautical miles east of Yemen's port of Aden. Both said that no water entry or oil leaks were observed.</p>

<p>Built in 2002, the ship was heading to Djibouti, according to Refinitiv data.</p>

<p>The attack is the first since an apparent lull following Israel's attack on Hodeidah, which occurred a day after a drone launched by the Iranian-backed group hit Israeli economic hub Tel Aviv.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/hkp49t58_houthis-reuters-_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack is the first since an apparent lull following Israel's attack on Hodeidah]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/neuralink-successfully-implanted-in-2nd-patient-working-well-elon-musk-6263559]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Neuralink Successfully Implanted In 2nd Patient, Working Well: Elon Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/neuralink-successfully-implanted-in-2nd-patient-working-well-elon-musk-6263559]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:48:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Neuralink has successfully implanted in a second patient its device designed to give paralyzed patients the ability to use digital devices by thinking alone, according to the startup's owner Elon Musk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Neuralink has successfully implanted in a second patient its device designed to give paralyzed patients the ability to use digital devices by thinking alone, according to the startup's owner Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Neuralink is in the process of testing its device, which is intended to help people with spinal cord injuries. The device has allowed the first patient to play video games, browse the internet, post on social media and move a cursor on his laptop.</p>

<p>Musk, in comments made during a podcast released late on Friday that ran more than eight hours, gave few details about the second participant beyond saying the person had a spinal cord injury similar to the first patient, who was paralyzed in a diving accident. Musk said 400 of the implant's electrodes on the second patient's brain are working. Neuralink on its website states that its implant uses 1,024 electrodes.</p>

<p>"I don't want to jinx it but it seems to have gone extremely well with the second implant," Musk told podcast host Lex Fridman. "There's a lot of signal, a lot of electrodes. It's working very well."</p>

<p>Musk did not disclose when Neuralink performed the second patient's surgery. Musk said he expects Neuralink to provide the implants to eight more patients this year as part of its clinical trials.</p>

<p>The first patient, Noland Arbaugh, was also interviewed on the podcast, along with three Neuralink executives, who gave details about how the implant and the robot-led surgery work.</p>

<p>Before Arbaugh received his implant in January, he used a computer by employing a stick in his mouth to tap the screen of a tablet device. Arbaugh said with the implant he now can merely think about what he wants to happen on the computer screen, and the device makes it happen. He said the device has given him a modicum of independence and reduced his reliance on caregivers.</p>

<p>Arbaugh initially faced issues after his surgery when the tiny wires of his implant retracted, resulting in a sharp reduction in the electrodes that could measure brain signals. Reuters has reported Neuralink was aware of this issue from its animal trials.</p>

<p>Neuralink has said it restored the implant's ability to monitor Arbaugh's brain signals by making changes that included modifying its algorithm to be more sensitive. Arbaugh has improved on his previous world record for the speed at which he can control a cursor with thoughts alone "with only roughly 10, 15% of the electrodes working," Musk said on the podcast.</p>

<p>Musk also said he has spoken with Republican candidate Donald Trump, who he has endorsed in the U.S. presidential race, about forming a commission aimed at improving "government efficiency" through reduced business regulation, and would be willing to participate. Musk said that in his view U.S. regulations hamper innovation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pnvon14o_elon-musk-neuralink_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk said he expects Neuralink to provide the implants to eight more patients this year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/would-be-foolish-not-to-have-good-relations-with-army-says-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-6263380]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Would Be "Foolish" Not To Have Good Relations With Army, Says Imran Khan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/would-be-foolish-not-to-have-good-relations-with-army-says-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-6263380]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:12:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's jailed former prime minister, Imran Khan, who blames the military for his ouster and 12-month-old imprisonment on what he calls trumped-up charges, said on Sunday it would be "foolish" not to have "excellent" relations with the army.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Pakistan's jailed former prime minister, Imran Khan, who blames the military for his ouster and 12-month-old imprisonment on what he calls trumped-up charges, said on Sunday it would be "foolish" not to have "excellent" relations with the army.</p>

<p>Ahead of Monday's anniversary of his jailing on dozens of charges ranging from corruption to leaking state secrets, Khan also said in written responses to Reuters questions that he held no grudges against the United States, whom he has also blamed for his 2022 ouster from office.</p>

<p>"Given Pakistan's geographical position and the military's significant role in the private sector, it would be foolish not to foster such a relationship," Imran Khan wrote in replies relayed by his media and legal team.</p>

<p>"We are proud of our soldiers and armed forces," he said.</p>

<p>Imran Khan said his criticisms since his ouster had been directed at individuals, not the military as an institution. "The miscalculations of the military leadership shouldn't be held against the institution as a whole."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Imran Khan offered to hold "conditional negotiations" with the South Asian nation's military - if "clean and transparent" elections were held and the "bogus" cases against his supporters were dropped.</p>

<p>Pakistan's army and government did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Imran Khan's remarks to Reuters. They have both repeatedly denied his assertions.</p>

<p>The United States denies any role in his ouster.</p>

<p>In his replies, the 71-year-old former cricket star did not specify what he wanted to discuss with the military.</p>

<p>'OPEN TO ANY DIALOGUE' WITH ARMY</p>

<p>The army, which has ruled Pakistan for more than half its 76-year independent history, plays an oversized role in the politics and governance of the nation of 240 million people.</p>

<p>No Pakistani prime minister has completed a full five-year term in office, and most have served time in jail. Analysts say most of those secured their release after striking deals with the military, a claim the army denies.</p>

<p>Imran Khan, who lost power in a parliamentary vote of no confidence after falling out with the generals, has said the army has been backing what he calls the politically motivated cases against him, which the military has denied.</p>

<p>Still, he said, there would be "no harm" in engaging with the generals if he should be released from jail and seek to return to power.</p>

<p>"We are open to any dialogue that could help improve the dire situation in Pakistan," he said, adding that it was useless to open any such talks with the coalition government of Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif, which he says does not enjoy public backing because he claims it won a stolen election in February.</p>

<p>Rather, Imran Khan said, it would be "more productive to engage with those who actually wield power".</p>

<p>The military - which says Imran Khan and his party were behind attacks on military installations last year during widespread protests against his detention - has previously ruled out any talks with him.</p>

<p>Imran Khan's imprisonment has added to the political volatility in Pakistan, which has experienced a prolonged economic crisis and last month received a bailout from the International Monetary Fund.</p>

<p>The political instability since Imran Khan's ouster from power helped force Islamabad to accept the IMF's painful fiscal consolidation requirements, which have burdened the people with heavy taxes, analysts say.</p>

<p>The IMF has called for political stability to help put the $350 billion economy on a recovery path.</p>

<p>Imran Khan rejected the idea of reaching an out-of-court settlement with the government or military, unless they accepted that his PTI party had won a majority in February's election.</p>

<p>"The elections were the most rigged in Pakistan's history," Imran Khan told Reuters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jbg3lne_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The elections were the most rigged in Pakistan's history," said Imran Khan (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/30-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-2-schools-says-gaza-agency-6262853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[30 Killed After Israeli Strike Hits 2 Schools, Says Gaza Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/30-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-2-schools-says-gaza-agency-6262853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 21:36:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli strike hit two schools in Gaza City on Sunday, killing at least 30 people, while the military reported it had struck Hamas command centres.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli strike hit two schools in Gaza City on Sunday, killing at least 30 people, while the military reported it had struck Hamas command centres.</p>

<p>These bring to at least 11 the number of schools in Gaza to be struck since July 6, killing around 150 people, based on a tally of tolls previously given by officials in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p>"The number of martyrs in the massacre of the Hassan Salameh and Al-Nasr schools' bombing has risen to 30. Dozens were also wounded," civil defence spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP.</p>

<p>Bassal said most of the dead and wounded were women and children.</p>

<p>He said the schools were housing Palestinians displaced from their homes in the ongoing war between Israel and Hamas operatives.</p>

<p>Israel's military confirmed the strike targeting the two schools.</p>

<p>"The schools were used by Hamas' Al-Furqan Battalion as a hiding place for its terrorist operatives and as command centres," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>On Saturday, a similar Israeli strike hit another school compound in Gaza City, killing at least 17 people, according to the civil defence agency.</p>

<p>The Israeli military has repeatedly accused Hamas of using civilian facilities as command and control centres or to hide their commanders and operatives. The Palestinian group denies the accusation.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began when Hamas operatives attacked Israel on October 7, resulting in the death of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Operatives also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held hostage in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed at least 39,583 people, according to the territory's health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza, which does not give details of civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mahmud Bassal said most of the dead and wounded were women and children. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-f-16-fighter-jets-arrive-in-ukraine-zelensky-says-we-did-it-6262746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: F-16 Fighter Jets Arrive In Ukraine, Zelensky Says "We Did It"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-f-16-fighter-jets-arrive-in-ukraine-zelensky-says-we-did-it-6262746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 21:19:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian pilots have started flying F-16s for operations within the nation, President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Sunday, confirming the long-awaited arrival of the U.S.-made fighter jets more than 29 months since Russia's invasion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian pilots have started flying F-16s for operations within the nation, President Volodymyr Zelensky said on Sunday, confirming the long-awaited arrival of the U.S.-made fighter jets more than 29 months since Russia's invasion.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian leader announced the use of F-16s, which Kyiv has long lobbied for, as he met military pilots at an air base flanked by two of the jets with two more flying overhead.</p>

<p>"F-16s are in Ukraine. We did it. I am proud of our guys who are mastering these jets and have already started using them for our country," Zelensky said at a location that authorities asked Reuters not to disclose for security reasons.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are now in a new phase of development for the Air Force of the Armed Forces of Ukraine. We have done a lot to transition the Ukrainian Air Force to a new aviation standard  Western combat aviation. From the beginning of this war, we have been talking with our partners about <a href="https://t.co/z21yTU0Hjo">pic.twitter.com/z21yTU0Hjo</a></p>
 Volodymyr Zelenskyy /   (@ZelenskyyUa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1820097797556765019?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The arrival of the jets is a milestone for Ukraine after many months of waiting, though it remains unclear how many are available and how much of an impact they will have in enhancing air defences and on the battlefield.</p>

<p>Russia has been targeting bases that may house them and vowed to shoot them down so they will not impact the war.</p>

<p>Built by Lockheed Martin, the F-16s had been on Ukraine's wish list for a long time because of their destructive power and global availability. They are equipped with a 20mm cannon and can carry bombs, rockets and missiles.</p>

<p>Talking to reporters on the tarmac of an airfield, Zelenskiy said Ukraine still did not have enough pilots trained to use the F-16s or enough of the jets themselves.</p>

<p>"The positive thing is that we are expecting additional F-16s ... many guys are now training," he said.</p>

<p>It was important, he said, that Kyiv's allies found ways to expand training programmes and opportunities for both Ukrainian pilots and engineering teams.</p>

<p><strong>'NEW AVIATION STANDARD'</strong></p>

<p>Ukraine has previously relied on an ageing fleet of Soviet-era warplanes that are outgunned by Russia's more advanced and far more numerous fleet.</p>

<p>Russia has used that edge to conduct regular long-range missile strikes on targets across Ukraine and also to pound Ukrainian front line positions with thousands of guided bombs, supporting its forces that are slowly advancing in the east.</p>

<p>"This is the new stage of development of the air force of Ukraine's armed forces," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>"We did a lot for Ukrainian forces to transition to a new aviation standard, the Western combat aviation," he added, citing hundreds of meetings and unrelenting diplomacy to obtain the F-16s.</p>

<p>"We often heard 'it is impossible' as an answer but we still made our ambition, our defensive need, possible," he said.</p>

<p>It remains unclear what missiles the jets are equipped with. A longer range of missile would allow them to have a greater battlefield impact, military analysts say.</p>

<p>Zelensky said he also hoped to lobby allied neighbouring countries to help intercept Russian missiles being launched at Ukraine through conversations at the Ukraine-NATO Council platform.</p>

<p>"This is another tool, and I want to try it, so that NATO countries can talk to Ukraine about the possibility of a small coalition of neighbouring countries shooting down enemy missiles," he said.</p>

<p>"I think this decision is probably difficult for our partners, they are always afraid of excessive escalation but we are fighting that."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q99mffu8_zelenskiy-fighter-jet_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I am proud of our guys who are mastering these jets," said Volodymyr Zelenskiy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-reveals-steve-jobs-called-for-investment-tips-ignored-advice-6262623]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Warren Buffett Reveals Steve Jobs Called For Investment Tips, Ignored Advice]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-reveals-steve-jobs-called-for-investment-tips-ignored-advice-6262623]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 20:57:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jobs decided not to follow Mr Buffett's advice. "He didn't do anything, and of course, he didn't want to do anything. He just liked having the cash."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following the release of Apple's Q3 earnings report, which exceeded expectations, a story from 2012 has resurfaced about Steve Jobs seeking investment advice from legendary American investor Warren Buffett regarding Apple's cash reserves.</p>

<p>In a 2012 interview with <em>CNBC</em>, Mr Buffett recalled a memorable phone call he had with Mr Jobs two years prior. "It was an interesting conversation because I hadn't talked to him in a long time," said the Berkshire Hathaway chairman. Mr Jobs had reached out for advice on managing Apple's significant cash reserves. "He said, 'We've got all this cash. What should we do with it?' So we went over the options."</p>

<p>Mr Buffett explained that companies typically have four choices for utilizing cash: stock buybacks, dividends, acquisitions, or holding onto it. Mr Jobs made it clear that Apple wouldn't pursue large acquisitions requiring substantial cash.</p>

<p>"I went through the logic of each option. He told me they would not have the opportunity for big acquisitions that would require lots of money," Mr Buffett said during the interview. When Buffett suggested stock buybacks if Apple believed its stock was undervalued, Mr Jobs replied, "I think my stock is very undervalued."</p>

<p>Ultimately, Mr Jobs decided not to follow Mr Buffett's advice. "He didn't do anything, and of course, he didn't want to do anything. He just liked having the cash," Mr Buffett said with a laugh. "It was very interesting to me because I later learned that he said I agreed with him to do nothing with the cash."</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Bill Gates, the founder of Microsoft in an interview with Dax Shepard said, "Steve Jobs was a natural. It was always fun to watch him rehearse because part of his genius was when he would finally do it, he would make it look like he's just thinking it up right there," he said. &nbsp;"I'll never achieve that level," Mr Gates added.</p>

<p>During the podcast, Mr Gates stated that he and Mr Jobs were travelling the world in their respective capacities as representatives of Microsoft and Apple and that their task was to convince individuals and organisations of the potential benefits that tools like spreadsheets and email could have for their daily lives and careers.</p>

<p>"We even called it evangelization. Some people might not like that we stole a term of religion, but telling the story of the magic of software is something that - certainly by the time I was in my 30s - was a big part of the job," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/l6ul7j_steve-jobs-and-warren-buffet_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Buffett recalled a memorable phone call he had with Mr Jobs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/atlantic-oceans-current-system-could-collapse-by-2030-heres-why-its-bad-news-6262328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Atlantic Ocean's Current System Could Collapse By 2030. Why It's Bad News]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/atlantic-oceans-current-system-could-collapse-by-2030-heres-why-its-bad-news-6262328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 19:56:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists emphasize the urgent need for immediate and drastic action to mitigate climate change and potentially stave off this catastrophic tipping point.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New scientific research paints a stark and alarming picture: the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC), a crucial oceanic current system regulating global climate, is on the brink of collapse. This impending disaster, accelerated by human-induced climate change, could occur as early as the late 2030s, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/08/02/climate/atlantic-circulation-collapse-timing/index.html"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The consequences of an AMOC shutdown are profound and far-reaching. A dramatic shift in global weather patterns is expected, including extreme weather events, altered precipitation patterns, and disruptions to agriculture. Europe and North America could experience significant temperature drops, while regions like the Amazon rainforest face drastic changes in seasonal weather.</p>

<p>"This is really worrying," said Rene van Westen, a marine and atmospheric researcher at the University of Utrecht in the Netherlands and study co-author.</p>

<p>"All the negative side effects of anthropogenic climate change, they will still continue to go on, like more heat waves, more droughts, more flooding," he told CNN. "Then if you also have on top of that an AMOC collapse ... the climate will become even more distorted."</p>

<p>The implications for ecosystems and human societies are equally severe. Marine life reliant on the AMOC for nutrient distribution will be jeopardized, and coastal communities face increased risks from rising sea levels and intensified storms.</p>

<p>An AMOC collapse is a really big danger that we should do everything we can to avoid, said Stefan Rahmstorf, a physical oceanographer at Potsdam University in Germany who was not involved in the latest research.</p>

<p>Scientists emphasize the urgent need for immediate and drastic action to mitigate climate change and potentially stave off this catastrophic tipping point. The world is at a crossroads, and the decisions made today will determine the planet's future.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e83ofc6g_atlantic-ocean_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The consequences of an AMOC shutdown are profound and far-reaching.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>