<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 22:29:57 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-cancer-vaccine-offers-hope-early-trials-of-mrna-vaccine-show-encouraging-results-6559617]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Breakthrough mRNA Cancer Vaccine Shows Early Promise In Clinical Trials]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-cancer-vaccine-offers-hope-early-trials-of-mrna-vaccine-show-encouraging-results-6559617]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 22:08:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Modernas new cancer vaccine, mRNA-4359, shows promising results in early clinical trials. Utilizing mRNA technology, similar to its Covid-19 vaccine, this treatment primes the immune system to identify and destroy cancer cells.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A groundbreaking vaccine against cancer cells has given encouraging early results from its first clinical trials, according to <em>The Metro</em>. Developed by Moderna Pharmaceuticals-the same company that made headlines with its Covid-19 vaccine-the jab, known as mRNA-4359, is designed to activate the body's immune system to identify and destroy cancer cells.</p>

<p>Uses mRNA technology, such as that employed by Covid-19 vaccines, to instruct the immune system to recognise healthy cells versus tumour cells. In a phase-one clinical trial involving 19 patients with advanced solid tumours, it was observed that eight patients had no growth of the tumours and no new tumours appeared. Importantly, the vaccine was found to be well tolerated, without any serious adverse effects.</p>

<p>Chief investigator Dr Debashis Sarker, a clinical reader in experimental oncology at King's College London and a consultant in medical oncology at Guy's &amp; St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/09/13/cancer-fighting-jab-showing-early-promise-trials-21596668/"><em>The Metro</em></a>: "This study evaluating an mRNA cancer immunotherapy is an important first step in hopefully developing a new treatment for patients with advanced cancers. We have shown that the therapy is well tolerated without serious side effects and can stimulate the body's immune system in a way that could help to treat cancer more effectively."</p>

<p>"However, as this study has only involved a small number of patients to date, it's too early to say how effective this could be for people with advanced stage cancer."</p>

<p>Now the study is enrolling patients with specific cancers, namely melanoma and non-small-cell lung cancer.</p>

<p>Among such studies, the mRNA-4359 trial is one of the studies being conducted exploring the likelihood of cancer vaccines. Others include a personalised mRNA vaccine for melanoma by Moderna and a lung cancer vaccine under test by BioNTech. These vaccines are major breakthroughs in treating cancer, offering the first rays of hope for patients in advanced stages of cancer.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/msiv6fsg_cancer_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This trial is part of broader research exploring mRNA vaccines for cancer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-making-new-kamikaze-drone-with-chinese-engine-us-voices-concern-6559498]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Making New Kamikaze Drone With Chinese Engine, US Voices Concern]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-making-new-kamikaze-drone-with-chinese-engine-us-voices-concern-6559498]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 21:47:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia started producing a new long-range attack drone called the Garpiya-A1 last year using Chinese engines and parts, which it deployed in the Ukraine war, according to two sources from a European intelligence agency and documents seen by Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia started producing a new long-range attack drone called the Garpiya-A1 last year using Chinese engines and parts, which it has deployed in the war in Ukraine, according to two sources from a European intelligence agency and documents seen by Reuters.</p>

<p>The intelligence - which included a production contract for the new drone, company correspondence on the manufacturing process and financial documents - indicated that IEMZ Kupol, a subsidiary of Russian state-owned weapons maker Almaz-Antey, produced more than 2,500 Garpiyas from July 2023 to July 2024.</p>

<p>The existence of the new Russian drone incorporating Chinese technology has not been previously reported. IEMZ Kupol and Almaz-Antey did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>The two intelligence sources said that the Garpiya, which means Harpy in Russian, has been deployed against military and civilian targets in Ukraine, causing damage to critical infrastructure as well as both civilian and military casualties.</p>

<p>They shared with Reuters what they said were images from Ukraine of the wreckage of a Garpiya, without providing further details. Reuters found information that reinforces this conclusion, but was unable to confirm the images independently.</p>

<p>The sources asked that neither they nor their agency be identified due to the sensitivity of the information. They also asked that certain details, such as dates, related to the documents be withheld.</p>

<p>Samuel Bendett, an adjunct senior fellow at the Center for a New American Security, a Washington DC-based think tank, told Reuters that Garpiya, if confirmed, would mark a departure from Russia's reliance on Iranian designs for long-range drones.</p>

<p>"If this is happening, it could indicate that Russia can now rely more on domestic development as well as, obviously, on China, since both sides in this war depend on many Chinese components for drone production," he said.</p>

<p>Iran, which didn't comment for this story, has supplied more than a thousand Shahed "kamikaze" drones to Russia since the start of the invasion in February 2022, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said in May last year.</p>

<p>They have been used to exhaust Ukrainian air defences and hit infrastructure far from the front lines. Iran has repeatedly denied sending drones to Russia for use in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry did not respond to a request for comment for this story. The Chinese foreign ministry said in a statement to Reuters that Beijing strictly controls the export of items with potential military applications, including drones.</p>

<p>"With regard to the Ukrainian crisis, China has always been committed to promoting peace talks and political settlement," the statement said. It added that there were no international restrictions on China's trade with Russia.</p>

<h2><strong>NATO APPEAL</strong></h2>

<p>NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg last week called on China to stop supporting Russia's war in Ukraine and said Beijing's assistance has been a significant factor in the continuation of the conflict.</p>

<p>The Garpiya "closely resembles the Shahed" but it has several distinguishing features, including a unique bolt-on fin and Limbach L-550 E engines, the European agency said in a statement to Reuters. The engine, which was originally designed and manufactured by a German company, is now produced in China by a local firm, Xiamen Limbach. The company did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Reuters reviewed a contract worth more than 1 billion rubles (10 million euros) signed in the first quarter of 2023 between the Russian defence ministry and Kupol for the development of a factory to produce the drones.</p>

<p>The intelligence sources said a former cement factory situated in Izhevsk, Udmurt Republic, in western Russia - which was purchased by Kupol in 2020 - is being used to produce the drones.</p>

<p>Using a video of a Russian drone production facility posted on the Telegram messaging app, Reuters was able to identify the site as the factory in Izhevsk from the colour and design of the building's beams and internal architecture which matched file imagery of the site. The location of the file imagery was verifiable from nearby buildings, roads, and trees that matched street views and satellite imagery.</p>

<p>A prototype of the Garpiya was launched in the first half of 2023, company communications showed. Production reached several hundred in the second half of 2023 and more than doubled to around 2,000 in the first half of 2024, the agency said.</p>

<p>Bendett, the defence analyst, said 2,500 drones per year would represent a sizeable chunk of Russia's output. Ukraine's top military commander, Oleksandr Syrskyi, said last month that Russia has fired nearly 14,000 strike drones since it invaded in February 2022, including the Iranian Shahed as well as the Russian-made Geran-2 and Lancet drones.</p>

<p>Corporate documents dated from the second quarter of 2023, reviewed by Reuters, showed that supplier TSK Vektor procured parts from Chinese companies for assembly at the Kupol site; 800 Chinese engines were also to be delivered to the new plant where the production line was due to ready by end of the quarter.</p>

<p>TSK Vektor did not respond to request for comment.</p>

<p>The European intelligence service said in the statement it was concerned that Chinese companies were continuing to provide components that enabled Russian production of large kamikaze drones. "The export of the essential components to Russia needs to stop," it said.</p>

<h3><strong>UNITED STATES VOICES CONCERN</strong></h3>

<p>Washington has repeatedly warned Beijing over its support for Russia's defence industry. It has imposed hundreds of sanctions aimed at curbing Moscow's ability to exploit certain technologies for military purposes. The State Department and the White House did not respond to a request for comment for this story.</p>

<p>In July, China said it would tighten drone export rules starting on Sept. 1. Beijing has said U.S. sanctions on Chinese entities over the Ukraine war are "illegal and unilateral".</p>

<p>The Garpiya has a take-off weight of less than 300 kilos and a maximum range of 1,500 kilometres, the production contract between Kupol and the Russian defense ministry said - roughly similar to Iran's Shahed-136 drones that Moscow has used extensively in Ukraine.</p>

<p>The Washington Post reported in August that Russia aimed to increase production of a domestic version of the Shahed-136, known as the Geran-2, at a plant in the Alabuga Special Economic Zone, in Tatarstan. Ukraine said in April it had carried out a drone strike against a drone manufacturing plant at Alabuga.</p>

<p>A third document reviewed by Reuters - a delivery status update between the intermediary TSK Vektor and the manufacturer Kupol, dated in the first quarter of 2024 - detailed an order for 100 axles, carburettors and other Limbach engine parts supplied by two other Chinese companies: Juhang Aviation Technology and Redlepus Vector Industries, both based in Shenzhen.</p>

<p>Juhang, which was placed under British sanctions in February and U.S. sanctions in May for providing Russia with drone equipment, and Redlepus did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Customs data, obtained from a commercial supplier that records and compiles the information, showed that from April 2022 to December 2023, TSK Vektor imported $36.3 million in goods from Chinese Juhang Aviation Technology, and $6.2 million from Redlepus TSK Vector Industrial Shenzhen Co Ltd.</p>

<p>According to the customs documents, the goods included aircraft engines, transistors, electronic modules, connectors, plugs and sockets, spare parts and components most of them marked as "for general civil purpose", "for general industrial purpose", "for general civil use".<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gd6i27eo_russian-kamikaze-drone-reuters_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia is producing a new long-range attack drone called the Garpiya-A1 using Chinese engines.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-maldives-faces-debt-default-china-inks-new-finance-pact-details-here-6559338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Maldives Faces Debt Default, China Inks New Finance Pact. Details Here]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-maldives-faces-debt-default-china-inks-new-finance-pact-details-here-6559338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 21:25:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China and Maldives have signed a new agreement today that allows Beijing to lend more financial support to the already debt-distressed nation. China's central bank has said the pact will also help strengthen trade and investment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China and Maldives have signed a new agreement today that allows Beijing to lend more financial support to the already debt-distressed nation. China's central bank has said the pact will also help strengthen trade and investment.</p>

<p>The memorandum of understanding or MoU between the People's Bank of China and Maldives' Economic Development Ministry allows Beijing and Male to boost direct investments and permit local currency settlement for current account transactions.</p>

<p>China has not revealed anything else about the agreement. Maldives, which is already facing a massive debt, is barely managing to avoid default.</p>

<p>In a statement after the agreement, China's foreign ministry said it has active communication with Maldives over its mounting debt to Beijing and is increasing its financial cooperation.</p>

<p>"China will, as always, provide support and assistance to the economic and social development of the Maldives within its capability," Mao Ning, a Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said.</p>

<h2>MALDIVES' RISING DEBT WORRY</h2>

<p>Maldives's debt concern is a serious one and is rising at a rapid pace. The Maldivian government vowed&nbsp; on Thursday that it will not become the first nation to default on Islamic sovereign debt by failing pay $25 million which is due next month.</p>

<p>According to the World Bank, Maldives' biggest lender is China and the debt it owes to Beijing has risen to above $1.3 billion. China has been in talks with Maldives to lend even more "support".</p>

<p>Maldives' debt crisis has come with the change in government and its political and geopolitical stance. The new government in Maldives has increasingly been pro-China despite its rising debt to the nation.</p>

<p>Maldivian President Mohamed Muizzu's party managed a landslide win the the parliamentary elections held in April this year. The outcome has led to a major shift in stance with the island nation's ties growing rapidly with China and moving away from its traditional partner, India.</p>

<p>Maldives has been criticised in recent weeks over doubts that it may not be able to pay back its debt.</p>

<h3><strong>INDIA-MALDIVES TIES STRAINED</strong></h3>

<p>Maldivian President Mohamed Muizzu will travel to India on an official visit "very soon", his spokesperson has said.</p>

<p>The announcement of Mr Muizzu's visit came on a day when two junior ministers, suspended in January for derogatory comments against Prime Minister Narendra Modi, resigned from the government.</p>

<p>Mr Muizzu, known for his pro-China leanings, visited New Delhi on June 9 to attend Prime Minister Modi's swearing-in ceremony. Unlike his predecessors, who made the first port of call to New Delhi after assuming office, Mr Muizzu travelled to Turkiye first and to China for his first state visit in January.</p>

<p>India's relationship with the Maldives came under strain since Mr Muizzu took charge as the President. Within hours of his oath, he had demanded the withdrawal of Indian military personnel manning three aviation platforms gifted by India to the Maldives. After talks between the two sides, the Indian military personnel were replaced by civilians.</p>

<p>Things escalated after three Maldivian deputy ministers made controversial remarks regarding India and Prime Minister Modi on social media.</p>

<p>Maldives Foreign Ministry distanced itself from their remarks, saying they do not represent the views of the Male government.</p>

<p>The three junior ministers were suspended, and two of them - Mariyam Shiuna and Malsha Shareef - have now resigned.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k11rqcqo_xi-jinping-mohamed-muizzu-china-maldives-ties-reuters_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China and Maldives have signed a new financial agreement amid the rising debt crisis in Maldives.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-men-jailed-in-uks-largest-child-abuse-probe-for-decades-old-crimes-6559213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[7 Men Jailed In UK's Largest Child Abuse Probe For Decades-Old Crimes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-men-jailed-in-uks-largest-child-abuse-probe-for-decades-old-crimes-6559213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 21:08:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Seven men who sexually abused two girls two decades ago received hefty jail sentences in the UK on Friday as a result of Britain's biggest ever investigation into child abuse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Seven men who sexually abused two girls two decades ago received hefty jail sentences in the UK on Friday as a result of Britain's biggest ever investigation into child abuse.</p>

<p>The men were imprisoned for between seven and 25 years after being convicted in June of offences committed in Rotherham, in northern England, in the early 2000s.</p>

<p>The cases stem from the National Crime Agency's (NCA) Operation Stovewood, a decade-long investigation into child sexual abuse that is the largest of its kind in UK history.</p>

<p>It began in 2014 following the publication of the Jay Report, which sent shockwaves around the country.</p>

<p>It found that at least 1,400 girls were abused, trafficked and groomed by gangs of men of mainly Pakistani heritage in Rotherham between 1997 and 2013.</p>

<p>The report found that police and social services failed to put a stop to the abuse.</p>

<p>Some 36 people have been convicted so far as a result of the operation, according to the NCA, which investigates serious, organised and international crime.</p>

<p>The latest convictions came at the end of a nine-week trial at Sheffield Crown Court.</p>

<p>The trial heard how the victims, who were aged between 11 and 16 at the time of the offences and were both in the care of social services, were groomed and often plied with alcohol or cannabis before being raped or assaulted.</p>

<p>They would often be collected by their abusers from the children's homes where they lived at the time, the NCA said.</p>

<p>"These men were cruel and manipulative, grooming their victims and then exploiting them by subjecting them to the most harrowing abuse possible," said NCA senior investigating officer Stuart Cobb.</p>

<p>Rotherham, a once prosperous industrial town that has suffered years of economic decline, experienced some of the worst anti-migrant violence during this summer's riots in England when hundreds of people attacked a hotel housing asylum-seekers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jqjk6bh_jail-generic_625x300_21_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The report found that police and social services failed to put a stop to the abuse. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/morocco-records-first-mpox-case-in-marrakesh-since-who-emergency-alert-6558874]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Morocco Records First Mpox Case In Marrakesh Since WHO Emergency Alert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/morocco-records-first-mpox-case-in-marrakesh-since-who-emergency-alert-6558874]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 20:21:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Morocco has recorded a case of mpox in the tourist city of Marrakesh, the first in north Africa since the WHO declared an international emergency last month, the Africa CDC said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Morocco has recorded a case of mpox in the tourist city of Marrakesh, the first in north Africa since the WHO declared an international emergency last month, the Africa CDC said.</p>

<p>"Africa CDC confirms the first mpox case in North Africa for 2024, reported by Morocco's Ministry of Health" on September 12, a statement on the Centres for Disease Control and Prevention website said on Thursday.</p>

<p>With Morocco, 15 African Union member states have reported cases -- now across every region of the continent, according to Africa CDC.</p>

<p>Mpox, previously known as monkeypox, is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals but can also be passed from human to human through close physical contact.</p>

<p>Sometimes deadly, it causes fever, muscular aches and large boil-like skin lesions.</p>

<p>The 32-year-old patient from Marrakesh "tested positive and is receiving treatment," Africa CDC said.</p>

<p>"The Moroccan authorities have activated emergency operations, deployed a rapid response team and begun epidemiological investigations and contact tracing," the statement added.</p>

<p>Morocco's health ministry said separately that the patient was receiving care at a specialised medical centre in Marrakesh and was "in a stable health condition that does not give cause for concern".</p>

<p>So far, nobody who has been in contact with the patient is showing symptoms, the ministry added.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization declared an international emergency on August 14, concerned by the surge in cases of the new Clade 1b strain in the Democratic Republic of Congo that spread to nearby countries.</p>

<p>Africa CDC figures show most of the cases are in Central Africa.</p>

<p>According to the agency, since the beginning of the year, 26,544 cases have been reported in the 15 affected countries, 5,732 of which were confirmed. It said that 724 deaths have also been reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1n5d9p5_mpox-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mpox is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-250-000-displaced-in-myanmar-after-typhoon-yagi-floods-report-6558555]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nearly 250,000 Displaced In Myanmar After Typhoon Yagi Floods: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-250-000-displaced-in-myanmar-after-typhoon-yagi-floods-report-6558555]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 19:42:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Floods in Myanmar sparked by Typhoon Yagi have displaced more than 235,000 people and killed at least 33, the junta said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Floods in Myanmar sparked by Typhoon Yagi have displaced more than 235,000 people and killed at least 33, the junta said on Friday.</p>

<p>"There are 236,649 people from 59,413 households who were displaced because of typhoon floods... There were 33 deaths and one person injured around the country," junta spokesman Zaw Min Tun said in an audio statement.</p>

<p>He said authorities have "lost communication with some areas" and urged those living near river banks to seek shelter elsewhere and "be vigilant" until Sunday.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, Myanmar's fire service gave a higher death count of 36.</p>

<p>Authorities were investigating reports that dozens of migrant workers in gold mining areas in central Mandalay region were missing following landslides, the junta spokesman said.</p>

<p>People in parts of Vietnam, Laos, Thailand and Myanmar have been battling floods and landslides in the wake of Typhoon Yagi, which dumped a colossal deluge of rain when it hit the region last weekend.</p>

<p>More than 2.7 million people were already displaced in Myanmar by conflict triggered by the junta's 2021 coup, which has plunged the country into turmoil.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/uqfehn9o_myanmar-floods_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dozens are still missing, according to reports (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/life-is-not-khata-khat-it-is-hardwork-s-jaishankars-swipe-at-rahul-gandhi-6558408]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Life Is Not  Khata-Khat ...": S Jaishankar's Swipe At Rahul Gandhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/life-is-not-khata-khat-it-is-hardwork-s-jaishankars-swipe-at-rahul-gandhi-6558408]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 19:27:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar while addressing the Indian diaspora in Geneva said that life is not "khata-khat" (an easy job), it requires hard work.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar while addressing the Indian diaspora in Geneva said that life is not "<em>khata-khat</em>" (an easy job), it requires hard work. The use of the phrase was also a jibe at Congress leader Rahul Gandhi who had claimed that the Congress would solve issues 'Khata Khat" if voted to power.</p>

<p>Talking about human resources needed to build infrastructure, he said that people who have worked understand the importance of hard work and diligence.</p>

<p>"Until we develop the human resources, it requires hard work, until you build the infrastructure, until you have those policies. So life is not <em>'khata-khat</em>'. Life is hard work. Life is diligence. Anybody who's held a job and laboured at it, knows it. So that's my message to you, that we have to work hard at it," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said that a country cannot be a major power in the world without manufacturing.</p>

<p>"And there are...people who say that we are incapable of it, we should not even attempt it. So, now ask yourself, can you actually be a major power in the world without manufacturing? Because a major power needs technology. Nobody can develop technology without developing manufacturing," he said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Interacting with the Indian community in Geneva, EAM Dr S Jaishankar says, "...Until you build infrastructure &amp; human resources, have those policies in place, it is hard work. Life is not 'khata-khat', life is hard work and diligence..."<br />
<br />
(Video source: Ministry of… <a href="https://t.co/Bdcv76dNgJ">pic.twitter.com/Bdcv76dNgJ</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1834556740303802429?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said that in terms of human resources, India has achieved a lot and the intent today is to ramp it up even more.</p>

<p>"In terms of human resources... it's again important to look here at achievements. So I can tell you the intent today is actually to speed it up, to ramp it up, to increase it, to keep telling ourselves that what we have done is just a beginning. I mean there is no intention of resting on whatever levels there may be," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said that apart from the professional conversation, world leaders are interested in what is happening in India.</p>

<p>"When I travel around the world- and you would have noticed I do a fair deal of that [chuckles]- most of my counterparts, most of the presidents and prime ministers are meet. Yes, we do the foreign policy, but that's the professional part of it. But they are enormously interested, actually, in what is happening in India," he said.</p>

<p>"Sometimes the conversation, even the words, are very similar. I had the leader of a very major Arab country actually say, we have food distribution system and, Minister, you don't know how much leakage we have. Because he was very interested, how do we today manage the food support, where today they are covering 830 million people. How do we manage that with actually much less leakage than there has ever been in the past? People who ask today, how have you improved your income tax collection? Because every president and prime minister is interested in increasing their revenues," Jaishankar added, talking about food support in India.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said that in what India is doing, there are lessons for the rest of the world.</p>

<p>"When I look back at these ten years, yes, there have been changes for the good in our country, but I will also say to all of you that those changes actually globally resonate. That other countries today look with deep interest, they may not be able to exactly copy it, but somewhere in what we are doing there are lessons for the rest of the world. And people feel this country, which, bear in mind, which still has USD 3000 per capita income below that, is able to do that much," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar added that achievements are meant to motivate and not be satiated.</p>

<p>"Achievements not to satiate but to motivate. Not to say I've done well, so I'm done. But to say I've done well and I could have done so much more. And if I could have done this in two terms, how much more can I do in a third?" he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1ht0ulco_s-jaishankar_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar said that a country cannot be a major power in the world without manufacturing]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-age-family-net-worth-political-career-and-more-6558144]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump: Age, Family, Net Worth, Political Career And More]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-age-family-net-worth-political-career-and-more-6558144]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 18:55:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Before becoming the 45th US President, Donald Trump was a celebrity and a property tycoon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald John Trump has had a profound impact on US politics. His presidency is still, and perhaps forever, be remembered for bold statements and decisions he took. To explain who Donald Trump is and what makes him tick involves lots of metaphors. From "insomniac", to "Godzilla" and a "Navy SEAL", the 45th President of the United States has earned praises and brickbats from his countrymen.</p>

<p>Mr Trump, born into wealth and growing up in the heart of New York's business world, rose to global prominence as POTUS. From real estate mogul to reality TV star to the most powerful political figure in America, his life has been anything but conventional. His presidency (2017-2021) saw major political upheaval, deeply polarising the nation. Even after his term ended, Trump continues to dominate the political conversation, and in a debate with Vice President and Democrat nominee Kamala Harris, he made a strong pitch why the US needs him in power.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump Birth And Early Life</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/bj7vkolo_donald-trump-early-life-getty_625x300_13_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Getty</span></p>
</div>

<p>He was born on June 14, 1946, in Queens, New York City, to Frederick Christ Trump, a wealthy real estate developer, and Mary Anne MacLeod, a Scottish immigrant. He was the fourth of five children in a well-off family that built its fortune in the post-World War II construction boom.</p>

<p>Fred Trump was a powerful figure in real estate, particularly in Brooklyn and Queens, which profoundly influenced Donald's ambitions. Raised with a competitive spirit and taught the value of success from a young age, Donald followed closely in his father's footsteps. His early years were marked by privilege but also discipline. Trump's parents sent him to the New York Military Academy at age 13 to channel his energy and focus on his studies.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump Education</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t2q61958_donald-trump-real-estate-getty_625x300_13_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump attended the New York Military Academy before moving on to Fordham University for two years. He then transferred to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/09/10/did-donald-trump-attend-wharton/75168213007/">Wharton School</a> of the University of Pennsylvania, where he earned a degree in economics in 1968.</p>

<p>Armed with a business education and the family fortune, Trump joined his father's real estate business, eventually taking control in 1971 and renaming it The Trump Organisation. His early projects included transforming rundown buildings in Manhattan into luxury high-rises. Trump's career was characterised by a knack for branding and a relentless pursuit of high-profile deals. Notably, he developed the Grand Hyatt Hotel in New York and Trump Tower on Fifth Avenue, both of which bolstered his reputation as a high-stakes real estate mogul.</p>

<p>In the 1980s, Trump expanded into the casino business with mixed success. His ventures, such as Trump Plaza and Trump Castle helped cement his image as a larger-than-life businessman, though financial trouble followed. Trump's companies declared bankruptcy several times, but he consistently rebounded, largely due to his mastery of public relations and branding.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump Marriages</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0oh3rkmg_donald-trump-melania-getty_625x300_13_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Getty</span></p>
</div>

<p>Trump's personal life, including his three marriages, has been as highly publicised as his professional one. His first marriage, to Ivana Zelnickova, a Czech model and businesswoman, lasted from 1977 to 1992, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-62172028">according to the <em>BBC</em></a>. Together, they had three children: Donald Jr, Ivanka and Eric Trump. The couple was a fixture in the New York social scene throughout the 1980s, though their relationship ended in a widely publicised divorce amid rumours of Trump's infidelity.</p>

<p>In 1993, Trump married actress Marla Maples, with whom he had one daughter, Tiffany Trump. This marriage, too, ended in divorce, in 1999.</p>

<p>In 2005, Trump married Slovenian model Melania Knauss, with whom he has a son, Barron Trump. Melania would go on to become the First Lady during Trump's presidency. Throughout his personal and professional life, Trump has kept his family close, with his children playing prominent roles in both his business empire and his political campaigns.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump Net Worth</strong></h3>

<p>In May this year, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/danalexander/article/the-definitive-networth-of-donaldtrump/"><em>Forbes</em></a> released the answer to the question people were asking for decades - what's Donald Trump really worth? As per the magazine, $7.5 billion. The figure includes the assets and businesses the former US President owns. Truth Social, the platform Trump owns, is alone worth $5.6 billion. His real estate business is worth $1.1 billion, while the clubs and resorts $0.81 billion. Mr Trump has $0.41 billion as cash and $0.1 billion in other assets, as per Forbes.</p>

<p>The outlet further said that he reached the $1 billion mark in 1988, but was out of Forbes' 400 list from 1990 to 1995.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump Age</strong></h3>

<p>At 78, Trump is still actively involved in politics and business. He maintains a high-profile presence, particularly through his social media platform, Truth Social.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump Presidency</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m8f0qhh_donald-trump-presidency-afp_625x300_13_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Though Trump flirted with politics for years, his serious plunge into the political arena came in 2015 when he announced his candidacy for the Republican nomination for President. Few in the Republican Party believed when Trump launched his improbable White House bid that he'd still be a factor at the end of that year. But the billionaire topped national polls after entering the race, as per CNN.</p>

<p>Donald Trump quickly emerged as the frontrunner, gaining notoriety for his unfiltered rhetoric, often attacking rivals and the media. His promise to build a wall along the US-Mexico border and his tough stance on immigration became central themes of his campaign.</p>

<p>In November 2016, Trump defied pollsters and political analysts by defeating Democratic candidate Hillary Clinton in one of the most shocking political upsets in US history. His electoral victory, largely fuelled by wins in key swing states, underscored the deep divides in American society.</p>

<p>Trump's presidency was marked by a series of unconventional and controversial actions, from his combative relationship with the press to his unpredictable foreign policy moves. Domestically, Trump implemented tax cuts, rolled back regulations, and installed conservative judges at a record pace, including three Supreme Court Justices, reshaping the judiciary for decades.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump political career</strong></h3>

<p>One of the Trump administration's defining moments came in 2020 with the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic. Trump's handling of the crisis received heavy criticism, with detractors accusing him of downplaying the severity of the virus and mishandling the federal response. His administration's policies on immigration, trade and race relations also ignited fierce debates and further polarised the country.</p>

<p>Trump's foreign policy approach was similarly contentious. He withdrew the US from several international agreements, including the Paris Climate Accord and the Iran Nuclear Deal, while also seeking a more assertive stance against China. Trump's "America First" policy, which often alienated traditional US allies, further underscored his unorthodox approach to global affairs.</p>

<p>In December 2019, Trump became the third US president to be impeached by the House of Representatives, accused of abusing his power by pressuring Ukraine to investigate political rival Joe Biden. The Senate ultimately acquitted him in February 2020. He was impeached for the second time by the House of Representatives on January 13, 2021, one week before his term expired for incitement of insurrection. He is the only US President to be impeached twice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5hv2kcrg_donald-trump-getty_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is contesting for second term as US President.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-restrict-junk-food-ads-to-tackle-high-childhood-obesity-levels-6557588]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK To Restrict Junk Food Ads To Tackle High Childhood Obesity Levels]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-restrict-junk-food-ads-to-tackle-high-childhood-obesity-levels-6557588]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 17:41:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK will ban junk food advertising on the internet and daytime TV in a bid to tackle childhood obesity, sparking criticism on the political right over "nanny state" meddling.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK will ban junk food advertising on the internet and daytime TV in a bid to tackle childhood obesity, sparking criticism on the political right over "nanny state" meddling.</p>

<p>The measure was included in the Labour manifesto that won Keir Starmer's Labour a resounding victory in July, and is due to be introduced on October 1, 2025, the government said Thursday.</p>

<p>The announcement came after Starmer promised wide-ranging reforms to the crisis-hit National Health Service (NHS), in particular by placing a greater emphasis on prevention.</p>

<p>Junior health minister Andrew Gwynne said in a written statement to parliament that more than one in five children in England are "overweight or living with obesity by the time they start primary school" at age four or five.</p>

<p>By the time they leave at aged 11, the figure is more than one third, he added.</p>

<p>"These restrictions will help protect children from being exposed to advertising of less healthy food and drinks, which evidence shows influences their dietary preferences from a young age," he said.</p>

<p>Advertising for foods that are too fatty, too sweet or too salty will be banned before 9:00 pm on television and completely online.</p>

<p>The ban was supported by the Conservative Party under Boris Johnson, who has talked about his own struggles with weight gain, but was postponed to give manufacturers in the sector more time to adapt.</p>

<p>Others on the political right, however, criticised the move as an attack on individual freedom.</p>

<p>They included the Conservative-supporting Daily Mail, whose front-page headline Friday read "Nanny Starmer's ban on junk food ads 'to save NHS'".</p>

<p>"Keir Starmer ushered in a new era of the nanny state yesterday by unveiling plans for a pre-watershed ban on junk food advertising," it added.</p>

<p>The Labour government plans other interventions to ease the strain on the health system, such as banning high-sugar and caffeine energy drinks for under-16s.</p>

<p>Children's think-tank The Centre for Young Lives on Friday urged the government to "ignore 'Nanny State' critics and expand sugar taxes, ban (the) sale of energy drinks to under 16s, and roll out national supervised toothbrushing programme in schools."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6mrlseqo_junk-food-generic_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ban was supported by the Conservative Party under Boris Johnson. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chicago-restaurant-offers-the-most-expensive-martini-in-us-priced-at-6557267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chicago Restaurant Offers The Most Expensive Martini In US, Priced At...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chicago-restaurant-offers-the-most-expensive-martini-in-us-priced-at-6557267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 17:01:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Adalina, an Italian restaurant in Chicago led by Top Chef alum Soo Ahn, has launched a "Marrow Martini," considered one of the most expensive cocktails in the US Priced at several thousand dollars.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An ultra luxurious new cocktail in Chicago, Illinois, comes with a several thousand dollar price tag attached. According to <em>Fox News Digital,</em> Adalina, an Italian restaurant in the Windy City, has unveiled the "Marrow Martini, which contains more than just a drink; it's a piece of stunning diamond jewellery.</p>

<p>Led by Top Chef alum Soo Ahn, Adalina partnered with the jewellery brand Marrow Fine, headquartered just underneath the restaurant, to develop a truly unique experience. The martini will be served with a 9-carat diamond tennis necklace featuring 150 diamonds set in 14K gold.</p>

<p>With that, "it's likely the most expensive Martini in the United States," says Colin Hofer, a manager at Adalina, in an email to<em> <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/food-drink/chicago-restaurant-serving-most-expensive-martini-us-priced-13k">Fox News Digital.</a> </em>It pumps up the luxury within the cocktail scene in the United States.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sgat1r9_adalinachicagocom_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"Instead of traditional spirits like gin or vodka, I chose Mezcal because I believe it has untapped potential as a luxury spirit. Mezcal, much like heirloom jewellery, is often overlooked despite its richness. The particular Mezcal we use is a rare, sought-after brand made from Green Agave, native to the deserts of San Luis Potosi, Mexico," Hofer said.</p>

<p>Jillian Sassone, founder of Marrow Fine, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/food-drink/chicago-restaurant-serving-most-expensive-martini-us-priced-13k"><em>Fox News Digital </em></a>via email she suspects the drink will make for memorable evenings.</p>

<p>"Adalina was a natural choice to partner with, not only because of its proximity but also because of their world-class menu from Top Chef Soo Ahn. Each time I have visited Adalina, I'm blown away by every dish but also by the palpable energy and excitement in the restaurant," she said.</p>

<p>"While it's not something we expect to see sold frequently, it has sparked a lot of interest among our clientele. It's more about creating an iconic experience for a select few rather than broad popularity," Hofer said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n3ih08ig_most-expensive-martini-in-us_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The unique experience is aimed at elite clientele. (Representative Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovered-my-father-was-on-flight-s-jaishankar-recalls-1984-hijack-6557247]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Discovered My Father Was On Flight": S Jaishankar Recalls 1984 Hijack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovered-my-father-was-on-flight-s-jaishankar-recalls-1984-hijack-6557247]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 17:00:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Friday revealed that his father was on a hijacked flight in 1984 and said he had a unique window on "both sides" in such situations - the perspective of family members and those in the government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Friday revealed that his father was on a hijacked flight in 1984 and said he had a unique window on "both sides" in such situations - the perspective of family members and those in the government.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar was answering a question during a community event in Geneva about the recently released television series on the hijacking of IC-814 in 1999.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar told the audience how as a young officer then, he was part of the team dealing with the hijack situation on the one hand and on the other, he was part of the group of families putting pressure on the government.</p>

<p>During the question and answer session after his address to the Indian community, a member of the audience asked the Minister about his comments on the recently released series 'IC-814: The Kandahar Hijack' on Netflix, which he said, showed "the bureaucracy and the government dealing with hijacking in poor light." With a disclaimer that he has not watched the series, Mr Jaishankar went on to reveal his personal connection with the hijacking incident.</p>

<p>"In 1984 there was a hijacking. I was a very young officer. I was part of the team which was dealing with it. I rang up my mother, actually, to tell her, 'Look, I can't come. There's a hijacking," he said elaborating how it was his turn to go home and feed his young son as his wife too was working.</p>

<p>"And then I discovered, my father was on the flight. The flight ended up in Dubai. It's a long story, but fortunately, nobody got killed. It could have ended as a problem," he added.</p>

<p>On July 5, 1984, an Indian Airlines flight was hijacked from Pathankot and taken to Dubai. After more than 36 hours, 12 pro-Khalistani hijackers surrendered to authorities and released all 68 passengers and six crew members unharmed.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar was an IFS officer and became a minister after his retirement. His father K Subrahmanyam was an IAS officer and a regular commentator on strategic issues.</p>

<p>"And it was interesting because on the one hand, I was part of the team which was working on the hijacking. On the other hand, I was part of the family members who are pressing the government for the hijacking. So actually, I have that very unique window on both sides, in that sense of the problem," he added.</p>

<p>"So, often these are situations and movie guys don't make the governments look good. The hero is supposed to look good. Then nobody would watch the movie and you got to accept that," he commented, evoking peals of laughter from the audience.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r4k60am8_s-jaishankar-reuters_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The remarks by S Jaishankar came while he was interacting with the Indian community in Geneva]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-origin-man-guilty-of-murdering-indian-by-crushing-him-under-range-rover-in-uk-6556897]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak-Origin Man Found Guilty Of Murdering Indian With Range Rover SUV In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-origin-man-guilty-of-murdering-indian-by-crushing-him-under-range-rover-in-uk-6556897]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:51:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 25-year-old man of Pakistani heritage has been convicted of murdering an Indian restaurant manager with a stolen car while the victim was cycling back home in south-east England on Valentine's Day this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 25-year-old man of Pakistani heritage has been convicted of murdering an Indian restaurant manager with a stolen car while the victim was cycling back home in south-east England on Valentine's Day this year.</p>

<p>Vignesh Pattabhiraman, 36, was killed by Shazeb Khalid with a "stolen Range Rover" while he cycling back from his workplace - an Indian restaurant 'Vel' - in Reading, United Kingdom.</p>

<p>The Indian man was declared dead at the Royal Berkshire Hospital and a murder investigation was launched.</p>

<p>Khalid was arrested on February 19 and charged with murder the following day.</p>

<p>Khalid was on Wednesday found guilty of murdering Pattabhiraman following a trial at Reading Crown Court that lasted 28 days.</p>

<p>Khalid pleaded guilty to the lesser charge of manslaughter at an earlier hearing but was convicted of murder by the jury.</p>

<p>Soiheem Hussain, 27, and Mya Reilly, 20, who were also arrested and charged in the case, also appeared during the same trial.</p>

<p>While Hussain was found guilty of assisting an offender, Reilly was found not guilty on the same charge.</p>

<p>Khalid is set to be sentenced on October 10.</p>

<p>Thames Valley Police, which had conducted the murder investigation, told the court that a post-mortem examination ascertained that Pattabhiraman had died due to a head injury following the collision.</p>

<p>"I am glad that the jury has found Khalid guilty of murder," said Detective Chief Inspector (DCI) Stuart Brangwin, the Senior Investigating Officer of the case at Thames Valley Police.</p>

<p>"It was obviously clear to the jury that Khalid intended to cause Vignesh harm that evening. He used the stolen Range Rover he was driving as a weapon and left him to suffer knowing that he had hit him," he said.</p>

<p>"The communication between Khalid and Hussain throughout the evening of Pattabhiraman's death showed that Hussain was very much aware of what happened and that he assisted in the aftermath. The death of Vignesh has left his family devastated, and I hope this verdict will help them in some way," added DCI Brangwin.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a Just Giving charity initiative set up online by Pattabhiraman's friends and family to help with repatriation costs and support for his grieving wife Ramya after the "senseless tragedy" has raised over GBP 52,500.</p>

<p>"Vignesh was a committed restaurant manager at Vel, where he poured his heart and soul into his work, earning recognition for his exceptionally warm nature, customer service and work ethic. His dream of reaching a senior management position in the hotel industry was within reach, with an exciting opportunity awaiting him at Hyatt Regency Mayfair London," reads the online tribute.</p>

<p>"In addition to his professional endeavours, Pattabhiraman cherished time with his beloved wife, Ramya, and their shared aspirations for a bright future in the UK. Their dreams were shattered by this senseless tragedy, leaving behind a void that cannot be filled," it adds.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0gs6hg5c_indian-man-vignesh-pattabhiraman-killed-by-pak-man-in-uk_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vignesh Pattabhiraman, 36, was killed by Shazeb Khalid with a "stolen Range Rover".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/osama-bin-ladens-son-hamza-alive-leading-al-qaeda-in-afghanistan-report-6557098]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Osama Bin Laden's Son Hamza Alive, Leading Al Qaeda In Afghanistan: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/osama-bin-ladens-son-hamza-alive-leading-al-qaeda-in-afghanistan-report-6557098]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:38:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The report warned that warning that "under his command, Al Qaeda is regrouping and preparing for future attacks on Western targets".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamza bin Laden, the son of Al Qaeda chief Osama bin Laden, is alive and leading the terror outfit, according to intelligence reports cited by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.themirror.com/news/world-news/osama-bin-ladens-dead-son-691261"><em>The Mirror</em></a>. Hamza is secretly running Al Qaeda from Afghanistan along with his brother, Abdullah bin Laden, the publication says in an explosive report. The National Mobilisation Front (NMF), an anti-Taliban military alliance, also carried a report detailing the operations of Hamza and his associates. The outlet said that the man dubbed the “crown prince of terror” is hiding in northern Afghanistan under the constant protection of 450 snipers.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.memri.org/jttm/afghan-resistance-media-reports-terror-hideouts-afghanistan-abdullah-bin-laden-son-osama-bin">The </a><em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.memri.org/jttm/afghan-resistance-media-reports-terror-hideouts-afghanistan-abdullah-bin-laden-son-osama-bin">NMF</a> </em>has warned that since the 2021 fall of Kabul, Afghanistan has become a "training centre for various terror groups".</p>

<p>"Hamza bin Laden has been moved to Dara Abdullah Khel district (in Panjshir), where 450 Arabs and Pakistanis are protecting him," it said, warning that "under his command, Al Qaeda is regrouping and preparing for future attacks on Western targets".</p>

<p>The <em>NMF</em> report contradicted claims that Hamza was killed in a 2019 US airstrike. Hamza is believed to have worked closely with Ayman al-Zawahiri, who took over the affairs of Al Qaeda after Osama's killing.</p>

<p>The news about Hamza's killing was released after his audio and video messages surfaced calling for attacks on the US and other countries.</p>

<p>However, the place and date of death was unclear, per an old <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-49187315"><em>BBC</em> report</a>. The Pentagon too did not comment on the issue.</p>

<p>Hamza bin Laden was officially designated by the US as a global terrorist and was believed to have been under house arrest in Iran.</p>

<p>He is thought to have been born in Jeddah in Saudi Arabia, before spending years with his mother in Iran.</p>

<p>Hamza's father Osama bin Laden was killed by US Special Forces in 2011, in a compound in Abbottabad, Pakistan. He had approved the attacks on the US on 11 September 2001, in which nearly 3,000 people were killed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/crqonrco_osama-son-hamza-afp_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The NMF report contradicted claims that Hamza was killed in a 2019 US airstrike.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-clears-worlds-first-mpox-vaccine-for-use-in-some-areas-6557093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Clears World's First Mpox Vaccine For Use In Some Areas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-clears-worlds-first-mpox-vaccine-for-use-in-some-areas-6557093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:38:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) has announced the MVA-BN vaccine as the first vaccine against mpox to be added to its prequalification list.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) has announced the MVA-BN vaccine as the first vaccine against mpox to be added to its prequalification list. This is expected to facilitate timely and increased access to this vital product in communities with urgent need, to reduce transmission and help contain the outbreak, WHO said in a statement on its website.</p>

<p>WHO 'prequalification' and 'emergency use listing' are mechanisms used to evaluate quality, safety and efficacy of medical products, such as vaccines, diagnostics and medicines, and product suitability for use in a low- and middle-income country context.</p>

<p>WHO's assessment for prequalification of the mpox vaccine is based on information submitted by the manufacturer, Bavarian Nordic A/S, and reviewed by the European Medicines Agency, the regulatory agency of record for this vaccine.</p>

<p>"This first prequalification of a vaccine against mpox is an important step in our fight against the disease, both in the context of the current outbreaks in Africa, and in future," said WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus.</p>

<p>"We now need urgent scale up in procurement, donations and rollout to ensure equitable access to vaccines where they are needed most, alongside other public health tools, to prevent infections, stop transmission and save lives," Dr Ghebreyesus said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">WHO has prequalified the MVA-BN vaccine, the first vaccine against <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mpox?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#mpox</a> to be approved!<br />
<br />
This approval is a major step towards expanding access and reducing transmission in high-risk communities.<a href="https://t.co/Tk700dct6J">https://t.co/Tk700dct6J</a> <a href="https://t.co/v42K66u0rP">pic.twitter.com/v42K66u0rP</a></p>
— World Health Organization (WHO) (@WHO) <a href="https://twitter.com/WHO/status/1834528802619236558?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The MVA-BN vaccine can be given to people over 18 years old as a two-dose injection, four weeks apart, WHO said. After prior cold storage, the vaccine can be kept at 2-8 degree Celsius for up to eight weeks, it said.</p>

<p>The WHO Strategic Advisory Group of Experts (SAGE) on immunisation reviewed all available evidence and recommended the use of MVA-BN vaccine in the context of an mpox outbreak for people at high risk of exposure, WHO said.</p>

<p>While MVA-BN is currently not licensed for people younger than 18 years, this vaccine may be used "off-label" in infants, children and adolescents, and in pregnant and immunocompromised people, WHO said. This means the vaccine use is recommended in outbreak settings where the benefits of vaccination outweigh the potential risks.</p>

<p>WHO has, however, emphasised the need to collect further data on vaccine safety and effectiveness under these circumstances.</p>

<p>Available data shows that a single-dose MVA-BN vaccine given before exposure has an estimated 76 per cent effectiveness in protecting people against mpox, with the two-dose schedule achieving an estimated 82 per cent effectiveness.</p>

<p>Vaccination after exposure is less effective than pre-exposure vaccination, WHO said.</p>

<p>The escalating mpox outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and other countries was declared a public health emergency of international concern by the WHO Director-General on August 14.</p>

<p>Over 120 countries have confirmed more than 1.03 lakh cases since the onset of the global outbreak in 2022. In 2024 alone, there were 25,237 suspected and confirmed cases, and 723 deaths from different outbreaks in 14 African nations, WHO said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/do27fi7_who_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WHO's assessment for prequalification of mpox vaccine is based on details given by the manufacturer]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/climate-change-sent-sub-surface-tremors-caused-landslide-for-9-days-study-6556913]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Change Sent Sub-Surface Tremors, Caused Landslide For 9 Days: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/climate-change-sent-sub-surface-tremors-caused-landslide-for-9-days-study-6556913]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:13:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In September 2023, a 1.2 kilometre-high mountain peak in an East Greenland fjord - a narrow inlet of sea between two steep cliffs - collapsed, causing a tsunami about 200 metres tall.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A landslide in Greenland, triggered by glacier melting due to climate change, caused an earthquake, vibrations from which reverberated throughout the planet for nine straight days and damaged infrastructure, according to a new study.</p>

<p>In September 2023, a 1.2 kilometre-high mountain peak in an East Greenland fjord - a narrow inlet of sea between two steep cliffs - collapsed, causing a tsunami about 200 metres tall.</p>

<p>Researchers said the giant wave rocked back and forth across the fjord for nine days, which sent seismic shocks reverberating throughout Earth's crust, baffling scientists around the world.</p>

<p>While no one was hurt, the shocks destroyed infrastructure worth nearly USD 2,00,000 at an unoccupied research station on Ella Island in eastern Greenland, the international team, including researchers from the University College London, UK, said.</p>

<p>According to them, the landslide was a result of the melting of glacier at the foot of the mountain, becoming thinner and unable to hold up the rock-face above it - this was ultimately due to climate change.</p>

<p>"Our findings highlight how climate change is causing cascading, hazardous feedbacks between the cryosphere, hydrosphere and lithosphere," the authors wrote in the study published in the journal Science.</p>

<p>"When I first saw the seismic signal, I was completely baffled. Even though we know seismometers can record a variety of sources happening on Earth's surface, never before has such a long-lasting, globally travelling seismic wave, containing only a single frequency of oscillation, been recorded. This inspired me to co-lead a large team of scientists to figure out the puzzle," co-author Stephen Hicks, from the University College London, said.</p>

<p>For the study, the researchers used a mathematical model and recreated the landslide, along with the uniquely narrow and bendy fjord, to understand how the sloshing of water could have continued on for nine straight days without dying down.</p>

<p>The team, comprising 68 scientists from 41 research institutions, combined seismic recordings from around the world, field measurements, satellite imagery and computer simulations for their analysis.</p>

<p>The simulations were eventually able to closely match the height of the real-world tsunami as well as the slow cycles of the long-lasting back-and-forth sloshing of water, they said.</p>

<p>By bringing together diverse datasets, the model predicted that the giant tsunami wave would have moved back and forth every 90 seconds, matching the recordings of vibrations travelling in the Earth's crust all around the globe, the researchers said.</p>

<p>As climate change continues to melt Earth's polar regions, it could lead to an increase in large, destructive landslides such as this one, they said.</p>

<p>"Climate change is shifting what is typical on Earth, and it can set unusual events into motion," said co-author and seismologist Alice Gabriel, Scripps Institution of Oceanography, University of California - San Diego, US.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/0vdfur1o_earthquake-generic_625x300_10_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to them, the landslide was a result of the melting of glacier.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-global-seismic-signal-traced-to-greenland-mega-landslide-study-6556854]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mysterious Global Seismic Signal Traced To Greenland Mega-Landslide: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-global-seismic-signal-traced-to-greenland-mega-landslide-study-6556854]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:07:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A year after a bizarre seismic signal baffled scientists globally, researchers have finally pinpointed its origin. The signal, classified as an "unidentified seismic object", was traced back to a colossal landslide in Greenland's remote Dickson Fjord]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A year after a bizarre seismic signal baffled scientists globally, researchers have finally pinpointed its origin. The enigmatic signal, classified as an "unidentified seismic object" (USO), was traced back to a colossal landslide in Greenland's remote Dickson Fjord. The landslide, triggered by the thinning of a glacier due to global warming, caused a mega-tsunami and a seiche, resulting in a continuous hum with a single vibration frequency that lasted for nine days.</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to a <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adm9247">new study published in the journal Science</a>, the landslide's immense power was due to the weakening of the mountain's support caused by decades of glacier thinning. When the mountain collapsed, it sent vibrations through the Earth, shaking the planet and generating seismic waves that were felt globally.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The glacier, enough to fill 10,000 Olympic swimming pools, had plunged into the fjord, triggering a towering mega-tsunami. The resulting wave reached an astonishing 200 metres in height – twice the size of London's iconic Big Ben.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In the study, researchers revealed that the unusual seismic signal was generated by standing waves in the fjord caused by the rockslide. Scientists warn that we may see more of these unexpected events as the planet continues to warm.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The study further reveals a complex interplay between climate change, the cryosphere, hydrosphere and mass wasting events. The authors suggest that signals like this may offer a new perspective on understanding these interactions.</p>

<p dir="ltr">This event marks the first reported tsunamigenic landslide in Greenland. The findings suggest that such events may become more frequent and intense, posing as a danger to the environment and human populations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nq4j4dko_greenland_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The glacier, enough to fill 10,000 Olympic swimming pools, had plunged into the fjord. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/lizard-car-tire-and-a-rs-50-crore-watch-hotels-reveal-most-unusual-lost-and-found-items-6556693]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lizard, Car Tire, And Rs 50 Crore Watch: Hotels Reveal Bizarre Lost Items]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/lizard-car-tire-and-a-rs-50-crore-watch-hotels-reveal-most-unusual-lost-and-found-items-6556693]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 15:41:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hotels.com's annual Hotel Room Insights Report reveals common and bizarre items left behind in hotel rooms, such as phone chargers and a $6 million watch. Some guests have also made unusual room service requests, like Evian-filled tubs and caviar hot]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hotels.com, a global website for booking hotel rooms online, has released its annual Hotel Room Insights Report, highlighting the most common items left behind by hotel guests and some of the most unusual room service requests.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.expedia.com/newsroom/hotel-room-innsights-report-hotels-com-pulls-back-the-covers-on-the-surprising-world-of-hotels-2/">the report,</a> which is based on data from over 400 hotels worldwide, the most frequently forgotten items include phone chargers, dirty laundry, power adapters, makeup, and toiletries. In addition, 10% of hotels reported finding dentures left behind by guests.</p>

<p>Some of the more unusual items left behind in hotel rooms include a Rolex watch, a $6 million (Rs 50 crore) watch, a Hermes Birkin bag, luxury car keys and documents, a car tire, an engagement ring, a tooth, two full-leg casts, stacks of cash, a pet lizard, and a chick. Fortunately, the lizard and chick were safely reunited with their owners.</p>

<p>The report also highlights some unusual room service requests, including an Evian-filled tub for a child's bath, a customised allergen menu for a pet, burnt toast, a caviar hot dog, fresh goat milk, 4 pounds of bananas, and a high five from a team member to confirm their request was received.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.expedia.com/newsroom/hotel-room-innsights-report-hotels-com-pulls-back-the-covers-on-the-surprising-world-of-hotels-2/"><em>Hotel Room Innsights Report </em></a>also provides a fascinating glimpse into the Hidden Hotel Perks-The Perks You Never Knew You Needed around the world.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Stroll through a 400-year-old Japanese garden at Hotel New Otani Tokyo The Main.</li>
	<li>The Four Seasons Hotel Austin provides an in-room guitar concierge for guests who want to strum on a premium guitar.</li>
	<li>The Sentinel Hotel in Portland offers Very Important Pets services, including access to top groomers and a pet acupuncturist for stressed pets.</li>
	<li>Take a private guided tour of the British Museum at The Montague on the Gardens in London.</li>
	<li>Savour a personalised wine tasting experience in the cellar of Villa Gallici Hotel &amp; Spa.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m3labgr_hotels_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Report detailed some of the most unusual lost and found items at hotels, including a pet lizard.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-keeps-forgetting-he-isnt-contesting-biden-anymore-6556389]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Trump Keeps Forgetting He Isn't Contesting Biden Anymore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-keeps-forgetting-he-isnt-contesting-biden-anymore-6556389]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 15:04:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[No question, Harris got the debate she would have wanted in her dreams. Trump was either poorly prepared or, more likely, not prepared at all.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h2nia058_trump_625x300_13_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Consider the full magnitude of Kamala Harris' challenge coming into Tuesday's debate. She is half Black and half Indian in a predominantly white nation where they are in a growing funk about being reduced to less than a majority by 2042. Her opponent is an alpha male, Donald Trump, in a society that is more macho than any other “advanced” country.</p>

<p>Harris had a disastrous campaign for the Democratic nomination in 2020. She is remembered for her left-of-centre policies like universal health care and decriminalisation of illegal immigration, and for opposing fracking. She was the Vice-President - among the nation's most nondescript jobs - to a president who became deeply unpopular because of high inflation and botched immigration controls.</p>

<p>She did not go through the grind of nomination party primaries where her policies, postures and personality would get defined. She was catapulted into being the Domestic contender less than 100 days before election eve. She is not the leftist of 2020. She cannot position herself as the baton carrier of Biden's legacy because that would be electoral suicide. Her biggest problem is that people do not know enough about her or what she stands for.</p>

<h2><strong>Most Don't Know Who Kamala Really Is</strong></h2>

<p>She had a great debut at the August Democratic National Convention (DNC), but the NYT/Siena poll on the eve of the debate came as a damper. Almost a third of those polled said they do not know enough about her or her policies, compared to only 5% for Trump. Some 36% felt she is too “progressive” compared to 28% who felt Trump is too “conservative”. As many as 97% of those who voted for Trump in 2020 said they would vote for him again. His base of white non-college educated, elderly, rural and evangelicals is rock solid.</p>

<p>Going into the debate, it was the swing vote in the “Arjun eye” of both Trump and Harris. Some 18 million of the US's 161 million American voters are registered as “undecided”. Within them, it is estimated that the swing vote is 7% in seven states. Now observers have narrowed the swing vote down to 50,000 from five states.</p>

<p>For that narrow target audience - as much for anybody other than MAGA (Make America Great Again) <em>bhakts</em> - there is little doubt that Harris won the debate, hands down. In a consolidation of her convention profile, she came across as presidential, fully aware of the power and prestige of the office; as somebody who engages with policies and solutions, and wants to represent all Americans, including Republicans; somebody who values freedom in its widest sense, including woman's rights over their bodies; somebody who wants to lead Americans out of their recent fractious past into a future of opportunity.</p>

<h2><strong>Kamala Sprung A Surprise</strong></h2>

<p>She had become fully prepped by a team which, in a departure from Biden's lot, includes disillusioned ex-members of Trump's core team. She had her list of talking points and she made sure she ticked off all of them, irrespective of the questions asked. She made no effort to defend Biden's record on its weakest legacies but spiritedly defended the regime's record on healthcare and the NATO support for Ukraine. Her policy prescriptions were as nondescript — whatever does an “economy of opportunity mean? — as at the DNC, but she was at her passionate best on abortion.</p>

<p>Most importantly, she baited Trump repeatedly on all his pet peeves, so that the worst of him came out. This she did brilliantly from her opening statement, priming the audience to expect the “same old playbook and bunch of lies”. To her delight, Trump fell for every single bait she laid for him.</p>

<p>She said people left his rallies out of “boredom and exhaustion”; predictably, Trump thundered that his rallies are the “biggest ever”. She said the world's leaders she had met as V-P would laugh at Trump; at how easily he could be manipulated by flattery; that they call him a “disgrace”. He shouted into the mic how “strong” world leaders like Victor Urban of Hungary say that the world has gone to pieces after Trump; how the wars in Ukraine and Israel-Gaza would never have happened had be been President; how he would end the wars in “24 hours” by bashing the heads of all combatants the day he became the President-elect.</p>

<h2><strong>How Trump Missed Opportunities</strong></h2>

<p>Her coup de grace against Trump was on the results of the 2020 elections. In response to a question from the moderator, Trump repeated that he had not accepted that he had lost the last election. Harris latched on to the response, saying he had been “fired” by 81 million voters, and that his attempts at reviewing the vote had been turned down by over 60 courts. She stressed how his refusal to process the fact that he had indeed lost the election cast doubt on whether “this candidate standing to my right” had the cognitive ability to accept facts, and that the American people deserved something better from their Chief Executive.</p>

<p>So rattled was Trump that he barely nicked Harris on her vulnerabilities when he could have stuck a knife through her. He did repeat rants like “Biden was the worst President of the US and she was the worst Vice-President”, and he did nail the Biden administration on the chaotic withdrawal from Afghanistan leaving behind $ 85 billion of fresh armaments. But he failed to pin her down on her several policy flip-flops, on the crisis of affordability in American families on the price of groceries, housing and healthcare, on the inability of the Biden administration to end the war in Gaza or to cripple Russia's economy because of the Ukraine invasion, or to prevent China from attaining superiority in strategic technologies.</p>

<p>On abortion, where he was on the defensive, he could have deeply wounded Harris by pointing out that women seeking abortion in Minnesota face no restriction on which pregnancy stage they opt for abortion at. In fact, Trump mentioned Tom Walz, the Minnesota governor and Harris's V-P nominee, as he began his answer on abortion, but he made only an elliptical reference to Walz and then lost his way. Instead, he alleged that Democrats were allowing unwanted babies to be “executed” after they were born, only to be corrected by the fact-checking moderators.</p>

<h2><strong>Shooting Himself In The Foot</strong></h2>

<p>Much as Harris predicted, Trump brought up immigration even when the question was not about that. He repeatedly ranted at the “millions and millions of criminals and insane lunatics” invading the country and went on to make the fantastic claim that this “invasion” would lead to WW-III.</p>

<p>In his first mention of immigration on the debate, he predictably repeated a lie that Haitian migrants in Ohio were eating cats and dogs of the people. Only, again, to be fact-checked by the moderator that town authorities had completely denied the story. The next day, the parents of the boy whose story had ostensibly led to the lie spread by the right-wing media and brought to national attention by a tweet from J.D. Vance asked the Republicans to back off.</p>

<h2><strong>Did Trump Underestimate Kamala?</strong></h2>

<p>No question, Harris got the debate she would have wanted in her dreams. Trump was either poorly prepared or, more likely, not prepared at all. A&nbsp;<i>New York Post</i>&nbsp;reporter, who has met him over the last 10 years, was shocked to learn at her latest meeting that Trump did not seem to know that Harris's upbringing had little to do with her Marxist-economist professor father. His staff confirmed to her that he was not being briefed.</p>

<p>It was evident in the debate that Trump is yet to come to terms with being denied the opportunity to take revenge from Biden. Sensing this, a sharp Harris reminded him in the debate that it wasn't Biden who he was contesting against, reinforcing the image of a man not in touch with reality. The debate was not even over when Taylor Swift tweeted that she was endorsing Harris, identifying herself as a “Cat Lady”, referring to Vance's rant against “cat ladies”. Swift's endorsement, in the air since the DNC, will impact some of the youth vote.</p>

<h2><strong>A Trip To The 'Spin Room'</strong></h2>

<p>There were other happy straws in the wind to follow for Harris. Word got out that Trump had visited the “spin room” immediately after the debate. This is a room where the candidate's media team gathers to issue denials and clarifications, gauge response and initiate social media ripples, knowing that it is the memes and clips that are played over and over again that agglomerate the debate's impact among fans and critics. Candidates typically never visit the “spin room” post the debate.</p>

<p>The next morning brought further confirmation for Harris when Trump lashed out at the&nbsp;<i>ABC</i>, the host of the debate. He charged the moderators with being biased because of their several fact-checks, which the channel had announced it would do, unlike other media hosts in the past. Trump ranted that the moderators should be criminally prosecuted and that the channel's licence should be revoked.</p>

<p>This was the ultimate proof that Harris had eminently succeeded in her objective of getting under his skin.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>Harris Has Round One</b></h2>

<p>Will there be another debate? Harris needs the vast audience these debates bring — 67 million watched the Tuesday debate — to present her personable and confident self to the electorate. Democrats have made it known they want another slugfest. Trump may not be able to resist the opportunity to get his own back at a candidate who he disparages privately far more than he does so richly in public.</p>

<p>This election will hinge on countless anonymous assessments made regarding which candidate has the better character to be the next President of the United States, based on fleeting and superficial considerations by people with only a scant interest in politics. The Harris team won this gladiatorial contest but the war will be on at full pitch till November 5.</p>

<p><em>(Ajay Kumar is a senior journalist. He is former Managing Editor, Business Standard, and former Executive Editor, The Economic Times.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jgvl6hn8_trump_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/can-social-media-ban-for-children-like-australias-work-evidence-suggests-6556305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Can Social Media Ban For Children Like Australia's Work? Evidence Suggests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/can-social-media-ban-for-children-like-australias-work-evidence-suggests-6556305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 14:51:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Banning children under 16 from social media sounds like a seductive idea. For overwhelmed parents navigating their kids' lives in a digital age, this move from the Australian government may seem like a welcome relief.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">Banning children under 16 from social media <a href="https://theconversation.com/view-from-the-hill-social-media-age-ban-all-to-the-good-but-can-albanese-deliver-before-election-238686">sounds like a seductive idea</a>. For overwhelmed parents <a href="https://theconversation.com/should-parents-be-worried-about-social-media-we-asked-5-experts-238772">navigating their kids' lives</a> in a digital age, this move from the Australian government may seem like a welcome relief.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>However, evidence shows it's highly <a href="https://www.beyondblue.org.au/about/media/media-releases/mental-health-organisations-collaborate-to-call-for-changes-to-social-media-platforms">unlikely bans will positively impact the youth mental health crisis</a> in this country. Indeed, bans <a href="https://theconversation.com/should-parents-be-worried-about-social-media-we-asked-5-experts-238772">may make our children even more vulnerable</a> online.</p>

<p>Children and young people <a href="https://www.westernsydney.edu.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0006/1334805/Young_and_Online_Report.pdf">go online primarily to socialise with their peers</a>. Online spaces are one of the few avenues our <a href="https://theconversation.com/active-or-overscheduled-kids-how-parents-can-consider-benefits-and-risks-of-extracurricular-activities-218988">overscheduled children</a> have to interact freely with each other, which is crucial for their wellbeing.</p>

<h3><strong>Not just safe, but optimal</strong></h3>

<p>Safety by design is not the whole solution. Building on the efforts to develop <a href="https://www.esafety.gov.au/industry/codes#:%7E:text=online%20industry%20must%20prevent%20and,1C%20and%20class%202%20material.">industry codes</a>, industry and government should come together to develop a wider range of standards that deliver not just safe, but <em>optimal</em> digital environments for children.</p>

<p>How? High-quality, child-centred evidence can help major platforms develop industry-wide standards that define what kinds of content are appropriate for children of different ages.</p>

<p>We also need targeted education for children that builds their <a href="https://www.westernsydney.edu.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0004/1976503/Reimagining_Online_Safety_Education.pdf">digital capabilities</a> and prepares them to deal with and grow through their engagement online.</p>

<p>For example, rather than education that focuses on extreme harm, children are calling for online safety education in schools and elsewhere that supports them in managing the low-level, everyday risks of harm they encounter online: disagreements with friends, inappropriate content or feeling excluded.</p>

<h3><strong>Heed the evidence</strong></h3>

<p>Some authoritative, <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/documents/general-comments-and-recommendations/general-comment-no-25-2021-childrens-rights-relation">evidence-based guidance</a> already exists. It tells us how to ensure children can mitigate potential harms and maximise the benefits of the digital environment.</p>

<p>Where the evidence doesn't yet exist, we need to invest in child-centred research. It's the best method for gaining nuanced accounts of children's digital practices and can guide a coherent and strategic <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1745691620919372">long-term approach to policy and practice</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://philarchive.org/rec/STEFSS-5">Drawing on lessons from the COVID pandemic</a>, we also need to better align evidence with decision-making processes. This means speeding up high-quality, robust research processes or finding ways for research to better anticipate and generate evidence around emerging challenges. This way, governments can weigh up the benefits and drawbacks of particular policy actions.</p>

<p>Technology is not beyond our control. Rather, we need to decide, together, what role we want technology to play in childhood.</p>

<p>We need to move beyond a protectionist focus and <a href="https://researchdirect.westernsydney.edu.au/islandora/object/uws%3A44562">work with children themselves</a> to build the very best digital environments we can imagine. Nothing short of the future is at stake in doing so.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238798/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amanda-third-1108">Amanda Third</a>, Co-Director, Young and Resilient Research Centre/Professorial Research Fellow, Institute for Culture and Society, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/western-sydney-university-1092">Western Sydney University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/instead-of-banning-kids-from-online-spaces-heres-what-we-should-offer-them-instead-238798">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ognl4gfo_children-on-social-media-_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Children and young people go online primarily to socialise with their peers (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-species-emerged-as-tectonic-plates-shifted-surprise-discovery-6555726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Species Emerged As Tectonic Plates Shifted: Surprise Discovery]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-species-emerged-as-tectonic-plates-shifted-surprise-discovery-6555726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 13:26:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Coelacanths are deep-sea fish that live off the coasts of southern Africa and Indonesia and can reach up to two metres in length. For a long time, scientists believed they were extinct.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Coelacanths are deep-sea fish that live off the coasts of southern Africa and Indonesia and can reach up to two metres in length. For a long time, scientists believed they were extinct.</span></p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>In <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-51238-4">new research</a> published in Nature Communications, we reveal the best-preserved coelacanth fossil ever found from the ancient period hundreds of millions of years ago when these ancient sea-dwellers first evolved. The fossil comes from the Gogo Formation on Gooniyandi Country in northern Western Australia.</p>

<p>We also studied the evolution of all the hundreds of coelacanth species we know from the fossil record to find out what drove the creation of new species across the aeons.</p>

<p>The answer came as a surprise: the greatest influence on coelacanth evolution was not ocean.</p>

<p>Later, during the age of dinosaurs which began around 250 million years ago, coelacanths became more diverse. In total, we have found traces of more than 175 fossil species from all over the globe.</p>

<p>Finally, at the end of the Cretaceous period, 66 million years ago, all signs of coelacanths mysteriously vanished from the fossil record. For a long time, scientists assumed the coelacanths were casualties of the massive asteroid impact that also signed the death warrant of the dinosaurs (along with around three-quarters of all life on Earth).</p>

<p>All that changed in 1938, when fisherpeople in South Africa pulled a large, enigmatic fish from the ocean depths that was like nothing they had seen before. A local museum employee with a keen interest in the natural sciences, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marjorie_Courtenay-Latimer">Marjorie Courtenay-Latimer</a>, immediately knew the fish was special.</p>

<p>Courtenay-Latimer enlisted her friend <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._L._B._Smith">J. L. B. Smith</a>, a renowned South African chemist with an interest in ichthyology (the study of fish). Smith identified and named <em>Latimeria</em>, the first living coelacanth known to science.</p>

<p>Discovering this “Lazarus fish” was like stumbling across a live <em>Triceratops</em> dinosaur still roaming the forests of North America today. Even today, coelacanths are often described as “living fossils”.</p>

<h3><strong>A new fossil coelacanth</strong></h3>

<p>Our team from Flinders University, together with other colleagues from Australia, Canada and Europe, discovered a new species of fossil coelacanth on Gooniyandi Country in northern WA. Around 380 million years ago, the site was a tropical reef teeming with more than 50 species of fish.</p>

<p><em>Ngamugawi wirngarri</em>, the new fossil coelacanth, is the first fish found in the area to bear a name given to us from the Gooniyandi language. The name means “ancient fish in honour of Wirngarri”, a respected elder of the community.</p>

<p><em>Ngamugawi</em> is the best three-dimensionally preserved coelacanth from the Devonian Period (359 million to 419 million years ago). This fossil provides a great insight into the early anatomy of this lineage.</p>

<h3><strong>Plate tectonics drive coelacanth evolution</strong></h3>

<p>Our study of the new species led us to analyse the evolutionary history of all known coelacanths. In doing so, we calculated the rates of evolution across their 410 million-year history.</p>

<p>We found that coelacanths have generally evolved slowly, with a few intriguing exceptions.</p>

<p>Furthermore, we analysed a series of environmental factors that we considered potential candidates for influencing coelacanth evolutionary rates. These included tectonic plate activity, ocean temperatures, water oxygen levels, and atmospheric carbon dioxide levels.</p>

<p>Of all the variables we looked at, the one with the greatest influence on the rate of coelacanth evolution was tectonic plate activity. New species of coelacanth were more likely to evolve during periods of heightened tectonic activity, as seismic movement transformed habitats.</p>

<h3><strong>Are coelacanths still evolving?</strong></h3>

<p>Along with our analysis of all fossil coelacanths, we also had a close look at the two living species, <em>Latimeria chalumnae</em> and <em>Latimeria menadoensis</em>.</p>

<p>At first glance, these fish look almost identical to some of their counterparts from hundreds of millions of years ago. However, on closer analysis, we could see they were in fact distinct from their extinct relatives.</p>

<p>While <em>Latimeria</em> has essentially ceased evolving new features, the proportions of its body and the details of its DNA are still changing a little. So perhaps it's not a “living fossil” after all.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/236693/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/alice-clement-277093">Alice Clement</a>, Research Associate in the College of Science and Engineering, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/john-long-98402">John Long</a>, Strategic Professor in Palaeontology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/exceptional-new-fish-fossil-sparks-rethink-of-how-earths-geology-drives-evolution-236693">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/njoh1kt_coelacanth_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Coelacanths are deep-sea fish up to two metres in length which were believed to have been extinct.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>