<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 10:20:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-7-eleven-may-go-private-to-avoid-45-billion-foreign-buyout-7007166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan's 7-Eleven May Go Private To Avoid $45 Billion Foreign Buyout]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-7-eleven-may-go-private-to-avoid-45-billion-foreign-buyout-7007166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 10:00:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Japanese owner of 7-Eleven is considering going private by buying back its own shares in a bid to avoid a takeover attempt by Canadian rival Alimentation Couche-Tard.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Japanese owner of 7-Eleven is considering going private by buying back its own shares in a bid to avoid a takeover attempt by Canadian rival Alimentation Couche-Tard, according to a report Wednesday.</p>

<p>Seven &amp; i Holdings is eyeing the move as a countermeasure to Couche-Tard's seven trillion yen ($45 billion) takeover proposal, the Nikkei business daily said, citing sources close to the company.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j17n6lu8_7eleven_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Seven & i Holdings is eyeing to go private.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-replaces-ceo-of-futuristic-mega-city-neom-amid-rising-scepticism-7007137]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia Replaces CEO Of Futuristic Mega-City NEOM Amid Rising Scepticism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-replaces-ceo-of-futuristic-mega-city-neom-amid-rising-scepticism-7007137]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:50:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia announced that it was replacing the chief executive of its futuristic mega-city NEOM as scepticism mounts over the Gulf kingdom's most ambitious development projects.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia announced Tuesday that it was replacing the chief executive of its futuristic mega-city NEOM as scepticism mounts over the Gulf kingdom's most ambitious development projects.</p>

<p>"Following the departure of Nadhmi al-Nasr", who had served as the project's chief executive since 2018, "Aiman al-Mudaifer has been appointed as interim CEO", NEOM said in a statement.</p>

<p>The company said that Mudaifer brought with him a "deep and strategic understanding of NEOM" after serving as head of a property arm of the Saudi sovereign wealth fund since 2018.</p>

<p>There has been mounting scepticism over signature projects such as NEOM, a planned futuristic megacity in northwestern Saudi Arabia meant to feature a ski resort and twin skyscrapers 170 kilometres (105 miles) long.</p>

<p>Authorities have reportedly scaled back 2030 size and population targets for NEOM, though officials have not confirmed any revisions.</p>

<p>Unveiling The Line in 2022, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, the country's de facto leader, said its population would exceed one million by 2030 before climbing to nine million by 2045.</p>

<p>However, Bloomberg reported earlier this year that under revised projections just 300,000 people would be living in The Line by decade's end, and only 2.4 kilometres of the project would be completed by then.</p>

<p>Work on NEOM is progressing alongside other major development projects launched as part of Vision 2030, Prince Mohammed's bid to position the world's biggest crude exporter for an eventual post-oil future.</p>

<p>Last year the Gulf kingdom emerged as the only bidder to host the 2034 football World Cup, meaning it now has a decade to build the necessary stadiums and boost its lodging and transport capacity.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r6shj5j_neom_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There has been mounting scepticism over signature projects such as NEOM. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysias-former-finance-minister-daim-zainuddin-dies-at-86-7006898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Malaysia's Former Finance Minister Daim Zainuddin Dies At 86]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysias-former-finance-minister-daim-zainuddin-dies-at-86-7006898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:08:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Malaysian Finance Minister Daim Zainuddin, who pleaded not guilty to charges of failing to disclose assets earlier this year, died early on Wednesday, his lawyer said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Malaysian Finance Minister Daim Zainuddin, who pleaded not guilty to charges of failing to disclose assets earlier this year, died early on Wednesday, his lawyer said.</p>

<p>The 86-year-old Daim served as finance minister from 1984 to 1991 and from 1999 to 2001 under former premier Mahathir Mohamad.</p>

<p>His lawyer, Gurdial Singh Nijar, confirmed Daim's passing to Reuters, and said the funeral would be held on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"In the past few weeks, he was in ICU (intensive care unit) after he had a stroke," Singh Nijar said, but added that he did not know the cause of death.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Daim, an ally of veteran leader Mahathir, was charged with failing to disclose assets under an anti-corruption law in one of the highest-profile graft cases involving prominent figures. Daim had pleaded not guilty.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/slf6eve_daim-zainuddin_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Daim was an ally of veteran leader Mahathir.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-doge-in-donald-trumps-us-government-what-it-is-7006861]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk To Lead 'DOGE' In Donald Trump's US Government. What It Is]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-doge-in-donald-trumps-us-government-what-it-is-7006861]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 08:59:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk, alongside Indian-American entrepreneur Vivek Ramaswamy, will lead the 'Department of Government Efficiency' in the Donald Trump-led US government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, alongside Indian-American entrepreneur Vivek Ramaswamy, will lead the '<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-us-government-efficiency-department-donald-trump-7006239">Department of Government Efficiency</a>' in the Donald Trump-led US government, the US President-elect announced on Wednesday. According to Trump, the duo will provide "advice and guidance" from outside the government and will partner with the White House and Office of Management and Budget to drive large-scale structural reform.</p>

<h3><strong>What is the Department of Government Efficiency?&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Department of Government Efficiency is a new wing in the new Donald Trump-led US government. It was first proposed by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-elon-musk-starlink-what-trumps-praise-for-musks-starlink-could-mean-for-internet-in-india-6962613">Musk</a> and was championed by Trump as a way to cut down on government bureaucracy. The department goes by the acronym 'DOGE' - the name of the Dogecoin cryptocurrency often touted by Musk.</p>

<p>While it is not immediately clear how the department would work, according to Trump, Musk and Ramaswamy's mission under this department will be to dismantle government bureaucracy, slash excess regulations, cut wasteful expenditures, and restructure federal agencies.</p>

<p>Trump believes that 'DOGE' can be the 'Manhattan Project' of this time. The 'Manhattan Project', led by the US in collaboration with the UK and Canada, was a research and developmental program undertaken during World War II to produce the first nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>Musk's position in this department could represent a conflict of interest for him as the companies he runs, including Tesla and SpaceX, have billions of dollars worth of federal contracts and have benefited from federal spending, including electric vehicle tax credits and infrastructure investments, reported Bloomberg.</p>

<h3><strong>What Elon Musk said&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Elon Musk, in a statement, said that the 'DOGE' will send "shockwaves through the system and anyone involved in government waste".</p>

<p>"This will send shockwaves through the system, and anyone involved in Government waste, which is a lot of people!" he said.</p>

<p>The staunch supporter of Trump added that all actions of the 'DOGE' will be posted online for maximum transparency.</p>

<p>"Anytime the public thinks we are cutting something important or not cutting something wasteful, just let us know! We will also have a leaderboard for the most insanely dumb spending of your tax dollars. This will be both extremely tragic and extremely entertaining," he said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-asks-elon-musk-to-join-call-with-ukraines-zelensky-in-big-hint-at-his-possible-role-6976601">Donald Trump</a>, who won the presidential elections last week defeating Democratic rival Kamala Harris by 69 electoral votes, had hinted at a top position for Musk in the government during his Presidential campaign. Musk was a key part of the Republican's Presidential campaign who donated over 100 million dollars to Trump's re-election battle.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0lbt9618_elon-musk_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has been a staunch supporter of Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-matga-movement-a-deadly-tiktok-trend-glorifying-poisoning-men-after-trumps-win-7006527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deadly 'MATGA Movement' Emerges In US After Trump's Win, Here's What It Is]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-matga-movement-a-deadly-tiktok-trend-glorifying-poisoning-men-after-trumps-win-7006527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 07:38:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Following Donald Trump's victory in the US presidential elections, a new trend has emerged on social media platforms called the 'MATGA movement'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following Donald Trump's victory in the US presidential elections, a new trend has emerged on social media platforms called the 'MATGA movement'. The 'Make Aqua Tofana Great Again' or 'MATGA' movement hits out at Donald Trump's popular 'Make America Great Again' (MAGA) slogan. In this movement, US women are filming murder-fantasy videos in which they lace men's drinks with deadly poison. Notably, the movement is a nod to ancient killer Giulia Tofana - a 17th-century Italian woman who sold Aqua Tofana poison to women who wanted to murder their husbands because of violence at home.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/what-matga-anti-trump-women-deadly-new-trend-giulia-tofana-1983610"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, social media videos related to this trend show young women smiling as they add unknown substances to drinks. Some clips also show women advertising poison rings that can be worn on fingers.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">HOLY SH*T, Karens lost their fvcking minds over Trump's win and launched MATGA—short for Make Aqua Tofana Great Again.<br />
<br />
Aqua Tofana was a powerful poison in 17th-century Sicily, sold by women to other women seeking to escape abusive relationships by discreetly poisoning their… <a href="https://t.co/KvHK8ZXWz4">pic.twitter.com/KvHK8ZXWz4</a></p>
— I Meme Therefore I Am ?? (@ImMeme0) <a href="https://twitter.com/ImMeme0/status/1855428375734841575?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>MATGA movement owes most of its development to Giulia Tofana. Her invention, the famous Aqua Tofana poison, was a deadly, undetectable poison used across Italy, gaining notoriety for its stealth and potency. The poison was typically concealed in everyday cosmetic containers, allowing unsuspecting husbands to remain oblivious to their approaching demise.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Therefore, the MATGA trend has become synonymous with Tofana. This movement comes after misogynistic phrases like "Your body, my choice" went viral online following Mr Trump's presidential win with men messaging random women online threatening them that their bodies no longer belong to them. So, the MATGA movement seems to be in response to this rising misogynistic hate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Some people online have framed this latest movement as a modern-day reminder of the long-standing fight for women's rights. However, according to <em>Newsweek</em>, critics have argued that referring to a deadly poison, even in jest, can send the wrong message.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heres-how-indians-reacted-to-elon-musks-comments-on-canada-pm-justin-trudeau-6999001">Here's How Indians Reacted To Elon Musk's Comments On Canada PM Justin Trudeau</a></strong></p>

<p>One TikToker urged women who are taking part in "MATGA" to think about the consequences of poisoning people. "You do know those videos can be used against you, right? The internet is forever. Also, the 1600s were a lot different than 2024 advancements in detecting poison," read the caption of one video.</p>

<p>Separately, Georgia Representative Marjorie Taylor Greene raised an alarm to the FBI and called for an investigation into the "public death threats". "@FBI these are public death threats and must [be] investigated! These women are telling others how to poison and murder men because they are angry over the election. If you tracked down J6'ers (January 6 rioters), pro-lifers, parents angry at school boards, then you better go after these psychopaths!" Ms Greene said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fsjb7rqg_matga-movement_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[MATGA movement owes most of its development to Giulia Tofana.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-strikes-iranian-backed-groups-in-syria-7006505]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Military Strikes 'Iranian-Backed Groups' In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-strikes-iranian-backed-groups-in-syria-7006505]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 07:33:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US forces on Tuesday carried out strikes against targets linked to an Iranian-backed groups in Syria in response to a rocket attack on Washington's troops in the country, the US military said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American forces on Tuesday carried out strikes against targets linked to an Iranian-backed militia in Syria in response to a rocket attack on Washington's troops in the country, the US military said.</p>

<p>The strikes targeted the group's "weapons storage and logistics headquarters facility... in response to a rocket attack on US personnel," the US Central Command (CENTCOM) said in a post on social media that did not identify the militia by name.</p>

<p>"There was no damage to US facilities and no injuries to US or partner forces during the attack," CENTCOM said.</p>

<p>The previous day, US forces bombed nine targets associated with Iranian-backed groups in response to recent drone and rocket attacks, according to the Pentagon.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a monitoring group, said the Monday strikes killed four members of groups loyal to Iran.</p>

<p>The US military has around 900 troops in Syria and 2,500 in Iraq as part of the international coalition that was established in 2014 to help combat the Islamic State jihadist group.</p>

<p>Since war broke out in the Gaza Strip after Hamas attacked Israel on October 7, 2023, pro-Iran groups have repeatedly targeted US forces in Iraq and Syria in response to Washington's support for Israel.</p>

<p>The United States has on multiple occasions responded to such attacks with strikes on Iran-backed groups.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kttp0688_israeli-strike-in-syria_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US military has around 900 troops in Syria. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-us-government-efficiency-department-donald-trump-7006239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Top Roles For Elon Musk, Vivek Ramaswamy In Donald Trump's Cabinet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-us-government-efficiency-department-donald-trump-7006239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 06:29:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump announced that Elon Musk will lead the 'Department of Government Efficiency'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump announced that Elon Musk will lead the 'Department of Government Efficiency' - a position Trump hinted at during his campaign trail. Musk will head the department alongside Indian-American entrepreneur Vivek Ramaswamy.</p>

<p>"Together, these two wonderful Americans will pave the way for my Administration to dismantle Government Bureaucracy, slash excess regulations, cut wasteful expenditures, and restructure Federal Agencies - Essential to the 'Save America' Movement," Trump said in a statement.</p>

<p>"I look forward to Elon and Vivek making changes to the Federal Bureaucracy with an eye on efficiency and, at the same time, making life better for all Americans," he added.</p>

<p>According to Trump, they will drive out the "massive waste and fraud" from the government.</p>

<p>Donald Trump won the presidential elections last week, defeating Democratic rival Kamala Harris by 69 electoral votes.</p>

<p>During his <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-live-thats-why-i-love-you-big-elon-musk-mention-in-donald-trumps-victory-speech-6955600">victory speech</a>, Trump praised Musk and described him as an "amazing and super genius guy". He also mentioned that the billionaire spent two weeks in Philadelphia and Pennsylvania campaigning with him.</p>

<p>"We have a new star, a star is born: Elon. He's an amazing guy. We were sitting together tonight. You know, he spent two weeks in Philadelphia, in different parts of Pennsylvania, campaigning," Trump told his supporters.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-asks-elon-musk-to-join-call-with-ukraines-zelensky-in-big-hint-at-his-possible-role-6976601">Musk</a>, who has been a staunch supporter of Trump, was a key part of the Republican's Presidential campaign. The Tesla CEO donated over 100 million dollars to Trump's re-election battle and campaigned aggressively using his social media platform X (formerly Twitter).</p>

<p>On November 9, Trump made it even more evident that Musk would be a part of his administration after he reportedly asked him to join a call with Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelensky. According to a Ukrainian official, Zelensky thanked Musk for the Starlinks and they talked briefly, however, the main conversation was with Trump, reported news agency AFP.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j013fjh8_elon-musk-trump-_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump won the US presidential election against Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-attack-us-warships-with-drones-missiles-pentagon-7006088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthis Attack US Warships With Drones, Missiles: Pentagon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-attack-us-warships-with-drones-missiles-pentagon-7006088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 05:32:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Huthi rebels targeted two US destroyers with drones and missiles as they transited the Bab al-Mandab Strait, but the warships defeated the attacks, the Pentagon said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Yemen's Huthi rebels targeted two US destroyers with drones and missiles as they transited the Bab al-Mandab Strait, but the warships defeated the attacks, the Pentagon said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The Huthis began striking ships in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden in November 2023, part of the region-wide fallout from Israel's devastating war in Gaza, which groups in multiple countries have cited as justification for attacks.</p>

<p>The US warships "were attacked by at least eight one-way attack uncrewed aerial systems, five anti-ship ballistic missiles and three anti-ship cruise missiles, which were successfully engaged and defeated," Pentagon spokesman Major General Pat Ryder told journalists.</p>

<p>"The vessels were not damaged, no personnel were hurt," Ryder said of the Monday attacks.</p>

<p>A claim from the Huthis that they also attacked the USS Abraham Lincoln aircraft carrier is not accurate, he said.</p>

<p>"Based on the information I have, it was not attacked, contrary to some of the allegations... by the Huthis," Ryder said, declining to specify the carrier's location.</p>

<p>The Yemeni rebels say their attacks -- a significant international security challenge that threatens a major shipping lane -- are in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza.</p>

<p>Anger over Israel's ongoing military campaign in the small coastal territory, which began after an unprecedented Hamas attack on October 7, has stoked violence involving Iran-backed groups in Lebanon, Iraq, Syria and Yemen.</p>

<p>The United States and other countries have deployed military vessels to help shield shipping from the Huthi strikes, but attacks directly targeting American warships are relatively rare.</p>

<p>Washington's forces have also carried out frequent air strikes on the Huthis in a bid to degrade their ability to target shipping and have sought to seize weapons before they reach the rebels, but their attacks have persisted.</p>

<p>Ryder said Tuesday that US forces carried out multiple air strikes over the weekend against Huthi weapons storage facilities.</p>

<p>"These facilities housed a variety of advanced conventional weapons used by the Iran-backed Huthis to target US and international military and civilian vessels navigating international waters," he said, noting that both US Air Force and Navy assets were involved.</p>

<p>US forces also targeted Iran-backed groups in Syria on Monday in response to drone and rocket attacks on American troops in that country the previous day.</p>

<p>The attacks did not result in any American casualties, according to Ryder, who said he did not have information to provide on whether the subsequent US strikes killed or wounded operatives.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/omrp6b7g_houthis-attacks-us-ship_625x300_19_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Yemeni rebels say their attacks are in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-33-killed-in-israeli-strikes-says-lebanon-7006032]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[33 Killed In Israeli Strikes, Says Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-33-killed-in-israeli-strikes-says-lebanon-7006032]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 05:18:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon said Israeli strikes killed 33 people across the country on Tuesday, among them many who had been displaced by the intensified conflict between Israel and Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon said Israeli strikes killed 33 people across the country on Tuesday, among them many who had been displaced by the intensified conflict between Israel and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The attacks targeted not only known Hezbollah strongholds such as the southern suburbs of Beirut, but also areas where the Iran-backed group has not traditionally had a presence.</p>

<p>The health ministry said a strike on a town in the Chouf region south of Beirut killed at least 15 people, revising a previous toll upwards from 12.</p>

<p>"The Israeli raid on Joun in the Chouf district resulted... in the death of 15 martyrs, including eight women and four children," it said.</p>

<p>Twelve others were wounded in the strike, the ministry added.</p>

<p>The official National News Agency (NNA) said the building had housed displaced people fleeing bombardment by Israel in its war against Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The health ministry said a strike a few kilometres further north in the mountainous Aley region east of the capital killed eight people.</p>

<p>A security source told AFP the attack had hit a house where people displaced in the war had taken refuge.</p>

<p>The ministry also reported one dead in an Israeli strike in the Tyre area in south Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>Two killed in Israel</strong></p>

<p>Elsewhere in the south of the country, the ministry reported strikes on the towns of Tefahta and Roumin killed seven people.</p>

<p>Attacks on the Hermel region in the Bekaa Valley in the east of the country bordering Syria killed another two people.</p>

<p>Nabatiyeh, the largest city in the south, again came under attack. Last month, Israeli strikes razed its historic marketplace and killed the mayor.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, meanwhile, said it fired missiles at an air base near Tel Aviv, following a wave of Israeli air strikes on the group's south Beirut bastion.</p>

<p>Israel reported two people killed in the northern town of Nahariya by rocket fire from Lebanon.</p>

<p>Since September 23, Israel has stepped up its bombing campaign in Lebanon, mainly targeting Hezbollah strongholds in south Beirut and in the east and south of the country. On September 30, it sent in ground troops.</p>

<p>Israeli strikes outside Hezbollah strongholds have often targeted buildings where displaced civilians have sought refuge, with Lebanese security officials telling AFP the targets were Hezbollah operatives.</p>

<p>On Tuesday morning Israel launched more than a dozen air strikes on south Beirut, state media said, shortly after its military warned residents of four districts to evacuate.</p>

<p><strong>Thousands killed in Lebanon</strong></p>

<p>Israel's military said it had hit "Hezbollah terrorist targets" in south Beirut including "command centres, weapons production sites, and additional Hezbollah terrorist infrastructure".</p>

<p>Witnesses told AFP they heard gunfire in the area ahead of the strikes -- warning shots by residents for people to leave following the evacuation call.</p>

<p>The Lebanon war came after nearly a year of cross-border exchanges of fire, launched by Hezbollah in support of Hamas following its Palestinian ally's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel that triggered the Gaza war.</p>

<p>With little sign of an end to the conflict, UN peacekeeping chief Jean-Pierre Lacroix met Prime Minister Najib Mikati in Beirut on Tuesday as part of a visit aimed at boosting calls for a ceasefire.</p>

<p>More than 3,300 people have been killed in Lebanon since the clashes began last year, according to the health ministry, the majority of them since late September.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel reported 2 people killed in Nahariya by rocket fire from Lebanon. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-major-push-for-nuclear-power-india-asks-states-to-set-up-reactors-7005942]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Major Push For Nuclear Power, India Asks States To Set Up Reactors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-major-push-for-nuclear-power-india-asks-states-to-set-up-reactors-7005942]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 04:49:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has ambitious plans to set up nuclear reactors across the country, especially in states where thermal power plants have either completed its life, or where access to coal is a challenge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has ambitious plans to set up nuclear reactors across the country, especially in states where thermal power plants have either completed its life, or where access to coal is a challenge.</p>

<p>With its focus on clean energy, India aims to reduce its dependence fossil fuels, and for this, the central government has now asked states to set up nuclear power plants.</p>

<p>India's Power Minister, Manohar Lal, on Tuesday chaired the Conference of Power Ministers of States &amp; Union Territories where he asked states that are distant from coal resources to set up nuclear-based power plants. The move has also been made keeping in mind the rapidly-growing demand for electricity in the country.</p>

<p>In the Union Budget, the central government had proposed to partner with private investors to set up small-scale nuclear reactors to meet its growing energy demands.</p>

<p>"States should consider setting up nuclear power plants at the sites where coal-based thermal power plants have completed their life," the Union Minister told state governments as per a statement issued by the Centre.</p>

<p>The minister also asked states to identify power utilities and list them on the stock exchange to meet its investment targets in the power sector. Asking states to ramp up its renewable energy capacity, the minister emphasised on the need to improve transmission systems in order to achieve that.</p>

<p>Many foreign power plant builders have stayed away from building atomic and nuclear plants in India because of stringent laws over compensation as well as very strict rules and regulations imposed by New Delhi in the event of an accident, mishap or leak.</p>

<p>India currently has 24 nuclear power plants in operation. All of them are run and maintained by the Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited or NPCIL, which comes under the Department of Atomic Energy. NPCIL is a government-owned public sector undertaking or PSU, headquartered in Mumbai.</p>

<p>India's current power generation from nuclear plants is around 8 gigawatt. New Delhi has ambitious plans to increase this to more than 20 gigawatt by 2032.</p>

<p>Being the only G20 nation to achieve its climate goals ahead of its deadline, India aims to add 500 gigawatt of renewable energy to its grid by 2030. Prime Minister Narendra Modi has also pledged to make India a nation with net-zero carbon emission by 2070.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-03/nuclear-reactor-istock_650x400_51490779852.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has asked states to consider setting up nuclear plants to reduce dependency on fossil fuels]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-airman-gets-15-year-jail-over-leaking-classified-pentagon-documents-report-7005939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Airman Gets 15 Year Jail Over Leaking Classified Documents: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-airman-gets-15-year-jail-over-leaking-classified-pentagon-documents-report-7005939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 04:41:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US airman who admitted to leaking a trove of classified Pentagon documents was jailed for 15 years on Tuesday, US media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US airman who admitted to leaking a trove of classified Pentagon documents was jailed for 15 years on Tuesday, US media reported.</p>

<p>Jack Teixeira orchestrated the most damaging leak of classified information in a decade while serving as an IT specialist with the Massachusetts Air National Guard.</p>

<p>He posted highly sensitive documents on the social media platform Discord, from which they spread across the internet.</p>

<p>"I wanted to say that I'm sorry for all of the harm that I've brought and that I've caused, and that I don't think I can really sum up how contrite I am," Teixeira told the court ahead of sentencing, The Boston Globe reported.</p>

<p>Jack Teixeira, whose family members were in court for the sentencing, was arrested in April 2023 and pleaded guilty in March this year to six federal counts of willful retention and transmission of national defense information.</p>

<p>Because he was on active duty at the time of the offenses, he was subject to both federal law and the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</p>

<p>He will now face a military trial.</p>

<p>The documents leaked by Teixeira pointed to US concern over Ukraine's military capacity against invading Russian forces, and also showed Washington had apparently spied on allies Israel and South Korea, among other sensitive details.</p>

<p>It was the biggest such breach since the 2013 dump of National Security Agency documents by Edward Snowden, and raised serious questions about access by Teixeira and other junior staffers to high-level secrets.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4rvr5vq_jack-teixeira-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jack Teixeira was arrested in April 2023. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-mike-huckabee-as-next-us-ambassador-to-israel-7005882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Nominates Mike Huckabee As Next US Ambassador To Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-mike-huckabee-as-next-us-ambassador-to-israel-7005882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 04:29:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump said on Tuesday he was nominating former Arkansas Governor Mike Huckabee as the next U.S. ambassador to Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump said on Tuesday he was nominating former Arkansas Governor Mike Huckabee as the next U.S. ambassador to Israel, tapping a staunchly pro-Israel conservative whose choice could signal future U.S. policy toward conflicts in the Middle East.</p>

<p>An evangelical Christian, Huckabee has been a vocal supporter of Israel throughout his political career and a longtime defender of Jewish settlements in the occupied West Bank. A former Republican presidential hopeful, Huckabee hosted a weekly Fox News TV show for six years ending in 2015.</p>

<p>"There's no such thing as an occupation," Huckabee said in a 2017 interview with CNN, in which he referred to the West Bank by its biblical names Judea and Samaria.</p>

<p>Evangelicals are an overwhelmingly pro-Israel part of Trump's base and voted heavily in favor of him in the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>Trump's announcement of the nomination drew immediate praise from senior Israeli officials but was likely to be slammed by Palestinians, whose nationalist cause Huckabee has denigrated in the past.</p>

<p>"He loves Israel, and the people of Israel, and likewise, the people of Israel love him. Mike will work tirelessly to bring about Peace in the Middle East!" Trump said in a statement.</p>

<p>Huckabee, 69, would take on one of Washington's most sensitive diplomatic posts at a time when Israel is fighting the Palestinian group Hamas in Gaza and the Hezbollah armed group in Lebanon while facing off against regional arch-foe Iran.</p>

<p>Huckabee has criticized President Joe Biden for pressuring Israel to moderate its conduct of the Gaza war and has opposed the current Democratic administration's calls for a ceasefire there.</p>

<p>"If a person is pro-Israel, how can you be pro-Biden because the Biden administration has made it very clear they will make concessions to Hamas," Huckabee said in an interview in March on News Nation.</p>

<p><strong>ISRAELI OFFICIALS HAIL NOMINATION</strong></p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and his allies celebrated the election of Trump, a staunch but sometimes unpredictable ally of Israel. In his first term the Republican president-elect delivered major wins for the Israeli leader.</p>

<p>Members of Netanyahu's right-wing coalition, which includes pro-settler parties that oppose Palestinian statehood, hailed Huckabee's nomination.</p>

<p>"I look forward to working with you to strengthen the bond between our peoples," Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar wrote on X. "As a longstanding friend of Israel and our eternal capital Jerusalem - I hope you will feel very much at home."</p>

<p>Trump has strongly backed Netanyahu's goal of destroying Hamas but has called for Israel to finish the job quickly. He has promised to bring peace to the Middle East but has not said how.</p>

<p>If his first term is any indication, Trump is likely to pursue a strongly pro-Israel approach, going even beyond the solid support given by Biden to Washington's top regional ally.</p>

<p>Huckabee, who has led evangelical tours to Israel for years, has been a supporter of Israeli settlement building in the West Bank, which Palestinians want as part of an independent state that would include the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Most of the international community views as illegal the settlements on the West Bank land occupied by Israel in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>

<p>Huckabee served as Arkansas governor from 1996 to 2007. He fell short in bids for the Republican nomination for president in 2008 and 2016.</p>

<p>His daughter, Sarah Huckabee Sanders, is the current governor of Arkansas. She served as Trump's White House press secretary from 2017 to 2019.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d6josbp8_mike-huckabee_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mike Huckabee served as Arkansas governor from 1996 to 2007.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-the-church-of-england-hit-by-unprecedented-scandal-will-pick-its-next-leader-7005688]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Church Of England, Hit By Unprecedented Scandal, Will Pick A New Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-the-church-of-england-hit-by-unprecedented-scandal-will-pick-its-next-leader-7005688]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 03:17:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The archbishop of Canterbury, Justin Welby, resigned over an abuse cover-up scandal on Tuesday, marking an unprecedented moment for the Church of England.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The archbishop of Canterbury, Justin Welby, resigned over an abuse cover-up scandal on Tuesday, marking an unprecedented moment for the Church of England.</p>

<p>He becomes the first leader of the church, as well as the wider Anglican Communion of 85 million Christians worldwide, to be forced out in this manner, religious experts say.</p>

<p>Announcing he is leaving "in sorrow," Welby said the timing of his departure would be decided once a review of his remaining obligations had been completed.</p>

<p>The 68-year-old had been in the role since 2013, and would have been expected to retire around age 70.</p>

<h2><strong>HOW IS THE LIST OF CANDIDATES WHITTLED DOWN?</strong></h2>

<p>A period of consultation on the needs of the Church of England, as well as the Anglican Communion, will be followed by an appointment of a Crown Nominations Committee.</p>

<p>The committee will consist of 17 voting members, including the archbishop of York who is the second-most-senior bishop in the institution, another bishop elected by the House of Bishops, and representatives from the Anglican Communion, the Diocese of Canterbury, and the church's governing body - the General Synod.</p>

<p>It will be chaired by an Anglican, ideally in public life, chosen by Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</p>

<p>Assembling the committee could take a couple of months, David Thompson, emeritus professor of modern church history at the University of Cambridge, told Reuters, adding that the whole process could take up to six months.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT DOES THE COMMITTEE DO?</strong></h3>

<p>The committee will make a recommendation to Starmer. If the prime minister accepts it, he will put the name forward to King Charles, who is the supreme governor of the Church of England.</p>

<h3><strong>WHO ARE POSSIBLE SUCCESSORS? &nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Three bishops have been tipped to succeed Welby as the 106th archbishop of Canterbury: Martyn Snow, the bishop of Leicester, Graham Usher, the bishop of Norwich, and Guli Francis-Dehqani, the bishop of Chelmsford.</p>

<p>Snow abstained in a church assembly vote on blessing for gay couples, while Usher is in favour of gay rights and has pushed for higher taxes on fossil-fuel companies.</p>

<p>Francis-Dehqani, who was ordained in 2017, just three years after the first woman bishop was appointed, was born in Iran and has spoken about how her brother was murdered in the aftermath of the Iranian Revolution.</p>

<p>She would be the first woman to become archbishop if selected.</p>

<p>Francis-Dehqani and Usher were among 44 bishops who signed a letter last year expressing regret that the authorisation of standalone services to bless same-sex couples had been delayed.</p>

<h3><strong>WHAT AWAITS THEM?</strong></h3>

<p>The new archbishop will likely face the same persistent divisions on same-sex relationships that Welby tried to balance during his 11-year tenure.</p>

<p>It has been a matter of contention not just in the wider Anglican Communion, which includes African churches where homosexuality is taboo, but also within the Church of England.</p>

<p>"The principal problem for the archbishop of Canterbury ... is that he combines the role of the primate of all England, with being the head of the Anglican Communion," Thompson said. "This is effectively a relic of empire, because that was the context in which the Anglican Communion developed.</p>

<p>"It increasingly in the late 20th century and the early 21st century has revealed a conflict of role which hasn't been satisfactorily resolved during Archbishop Welby's tenure." &nbsp;</p>

<p>In his resignation, Welby said his decision made it "clear how seriously the Church of England understands the need for change."</p>

<p>"For nearly twelve years I have struggled to introduce improvements," he wrote. "It is for others to judge what has been done."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d8filkdg_justin-welby-archbishop-of-canterbury-resigns-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The archbishop of Canterbury, Justin Welby, resigned over an abuse cover-up scandal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photos-donald-trumps-cabinet-whos-been-picked-whos-in-the-running-7005593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Photos: Donald Trump's Cabinet - Who's Been Picked, Who's In The Running]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photos-donald-trumps-cabinet-whos-been-picked-whos-in-the-running-7005593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 02:40:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has begun the process of choosing a cabinet and selecting other high-ranking administration officials following his presidential election victory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has begun the process of choosing a cabinet and selecting other high-ranking administration officials following his presidential election victory.</p>

<p>Here are the early picks and top contenders for some of the key posts overseeing defense, intelligence, diplomacy, trade, immigration and economic policymaking. Some are in contention for a range of posts.</p>

<h2><strong>SUSIE WILES, Chief Of Staff</strong></h2>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fbdesfik_susie-wiles-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced last week that Wiles, one of his two campaign managers, will be his White House chief of staff.</p>

<p>While the specifics of her political views are somewhat unclear, Wiles, 67, is credited with running a successful and efficient campaign. Supporters hope she will instill a sense of order and discipline that was often lacking during Trump's first four-year term, when he cycled through a number of chiefs of staff.</p>

<h3><strong>TOM HOMAN, 'Border Czar'</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/32u43a4c_tom-homan-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced on Sunday night that Homan, the acting director of Immigration and Customs Enforcement during Trump's first administration, will be in charge of the country's borders.</p>

<p>Trump made cracking down on people in the country illegally a central element of his campaign, promising mass deportations.</p>

<p>Homan, 62, said on Monday he would prioritize deporting immigrants in the U.S. illegally who posed safety and security threats as well as those working at job sites.</p>

<p>Trump, in a post on his Truth Social platform, said Homan will be "in charge of our nation's borders ('The Border Czar'), including, but not limited to, the Southern Border, the Northern Border, all Maritime, and Aviation Security," including the deportation of immigrants in the U.S. illegally.</p>

<h3><strong>ELISE STEFANIK, UN Ambassador</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/b5jg0s2_elise-stefanik-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced on Monday that Stefanik, a Republican congresswoman and staunch Trump supporter, would be his ambassador to the United Nations.</p>

<p>Stefanik, 40, a U.S. representative from New York state and House Republican conference chair, took a leadership position in the House of Representatives in 2021 when she was elected to replace then-Representative Liz Cheney, who was ousted for criticizing Trump's false claims of election fraud.</p>

<p>"I am honored to nominate Chairwoman Elise Stefanik to serve in my Cabinet as U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations," Trump said in a statement. "Elise is an incredibly strong, tough, and smart America First fighter."</p>

<p>Stefanik will arrive at the U.N. after bold promises by Trump to end the Russia-Ukraine war and Israel's war in Gaza.</p>

<h3><strong>LEE ZELDIN, EPA Administrator</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/930bpq3o_lee-zeldin-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump announced on Monday he had appointed former congressman Lee Zeldin of New York state as administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and Zeldin said he had accepted the role.</p>

<p>Zeldin, 44, a staunch Trump ally, served in Congress from 2015 to 2023. In 2022, he lost the New York governor's race to Democratic incumbent Kathy Hochul.</p>

<p>Trump has promised to overhaul U.S. energy policy, with the aim of maximizing the country's already record-high oil and gas production by rolling back regulations and speeding up permitting.</p>

<p>As head of the EPA, Zeldin will play a key role in implementing those policies.</p>

<h3><strong>MARCO RUBIO, Secretary Of State</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6ophigok_marco-rubio-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump is expected to tap U.S. Senator Marco Rubio to be his secretary of state, sources said on Monday, putting the Florida-born politician on track to be the first Latino to serve as the United States' top diplomat.</p>

<p>Rubio, 53, was arguably the most hawkish option on Trump's shortlist for secretary of state. The senator has in past years advocated for a muscular foreign policy with respect to U.S. geopolitical foes, including China, Iran and Cuba.</p>

<p>Over the last several years he has softened some of his stances to align more closely with Trump's views. The president-elect accuses past U.S. presidents of leading the U.S. into costly and futile wars and has pushed for a more restrained foreign policy.</p>

<h3><strong>MIKE WALTZ, National Security Adviser</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bgettsik_mike-waltz-michael-waltz-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump on Tuesday said he had picked for national security adviser Republican U.S. Representative Mike Waltz, a retired Army Green Beret who has been a leading critic of China.</p>

<p>Waltz, a 50-year-old Trump loyalist who also served in the National Guard as a colonel, has criticized Chinese activity in the Asia-Pacific and has voiced the need for the U.S. to be ready for a potential conflict in the region.</p>

<p>The national security adviser is a powerful role, which does not require Senate confirmation. Waltz will be responsible for briefing Trump on key national security issues and coordinating with different agencies.</p>

<p>While slamming the Biden administration for a disastrous withdrawal from Afghanistan in 2021, Waltz has publicly praised Trump's foreign policy views.</p>

<h3><strong>KRISTI NOEM, Homeland Security Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7tq94hrk_kristi-noem-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump has chosen South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem to serve as the next homeland security secretary, two sources familiar with the decision said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Noem, 52, once seen as a possible running mate for Trump, is currently serving her second four-year term as South Dakota's governor. She rose to national prominence after refusing to impose a statewide mask mandate during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>

<p>The Department of Homeland Security is responsible for everything from border protection and immigration to disaster response and the U.S. Secret Service.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign and Noem's office did not immediately respond to requests for comments.</p>

<h3><strong>SCOTT BESSENT, Potential Treasury Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/971vpc08_scott-bessent-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Bessent, a key economic adviser to Trump, is widely seen as a top candidate for treasury secretary. A longtime hedge fund investor who taught at Yale University for several years, Bessent has a warm relationship with the president-elect.</p>

<p>While Bessent has long favored the laissez-faire policies that were popular in the pre-Trump Republican Party, he has also spoken highly of Trump's use of tariffs as a negotiating tool. He has praised the president-elect's economic philosophy, which rests on a skepticism of both regulations and international trade.</p>

<h3><strong>ROBERT LIGHTHIZER, Potential Treasury Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fti7e77o_robert-lighthizer-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A loyalist who served as Trump's U.S. trade representative for essentially the then-president's entire term, Lighthizer will almost certainly be invited back. Though Bessent likely has a better shot at becoming treasury secretary, Lighthizer has an outside chance, and he might be able to reprise his old role if he's interested.</p>

<p>Like Trump, Lighthizer, 77,&nbsp; is a trade skeptic and a firm believer in tariffs. He was one of the leading figures in Trump's trade war with China and the renegotiation of the North American Free Trade Agreement, or NAFTA, with Mexico and Canada during Trump's first term.</p>

<h3><strong>HOWARD LUTNICK, Potential Treasury Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ripbsl8s_howard-lutnick-twitter_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The co-chair of Trump's transition effort and the longtime chief executive of financial services firm Cantor Fitzgerald, Lutnick is in the running for treasury secretary.</p>

<p>A bombastic New Yorker like Trump, Lutnick, 63, has uniformly praised the president-elect's economic policies, including his use of tariffs.</p>

<p>He has at times given elaborate, unvarnished opinions about what policies will be enacted in Trump's second term. Some Trump allies had privately complained that he too often presented himself as speaking on behalf of the campaign.</p>

<h3><strong>LINDA McMAHON, Potential Commerce Secretary</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a5jepvq_linda-mcmahon-twitter_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Professional wrestling magnate and former Small Business Administration director Linda McMahon is seen as the frontrunner to lead Trump's Department of Commerce, three sources briefed on the plans said.</p>

<p>McMahon, 76, is a major donor and was an early supporter of the Republican president-elect when he first ran for the White House almost a decade ago. This time, Trump tapped her to co-lead a transition team formed to help vet personnel and draft policy ahead of the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>McMahon is the co-founder and former CEO of the professional wrestling franchise WWE. She later served as director of the Small Business Administration, resigning in 2019, and went on to lead a pro-Trump political action committee that supported his 2020 reelection bid.</p>

<h3><strong>JOHN RATCLIFFE, Potential CIA Director</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6eaho2m8_john-ratcliffe-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A former congressman and prosecutor who served as director of national intelligence during Trump's last year in office, Ratcliffe, 59, is seen as a leading contender to be director of the CIA, according to two people familiar with the transition process. Ratcliffe is also a potential attorney general pick.</p>

<p>The president-elect's allies view Ratcliffe as a hardcore Trump loyalist who could likely win Senate confirmation. Still, during his time as director of national intelligence, Ratcliffe often contradicted the assessments of career civil servants, drawing criticism from Democrats who said he politicized the role.</p>

<h3><strong>MIKE LEE, Potential Attorney General</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ri5hg36c_mike-lee-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A U.S. senator from Utah, Lee is widely seen as another top candidate for attorney general. Though the former prosecutor declined to vote for Trump during the 2016 election, he later became an unwavering ally, and he has become something of an intellectual hero among some factions of Trumpworld.</p>

<p>Lee, 53, was a key figure in attempts by Trump and his allies to overturn his 2020 election loss to Democrat Joe Biden, and has spread unfounded conspiracy theories about the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the Capitol.</p>

<h3><strong>KASH PATEL, Potential Candidate For National Security Posts</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ej9qilhk_kash-patel-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A former Republican House staffer who served in various high-ranking staff roles in the defense and intelligence communities during Trump's first term, Patel frequently appeared on the campaign trail to rally support for the candidate.</p>

<p>Some Trump allies would like to see Patel, considered the ultimate Trump loyalist, appointed CIA director. Any position requiring Senate confirmation may be a challenge, however.</p>

<p>Patel, 44, has leaned into controversy throughout his career. In an interview with Trump ally Steve Bannon last year, he promised to "come after" politicians and journalists perceived to be enemies of Trump.</p>

<p>During Trump's first term, Patel drew animosity from some more experienced national security officials, who saw him as volatile and too eager to please the then-president.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-04/3nop7tug_donald-trump-white-house-briefing-_625x300_28_April_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is in the process of choosing a Cabinet and selecting high-ranking officials]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inflation-in-argentina-dips-below-200-for-first-time-in-a-year-7005378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inflation In Argentina Dips Below 200% For First Time In A Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inflation-in-argentina-dips-below-200-for-first-time-in-a-year-7005378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:30:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Argentine inflation has dipped to 193%, landing below the 200% threshold for the first time in close to a year, data from statistics agency INDEC showed on Tuesday, as President Javier Milei's dramatic austerity agenda bears fruit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Argentine inflation has dipped to 193%, landing below the 200% threshold for the first time in close to a year, data from statistics agency INDEC showed on Tuesday, as President Javier Milei's dramatic austerity agenda bears fruit.</p>

<p>Slowing inflation, pulled back in part by the government's dramatic public spending adjustments, has however come at the cost of consumption in a battered economy where more than half of the country has fallen into poverty.</p>

<p>Data from INDEC showed that monthly inflation slowed to 2.7% in October from 3.5% the previous month, its lowest since November 2021. The annual rate dipped below 200% for the first time since November last year.</p>

<p>While rent and utility costs drove monthly price rises, up 5.4%, prices in transport, food and non-alcoholic drinks rose just 1.2% from the previous month.</p>

<p>But the good news can be hard to grasp for Argentines who have had to tighten their belts to make it to the end of the month.</p>

<p>The government has slashed subsidies on public services, and increased public sector layoffs. Inflation is still very high by global standards and has contributed to a deep fall in purchasing power.</p>

<p>"Sales have been dropping a lot, perhaps people come more to buy on a daily basis, small quantities, and you can see the difference," said Maria Sunilda Correa, who works in a poultry store.</p>

<p>Consumers are buying less beef in the famously steak-loving country after Milei ended the previous government's freeze on beef prices. Beef consumption fell in the first six months of the year to its lowest level in 13 years, according to a report by industry group Ciccra.</p>

<p>"The price of meat has not gone up these months because there is very little consumption. As consumption goes down, sales also go down. And well, it is a bit complicated," said Gabriel Segovia, a 52-year-old butcher in Buenos Aires.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v0s9vcko_argentina-inflation-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Argentine inflation has dipped to 193%, landing below the 200% threshold.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-the-latest-science-shows-us-about-climate-change-7005286]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What The Latest Science Shows Us About Climate Change]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-the-latest-science-shows-us-about-climate-change-7005286]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:00:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This year's UN climate summit - COP29 - is being held during yet another record-breaking year of higher global temperatures, adding pressure to negotiations aimed at curbing climate change.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year's UN climate summit - COP29 - is being held during yet another record-breaking year of higher global temperatures, adding pressure to negotiations aimed at curbing climate change.</p>

<p>The last global scientific consensus on climate change was released in 2021 through the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, however scientists say that evidence shows global warming and its impacts are unfolding faster than expected.</p>

<h2><strong>Here is some of the latest climate research:</strong></h2>

<h2><strong>1.5C BREACHED?</strong></h2>

<p>The world may already have hit 1.5 degree Celsius (2.7 F) of warming above the average pre-industrial temperature - a critical threshold beyond which it is at risk of irreversible and extreme climate change, scientists say.</p>

<p>A group of researchers made the suggestion in a study released on Monday based on an analysis of 2,000 years of atmospheric gases trapped in Antarctic ice cores that extends the understanding of pre-industrial temperature trends.</p>

<p>Scientists have typically measured today's temperatures against a baseline temperature average for 1850-1900. By that measure, the world is now at nearly 1.3 C (2.4 F) of warming.</p>

<p>But the new data suggests a longer pre-industrial baseline, based on temperature data spanning the year 13 to 1700, the study published in the journal Nature Geoscience said.</p>

<p>Either way, 2024 is certain to be the warmest year on record.</p>

<h3><strong>SUPERCHARGED HURRICANES</strong></h3>

<p>Not only is ocean warming fuelling stronger Atlantic storms, it is also causing them to intensify more rapidly, for example, jumping from a Category 1 to a Category 3 storm in just hours.</p>

<p>Growing evidence shows this is true of other ocean basins.</p>

<p>Hurricane Milton needed only one day in the Gulf of Mexico in October to go from tropical storm to the Gulf's second-most powerful hurricane on record, slamming Florida's west coast.</p>

<p>Warmer air can also hold more moisture, helping storms carry and eventually release more rain. As a result, hurricanes are delivering flooding even in mountain towns like Asheville, North Carolina, inundated in September by Hurricane Helene.</p>

<h3><strong>WILDFIRE DEATHS</strong></h3>

<p>Global warming is drying waterways and sapping moisture from forests, creating conditions for bigger and hotter wildfires from the U.S. West and Canada to southern Europe and Russia's Far East creating more damaging smoke.</p>

<p>Research published last month in Nature Climate Change calculated that about 13% of deaths associated with toxic wildfire smoke, roughly 12,000 deaths, during the 2010s could be attributed to the climate effect on wildfires.</p>

<h3><strong>CORAL BLEACHING</strong></h3>

<p>With the world in the throes of a fourth mass coral bleaching event — the largest on record&nbsp; — scientists fear the world's reefs have passed a point of no return.</p>

<p>Scientists will be studying bleached reefs from Australia to Brazil for signs of recovery over the next few years if temperatures fall.</p>

<h3><strong>AMAZON ALARM</strong></h3>

<p>Brazil's Amazon is in the grips of its worst and most widespread drought since records began in 1950. River levels sank to all-time lows this year, while fires ravaged the rainforest.</p>

<p>This adds concern to scientific findings earlier this year that between 10% and 47% of the Amazon will face combined stresses of heat and drought from climate change, as well as other threats, by 2050.</p>

<p>This could push the Amazon past a tipping point, with the jungle no longer able to produce enough moisture to quench its own trees, at which point the ecosystem could transition to degraded forests or sandy savannas.</p>

<p>Globally, forests appear to be struggling.</p>

<p>A July study found that forests overall last year failed to absorb as much carbon dioxide from the atmosphere as in the past, due largely to the Amazon drought and wildfires in Canada.</p>

<p>That means a record amount of CO2 entered the atmosphere.</p>

<h3><strong>VOLCANIC SURGE</strong></h3>

<p>Scientists fear climate change could even boost volcanic eruptions.</p>

<p>In Iceland, volcanoes appear to be responding to rapid glacier retreat. As ice melts, less pressure is exerted on the Earth's crust and mantle.</p>

<p>Volcanologists worry this could destabilize magma reservoirs and appears to be leading to more magma being created, building up pressure underground.</p>

<p>Some 245 volcanoes across the world lie under or near ice and could be at risk.</p>

<h3><strong>OCEAN SLOWDOWN</strong></h3>

<p>The warming of the Atlantic could hasten the collapse of a key current system, which scientists warn could already be sputtering.</p>

<p>The Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC), which transports warm water from the tropics to the North Atlantic, has helped to keep European winters milder for centuries.</p>

<p>Research in 2018 showed that AMOC has weakened by about 15% since 1950, while research published in February in the journal Science Advances, suggested that it could be closer to a critical slowdown than previously thought.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jb3e9h3g_climate-change-global-warming-greenhouse-gas-emissions-pixabay_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The last global scientific consensus on climate change was released in 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-senate-democrats-rush-to-confirm-judges-before-donald-trump-takes-office-7005228]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Senate Democrats Rush To Confirm Judges Before Trump Takes Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-senate-democrats-rush-to-confirm-judges-before-donald-trump-takes-office-7005228]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:42:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Senate's Democratic majority began a crusade on Tuesday to confirm as many new federal judges nominated by President Joe Biden as possible to avoid leaving vacancies that Republican Donald Trump could fill after taking office on Jan. 20.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Senate's Democratic majority began a crusade on Tuesday to confirm as many new federal judges nominated by President Joe Biden as possible to avoid leaving vacancies that Republican Donald Trump could fill after taking office on Jan. 20.</p>

<p>With Republicans set to take control of the chamber on Jan. 3, the Senate is set on Tuesday to hold a confirmation vote on one of Biden's judicial nominees - former prosecutor April Perry - for the first time since Trump won the Nov. 5 presidential election. Perry was nominated by the Democratic president to serve as a U.S. district court judge in Illinois.</p>

<p>All told, Biden has announced 31 judicial nominees who are awaiting Senate confirmation votes, including Perry. She is one of 17 who already have been reviewed by the Senate Judiciary Committee and are awaiting a final confirmation vote by the full Senate. Another 14 nominees are awaiting committee review.</p>

<p>The U.S. Constitution assigns to the Senate the power to confirm a president's nominees for life-tenured seats on the federal judiciary.</p>

<p>"We are going to get as many done as we can," Democratic Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer said in a statement.</p>

<p>Trump made 234 judicial appointments during his first four years in office, the second most of any president in a single term, and succeeded in moving the judiciary rightward - including building a 6-3 conservative majority on the U.S. Supreme Court with three appointees.</p>

<p>Biden has appointed a host of liberal judges. Since the beginning of his presidency in 2021, the Senate has confirmed 213 Biden judicial nominees, including liberal Supreme Court Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson. About two-thirds were women, and the same share were racial minorities.</p>

<p>Senate Democrats are under pressure to swiftly confirm the remaining nominees, along with any new picks Biden may name in the waning weeks of his presidency.</p>

<p>How many nominees Senate Democrats will be able to confirm remains to be seen. Trump in a social media post on Sunday called on the Senate to halt approving Biden's nominees, saying, "Democrats are looking to ram through their Judges."</p>

<p>Billionaire Trump backer Elon Musk on Tuesday wrote on social media that "activist" judicial nominees are "bad for the country." Mike Davis, a Trump ally at the conservative judicial advocacy group Article III Project, in another post urged Senate Republicans to vote down all judicial appointments until January.</p>

<p>"The American people voted for monumental change," Davis wrote on social media last week. "Grind the Senate to a halt."</p>

<p>Current Senate Republican leader Mitch McConnell's office declined comment. McConnell has consistently opposed Biden's nominees and, as majority leader, was instrumental in getting Trump's previous nominees confirmed.</p>

<p>Trump's judicial appointees have been involved in major decisions welcomed by conservatives including Supreme Court rulings rolling back abortion rights, widening gun rights, rejecting race-conscious collegiate admissions and limiting the power of federal regulatory agencies.</p>

<p>Judicial nominees require a simple majority for confirmation. Democrats currently hold a slim 51-49 majority, meaning that they can ill afford any defections or absences if Republicans show up in force to oppose Biden's nominees during the chamber's post-election "lame duck" session.</p>

<p>West Virginia Senator Joe Manchin, an independent who caucuses with the Democrats, has said he would not vote for any nominee who does not garner at least one Republican vote. Must-pass legislation like a spending bill to avert a government shutdown also may consume precious time during the session.</p>

<h2><strong>'EVERY POSSIBLE NOMINEE'</strong></h2>

<p>Biden's allies have said a concerted push to confirm his remaining nominees would allow him to build on his legacy of helping to diversify a federal bench long dominated by white men.</p>

<p>He is not done nominating judges. On Friday, Biden announced his first post-election nominee, Tali Farhadian Weinstein, who after unsuccessfully running in the 2021 Democratic primary to be Manhattan district attorney was picked for a job as a federal district judge in New York.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Senator Dick Durbin, the No. 2 Senate Democrat and chair of the Judiciary Committee, said in a statement that he "aims to confirm every possible nominee before the end of this Congress."</p>

<p>White House spokesperson Andrew Bates on Monday noted that during Trump's first term, the Republican-controlled Senate confirmed 18 judges after Biden had won the 2020 election but before he took office.</p>

<p>Pending nominees include five to the influential federal appeals courts. Republicans said before the election that they had the votes to block two of them: Adeel Mangi, who would become the first Muslim federal appellate judge, and North Carolina Solicitor General Ryan Park, who unsuccessfully defended the race-conscious admissions policies before the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>There are an additional 26 picked by Biden to serve as trial court judges, including Perry, a former prosecutor now working at Chicago-headquartered GE HealthCare who would join the bench in Illinois. Biden nominated her to a judgeship in April after her prior nomination to become Chicago's top federal prosecutor was blocked by Republican Senator JD Vance.</p>

<p>Vance began placing a hold on Biden's nominees to the U.S. Justice Department in 2023 after Special Counsel Jack Smith secured the first of two federal indictments against Trump, who subsequently picked the senator as his vice presidential running mate.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/peo27eb8_us-capitol-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Senate is set today to hold a confirmation vote on one of Biden's judicial nominees]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-western-liberal-propaganda-of-choosing-not-to-have-children-7005007]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Bans "Western Liberal Propaganda" Of Choosing Not To Have Children]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-western-liberal-propaganda-of-choosing-not-to-have-children-7005007]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:51:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian MPs on Tuesday passed in the final third reading controversial legislation banning "propaganda" of choosing not to have children, the latest measure targeting what Moscow depicts as Western liberal ideas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian MPs on Tuesday passed in the final third reading controversial legislation banning "propaganda" of choosing not to have children, the latest measure targeting what Moscow depicts as Western liberal ideas.</p>

<p>Facing an ageing population and low birth rates, Moscow is seeking to reverse a demographic slump - accentuated by its military offensive on Ukraine - that threatens its economic future.</p>

<p>MPs in the Duma lower house of parliament voted unanimously in favour of the draft bill, which would apply to materials online, in media, advertising and in films that promote "rejection of childbearing".</p>

<p>The bill targets "destructive content" that promotes a "conscious" rejection of having children.</p>

<p>The bill's authors have said it will not be used as punishment for "a personal choice or lifestyle" but only for promoting such a lifestyle, although it is unclear how this would be differentiated in practice.</p>

<p>Violations would be punishable by fines up to 400,000 rubles ($4,000) on individuals and up to five million rubles for businesses. The bill also includes a provision to deport foreigners found guilty of disseminating the banned information.</p>

<p>"This is a fateful law... Without children, there will be no country. This ideology will lead to people stopping giving birth to children," the Duma's speaker Vyacheslav Volodin said ahead of the vote.</p>

<p>He also said the legislation was about "protecting citizens, primarily the generation growing up, from information spread in the media space that negatively affects the development of personality".</p>

<p>This is "so new generations of our citizens grow up orientated towards traditional family values", he said.</p>

<p>Nina Ostanina, a Communist Party MP who heads the Duma committee on family policy, said the bill aims to "guard our youth from unnecessary ideologies".</p>

<p>The legislation will now be considered by the upper house of parliament on November 20, before coming before President Vladimir Putin, who is expected to sign it into law.</p>

<p>It comes on top of existing bans on "propaganda" of LGBTQ relationships or changing gender.</p>

<h2><strong>ADOPTION BAN</strong></h2>

<p>The Duma also unanimously passed legislation in the third reading banning foreigners living in countries that allow gender reassignment from adopting Russian children.</p>

<p>The bill is aimed at stopping Russian children from being able to legally change gender.</p>

<p>Moscow has long portrayed itself as a bulwark against liberal values, but that trend has hugely accelerated since the Kremlin launched its Ukraine offensive, further rupturing ties with the West.</p>

<p>The bill would ban adoption by citizens of countries that authorise "the change of sex by medical intervention, including with the use of medicine", or allow individuals to change their gender on official identity documents.</p>

<p>Since 1993, foreigners have adopted 102,403 children from Russia, Volodin said, warning that "Western policy towards children is destructive."</p>

<p>Russia previously banned all US adoptions in 2012 with a bill named after a Russian toddler who died of heat stroke in 2008 after his adoptive American father forgot him in a car.</p>

<p>Russia has created an inhospitable environment for LBGTQ people for years. In July 2023, it banned the "international LGBT movement" as extremist and made gender reassignment illegal.</p>

<p>Putin himself has repeatedly mocked people who have undergone gender reassignment as well as LGBTQ people.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-12/red-square-afp_650x400_61451303314.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia passed a law banning "propaganda" of childless lifestyles calling it "western liberal ideas"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-nigeria-guyana-and-brazil-for-g20-summit-next-week-7004967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi To Visit Nigeria, Guyana, And Brazil For G20 Summit, Next Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-nigeria-guyana-and-brazil-for-g20-summit-next-week-7004967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:42:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi will travel to Brazil to attend the annual G20 summit and to Nigeria and Guyana as part of a three-nation visit beginning November 16, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will travel to Brazil to attend the annual G20 summit and to Nigeria and Guyana as part of a three-nation visit beginning November 16, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>PM Modi's first destination will be Nigeria and it will be the first visit to the resource-rich African country by an Indian prime minister in 17 years.</p>

<p>From Nigeria, PM Modi will travel to the Brazilian city of Rio De Janeiro on a two-day trip beginning November 18 to participate in the G20 summit. India is part of the G20 troika along with Brazil and South Africa.</p>

<p>The prime minister will put forward India's positions on various issues of global importance and build on the outcomes from the G20 New Delhi Leaders' Declaration and Voice of the Global South Summits, the MEA said.</p>

<p>On the sidelines of the summit, PM Modi is expected to meet several leaders, it said.</p>

<p>Under its G20 presidency that ended on November 30 last year, India focused on a variety of issues like inclusive growth, digital innovation, climate financing and equitable global health access with an aim largely to benefit the Global South or the developing countries.</p>

<p>PM Modi will visit Nigeria from November 16 to 17 at the invitation of Nigerian President Bola Ahmed Tinubu, the MEA said.</p>

<p>"During the visit, the prime minister will hold talks to review the strategic partnership between India and Nigeria and discuss further avenues to enhance the bilateral relationship," it said.</p>

<p>He is also scheduled to address a gathering of the Indian community in Nigeria.</p>

<p>"India and Nigeria have been strategic partners since 2007 with growing economic, energy and defence collaboration. More than 200 Indian companies have invested over USD 27 billion in important sectors in Nigeria," the MEA said.</p>

<p>It said India and Nigeria also share a strong development cooperation partnership.</p>

<p>The prime minister's final destination will be Guyana. He will visit the island nation from November 19 to 21 at the invitation of President Mohamed Irfaan Ali, according to the MEA.</p>

<p>"This visit to Guyana will be the first by an Indian prime minister since 1968," it said.</p>

<p>In 2023, President Ali visited India as the chief guest at the 17th Pravasi Bharatiya Divas in Indore and he was awarded the Pravasi Bharatiya Samman.</p>

<p>"During the visit, the prime minister will hold discussions with President Ali, meet other senior leaders of Guyana, address the Parliament of Guyana and address a gathering of the Indian diaspora," the MEA said.</p>

<p>"In Georgetown, Guyana, the prime minister will also participate in the second CARICOM-India Summit and hold meetings with leaders of CARICOM member countries to further enhance India's long-standing friendship with the region," it said.</p>

<p>The Caribbean Community (CARICOM) is an intergovernmental organisation of 15 member states in the Caribbean region having the primary objective to promote economic integration and cooperation among the members.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/2dr9i44k_narendra-modi-wave-narendra-modi-india-flag-ndtv-file-photo_625x300_15_June_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi's first destination will be Nigeria, and then he will be visiting Rio De Janeiro. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insight-these-countries-offer-assisted-dying-or-are-considering-it-know-the-law-7004789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[These Countries Offer 'Assisted Dying' Or Are Considering It. How It's Done]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insight-these-countries-offer-assisted-dying-or-are-considering-it-know-the-law-7004789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:14:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain is to debate whether to legalise assisted dying for the terminally ill, potentially paving the way for the law to change. Below is a list of countries which allow people to choose to end their lives or are considering doing so.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>SWITZERLAND </strong>- Switzerland legalised assisted dying in 1942 on the condition the motive is not selfish, making it the first country in the world to permit the practice. Doctors can prescribe drugs and administer them or had them over for self-administration. A number of Swiss organisations such as Dignitas offer their services to foreign nationals.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>UNITED STATES</strong> - Medical aid in dying, also known as physician assisted dying is legal in 10 states: California, Colorado, Hawaii, Montana, Maine, New Jersey, New Mexico, Oregon, Vermont and Washington, plus the District of Columbia. Oregon was the first state to legalise it under a law which came into effect in 1997. It allows mentally competent patients who are terminally ill and with less than six months to live to ask for life-ending medication. People from outside Oregon may travel to the state to take advantage of the law.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>NETHERLANDS </strong>- The "Termination of Life on Request and Assisted Suicide (Review Procedures) Act" came into effect in 2002. A doctor is immune from punishment for euthanasia and assisted suicide where patients are experiencing "unbearable suffering with no prospect of improvement". Minors can request euthanasia from the age of 12 but require parental permission before the age of 16.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>BELGIUM </strong>- Belgium legalised medically assisted dying in 2002 for the terminally ill and for people experiencing unbearable suffering, which includes patients with psychiatric conditions. Since 2014, those under the age of 18 who are terminally ill are covered by the law as long as they have parental permission.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>CANADA </strong>- Canada introduced "Medical Assistance in Dying" in 2016 for those whose death was deemed to be "reasonably foreseeable". Five years later, the law was extended to permit people with a "grievous and irremediable" medical condition to request assisted dying. The country has delayed until 2027 a plan to extend medical assistance in dying to include those with a mental illness.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>AUSTRALIA </strong>- Voluntary assisted dying for the terminally ill or those with a condition that is causing intolerable suffering is legal in most Australian states, after being introduced first in Victoria in 2019. Doctors can prescribe medication for self-administration or administer them where required.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>SPAIN </strong>- Spain approved a law in 2021 which allows euthanasia and medically assisted suicide for people with incurable or debilitating diseases who want to end their life.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>GERMANY </strong>- Assisted dying had been legal in Germany until 2015 when the country outlawed its provision on an organised or commercial basis, effectively banning it in many cases. Five years later the country's top court ruled in favour of groups providing terminally ill adults with assisted suicide services, but lawmakers are yet to finalise new rules.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>FRANCE </strong>- Doctors in France have since 2016 been allowed to put a person who is close to death and in great pain into deep sedation, but not to administer life-ending medication. President Emmanuel Macron earlier this year backed new legislation which would allow assisted dying for those with incurable conditions and a bill was introduced in April, but elections in June and July interrupted the proposed law's progress.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>BRITAIN </strong>- A bill to allow terminally ill adults with six months or less left to live the right to end their lives was introduced to parliament earlier in October and will be debated on Nov. 29.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>IRELAND </strong>- A cross-party Irish parliamentary committee recommended this year that the government should legalise assisted dying in certain restricted circumstances. A majority of lawmakers in October voted in favour of "noting" the committee's findings. With a national election due on Nov. 29, it will be up to the next government to decide whether to consider proposing a new law.</li>
</ol>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/glaov5c8_graveyad-generic-grave-generic-grave-flowers-istock_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>