<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 05:38:46 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-names-political-veteran-chris-lehane-as-head-of-global-policy-report-6456775]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Names Chris Lehane Head of Global Policy: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-names-political-veteran-chris-lehane-as-head-of-global-policy-report-6456775]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 05:24:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[ChatGPT-maker OpenAI has named political veteran Chris Lehane as its vice president of global policy, the New York Times reported on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ChatGPT-maker OpenAI has named political veteran Chris Lehane as its vice president of global policy, the New York Times reported on Friday.</p>

<p>Lehane, who is a member of the executive team at OpenAI, was a former policy chief for Airbnb and a member of the Clinton White House.</p>

<p>OpenAI did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>The appointment comes as Apple and chip giant Nvidia are reportedly in talks to invest in OpenAI as part of a new fundraising round that could value the Microsoft-backed startup above $100 billion.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, the Financial Times reported that OpenAI is weighing changes to its corporate structure to become more investor-friendly.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ijrpj09g_openai_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[OpenAI has named political veteran Chris Lehane as its vice president of global policy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-brazil-pseudo-judge-after-order-to-suspend-x-6456714]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Slams Brazil "Pseudo-Judge" After Order To Suspend X]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-brazil-pseudo-judge-after-order-to-suspend-x-6456714]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 05:03:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Supreme Court judge on Friday ordered the suspension of Elon Musk's X social media network in Brazil, after months-long standoff over disinformation in South America's largest nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Supreme Court judge on Friday ordered the suspension of Elon Musk's X social media network in Brazil, after months-long standoff over disinformation in South America's largest nation.</p>

<p>The judge, Alexandre de Moraes, handed down the ruling after Musk failed to comply with an order to name a new legal representative for the company.</p>

<p>Musk, who also owns Tesla and SpaceX, reacted with fury, branding Moraes an "evil dictator cosplaying as a judge" and accusing him of "trying to destroy democracy in Brazil."</p>

<p>"Free speech is the bedrock of democracy and an unelected pseudo-judge in Brazil is destroying it for political purposes," the billionaire wrote on X.</p>

<p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Free speech is the bedrock of democracy and an unelected pseudo-judge in Brazil is destroying it for political purposes <a href="https://t.co/eqbowALCeu">https://t.co/eqbowALCeu</a></p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1829624142452195334?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 30, 2024</a></blockquote></p>

<p>The two have been locked in an ongoing, high-profile feud for months as Moraes leads a battle against disinformation in Brazil.</p>

<p>Musk has previously declared himself a "free speech absolutist," but since he took over the platform formerly known as Twitter in 2022 he has been accused of turning it into a megaphone for right-wing conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>Moraes ordered the "immediate, complete and comprehensive suspension of the operation of" X in the country, telling the national communications agency to take "all necessary measures" to implement the order within 24 hours.</p>

<p>He also asked Google, Apple, and internet providers to "introduce technological obstacles capable of preventing the use of the X application" and access to the website.</p>

<p>And he threatened to fine people 50,000 reais ($8,900) if they used "technological subterfuges" to get around the block, such as a VPN.</p>

<p>The social media platform has more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<p>Musk shut X's business operations in Brazil earlier this month, claiming Moraes had threatened the company's previous legal representative with arrest to force compliance with "censorship orders."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Moraes told Musk he had 24 hours to find a new representative or he would face suspension.</p>

<p>Shortly after the deadline passed, X said in a statement that it expected Moraes to shut it down "simply because we would not comply with his illegal orders to censor his political opponents."</p>

<p>- 'Who does Musk think he is?'-</p>

<p>The standoff with Musk began when Moraes ordered the suspension of several X accounts belonging to supporters of Brazil's former far-right president Jair Bolsonaro, who tried to discredit the voting system in the 2022 election, which he lost.</p>

<p>Brazilian authorities are investigating whether Bolsonaro plotted a coup attempt to prevent current President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva from assuming office in January 2023.</p>

<p>Online users blocked by Moraes include figures like far-right ex-congressman Daniel Silveira, who was sentenced to nine years in prison in 2022 on charges of leading a movement to overthrow the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In April, Moraes ordered an investigation of Musk, accusing him of reactivating some of the banned accounts.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Musk's satellite internet operator Starlink said it had received an order from Moraes that froze its accounts and prevented it from conducting financial transactions in Brazil.</p>

<p>Starlink alleged that the order "is based on an unfounded determination that Starlink should be responsible for the fines levied -- unconstitutionally -- against X."</p>

<p>The company said on X that it intended "to address the matter legally."</p>

<p>Musk is also the subject of a separate judicial investigation into an alleged scheme where public money was used to orchestrate disinformation campaigns in favor of Bolsonaro and those close to him.</p>

<p>"Any citizen from anywhere in the world who has investments in Brazil is subject to the Brazilian Constitution and laws," Lula told a local radio station on Friday.</p>

<p>"Who does (Musk) think he is?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8trrs42_elon-musk_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk said that Brazil is destroying democracy for political purposes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-attacks-passengers-with-knife-on-bus-in-germany-5-injured-cops-6456561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Attacks Passengers With Knife On Bus In Germany, 5 Injured: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-attacks-passengers-with-knife-on-bus-in-germany-5-injured-cops-6456561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 04:16:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On Friday evening, a violent incident occurred on a bus in Siegen, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany, leaving five people injured after a woman attacked them with a knife, local police confirmed, Xinhua reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;On Friday evening, a violent incident occurred on a bus in Siegen, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany, leaving five people injured after a woman attacked them with a knife, local police confirmed, Xinhua reported.</p>

<p>Notably, the woman has been arrested.</p>

<p>The police informed that three persons were in life-threatening conditions. At least 40 other passengers were on the bus at the time of the incident. No further danger is posed, police said, according to Xinhua.</p>

<p>According to German newspaper Bild, the attacker is believed to be a German national, with indications suggesting that they may have been struggling with mental health issues and potentially under the influence of drugs. The police has clarified that they do not suspect terrorism to be a motivating factor.</p>

<p>The incident comes days after a Syrian man brought himself in and admitted to stabbing three people to death and several others at a festival in the western German city of Solingen on Friday, CNN reported citing the police.</p>

<p>The incident claimed the lives of two men, ages 67 and 56, and a lady, age 56.</p>

<p>It stunned Germany and led opposition parties to demand stricter immigration laws. The 26-year-old is accused by German prosecutors of being an ISIS member. Via its Amaq news agency, the terrorist group claimed responsibility for the incident. But it provided no proof to support that claim.</p>

<p>In a statement, prosecutors said that due to his "radical Islamist convictions, [the suspect] decided to kill as many people as possible at the Solingen city festival."</p>

<p>The suspect went on a significant manhunt before turning himself in. The man stated, "I'm the one you're looking for," to the officers while covered in blood, according to the daily Bild, reported CNN.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/k11jji0g_germany-police-reuters-august-3_625x300_04_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police has clarified that they do not suspect terrorism to be a motivating factor. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazils-supreme-court-orders-suspension-of-elon-musks-x-amid-row-6456202]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil's Supreme Court Orders Suspension Of Elon Musk's X Amid Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazils-supreme-court-orders-suspension-of-elon-musks-x-amid-row-6456202]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 02:04:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Supreme Court judge on Friday ordered the suspension of Elon Musk's X social media network in Brazil for failing to comply with an order to name a new legal representative for the company, a source at the court told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Supreme Court judge on Friday ordered the suspension of Elon Musk's X social media network in Brazil after the billionaire failed to comply with an order to name a new legal representative for the company.</p>

<p>Musk has been locked in a months-long feud with the judge, Alexandre de Moraes, who is leading a battle against disinformation in South America's largest nation.</p>

<p>Moraes ordered the "immediate, complete and comprehensive suspension of the operation of 'X Brasil Internet LTDA' in the national territory."</p>

<p>He ordered the National Telecommunications Agency (Anatel) to "adopt all necessary measures to implement" the order within 24 hours.</p>

<p>He also asked Google, Apple, and internet providers to "introduce technological obstacles capable of preventing the use of the X application" and access to the website.</p>

<p>The social media platform formally known as Twitter has more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<p>Musk shut X's business operations in Brazil earlier this month, claiming Moraes had threatened the company's previous legal representative with arrest to force compliance with "censorship orders."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Moraes told Musk "to appoint the company's new legal representative in Brazil within 24 hours" or face suspension.</p>

<p>The South African-born Tesla boss fired off tweets calling Moraes an "evil dictator cosplaying as a judge" and accusing him of "trying to destroy democracy in Brazil."</p>

<p>"Soon, we expect Judge Alexandre de Moraes will order X to be shut down in Brazil – simply because we would not comply with his illegal orders to censor his political opponents," X said in a statement shortly after the passing of a 24-hour deadline.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Who does Musk think he is?'-</strong></p>

<p>The standoff with Musk began when Moraes ordered the suspension of several X accounts belonging to supporters of Brazil's former far-right president Jair Bolsonaro, who tried to discredit the voting system in the 2022 election, which he lost.</p>

<p>Brazilian authorities are investigating whether Bolsonaro plotted a coup attempt to prevent current President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva from assuming office in January 2023.</p>

<p>Online users blocked by Moraes include figures like far-right ex-congressman Daniel Silveira, who was sentenced to nine years in prison in 2022 on charges of leading a movement to overthrow the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In April, Moraes ordered an investigation of Musk, accusing him of reactivating some of the banned accounts on the network formerly known as Twitter.</p>

<p>Musk and other critics accuse Moraes of stifling free speech.</p>

<p>"Any citizen from anywhere in the world who has investments in Brazil is subject to the Brazilian Constitution and laws," Lula told a local radio station on Friday.</p>

<p>"Who does (Musk) think he is?"</p>

<p><strong>- Starlink finances frozen -</strong></p>

<p>On Thursday, Musk's satellite internet operator Starlink said it had received an order from Moraes that "freezes Starlink's finances and prevents Starlink from conducting financial transactions" in the country.</p>

<p>Starlink, which operates in Brazil, particularly in the Amazon, alleged that the order "is based on an unfounded determination that Starlink should be responsible for the fines levied -- unconstitutionally -- against X."</p>

<p>The company said on X that it intended "to address the matter legally."</p>

<p>Musk is also the subject of a separate judicial investigation into an alleged scheme where public money was used to orchestrate disinformation campaigns in favor of Bolsonaro and those close to him.</p>

<p>The proliferation and amplification of misinformation and conspiracy theories on social media have sparked debate over the need for content moderation and a balance between calling out falsehoods and veering towards censorship or curbing free speech.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/puugc1eg_elon-musk_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explosive-trump-biopic-to-hit-us-theaters-before-election-reports-6455958]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explosive Trump Biopic To Hit US Theaters Before Election: Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explosive-trump-biopic-to-hit-us-theaters-before-election-reports-6455958]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:55:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A controversial biopic of Donald Trump that depicts the former president raping his wife and which has drawn legal threats from his attorneys will hit US theaters this October, it was reported Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A controversial biopic of Donald Trump that depicts the former president raping his wife and which has drawn legal threats from his attorneys will hit US theaters this October, it was reported Friday.</p>

<p>Tiny indie studio Briarcliff Entertainment plans to release "The Apprentice" for US audiences less than a month before Trump takes on Kamala Harris in the country's razor-tight presidential election, the Hollywood Reporter said.</p>

<p>Representatives for Briarcliff did not immediately respond to AFP queries.</p>

<p>The explosive film about Trump's younger years caused shockwaves at the Cannes Film Festival in May.</p>

<p>Its most talked about scene shows Trump raping his first wife, Ivana, after she belittles him for growing fat and bald.</p>

<p>In real life, Ivana accused Trump of raping her during divorce proceedings but later rescinded the allegation. She died in 2022.</p>

<p>The movie also shows Trump suffering erectile dysfunction, and undergoing liposuction and surgery for hair loss.</p>

<p>Just hours after "The Apprentice" premiered in May, Trump's lawyers vowed to sue the producers, calling the film "garbage" and "pure malicious defamation."</p>

<p>Further complicating the film's prospects for US release is that one of its early financial backers was pro-Trump billionaire Dan Snyder, who was reportedly displeased with its depiction of Trump and sought to block the movie.</p>

<p>He has now been bought out of his financial stake in the movie, according to the Hollywood Reporter. The film is set to be released in US theaters October 11, the Los Angeles Times said.</p>

<p>Sebastian Stan's lead performance as young New York property tycoon Trump received largely positive reviews at Cannes.</p>

<p>The film's screenplay was written by Gabriel Sherman, a journalist who covered real estate for the New York Observer and regularly spoke to Trump.</p>

<p>Far from a simple hatchet job, the film depicts Trump as an ambitious but naive social climber desperately trying to navigate the cutthroat world of Manhattan property deals and politics.</p>

<p>The Times of London argued it would "make you feel sympathy for Trump."</p>

<p>But Trump's decency is gradually eroded as he learns the dark arts of dealmaking and power from his mentor Roy Cohn, played by "Succession" star Jeremy Strong.</p>

<p>Film director Ali Abbasi told AFP he included the rape scene to show how Trump distanced himself from "human relationships that define him and that hold him in check as a human being."</p>

<p>Stan, best known from the Marvel superhero movies, added that Trump's early behavior "is much more relatable than we want to admit."</p>

<p>Briarcliff Entertainment launched in the late 2010s. Its founder Tom Ortenberg previously helped steer Oscar campaigns for best picture winners "Spotlight" and "Crash."</p>

<p>He is expected to promote "The Apprentice" in Hollywood's upcoming award season.</p>

<p>The news comes on the same day "Reagan," another biopic of a former Republican president, Ronald Reagan, hits US theaters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/da04e9s4_donald-trump_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The movie also shows Trump suffering erectile dysfunction and undergoing liposuction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-it-made-no-deals-with-arrested-telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-6455734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says It Made No Deals With Arrested Telegram CEO Pavel Durov]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-it-made-no-deals-with-arrested-telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-6455734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 23:52:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin has never made any deals with Telegram boss Pavel Durov, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said on Friday, adding that he was not aware of any meetings between the tech entrepreneur and Russian President Vladimir Putin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin has never made any deals with Telegram boss Pavel Durov, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said on Friday, adding that he was not aware of any meetings between the tech entrepreneur and Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>A French judge put Russian-born Durov under formal investigation on Wednesday for suspected complicity in running an online platform that allows illicit transactions, child sex abuse images, drug trafficking and fraud.</p>

<p>Durov's lawyer said on Thursday it was "absurd" to suggest he should be held responsible for any crimes committed on the app.</p>

<p>"There were no negotiations between Durov and the Kremlin," Peskov told reporters. "And the fact that he visited Russia, well, he is a Russian citizen, he moves freely, so naturally he visited Russia.</p>

<p>"There were no deals between the Kremlin and Durov," Peskov said in response to further questions.</p>

<p>Peskov said that as far as he was aware, Putin and Durov had never met.</p>

<p>Russia, after years of pressure on Durov and his tech ventures, has rallied behind him, with Peskov this week saying that the case against him should not become political persecution.</p>

<p>Moscow tried and failed to block Telegram, which has almost 1 billion users, in 2018, and has demanded the platform hand over data in the past, something Durov says he refused to do.</p>

<p>The case has plunged Franco-Russian relations to new lows, according to Moscow, where some pro-Kremlin figures have accused Washington of being behind the detention of Durov, something Paris has denied.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/g6g94rr_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kremlin spokesman said that as far as he was aware, Putin and Durov had never met. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/behind-telegram-ceos-arrest-a-small-paris-cybercrime-unit-with-big-ambitions-6455641]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Behind Telegram CEO's Arrest, A Paris Cybercrime Unit With Big Ambitions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/behind-telegram-ceos-arrest-a-small-paris-cybercrime-unit-with-big-ambitions-6455641]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 23:34:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The investigation into Telegram boss Pavel Durov that has fired a warning shot to global tech titans was started by a small cybercrime unit within the Paris prosecutor's office, led by 38-year-old Johanna Brousse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The investigation into Telegram boss Pavel Durov that has fired a warning shot to global tech titans was started by a small cybercrime unit within the Paris prosecutor's office, led by 38-year-old Johanna Brousse.</p>

<p>The arrest of Durov, 39, last Saturday marks a significant shift in how some global authorities may seek to deal with tech chiefs reluctant to police illegal content on their platforms.</p>

<p>The arrest signalled the mettle of the J3 cybercrime unit, but the true test of its ambitions will be whether Brousse can secure a conviction based on a largely untested legal argument, lawyers said.</p>

<p>In an unprecedented move against a major tech CEO, prosecutors argued Durov bears responsibility for the alleged illegality on his platform, placing him under formal investigation on organized crime charges. He is suspected of complicity in running an online platform that allows the posting of child sex abuse images, drug trafficking and fraud.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Durov's lawyer said on Thursday it was "absurd" for him to be held responsible and that the app abided by European laws, echoing an earlier statement by Telegram itself.</p>

<p>Being placed under formal investigation in France does not imply guilt or necessarily lead to trial, but indicates judges consider there is enough evidence to proceed with the probe. Investigations can last years before being sent to trial or dropped. Durov is out on bail, but barred from leaving France.</p>

<p>Brousse's unit began investigating Durov earlier this year after seeing his app being used for countless alleged crimes, and growing frustrated by the "almost total lack of response from Telegram to judicial requests", Paris Prosecutor Laure Beccuau said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Brousse declined to comment.</p>

<p>In an interview with newspaper Liberation in January, Brousse said her office was overseeing a growing number of probes involving Telegram and rival messaging app Discord, adding that tackling crime on them was "one of my battles".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Jason Citron, Discord's CEO, did not respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Brousse's J3 cybercrime unit is France's most important, with licence to prosecute nationwide. But it also is small, with just five prosecutors, well below the 55-60 cybercrime prosecutors in Switzerland, a 2022 parliamentary report found. With limited resources, they "prioritize the most serious crimes", Brousse told Le Figaro last year.</p>

<p>Brousse said in a 2022 podcast appearance she wanted to be tough "so cybercriminals believe that if they attack France, they will be judged and punished very severely".</p>

<p>"We want people to be prosecuted, either in their country ... or in France through arrest warrants," she said.</p>

<p>Her office was used to "extremely sensitive cases", she added. "Sometimes, legal and geopolitical issues intersect."</p>

<p>Patrick Perrot, who coordinates AI-assisted probes at the French gendarmerie and advises the Interior Ministry's cybercommand unit, said the J3 had been innovative in seeking to prosecute cases that set an international precedent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I think it shows that you can't do whatever you want with these platforms," he told Reuters. "It's a real question for the future, because these platforms won't stop multiplying, so the challenge of regulation is essential."</p>

<p><strong>TOUGH LEGAL GROUND?</strong></p>

<p>Brousse has led the J3 since 2020, which has given her oversight of one of the most important - and controversial - French cybercrime cases ever.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In late 2020, the J3 took charge of the probe into Sky ECC, which alongside Encrochat was one of the main encrypted communications services used by gangsters to buy drugs and weapons, or murder rivals. A few years earlier, French, Dutch and Belgian police had hacked into their servers, which were housed in northern France, giving French prosecutors jurisdiction over many of the resulting probes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There have been more than 6,500 arrests since the takedown of Encrochat in 2020, according to Europol, with the legality of the intercepts challenged in appeals courts across Europe.</p>

<p>Paul Krusky, the Canadian Encrochat boss, was extradited in February from the Dominican Republic to France, where he now awaits trial. Lawyers for Sky ECC's Jean-François Eap are contesting his French arrest warrant.</p>

<p>Stephane Bonifassi, Eap's lawyer, said his client was innocent, adding that "Sky ECC was not conceived as a tool for criminals, nor commercialized as such".</p>

<p>Krusky's lawyer, Antoine Vey, said his client was innocent.</p>

<p>"The service set up by Paul Krusky, like other services that have enjoyed global success, was only intended to protect the privacy and freedom of exchange of its users, and in no case to support criminal activities," Vey said in a statement.</p>

<p>Two other French lawyers who have worked on Sky ECC and Encrochat cases told Reuters that these earlier probes gave prosecutors the ambition - and a blueprint - to target Durov.</p>

<p>Robin Binsard, who has fought Encrochat cases at France's top court, said prosecutors would need to prove that Durov knew and approved of the criminality on the app, calling their argument "totally questionable".</p>

<p>The fact that Telegram didn't comply with law enforcement requests "does not automatically make one an accomplice to a criminal project", he added.</p>

<p>Binsard said it was clear "France is pursuing encrypted messaging providers", and that other operators of such apps, such as Signal, "should be concerned about whether or not they are in compliance with French regulations. Because the message is clear if they are not, legal action will take place".</p>

<p>Signal did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A source at the Paris prosecutor's office said the Sky ECC probe had no links to the Telegram investigation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/g6g94rr_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pavel Durov's lawyer said Telegram abided by European laws (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-man-accused-of-drugging-wife-recruiting-over-50-people-to-rape-her-6455593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Man Accused Of Drugging Wife, Recruiting Over 50 People To Rape Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-man-accused-of-drugging-wife-recruiting-over-50-people-to-rape-her-6455593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 23:27:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A French retiree goes on trial Monday accused of recruiting dozens of strangers online to rape his wife after he drugged her into unconsciouness, in a case that has horrified the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A French retiree goes on trial Monday accused of recruiting dozens of strangers online to rape his wife after he drugged her into unconsciouness, in a case that has horrified the country.</p>

<p>Fifty other men are also on trial in the southern city of Avignon alongside the main suspect, a 71-year-old former employee at France's power utility EDF.</p>

<p>They are accused of raping the woman who, her lawyers say, was so heavily sedated that she was not aware of the abuse.</p>

<p>The trial will be "a horrible ordeal" for the woman, now in her 70s, and who does not wish to be identified, said Antoine Camus, one of her lawyers.</p>

<p>"For the first time, long after the fact, she will have to live through the rapes that she endured over 10 years," he told AFP, adding that his client had "no recollection" of the abuses which she only discovered in 2020.</p>

<p>The woman could have asked for the trial to be held behind closed doors but didn't, because "that's what her attackers would have wanted", Camus said.</p>

<p>"She is completely determined to face them and her husband with whom she lived for 50 years but whom she knew nothing about, as she discovered at 68," the lawyer said.</p>

<p>Police began to investigate the defendant Dominique P. in September 2020 when he was caught by a security guard secretly filming under the skirts of three women in a shopping centre.</p>

<p>Examining his computer, police said they found thousands of pictures and videos of his wife, visibly unconscious and mostly in the fetal position.</p>

<p>The images are alleged to show dozens of instances of rape in the couple's home in Mazan, a village of barely 6,000 inhabitants some 33 kilometres (21 miles) from Avignon in Provence.</p>

<p><strong>Up to six times</strong></p>

<p>Investigators also found chats on a site called coco.fr, since shut down by police, in which he recruited strangers to come to their home and have intercourse with his wife.</p>

<p>Police counted a total of 92 rapes, committed by 72 men of whom 51 were formally identified.</p>

<p>Dominique P. admitted to investigators that he gave his wife powerful tranquilisers, especially Temesta, an anxiety-reducing drug.</p>

<p>The abuse started in 2011, when the couple was living near Paris, and continued after they moved to Mazan two years later.</p>

<p>The suspect gave the men strict instructions so they would not wake her up when they abused her during the night.</p>

<p>No aftershave or cigarette odour were allowed, and they had to warm their hands before touching her, and get undressed in the kitchen so they would not accidentally leave clothes behind in the bedroom.</p>

<p>The husband took part in the rapes, filmed them and encouraged the other men using degrading language, according to prosecutors.</p>

<p>No money exchanged hands.</p>

<p>The accused rapists, aged between 21 and 68, included a forklift driver, a fire brigade officer, a company boss, and a journalist.</p>

<p>Some were single, others married or divorced, and some family men. Most participated just once, some up to six times.</p>

<p><strong>'Closer to coma'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Their defence has been that they simply helped a libertine couple live out its sexual fantasies, but Dominique P. told investigators that they were all aware that his wife had been drugged without her knowledge.</p>

<p>The trial will have to establish to what degree they understood the situation when they had intercourse with the woman whose state, an expert said, "was closer to a coma than to sleep".</p>

<p>Her husband told prosecutors that only three men left the house quickly after arriving, while all others proceeded to have intercourse with his wife.</p>

<p>Dominique P., who said he himself was raped by a male nurse when he was nine, is ready to face "his family and his wife", his lawyer Beatrice Zavarro told AFP.</p>

<p>This trial may not be his last. He has also been charged with a 1991 murder and rape, which he denies, and an attempted rape in 1999, to which he admitted after conclusive DNA testing.</p>

<p>"There is no such thing as a typical rapist profile," Veronique Le Goaziou, a specialist on sexual violence, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Many people will say he is crazy," she said about Dominque P. "But that's in no way certain. Only a tiny number of rapists are diagnosed with a real mental illness."</p>

<p>Psychiatric evaluations during the investigation have shown Dominique P. to be "a patriarch" and "a manipulator" with a "perverse" personality who used his wife as "bait".</p>

<p>The trial is set to run to December.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/sg8ktf4g_france-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The trial will be "a horrible ordeal" for the woman, said one of her lawyers (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singaporean-man-plants-death-penalty-weed-in-wifes-car-jailed-6455523]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singaporean Man Plants 'Death Penalty' Weed In Wife's Car, Jailed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singaporean-man-plants-death-penalty-weed-in-wifes-car-jailed-6455523]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 23:13:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Singaporean man has been sentenced to nearly four years behind bars after attempting to frame his estranged wife by placing cannabis in her car, knowing she could get the death penalty.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Singaporean man has been sentenced to nearly four years behind bars after attempting to frame his estranged wife by placing cannabis in her car, knowing she could get the death penalty.</p>

<p>Tan Xianglong, 37, was sentenced at a district court on Thursday to three years and 10 months in jail, court documents showed.</p>

<p>The couple had been estranged for less than two years, after having sought a divorce but failing to get one immediately because of the short duration of their union, the documents said.</p>

<p>Tan had been angry at his wife because he thought she did not contribute enough financially to the marriage.</p>

<p>He consulted lawyers and "came away with the idea that a divorce could happen if one of the parties had a criminal record", the documents said.</p>

<p>He initially hired a private investigator to gather evidence she was committing adultery, but no proof was found.</p>

<p>This prompted Tan to hatch the scheme to frame his estranged wife by planting weed in her car -- describing it to his girlfriend as a "perfect plan".</p>

<p>Tan bought the drugs on the black market and weighed them at home, finding they came in at 510 grams (18 ounces) -- more than the 500-gram threshold that merits the death penalty in Singapore.</p>

<p>"From his research online, he knew that the involved party (his wife) would face the death penalty if convicted of trafficking more than 500 grams of cannabis," the court documents said.</p>

<p>"He nonetheless decided to proceed with his plan as he was very angry with the involved party."</p>

<p>A laboratory analysis of the drugs, however, showed they only contained 216.17 grams of pure cannabis.</p>

<p>Tan's wife was arrested after police discovered the drugs in her car, but they found no other incriminating evidence against her.</p>

<p>Police then turned their investigation to Tan, who was subsequently arrested.</p>

<p>The United Nations and rights groups say capital punishment has no proven deterrent effect, and have called for it to be discontinued.</p>

<p>Singaporean officials, however, contend it has helped make the country one of Asia's safest.</p>

<p>The city-state carries out the death penalty by hanging.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/bivti6k_arrest-jail-generic_625x300_05_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tan bought the drugs on the black market (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-air-force-commander-dismissed-day-after-f-16-jet-crash-6455482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Air Force Commander Dismissed Day After F-16 Jet Crash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-air-force-commander-dismissed-day-after-f-16-jet-crash-6455482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 23:06:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelenskiy dismissed Ukraine's Air Force Commander Mykola Oleshchuk on Friday, according to a presidential decree.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky dismissed Ukraine's Air Force Commander Mykola Oleshchuk on Friday, according to a presidential decree.</p>

<p>The dismissal was announced just a day after the Ukrainian military reported that an F-16 jet crashed and its pilot died while repelling a major Russian strike on Monday.</p>

<p>"I have decided to replace the commander of the Air Forces... I am eternally grateful to all our military pilots," President Volodymyr Zelensky said in his evening address.</p>

<p>He did not give a reason for dismissal but mentioned that personnel must be protected, and that there was a need to strengthen the command level.</p>

<p>Ukraine's General Staff said that General Lieutenant Anatoliy Kryvonozhka would temporarily perform the duties of commander.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian military did not provide a reason for Monday's crash but said the jet came down while it was approaching a Russian target. Oleshchuk said on Monday partners from the US were helping to investigate the incident.</p>

<p>A US defense official told Reuters that the crash did not appear to be the result of Russian fire, and possible causes from pilot error to mechanical failure were still being investigated.</p>

<p>The arrival of the first F-16 jets was a milestone for Ukraine in the fight against the full-scale invasion Russia launched 2-1/2 years ago.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3c6ugnbg_zelensky_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Ukrainian military did not provide a reason for Monday's crash (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/namibia-to-kill-700-animals-including-elephants-zebras-and-hippos-for-meat-amid-severe-drought-6454924]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Namibia To Kill 700 Animals, Including Hippos For Meat Amid Severe Drought]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/namibia-to-kill-700-animals-including-elephants-zebras-and-hippos-for-meat-amid-severe-drought-6454924]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 21:34:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The meat will be distributed to those affected as part of a drought relief program. This comes amid an ongoing El Nino-induced drought that has impacted 68 million people in Southern Africa, leading to widespread food shortages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Namibia has approved the killing of hundreds of animals, including elephants, to feed people affected by the severe drought, according to a notice from the southern African nation's government. Last month, the United Nations reported that almost half of Namibia's population suffered from acute food insecurity because of a widely reported food crisis in the country.</p>

<p>In response to this, Namibia's Ministry of Environment, Forestry, and Tourism announced on Monday that meat from the 723 animals to be culled will be distributed as part of a drought relief program. The measure seeks to alleviate the growing hunger crisis in the country.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-70-million-suffering-from-drought-in-southern-africa-report-6358755"><strong>Also Read | Nearly 70 Million Suffering From Drought In Southern Africa: Report</strong></a></p>

<p>"The Ministry will contribute 723 animals, comprising 30 hippos, 60 buffalos, 50 impalas, 100 blue wilderbeasts, 300 zebras, 83 elephants, and 100 elands. The animals are sourced from national parks and communal areas with sustainable game numbers," the ministry <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.meft.gov.na/files/files/Culling%20of%20Wild-animals%20as%20a%20Result%20of%20Drought.pdf">said in a press release.</a></p>

<p>"The culling is being conducted by professional hunters and safari outfitters contracted by the Ministry and conservancies in specific areas. To date, 157 animals comprising different species were hunted in Mangetti. National Park, 20 in Mahango, 70 in Kwando, 6 in Bufallo, and 9 in Mudumo, delivering 56875 kilogrammes of meat."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, about 68 million people in Southern Africa are suffering the effects of an El Nino-induced drought, which has wiped out crops across the region, the regional bloc SADC said on Saturday. The drought, which started in early 2024, has hit crop and livestock production, causing food shortages and damaging the wider economies. Heads of state from the 16-nation Southern African Development Community (SADC) were meeting in Zimbabwe's capital, Harare, to discuss regional issues, including food security.</p>

<p>It is Southern Africa's worst drought in years, owing to a combination of naturally occurring El Nino-when an abnormal warming of the waters in the eastern Pacific changes world weather patterns-and higher average temperatures produced by greenhouse gas emissions.</p>

<p>Countries including Zimbabwe, Zambia, and Malawi have already declared the hunger crisis a state of disaster, while Lesotho and Namibia have called for humanitarian support.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gl39rfh_namibia_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Namibia fighting severe food insecurity exacerbated by a severe drought.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kalpana-chawla-deaths-of-astronauts-weighed-on-nasa-in-sunita-williams-decision-6454781]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kalpana Chawla's Death Weighed On NASA In Sunita Williams Decision]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kalpana-chawla-deaths-of-astronauts-weighed-on-nasa-in-sunita-williams-decision-6454781]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 21:13:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The death of Indian-origin American astronaut Kalpana Chawla and six others on February 1, 2003 when the space shuttle Columbia broke up and burnt as it re-entered the Earth's atmosphere played heavily in the minds of NASA officials.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The death of Indian-origin American astronaut Kalpana Chawla and six others on February 1, 2003 when the space shuttle Columbia broke up and burnt as it re-entered the Earth's atmosphere played heavily in the minds of NASA officials, who decided to keep another Indian-origin American astronaut, Sunita Williams, in space for eight months.</p>

<p>Before the Columbia accident, the space shuttle Challenger had exploded and killed all crew on January 28, 1986. In all, 14 astronauts have lost their lives in these accidents.</p>

<p>The two accidents "very much affected the decision" to bring Boeing Starliner back without the astronauts, said NASA chief Bill Nelson, who is himself an astronaut and has been part of the investigations into the two space shuttle accidents. He said "obvious mistakes were made" by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA).</p>

<p>Kalpana Chawla died over the skies in southern US when the space shuttle Columbia and her crew broke apart during re-entry, 16 minutes prior to the scheduled landing. She went to Tagore School in Haryana's Karnal in 1976, and graduated with a BSc degree in aeronautical engineering from Punjab Engineering College in 1982. She joined NASA as an astronaut in 1994, after completing further education in the US.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/eaf2j3_starliner_625x300_30_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: NASA</span></p>
</div>

<p>Mr Nelson said the culture in NASA back then was such that despite junior flight engineers warning of risks, none heard them. "Today, folks are encouraged to speak their minds," he added.</p>

<p>So, NASA took the decision to bring home astronauts Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore in February 2025, instead of now, in the SpaceX Crew Dragon after engineers spoke their mind about the risks involved in flying the spacecraft in its current condition.</p>

<p>NASA officials said the decision to replace the return spacecraft was "unanimous".</p>

<p>"Spaceflight is risky, even at its safest and most routine. A test flight, by nature, is neither safe nor routine. The decision to keep Butch and Suni aboard the International Space Station (ISS) and bring Boeing's Starliner home without crewed is the result of our commitment to safety - our core value and our North Star," said Mr Nelson.</p>

<p>Space engineers identified helium leaks and experienced issues with the spacecraft reaction control thrusters or small rockets on June 6, as Starliner approached the ISS.</p>

<p>NASA in a statement had said the "uncertainty and lack of expert concurrence does not meet the agency's safety and performance requirements for human spaceflight."</p>

<p>NASA then announced it would bring home Boeing's Starliner without the two astronauts by September 6. It will take six hours to return the Starliner to Earth. The spacecraft has had two uncrewed missions before this one, and Boeing is hopeful that it will return safely.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/be6nk56_butch-wilmore-and-sunita-williams_625x300_30_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore in the International Space Station (ISS)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-singapore-visit-pm-modi-to-visit-singapore-on-september-4-5-to-bolster-strategic-ties-6454246]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi To Visit Singapore On September 4-5 To Bolster Strategic Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-singapore-visit-pm-modi-to-visit-singapore-on-september-4-5-to-bolster-strategic-ties-6454246]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 20:50:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi will visit Singapore in the first week of September, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) announced on Friday.The visit will be crucial in further strengthening bilateral ties between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will visit Singapore in the first week of September, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) announced on Friday.&nbsp;The visit will be crucial in further strengthening bilateral ties between the two nations.</p>

<p>"PM Modi will visit Singapore on September 4 and September 5, 2024, at the invitation of the&nbsp;PM, his excellency Lawrence Wong," Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said.</p>

<p>"The leaders will review the progress of India–Singapore Strategic Partnership and exchange views on regional and global issues of mutual interest. During the visit, Prime Minister will call on President of Singapore H.E. Mr. Tharman Shanmugaratnam and interact with Singaporean leadership. Prime Minister will also meet with business leaders from Singapore," the Ministry of External Affairs said in a press release.</p>

<p>PM Modi's Singapore visit was previously mentioned by Singaporean Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan after senior ministers of India and Singapore concluded a high-level meeting to further their strategic ties.</p>

<p>A four-member Indian delegation, including Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, Commerce Minister Piyush Goyal, and Railways and Information Technology Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw, recently attended the second India-Singapore Ministerial Roundtable (ISMR) in Singapore.</p>

<p>"A country with more than 1.4 billion people is now embarking on a major upgrade of its aviation sector. This is a once in a two, three-decade opportunity, and it's good that we are, in a sense, in the front seat and have a chance (to collaborate)," said Singaporean Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan after the meeting.</p>

<p>During the multi-ministerial meeting, the two countries covered how to strengthen bilateral cooperation in areas such as digital technology, skill development, sustainability, healthcare, connectivity, and manufacturing.</p>

<p>"Glad that progress has been made on several fronts since our last meeting. And new ideas for cooperation are being pursued, including in advanced manufacturing and connectivity. These initiatives will pave the way for closer strategic cooperation and partnership between India and Singapore," said Singapore&nbsp;PM&nbsp;Lawrence Wong after meeting the Indian ministers on Monday.</p>

<p>In 2023-24, bilateral trade between India and Singapore was $35.61 billion, making Singapore India's sixth largest global trade partner.&nbsp;</p>

<p>PM Modi will be visiting Singapore after a visit to Brunei on&nbsp;September 3-4. PM Modi's visit to Brunei will be the "first-ever bilateral visit by an Indian&nbsp;PM&nbsp;to Brunei and will coincide with the 40th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic ties between India and Brunei," says&nbsp;Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal.</p>

<p>"These visits will further strengthen India's cooperation with Brunei and Singapore both bilaterally and within the regional and multilateral frameworks," said the&nbsp;Ministry of External Affairs.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cektlbho_narendra-modi-singapore-pm-lawrence-wong_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Singapore PM Lawrence Wong in a meeting with Prime Minister Narendra Modi in New Delhi. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-takes-action-against-screen-addiction-with-smartphone-ban-in-schools-6454208]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Takes Action Against Screen Addiction With Smartphone Ban In Schools]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-takes-action-against-screen-addiction-with-smartphone-ban-in-schools-6454208]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 19:49:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In response to growing concerns about excessive screen time, France has introduced a law banning smartphones and other electronic devices in schools for students up to age 15.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this digital age, excess screen time has become one of the major health concerns, especially among young teenagers. It's really hampering their physical growth, mental stability, and the time they usually spend outdoors. The educational departments and governments of the whole world are finding ways to deal with this global problem.</p>

<p>Other initiatives aimed at helping people overcome screen addiction include conducting workshops on how to reduce screen time, as evidenced by the evolution of terms such as "digital detox," "screen fast," "unplugging," and "disconnecting from the digital realm." These initiatives highlight the growing recognition of the need to strike a balance between technology and a healthy lifestyle. Now, France is going to put a ban on the use of smartphones at school for students up to the age of 15, seeking to give children a "digital pause."</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.education.gouv.fr/interdiction-du-telephone-portable-dans-les-ecoles-et-les-colleges-et-pause-numerique-7334">release by the French government</a>, the ban covers the use of mobile phones and any other electronic communications terminal equipment (tablets or smart watches, for example) within schools and colleges.</p>

<p>The law also allows the board of directors of high schools to introduce, in the internal regulations, a ban on the use of these devices by high school students. This ban is valid during school and extracurricular time. It is also effective during all school activities organised outside the school or educational establishment.</p>

<p>However, the law has provided some exceptions. Students with disabilities or a disabling health condition retain authorisation to use medical devices associated with communication equipment (devices allowing diabetic children to manage their blood sugar levels, for example).</p>

<p>Concerning conditional prohibitions, the law allows for the stipulation of circumstances, in particular educational uses, and places in which the internal regulations expressly authorise the use of a mobile phone by students. These are indeed cumulative conditions, the internal regulations having to specify both circumstances and places.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gvi65m58_school-smartphone_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The law prohibits mobile phones, tablets, and smartwatches during school hours.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-floods-dumbur-dam-tripura-misleading-narrative-foreign-ministry-blasts-cnn-bangladesh-flood-report-6453954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Misleading Narrative": Foreign Ministry Blasts CNN Bangladesh Flood Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-floods-dumbur-dam-tripura-misleading-narrative-foreign-ministry-blasts-cnn-bangladesh-flood-report-6453954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 19:13:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) has once again trashed reports that the flooding in some areas of Bangladesh were caused by the opening of a dam on the Gumti River in Tripura.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) has once again trashed reports that the flooding in some areas of Bangladesh were caused by the opening of a dam on the Gumti River in Tripura. &nbsp;The Centre said that the report is "factually not correct" and its "narrative is misleading", adding that it &nbsp;"ignores the facts" issued by the Government of India.</p>

<p>"We have seen CNN report on flood situation in Bangladesh. Its narrative is misleading and suggests that India is somehow responsible for the floods. This is factually not correct and ignores the facts mentioned in the press releases issued by the Government of India clarifying the situation," MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said at a presser today. Mr Jaiswal was responding to media queries that flooding in southeast Bangladesh were caused by the opening of a dam on the Gumti River in Tripura.</p>

<p>"They have also ignored that we have regular and timely exchange of data and critical information between the two countries through existing joint mechanisms for water resources management," he added.</p>

<p>Bangladesh is grappling with devastating floods due to relentless monsoon rain and overflowing rivers which has killed at least 23 people. Water has inundated 11 districts, and large swathes of the city of nearly 1.5 million people are now submerged. Amid this, reports in foreign media claimed that the flooding in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/tripura-floods-gumti-river-bangladesh-not-correct-government-on-reports-india-dam-caused-bangladesh-floods-6391337">Bangladesh has been caused by opening a dam in India's northeastern state</a>, a claim denied by Centre twice.</p>

<h3><strong>What CNN Report Said?</strong></h3>

<p>A report published by CNN claimed that in people in Feni, a city in southeast Bangladesh, blame officials in India for the situation. According to the report, dozens in Feni -which is only a few miles from the India border- accused New Delhi of releasing water from the Dumbur dam in neighboring Tripura state with no warning.</p>

<h3><strong>Centre On Bangladesh Floods Claim</strong></h3>

<p>Centre has earlier clarified that flooding in eastern districts in the neighbouring country were not caused by the opening of a dam on the Gumti River in Tripura.</p>

<p>The MEA had acknowledged "the catchment areas of Gumti River that flows through India and Bangladesh witnessed heaviest rains of this year over the last few days", but said the floods in Bangladesh were mainly due to waters from downstream catchments areas.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/tripura-floods-gumti-river-bangladesh-not-correct-government-on-reports-india-dam-caused-bangladesh-floods-6391337">"Not Correct...": Government On Reports India Dam Caused Bangladesh Floods</a></strong></p>

<p>"The Dumbur dam is located quite far from the border - over 120 km upstream of Bangladesh. It is a low height (about 30m) dam that generates power that feeds into a grid and from which Bangladesh also draws 40MW power from Tripura," the ministry had said.</p>

<p>"Heavy rainfall has been continuing since August 21 in the whole of Tripura and adjoining districts of Bangladesh. Data showing rising trend has been supplied to Bangladesh till 1500 on August 21. At 1800, due to flooding, there was power outage leading to problems of communication... we tried to maintain communication through other means..."</p>

<p>"As two countries sharing 54 common cross-border rivers, river water cooperation is an important part of our bilateral engagement. We remain committed to resolving issues and mutual concerns in water resources and river water management through bilateral consultations and technical discussions," the MEA said in a statement.</p>

<p>Floods on the common rivers between India and Bangladesh are a shared problem inflicting sufferings to people on both sides, and requires close mutual cooperation towards resolving them, it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/explained-the-farakka-barrage-agreement-amid-fake-news-on-bangladesh-floods-6427801">Explained: The Farakka Barrage Pact Amid 'Fake News' On Bangladesh Floods</a></strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7g9jtbmg_bangladesh-floods_625x300_26_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh is grappling with devastating floods due to relentless monsoon rain (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-study-reveals-lasting-impact-of-alcohol-on-offsprings-health-and-aging-6453804]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Your Drinking Habits Could Impact Your Grandchildren's Lives]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-study-reveals-lasting-impact-of-alcohol-on-offsprings-health-and-aging-6453804]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 18:55:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite prior knowledge of the mental and social impacts of paternal drinking, the biological consequences on physical health were less understood.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The consequences of alcohol consumption can go way beyond the drinker's individual health. New studies say that excessive consumption may affect generations far into the future, even before it was conceived. Epigenetic inheritance indicates that gene expression is altered without changes in the DNA sequence itself and that the gene expression is inherited. Paternal alcohol exposure has been shown to affect the health and behaviour of the offspring; therefore, a change in practice regarding the long-term effects of alcohol intake is required.</p>

<p>Michael Golding, a Professor of Physiology at Texas A&amp;M University, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://today.tamu.edu/2024/08/28/drinking-alcohol-before-conceiving-a-child-could-accelerate-their-aging/">said in a release</a>, "Although researchers have long recognised that a father's alcohol abuse negatively affects his children's mental health and social development, it hasn't been clear if paternal drinking has any lasting biological effects on his offspring's physical health.</p>

<p>"My lab's recently published research shows that chronic alcohol use from both parents has an enduring effect on the next generation by causing their offspring to age faster and become more susceptible to disease."</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.niaaa.nih.gov/alcohols-effects-health/alcohol-topics/alcohol-facts-and-statistics/alcohol-use-disorder-aud-united-states-age-groups-and-demographic-characteristics">National Institutes of Health</a>, nearly 11% of adults in the US have an alcohol use disorder. Heavy drinking causes multiple health issues, including liver disease, heart problems, declining cognitive function, and accelerated ageing.</p>

<p>Parents may pass these health problems on to their children. Foetal alcohol spectrum disorders refer to a wide range of alcohol-related physical, developmental, and behavioural deficits that affect as many as 1 in 20 US schoolchildren.</p>

<p>"Children with foetal alcohol spectrum disorders experience an early onset of adult diseases, including type 2 diabetes and heart disease. Cardiovascular disease first appears during adolescence for people with these disorders, while the rest of the population is affected typically in their 40s and 50s."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/hkide4p8_chronic-alcohol-_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chronic alcohol use can accelerate aging and increase disease susceptibility in offspring.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-anthropic-sign-deals-with-us-govt-for-ai-research-and-testing-6453313]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI, Anthropic Sign Deals With US Govt For AI Research And Testing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-anthropic-sign-deals-with-us-govt-for-ai-research-and-testing-6453313]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 17:51:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The first-of-their-kind agreements come at a time when the companies are facing regulatory scrutiny over safe and ethical use of AI technologies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AI startups OpenAI and Anthropic have signed deals with the United States government for research, testing and evaluation of their artificial intelligence models, the U.S. Artificial Intelligence Safety Institute said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The first-of-their-kind agreements come at a time when the companies are facing regulatory scrutiny over safe and ethical use of AI technologies.</p>

<p>California legislators are set to vote on a bill as soon as this week to broadly regulate how AI is developed and deployed in the state.</p>

<p>"Safe, trustworthy AI is crucial for the technology's positive impact. Our collaboration with the U.S. AI Safety Institute leverages their wide expertise to rigorously test our models before widespread deployment," said Jack Clark, Co-Founder and Head of Policy at Anthropic, backed by Amazon and Alphabet.</p>

<p>Under the deals, the U.S. AI Safety Institute will have access to major new models from both OpenAI and Anthropic prior to and following their public release.</p>

<p>The agreements will also enable collaborative research to evaluate capabilities of the AI models and risks associated with them.</p>

<p>"We believe the institute has a critical role to play in defining U.S. leadership in responsibly developing artificial intelligence and hope that our work together offers a framework that the rest of the world can build on," said Jason Kwon, chief strategy officer at ChatGPT maker OpenAI.</p>

<p>"These agreements are just the start, but they are an important milestone as we work to help responsibly steward the future of AI," said Elizabeth Kelly, director of the U.S. AI Safety Institute.</p>

<p>The institute, a part of the U.S. commerce department's National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), will also collaborate with the U.K. AI Safety Institute and provide feedback to the companies on potential safety improvements.</p>

<p>The U.S. AI Safety Institute was launched last year as part of an executive order by President Joe Biden's administration to evaluate known and emerging risks of artificial intelligence models.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ijrpj09g_openai_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The agreements will also enable collaborative research to evaluate capabilities and risks of AI models.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-hormone-makes-starfish-lose-limb-to-survive-predators-humans-have-it-too-6452931]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Hormone Makes Starfish Lose Limb To Survive Predators. Humans Have It Too]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-hormone-makes-starfish-lose-limb-to-survive-predators-humans-have-it-too-6452931]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 17:10:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers have identified the hormone that triggers a starfish to shed its limbs to survive predators, describing it as being similar to the one controlling appetite in humans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have identified the hormone that triggers a starfish to shed its limbs to survive predators, describing it as being similar to the one controlling appetite in humans.</p>

<p>The research team at Queen Mary University of London, UK, proposed that when this hormone -- 'ArSK/CCK1' -- is released in response to stress, it triggers a muscle at the base of the starfish's arm to tense, thereby effectively causing it to break off. They studied a common European starfish, Asterias rubens.</p>

<p>The authors said the findings, published in the journal Current Biology, revealed a key piece of the puzzle regarding processes which underlie autotomy, or the ability of an animal to detach a body part to escape predatory attacks.</p>

<p>"Our findings shed light on the complex interplay of neurohormones and tissues involved in starfish autotomy. While we've identified a key player, it's likely that other factors contribute to this extraordinary ability," author Ana Tinoco from Queen Mary University of London said.</p>

<p>Starfish are known to possess the ability to regenerate limbs lost over time. Therefore, understanding the processes related to this ability could have implications for regenerative medicine and the development of new treatments for limb injuries, the researchers said.</p>

<p>"This research not only unveils a fascinating aspect of starfish biology but also opens doors for exploring the regenerative potential of other animals, including humans.</p>

<p>"By deciphering the secrets of starfish self-amputation, we hope to advance our understanding of tissue regeneration and develop innovative therapies for limb injuries," lead researcher Maurice Elphick, a professor of animal physiology and neuroscience at Queen Mary University of London, said.</p>

<p>Autotomy is a well-known survival strategy among animals, another example of which is lizards shedding tails.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/v3h79ch8_starfish-unsplash_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starfish are known to possess the ability to regenerate limbs lost over time (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-more-americans-find-one-job-no-longer-enough-to-survive-6452690]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why More Americans Find One Job No Longer Enough To Survive]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-more-americans-find-one-job-no-longer-enough-to-survive-6452690]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 16:39:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gig economy, once seen as a side hustle, has become essential for supplementing income as inflation outpaces wage increases.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the post-pandemic era, the United States has witnessed a disturbing trend: an increasing number of people are forced to take multiple jobs to make ends meet. Of late, what was once referred to as the "gig economy" or "side hustle" has turned necessary for most Americans who struggle through the rising cost of living, lack of wage increases, and poor economic security. Whereas inflation is consistently beating wage growth, the gig economy has become a sort of lifeline to supplement income derived from a primary source.</p>

<p>According to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/miami/news/more-americans-are-working-two-jobs-to-make-ends-meet/"><em>CBS News,</em></a>&nbsp;the jobs report from the US Department of Labour showed nearly 8.4 million people had multiple jobs in October, 2023. That's the highest number since the start of the pandemic. Women appear to be leading that trend. The federal data showed nearly six percent worked multiple jobs in October compared to 4.7 percent of men. Experts say people may be taking on additional jobs to offset high inflation, which has been easing but is still painfully high for some households. Non-profits like the United Way said inflation is outpacing wage growth, and that's making it harder for them to help families..</p>

<p>According to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/economy/jobs/workers-multiple-jobs-lifestyle-economy-344c8f10"><em>The Wall Street Journal</em></a>, job growth slowed sharply in July, 2024, with the national unemployment rate rising to its highest level since 2021. At the same time, the share of people holding more than one job ticked up to 5.3% in July from 5.2% in June. That is a significant increase from a pandemic low of 4% in April 2020, according to US Bureau of Labour Statistics data. The figure averaged 4.94% from 2010 through 2019.</p>

<p>The comeback of multiple-job holders speaks to some of the mixed currents in an economy that still boasts a growing job market but has come with higher prices on a broad variety of goods and services and essentials like rent and insurance.</p>

<p>"One story is that people are short of cash, and they need extra hours, and the only way to pick up extra hours is by picking up a short-term job," Christopher Taber, chairman of the economics department at the University of Wisconsin, Madison, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/economy/jobs/workers-multiple-jobs-lifestyle-economy-344c8f10">WSJ</a>. "Another story is that it's easier to work two jobs now than it was before."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3tgirkmg_us-cafe_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite a slowing job market, the share of people with more than one job has grown.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/in-shocking-discovery-nasa-finds-invisible-electric-field-around-earth-6452480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Shocking Discovery, NASA Finds Invisible Electric Field Around Earth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/in-shocking-discovery-nasa-finds-invisible-electric-field-around-earth-6452480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 16:10:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This electric field drives the polar wind, propelling charged particles into space at supersonic speeds and shaping Earth's atmosphere, particularly over the poles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a groundbreaking discovery, a long-suspected electric field around Earth has been observed to generate a kind of polar wind that propels particles into space at supersonic speeds. Scientists call this an "ambipolar electric field," which is a weak phenomenon on a global scale-one theorized for the very first time more than 60 years ago. Recent observations from NASA's Endurance rocket, published in <em>Nature</em>, confirm its existence and suggest it significantly influences Earth's atmosphere, most especially over the poles.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://science.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasa-discovers-long-sought-global-electric-field-on-earth/">NASA</a>, the ambipolar electric field is a key driver of the "polar wind," a steady outflow of charged particles into space that occurs above Earth's poles. This electric field lifts charged particles in our upper atmosphere to greater heights than they would otherwise reach and may have shaped our planet's evolution in ways yet to be explored.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UCM1MaYC5lM?si=0z3SarotK2UTZR7c" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Measurements from the rocket, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07480-3">NASA's Endurance mission</a>, have confirmed the existence of the ambipolar field and quantified its strength, revealing its role in driving atmospheric escape and shaping our ionosphere - a layer of the upper atmosphere - more broadly.</p>

<p>Understanding the complex movements and evolution of our planet's atmosphere provides clues not only to the history of Earth but also gives us insight into the mysteries of other planets and determining which ones might be hospitable to life. The paper was published Wednesday, August 28, 2024, in the journal Nature.</p>

<p>"Something had to be drawing these particles out of the atmosphere," said Glyn Collinson, principal investigator of Endurance at NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center in Greenbelt, Maryland, and lead author of the paper. Scientists suspected a yet-to-be-discovered electric field could be at work.</p>

<p>"It's like this conveyor belt, lifting the atmosphere up into space," Collinson added.</p>

<p>Endurance's discovery has opened many new paths for exploration. The ambipolar field, as a fundamental energy field of our planet alongside gravity and magnetism, may have continuously shaped the evolution of our atmosphere in ways we can now begin to explore. Because it's created by the internal dynamics of an atmosphere, similar electric fields are expected to exist on other planets, including Venus and Mars.</p>

<p>"Any planet with an atmosphere should have an ambipolar field," Collinson said. "Now that we've finally measured it, we can begin learning how it's shaped our planet as well as others over time."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0vprea4_earth_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The research opens new avenues for understanding planetary atmospheres.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>