<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 13:35:45 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-syrian-rebels-topple-assad-regime-how-it-may-impact-russia-ukrainewar-7199697]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Syrian Rebels Topple Assad Regime, How It May Impact Russia-Ukraine War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-syrian-rebels-topple-assad-regime-how-it-may-impact-russia-ukrainewar-7199697]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 13:24:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The five decades of Baath rule in Syria ended on Sunday as Islamist-led rebels declared that they had taken Damascus, sending President Bashar al-Assad fleeing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The five decades of Baath rule in Syria ended on Sunday as Islamist-led rebels declared that they had taken Damascus, sending President Bashar al-Assad fleeing. The lightning offensive left global stakeholders to reckon with the geopolitical impact of Syria's fall on ongoing conflicts including the Russia-Ukraine war.</p>

<p>After President Assad's alleged departure, Ukraine said the collapse of Russia's ally Syria in the face of an assault from rebel groups shows Moscow cannot fight on two fronts. "We can see that Russia cannot fight on two fronts -- this is clear from the events in Syria," Ukraine's foreign ministry spokesperson Heorhii Tykhyi told reporters while reiterating denials that Kyiv was involved in the fighting there.</p>

<p>Tykhyi was responding to a question about accusations from Iran, another ally of Assad, that Ukraine was supporting what Tehran called terrorist groups. "Ukraine categorically and decisively rejects any accusations ... about our supposed involvement in the deteriorating security situation in Syria," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>"Russia's significant losses in Ukraine have led Moscow to withdraw the majority of its troops and equipment from Syria, leaving its ally ... without the necessary support," Tykhyi said.</p>

<h2><strong>Fall Of Syria</strong></h2>

<p>At the peak of the conflict in Syria nearly a decade ago, Aleppo was at the frontlines of the war between government-controlled and rebel forces. However, with the help of Russian airpower and the Lebanon-based militant group Hezbollah, President Bashar al-Assad was able to regain control over the entire Aleppo by the end of 2016. Since then, conflict in Syria has been majorly static with the rebels largely confined to the Idlib governate, adjacent to the Aleppo governate.</p>

<p>However, after years locked behind frozen frontlines, Syrian rebels have burst forth to mount the swiftest battlefield advance by either side since a rebellion against President Assad descended into civil war 13 years ago.</p>

<p>Mr Assad, who had crushed all forms of dissent, flew out of Damascus for an unknown destination earlier on Sunday, two senior army officers told Reuters, as rebels said they had entered the capital with no sign of army deployments.</p>

<p>"After 50 years of oppression under Baath rule, and 13 years of crimes and tyranny and (forced) displacement... we announce today the end of this dark period and the start of a new era for Syria," the rebel factions said on Telegram.</p>

<p>But the Syrian army later said it was continuing operations against "terrorist groups" in the key cities of Hama and Homs and in Deraa countryside.</p>

<p>The pace of events in Syria has stunned Arab capitals and raised fears of a new wave of regional instability.&nbsp;Clearly, the armed opposition forces took advantage of the change in the power balance caused by nearby wars-- in Ukraine and in Lebanon and the Middle East.</p>

<p>Israel's war in Gaza and Lebanon has done significant damage to Mr Asaad's ally Iran's so-called axis of resistance, especially Hezbollah. At the same time, Russia, another stakeholder in Syria, is distracted by its fight in Ukraine making it harder to defend the Assad regime.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Russia's Stake In Syria</strong></h2>

<p>The lightning advance of rebels in Syria is threatening one of Russian President Vladimir Putin's proudest achievements, his 2015 military intervention to save Bashar al-Assad's regime. The end of Mr Asaad's control in Syria risks not just Russia's prestige, but its coveted military foothold in the eastern Mediterranean region-- the naval base of Tartus and, further north, the Hmeimim Air Base, both with 49-year-leases received after Russia's regime-saving intervention, according to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/12/06/russia-syria-war-rebels-tartus-bases/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">The Washington Post</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In addition to using these bases to protect Mr Assad's fragile regime, Moscow has used them to challenge American supremacy by projecting its military power in the eastern Mediterranean and claiming the role of a world power with vital regional interests.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Russia, however, currently has its hands full with its war on Ukraine. As per an estimate by Britain's Ministry of Defense, November was the costliest month of the war so far for Moscow's forces, with an average of more than 1,500 killed or wounded a day. Russia has been facing a Ukrainian incursion on its own soil since August that it is struggling to expel, now with the help of North Korean soldiers.</p>

<p>Now, amid the reports of the fall of Syria, Russia is at risk of losing control over the Hmeimim and Tartus bases.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>How Could Fall Of Syria Impact Russia's War In Ukraine?</strong></h2>

<p>According to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://kyivindependent.com/fall-of-aleppo-deals-blow-to-russias-middle-east-clout-may-indirectly-strengthen-ukraines-hand/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">The Kyiv Independent</a>, Charles Lister, a Syria expert at the Middle East Institute said even during the war on Ukraine, Moscow never scaled its military presence back down. However, the quality of Russia's officer corps in Syria had declined.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Russia retains exactly the same troop levels. They've conducted the same number of air sorties over Syria with the same geographical breadth that they did prior to the war in Ukraine," he said, speaking on the Lawfare podcast.</p>

<p>What has changed, however, is that Russia can no longer count on the Wagner Group, which has played a significant role in safeguarding the Kremlin's interests in Syria in the past. Bogged down in Ukraine, Russia cannot send serious reinforcements to its military contingent in the Middle Eastern country either, according to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/russia-loser-fall-syria-s-aleppo" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">The Interpreter.</a>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Following its invasion of Ukraine, the Kremlin has lost several allies from the Collective Security Treaty Organisation (CSTO). The end of Mr Asaad's regime could mean Russia loses Syria as well, forcing the Kremlin to eventually shut down its Khmeimim Air Base in the Latakia area, and the naval facility in Tartus.</p>

<p>In the last two years of war, Moscow has redeployed weaponry from Syria to Ukraine, including Pantsir missile systems. Exposing its military and political weakness in Syria could undermine Russia's leverage in any potential negotiations surrounding Ukraine.</p>

<p>The fall of Aleppo has exposed the Kremlin to the risk of military overreach and has put its alliance with Iran under stress because of its competing military objectives in the country, according to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.euronews.com/2024/12/04/syria-how-the-conflict-could-impact-the-ukraine-crisis-and-migration" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Euro News</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Russia is thus keen on encouraging dialogue between Ankara and Damascus and has deployed diplomatic efforts to open trilateral negotiations.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/61kuovo_syria-civil-war-afp_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/united-airlines-offers-free-fantasy-flights-to-see-santa-at-north-pole-7199556]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[United Airlines Offers Free 'Fantasy Flights' To See Santa At North Pole]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/united-airlines-offers-free-fantasy-flights-to-see-santa-at-north-pole-7199556]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 13:00:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Children with cancer or who have been orphaned by the loss of someone on active duty are taken aboard the short flight to the fantasy land.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US-based United Airlines is spreading Christmas cheer by offering free 'Fantasy flights' to children in need to the 'North Pole' to see Santa Claus. The flights will depart from 13 cities including Los Angeles London and Tokyo among others. One of the first "Fantasy Flight" took off from Honolulu on Saturday (Dec 7) bringing some smiles to those in need. "Santa has invited us to Christmas Island and all his elves are waiting there on the ground for us," the pilot of Flight 3894, announced over the intercom.</p>

<p>Families that have children with cancer or who have been orphaned by the loss of someone on active duty are taken aboard a short flight that loops back around and lands right where they started. However, upon exiting, children are transported to Santa's hometown, the “North Pole" -- a fantasy winter wonderland created by United airport employees and local volunteers who "transform an average airport gate or maintenance hangar into a sea of twinkling lights, sparkling Christmas trees and Santa himself – along with his elves".</p>

<p>"We've stocked up on de-icing fluid to fly from even more cities. United is honoured to uplift children and their families through the joy of the holiday season. Making the North Pole closer than ever is one of the many ways we can show support for the communities where we live, work and fly," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.united.com/en/us/newsroom/announcements/cision-125357" rel="noindex, nofollow">said </a>Kate Gebo, United's Executive Vice President of Human Resources.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/these-are-the-best-and-worst-airlines-of-2024-according-to-airhelp-score-report-7178362" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | These Are The Best And Worst Airlines Of 2024, According To AirHelp Score Report</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Internet reacts</strong></h3>

<p>Social media users lauded the move by United Airlines and called it a heartwarming gesture that would mean a lot to the kids.</p>

<p>"That is the nicest most heartwarming story. Thank you, United for spreading true Christmas joy!" said one user while another added: "What a wonderful experience for these children &amp; families...ENJOY!"</p>

<p>A third commented: "Christmas is the season of miracles. Good on United to bring cheer to these kids."</p>

<h3><strong>Flight schedule:</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Honolulu (HNL) December 5</li>
	<li>Washington-Dulles (IAD) December 7</li>
	<li>Houston Bush (IAH) December 7</li>
	<li>Los Angeles (LAX) December 7</li>
	<li>London (LHR) December 7</li>
	<li>Chicago-O'Hare (ORD) December 7</li>
	<li>San Francisco (SFO) December 7</li>
	<li>Tokyo (NRT) December 8</li>
	<li>Cleveland (CLE) December 10</li>
	<li>Fort Lauderdale (FLL) December 10</li>
	<li>Guam (GUM) December 13</li>
	<li>Denver (DEN) December 14</li>
	<li>Newark (EWR) December 14</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1lb3lts8_christmas_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[United Airlines dressed for the 'Fantasy Flights'.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/whos-who-of-the-al-assads-brother-maher-sister-bushra-her-husband-asef-shawkat-7199005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Who's Who Of Al-Assads: Inside Syria's Most Powerful Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/whos-who-of-the-al-assads-brother-maher-sister-bushra-her-husband-asef-shawkat-7199005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:52:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Behind the smoke and chaos of Syria's ongoing turmoil, the Al-Assad family stands as the untouchable core -- a dynasty that has moulded the country's fate for over half a century. At the centre is Bashar al-Assad.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syrian President Bashar Al-Assad has reportedly fled Damascus, signalling the end of his rule after more than a decade of brutal civil war. Rebel groups, including Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, have made significant advances, leaving the capital vulnerable and marking the collapse of Assad's once impenetrable government.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The capital, now left vulnerable, stands as a symbol of the regime's sudden fall.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The shifting power dynamics reflect the unravelling of a family dynasty that has defined Syria's fate for over half a century. Bashar Al-Assad was the "last standing". Often called "a dictator without a dictator," his power relied not just on his leadership, but on the unyielding support of his "inner circle", his closest family members - his brother Maher, a fiery military commander; his sister Bushra, known as "the Iron Lady"; and her husband Asef Shawkat, a calculating intelligence figure. But as Assad flees, their once-unified front begins to fracture.</p>

<p>Here's a closer look at the key players within the regime's inner circle:</p>

<p><strong>Maher Al-Assad</strong></p>

<p>Fifty-six-year-old Maher al-Assad, Bashar's younger brother, commands Syria's Republican Guard and the 4th Armoured Division, making him a key figure in both Syria's military and its alliance with Iran. Known as the hardliner of the family, Maher is described as "the ruthless face of power" and oversees the Shabiha militia, which protects the Assad regime's interests.</p>

<p>Sanctioned by the EU in 2011 for his role in violence against protesters, Maher's reputation for cruelty is reflected in protests that often target him directly. He has also been linked to the 1999 shooting of his brother-in-law, Asef Shawkat, and named a suspect in the 2005 assassination of Lebanese prime minister Rafik Hariri.</p>

<p><strong>Anisa Makhlouf</strong></p>

<p>Anisa Makhlouf, widow of the late Syrian President Hafez al-Assad and mother of Bashar, may keep a low profile, but she holds the final say on all matters within the Assad family. "Decisions are made collectively in the family's inner circle, but Anisa has the last say," said Wael al-Hafez, a member of the Syrian opposition in exile, according to the feminist blog Les Martiennes.</p>

<p><strong>Bushra Al-Assad</strong></p>

<p>Born in 1960, Bushra Al-Assad is Bashar's only sister and a trained pharmacist. Like her brother Maher, she is known as a hawk within the regime and plays a significant role as Bashar's secretary. In the mid-1990s, she married Asef Shawkat. Bushra has also had a strained relationship with Bashar's wife, Asma. According to former Syrian diplomat Mohammed Daoud, Bushra long prevented Asma from assuming the title of Syria's "First Lady," a title she preferred to keep with her mother, Anisa. She has business ties with Rami Makhlouf, Bashar's maternal cousin.</p>

<p><strong>Rami Makhlouf</strong></p>

<p>Rami Makhlouf, Bashar al-Assad's first cousin, controls about 60 per cent of Syria's business. Born in 1965, he's considered Syria's richest man, with interests in telecommunications, retail, energy, banking, and transportation. The US sanctioned him in 2008 for abusing political influence, and the EU followed in 2011, accusing him of funding the crackdown on protesters.</p>

<p>Hated for corruption, Rami Makhlouf recently announced plans to donate part of his fortune to charity. His brother, Hafez Makhlouf, heads Syria's civilian intelligence service.</p>

<p><strong>Asef Shawkat</strong></p>

<p>General Asef Shawkat, an Alawite military officer, married Bashar al-Assad's sister, Bushra, in 1995. Initially rejected by the Assad family, he eventually gained their trust and built a close relationship with Bashar. Asef Shawkat quickly rose through the ranks, serving as Head of Military Intelligence, then Deputy Military Intelligence Chief, and later Chief of Military Intelligence until 2005. Despite facing international controversies, he was reassigned as Deputy Chief-of-Staff in 2008. He, along with Maher al-Assad, is linked to the 2005 assassination of Lebanese Prime Minister Rafik Hariri.</p>

<p><strong>Asma Al-Assad</strong></p>

<p>Born in London in 1975 to a Syrian diplomat family, Asma Al-Assad married Bashar al-Assad in December 2000. The couple has three sons: Hafez, Zein, and Karim. Asma holds degrees in computer science and French literature from King's College London and worked in investment banking before marrying Bashar. She played a key role in shaping Bashar's image as a moderate reformer. In 2005, she launched an organisation to encourage Syrian youth to embrace "active citizenship." Rumors suggest that, since the uprising began, Asma has exiled herself in London with their children.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/5dr2eku_assad-family-_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Assad family's long rule over Syria seems to be at an end.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-civil-war-the-rise-of-baath-party-and-how-it-solidified-its-hold-on-syria-7199256]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Rise Of Ba'ath Party And How It Solidified Its Hold On Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-civil-war-the-rise-of-baath-party-and-how-it-solidified-its-hold-on-syria-7199256]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:34:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Since Hafez al-Assad seized power in 1971, Syria's political structure has been dominated by three key pillars: the Ba'ath Party, the Alawite minority, and the Syrian Army.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syrian President Bashar al-Assad has fled Damascus as rebel forces, including Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, entered the capital, marking what they have called the “end of the era of tyranny.” This follows over a decade of civil war that has devastated Syria. Since his father Hafez al-Assad seized power in 1971, Syria's political structure has been dominated by three key pillars: the Ba'ath Party, the Alawite minority, and the Syrian Army, which have formed the foundation of the Assad regime and its ruling elite. The Ba'ath Party, a pan-Arab socialist movement, has shaped Syria's governance for decades since its establishment in the mid-20th century.</p>

<h2><strong>The Ba'ath Movement</strong></h2>

<p>The Arab Baʽath Movement, founded by Michel Aflaq in 1940, was the precursor to the Arab Socialist Baʽath Party. Initially named the Arab Ihya Movement (Arab Revitalisation Movement), it focused on Arab nationalism and socialism.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-president-bashar-al-assad-has-left-damascus-as-rebels-advance-towards-capital-news-agency-reuters-7198265">"End Of Era Of Tyranny": Bashar Al-Assad Flees Syria As Rebels Move In</a></p>

<p>The movement became involved in anti-colonial activities, including supporting Iraq during the Anglo-Iraqi War in 1941. Aflaq also ran for the Syrian parliament in 1943 but lost. Afterward, the movement worked with other political parties, including Akram El-Hourani's Arab Socialist Movement. In 1947, the Arab Ihya Movement merged with Al-Arsuzi's Arab Baʽath Party, and in the 1950s, El-Hourani's movement joined as well, creating the Arab Socialist Baʽath Party.</p>

<h2><strong>The Formation of the Ba'ath Party</strong></h2>

<p>The Ba'ath Party is a political organisation that has dominated Syrian life for nearly five decades. Initially focused on Arab nationalism and pan-Arab unity, the Baath Party's slogan, "unity, freedom, socialism," appealed to many across the Middle East in the mid-20th century. Its goal was to challenge Western-backed governments and establish a modern, industrial economy.</p>

<h2><strong>The Ba'ath Party in Syria</strong></h2>

<p>In 1963, military officers including Hafez Al-Assad seized control of Syria through a coup, making the party shift to military dominance. The Ba'ath Party's ideological roots clashed with its military wing, causing rifts, and by 1970, Hafez al-Assad consolidated his power, sidelining civilian leaders like Aflaq.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After Assad's rise to power in 1971, the party solidified its hold on Syria, using a combination of political repression and strategic alliances with the Alawite minority, the military, and key tribal groups. The Ba'ath Party's power was intertwined with the Assad family's rule, creating a highly centralised regime that, while espousing socialism and Arab unity, became increasingly authoritarian.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-assad-family-damascus-the-al-assads-syrias-first-familys-rapid-rise-brutal-rule-abrupt-end-7198899">Fall Of Assads: How An Alawite Family Ruled Over A Sunni Nation For Decades</a></p>

<p>The 1973 constitution granted the Ba'ath Party unique status as the “leader of the state and society,” embedding it into every facet of Syrian life – from schools to government and military structures.</p>

<p>Bashar Al-Assad, who succeeded his father Hafez as president in 2000, initially appeared as a reformer but faced backlash as his attempts to open the system fell short. The party continued to thrive in an increasingly authoritarian state, with opposition stifled by brutal force, such as in the 1982 Hama massacre. Despite calls for reform, the Baath Party remained central to Syria's political structure. Bashar's rule faced significant unrest in 2011, but the party's leadership, largely loyal to the Assad family, held firm.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Syrian vs Iraqi Ba'ath Parties</strong></h2>

<p>Although both the Syrian and Iraqi branches of the Ba'ath Party shared common origins and ideals, their paths diverged significantly after the party's initial rise to power in both countries.</p>

<p>In Syria, the Ba'ath Party evolved under Hafez al-Assad and later his son, Bashar al-Assad. The party upheld the principles of Arab unity and socialism but focused heavily on maintaining control through a close-knit alliance with the Alawite minority and the military. The Assad family's inner circle played a key role in decision-making, ensuring the party's grip on power.</p>

<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-syrias-assad-used-chemical-weapons-to-suppress-civilian-unrest-7199264">How Syria's Assad Used Chemical Weapons To Suppress Civilian Unrest</a></p>

<p>In Iraq, Saddam Hussein led the Ba'ath Party with a more authoritarian and nationalist approach. Unlike Syria, Saddam did not rely on a specific minority group to consolidate power but instead promoted a strong Arab nationalist agenda. His regime was marked by aggressive internal purges and brutal policies toward ethnic minorities, such as Kurds and Shiites, to maintain control.</p>

<p>Though both parties aimed for Arab unity, Saddam's vision was more focused on Iraq's dominance in the Arab world, often leading to policies that conflicted with Syria's interests, including Iraq's invasion of Kuwait in 1990.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mqfgr9lg_assad-afp_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Arab Baath Movement was founded by Michel Aflaq in 1940.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-launches-free-tier-for-grok-ai-chatbot-7199369]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Grok AI Chatbot Now Free For All Users, But Has Limits]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-launches-free-tier-for-grok-ai-chatbot-7199369]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:24:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X (formerly known as Twitter) has rolled out a free, limited-tier version of its AI chatbot, Grok, in a move to broaden its user base.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X (formerly known as Twitter) has rolled out a free, limited-tier version of its AI chatbot, Grok, in a move to broaden its user base. This offering, which was previously locked behind a premium subscription, is now accessible to non-premium users, albeit with certain restrictions.</p>

<p>On Friday, users discovered that the chatbot, developed by Musk's AI company xAI, is available to free-tier subscribers, allowing them to send up to 10 messages to Grok every two hours. The free version also includes limited access to image-related features, with users able to analyse up to three images and generate four new ones per day.</p>

<p>For X's Premium subscribers, which include those paying $7 for Premium and $14 for Premium+, access to Grok is more extensive, allowing up to 50 questions per day. Users must also have an X account that is at least seven days old and linked to a phone number to access the free-tier chatbot.</p>

<p>Grok, which xAI launched in 2023 as a "humorous AI assistant", was initially exclusive to Premium users of X. The chatbot was enhanced in August with a text-to-image generation tool, though it quickly gained attention for producing some controversial images. A month later, xAI began testing a free version of Grok in select regions, and the current update expands that availability.</p>

<p>Grok's capabilities go beyond casual conversation. It can assist with research, coding support, and even automate customer service for businesses. While xAI has not disclosed exact user numbers, unofficial estimates suggest that Grok's user base could be in the millions, a number that could grow with the introduction of the free tier.</p>

<p>The free-tier rollout is seen as a strategic effort to compete with other popular, no-cost chatbots such as OpenAI's ChatGPT, Google's Gemini, Microsoft's Copilot, and Anthropic's Claude. These competitors have established a significant presence in the AI space, with OpenAI reporting 300 million active weekly users, and Meta's chatbot boasting nearly 600 million monthly active users.</p>

<p>Grok is the flagship product of xAI, which was founded by Musk in 2023 and is currently valued at $50 billion. The company's AI offerings have an edge due to the vast amounts of data collected from X and Tesla, the latter contributing visual data from its car cameras. xAI also has substantial computing power, thanks to a newly built supercomputer in Memphis, Tennessee, which is being expanded to further scale up AI training.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fgvbcodo_grok_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Grok was launched in 2023 as a "humorous AI assistant".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-war-bashar-al-assad-damascus-how-syrian-teens-graffiti-became-bashar-al-assads-writing-on-the-wall-7199318]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Syrian Teen's Graffiti Became Bashar Al-Assad's Writing On The Wall]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-war-bashar-al-assad-damascus-how-syrian-teens-graffiti-became-bashar-al-assads-writing-on-the-wall-7199318]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:16:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In early 2011, in the streets of Daraa, southern Syria, a teenager's rebellious act against an authoritarian regime triggered a civil war that reshaped the country's destiny.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In early 2011, in the streets of Daraa, southern Syria, a teenager's rebellious act against an authoritarian regime triggered a civil war that reshaped the country's destiny. Mouawiya Syasneh, then just 14 years old, spray-painted a wall with words that would have grave implications.</p>

<p>"Ejak el door, ya doctor (It's your turn, Doctor) - this graffiti, directed at President Bashar al-Assad, with reference to his medical background, became the catalyst for a national uprising that descended into one of the most devastating civil wars of the 21st century.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-assad-family-damascus-the-al-assads-syrias-first-familys-rapid-rise-brutal-rule-abrupt-end-7198899#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Fall Of Assads: How An Alawite Family Ruled Over A Sunni Nation For Decades</a></p>

<p>The graffiti was a teenage prank born of frustration. Mouawiya and his friends, subjected to harassment by local police, decided to make their voices heard in the most visible way they knewt. But this act of rebellion against Assad's regime drew a swift and brutal response.</p>

<p>The secret police, or the Mukhabarat detained them for 26 days. Tortured and beaten, their eventual release only fueled the anger of Daraa's residents. Parents, neighbours, and activists who had protested for their release were met with tear gas and bullets.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-president-bashar-al-assad-has-left-damascus-as-rebels-advance-towards-capital-news-agency-reuters-7198265">"End Of Era Of Tyranny": Bashar Al-Assad Flees Syria As Rebels Move In</a></p>

<p>As images of the battered boys spread, the incident became a rallying cry. Protests erupted not only in Daraa but across Syria. On March 15, 2011, Syria experienced its first coordinated "Day of Rage," transforming local unrest into a nationwide movement demanding freedom and the end of Assad's regime.</p>

<h2><strong>The Domino Effect</strong></h2>

<p>The crackdown that followed was brutal and unrelenting. Security forces opened fire on peaceful demonstrators, imprisoned dissidents, and subjected countless Syrians to torture. What began as a movement inspired by the Arab Spring quickly escalated into a bloody conflict as opposition forces armed themselves in response. By the time the Arab Spring erupted in neighbouring Tunisia and Egypt - toppling Zine El Abidine Ben Ali and Hosni Mubarak, respectively - Syria was a powder keg waiting for a spark.</p>

<p>The Free Syrian Army (FSA) emerged in July 2011, comprising defectors from Assad's military, but it lacked the cohesion and resources to present a unified front. This vacuum allowed extremist groups, such as Jabhat al-Nusra and later the Islamic State, to rise, capitalising on the chaos and sectarian fractures.</p>

<p><strong>WATCH </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-regime-change-bashar-al-assad-video-statues-of-bashar-al-assads-father-dragged-through-syria-roads-7199151#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Video: Statues Of Bashar Al-Assad's Father Dragged Through Syria Roads</a></p>

<p>Twelve years after those fateful graffiti strokes, Syria lay in ruins. More than 500,000 were killed, and over 13 million Syrians were displaced.</p>

<p>Now, after a brief thaw, a renewed civil uprising looks set to remove the Assad family's control over Syria. Led by a group called Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), several rebel factions have taken over key Syrian cities, including the capital Damascus, the seat of Assad's power.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to reports, Assad has left Damascus for an unknown destination, with speculations suggesting that he might have left for Tehran. Iran, a long-standing partner of the Assad family, is believed to be ready to offer the Assad family a safe haven while Syria descends into uncertainty. &nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/27u02nt8_syria-teen-graffiti_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Twelve years after those fateful graffiti strokes, Syria lay in ruins.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-syrias-assad-used-chemical-weapons-to-suppress-civilian-unrest-7199264]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Syria's Assad Used Chemical Weapons To Suppress Civilian Unrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-syrias-assad-used-chemical-weapons-to-suppress-civilian-unrest-7199264]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:07:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Syrian rebels have declared the start of a new era as they marched into the capital Damascus this morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syrian rebels have declared the start of a new era as they marched into the capital Damascus this morning. President Bashar Al-Assad, whose family has ruled the Middle Eastern country for over 50 years, has fled the country and the Syrian army command has confirmed to its officers that the Assad rule has ended.</p>

<p>Assad had maintained a strong grip on Syria despite protests and rebels joining hands to free the Sunni-majority country from an Alawite ruler. Even the slightest of protests evoked the strictest of responses from Assad's forces. Assad had used chemical weapons to suppress the civilian unrest that had kept his government on the brink for over a decade.</p>

<p>The use of chemical weapons amounts to a war crime, as per international laws. At least 193 countries are signatories to the Chemical Weapons Convention, which aims to eliminate chemical weapons as a weapons of mass destruction.</p>

<p>Syria became a member of the convention in 2013 and declared they have removed all their chemical weapons. However, questions still remain about the completeness of Syria's declaration.</p>

<h2><strong>Attacks On Ghouta</strong></h2>

<p>Ghouta bears witness to one of the worst chemical attacks in the history of Syria. The morning of August 21, 2013 captured a horror never seen before as the Assad regime carried out two chemical attacks on the opposition-controlled suburbs of Damascus. The attacks led to the death of hundreds of civilians, including children.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/g5ecut2g_ghouta-chemical-attack-2013_625x300_08_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A surface-to-surface rocket system was used to carry out the attack, according to an investigation by Human Rights Watch. Sarin, an extremely potent nerve agent, was likely used in the attack as doctors said the victims showed symptoms of exposure to nerve gas - suffocation, nausea, frothing in the mouth, and fluids coming out of eyes and noses.</p>

<p>Denying responsibility for the attack, the Syrian government had put the blame on the opposition groups. HRW claims that it has found no evidence that supported the Syrian claim.</p>

<p>The severity of the attack could be understood from the visuals -available online - showing rows of bodies of dead adults and children wrapped in white shrouds.</p>

<p>In 2017, Assad had carried out another chemical attack on rebels in Khan Shaykhun. In response, then-US President Donald Trump had ordered strikes on Syria.</p>

<h2><strong>Fears Over Chemical Weapons</strong></h2>

<p>The Assad chapter may be over, but fears remain over the future of chemical weapons. US intelligence agencies assess that the forces had limited stockpiles, including sarin-loaded munitions, intended to be used against the rebels. The agencies are now monitoring the chemical weapons storage sites.</p>

<h2><strong>Torture Of Detainees</strong></h2>

<p>Syrian protesters were often picked up and tortured in jails. There have been reports of children being maimed and sexually abused by Assad's forces and recruited for fighting by the rebels.</p>

<p>In a recent <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/12/1157931" rel="no follow,no index">UN report</a>, former detainees of the Syrian government have described the inhumane conditions they were kept in and the physical and psychological abuse unleashed on them. This includes beatings, stress positions, and sexual violence.</p>

<p>"Thousands of families bear the psychological toll of not knowing where their loved ones are. This is unimaginable psychological torture, yet the Syrian Government continues to intentionally withhold and cover-up information," said Robert Petit, head of the UN International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism (IIIM), which prepared the report.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/918h2ic8_ghouta-chemical-attack-2013_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Assad had maintained a strong grip on Syria despite protests. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-is-bashar-al-assad-questions-over-syrian-presidents-whereabouts-7199259]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Where Is Bashar Al-Assad? Questions Over Syrian President's Whereabouts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-is-bashar-al-assad-questions-over-syrian-presidents-whereabouts-7199259]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:06:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Syria war monitor said that President Bashar al-Assad has left the country, after losing swathes of territory to a lightning offensive led by an Islamist-led rebel coalition that said it entered Damascus on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Syria war monitor said that President Bashar al-Assad has left the country, after losing swathes of territory to a lightning offensive led by an Islamist-led rebel coalition that said it entered Damascus on Sunday.</p>

<p>Residents in the Syrian capital told AFP heavy gunfire rang out, after a source close to Hezbollah saying fighters from the key Assad ally had left their positions around Damascus.</p>

<p>The president's reported departure comes less than two weeks after the Islamist Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS) group launched its campaign challenging more than five decades of rule by the Assad family.</p>

<p>"Assad left Syria via Damascus international airport before the army security forces left" the facility," Rami Abdel Rahman, head of the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights told AFP.</p>

<p>AFP was unable to immediately confirm the report.</p>

<p>After saying their forces were heading into the capital, HTS announced an "end of the era of tyranny in the prison of Sednaya" as they broke into the jail which has become a by-word for darkest abuses of the Syrian regime.</p>

<p>The rapid developments in Damascus come only hours after HTS said they had captured the strategic city of Homs, on the way to the capital.</p>

<p>The defence ministry earlier denied that rebels had entered Homs, describing the situation there as "safe and stable".</p>

<p>Homs lies about 140 kilometres (85 miles) north of the capital and was the third major city seized by the rebels who began their advance on November 27, reigniting a years-long war that had become largely dormant.</p>

<h3><strong>Hezbollah fighters leave</strong></h3>

<p>Monitoring events in Damascus, the Britain-based Observatory confirmed "the doors of the infamous 'Sednaya' prison... have been opened for thousands of detainees who were imprisoned by the security apparatus throughout the regime's rule".</p>

<p>Earlier, Assad's government denied the army had withdrawn from areas around Damascus.</p>

<p>"A very strong security and military cordon" was being established by the armed forces around the capital "and no one... can penetrate this defensive line", Interior Minister Mohammed al-Rahmoun told state television.</p>

<p>Assad has for years been backed by Lebanese Hezbollah, whose forces "vacated their positions around Damascus" according to a source close to the group.</p>

<p>Hezbollah "has instructed its fighters in recent hours to withdraw from the Homs area, with some heading to Latakia (in Syria) and others to the Hermel area in Lebanon", the source also told AFP.</p>

<p>A source close to Hezbollah earlier said it had sent 2,000 fighters into Syria, to an area near the Lebanese border, "to defend its positions".</p>

<h3><strong>'Suddenly everyone was scared'</strong></h3>

<p>The defence ministry earlier insisted: "There is no truth to news claiming our armed forces... have withdrawn" from positions near Damascus.</p>

<p>The Syrian army said that, in addition to the area around Damascus, it was reinforcing positions in the south, and operations against the rebels were beginning in the Hama, Homs and Daraa areas.</p>

<p>AFP has been unable to independently verify some of the information provided by the government and the rebels, as its journalists cannot reach the areas around Damascus where the rebels say they are present.</p>

<p>Residents of the capital described to AFP a state of panic as traffic jams clogged the city centre, people sought supplies and queued to withdraw money from ATMs.</p>

<p>"The situation was not like this when I left my house this morning... suddenly everyone was scared," said one woman, Rania.</p>

<p>A few kilometres (miles) away, the mood was starkly different.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a Damascus suburb, witnesses said protesters toppled a statue of Assad's father, the late leader Hafez al-Assad.</p>

<p>AFPTV images from Hama, Syria's fourth-largest city, showed abandoned tanks and other armoured vehicles, one of them on fire.</p>

<p>Hama resident Kharfan Mansour said he was "happy with the liberation of Hama and the liberation of Syria from the Assad regime".&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Soldiers 'fled' to Iraq</strong></h3>

<p>The Observatory said government forces had ceded more key ground, losing control of all southern Daraa province, the cradle of the 2011 uprising.</p>

<p>The army said it was "redeploying and repositioning" in Daraa and another southern province, Sweida.</p>

<p>The Observatory also said troops were also evacuating posts in Quneitra, near the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Jordan has urged its citizens to leave neighbouring Syria "as soon as possible", as have the United States and Assad ally Russia, which both keep troops in Syria.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent in Daraa saw local fighters guarding public property and civil institutions.</p>

<p>In Sweida, a local fighter told AFP that after government forces withdrew "from their positions and headquarters, we are now securing and protecting vital facilities".</p>

<p>An Iraqi security source told AFP that Baghdad has allowed in hundreds of Syrian soldiers, who "fled the front lines", through the Al-Qaim border crossing. A second source put the figure at 2,000 troops, including officers.</p>

<h3><strong>'War, blood and tears'</strong></h3>

<p>HTS is rooted in the Syrian branch of Al-Qaeda. Proscribed as a terrorist organisation by Western governments, it has sought to soften its image in recent years, and told minority groups living in areas they now control not to worry.</p>

<p>Since the offensive began, at least 826 people, mostly combatants but also including 111 civilians, have been killed, the Observatory said.</p>

<p>The United Nations said the violence has displaced 370,000 people.</p>

<p>UN special envoy to Syria, Geir Pedersen, called for "urgent political talks" to implement a 2015 Security Council resolution, which set out a roadmap for a negotiated settlement.</p>

<p>US President-elect Donald Trump posted on his Truth Social platform that the United States should "not get involved", after outgoing US Secretary of State Antony Blinken called Friday for a "political solution to the conflict", in a call with Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan.</p>

<p>After Fidan and his Iranian and Russian counterparts discussed Syria in Qatar on Saturday, Iran's top diplomat Abbas Araghchi said they agreed on the initiation of "political dialogue between the Syrian government and legitimate opposition groups".</p>

<p>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said it was "inadmissible" to allow a "terrorist group to take control" of Syrian territory.</p>

<p>Moscow and Tehran have supported Assad's government and army during the war.</p>

<p>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, whose government backs some armed groups in northern Syria, said Saturday that Syria "is tired of war, blood and tears".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/bashar-al-assad-reuters_625x300_1528038939914.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United Nations said the violence has displaced 370,000 people.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-regime-change-bashar-al-assad-video-statues-of-bashar-al-assads-father-dragged-through-syria-roads-7199151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Statues Of Bashar Al-Assad's Father Dragged Through Syria Roads]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-regime-change-bashar-al-assad-video-statues-of-bashar-al-assads-father-dragged-through-syria-roads-7199151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 11:41:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Syrian President Bashar Al Assad fled the country amid a regime change and rebel forces moved in, statues of his father and former President Hafez Al-Assad in and around the capital were pulled down by protesters welcoming the rebel fighters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Syrian President Bashar Al Assad fled the country amid a regime change and rebel forces moved in, statues of his father and former President Hafez Al-Assad in and around the capital were pulled down by protesters welcoming the rebel fighters.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">More history in the making - Syrians in Jaramana, a SE <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Damascus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Damascus</a> suburb, tear down the Hafez al-<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Assad?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Assad</a> statue.<br />
<br />
The end is near. <a href="https://t.co/ySTpVKHImo">pic.twitter.com/ySTpVKHImo</a></p>
— Charles Lister (@Charles_Lister) <a href="https://twitter.com/Charles_Lister/status/1865391700576714930?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Seizing power through a coup in 1970, Hafez Al-Assad started as a Prime Minister and then remained Syria's President till his death in 2000. The three-decade rule, though autocratic, gave Syria an era of stability and established it as a major force in the Middle East. His son, Bashar Al Assad, succeeded him and ruled Syria for over two decades till an armed rebellion overthrew his regime.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is the head of a statue of Hafez Al-Assad. The person who massacred their families in the 80s, the former dictator and the father of the current dictator. Syrians will never stop fighting until freedom is achieved. This is <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hama?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Hama</a> <a href="https://t.co/wxQJTGwlyj">pic.twitter.com/wxQJTGwlyj</a></p>
— Omar Alshogre | عمر الشغري (@omarAlshogre) <a href="https://twitter.com/omarAlshogre/status/1865141639406100744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Dramatic scenes played out in the streets of Damascus and other cities as the regime changed in Syria. In particularly symbolic visuals, a statue of former President Hafez al-Assad was pulled down in Syria's fourth-largest city Hama -- over 200 km from Damascus. Celebratory firing and cries of 'Allahu Akbar' rang out loud as the statue was destroyed. A video showed a vehicle dragging the statue's decapitated head through the road as people chased it to kick. In the city of Latakia too, a statue of the former President was pulled down as protesters cheered and recorded the moment on their phones.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>The vandalism of statues is a symbolic act witnessed in regime changes worldwide in recent history. When the Sheikh Hasina government in Bangladesh was overthrown earlier this year, statues of the country's first president and Sheikh Hasina's father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman were vandalised. The scenes in Syria are also reminiscent of the 2003 footage of a US armoured vehicle toppling a statue of former dictator Saddam Hussein on the day Baghdad fell.</p>

<p>The rebellion that proved to be Bashar Al Assad's undoing began after peaceful anti-government protests in 2011 were repressed. Over time, the movement snowballed into a complex conflict drawing in foreign powers and leaving half a million people dead and many more displaced.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/q2almmng_syria_625x300_08_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former Syria President Hafez Al Assad's statues are being pulled down]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/internet-detectives-are-refusing-to-solve-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-heres-why-7199067]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Internet Sleuths Refusing To Solve UnitedHealthcare CEO's Murder. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/internet-detectives-are-refusing-to-solve-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-heres-why-7199067]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 11:27:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Online armchair detectives and true crime enthusiasts are refusing to provide any help as police investigate the death of UnitedHealthcare CEO.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the authorities expand their search effort to nab the masked assailant who gunned down UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, internet sleuths are refusing to step in to provide any help. The assassin fired multiple rounds on Mr Thompson from behind in the early morning using a gun with a silencer attached to it. He fled the scene on a bicycle before entering Central Park with the police claiming that he may have fled the city by bus. Several videos and still images going viral on social media show the gunman calmly going about his business after the killing.</p>

<p>Despite the trail of evidence, the authorities have been unable to catch him so far. Online armchair detectives and true crime enthusiasts who usually end up solving such cases have been uncharacteristically reluctant to provide any help, primarily owing to the history of the healthcare company in denying claims to those in need.</p>

<p>Michael McWhorter, better known as TizzyEnt on social media, where he posts true crime and viral news content said the community was indifferent to the death of the top Manhattan CEO.</p>

<p>"I have yet to see a single video that's pounding the drum of 'we have to find him,' and that is unique," said Mr McWhorter in one of the videos, adding: "And in other situations of some kind of blatant violence, I would absolutely be seeing that."</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQH24EP94H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQH24EP94H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQH24EP94H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQH24EP94H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Michael McWhorter (@tizzyent)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Savannah Sparks, who has 1.3 million followers on her social media and has previously helped train police officers on how to track suspects online, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/internet-sleuths-say-wont-help-find-unitedhealthcare-ceo-suspect-rcna183228" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>NBC News</em></a>, "Absolutely the f--- not," when asked if she was working to find the suspect.</p>

<p>Another online sleuth who goes by the handle thatdaneshguy told his followers in a video: "I don't have to encourage violence. I don't have to condone violence by any means. But I also don't have to help."</p>

<p>Danesh added that he had removed a photo that may have helped the police find the killer as he did not want to "accidentally help".</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNqxogyu2_/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNqxogyu2_/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNqxogyu2_/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDNqxogyu2_/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Danesh (@thatdaneshguy)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<h3><strong>Reward offered to identify gunman</strong></h3>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) is offering $50,000 for any information leading to the arrest and conviction of the gunman. The FBI's reward is in addition to a $10,000 reward offered by the police. As per the New York Police Department (NYPD), the attack appears to be pre-mediated based on the evidence collected so far.</p>

<p>The bullet casings found at the scene were carved with the words, "deny," "defend" and "depose" -- the three tenets employed by insurers to deny claims, and described in a 2010 book critical of the industry titled <em>Delay Deny Defend</em>.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-search-in-new-york-to-find-suspect-who-shot-unitedhealth-ceo-7187154" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Massive Search In New York To Find Suspect Who Shot UnitedHealth CEO</strong></a></p>

<p>UnitedHealth is the largest US health insurer, providing benefits to tens of millions of Americans. However, the company has received widespread scrutiny for leaving its customers in peril when they seek healthcare benefits for the hefty insurance premiums they have paid for years. Notably, Thompson joined UnitedHealth in 2004 and became the CEO of UnitedHealthcare, a unit of UnitedHealth Group, in April 2021.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gv8mu7g_united_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The suspect caught in CCTV footage wearing a mask and hoodie.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-autism-center-faces-abuse-allegations-after-staffer-drags-child-by-genitals-7198971]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Autism Center Faces Abuse Allegations After Staffer Drags Child By Genitals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-autism-center-faces-abuse-allegations-after-staffer-drags-child-by-genitals-7198971]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 11:09:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Garnet Collins, 50, a caregiver at the facility, was seen allegedly trying to control Anil's son by squeezing his genitals.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Anderson Center for Autism, a prestigious institution in Dutchess County, New York, is facing renewed scrutiny following disturbing allegations of abuse against its vulnerable residents. This renowned facility, with a century-long history of providing services for individuals with autism and developmental disabilities, has been the subject of growing concern due to repeated reports of mistreatment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A recent incident, captured on video by a whistleblower, has brought the issue to the forefront. The footage allegedly depicts a caregiver, Garnet Collins, abusing a teenage resident. This revelation has sparked outrage and raised serious questions about the quality of care provided within the institution.</p>

<p>In the disturbing footage, Garnet Collins, 50, a caregiver at the facility, was seen allegedly trying to control Anil's son by squeezing his genitals.</p>

<p>"Every day. Every day. Every day. It kills me to think about the amount of abuse and torture he went through," Anil told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fox5ny.com/news/autism-facility-faces-abuse-allegations-after-shocking-video-surfaces" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Fox5</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The incident has had a profound impact on Anil, the father of the abused teenager. He shared his harrowing experience, highlighting the distress caused by the alleged abuse. The whistleblower, who risked their own well-being to expose the misconduct, deserves recognition for their bravery in bringing this critical issue to light.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We immediately got in the car, drove upstate, pulled him out of the residence, and contacted the New York State Troopers," Anil recalled.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Garnet Collins, the caregiver accused of abusing a resident at the Anderson Center for Autism, was arrested and charged with endangering the welfare of an incompetent person and forcible touching. Despite facing a potential decade in prison, legal experts predict a much shorter sentence, possibly even avoiding jail time entirely, the media outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Collins's arrest follows a disturbing pattern of alleged abuse at the facility. In 2023, another caregiver was found responsible for injuring Anil's son with a broom handle. The family also alleges that their son experienced significant weight loss due to inadequate food and care.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7lmkuefg_anderson-center-for-autism_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A recent incident, captured on video by a whistleblower, has brought the issue to the forefront.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-assad-family-damascus-the-al-assads-syrias-first-familys-rapid-rise-brutal-rule-abrupt-end-7198899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fall Of Assads: How An Alawite Family Ruled Over A Sunni Nation For Decades]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-assad-family-damascus-the-al-assads-syrias-first-familys-rapid-rise-brutal-rule-abrupt-end-7198899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 10:51:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Assads have ruled Syria for over half a century. Today, rebel forces have breached their seat of power Damascus, prompting President Bashar al-Assad to flee and effectively ending the family's rule over Syria.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Assads have ruled <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-war-bashar-al-assad-syrian-rebels-beseige-damascus-assad-regime-braces-for-last-stand-7198085" target="_blank">Syria</a> for over half a century. Today, rebel forces have breached their seat of power Damascus, prompting President Bashar al-Assad to flee and effectively ending the family's rule over Syria.</p>

<p>For over five decades, this Alawite dynasty has held sway over a predominantly Sunni nation. This long rule, initiated by Hafez al-Assad in 1970, now stares at an abrupt end.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Hafez al-Assad: Architect Of Modern Syria</strong></h2>

<p>Hafez al-Assad rose to power in a coup on November 13, 1970, marking the beginning of a new era in Syria. At the time, the country was characterised by political instability, with a series of coups dominating its post-independence history. Hafez, a member of the Alawite minority, built his power base as commander of the Syrian Air Force and minister of defence. By the time he seized control, he had cultivated a loyal network within the military and the Ba'ath Party.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-president-bashar-al-assad-has-left-damascus-as-rebels-advance-towards-capital-news-agency-reuters-7198265#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"End Of Era Of Tyranny": Bashar Al-Assad Flees Syria As Rebels Move In</a></p>

<p>Hafez's strategy relied on divide-and-rule tactics, exploiting Syria's ethnic, religious, and political divisions. His system meant that he became the linchpin holding the state together. The result was a weak institutional structure that left his successors with a brittle foundation.</p>

<p>To fortify his regime, Hafez elevated the Alawite minority, traditionally a marginalised group, to positions of power in the military and government. At the same time, he manipulated Syria's sectarian and tribal fault lines to neutralize potential threats, ensuring that no single group could challenge his authority.</p>

<p>Following Syria's independence in 1946, the Alawite community emerged as a significant force in two key areas: political movements and the armed forces. This shift marked a departure from their historically marginalised status, as the Alawites began to assert influence within Syria's evolving power structures.</p>

<p>The Alawite minority, which makes up roughly 12-15 per cent of Syria's pre-war population, has been the regime's primary base of support. This loyalty stems in part from the community's historical marginalisation and the opportunities afforded to them under the Assads, particularly in the military and security services.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-war-bashar-al-assad-syrian-rebels-beseige-damascus-assad-regime-braces-for-last-stand-7198085#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Syrian Rebels Enter Damascus, US Fears President Assad's Chemical Weapons</a></p>

<p>Alawites, while not doctrinally Shia, venerate Ali ibn Abi Talib, a figure central to Shia Islam.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Baath Party, established in 1947, &nbsp;sought to unite Arab nationalism, socialism, secularism, and anti-imperialism. For many Alawites, the Baath Party's secular and inclusive ideals offered a more appealing alternative to the Muslim Brotherhood, a Sunni Islamist organisation founded in Egypt that had garnered a considerable following in Syria.</p>

<h2><strong>A Dynasty By Design</strong></h2>

<p>Hafez al-Assad intended to pass his legacy to his eldest son, Bassel, who was groomed for leadership. However, Bassel's untimely death in a car accident in 1994 forced Hafez to turn to his second son, Bashar, a relatively inexperienced ophthalmologist. When Hafez died in 2000, Bashar assumed the presidency, confirmed in office by a referendum that secured 97 per cent of the vote - a predictable outcome.</p>

<p>Bashar's ascent was initially met with optimism. Many Syrians and foreign observers hoped he would bring reforms and openness to a system long stifled by authoritarian rule. However, those hopes quickly dissipated. Bashar inherited not only his father's system but also his father's inner circle, composed of ageing revolutionary leaders who had controlled key state institutions since the 1970s.</p>

<h2><strong>Bashar's Consolidation Of Power</strong></h2>

<p>Bashar's early years in power were marked by attempts to replace his father's allies with his own confidants, most of whom belonged to Syria's urban elite. Unlike their predecessors, Bashar's inner circle had no grassroots connections, isolating the regime from Syria's rural population.</p>

<p>The weakening of state institutions under Bashar coincided with the rise of a narrow clique of elites centred around his family. Figures such as his brother Maher, his sister Bushra, and her husband Asef Shawkat played key roles in the regime's security and military apparatus. Economic power was concentrated in the hands of regime cronies, most notably Rami Makhlouf, Bashar's cousin, who reportedly controlled more than 60 per cent of Syria's economy.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-news-assad-regime-falls-rebels-declare-new-era-5-big-developments-7198671#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Assad Regime Falls, Rebels Declare "New Era" In Syria: 5 Big Developments</a></p>

<p>Hafez al-Assad's rule was marked by brutal repression, most infamously in 1982 when the Syrian military crushed an armed uprising by the Muslim Brotherhood in the city of Hama. Estimates of the death count range from 10,000 to 40,000, making it one of the most violent crackdowns in modern Middle Eastern history.</p>

<p>This pattern of repression continued under Bashar, culminating in the 2011 uprising that marked Syria's entry into the wave of Arab Spring protests. What began as peaceful demonstrations in Deraa escalated into a full-scale civil war after the regime responded with violent crackdowns. The conflict has since claimed hundreds of thousands of lives and displaced millions.</p>

<p>Bashar's tenure has been marked by economic mismanagement and growing inequality. While GDP per capita doubled between 2000 and 2010, the benefits were concentrated among a small elite. Widespread poverty, unemployment, and corruption exacerbated public discontent. A severe drought in the late 2000s, compounded by poor resource management, forced hundreds of thousands of rural Syrians into urban areas.</p>

<p>The Assad regime's survival strategy has been rooted in its "shadow state" model, where real power resides outside formal institutions. This system, designed to be coup-proof, relies on overlapping security agencies, patronage networks, and a culture of mutual surveillance. While effective in maintaining control, it has rendered Syria's governance opaque and unaccountable.</p>

<p>Despite the façade of elections and constitutional reforms, Syria remained a de facto dictatorship.</p>

<h2><strong>2011 And Beyond&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Over thirteen years after the Syrian uprising began with hopeful cries for reform, the civil war remains an unresolved catastrophe. Born from the Arab Spring, Syria's descent into chaos was marked by the regime's violent crackdown on protests that spread from Daraa in 2011.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Those early demonstrations, driven by demands for modest reforms, escalated into an all-out civil war, leaving hundreds of thousands dead and millions displaced. &nbsp;In 2024, after a brief thaw, a renewed surge in violence thrust the conflict back into global focus.</p>

<p>Rebel forces, led by a group called Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), have launched an unprecedented offensive, directly challenging the regime for the first time in years. HTS, an Islamist faction once linked to al-Qaida, has attempted to shed its extremist image under the leadership of Abu Mohammed al-Jolani, yet it remains designated a terrorist organisation by the United Nations and the United States.</p>

<p>The rebels' rapid march and occupation of key cities eventually ended with them taking control of Damascus and prompting the al-Assads to flee.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/q1cek90g_assad-family-afp-_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bashar al-Assad's ascent was initially met with optimism.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrias-mohammed-al-jolani-leader-of-rebel-alliance-who-led-assads-downfall-7198896]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syria's Mohammed Al-Jolani: Leader Of Rebel Alliance Who Led Assad's Downfall]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrias-mohammed-al-jolani-leader-of-rebel-alliance-who-led-assads-downfall-7198896]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 10:50:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Abu Mohammed al-Jolani is the leader of the Islamist alliance that spearheaded an offensive that rebels say brought down President Bashar al-Assad and ended five decades of Baath Party rule in Syria.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Abu Mohammed al-Jolani is the leader of the Islamist alliance that spearheaded an offensive that rebels say brought down President Bashar al-Assad and ended five decades of Baath Party rule in Syria.</p>

<p>Jolani heads Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), which is rooted in Syria's branch of Al-Qaeda.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He is an extremist who adopted a more moderate posture in order to achieve his goals.</p>

<p>On Sunday, as the rebels entered Damascus, he ordered all military forces in the capital not to approach public institutions.</p>

<p>He had earlier this week said the objective of his offensive, which saw city after city fall from government control, was to overthrow Assad.</p>

<p>Thirteen years after Assad cracked down on a nascent democracy movement, sparking Syria's civil war, the rebels said the president had fled the country and declared Damascus free of the "tyrant".</p>

<p>Jolani had for years operated from the shadows.</p>

<p>Now, he is in the spotlight, giving interviews to the international media and delivering statements that have Syrians all around the world glued to their phones for clues of what the future might hold.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier in the offensive, which began on November 27, he appeared in Syria's second city Aleppo after wresting it from government control for the first time in the war.</p>

<p>He has over the years stopped sporting the turban worn by jihadists, often favouring military fatigues instead.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, he wore a khaki shirt and trousers to visit Aleppo's citadel, standing at the door of his white vehicle as he waved and moved through the crowds.</p>

<p>Since breaking ties with Al-Qaeda in 2016, Jolani has sought to portray himself as a more moderate leader.</p>

<p>But he is yet to quell suspicions among analysts and Western governments that still class HTS as a terrorist organisation.</p>

<p>"He is a pragmatic radical," Thomas Pierret, a specialist in political Islam, told AFP.</p>

<p>"In 2014, he was at the height of his radicalism," Pierret said, referring to the period of the war when he sought to compete with the jihadist Islamic State group.</p>

<p>"Since then, he has moderated his rhetoric."</p>

<h3><strong>Well-to-do</strong></h3>

<p>Born in 1982, Jolani was raised in Mazzeh, an upscale district of Damascus.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He stems from a well-to-do family and was a good student.</p>

<p>During the offensive, he started signing his statements under his real name -- Ahmed al-Sharaa.</p>

<p>In 2021, he told US broadcaster PBS that his nom de guerre was a reference to his family roots in the Golan Heights, claiming that his grandfather had been forced to flee after Israel's annexation of the area in 1967.</p>

<p>According to the Middle East Eye news website, it was after the September 11, 2001 attacks that Jolani was first drawn to jihadist thinking.</p>

<p>"It was as a result of this admiration for the 9/11 attackers that the first signs of jihadism began to surface in Jolani's life, as he began attending secretive sermons and panel discussions in marginalised suburbs of Damascus," the website said.</p>

<p>Following the US-led invasion of Iraq, he left Syria to take part in the fight.</p>

<p>He joined Al-Qaeda in Iraq, led by Abu Musab al-Zarqawi, and was subsequently detained for five years, preventing him from rising through the ranks of the jihadist organisation.</p>

<p>In March 2011, when the revolt against Assad's rule erupted in Syria, he returned home and founded the Al-Nusra Front, Syria's branch of Al-Qaeda.</p>

<p>In 2013, he refused to swear allegiance to Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, who would go on to become the emir of the Islamic State group, and instead pledged his loyalty to Al-Qaeda's Ayman al-Zawahiri.</p>

<h3><strong>'Smart thing to do'</strong></h3>

<p>A realist in his partisans' eyes, an opportunist to his adversaries, Jolani said in May 2015 that he, unlike IS, had no intention of launching attacks against the West.</p>

<p>He also proclaimed that should Assad be defeated, there would be no revenge attacks against the Alawite minority that the president's clan stems from.</p>

<p>He cut ties with Al-Qaeda, claiming to do so in order to deprive the West of reasons to attack his organisation.</p>

<p>According to Pierret, he has since sought to chart a path towards becoming a credible statesman.</p>

<p>In January 2017, Jolani imposed a merger with HTS on rival Islamist groups in northwest Syria, thereby claiming control of swathes of Idlib province that had fallen out of government hands.</p>

<p>In areas under its grip, HTS developed a civilian government and established a semblance of a state in Idlib province, while crushing its rebel rivals.</p>

<p>Throughout this process, HTS faced accusations from residents and rights groups of brutal abuses against those who dared dissent, which the UN has classed as war crimes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Aware perhaps of the fear and hatred his group has sparked, Jolani has addressed residents of Aleppo, home to a sizeable Christian minority, in a bid to assure them that they would face no harm under his new regime.</p>

<p>He also called on his fighters to preserve security in the areas they had "liberated" from Assad's rule.</p>

<p>"I think it's primarily just good politics," said Aron Lund, a fellow at the Century International think tank.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The less local and international panic you have and the more Jolani seems like a responsible actor instead of a toxic jihadi extremist, the easier his job will become. Is it totally sincere? Surely not," he said.</p>

<p>"But it's the smart thing to say and do right now."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dc1boc6o_syria_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jolani heads Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), which is rooted in Syria's branch of Al-Qaeda.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-regime-change-bashar-al-assad-shops-shutting-down-atms-dry-panic-in-damascus-as-syria-regime-changes-7198806]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Are Afraid Because...": As Rebels Move In, Damascus Fears Uncertainty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-regime-change-bashar-al-assad-shops-shutting-down-atms-dry-panic-in-damascus-as-syria-regime-changes-7198806]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 10:33:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As rebel forces move into the Syrian capital Damascus after the fall of the Bashar Al-Assad regime, there is panic as well as celebration on the streets]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As rebel forces move into the Syrian capital Damascus after the fall of the Bashar Al-Assad regime, there is panic as well as celebration on the streets. While some people were seen celebrating atop a tank in Ummayad Square, a resident told AFP that Damascus residents were worried over what would come next and looking for essential supplies.</p>

<p>Rania, a woman resident, said traffic jams had begun as people amassed essential items and queued to withdraw money from ATMs. "The situation was not like this when I left my house this morning... suddenly everyone was scared," Rania told AFP.</p>

<p>"We are afraid because we really don't know what's going to happen," another resident, Shahla, told BBC. "Nobody wants to see fighting in Damascus. Everything is ambiguous and nothing is clear for anyone."</p>

<p>Rim Turkmani, director of Syria Conflict Research Programme at the London School of Economics, told BBC that her sister in Damascus told her that shops were closing down, supplies were running low and ATMs were out of cash. "No one knows what's happening," Ms Turkmani said.</p>

<p>When an Al Jazeera correspondent spoke to people on the streets, they welcomed the rebel forces' win. Slamming the Bashar Al-Assad regime, one of them said it was forcing young men to join the Army and many people fled to Lebanon because they did not want to fight their fellow Syrians.</p>

<p>The overthrow of the Bashar al-Assad regime follows a 13-year rebellion that started as a peaceful uprising against President Assad and snowballed into a full-scale civil war that devastated Syria.</p>

<p>Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, which led the offensive, was formed in 2012 under the name of al-Nusra. It pledged allegiance to al-Qaeda the next year. In 2016, however, it broke ties with al-Qaeda and took the name Hayat Tahrir al-Sham. Global powers, including the US and the UK, continue to see it as an al-Qaeda affiliate. The organisation has, in recent times, tried to soften its image and assured minority groups in the areas it controls have no cause to worry.</p>

<p>Hayat Tahrir al-Sham consolidated its power in Idlib and Aleppo and formed the Syrian Salvation Government to administer the territory. In 2020, Turkey and Russia brokered a ceasefire to halt the Bashar Al-Assad regime's push to retake Idlib.</p>

<p>Over the last two months, the rebels renewed their offensive, aware that the Syrian government's allies were caught up in other conflicts. Hezbollah and Iran have taken a blow after Israel's offensive and Russia is fighting Ukraine. This left Bashar Al-Assad exposed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/iiofo85o_syria-streets_625x300_08_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Bashar al-Assad regime as fallen and rebels have taken control of Damascus]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-news-assad-regime-falls-rebels-declare-new-era-5-big-developments-7198671]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What's Happening In Syria? 5 Big Developments As Rebels Take Over]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-news-assad-regime-falls-rebels-declare-new-era-5-big-developments-7198671]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 10:03:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Bashar al-Assad government has, by all means, fallen in Syria. The Sunni-majority country, rocked by a fierce rebellion against an Alawite ruler, now looks ahead for a new start after half a century.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Syrian army command has informed its soldiers that the Assad regime has fallen after the rebels declared that President Assad has fled the country. "We declare the city of Damascus free," they said on Telegram as they stomped into the capital this morning.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The rebels also announced the start of a "new era" for Syria. "After 50 years of oppression under Baath rule, and 13 years of crimes and tyranny and (forced) displacement, we announce today the end of this dark period and the start of a new era for Syria," they said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Syrian rebels have called on citizens staying abroad to return to a "free Syria". This morning, they broke into Sednaya jail - known for the darkest abuses under Assad regime - and set the prisoners free.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Syrian Prime Minister Mohammed al-Jalali has vowed to cooperate with any leadership that the people choose. Stating that he is ready for any handover process, he said in a Facebook broadcast, "We are ready to cooperate and offer all possible facilities."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The rebel forces' leader has asserted that government institutions will remain under the Prime Minister until the handover process is over. Abu Mohammed al-Jolani, who heads the rebel group Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, has ordered the "military forces" in Damascus not to approach the institutions.</li>
</ol>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/if1j4gmg_syria-assad-afp_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rebels have announced the start of a "new era" for Syria.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-stopped-gifting-his-family-10-000-in-cash-at-christmas-he-did-this-instead-7198667]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Warren Buffett Stopped Gifting His Family $10,000 On Christmas. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-stopped-gifting-his-family-10-000-in-cash-at-christmas-he-did-this-instead-7198667]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 10:01:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Buffett began gifting his family members shares in companies he had recently invested in, including Coca-Cola.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire investor Warren Buffett, known for his frugal lifestyle, initially gifted his family members thousands of dollars in cash. However, after witnessing their tendency to quickly spend these gifts, he shifted his approach, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fortune.com/2024/12/06/warren-buffett-family-christmas-gifts-cash-spending-stocks/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Fortune </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"As soon as we got home, we'd spend it, whoo!" the billionaire's former daughter-in-law, Mary Buffett, who was married to his son Peter in 1980 told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thinkadvisor.com/2019/10/25/how-warren-buffetts-daughter-in-law-learned-his-investing-secrets/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>ThinkAdvisor</em></a>. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Instead of cash, Buffett began gifting his family members shares in companies he had recently invested in, including Coca-Cola.</p>

<p>"Then, one Christmas there was an envelope with a letter from him. Instead of cash, he'd given us $10,000 worth of shares in a company he'd recently bought, a trust Coca-Cola had," she said.</p>

<p>This strategy not only provided a more valuable gift in the long term but also served as an invaluable lesson in investing and wealth building.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His former daughter-in-law recounted how she initially intended to sell the gifted shares but ultimately held onto them, witnessing their significant growth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I thought: "Well, [the stock] is worth more than $10,000. So I kept it, and it kept going up."&nbsp;</p>

<p>This experience instilled in her a long-term investment perspective, influencing her financial strategies.</p>

<p>Warren Buffett's commitment to prioritizing long-term investments over short-term gratification reflects his philosophy of building wealth through patience and discipline.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At 94 years old, Buffett is well-known for his pledge to donate 99% of his wealth and not leave the bulk of his fortune to his children, stating he has "never wished to create a dynasty." Dubbed the "Oracle of Omaha," Buffett reiterated this stance last month while appointing three independent trustees to oversee his philanthropy after his three children stepped down, as reported by CNBC.</p>

<p>In a letter, Buffett explained his decision, writing: "I've never wished to create a dynasty or pursue any plan that extended beyond the children. I know the three well and trust them completely. Future generations are another matter. Who can foresee the priorities, intelligence, and fidelity of successive generations to deal with the distribution of extraordinary wealth amid what may be a far different philanthropic landscape?"</p>

<p>Buffett, whose children are now 71, 69, and 66 years old, has acknowledged the possibility that his wealth could take longer to distribute than his children may live. In addition to naming the trustees, he also donated $1.1 billion in Berkshire Hathaway stock to his family's four charitable foundations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-03/nadlfpao_warren-buffett-bloomberg_625x300_01_March_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Buffett is well-known for his pledge to donate 99% of his wealth]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrias-bashar-al-assad-the-president-who-led-a-bloody-crackdown-7198591]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syria's Bashar Al-Assad: The President Who Led A Bloody Crackdown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrias-bashar-al-assad-the-president-who-led-a-bloody-crackdown-7198591]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 09:48:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Syrian President Bashar al-Assad oversaw a merciless crackdown on a pro-democracy revolt that morphed into one of the bloodiest wars of the century.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syrian President Bashar al-Assad oversaw a merciless crackdown on a pro-democracy revolt that morphed into one of the bloodiest wars of the century.</p>

<p>On Sunday, as rebels entered the capital, a Syrian war monitor said he had left the country, in what could spell the end not just of his 24-year rule but the downfall of his clan's five-decade reign.</p>

<p>After facing down nationwide protests demanding his ouster and an armed rebellion that he all but crushed, Assad had -- until a lightning rebel offensive -- taken back control of much of Syria in the civil war that began in 2011.</p>

<p>Quiet in demeanour, Assad had for years relied on his alliances with Russia, Iran and Lebanon's Hezbollah in order to maintain power.</p>

<p>While leading a merciless war of survival for his rule, he presented himself to his people and the outside world as Syria's only viable leader in the face of the Islamist threat.</p>

<p>But an Islamist-led rebel offensive that began on November 27 wrested city after city from Assad's control.</p>

<p>On Sunday the rebels announced they had entered Damascus.</p>

<p>Shortly afterwards, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said he had left the country, while the rebels themselves said the "tyrant" had "fled".</p>

<h3><strong>No real opposition</strong></h3>

<p>For years, Assad had cast himself as the protector of Syria's minorities, a bulwark against extremism and the sole possible purveyor of stability for a country ravaged by war.</p>

<p>In multiple votes held over the years, conducted solely on government-held territory, he took the vast majority of the ballots, amid accusations from Western countries and rights groups that the elections were neither free nor fair.</p>

<p>In official meetings, during interviews and even on the front lines, the 59-year-old ophthalmologist by training conducted himself calmly.</p>

<p>Behind the facade, however, was an astonishing ability to hold onto power amid multiple waves of violence and transformative change in Syria and the wider region.</p>

<h3><strong>'Shuffle the cards'</strong></h3>

<p>One journalist, who met with Assad on several occasions before and after war broke out in 2011, told AFP Assad is a "unique and complex figure".</p>

<p>Assad has "the same qualities" as his father, Hafez al-Assad, who ruled Syria for nearly three decades until his death in 2000, said the journalist, who declined to be named.</p>

<p>Hafez al-Assad, head of the Syrian Baath Party, imposed in the country a secretive, paranoid regime where even the slightest suspicion of dissent could land one in jail or worse.</p>

<p>Bashar al-Assad was never meant to become president, but his life changed radically when his older brother Bassel, who was being groomed to inherit power, died in a road accident in 1994.</p>

<p>Bashar quit his studies in ophthalmology and left London, where he had met his wife Asma, a British-Syrian and Sunni Muslim who worked for financial services firm JP Morgan.</p>

<p>Back home, he took a course in military studies and was tutored in politics by his father.</p>

<p>When the latter died, Bashar became president by referendum, running unopposed, then winning a second term in 2007.</p>

<p>Sworn in at the age of 34, Assad was initially seen by Syrians pining for freedoms as a reformer who could do away with years of repression and introduce economic liberalisation.</p>

<p>In the early days, Assad would be seen driving his own car or having dinner at restaurants with his wife.</p>

<p>He relaxed some of the heavy restrictions that existed under his father.</p>

<h3><strong>Deadly crackdown</strong></h3>

<p>But his initial image as a reformer quickly evaporated as authorities arrested and jailed academics, intellectuals and other members of what was then known as the Damascus Spring movement.</p>

<p>When the Arab Spring reached Syria in March 2011, peaceful demonstrations broke out calling for change.</p>

<p>Assad, who was also commander-in-chief of the armed forces, responded by ordering a brutal crackdown on the protesters and civil war swiftly ensued.</p>

<p>Throughout the war, which killed more than 500,000 people and displaced half the population, Assad's position on the demonstrators and the opposition did not change.</p>

<p>To Syria and to the world, he justified the bombings and military campaigns as a war on "terrorists".</p>

<p>Meanwhile, his security apparatus enforced a brutal system of imprisoning dissidents in a network of detention centres and jails dotted around the country that have become notorious for abuses.</p>

<p>He was the subject of countless cartoons by dissident artists depicting him as a killer, not least in the aftermath of the 2013 chemical attacks on rebel bastions around Damascus.</p>

<p>Since the start of the Islamist-led rebel offensive, Assad has echoed his long-held stance that the conflict in Syria is machinated from abroad.</p>

<p>"The terrorist escalation reflects the far-reaching goals of dividing the region and fragmenting the countries in it and (to) redraw the map in line with the objectives of the United States and the West," Assad said on Monday.</p>

<p>He is the father of three children. His wife, Asma, was dubbed a "rose in the desert" by Vogue magazine before the revolt.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1g9g6fvo_assad_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Sunday the rebels announced they had entered Damascus.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/musical-parodying-viral-breakdancer-raygun-cancelled-after-her-team-threatens-legal-action-7198533]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musical Parodying B-Girl Raygun Cancelled After Her Team Threatens Action]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/musical-parodying-viral-breakdancer-raygun-cancelled-after-her-team-threatens-legal-action-7198533]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 09:35:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Comedian Steph Broadbridge who helmed the project, took to Instagram to inform about the musical's cancellation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australian Olympian Rachael 'Raygun' Gunn has managed to shut down a musical parody that was scheduled to debut on Saturday (Dec 7) night at the iD Comedy Club in Sydney -- based on her breakdancing performance at the Paris Olympics. Ms Gunn's legal team approached the writer and promoter of the musical, titled <em>Raygun: The Musical parody</em>, and threatened them with action if they did not stop the production. Comedian Steph Broadbridge who helmed the project, took to Instagram to inform about the cancellation, stating that they were told not to use the name "Raygun" or the infamous "kangaroo dance" over concerns for her intellectual property.</p>

<p>"They were very concerned that people would think that Rachael Gunn was affiliated with the musical," said Ms Broadbridge. "I want to assure everyone that she will not be part of the show. She's very welcome to come, I would love for her to see it."</p>

<p>Ms Broadbridge said despite the setback, she would be bringing the show back soon and "with a whole new arc".</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQTiBbzLiZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQTiBbzLiZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQTiBbzLiZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDQTiBbzLiZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Steph broadbridge (@stephbroadbridge)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<h3><strong>'Protecting the brand'</strong></h3>

<p>Meanwhile, Raygun's team said they were "committed to protecting her intellectual property and ensuring that her brand remains strong and respected".</p>

<p>"While we have immense respect for the credible work and effort that has gone into the development of the show, we must take necessary steps to safeguard Rachael's creative rights and the integrity of her work," read the statement.</p>

<p>"This action is not intended to diminish the contributions of others, but rather to ensure her brand is properly represented and protected in all future endeavours," it added.</p>

<p>Raygun's team managed to stop the show despite satire and comedy being exempt under fair dealing in the Australian copyright law. Notably, Ms Gunn applied to have the name "RAYGUN" trademarked in August but the application remains under scrutiny.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://sports.ndtv.com/othersports/australian-breakdancer-raygun-who-got-trolled-in-paris-olympics-takes-huge-step-6962562" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Australian Breakdancer "Raygun", Who Got Trolled In Paris Olympics, Takes Huge Step</strong></a></p>

<p>Raygun became viral on social media after her performance during the Olympics invited attention to the sport of breakdancing. She participated in three Olympic battles against breakers from the United States, France and Lithuania and lost all of them without scoring a single point.</p>

<p>Wearing a green Australian tracksuit, Raygun's kangaroo-inspired hop and jump performance was viewed millions of times and led to a sea of memes. Even after her rather amusing performance, the World DanceSport Federation (WDSF) - the governing body of breaking and other dance sports, ranked her as the no.1 breakdancer in the world in September.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/j5s4g0m_rachael-raygun-gunn_625x300_08_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia's Rachael Gunn, known as Raygun during Paris Olympics.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-army-assists-un-forces-in-repelling-attack-in-syria-7198531]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Army Assists UN Forces In 'Repelling Attack' In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-army-assists-un-forces-in-repelling-attack-in-syria-7198531]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 09:33:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army said Saturday that its troops were assisting UN peacekeepers in the Syrian-controlled part of the Golan Heights in repelling an attack "by armed individuals".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army said Saturday that its troops were assisting UN peacekeepers in the Syrian-controlled part of the Golan Heights in repelling an attack "by armed individuals".</p>

<p>"A short while ago, an attack was carried out by armed individuals at a UN post in the Hader area in Syria," the army said in a statement, referring to a town on the edge of the UN-patrolled buffer zone on the Golan Heights.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The (Israeli army) is currently assisting the UN forces in repelling the attack."&nbsp;</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from the UN force.</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, Syrian rebels took control of the provincial capital of Quneitra around 12 kilometres (eight miles) south of Hader, Britain-based war monitor the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said.</p>

<p>The long-stalemated Syrian civil war burst back into life late last month, with rebels sweeping across the country and capturing multiple major cities.</p>

<p>The military said that army chief Herzi Halevi visited the Syrian border on Saturday and said his country was "not intervening in events in Syria" but was "working to thwart and prevent threats in the area".</p>

<p>The military declined to comment on Saturday evening when asked if the attack was ongoing.</p>

<p>On Friday, the Israeli military said it was "reinforcing aerial and ground forces" in the Israeli-occupied parts of the Golan in response to the situation in Syria. And on Saturday it said it had conducted exercises to ensure troop readiness.</p>

<p>Israel conquered most of the Golan Heights during the Six-Day War of 1967 and later annexed the territory in a move never recognised by the international community as a whole.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A UN peacekeeping force, UNDOF, has patrolled a buffer zone between the Israeli- and Syrian-controlled zones since 1974.</p>

<p>In August 2014, Islamist rebels attacked UNDOF and took more than 40 Fijian peacekeepers hostage, holding them captive for almost two weeks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3753glao_israel_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel conquered most of the Golan Heights during the Six-Day War of 1967.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-releases-new-video-of-israeli-hostage-held-for-more-than-420-days-7198454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Releases Video Of Israeli Hostage, Mother Demands "Comprehensive Deal"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-releases-new-video-of-israeli-hostage-held-for-more-than-420-days-7198454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Dec 2024 09:14:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The armed wing of Hamas, the Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, released a video on Saturday of an Israeli hostage held in the Gaza Strip since the Hamas attack of October 2023.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The armed wing of Hamas, the Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, released a video on Saturday of an Israeli hostage held in the Gaza Strip since the Hamas attack of October 2023.</p>

<p>In the undated, three-and-half-minute video that AFP has not been able to verify, Matan Zangauker says in Hebrew that he has been in captivity for more than 420 days and calls for public pressure on the Israeli government to secure the release of all captives held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Zangauker, who was 24 at the time, was taken from Nir Oz kibbutz along with his partner, Ilana Gritzewsky. She was released during a truce last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His mother, Einav Zangauker, has been one of the most prominent figures in Israel calling for the government to negotiate a hostage release deal that would end the war.</p>

<p>Addressing herself to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, she said: "That Matan is still alive today does not mean he will survive the winter or the continuing military pressure. The only way to bring Matan back is with a deal."</p>

<p>She added: "I demand the following from you, Netanyahu: give full mandate to the negotiating team to bring a comprehensive deal that will bring everyone back. A comprehensive deal that will bring everyone back, even if it means ending the war. No tricks, no excuses."</p>

<p>The Hostages and Missing Families Forum, a campaign group for relatives of those abducted to Gaza, said the video was evidence that hostages remained alive and that "the critical need" to secure their release "becomes more urgent with each passing hour".</p>

<p>"These hostages' lives hang by a thread," the group said.</p>

<p>Critics have accused Netanyahu of stalling truce negotiations and prolonging the war to appease his far-right coalition partners.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There have been large and frequent protests in Israel since the early days of the war calling for the government to negotiate a hostage release deal with Hamas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Saturday night there were again major protests in Tel Aviv, which Einav Zangauker attended, as well as other Israeli cities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Palestinian militants kidnapped 251 people during their surprise attack, of whom 96 remain in Gaza including 34 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Qatar said "momentum is coming back" for the talks, while a source close to the Hamas delegation told AFP that a new round of negotiations will "most likely" begin in the coming week.</p>

<p>With Cairo and Washington, Doha has been mediating negotiations for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal for more than a year without success.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tus05lro_hamas_625x300_08_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Critics have accused Netanyahu of stalling truce negotiations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>