<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:59:11 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-thanks-india-for-2-5-million-financial-aid-to-its-un-agency-7056555]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Palestine Thanks India For $2.5 Million Financial Aid To Its UN Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-thanks-india-for-2-5-million-financial-aid-to-its-un-agency-7056555]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:40:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestine on Tuesday expressed its deep gratitude to India for releasing the second tranche of $2.5 million financial aid to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestine on Tuesday expressed its deep gratitude to India for releasing the second tranche of $2.5 million financial aid to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA), thus fulfilling its pledged annual contribution of $5 million for the year 2024-2025.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Palestinian Embassy said, "We extend our sincere gratitude and appreciation to the Government of India for releasing the second tranche of $2.5 million to UNRWA, fulfilling its annual contribution of $5 million for the year."</p>

<p>The Embassy further lauded India's commitment to humanitarian assistance, stating, "We also acknowledge India's pledge to continue providing humanitarian aid and medicines to UNRWA, assisting the agency in meeting its responsibilities toward the welfare of Palestinian refugees."</p>

<p>Abed Elrazeg Abu Jazer, Charge d'affaires of the Embassy of Palestine, emphasised the significance of the financial support, calling it a "testament to India's unwavering support" for UNRWA's mandate, established in 1949.</p>

<p>"This financial contribution is a critical step in countering Israeli attempts to undermine UNRWA and halt its activities in Palestinian territories," the statement quoted him as saying.</p>

<p>Highlighting the strong historical ties between India and Palestine, Jazer added, "The Palestinian people deeply value India's support and look forward to its continued backing at both political and material levels until their aspirations for freedom, independence, and the establishment of their own state are realised."</p>

<p>India's Representative Office to Palestine on Monday announced the release of the $2.5 million tranche. Over the years, India has provided financial aid amounting to $40 million for UNRWA's core programs and services, including education, healthcare, relief, and social services for Palestinian refugees.</p>

<p>"In addition to financial assistance, India remains committed to providing humanitarian aid and medicines to UNRWA, helping the agency fulfil its responsibilities toward the welfare of Palestinian refugees," the Representative Office noted.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Embassy expressed hope that this financial support would continue to strengthen UNRWA's efforts to serve Palestinian refugees, even as they face challenges in the region.</p>

<p>"The Indian contribution reaffirms its enduring commitment to UNRWA's services and the Palestinian cause. We are grateful for this support, which highlights India's role as a steadfast ally in our struggle for independence and self-determination," the Embassy statement concluded.</p>

<p>India's consistent financial aid and humanitarian assistance reflect its solidarity with the Palestinian people and its dedication to promoting peace and stability in the region.</p>

<p>New Delhi has for long supported a negotiated two-state solution, towards the establishment of a sovereign, independent and viable State of Palestine within secure and recognised borders, living side by side in peace with Israel.</p>

<p>At the same time, India has also strongly and unequivocally condemned the October 7 terror attacks on Israel, last year, calling for the unconditional and immediate release of all hostages, ceasefire, the need for continued humanitarian assistance, and adherence to international humanitarian law.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tvebgnig_gaza_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India fulfilled its pledged annual contribution of $5 million amid the ongoing crisis in Palestine.(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heres-why-elon-musks-spacex-steps-in-to-launch-indias-gsat-n2-satellite-7056445]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Here's Why Musk's SpaceX Steps In To Launch India's GSAT-N2 Satellite]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heres-why-elon-musks-spacex-steps-in-to-launch-indias-gsat-n2-satellite-7056445]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:27:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's SpaceX launched GSAT-20 - ISRO's latest communications satellite from Cape Canaveral in Florida on November 19th. The launch had utilised Space X's Falcon 9 rocket.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's SpaceX launched GSAT-20 - ISRO's latest communications satellite from Cape Canaveral in Florida on November 19th. The launch had utilised Space X's Falcon 9 rocket. This is a unique collaboration as this indicates the first major commercial partnership between SpaceX and ISRO.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The estimated cost for this collaboration is between $60-70 million.</p>

<p>Earlier, India depended on French commercial launch service provider Arianespace for launching heavy weight satellites. Furthermore, SpaceX and ISRO have signed another agreement to send an Indian astronaut to the International Space Station (ISS) for $60 million.</p>

<h2><strong>What is Falcon 9?</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>According to SpaceX, "Falcon 9 is the world's first orbital class reusable rocket. Reusability allows SpaceX to refly the most expensive parts of the rocket, which in turn drives down the cost of space access."</li>
	<li>It is a two stage rocket designed to transport both payloads and people reliably into Earth's orbit.</li>
	<li>It is 70 metres in height, weighs about 549,054 kg or 1,207,920 lb</li>
	<li>It has about 396 total launches, 352 total landings and 327 total reflights according to the SpaceX website.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>What is GSAT-20?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p>GSAT-N2 or GSAT-20 is a 4,700 kg satellite that exceeds the weight capacity of India's indigenous rockets.</p>
	</li>
	<li>The satellite has a mission-life of 14 years, providing essential internet and communication services across India and even in remote regions.</li>
	<li>It is operating in the Ka-band with a capacity of 48Gbps. It will enhance broadband as well as in-flight connectivity throughout the Indian region.</li>
	<li>According to ISRO, the satellite is equipped with 32 user beams of which 8 narrow spot beams cover the Northeast region and 24 wide spot beams for the rest of India.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Why SpaceX?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>The primary reason for ISRO choosing SpaceX to deliver the satellite is the weight of it. The GSAT-20 being 4,700 kgs could not be delivered through India's indigenous rockets. ISRO's heaviest launch vehicle, the LVM-3, is capable of launching only 4000 kg.</li>
	<li>As the French commercial launch service provider Arianespace lacked operational rockets, Russia's was unavailable due to the Ukraine conflict, and China being off limits, SpaceX was the best option.</li>
	<li>This collaboration was not only a new start for NSIL (New Space India Limited), but also shows India's growing engagement with international space agencies.</li>
</ul>

<p>Union Minister Jitendra Singh praised the launch, through a post on X, "Kudos to team ISRO &amp; SpaceX for the successful launch of GSAT-N2. Under the leadership of PM Narendra Modi, collaboration between ISRO &amp; SpaceX aims at enhancing internet services, including in remote areas as well as in-flight connectivity, with a mission lifespan of 14 years."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0drnso1_spacex-falcon-9-launch-x_625x300_19_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's SpaceX launched GSAT-20 - ISRO's latest communications satellite]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraine-fired-us-ballistic-missiles-at-army-facility-says-russia-report-7056305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Fired US Ballistic Missiles At Army Facility, Says Russia: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraine-fired-us-ballistic-missiles-at-army-facility-says-russia-report-7056305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:10:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's military said Tuesday that Ukraine fired US-supplied long-range missiles at a military facility in the Bryansk border region, in what would be the first attack since Washington authorised the use of its weapons.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's military said Tuesday that Ukraine fired US-supplied long-range missiles at a military facility in the Bryansk border region, in what would be the first attack since Washington authorised the use of its weapons.</p>

<p>"At 03:25 am (0025 GMT), the enemy struck a site in the Bryansk region with six ballistic missiles. According to confirmed data, US-made ATACMS tactical missiles were used," the defence ministry as saying in a statement.</p>

<p>Ukraine had for months been demanding that Washington let it use the longer-range ATACMS missiles to hit sites on Russian territory.</p>

<p>Moscow has said the use of Western weapons to attack Russia's internationally recognised territory would make the United States a direct participant in the conflict and pledged an "appropriate and palpable response".</p>

<p>In its statement, Russia's defence ministry said five missiles were shot down by its air defences, while fragments from a sixth fell onto an unspecified "military facility", causing a small fire.</p>

<p>"There were no casualties or damage," it said.</p>

<p>Ukraine's foreign minister hailed on Monday the permission to use the missiles for strikes inside Russia as a potential "game changer" in the nearly three-year old conflict.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["There were no casualties or damage," Russia said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-says-by-2025-world-will-know-the-winner-of-russia-ukraine-war-7055744]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Says By 2025 World Will Know The Winner Of Russia-Ukraine War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-says-by-2025-world-will-know-the-winner-of-russia-ukraine-war-7055744]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:08:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Tuesday that 2025 will be decisive in determining who wins the war unleashed by Russia almost three years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Tuesday that 2025 will be decisive in determining who wins the war unleashed by Russia almost three years ago.</p>

<p>"In the decisive moments -- and they are coming next year -- we must not allow anyone in the world to doubt the resilience of our entire state. And at this stage, it is being decided who will prevail," Zelensky told the Ukrainian parliament.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/6vgoq3ck_volodymyr-zelensky-afp_625x300_07_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelensky was speaking at Ukrainian parliament.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/the-logistics-of-us-president-elect-donald-trumps-deportation-dream-are-not-so-pretty-7055604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: The Logistics Of Trump's Deportation Dream Are Not So Pretty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/the-logistics-of-us-president-elect-donald-trumps-deportation-dream-are-not-so-pretty-7055604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:47:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The hurdles in actually executing Trump's grand plan are staggering. The logistics of ramping up the system are as daunting as the rhetoric is bold.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-04/j8u2trc8_immigration-generic-afp-650_625x300_22_April_20.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Donald Trump hit the ground running as President-elect, dedicating his first week to assembling his team. By the start of his second week, he announced on Truth Social his intention to declare a national emergency on border security. His plan includes suggestions that he might deploy the National Guard to execute a mass deportation of undocumented migrants—a bold move that underscores the priorities of his administration. Yet, specifics remain unclear on how this colossal undertaking will actually be managed.</p>

<p>‘Trumpworld', as many are calling it, promises to be a land purged of its estimated 11 million undocumented immigrants. "America First" policies will be this world's mantra. It will be a world where work begins to Make America Great Again (MAGA) and, of course, a world where a revival of hardline conservative values has long been awaited. The MAGA campaign, as envisioned by Trumpworld and its far-right champions, pledges to drive all undocumented immigrants out. It must concern Indians too, given that around 7,25,000 of the estimated 11 million undocumented immigrants in the US are from India, according to the Pew Research Centre. It makes them the third-largest group after Mexico and El Salvador.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Indians In US: A Tale Of Extremes</strong></h2>

<p>Indian immigrants in the US are often celebrated for powering the success of Silicon Valley, but the quiet contributions of the thousands of undocumented Indians rarely get a mention—largely because they are living in the country illegally. They make up nearly 6% of the country's total undocumented migrants. &nbsp;Together, their population is 2.71 million-strong. The total number of both legal and illegal Indian immigrants is second only to Mexico (4.5 million). Now that Trump is back in the White House, uncertainty looms for many of these Indian immigrants, most of whom are young and settled in their jobs.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Can Bluster Turn Into Policy?</strong></h2>

<p>Tom Homan will be in charge of America's borders following Trump's inauguration in January. A former police officer and ex-director of US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), a federal agency responsible for enforcing immigration laws within the US, Homan is known for his hardline rhetoric. At the Republican National Convention this year, he didn't mince words as he warned undocumented immigrants: “You better start packing now.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Besides Homan's appointment as the Border Czar, Trump has also nominated Stephen Miller as Deputy Chief of Staff for Policy. Both positions reinforce his campaign promise of being extremely tough on immigration and deporting all illegal immigrants. Homan will oversee, among other things, US borders and deportations, while Miller, known for his role in shaping Trump's immigration stance during his first term, will focus on implementing the administration's mass deportation promises. It has been announced that South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem will serve as Secretary of Homeland Security, coordinating with Homan and Miller on border security initiatives.</p>

<p>However, the hurdles in actually executing Trump's grand plan are staggering. The logistics of ramping up the system are as daunting as the rhetoric is bold.</p>

<h2><strong>Tracing Origins</strong></h2>

<p>In order to deport a person with no documents or passport, border agencies have to first establish beyond doubt which country a potential deportee comes from. Let me draw a parallel here. India faces a similar problem with regard to many Nigerian immigrants. Once, an annoyed Javed Ahmed, former Mumbai cop and Maharashtra police chief, told me how it was nearly impossible to deport overstayed Nigerians back to their country. Why? Because once in India, they would destroy their passports and all other national IDs so that the authorities would not be able to establish their Nigerian antecedents. Unless their origins are established, the Nigerian government is within its rights to refuse to accept them.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
So, if the US government wants to send an undocumented Indian back to India, it won't be easy. The US does have repatriation agreements with Mexico and some Central American countries, but these agreements primarily focus on recent border crossers, not long-term undocumented immigrants. For those residing in the US for 10 years or more, removal procedures become complex. Documentation, verifying citizenship and obtaining travel documents can be difficult. Also, removing long-term residents may separate families, and returnees may face challenges in reintegrating into their countries of origin. These difficulties have been acknowledged by the US government itself.</p>

<h2><strong>Manpower Shortage</strong></h2>

<p>Another challenge is the lack of manpower. Immigration enforcement agencies are stretched thin, which partly explains why even during Trump's first term, the average annual deportation rate was 3,50,000—a figure that pales in comparison to Obama years, which saw 4,32,000 deportations in a single year. Ironically, it was Obama who had appointed Tom Homan to oversee these deportations.</p>

<p>Trump's supporters have floated the idea of enlisting the National Guard, one of the oldest elements of the US armed forces, to solve the manpower crunch, but experts like Jean Lantz Reisz from the Gould School of Law warn this would likely invite legal challenges. The Supreme Court has made it clear that the President cannot unilaterally deploy the military for immigration enforcement. Attempts to use the Insurrection Act of 1807, a federal law authorising the President to deploy the army to quell domestic insurrections when state authorities request assistance or national security is threatened, would likely hit the same legal wall.</p>

<h2><strong>Legal Logjam</strong></h2>

<p>The sheer lack of judicial and detention capacity, as highlighted by immigration experts, is also a challenge. With a staggering backlog of 3.7 million pending immigration cases (Syracuse University's data), the system is already buckling under weight. Meanwhile, the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) currently detains 37,000 people in total—far from enough to handle Trump's mass deportation plans. Expanding this capacity won't come cheap and taxpayers would almost certainly be handed the bill.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Budgetary Constraints</strong></h2>

<p>It is claimed that removing all 11 million unauthorised immigrants will cost close to $300 billion. Trump has, however, already said the cost is a non-issue. But cost is not the only consideration. According to researchers, nearly one million of the 11 million undocumented immigrants run their own businesses and pay taxes to the tune of $100 billion. In states such as California and Texas, in sectors like agriculture, infrastructure and hospitality, the engagement of undocumented workers is crucial. Reisz offers a blunt reality check: “You could put 11 million people in removal proceedings, but it would take years to actually deport them from the US.” Without significant legal changes—and congressional action to back them up—Reisz sees mass deportations as little more than a pipe dream.</p>

<h2><strong>The History Of Prejudice</strong></h2>

<p>The US, often called a “nation of immigrants”, was built on several waves of immigration in the early centuries, mostly from Europe. Just to give perspective, while the European settlers were busy driving the indigenous people out of their land and trying to build homes for themselves in the New World in the 17th century, the Mughal and Ottoman empires were at their peak—exuding prosperity, exquisite art and breathtaking architecture. After several centuries of mostly-White European migration, the US developed into a New World, finally evolving into a world power in the 20th century.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The anti-immigration sentiments began growing in the late 19th and early 20th centuries as the composition of the immigrant population changed. Earlier immigrants, primarily from Northern and Western Europe, were openly welcomed, but the influx of Africans, Chinese and others fuelled xenophobia and nativism. Racial prejudices were actually codified into laws by the US. The Immigration Act of 1917, for instance, created a "barred zone," excluding immigrants from most of Asia. In 1924, the Johnson-Reed Act further entrenched discrimination by establishing quotas based on origin, favouring Northern and Western Europeans while excluding Asians entirely. White Europeans were typically seen as more desirable and got citizenship easily. But Black, Asian and Latino immigrants faced outright exclusion, segregation and legal barriers. For instance, the Naturalisation Act of 1790 limited citizenship to “free white persons”—a restriction that wasn't lifted, hold your breath, until the mid-20th century. Anti-immigrant sentiments weren't just about numbers—it reflected deep-rooted anxieties over race, culture, and the fear of being overwhelmed.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>Achievable Goals</b></h2>

<p>Even with the best intentions and a commitment to walking the talk, Trump's new immigration team will not find it easy to surpass Obama's peak of 4,32,000 deportations per year. Even if they manage an ambitious half a million annually—assuming no legal or logistical roadblocks—it would still take 22 years to clear the current backlog of undocumented immigrants. Experts, however, believe Trump is more likely to focus on deporting recent arrivals, whose records are easier to trace.</p>

<p>However, with Trump legally unable to seek re-election in 2028, the big question looms: who will be held accountable if this bold promise falls short?</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-04/j8u2trc8_immigration-generic-afp-650_625x300_22_April_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/fans-mourn-death-of-paul-teal-after-one-tree-hill-star-dies-at-35-7055528]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fans Mourn Death Of Paul Teal After 'One Tree Hill' Star Dies At 35]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/fans-mourn-death-of-paul-teal-after-one-tree-hill-star-dies-at-35-7055528]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:36:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Paul Teal shot to prominence for his portrayal of Josh Avery in the seventh season of the popular CW show, 'One Tree Hill'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fans across the globe are mourning the death of Paul Teal who died at the age of 35 after a battle with cancer. Mr Teal's death was confirmed by his representatives who shared a heartfelt message, commemorating the memory of the <em>One Tree Hill</em> star. "His exceptional talent and kind spirit touched the hearts of everyone who had the privilege of knowing him. The void he leaves behind will be deeply felt," they wrote. Mr Teal's fiancee, Emilia Torello shared an emotional tribute on Instagram, calling herself the 'luckiest person' to have shared her life with him.</p>

<p>"Paul, you were my soulmate, my soon-to-be-husband, my rock, and my future. You filled my lungs with laughter, my stomach with butterflies, and my heart with love. You were taken too soon, in a battle that you fought bravely without fail," wrote Ms Torello.</p>

<p>"While a part of me died with you, I promise to fight to find joy in life as hard as you fought to live every single day. The world is lucky to have even had a moment with Paul Teal, and I am the luckiest person in it because I got to call you mine. I will love you forever," she added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCfO6eluoxO/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCfO6eluoxO/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCfO6eluoxO/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCfO6eluoxO/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Emilia Torello (@emiliatorello)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Mr Teal shot to prominence for his portrayal of Josh Avery in the seventh season of the popular CW show. Bethany Joy Lenz, one of Mr Teal's co-stars from <em>One Tree Hill</em>, posted a picture with him, reminiscing the time they shared together on the show's set. Ms Lenz also recalled their appearance in the musical, <em>The Notebook</em>.</p>

<p>"My heart is heavy. Paul Teal was the kind of guy who lit up a room without trying. His bright smile, infectious laugh and kind heart made you want to be near him," said Ms Lenz.</p>

<p>"Paul, your time here was like a summer romance for all of us who knew you, especially if only for a season. Bursting, exciting, deeply moving, and unforgettable," she added.</p>

<h3><strong>Fans mourn the loss</strong></h3>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Fans took to social media and shared their grief about Mr Teal's passing and shared video clips of some of his best moments from the show.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Best scene Paul teal R.i.P. I heard about his passing <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/onetreehill?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#onetreehill</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/seasonseven?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#seasonseven</a> <a href="https://t.co/1UdJqXEqy2">pic.twitter.com/1UdJqXEqy2</a></p>
— ultimate Socali Loner ????‍♀️?‍♀️ (@stephgreen2321) <a href="https://twitter.com/stephgreen2321/status/1858587176122151099?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are devastated to hear about the loss of the incredibly kind and talented, Paul Teal. He was such a light on &amp; off the show, and he truly will never be forgotten. Our thoughts are with his family &amp; friends, today and everyday. ? <a href="https://t.co/lSGr7kzDFn">pic.twitter.com/lSGr7kzDFn</a></p>
— one tree hill comfort (@othcomfort) <a href="https://twitter.com/othcomfort/status/1858586253832147023?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Apart from One Tree Hill, Mr Teal also appeared on popular television series, including The Walking Dead, Outer Banks, Dynasty, The Staircase, and Good Behavior among others. He also appeared in Deep Water (2022) -- a psychological thriller by Adrian Lyne, starring Ben Affleck and Ana de Armas.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/p2p7guto_paul_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Paul Teal lost the battle against cancer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-putin-to-visit-india-next-year-dates-yet-to-announced-7055457]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian President Putin To Visit India Next Year, Dates Yet To Announced]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-putin-to-visit-india-next-year-dates-yet-to-announced-7055457]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:29:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin may visit India next year, diplomatic sources said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin may visit India next year, diplomatic sources said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The two sides are looking at the possibility of the visit but nothing has been finalised, they said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi invited the Russian President to visit India when the two leaders held talks in Moscow in July.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bq31g8eg_modi-putin_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi invited the Russian President to visit India. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-man-mauled-to-death-by-great-white-shark-off-new-zealands-chatham-islands-7055293]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[24-Year-Old Man Mauled To Death By Great White Shark In New Zealand]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-man-mauled-to-death-by-great-white-shark-off-new-zealands-chatham-islands-7055293]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:03:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Chatham Islands lie about 800 kilometres east of New Zealand's South Island, and such incidents are rare.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 24-year-old commercial diver named Jade Kahukore-Dixon died following a shark attack near New Zealand's remote Chatham Islands. The incident occurred while he was diving off a boat on Tuesday, November 19. Emergency services responded around midday and rushed him to Chatham Islands Health Centre, but he could not be saved, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/technology/science/animals/man-killed-in-shark-attack-near-chatham-islands-in-new-zealand/news-story/89e12257c459dc86fbaf35827441fd6c" rel="nofollow, noindex">news.com.au</a></em> reported. The Chatham Islands lie about 800 kilometres east of New Zealand's South Island, and such incidents are rare but deeply shocking for the community.</p>

<p>A police spokesperson confirmed a man died in hospital after being attacked by a shark on the islands on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Emergency services were called around midday, following reports the man - who had been diving off a boat - had been critically injured. He was rushed to Chatham Island Hospital, but has since died," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The man's grieving father Jacky Dixon told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.stuff.co.nz/nz-news/360492082/diver-attacked-shark-near-chatham-islands"><em>Stuff</em></a> his son was “an amazing boy” who loved fishing and diving.</p>

<p>"I couldn't believe it. I kept picturing him when he was little. I'm not going to have my son. He would do anything to protect his family. He was an amazing boy, a very much loved family member," he said.&nbsp;Mr Dixon&nbsp;said his son often saw great whites but wasn't afraid of them, adding he would hide behind rocks before sneaking back to the boat.</p>

<p>Chatham Islands mayor Monique Croon said she knew the young man. "He's a local boy. He's well-known and well-liked, which will be devastating for our commercial divers … everybody is in shock. It's the biggest risk, the biggest fear," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This incident marks the first fatal shark attack in New Zealand since 2021 when 19-year-old Kaelah Marlow lost her life to a great white shark at Waihi Beach on the North Island.&nbsp;Historical records reveal that at least 29 lives have been lost to shark attacks in New Zealand since 1860.</p>

<p>Contrary to their fearsome reputation, shark attacks are exceedingly rare. The International Shark Attack File (ISAF) reports an average of six deaths annually.&nbsp;Last year, 14 people were killed in shark attacks, up from nine in 2022. Experts stress that shark encounters are typically non-predatory and mistaken identity often drives attacks on humans.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ctj3i7o8_great-white-shark_625x300_19_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Contrary to their fearsome reputation, shark attacks are exceedingly rare.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/what-is-googles-waves-of-interest-tracking-trends-in-us-election-years-7055290]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Google's Waves of Interest, Tracking Trends In US Election Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/what-is-googles-waves-of-interest-tracking-trends-in-us-election-years-7055290]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:03:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Waves of Interest is a collaboration between Google Trends and Truth & Beauty that explores the hidden patterns in Google search data.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inflation was the top trending topic during the US presidential election in 2024, compared to 2020, according to Google's Waves of Interest -- an interactive platform launched by the tech giant that traces search interest in the election years. Compared to 2020, the search for inflation was up 114 per cent, pension funds came in second with a 76 per cent increase while the budget deficit witnessed a 39 per cent surge. Racism, student loans, the Second Amendment, and gun control saw a decrease in search interest compared to 2020.</p>

<p>This 2024 edition is based on an earlier version launched on the occasion of the 2020 US election. During the previous election cycle where Donald Trump lost, electoral fraud was the biggest search term trend with a whopping 361 per cent increase compared to 2016 while 'opinion poll' saw an uptick of 342 per cent.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/google-searches-skyrocket-1-514-after-donald-trumps-historic-comeback-6981190" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Google Searches Skyrocket 1,514% After Donald Trump's Historic Comeback</strong></a></p>

<p><strong>What is Waves of Interest?</strong></p>

<p>Waves of Interest is a collaboration between Google Trends and Truth &amp; Beauty that explores the hidden patterns in Google search data. This site presents Google Trends data on a curated set of political topics, comprising the currently most searched political concepts in the US, topics from Pew Research Center's election surveys, as well as a few manual additions to account for emerging issues.</p>

<p>The platform shows both a list of top rising topics in the election years but also a detailed chart of how their search interest values unfolded over the years. Notably, the chart shows search interest for a particular topic in the years 2004-2024 by month.</p>

<p>"This comparison allows us to understand where we are in the "attention cycle" around certain topics - and also gives us an opportunity to introduce the topic lists we are working with," said Moritz Stefaner of Truth &amp; Beauty, who designed the platform.</p>

<p>On the detail page for a topic, the numbers on the map view show how search interest in individual states differs from the US average. The colour scale for the whole map is based on both the total search volume for the topic in that year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7qn3ms5o_waves-of-interest_625x300_19_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The project shows the interests and concerns of Americans in recent election years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-to-visit-india-soon-dates-being-finalised-says-kremlin-7055238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin To Visit India Soon, Dates Being Finalised, Says Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-to-visit-india-soon-dates-being-finalised-says-kremlin-7055238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:58:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin will visit India soon, the Kremlin said today, adding that Moscow and New Delhi are "working on the dates".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin will visit India soon, the Kremlin said today, adding that Moscow and New Delhi are "working on the dates". The visit, which is likely to be early next year, will be part of a laid down structure between the two countries for reciprocal annual visits by their leaders.</p>

<p>Without giving any specific details on the agenda of the visit, Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov said, "We are looking forward to the visit. The dates will be mutually worked out soon."</p>

<p>The announcement of Vladimir Putin's visit to India came on the 1,000th day of the war in Ukraine and on the same day that Russia updated its nuclear doctrine for a second time, allowing Moscow to target non-nuclear states should the need arise. Despite efforts to broker peace between Russia and Ukraine, the conflict has seen a sharp escalation in the last few days with US President Joe Biden giving the green signal to Kyiv to use long-range missiles to target territory deep within Russia.</p>

<p>President Putin will meet Prime Minister Narendra Modi in New Delhi during his visit. The two leaders had last met during PM Modi's visit to Kazan in Russia for the BRICS Summit in late-October. During the visit, PM Modi had extended an invitation to President Putin to visit India.</p>

<p>In their last meeting Prime Minister Modi had conveyed to President Vladimir Putin that India believes in peaceful solutions to conflicts, referring to the Russia-Ukraine issue. "We have been in touch with all sides in the Russia-Ukraine problem. It has always been our position that all conflict can be solved with dialogue. We believe there should be peaceful solutions to conflicts. India is always ready to help bring peace," PM Modi had said.</p>

<p>India and Russia share a time-tested 'special and privileged strategic partnership', and PM Modi has said New Delhi will help in whatever way it can to help end the war and find a peaceful solution that would be acceptable to both Russia and Ukraine.</p>

<p>PM Modi had even sent National Security Adviser Ajit Doval, reportedly with a peace plan to Moscow where he had a meeting with Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>Since his third successive term as Prime Minister began in May this year, Narendra Modi has shown the importance New Delhi attaches to its relations with Moscow by visiting Russia twice within six months. PM Modi has also visited Ukraine - a historic first by any Indian prime minister - since the formation of the country. In Ukraine, PM Modi met President Zelensky, and both leaders agreed on finding a peaceful solution to the over-two-year war in the country.</p>

<p>PM Modi has been stressing that "This is not an era for war", and that "solutions can not be found on the battlefield. It can only be found through diplomacy and dialogue" - remarks that were appreciated not just by Kyiv and Moscow, but also earned praise by leaders in Europe and the US.</p>

<p>India and Russia share strong bilateral ties and trade between the two nations have continued despite the war in Ukraine.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/jem1lnh8_narendra-modi-vladimir-putin-ani-modi-putin-ani_625x300_30_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin will visit India soon, meet Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Kremlin said today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/security-our-responsibility-american-envoy-talks-about-safety-of-indian-consulate-in-us-7055231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: What American Diplomat Said On Attacks At Indian Consulates In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/security-our-responsibility-american-envoy-talks-about-safety-of-indian-consulate-in-us-7055231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:56:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, a wreath-laying ceremony was organised in memory deceased. The ceremony was attended by senior American diplomats including, Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security, Gentry Smith and Consul General, Kathy Giles-Diaz.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been over 12 years since four police constables and a private security guard were killed, while 20 other people were injured when terrorists attacked an American cultural centre in Kolkata on 22 January 2002. On Tuesday, a wreath-laying ceremony was organised in memory deceased in Kolkata. The ceremony was attended by senior American diplomats including, Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security Gentry O. Smith and Consul General Kathy Giles-Diaz, along with senior West Bengal Police officials.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters at the American Centre in Kolkata, Mr Smith talked about attacks on Indian consulates in the US and said the discussions on safety-related issues will come up when he is in Delhi.</p>

<p>Notably, the Consulate General of India in San Francisco was attacked twice in 2023--on March 19 and July 2--by a group of assailants who committed criminal trespass, damaged public property, and attacked officials of the Consulate.&nbsp;On March 19, 2023, protestors also tried to vandalise the Indian High Commission in London and pulled down the national flag while holding protests outside the High Commission last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I think a lot of those conversations will take place when I am in Delhi. One of my responsibilities in the position that I have is to ensure that all diplomats who serve within the United States receive a proper amount of attention. If there are security issues, we are engaged about them. We are engaged at the local level, and we are engaged at my level as well. I have personnel in multiple locations throughout the US where there are embassies and consulates. And principal to those locations is the safety and security of all the diplomats who serve in those locations," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Smith also stressed the importance of security for consulates, especially in the backdrop of the attacks on Indian consulates in recent times.</p>

<p>"My job is to ensure that our personnel can serve abroad in a safe manner. We cannot do that without the collaboration of those who have the same responsibilities of security in the countries that we serve. From a reciprocal standpoint, we owe that to the diplomats who are serving in the United States as well," he said.</p>

<p>"We are in contact with embassies, consulates and other foreign missions within the US, to ensure that when we take into consideration all of the responsibilities that we have, we never lose sight of the fact that security is one of those responsibilities as well," Mr Smith added.</p>

<p>Remembering the attack on the American Centre in 2002, Consul General Kathy Giles-Diaz said, "It is unfortunate that this attack happened in Kolkata and we have that tragic distinction of being the only place in India that has had an attack on an American diplomatic facility but I have been very grateful and continue to be very grateful for the cooperation with the Police and with our local guard force."&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kn43j1ro_gentry-smith-us-dept-of-states-_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gentry O. Smith has been serving as Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security since 2021]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-passengers-claim-stuck-in-phuket-for-80-hours-7055085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Emergency Landing, Fliers Stuck For 3 Days In Phuket; Air India Responds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-passengers-claim-stuck-in-phuket-for-80-hours-7055085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:38:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over 100 New Delhi-bound passengers of an Air India flight have been stranded in Thailand's Phuket for over 80 hours now after several delays due to technical faults, according to multiple posts put out by passengers on social media]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 100 New Delhi-bound passengers of an Air India flight have been stranded in Thailand's Phuket for over 80 hours now after several delays due to technical faults, according to multiple posts put out by passengers on social media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the passengers, the flight was scheduled to take off for Delhi on the night of November 16. But the airline's representatives informed the passengers of a six-hour delay due to a technical fault. The passengers allege that after being made to wait for hours at the airport, they were asked to board the plane, only to be deboarded an hour later. The flight was cancelled.</p>

<p>Air India, while regretting the inconvenience to passengers, said the November 16 flight was "cancelled due to a technical issue". The airline insisted that the staff on the ground made efforts to minimise passengers' inconvenience, providing all on-ground assistance including hotel accommodations and meals.</p>

<p>"Some of the guests were also accommodated on alternatively available flights. Passengers were also offered options for full refunds on cancellation and complimentary rescheduling. At Air India, the safety and security of our passengers and crew is a top priority," it added.</p>

<p>The passengers included elderly and children. The next the plane was prepped for a flight. The passengers say they were told that it was the same plane, but the fault had been fixed. The plane took off and about two-and-a-half hours after take-off, it landed back at Phuket and the passengers were again told that there was a technical fault. Since then, the passengers have been stuck at Phuket.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3o1gqid_air-india-phuket_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The plane's trajectory, as captured by tracking app FlightRadar, shows its two-hour flight before it returned to Phhuket.</p>

<p>Social media posts allege that passengers are not getting any satisfactory response from airline representatives.</p>

<p>Earlier, the airline source said, "Several passengers have been sent back. About 40 are still in Phuket, they would be sent back this evening."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bg4hsr3g_air-india-a350-_625x300_01_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-atacms-the-us-ballistic-missiles-ukraine-may-use-against-russia-7053272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About US Ballistic Missiles That Ukraine Could Use To Target Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-atacms-the-us-ballistic-missiles-ukraine-may-use-against-russia-7053272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:30:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Joe Biden administration in the US has for the first time authorised Ukraine to use its ballistic missiles to carry out attacks inside Russia, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Joe Biden administration in the US has for the first time authorised Ukraine to use its ballistic missiles to carry out attacks inside Russia, officials said. Known as Army Tactical Missile Systems, or ATACMS, it's expected to be first used in western Russia's Kursk region, officials added.</p>

<p>The approval comes in the middle of the Biden administration preparing for a smooth transition of power to President-elect Donald Trump, who has clearly said that he will attempt to bring a quick end to Russia's invasion of Ukraine. The two countries have been locked in a war for over 1000 days.</p>

<h2><strong>ATACMS Capabilities</strong></h2>

<p>Made by Lockheed Martin, the ATACMS are short-range ballistic missiles. Depending upon the model, it has the capability to strike targets 190 miles away with a warhead containing around 375 pounds of explosives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These ballistic missiles can fly way higher into the atmosphere compared to artillery rockets and even farther. It comes down to the ground at a very high speed due to the gravitational pull, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/17/world/europe/what-are-atacms-missiles-ukraine-russia.html#">The New York Times</a> reported.</p>

<p>They can be easily fired with the help of the HIMARS mobile launchers, which Ukraine has already received from the US, as well as the older M270 launchers sent to the war-torn nation by Britain and Germany.</p>

<p>While ATACMS are often called “long-range missiles,” they cannot travel as far as cruise missiles or intercontinental ballistic missiles.</p>

<p>Developed in the 1980s to target Soviet targets, the ATACMS missile was made as a rare guided weapon when the US heavily relied on “dumb bombs” as well as other unguided munitions.</p>

<p>At present, the country has two ATACMS versions -- a cluster weapon and one that carries a single explosive charge.</p>

<h2><strong>Why now?</strong></h2>

<p>The US supplied ATACMS to Ukraine last year but the country didn't approve their usage across the border into Russia. The White House remained concerned that Russian President Vladimir Putin would respond to it by escalating the war.</p>

<p>“We're trying to avoid World War III,” President Biden earlier said.</p>

<p>Several Pentagon officials have also opposed sending these missiles to Ukraine due to its limited supplies.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/e2turnh_atacms-missile_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weve-taken-back-the-culture-netizens-react-as-viral-trump-dance-takes-us-by-storm-7054899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netizens React As 'Trump Dance' Goes Viral: 'Taken The Culture Back']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weve-taken-back-the-culture-netizens-react-as-viral-trump-dance-takes-us-by-storm-7054899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:10:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The trendy move stems from an awkward mishmash of steps performed by Trump during the election to the tune of YMCA song.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's presidential election victory has brought a cultural reset it seems. US Men's National Team (USMNT) forward Christian Pulisic was seen celebrating his goal against Jamaica on Monday (Nov 18) by doing the 'Trump Dance' - a signature move popularised by the Republican leader during the election campaigning trail. Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) fighter Jon Jones performed a similar move last week after defeating Stipe Miocic by technical knockout, with President-elect Trump present ringside at the Madison Square Garden, alongside his coterie of soon-to-be-inaugurated cabinet leaders.</p>

<p>Netizens have been celebrating the dance move, claiming that it was a significant moment in US history, which had been dominated by identity politics and a rampant cancel culture.</p>

<p>"We have officially taken back the culture. Everyone is doing the Trump dance now," said one user, while another added: "Trump started a movement with YMCA dance as people love just having fun, except liberals! Lol."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">TRUMP STARTED A MOVEMENT WITH YMCA DANCE AS PEOPLE LOVE JUST HAVING FUN, EXCEPT LIBERALS ! LOL <a href="https://t.co/gPJbVCDW7O">pic.twitter.com/gPJbVCDW7O</a></p>
— Fritz &amp; Athena Harrod (@bignels2) <a href="https://twitter.com/bignels2/status/1856993838201802771?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Trump Dance that's sweeping the nation is like a refreshing shower after years wallowing in the mud of the woke mind virus. <a href="https://t.co/aaQ2cdSmaE">pic.twitter.com/aaQ2cdSmaE</a></p>
— Eric Sammons (@EricRSammons) <a href="https://twitter.com/EricRSammons/status/1858667508896854302?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>A third commented: "The Trump dance has gone mega viral as the cultural shift hits full effect. Sports stars in the US and around the world are doing it as a celebration, as is everyone else...even people in China."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We have officially taken back the culture. Everyone is doing the Trump dance now <a href="https://t.co/If4jLFwc1E">pic.twitter.com/If4jLFwc1E</a></p>
— James Jinnette (@james_jinnette1) <a href="https://twitter.com/james_jinnette1/status/1858244758126121154?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Trump Dance is everywhere.<br />
<br />
Culture belongs to us now. <a href="https://t.co/Vr8e4RQlN8">pic.twitter.com/Vr8e4RQlN8</a></p>
— Vince Dao (@VinceDaoTV) <a href="https://twitter.com/VinceDaoTV/status/1858294516479893776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Instead of mocking the awkward dance, athletes appear to be dancing in support of Trump who not only won the popular vote but also helped the Republicans win the House and the Senate.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/do-the-donald-trump-dance-takes-us-sport-by-storm-7054161" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also read | Do The Donald! Trump Dance Takes US Sport By Storm</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>What is the 'Trump Dance'?</strong></h3>

<p>The trendy move stems from an awkward mishmash of steps performed by Trump during the election to the tune of YMCA song, produced by the American disco group, Village People.</p>

<p>The influence of Trump Dance has not been limited to the USA. England's Charley Hull was recently seen performing the move during her final showdown with Nelly Korda at the Annika tournament held at Pelican Golf Club.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/va79169o_donald-trump_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump performing his signature move.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-okays-broader-use-of-nuclear-weapons-as-russia-marks-1-000-days-of-ukraine-war-7054872]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Responds To Biden's Missile Approval By Changing Nuclear Doctrine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-okays-broader-use-of-nuclear-weapons-as-russia-marks-1-000-days-of-ukraine-war-7054872]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:09:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin vowed on Tuesday to defeat Ukraine, saying Western support for Kyiv would have no impact on the conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a clear message to the West and Ukraine, Russian President Vladimir Putin on Tuesday signed a decree broadening the scope of Moscow using nuclear weapons on a non-nuclear state if it is supported by nuclear powers.</p>

<p>This decision comes on the 1,000th day of Russia invading Ukraine, after Joe Biden gave Ukraine permission to use its long-range missiles to strike deeper in Russian territory.</p>

<p>The Biden administration had made a significant policy change, allowing Ukraine to use US-made ATACMS missiles to strike targets inside Russia for the first time.</p>

<p>This decision came just two months before President Joe Biden hands over power to Donald Trump, who has expressed scepticism about US military aid to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The Kremlin vowed on Tuesday to defeat Ukraine, saying Western support for Kyiv would have no impact on the conflict and that western aid "cannot affect the outcome of our operation. It continues, and will be completed."</p>

<p>"The military operation against Kyiv continues," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said.</p>

<p>He also said that aggression by a non-nuclear state with the participation of a nuclear state is considered as a joint attack referring to Ukraine and its Western backers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Peskov added that, Russia "has always viewed nuclear weapons as a means of deterrence," and that they would only be deployed if Russia feels "forced" to.</p>

<p>NATO chief has said that Putin must not 'get his way' in Ukraine. However only a month back, he had said that he does not see an imminent danger of nuclear weapons from Russia despite "reckless and irresponsible" from the country.</p>

<p>The nuclear doctrine will also be extended to Russia's close ally Belarus.</p>

<p>This reflects Putin's swiftness to force the West to back down while Russia continues its slow moving offence in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a Bloomberg <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-19/ukraine-carries-out-first-atacms-strike-in-russia-rbc-ukraine" rel="noindex,nofollow">report</a>, Ukrainian armed forces carried out their first strike in a border region within Russian territory with a ATACMS missile, RBC Ukraine reports, citing an official in the nation's military.</p>

<p>The war between Russia and Ukraine, the deadliest conflict Europe has seen since the World War II, marks its 1,000th day today. Over one million people have reportedly either died or have been grievously injured since the beginning of the war.</p>

<p>Amid the grim reality of the deadliest war of the 21st Century, cities, towns, and villages in Ukraine have been devastated and now lie in ruin. The loss of human life and material wealth keep mounting in a never-ending series of heartbreaking stories emerging from the war-torn country.</p>

<p>Both Russia and Ukraine have diminishing populations and have been struggling from even before the war. The staggering death count due to the war will thereby have far-reaching demographic implications for both nations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/55ha3a7_russian-nuclear-missiles-russia-nukes-istock_625x300_10_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin okays broader use of nuclear weapons as Russia marks 1,000 days of Ukraine war]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-100th-day-of-ukraine-war-putin-allows-russia-to-use-nuclear-weapons-7054622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Allows Broader Use Of Nuclear Weapons On 1,000th Day Of Ukraine War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-100th-day-of-ukraine-war-putin-allows-russia-to-use-nuclear-weapons-7054622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:35:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Tuesday signed a decree broadening the scope of when Moscow can use nuclear weapons in a clear message to the West and Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Tuesday signed a decree broadening the scope of when Moscow can use nuclear weapons in a clear message to the West and Ukraine.</p>

<p>The move comes on the 1,000th day of Russia's offensive on Ukraine and after the United States gave Kyiv permission to use long-range missiles to strike military targets inside Russia.</p>

<p>The new doctrine outlines that Russia will consider using nuclear weapons against a non-nuclear state if they are supported by nuclear powers.</p>

<p>"Aggression by a non-nuclear state with the participation of a nuclear state is considered as a joint attack," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told reporters on Tuesday -- a clear reference to Ukraine and its Western backers.</p>

<p>"It was necessary to bring our principles in line with the current situation," Peskov added, calling the update a "very important" document that should be "studied" abroad.</p>

<p>Russia "has always viewed nuclear weapons as a means of deterrence," he said, adding that they would only be deployed if Russia felt "forced" to respond.</p>

<p>Putin has issued a string of nuclear threats throughout the almost three-year campaign against Ukraine, triggering concern in the West over rhetoric it has slammed as reckless.</p>

<p>The new doctrine also allows Moscow to unleash a nuclear response in the event of a "massive" air attack, even if it only uses conventional weapons.</p>

<p>When the Kremlin first unveiled the proposed changes in September, Peskov called it a "warning" against anybody who was thinking about participating "in an attack on our country by various means, not necessarily nuclear".</p>

<p>Moscow's nuclear umbrella will also be extended to its close ally Belarus under the new doctrine.</p>

<p>Speaking on the 1,000th day of the conflict, Peskov said the "collective West" had unleashed a "war" against Russia, pledging that Moscow would see what it calls its "special military operation" through to the end.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pqsvmrc_vladimir-putin-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The move comes on the 1,000th day of Russia's offensive on Ukraine]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-sees-total-collapse-of-law-and-order-as-100-aid-trucks-violently-looted-un-7054547]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Plunges Into Lawlessness As 100 Aid Trucks "Violently Looted": UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-sees-total-collapse-of-law-and-order-as-100-aid-trucks-violently-looted-un-7054547]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:23:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The drivers were forced to unload the trucks at gunpoint, aid workers were injured, and vehicles were extensively damaged.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A devastating incident occurred in southern Gaza on Saturday, where nearly 100 aid trucks were "violently looted", with 97 out of 109 trucks carrying food supplies for UNRWA and the World Food Programme being "lost" in the looting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This has been described by UNRWA as "one of the worst" incidents of its kind.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The drivers were forced to unload the trucks at gunpoint, aid workers were injured, and vehicles were extensively damaged.</p>

<p>The perpetrators of the looting remain unidentified, but UNRWA blames the "collapse of law and order" and the "approach of the Israeli authorities" for creating a perilous environment.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A joint 109-truck <a href="https://twitter.com/UN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@UN</a> convoy carrying food supplies to people in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Gaza?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Gaza</a> was violently looted on 16 November. The vast majority of the trucks, 97 in total, were lost and drivers were forced at gunpoint to unload aid.<br />
<br />
Due to critical shortages of flour, all eight UN-supported… <a href="https://t.co/59RHJKWLAU">pic.twitter.com/59RHJKWLAU</a></p>
— UNRWA (@UNRWA) <a href="https://twitter.com/UNRWA/status/1858521152483705001?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Well, we have been warning for a long time about the total breakdown of civil order; (until) four or five months ago, we still had local capacity, people who were escorting the convoys. This has completely gone," Lazzarini told a press conference in Geneva on Monday.</p>

<p>This incident comes amid warnings from the UN that severe food and aid shortages in Gaza will worsen without immediate intervention. Civilians fleeing northern Gaza report chronic food scarcity and hunger-related deaths, with aid agencies warning of an impending famine.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/18/world/middleeast/gaza-aid-convoy-looted-unrwa-israel.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">NYT</a>, Louise Wateridge, an UNRWA spokeswoman currently in Gaza, said that, "People at the moment are absolutely desperate for anything. We're back at a stage where we're seeing people literally fighting over a bag of flour."</p>

<p>Israel's parliament recently voted to ban UNRWA, restricting its operations in territories Israel occupies, including the West Bank and East Jerusalem. Israel claims UNRWA has ties to Hamas and promotes hate against Israel, allegations UNRWA denies.</p>

<p>UNRWA is not allowed to use their own trucks and drivers and have to resort to Israel authorities to provide the vehicles and the aid workers are not even allowed to have armed guards. Wateridge said, "It looks like something out of a sci-fi movie. They try and armour the vehicles as best as possible and protect themselves. And they drive very, very fast and just try and try and not stop and just keep going. That's the only protection they have."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Israeli airstrikes in Gaza continue to take a heavy toll on civilians. On Monday, airstrikes killed at least 50 people, including 17 members of a single family. The local health ministry reported that the victims included children and a weeks-old newborn.</p>

<p>The director of the Kamal Adwan hospital, Dr. Hussam Abu Safiya, described the scene as "very violent targeting, with shells from tanks." Patients are filled with fear and horror, pleading for the world to stop the killing machine and bombing.</p>

<p>The situation in Gaza remains dire, with the risk of famine persisting. The World Food Programme warns that one million people are at risk of starvation.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hdbtrf8g_gaza-aid-trucks-looted-reuters_625x300_19_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A truck carries humanitarian aid destined for the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing conflict]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-health-concerns-a-look-at-what-sunita-williams-eats-on-space-station-7054543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Health Concerns, A Look At What Sunita Williams Eats On Space Station]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-health-concerns-a-look-at-what-sunita-williams-eats-on-space-station-7054543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:23:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sunita Williams and fellow astronaut, Butch Wilmore, initially scheduled for an 8-day mission, have been stranded on the ISS for five months now]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-American astronaut Sunita Williams, who has been stranded on the International Space Station (ISS) for over five months, appears to have lost weight, sparking concerns about her health. In a recent photo, Ms Williams looked gaunt, with sunken cheeks and a thinner frame. NASA insists the weight loss is not due to any deficiencies in her diet; it's a result of the microgravity environment aboard the ISS.</p>

<p>Ms Williams and her fellow astronaut, Butch Wilmore, have been surviving on a limited yet sufficient variety of food provided on the space station. According to a specialist familiar with the Starliner mission, their meals include freeze-dried foods, such as breakfast cereals with powdered milk, pizza, tuna, shrimp cocktails, roast chicken and dehydrated stews. One notable shortcoming of their diet is the lack of fresh produce, replenished by the ISS only once every three months.</p>

<p>"There's fresh fruit at first, but as the three months continues that goes away - and their fruits and vegetables are packaged or freeze-dried," the specialist was quoted as saying by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/18/us-news/heres-what-the-astronauts-stranded-on-the-iss-are-eating-each-day/">New York Post</a>.</p>

<p>The astronauts' daily food consumption is carefully monitored by doctors, with each astronaut being allotted 3.8 pounds (around 1.7 kg) of food per day, along with extra supplies in case of mission extensions. Despite the absence of fresh produce, the ISS's recycling system ensures no food goes to waste, even converting the astronauts' sweat and urine into fresh water for cooking and hydration.</p>

<p>Still, health concerns about the astronauts' well-being remain, particularly as the strain of living in space begins to take a visible toll. Ms Williams, 59, has dismissed the concerns, attributing her weight loss to fluid shifting in her body due to the zero-gravity environment. She said in a video interview, "There's some rumours around out there that I'm losing weight and stuff. No, I'm actually right at the same amount."</p>

<p>Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore, originally scheduled for an eight-day mission, have been stranded on the ISS for five months due to technical issues with their Boeing Starliner spacecraft and are now expected to return to Earth in February 2024.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dlpu640o_sunita-williams-butch-wilmore_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The astronauts' daily food consumption is carefully monitored by doctors (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/distressed-uk-vet-dies-by-suicide-after-rich-clients-euthanise-their-pets-to-save-money-7054349]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Vet Dies By Suicide After Rich Clients Euthanise Pets To Save Money]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/distressed-uk-vet-dies-by-suicide-after-rich-clients-euthanise-their-pets-to-save-money-7054349]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:55:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dr Ellis had tricked a veterinary nurse into giving him the deadly medication by claiming that he needed it to put down a friend's large dog.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A veterinarian in the UK has died by suicide by consuming drugs used to euthanise pets after becoming distressed at rich customers asking him to put down their animals, according to a report in The Independent. The vet, identified as Dr John Ellis, 35, was a resident at the Anderson Moores Veterinary Specialists at the time of his death. He had become resentful of clients with "brand-new" cars, parked outside his clinic, refusing to pay to help the poor animals.</p>

<p>Dr Ellis reportedly confided to her mother, Tine Ellis that he had been having sleeping troubles due to the workplace issue. During an inquest into her son's death, Ms Ellis, a Conservative councilor in Fareham, called her son's death 'destroying'.</p>

<p>"Owners are leaving it too late to come in, they weren't seeking help early enough for things that could have been quite simple," said Ms Ellis.</p>

<p>Ms Ellis also revealed what her son had told her before taking his life: "When I've got somebody saying they won't pay to help their animal and they're sitting there with a brand new car outside, and other people who were really struggling [financially] would do anything to save their animals, but there was nothing they could do because it was already too late."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-veteran-kills-herself-her-brother-died-by-suicide-when-she-was-14-4908303" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | US Army Veteran, Influencer Dies By Suicide Days After Daughter's Birthday</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Dr Ellis tricked nurse</strong></h3>

<p>According to the findings of the hearing, Dr Ellis had tricked a veterinary nurse into giving him the deadly medication by claiming that he needed it to put down a friend's large dog. However, he used the drug to take his own life.</p>

<p>Winchester Coroner's Court, in Hampshire, said Dr Ellis had been experiencing considerable stress in both his professional and private life at the time of the death. Meanwhile, Simon Burge, the assistant coroner for Hampshire said Dr Ellis's death was "a huge waste of a talented life".</p>

<p>"It's a matter of great regret to the family and all his friends that he should have rashly, unnecessarily made the decision that he did," said Mr Burge.</p>

<p>The family also released a statement, stating they were devastated by the loss of their loved one, adding that people "will remember him not only for his professional expertise but also for his warmth, generosity and genuine love for animals".</p>

<p>"We continue to grapple with the heartbreak and shock that come with the death of someone so young and full of potential. We want to take this opportunity to encourage anyone who may be struggling with mental health challenges to seek support and not suffer in silence," the family added.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/phq53abg_john_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr John Ellis, 35, died by suicide after growing distressed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-offers-100-million-to-undo-indonesia-iphone-16-ban-7054273]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple Offers $100 Million To Undo Indonesia iPhone 16 Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-offers-100-million-to-undo-indonesia-iphone-16-ban-7054273]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:47:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple Inc. has increased its offer to invest in Indonesia by almost tenfold, according to people familiar with the matter, in the US tech giant's latest bid to persuade the government to lift its sales ban on the iPhone 16.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple Inc. has increased its offer to invest in Indonesia by almost tenfold, according to people familiar with the matter, in the US tech giant's latest bid to persuade the government to lift its sales ban on the iPhone 16.</p>

<p>The proposal would see Cupertino-based Apple invest almost $100 million in Southeast Asia's largest economy over two years, the people said, asking not to be identified because they're not authorized to speak publicly. Apple's previous investment plan of close to $10 million would have involved the company investing in a factory making accessories and components in the city of Bandung, located southeast of Jakarta, Bloomberg News reported earlier.</p>

<p>After Apple submitted its increased offer, Indonesia's Ministry of Industry, which last month blocked a permit allowing the sale of the iPhone 16, is now demanding that the technology behemoth alter its investment plans to focus more on research and development for its smartphones in the country, the people said. The Ministry of Industry hasn't made a final decision on Apple's newest proposal, they added.</p>

<p>Following Apple's initial proposal, the ministry called for senior company executives to meet Minister Agus Gumiwang Kartasasmita. But after flying into Jakarta, Apple's senior executives were told that the minister wasn't available and so they had to meet with the ministry's director-general instead.</p>

<p>Apple and the Ministry of Industry didn't respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Apple's new investment proposal came after the Ministry of Industry last month blocked sales of the iPhone 16 on the grounds the US company's local unit hasn't met a 40% domestic content requirement for smartphones and tablets.</p>

<p>According to the Indonesian government, Apple has only invested 1.5 trillion rupiah ($95 million) in the nation via developer academies, falling short of a commitment of 1.7 trillion rupiah. The Southeast Asian nation has also banned the sale of Alphabet Inc.'s Google Pixel phones because of a similar lack of investment.</p>

<p>Indonesia's hardball tactics appear to be working, with the iPhone 16 ban becoming an example of the pressure new President Prabowo Subianto's government is putting on international firms to increase local manufacturing as it seeks to boost domestic industries.</p>

<p>Indonesia also resorted to such tactics under the administration of former President Joko Widodo, who blocked ByteDance Ltd.'s TikTok last year to shield its retail sector from cheap Chinese-made goods. This prompted the hugely popular video app to ultimately invest $1.5 billion in a joint venture with Tokopedia, the e-commerce arm of Indonesia's GoTo Group.</p>

<p>By offering to invest in the country, Apple is seeking to get unfettered access to Indonesia's 278 million consumers, more than half of which are under the age of 44 and tech savvy.</p>

<p>But such strong-arm tactics by Indonesia risk frightening off other firms from scaling up their presence or establishing a footprint in the first place, particularly ones that are looking to decouple from China. It may also jeopardize Prabowo's aim of attracting overseas investments to grow the economy and fund policy spending.</p>

<p>It's unclear as to which companies Apple's proposed investment might go. Apple typically backs assembly or components partners such as Foxconn in various countries, which in turn help produce or supply vital parts for its iPhones and iPads.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/19eei8do_iphone-16-pro_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indonesias Ministry of Industry last month blocked a permit allowing the sale of the iPhone 16.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>