<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 05:47:18 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-alleges-iranian-hackers-sent-stolen-trump-info-to-joe-biden-campaign-6598045]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Alleges Iranian Hackers Sent Stolen Trump Info To Biden Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-alleges-iranian-hackers-sent-stolen-trump-info-to-joe-biden-campaign-6598045]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 05:41:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US authorities on Wednesday said Iranian cyberattackers had offered "stolen, non-public" material from Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump's campaign to staff for his then White House rival, Joe Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US authorities on Wednesday said Iranian cyberattackers had offered "stolen, non-public" material from Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump's campaign to staff for his then White House rival, Joe Biden.</p>

<p>US intelligence and law enforcement agencies said the hackers "sent unsolicited emails to individuals then associated with President Biden's campaign that contained an excerpt taken from stolen, non-public material from former president Trump's campaign."</p>

<p>Biden was at the time the Democratic presidential nominee, before dramatically stepping aside in July and endorsing his vice president, Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>The joint statement from the US Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency said none of Biden's campaign staff replied to the emails.</p>

<p>In August, the same agencies first attributed the hack to Iran, accusing Tehran of seeking to influence the 2024 election. Iran denies the allegations.</p>

<p>"Foreign actors are increasing their election influence activities" as Election Day in November approaches, the US statement said, singling out Russia, Iran and China as "trying by some measure to exacerbate divisions in US society for their own benefit."</p>

<p>The US agencies said the Iranian cyberattackers had also attempted to share the information stolen from the Trump campaign with US media organizations. It did not name the outlets.</p>

<p>In August, Iran denied the allegations, with its mission to the United Nations challenging Washington to release proof.</p>

<p>"Such allegations are unsubstantiated and devoid of any standing," the mission said at the time.</p>

<p>"As we have previously announced, the Islamic Republic of Iran harbors neither the intention nor the motive to interfere with the US presidential election."</p>

<p>The United States goes to the polls on November 5, with both the Trump and Harris campaigns saying they have been targeted by cyberattacks in recent weeks.</p>

<p>US-based tech companies have also said they detected such attacks.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign on Wednesday said the plot attributed to Tehran was "proof the Iranians are actively interfering in the election to help Kamala Harris and Joe Biden."</p>

<p>Trump campaign press secretary Karoline Leavitt said this was "because they know President Trump will restore his tough sanctions and stand against their reign of terror."</p>

<p>In 2016, a hack of Democratic National Committee emails -- blamed on Russians -- exposed internal party communications, including about candidate Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>Trump, who would go on to win that election, was criticized for encouraging the hack.</p>

<p>Harris's campaign said on August 13 that it too had been targeted by foreign hackers, but did not give an indication of which country was believed to be behind the attempt.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cj8fhp7g_trump_625x300_16_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump, who would go on to win that election, was criticized for encouraging the hack.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvey-weinstein-pleads-not-guilty-to-new-sex-crime-charge-6598013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harvey Weinstein Pleads Not Guilty To New Sex Crime Charge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvey-weinstein-pleads-not-guilty-to-new-sex-crime-charge-6598013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 05:31:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disgraced Hollywood movie producer Harvey Weinstein pleaded not guilty on Wednesday to a new sex crime charge in New York.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disgraced Hollywood movie producer Harvey Weinstein pleaded not guilty on Wednesday to a new sex crime charge in New York.</p>

<p>Weinstein, 72, who had emergency heart surgery just over a week ago, appeared in a Manhattan courtroom in a wheelchair to enter his plea to a single count of committing a criminal sexual act.</p>

<p>The once-powerful movie mogul was unshaven and appeared pale and visibly frail during his brief court appearance before Judge Curtis Farber. He was wearing a dark suit, a white shirt and a blue tie.</p>

<p>Manhattan District Attorney Alvin Bragg said the new indictment of Weinstein is for the alleged sexual assault of a woman in a lower Manhattan hotel sometime between April 29, 2006 and May 6, 2006.</p>

<p>"Thanks to this survivor who bravely came forward, Harvey Weinstein now stands indicted for an additional alleged violent sexual assault," Bragg said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This investigation is ongoing," he added.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters after the arraignment, Arthur Aidala, Weinstein's lawyer, said the alleged sexual assault behind the new charge was "almost two decades ago" and "at this moment I don't know much more than that."</p>

<p>Weinstein is serving a 16-year prison sentence after being convicted on rape charges in California.</p>

<p>He was also convicted in New York in 2020 of the rape and sexual assault of an actress and of forcibly performing oral sex on a production assistant.</p>

<p>He was sentenced to 23 years in prison in that case.</p>

<p>The New York Court of Appeals, however, overturned that conviction in April and Weinstein is awaiting a retrial on those charges.</p>

<p>The new trial was scheduled to begin on November 12 but prosecutors said Wednesday the date seems "unrealistic."</p>

<p>Farber scheduled a next court hearing for Weinstein for October 2.</p>

<p>The one-time Hollywood heavyweight has suffered from a raft of health issues while in prison and has spent time in a secure hospital unit.</p>

<p>Weinstein was rushed to Bellevue Hospital last week from New York's Rikers Island prison for emergency heart surgery.</p>

<p>Allegations against Weinstein helped launch the #MeToo movement in 2017, a watershed moment for women fighting sexual misconduct.</p>

<p>More than 80 women accused him of harassment, sexual assault or rape, including prominent actors Angelina Jolie, Gwyneth Paltrow and Ashley Judd.</p>

<p>Weinstein claimed any sexual relations in question were consensual.</p>

<p>Weinstein and his brother Bob co-founded Miramax Films.</p>

<p>Their hits included 1994's "Pulp Fiction" and 1998's "Shakespeare in Love," for which Weinstein shared a best picture Oscar.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/eag2dt7o_harvey-weinstein-afp_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 80 women accused Harvey Weinstein of harassment, sexual assault or rape.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-will-be-high-on-agenda-at-quad-summit-white-house-6597961]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Will Be "High On Agenda" At Quad Summit: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-will-be-high-on-agenda-at-quad-summit-white-house-6597961]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 05:19:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China will certainly be "high on the agenda" at the Quad Summit set to be hosted by US President Joe Biden in Delaware's Wilmington on September 21, US National Security Council (NSC) Coordinator for Strategic Communications John Kirby said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China will certainly be "high on the agenda" at the Quad Summit set to be hosted by US President Joe Biden in Delaware's Wilmington on September 21, US National Security Council (NSC) Coordinator for Strategic Communications John Kirby on Wednesday (local time) said.</p>

<p>While addressing a press briefing, Kirby stressed that it would be irresponsible if the Quad leaders do not hold talks about the challenges that exist in the region caused by China.</p>

<p>When asked to what extent China will be a focus of the Quad Summit, Kirby stated, "I think it'll certainly be high on the agenda. I mean, there's not an opportunity when you get together with these particular leaders, the Indo-Pacific, Quad, where you in fact it would be irresponsible if they didn't talk about the challenges that still exist in the region caused by aggressive PRC military action for instance, unfair trade practices, tensions over the Taiwan Strait. I have no doubt that that all those issues will come up."</p>

<p>Biden is set to host the fourth in-person Quad Leaders summit in Delaware on September 21 and is looking forward to welcoming Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida. It is the first time Biden will host foreign leaders in his hometown.</p>

<p>When asked whether Quad nations view China as a threat to the Indo-Pacific region, John Kirby said, "I think you'd have to talk to the leaders about their particular view of the PRC. But, I think we all have a common understanding about the challenges that the PRC is posing, but each of them is a sovereign country; they get to decide for themselves what their relationship is going to be with the PRC and how that looks; each of them has a different relationship with the PRC, including us."</p>

<p>John Kirby said that Biden will meet Quad leaders individually and the four together in a larger plenary session where they will discuss expanding cooperation on various critically important issues.</p>

<p>Speaking about the upcoming Quad Summit, he said, "The President will meet individually with each of them, and then we'll also gather together in a larger plenary session where they will discuss expanding cooperation across a range of critically important issues. We believe that you'll see coming out of this summit that the Quad is more strategically aligned and more relevant than ever before."</p>

<p>"I think you can expect a robust agenda aimed at delivering concrete benefits to the people of the region as they all identify priorities such as health, security, natural disaster response, maritime security, quality infrastructure, critical and emerging technologies, climate and clean energy, and cybersecurity. You'll also see some announcements that demonstrate our intention to make sure that this special partnership the Quad endures and in fact thrives over the long term. We'll have more details, of course to share on the specific deliverables as we get a little closer to the weekend," he added.</p>

<p>When asked if Biden intends to press PM Modi on human rights during their bilateral meeting, Kirby responded, "There's not a conversation that he has with foreign leaders where he doesn't talk about the importance of respecting human and civil rights and that includes with Prime Minister Modi. He did when the Prime Minister was here in the United States and and I'm sure that, as appropriate, he'll do going forward. I'm not going to get ahead of the conversation but he never shies away from talking about our concerns over human and civil rights anywhere in the world."</p>

<p>Quad is a diplomatic partnership between four countries--Australia, India, Japan, and the United States. It is pertinent to note that in recent years, Quad Foreign Ministers have met eight times, and Quad governments continue to meet and coordinate at all levels.</p>

<p>PM Modi will be in the United States from September 21 to 23, during which he will take part in the Quad Summit and address the 'Summit of the Future' at the United Nations General Assembly in New York.PM Modi will take part in the fourth Quad Leaders' Summit in Wilmington, Delaware.</p>

<p>Following the request of the US side to host the Quad Summit this year, India has agreed to host the next Quad Summit in 2025.</p>

<p>At the Quad Summit, the leaders will review the progress achieved by the Quad over the last one year and set the agenda for the year ahead to assist the countries of the Indo-Pacific region in meeting their development goals and aspirations, a Ministry of External Affairs release said.</p>

<p>PM Modi will address 'Summit of the Future' at the United Nations General Assembly in New York on September 23. The theme of the Summit is 'Multilateral Solutions for a Better Tomorrow'.</p>

<p>On the sidelines of the summit, PM Modi will hold bilateral meetings with several world leaders and discuss issues of mutual interest. The Prime Minister will address a gathering of the Indian community on September 22 in New York.</p>

<p>He would also be interacting with CEOs of leading US-based companies to foster greater collaborations between the two countries, according to the MEA release. He is also expected to interact with thought leaders and other stakeholders active in the India-US bilateral landscape.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/mk7eukq8_quad-summit-pm-modi-quad-summit-ani_625x300_19_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The annual Quad summit will be held in Delaware on September 21.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-house-subpoenas-antony-blinken-over-afghanistan-on-september-24-6597929]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US House Subpoenas Blinken Over Afghanistan On September 24]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-house-subpoenas-antony-blinken-over-afghanistan-on-september-24-6597929]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 05:09:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Committee subpoenaed Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Wednesday to appear before it on Sept. 24 over the U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan in 2021.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Committee subpoenaed Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Wednesday to appear before it on Sept. 24 over the U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan in 2021.</p>

<p>"If Secretary Blinken fails to appear, the chairman will proceed instead with a full committee markup of a report recommending the U.S. House of Representatives find Secretary Blinken in contempt of Congress for violating a duly issued subpoena," according to a statement from the committee.</p>

<p>The committee had previously wanted Blinken to appear on Sept. 19. The State Department said earlier this month that Blinken was not available to testify on the dates proposed by the committee, but has proposed "reasonable alternatives."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f01agar_blinken_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The committee had previously wanted Blinken to appear on Sept. 19.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/x-update-allows-app-to-bypass-brazil-ban-internet-providers-6597305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[X Update Allows App To Bypass Brazil Ban: Internet Providers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/x-update-allows-app-to-bypass-brazil-ban-internet-providers-6597305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 01:31:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X social network carried out an automatic update overnight on phone applications that allowed it to bypass a ban in Brazil, an association of internet providers said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X social network carried out an automatic update overnight on phone applications that allowed it to bypass a ban in Brazil, an association of internet providers said Wednesday.</p>

<p>Some Brazilian users were surprised to have access again to the platform, formerly Twitter, from their phones after a Supreme Court judge last month ordered its shutdown in a legal standoff with Musk.</p>

<p>The Brazilian Association of Internet and Telecommunications Providers (ABRINT) explained that the return of X was due to an update of the app to Cloudflare software that uses constantly changing IP addresses.</p>

<p>The previous system used specific IPs, which act like a home address for servers or computers and could more easily be blocked.</p>

<p>The changes "make blocking the app much more complicated," said ABRINT.</p>

<p>Many of the dynamic IPs "are shared with other legitimate services, such as banks and large internet platforms, making it impossible to block an IP without affecting other services," the group said.</p>

<p>"Internet providers are in a delicate position," and awaiting technical analysis and instructions from Brazil's telecommunications agency, said ABRINT.</p>

<p>Brazil's shutdown of X infuriated Musk and has fueled a fierce debate on freedom of expression and the limits of social networks, both inside and outside the country.</p>

<p>The social media platform has more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<p>Judge Alexandre de Moraes last month ordered X to be banned after Musk refused to remove dozens of right-wing accounts and then failed to name a new legal representative in the country as ordered.</p>

<p>Moraes has repeatedly clashed with the South African-born billionaire after making it his mission to crack down on disinformation.</p>

<p>Last week he ordered the transfer of some $3 million from Musk's companies to pay fines incurred by X.</p>

<p>Moraes also froze the assets of X and Starlink, which has been operating in Brazil since 2022 -- especially in remote communities in the Amazon -- to ensure payment of fines imposed on X for its failure to follow court orders.</p>

<p>Musk reacted angrily to the suspension, calling Moraes a "dictator."</p>

<p>Moraes also ordered that those using "technological subterfuges" such as virtual private networks (VPNs) to access the blocked site could be fined up to $9,000.</p>

<p>"Judge Alexandre de Moraes: I didn't use a VPN to get in here, I just opened the app for my daily abstinence ritual and saw that it worked," wrote one user on X Wednesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9r47i6pc_elon-musk-ians_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brazil's shutdown of X infuriated Elon Musk and has fueled a fierce debate on freedom of expression.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-seeks-100-million-from-owner-of-ship-that-destroyed-baltimore-bridge-6597248]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Seeks $100 Million From Owner Of Ship That Destroyed Baltimore Bridge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-seeks-100-million-from-owner-of-ship-that-destroyed-baltimore-bridge-6597248]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 01:16:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Justice Department filed a lawsuit on Wednesday seeking more than $100 million from the Singapore owner and operator of a cargo ship that destroyed a Baltimore bridge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Justice Department filed a lawsuit on Wednesday seeking more than $100 million from the Singapore owner and operator of a cargo ship that destroyed a Baltimore bridge.</p>

<p>The 1,000-foot (300-meter) M/V Dali collided with the Francis Scott Key Bridge on March 26, killing six road workers and blocking the busy shipping channel.</p>

<p>The civil suit against Grace Ocean Private and Synergy Marine Private was filed in the US District Court for the District of Maryland.</p>

<p>"The Justice Department is committed to ensuring accountability for those responsible for the destruction of the Francis Scott Key Bridge," Attorney General Merrick Garland said in a statement.</p>

<p>"With this civil claim, the Justice Department is working to ensure that the costs of clearing the channel and reopening the Port of Baltimore are borne by the companies that caused the crash, not by the American taxpayer."</p>

<p>The Justice Department said the suit is aimed at recovering more than $100 million in costs incurred in responding to the disaster and for removing tons of bridge debris.</p>

<p>The Dali lost power while leaving the port of Baltimore for Sri Lanka and struck the bridge.</p>

<p>Principal Deputy Associate Attorney General Benjamin Mizer said the owner and operator of the Dali were "well aware of vibration issues on the vessel that could cause a power outage.</p>

<p>"But instead of taking necessary precautions, they did the opposite.</p>

<p>"Out of negligence, mismanagement, and, at times, a desire to cut costs, they configured the ship's electrical and mechanical systems in a way that prevented those systems from being able to quickly restore propulsion and steering after a power outage," Mizer said.</p>

<p>"As a result, when the Dali lost power, a cascading set of failures led to disaster."</p>

<p>The Justice Department suit comes after Grace Ocean and Synergy Marine filed a legal action of their own earlier this year seeking to limit their liability to $44 million.</p>

<p>The Justice Department lawsuit does not seek damages for the eventual costs of rebuilding the bridge. That is expected to be the subject of a separate claim from the state of Maryland.</p>

<p>The families of the six road workers who lost their lives are also pursuing legal claims of their own.</p>

<p>The Fort McHenry channel leading to the port of Baltimore, a key hub for the auto industry, reopened to commercial navigation on June 10.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/be9fvbg8_baltimore-bridge-collapse-afp_625x300_15_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Dali lost power while leaving the port of Baltimore for Sri Lanka and struck the bridge. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fears-of-all-out-war-as-new-lebanon-device-blasts-kill-dozens-6597244]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fears Of All-Out War As New Lebanon Device Blasts Kill Dozens]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fears-of-all-out-war-as-new-lebanon-device-blasts-kill-dozens-6597244]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 01:11:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A second wave of device explosions killed 14 people and wounded more than 450 others on Wednesday in Hezbollah strongholds in Lebanon, officials said, stoking fears of an all-out war with Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A second wave of device explosions killed 14 people and wounded more than 450 others on Wednesday in Hezbollah strongholds in Lebanon, officials said, stoking fears of an all-out war with Israel.</p>

<p>A source close to Hezbollah said walkie-talkies used by its members blew up in its Beirut stronghold, with state media reporting similar blasts in south and east Lebanon.</p>

<p>AFPTV footage showed people running for cover when an explosion went off during a funeral for Hezbollah militants in south Beirut in the afternoon.</p>

<p>Fourteen people were killed and more than 450 wounded in the latest attacks, the health ministry said, also describing the devices targeted as walkie-talkies.</p>

<p>They came a day after the simultaneous explosion of hundreds of paging devices used by Hezbollah killed 12 people, including two children, and wounded up to 2,800 others across Lebanon, in an unprecedented attack blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>There was no comment from Israel, which only hours before Tuesday's attacks had announced it was broadening the aims of its war with Hamas in Gaza to include its fight against the Palestinian group's ally Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"The centre of gravity is moving northward," Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said during a visit to an air base on Wednesday. "We are at the start of a new phase in the war."</p>

<p>Israeli officials have remained tight-lipped about the explosions which led the television news bulletins and dominated newspaper headlines.</p>

<p>Amos Harel of the left-leaning Haaretz newspaper said the pager and walkie-talkie blasts had put "Israel and Hezbollah on the brink of all-out war".</p>

<p>The Iran-backed Hezbollah has traded near-daily cross-border fire with Israeli forces since Palestinian militants attacked Israel on October 7, sparking the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Lebanese Foreign Minister Abdallah Bou Habib warned the "blatant assault on Lebanon's sovereignty and security" was a dangerous development that could "signal a wider war".</p>

<p>Hezbollah said Israel was "fully responsible for this criminal aggression" and vowed revenge.</p>

<p>The influx of so many casualties all at once overwhelmed hospitals in Hezbollah strongholds.</p>

<p>At a Beirut hospital, doctor Joelle Khadra said "the injuries were mainly to the eyes and hands, with finger amputations, shrapnel in the eyes -- some people lost their sight."</p>

<p>A doctor at another hospital in the Lebanese capital said he had worked through the night and that the injuries were "out of this world -- never seen anything like it".</p>

<p><strong>- Heavy blow -</strong></p>

<p>Analysts said operatives had likely planted explosives on the paging devices before they were delivered to Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"This was more than lithium batteries being forced into override," said Charles Lister of the Middle East Institute.</p>

<p>"A small plastic explosive was almost certainly concealed alongside the battery, for remote detonation via a call or page," the analyst said, adding Israel's spy agency "Mossad infiltrated the supply chain".</p>

<p>Among the dead was the 10-year-old daughter of a Hezbollah member, killed in east Lebanon's Bekaa Valley when her father's pager exploded, the family and a source close to the group said.</p>

<p>Tehran's ambassador in Beirut, Mojataba Amani, who was wounded, said on social media platform X that it was "a source of pride for me that my blood was mixed with that of the wounded Lebanese" in what he called a "horrific terrorist crime".</p>

<p>The attack dealt a heavy blow to Hezbollah, which already had concerns about the security of its communications after losing several key commanders to targeted air strikes in recent months.</p>

<p>The preliminary findings of a Lebanese investigation into the blasts found the pagers had been booby-trapped, a security official said.</p>

<p>"Data indicates the devices were pre-programmed to detonate and contained explosive materials planted next to the battery," the official said, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>A source close to Hezbollah, asking not to be identified, said the pagers were "recently imported" and appeared to have been "sabotaged at source".</p>

<p>After The New York Times reported the pagers had been ordered from Taiwanese manufacturer Gold Apollo, the company said they had been produced by its Hungarian partner BAC Consulting KFT.</p>

<p>A government spokesman in Budapest said the company was "a trading intermediary, with no manufacturing or operational site in Hungary".</p>

<p>As fears again surged of a regional conflagration nearly a year into the Gaza war, Lufthansa and Air France announced the suspension of flights to Tel Aviv, Tehran and Beirut until Thursday.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Extremely volatile' -</strong></p>

<p>Since October, the unabating exchanges of fire between Israeli troops and Hezbollah have killed hundreds of mostly fighters in Lebanon, and dozens including soldiers on the Israeli side.</p>

<p>They have also forced tens of thousands of people on both sides of the border to flee their homes.</p>

<p>United Nations rights chief Volker Turk said Tuesday's attack had come at an "extremely volatile time", calling the blasts "shocking" and their impact on civilians "unacceptable".</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres urged governments "not to weaponise civilian objects".</p>

<p>Senior diplomats from the United States, Britain, Germany, France and Italy will meet on Thursday in Paris to discuss the spiralling tensions in the Middle East, sources said, ahead of a UN Security Council meeting planned for Friday.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack that sparked the war resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, on the Israeli side, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures which includes hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Out of 251 hostages seized by militants, 97 are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,272 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to data provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has acknowledged these figures as reliable.</p>

<p>In Gaza on Wednesday, the civil defence agency said an Israeli air strike on a school-turned-shelter killed five people, while the Israeli military said it targeted Hamas militants.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/d3krg42g_lebanon-walkie-talkie-blast_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fourteen people were killed and more than 450 wounded in the latest attacks in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-new-president-names-first-sunni-governor-in-45-years-report-6597209]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's New President Names First Sunni Governor In 45 Years: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-new-president-names-first-sunni-governor-in-45-years-report-6597209]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 01:05:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's new president, Masoud Pezeshkian, on Wednesday nominated a member of the Sunni Muslim minority to be governor of Kurdistan province, official media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's new president, Masoud Pezeshkian, on Wednesday nominated a member of the Sunni Muslim minority to be governor of Kurdistan province, official media reported.</p>

<p>Arash Zerehtan was appointed head of the western state, IRNA news agency said, citing government spokesman Fatemeh Mohajerani.</p>

<p>He is the first Sunni to be made a regional governor in the predominantly Shiite country since the earliest days of the 1979 Islamic Revolution.</p>

<p>Arash Zerehtan, 48, served as a member of parliament for the city of Paveh between 2020 and this year.</p>

<p>Sunnis account for about 10 percent of Iran's population, where the vast majority are Shiites and Shiite Islam is the official state religion.</p>

<p>They have very rarely held key positions of power since the revolution.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian, 69, took office in July after an early election following the death of ultraconservative president Ebrahim Raisi in a helicopter crash.</p>

<p>During his election campaign, Pezeshkian criticised the lack of representation for ethnic and religious minorities, in particular Sunni Kurds, in important positions.</p>

<p>In August, he made another member of the Sunni minority, Abdolkarim Hosseinzadeh, one of his vice presidents.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9p54r2_iran-flag-_625x300_14_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Arash Zerehtan served as a member of parliament for the city of Paveh between 2020 and this year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/workers-at-elon-musks-tesla-spacex-donate-to-kamala-harris-while-he-backs-donald-trump-6597172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Workers At Musk's Tesla, SpaceX Donate To Harris While He Backs Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/workers-at-elon-musks-tesla-spacex-donate-to-kamala-harris-while-he-backs-donald-trump-6597172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:53:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has endorsed Republican former President Donald Trump in the race for the White House, but employees at his collection of companies are largely donating to Trump's Democratic rival Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has endorsed Republican former President Donald Trump in the race for the White House, but employees at his collection of companies are largely donating to Trump's Democratic rival Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Workers at Tesla have contributed $42,824 to Harris' presidential campaign versus $24,840 to Trump's campaign, according to OpenSecrets, a nonpartisan nonprofit that tracks U.S. campaign contributions and lobbying data.</p>

<p>Employees at Musk's rocket company SpaceX have donated $34,526 to Harris versus $7,652 to Trump. Employees at the social media platform X, formerly known as Twitter, have donated $13,213 to Harris versus less than $500 to Trump.</p>

<p>While the figures are relatively small for campaign fundraising, they indicate political leanings at odds with Musk's own. The world's richest man, Musk has boosted Trump on X and dismissed left-leaning ideas as a "woke-mind virus."</p>

<p>Musk did not immediately respond to a request for comment. He backed President Joe Biden in 2020 but has tacked rightward since then. Trump has said that if he wins the Nov. 5 election, he will appoint Musk to lead a government efficiency commission.</p>

<p>The OpenSecrets data includes donations from company employees and owners and those individuals' immediate family members. Campaign finance laws prohibit companies themselves from donating to federal campaigns.</p>

<p>Many of Musk's employees are based in California, a Democratic stronghold, said Ross Gerber, CEO of Gerber Kawasaki Wealth and Investment Management, which is a Tesla shareholder. Gerber is also an investor in X.</p>

<p>In July, Musk said he would move X and SpaceX headquarters to Texas from California because of a California gender-identity law he called the "last straw." Gerber said such a move would mean "losing out on a lot of potential talent" in California.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d89c4me8_elon-musk-donald-trump-_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many of Elon Musk's employees are based in California, a Democratic stronghold. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-in-pennsylvania-michigan-post-debate-poll-6597070]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Leads In Pennsylvania, Michigan: Post-Debate Poll]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-in-pennsylvania-michigan-post-debate-poll-6597070]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:29:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new poll released Wednesday shows Kamala Harris with significant leads over Donald Trump in swing-states Pennsylvania and Michigan, two "blue wall" battlegrounds seen as key to winning the White House in  November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new poll released Wednesday shows Kamala Harris with significant leads over Donald Trump in swing-states Pennsylvania and Michigan, two "blue wall" battlegrounds seen as key to winning the White House in&nbsp; November.</p>

<p>The surveys, conducted after the September 10 televised debate between the two candidates, suggest a post-showdown boost for Vice President Harris, who is widely perceived as having outperformed her Republican opponent on stage.</p>

<p>In the latest poll of likely voters by Quinnipiac University, Harris is leading ex-president Trump 51 percent to 45 percent in Pennsylvania, and tops him 50-45 percent in Michigan, two states in the post-industrial Rust Belt in the American Midwest and Northeast.</p>

<p>A third Rust Belt state that makes up a trio seen as vital for a Harris victory, Wisconsin, has the race essentially tied, with Harris one percentage point ahead, according to Quinnipiac.</p>

<p>Overall polling shows the tightest of races in the seven battleground states that will likely determine the winner in the US Electoral College system.</p>

<p>Trump leads narrowly in the so-called Sun Belt states of Arizona, Georgia, and North Carolina, according to an amalgam of polls on survey tracker RealClearPolitics.com. It shows Harris barely ahead in the fourth Sun Belt state of Nevada.</p>

<p>The Pennsylvania poll of 1,331 likely voters is notable as Harris's six-point margin is outside Quinnipiac's 2.7 percent margin of error -- and twice the same poll's margin of three percentage points in August.</p>

<p>Harris only became the Democratic Party's presidential candidate in July, after President Joe Biden dramatically ended his own reelection bid following a disastrous debate performance against Trump.</p>

<p>Her entrance provided an energetic jolt to the party and she has fared better against Trump than Biden did in the polls. Recent weeks have been seen as critical for Harris as voters have limited time to get to know the vice president and her policies before Election Day on November 5.</p>

<p>"Three crucial swing states wave a red flag at the Trump campaign," Quinnipiac University Polling analyst Tim Malloy said in a statement, noting that the Republican Party's typical "attack strategies against Democrats on immigration and the economy may be losing momentum."</p>

<p>The latest ABC News/Ipsos national poll, post-debate, shows Harris with a four-point overall lead, while a post-debate Atlas Intel poll has Trump ahead by three percentage points nationally.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is leading ex-president Trump 51 percent to 45 percent in Pennsylvania.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-stops-approving-war-weapons-exports-to-israel-report-6597039]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany Stops Approving War Weapons Exports To Israel: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-stops-approving-war-weapons-exports-to-israel-report-6597039]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:19:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Germany has put a hold on new exports of weapons of war to Israel while it deals with legal challenges, according to a Reuters analysis of data and a source close to the Economy Ministry.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Germany has put a hold on new exports of weapons of war to Israel while it deals with legal challenges, according to a Reuters analysis of data and a source close to the Economy Ministry.</p>

<p>Last year, Germany approved arms exports to Israel worth 326.5 million euros ($363.5 million), including military equipment and war weapons, a 10-fold increase from 2022, according to data from the Economy Ministry, which approves export licences.</p>

<p>However approvals have dropped this year, with only 14.5 million euros' worth granted from January to Aug. 21, according to data provided by the Economy Ministry in response to a parliamentary question.</p>

<p>Of this, the "weapons of war" category accounted for only 32,449 euros.</p>

<p>A source close to the ministry cited a senior government official as saying it had stopped work on approving export licences for arms to Israel pending a resolution of legal cases arguing that such exports from Germany breached humanitarian law.</p>

<p>The ministry did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>In its defence of two cases, one before the International Court of Justice and one in Berlin brought by the European Center for Constitutional and Human Rights (ECCHR), the government has said no weapons of war have been exported under any licence issued since the Oct. 7 Hamas attacks on Israel, apart from spares for long-term contracts, the source added.</p>

<p>Israel's assault on Gaza has killed more than 41,000 Palestinians since Oct. 7, according to the local Hamas-controlled health ministry. It has also displaced most of the population of 2.3 million, caused a hunger crisis and led to genocide allegations at the World Court, which Israel denies.</p>

<p>No case challenging German arms exports to Israel has yet succeeded, including a case brought by Nicaragua at the ICJ.</p>

<p><strong>DISAGREEMENT ON ARMS EXPORTS IN GERMAN GOVERNMENT</strong></p>

<p>But the issue has created friction within the government as the Chancellery maintains its support for Israel while the Greens-led Economy and Foreign ministries, sensitive to criticism from party members, have increasingly criticised the Netanyahu administration.</p>

<p>Legal challenges across Europe have also led other allies of Israel to pause or suspend arms exports.</p>

<p>Britain this month suspended 30 out of 350 licences for arms exports to Israel due to concerns that Israel could be violating international humanitarian law.</p>

<p>In February, a Dutch court ordered the Netherlands to halt all exports of F-35 fighter jet parts to Israel over concerns about their use in attacks on civilian targets in Gaza.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden's administration this year paused - but then resumed - shipments of some bombs to Israel after U.S. concerns about their use in densely populated Gaza.</p>

<p>Approvals and shipments of other types of weapons, in more precise systems, continued as U.S. officials maintained that Israel needed the capacity to defend itself.</p>

<p>Alexander Schwarz, a lawyer at ECCHR, which has filed five lawsuits against Berlin, suggested that the significant decline in approvals for 2024 indicated a genuine, though possibly temporary, reluctance to supply weapons to Israel.</p>

<p>"However, I would not interpret this as a conscious change in policy," Schwarz added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2225v5kg_israel-army_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's assault on Gaza has killed more than 41,000 Palestinians since Oct. 7, says Hamas. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-first-cut-since-covid-pandemic-us-federal-reserve-reduces-interest-rates-by-50-basis-points-6596876]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In 1st Since 2020, US Federal Reserve Cuts Interest Rate By 50 Basis Point]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-first-cut-since-covid-pandemic-us-federal-reserve-reduces-interest-rates-by-50-basis-points-6596876]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 23:42:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Federal Reserve cut its key lending rate by half a percentage-point Wednesday in its first reduction since the onset of the Covid-19 pandemic, sharply lowering borrowing costs shortly before November's presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Federal Reserve cut its key lending rate by half a percentage-point Wednesday in its first reduction since the onset of the Covid-19 pandemic, sharply lowering borrowing costs shortly before November's presidential election.</p>

<p>The Fed's decision will affect the rates at which commercial banks lend to consumers and businesses, bringing down the cost of borrowing on everything from mortgages to credit cards.</p>

<p>The news will likely be well-received by Democratic candidate Kamala Harris, who has looked to highlight President Joe Biden's economic record in her race against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Policymakers voted 11-to-1 in favor of lowering the US central bank's benchmark rate to between 4.75 percent and 5.00 percent, the Fed announced in a statement.</p>

<p>The key holdout was Fed governor Michelle Bowman, who supported a more conventional quarter-point cut.</p>

<p><strong>Fed 'gained greater confidence'</strong></p>

<p>The Fed said its rate-setting committee "has gained greater confidence that inflation is moving sustainably toward 2 percent, and judges that the risks to achieving its employment and inflation goals are roughly in balance."</p>

<p>The bank has a dual mandate from Congress to act independently to tackle both inflation and employment.</p>

<p>Analysts were expecting the Fed to cut rates on Wednesday, as inflation eases toward the bank's long-term target of two percent, and the labor market continues to cool in the surprisingly resilient post-Covid economy.</p>

<p>But they were highly uncertain about the size of the move, with some anticipating a small cut of a quarter of a percentage point, and others predicting the more significant half-point cut, which carries a greater risk of reigniting inflation.</p>

<p>In updated economic forecasts published alongside the Fed's rate decision, policymakers' median forecasts pointed to an unemployment rate of 4.4 percent, on average, in the fourth quarter of this year, up from 4.0 percent in the last update in June.</p>

<p>They also penciled in an annual headline inflation rate of 2.3 percent, slightly lower than in June.</p>

<p>The decision to cut more sharply to begin with caught some analysts by surprise.</p>

<p>"In our base case the Fed cuts 25bp (basis points) but signals 100bp of cuts this year with the median 2024 'dot'", economists at Citi wrote in an investor note published ahead of the rate decision.</p>

<p><strong>Election stakes</strong></p>

<p>The Fed's mandate gives it the independence to set monetary policy solely on the basis of economic data.</p>

<p>But its decision will likely have political ramifications, given the importance of inflation and the cost of living to US consumers.</p>

<p>Americans have consistently said both are a top concern ahead of the election.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly criticized Fed Chair Powell, who he first appointed to run the Fed, and has suggested that its decisions are political -- accusations the US central bank has strongly refuted.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-09/ud2ua6_us-federal-reserve-_625x300_11_September_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The decision to cut more sharply to begin with caught some analysts by surprise. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-abstains-from-un-resolution-demanding-israels-withdrawal-from-palestine-6596781]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Abstains From UN Resolution On Israel's Withdrawal From Palestine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-abstains-from-un-resolution-demanding-israels-withdrawal-from-palestine-6596781]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 23:25:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Wednesday abstained in the UN General Assembly on a resolution that demanded that Israel bring an end, "without delay", to its unlawful presence in the Occupied Palestinian Territory within 12 months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Wednesday abstained in the UN General Assembly on a resolution that demanded that Israel bring an end, "without delay", to its unlawful presence in the Occupied Palestinian Territory within 12 months.</p>

<p>The 193-member General Assembly adopted the resolution, with 124 nations voting in favour, 14 against and 43 abstentions, including that by India.</p>

<p>Those abstaining included Australia, Canada, Germany, Italy, Nepal, Ukraine and the United Kingdom.</p>

<p>Israel and the US were among the nations who voted against the resolution titled 'Advisory opinion of the International Court of Justice on the legal consequences arising from Israel's policies and practices in the Occupied Palestinian Territory, including East Jerusalem, and from the illegality of Israel's continued presence in the Occupied Palestinian Territory'.</p>

<p>The resolution adopted Wednesday demanded that "Israel brings to an end without delay its unlawful presence in the Occupied Palestinian Territory, which constitutes a wrongful act of a continuing character entailing its international responsibility, and do so no later than 12 months from the adoption of the present resolution." The Palestinian-drafted resolution also strongly deplored the continued and total disregard and breaches by the Government of Israel of its obligations under the Charter of the United Nations, international law and the relevant United Nations resolutions, and stressed that such breaches seriously threaten regional and international peace and security.</p>

<p>It recognised that Israel must be held to account for any violations of international law in the Occupied Palestinian Territory, including any violations of international humanitarian law and international human rights law, and that it "must bear the legal consequences of all its internationally wrongful acts, including by making reparation for the injury, including any damage, caused by such acts."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/pv5nruog_un-general-assembly-afp_625x300_23_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Other countried that abstained included Australia, Canada, Germany, UK, Ukraine (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-warns-war-centre-of-gravity-moving-north-amid-hezbollah-escalation-6596774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Warns War "Centre Of Gravity Moving North" Amid Hezbollah Escalation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-warns-war-centre-of-gravity-moving-north-amid-hezbollah-escalation-6596774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 23:24:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In Israel's first reaction since thousands of pager and walkie-talkie blasts rocked Lebanon over two days, the defence minister in the Netanyahu's government has announced that the "centre of gravity" of the Middle East conflict is "moving north".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Israel's first reaction since thousands of pager and walkie-talkie blasts rocked Lebanon over two days, the defence minister in Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government has announced that the "centre of gravity" of the Middle East conflict is "moving north".</p>

<p>Benjamin Netanyahu also gave a brief video statement in which he promised that tens of thousands of residents from Israel's northern border with Lebanon will "return to their homes".</p>

<p>Lebanon's militant outfit Hezbollah has been backing Hamas in the Gaza war shortly after it began in October 2023 and regular exchange of fire between Hezbollah militia and Israel's armed forces have been going on for the last many months, however tensions have surges since Tuesday's pager explosions across Lebanon which killed twelve and injured nearly 3,000 people, mostly linked with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has blamed Israel for what it calls their "biggest-ever" security breach. Mr Netanyahu, however, didn't speak directly about the explosions that have rocked Lebanon.</p>

<p>Less than twenty-four hours since thousands of pagers blew up across Lebanon, hand-held walkie-talkies have today exploded killing another nine people and wounding over 300.</p>

<p>During his statement Mr Netanyahu said, "I have said it before, we will return to the citizens of the north to their homes in security and that's exactly what we are going to do."</p>

<p>To this, Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant added that "forces are being sent to the northern border." Israel has said that the war has now "moved into a new phase", amid concerns that a new front to the war may soon see escalation.</p>

<p>"The 'centre of gravity' is moving north, meaning that we are allocating forces, resources and energy for the northern arena," the defence minister said in remarks released by his office.</p>

<p>While the Gaza strip is on Israel's south-western front, Lebanon shares a border with Israel's north.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-against-further-middle-east-escalation-after-lebanon-blasts-6596480" target="_blank">Antony Blinken has warned</a> against any escallation of the war in the Middle East.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/itlt6efc_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu has vowed that settlers in the north will "return to their homes"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-murdered-husband-buried-body-under-fire-pit-and-impersonated-him-on-social-media-6596710]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Killed Husband, Buried Body, And Impersonated Him On Social Media]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-murdered-husband-buried-body-under-fire-pit-and-impersonated-him-on-social-media-6596710]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 23:11:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida woman, Laurie Leigh Shaver, has been convicted of second-degree murder for killing her husband in 2015 and burying his body under a fire pit in their backyard.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman from Florida, United States, Laurie Leigh Shaver, was convicted on Friday for the 2015 murder of her husband, Michael Douglas Shaver, who was 36 years old. The jury pronounced Shaver guilty of second-degree murder with a firearm after four hours of deliberation, but she was acquitted for accessory charges.</p>

<p>Trial began on September 9, and there was an indication that Michael's body was buried underneath the concrete fire pit at their house in Clermont, Lake County. He had been missing since November 2015, and his friend had alerted the authorities in February 2018 citing his disappearance. Michael was a monorail technician at Disney World.</p>

<p>When Lake County deputies first responded to the Shaver home, Laurie was claiming Michael had abandoned his family, but Laurie became evasive when police asked her to grant them permission to search the property with dogs. A later search, equipped with cadaver dogs and ground-penetrating radar, led to the discovery of Michael's body, wrapped in a tarp and buried under the fire pit.</p>

<p>Police confirmed that Laurie Shaver was posing as her husband on social media so that she wouldn't be noticed as the murderer.</p>

<p>"We understand the profound impact this case has had on Michael Shaver's family and friends. We hope this verdict brings some measure of closure for them. Crimes like this leave a deep and lasting impact on our society," said fifth-judicial-circuit state attorney Bill Gladson.</p>

<p>"I would like to commend Sheriff Peyton Grinnell and Lieutenant Tamara Dale of the Lake County Sheriff's Office in Florida, along with Assistant State Attorneys Nick Camuccio and Rich Buxman for their diligent work throughout the investigation of this case. Their efforts have been instrumental in obtaining justice for Michael," said the state attorney Bill Gladson.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lp5f7s3_laurie-shaver-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Laurie Shaver had been impersonating her husband on social media to cover up the murder.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pagers-were-booby-trapped-shows-initial-probe-report-6596577]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Pagers Were Booby-Trapped, Shows Initial Probe: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pagers-were-booby-trapped-shows-initial-probe-report-6596577]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 22:51:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A preliminary investigation has found hundreds of pagers that exploded across Lebanon, killing at least 12 people and wounding up to 2,800, had been booby-trapped, a security official said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A preliminary investigation has found hundreds of pagers that exploded across Lebanon, killing at least 12 people and wounding up to 2,800, had been booby-trapped, a security official said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Lebanon opened a probe into the explosions on Tuesday, a judicial official said, adding security services were working to determine the cause of the blasts which have been blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, a new wave of exploding hand-held devices, this time walkie-talkies, killed nine people and wounded more than 300 wounded across Lebanon, the health ministry said.</p>

<p>"Data indicates the devices were pre-programmed to detonate and contained explosive materials planted next to the battery," the official said about Tuesday's blasts, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>Some of the devices that exploded were being inspected, the security official said, but "most of them were destroyed and burned".</p>

<p>The official said it was unlikely the lithium batteries inside the devices had heated up and exploded.</p>

<p>"Exploding lithium batteries cause a fire-like incident... that may cause minor burns, but the blast from these devices resulted from highly explosive materials," he told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/d3krg42g_lebanon-walkie-talkie-blast_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some of the devices that exploded were being inspected, a security official said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sells-everything-for-rs-27-crore-cruise-thrown-off-for-whatsapp-comments-6596536]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Sells Everything For Rs 27 Crore Cruise, Thrown Off For WhatsApp Post]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sells-everything-for-rs-27-crore-cruise-thrown-off-for-whatsapp-comments-6596536]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 22:48:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida woman, Jenny Phenix, was banned from a $350,000 world cruise after her WhatsApp comments expressing frustrations and concerns about the cruise schedule and cabin arrangements were leaked, resulting in the cancellation of her contract.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida woman who spent her life savings of $350,000 (Rs 29,28,5410) on a dream trip around the world - selling everything she owns for a chance to circle the globe aboard the maiden voyage of the three-year Villa Vie Odyssey - has been banned from the cruise after her private WhatsApp comments were leaked, according to <em>The New York Post</em>. Jenny Phenix, a 68-year-old divorced mother of two, liquidated her possessions and businesses, living out of a suitcase as she prepared for the odyssey.</p>

<p>As changes were made to the cruise itineraries, Phenix wrote on her WhatsApp group to her fellow travelers: "I am just so disappointed we won't be docking in Miami where I will be picking up remaining belongings for our journey. I also worry that maybe we'll still have some refurbishment going on when we leave Belfast so that my cabin can be occupied by crew members, so I'll have a temporary cabin. Cruise ship operator Villa Vie Residences received her messages, leading to the cancellation of her contract due to "behavior impacting community morale."</p>

<p>"I cannot even begin to explain the emotional devastation and the physical toll this has taken on me," she told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/18/us-news/florida-mom-jenny-phenix-booted-from-her-dream-3-year-villa-vie-odyssey-cruise-over-whatsapp-messages-after-selling-her-possessions/"><em>The New York Post.</em></a> "It is still very hard for me to discuss, as I had the same dream everyone else on that ship does, and they took that from me seemingly without a thought."</p>

<p>"I will have to stay with my daughter until I figure out a whole new plan for my life."</p>

<p>The program starts at $300000 and requires guests to pay at least half the deposit, according to the company's website.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k6dus6j8_cruise_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman said she had been left emotionally devastated.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/down-but-not-out-these-critical-services-still-rely-on-pagers-6596481]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Down, But Not Out? These Critical Services Still Rely On Pagers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/down-but-not-out-these-critical-services-still-rely-on-pagers-6596481]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 22:38:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As mobile phones became the world's main communications tool, pagers, also known as beepers because of the sound they make to notify users about incoming messages, were largely rendered obsolete, with demand plunging from their 1990s heyday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As mobile phones became the world's main communications tool, pagers, also known as beepers because of the sound they make to notify users about incoming messages, were largely rendered obsolete, with demand plunging from their 1990s heyday.</p>

<p>But the tiny electronic devices remain a vital means of communication in some areas - such as healthcare and emergency services - thanks to their durability and long battery life.</p>

<p>"It's the cheapest and most efficient way to communicate to a large number of people about messages that don't need responses," said a senior surgeon at a major UK hospital, adding that pagers are commonly used by doctors and nurses across the country's National Health Service (NHS).</p>

<p>"It's used to tell people where to go, when, and what for."</p>

<p>Pagers grabbed headlines on Tuesday when thousands used by members of Lebanese group Hezbollah were detonated simultaneously across Lebanon, killing at least nine people and wounding nearly 3,000 others.</p>

<p>According to a senior Lebanese security source and another source, explosives inside the devices were planted by Israel's Mossad spy agency.</p>

<p>The UK's NHS was using around 130,000 pagers in 2019, more than one in 10 of the world's pagers, according to the government. More up-to-date figures were not available.</p>

<p>Doctors working in hospital emergency departments carry them when they are on call.</p>

<p>Many pagers can also send out a siren and then broadcast a voice message to groups so that whole medical teams are alerted simultaneously to an emergency, a senior doctor in the NHS said. That is not possible with a mobile phone.</p>

<p>Britain's Royal National Lifeboat Institution (RNLI) uses pagers to alert its crews, a source familiar with the lifeboat service told Reuters. The RNLI declined to comment.</p>

<p><strong>BURNER PHONES</strong></p>

<p>Pagers can be harder to track than smartphones because they lack more modern navigation technologies like the Global Positioning System, or GPS.</p>

<p>That has made them a popular choice among criminals, especially drug dealers in the United States, in the past.</p>

<p>But gangs are using mobile phones more these days, former FBI agent Ken Gray told Reuters.</p>

<p>"I don't know if anyone uses them (pagers)," he said.</p>

<p>"They all went to cell phones, burner phones" which can be easily disposed of and replaced with another phone with a different number, making them difficult to trace.</p>

<p>Gray, who served 24 years at the Federal Bureau of Investigation and now teaches criminal justice and homeland security at the University of New Haven, said that criminals changed with the times and newer technology.</p>

<p>The global pagers market, once a major source of revenue for companies like Motorola, amounted to $1.6 billion in 2023, according to an April report by Cognitive Market Research.</p>

<p>That amounts to a tiny fraction of the global smartphone market, which was estimated at around half a trillion U.S. dollars as of end-2023.</p>

<p>But demand for pagers is rising as a larger patient population creates more need for efficient communication in the healthcare sector, the report said, forecasting compound annual growth of 5.9% from 2023 to 2030.</p>

<p>It said North America and Europe are the two biggest pager markets, generating $528 million and $496 million in revenue respectively.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iuermu3_pagers-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pagers can be harder to track than smartphones]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-against-further-middle-east-escalation-after-lebanon-blasts-6596480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Warns Against Further Middle East Escalation After Lebanon Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-against-further-middle-east-escalation-after-lebanon-blasts-6596480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 22:37:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Wednesday warned against the risk of escalation in the Middle East after the detonation of thousands of Hezbollah pagers threatened to derail his latest regional diplomacy push.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Wednesday warned against the risk of escalation in the Middle East after the detonation of thousands of Hezbollah pagers threatened to derail his latest regional diplomacy push.</p>

<p>News of the blasts broke as the top US diplomat traveled to Cairo to meet senior Egyptian officials hoping to advance efforts to secure a ceasefire in Gaza and improve ties with Egypt.</p>

<p>Militant group Hezbollah promised to retaliate against Israel, accusing it of detonating pagers across Lebanon on Tuesday killing at least 12 people, including two children, and wounding nearly 3,000.</p>

<p>Israel has declined to respond to questions about the explosions.</p>

<p>Asked about the blasts, Blinken said the United States was still gathering facts but it was in no one's interest for conflict to spread.</p>

<p>"It's imperative that all parties refrain from any actions that could escalate the conflict," Blinken said at a news conference alongside his Egyptian counterpart.</p>

<p>He did not say who the US believes was behind the blasts.</p>

<p>Blinken said he was focused on securing a ceasefire deal that would bring calm, including to Israel's northern border with Lebanon, and that 15 out of 18 paragraphs of a deal had been agreed by all sides.</p>

<p>Making progress involved long waits for messages to be passed between the parties that left time for incidents to disrupt the talks, Blinken said.</p>

<p>"We've seen that in the intervening time, you might have an event, an incident - something that makes the process more difficult, that threatens to slow it, stop it, derail it - and anything of that nature, by definition, is probably not good in terms of achieving the result that we want, which is the ceasefire," Blinken said.</p>

<p>He cited Hamas' execution of six Israeli hostages last month. He did not name Israel, which is believed to have targeted members of groups aligned against it in Lebanon, Syria and Iran that have set back the talks.</p>

<p>President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi told Blinken in their meeting on Wednesday morning that Egypt opposed attempts to "escalate the conflict and expand its scope regionally" and called for all parties to act responsibly, the Egyptian presidency said in a statement.</p>

<p>Blinken will head from Cairo to Paris on Thursday for a meeting with the foreign ministers of France, Italy and Britain to discuss the Middle East and Ukraine and other issues, a State Department official said. Blinken will also meet French President Emmanuel Macron, the official said.</p>

<p>Blinken will not visit Israel on this trip, the first time he has skipped a stop in Washington's closest regional ally since Hamas sparked the war in Gaza nearly a year ago.</p>

<p>State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller said on Tuesday that was because Washington aimed to discuss bilateral issues with Egypt on this trip and the Gaza ceasefire proposal that U.S. and mediators have been working on was still not ready to present to Israel.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b3est4bo_antony-blinken-in-egypt-blinken-with-egypt-foreign-minister-badr-abdelatty_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Antony Blinken today warned against any escalation of war in the Middle East (Video Credit: Reuters)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-rescued-after-2-litres-of-vape-fluid-extracted-from-her-lungs-6596325]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Rescued After 2 Litres Of Vape Fluid Extracted From Her Lungs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-rescued-after-2-litres-of-vape-fluid-extracted-from-her-lungs-6596325]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 22:14:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jordan Brielle, a 32-year-old Ohio woman, suffered serious health issues after becoming addicted to vaping. Despite her deteriorating health, Brielle continued to vape, eventually leading to a medically induced coma.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An American woman in Ohio is on the mend after being put in a medically induced coma due to serious health problems stemming from her vaping habit. Jordan Brielle, 32, had two litres of "black and bloody" fluid removed from her lungs by doctors, according to <em>The New York Post. </em>Brielle started smoking when she was still a teenager but kicked over to vaping in 2021.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/16/lifestyle/vaping-addict-finally-quit-when-lungs-collapsed-black-goo-came-out/">According to her</a>, she became addicted very fast, and it became a strain on her pocket as she found herself spending up to $500 every week on vape products. "I was totally addicted," she said. "I was vaping so much that I slept with it and even took it into the shower."</p>

<p>"I wouldn't wish what I'd been through on anyone else. I feel grateful to be alive," Ms Brielle said.</p>

<p>This heavy vaping continued for two years until Brielle began to feel "heaviness" in her lungs last November, which was then diagnosed at first as a respiratory infection. Given her deteriorating health condition and troubled breathing, as well as persistent coughing, Brielle continued vaping.</p>

<p>She went to the hospital several times complaining of breathing problems.</p>

<p>"I had a horrible cough and was going to the hospital two or three times a week for help. I had little to no voice," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/16/lifestyle/vaping-addict-finally-quit-when-lungs-collapsed-black-goo-came-out/">Brielle recalled.</a> "Each time they would send me home. It felt like there were 80 pounds of pressure just lying on my chest. I'd never felt so sick in my life."</p>

<p>The situation worsened when her boyfriend discovered her unconscious with "black mucus coming out of my mouth and my nose." He said he could see she was breathing, but she wasn't reacting, with a very weak pulse.</p>

<p>Her boyfriend immediately dialled 911 and stayed beside her until the paramedics could reach her. They were able to rush her to the hospital, and doctors could extract the toxic substance from her lungs. Brielle's life story opens your eyes to the dangers of vaping; it is also a realisation of what health implications you will get from vaping.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1jnjvi7g_vaping_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite her deteriorating health, Brielle continued to vape. (Representative Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>