<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 01:00:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-threatens-of-even-stronger-retaliation-to-any-israeli-attack-6725054]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Threatens Of "Even Stronger" Retaliation To Any Israeli Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-threatens-of-even-stronger-retaliation-to-any-israeli-attack-6725054]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 23:50:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tehran's top diplomat in Damascus on Saturday threatened an "even stronger" reaction to any aggression, as Israel readied its response to an Iranian missile attack earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tehran's top diplomat in Damascus on Saturday threatened an "even stronger" reaction to any aggression, as Israel readied its response to an Iranian missile attack earlier this week.</p>

<p>"Our reaction to any attack by the Zionist regime is completely clear," Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi told reporters in the Syrian capital, where he met top officials including Tehran's ally President Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<p>"For every action, there will be a proportional and similar reaction from Iran, and even stronger," he said.</p>

<p>He spoke after an Israeli military official told AFP on condition of anonymity, as he was not authorised to discuss the issue publicly, the army was "preparing a response to the unprecedented and unlawful Iranian attack".</p>

<p>In Damascus earlier, Araghchi renewed his call for ceasefires in the Gaza Strip and in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Araghchi's visit, his first since he took office in August, comes almost a year after Iran-backed Palestinian militant group Hamas attacked Israel, triggering the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The conflict has also drawn in Iran's Lebanese ally Hezbollah, and on September 23 Israel sharply intensified its campaign against the militant group.</p>

<p>"The most important issue today is the ceasefire, especially in Lebanon and in Gaza," Araghchi said.</p>

<p>"There are initiatives in this regard. There have been consultations that we hope will be successful."</p>

<p>His meetings in Damascus follow a visit to Beirut on Friday during which he voiced support for a truce in Lebanon acceptable to Hezbollah, "simultaneously with a ceasefire in Gaza".</p>

<p>He travelled to Syria's capital by air after Lebanon said an Israeli air strike on Friday severed the main international highway linking the two countries.</p>

<p>Israel said the strike aimed to prevent the flow of weapons to Hezbollah from neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>Iran has been a staunch ally of Assad throughout the civil war that erupted in 2011 following the suppression of anti-government protests.</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, Assad's office quoted him as saying Iran's missile attack on Israel was "a strong response and taught the Zionist entity a lesson".</p>

<p>The attack came just days after an Israeli air strike in southern Beirut killed Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1kv784ko_iranian-missile-on-israel-sky_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iranian attack came just days after an Israeli air strike in southern Beirut.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-city-has-been-voted-worlds-best-for-its-unique-indoor-outdoor-way-of-life-6724240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This City Has Been Voted World's Best, Per Readers' Choice Awards 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-city-has-been-voted-worlds-best-for-its-unique-indoor-outdoor-way-of-life-6724240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 21:17:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sydney has been named the world's best city in a survey conducted by Conde Nast Traveller. The top-10 global cities rankings are part of the publication's annual Readers' Choice Awards for 2024, which launched on October 1 in the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sydney has been named the world's best city in a survey conducted by <em>Conde Nast Traveller</em>. The top-10 global cities rankings are part of the publication's annual Readers' Choice Awards for 2024, which launched on October 1 in the UK. Sydney, which ranked no. 1 with a score of 92.26, was praised by the Conde Nast Traveller UK for its "unique, indoor-outdoor way of life". Sydney beat out tourism hotspots spanning five continents, including Valencia in Spain (92.78), Singapore (92.47), Hong Kong (91.72) and Stockholm, Sweden (91.11), which ranked second to fifth place respectively.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/05/world-news/sydney-ranked-as-best-city-in-the-world-second-behind-singapore-in-friendliest-in-new-list/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post</em></a>, Sydney was also named the world's second-most friendly city, with a score of 93.85, behind Singapore, with 94.84 points, while Sydney hotel The Fullerton was crowned the best hotel in Australasia.</p>

<p>Conde Nast Traveler US also unveiled its Readers' Choice Awards this week, with Sydney placing third in the US awards list of the best cities in the world, describing it as "an ideal getaway no matter the season". Australian hotel Ritz-Carlton Melbourne was named the best hotel in Australia and New Zealand for 2024.</p>

<p>The UK and US Readers' Choice Awards winners were chosen based on the votes of more than half a million survey respondents, the <em>Post </em>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If you've experienced a snippet of life Down Under, you've probably fallen hard for the unique, indoor-outdoor way of life the Aussies embrace so well," Traveller said about Sydney.</p>

<p>Moreover, the publication also had readers vote on their favourite airlines with Air New Zealand coming first, followed by Singapore Airlines, Qatar Airways, Emirates and British Airways.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-takes-31-trips-to-disney-world-after-stealing-over-rs-4-crore-from-government-6722941">US Couple Takes 31 Trips To Disney World After Stealing Over Rs 4 Crore From Government</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, in September, Sydney was also named Oceania's Leading City Destination in the World Travel Awards 2024.</p>

<p>With results like that, you'd think Sydney was in the midst of an international tourism boom. However, according to the Post, the reality is somewhat different. According to the most recent International Visitor Survey data from Tourism Research Australia, Sydney welcomed only 3,446,000 foreign visitors in June, a figure still 16 per cent below the same period in 2019.</p>

<p>But John O'Sullivan, chief executive of Experience Co and former Tourism Australia managing director, told the Sydney Morning Herald, that the stellar awards results could go a long way to putting Sydney on the radar of high-value international travellers - that is, those likely to spend more, stay longer and travel further within Australia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dukptafo_sydney-generic_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sydney was also named the world's second-most friendly city.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-detained-in-brussels-for-blocking-road-during-protest-6724092]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greta Thunberg Detained In Brussels For Blocking Road During Protest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-detained-in-brussels-for-blocking-road-during-protest-6724092]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 20:53:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Climate activist Greta Thunberg was among dozens of protesters detained Saturday for blocking a road in the Belgian capital at a demonstration against fossil fuel subsidies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate activist Greta Thunberg was among dozens of protesters detained Saturday for blocking a road in the Belgian capital at a demonstration against fossil fuel subsidies.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist saw the iconic Swede -- who has previously been detained for civil disobedience at protests in various countries -- carried away by police after refusing to leave a sit-in.</p>

<p>Thunberg, 21, was part of a smaller group of demonstrators who broke away from a march organised by the United for Climate Justice movement that began outside the European Parliament.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The rally was calling for the European Union -- headquartered in Brussels -- to end subsidies for fossil fuels to achieve its ambitious goal of making the continent carbon neutral by 2050.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This will not happen without an immediate phase-out of fossil fuel subsidies," climate activists, scientists and economists wrote in an open letter to EU leaders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Until these necessary changes occur, people will continue to take to the streets to make our voices heard and hold you accountable."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/up9ir4u_greta-thunberg_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rally was calling for the European Union to end subsidies on Fossil Fuels.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasrallahs-potential-successor-out-of-contact-after-israeli-strikes-report-6723933]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Heir Apparent Out Of Contact After Israeli Air Strikes: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasrallahs-potential-successor-out-of-contact-after-israeli-strikes-report-6723933]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 20:27:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The potential successor to slain Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been out of contact since Friday, a Lebanese security source said on Saturday, after an Israeli airstrike that is reported to have targeted him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The potential successor to Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been out of contact since Friday, a Lebanese security source told Reuters on Saturday, after an Israeli airstrike that is reported to have targeted him.</p>

<p>In its campaign against the Iran-backed Lebanese group, Israel carried out a large strike on Beirut's southern suburbs late on Thursday that Axios cited three Israeli officials as saying targeted Hashem Safieddine in an underground bunker.</p>

<p>The Lebanese security source and two other Lebanese security sources said that ongoing Israeli strikes on Beirut's southern suburb - known as Dahiyeh - since Friday have kept rescue workers from scouring the site of the attack.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has made no comment so far on Safieddine since the attack.</p>

<p>Israeli Lieutenant Colonel Nadav Shoshani said on Friday the military was still assessing the Thursday night airstrikes, which he said targeted Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters.</p>

<p>The loss of Nasrallah's rumoured successor would be yet another blow to Hezbollah and its patron Iran. Israeli strikes across the region in the past year, sharply accelerated in the past few weeks, have decimated Hezbollah's leadership.</p>

<p>Israel expanded its conflict in Lebanon on Saturday with its first strike in the northern city of Tripoli, a Lebanese security official said, after more bombs hit Beirut suburbs and Israeli troops launched raids in the south.</p>

<p>Israel has begun an intense bombing campaign in Lebanon and sent troops across the border in recent weeks after nearly a year of exchanging fire with Hezbollah. Fighting had previously been mostly limited to the Israel-Lebanon border area, taking place in parallel to Israel's year-old war in Gaza against Palestinian group Hamas.</p>

<p>Israel says it aims to allow the safe return of tens of thousands of citizens to their homes in northern Israel, bombarded by Hezbollah since Oct.8 last year.</p>

<p>The Israeli attacks have eliminated much of Hezbollah's senior military leadership, including Secretary General Nasrallah in an air attack on Sept. 27.</p>

<p>The Israeli assault has also killed hundreds of ordinary Lebanese, including rescue workers, Lebanese officials say, and forced 1.2 million people - almost a quarter of the population - to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The Lebanese security official told Reuters that Saturday's strike on a Palestinian refugee camp in Tripoli killed a member of Hamas, his wife and two children. Media affiliated with the Palestinian group also said the strike killed a leader of its armed wing.</p>

<p>The Israeli military did not immediately comment on the strike on Tripoli, a Sunni Muslim-majority port city that its warplanes also targeted during a 2006 war with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israel has meanwhile staged nightly bombardment of Dahiyeh, once a bustling and densely populated area of Beirut and a stronghold for Hezbollah.</p>

<p>On Saturday, smoke billowed over Dahiyeh, large parts of which have been reduced to rubble sending residents fleeing to other parts of Beirut or of Lebanon.</p>

<p>In northern Israel, air raid sirens sent people running for their shelters amid rocket fire from Lebanon.</p>

<p>ISRAEL WEIGHS OPTIONS FOR IRAN</p>

<p>The violence comes as the anniversary approaches of Hamas' attack on southern Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, which killed 1,200 people and in which about 250 were taken as hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on Gaza has killed nearly 42,000 Palestinians, according to Gaza's health ministry, and displaced nearly all of the enclave's population of 2.3 million.</p>

<p>Iran, which backs both Hezbollah and Hamas, and which has lost key commanders of its elite Revolutionary Guards Corps to Israeli air strikes in Syria this year, launched a salvo of ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday. The strikes did little damage.</p>

<p>Israel has been weighing options in its response to Iran's attack.</p>

<p>Oil prices have risen on the possibility of an attack on Iran's oil facilities as Israel pursues its goals of pushing back Hezbollah militants in Lebanon and eliminating their Hamas allies in Gaza.</p>

<p>U.S. President Joe Biden on Friday urged Israel to consider alternatives to striking Iranian oil fields, adding that he thinks Israel has not yet concluded how to respond to Iran.</p>

<p>Israeli news website Ynet reported that the top U.S. general for the Middle East, Army General Michael Kurilla, is headed for Israel in the coming day. Israeli and U.S. officials were not immediately reachable for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rj463n3_hashem-safieddine_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The loss of Nasrallah's rumoured successor would be yet another blow to Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-on-pm-narendra-modis-vladimir-putin-volodymyr-zelensky-meetings-6723587]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Beginning Of Communication...": S Jaishankar On PM's Putin, Zelensky Meets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-on-pm-narendra-modis-vladimir-putin-volodymyr-zelensky-meetings-6723587]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 19:29:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi's meetings with the top leaders of Russia and Ukraine were "beginnings of a communication process" between two countries engaged in a serious conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi's meetings with the top leaders of Russia and Ukraine were "beginnings of a communication process" between two countries engaged in a serious conflict that has had enormous consequences, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said on Saturday.</p>

<p>In an interactive session at The Conclave 2024 organised by news channel Pratidin Time, Mr Jaishankar said Prime Minister Modi was one of the very few world leaders who has the "ability" to speak to both the leaders, who "trust" him.</p>

<p>"What are we trying to do? You don't necessarily have to mediate... sometimes you have to communicate. We are actually, simultaneously talking to two countries who are having a conflict," he said to a question on India's role in "mediation" in the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said Prime Minister Modi has had at least three meetings with Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky and one meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>He said National Security Adviser Ajit Doval also met Putin in September to brief him about PM Modi's discussions with Zelensky.</p>

<p>"Obviously that talk is centered around what the conflict is all about. It was necessary for NSA Doval to go to Russia so that the Russians know what the Prime Minister spoke to Zelensky," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>He said the Russia-Ukraine conflict has entered the third year and has had enormous human cost and huge economic consequences across the world.</p>

<p>"You can either watch this conflict and say none of us could do anything about it and say it will end when it ends. Or you can say I am one of the few countries or in our case one of the few prime ministers who has the ability to speak there and both parties trust him and see whether out of these conversations something moves," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>"I think these are the beginnings of a communication process. Where it will lead, I have not quite reached that point," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said the world leaders were supportive of what India was doing.</p>

<p>"People are very happy today. They say you have a person like PM Modi who has the ability to go to both capitals and have that kind of communication," he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ch4htg18_modi-zelensky_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar said the world leaders were supportive of what India was doing. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-activists-pretend-to-drown-themselves-in-oil-outside-un-agency-in-london-6723173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Protesters Pretend To Drown Themselves In Oil In London]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-activists-pretend-to-drown-themselves-in-oil-outside-un-agency-in-london-6723173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 18:22:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ocean Rebellion campaigners recently pretended to drown themselves in oil and gas in a protest outside a United Nations agency in London.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate protesters have become a daily sight on London's streets, undeterred by the honking horns of irate motorists, personal insults and even arrests. This time, Ocean Rebellion campaigners pretended to drown themselves in oil and gas in a protest outside a United Nations agency in London. The climate change activists staged the frightening demonstration on the steps of the International Maritime Organisation, the UN agency responsible for regulating maritime transport. "A drowning ocean goddess symbolizes the dire threat LNG poses to our oceans," the group wrote on X while sharing pictures of the stunt show.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The images show, one activist, dressed as an "ocean goddess", donning a fishbowl on her head filled with black liquid as though she was drowning. She could be seen screaming as the liquid engulfed her face before it quickly drained from the bowl. Other protesters around her were seen wearing gas masks and brandishing petrol pumps with flames spouting out of them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Liquid Natural Gas (LNG) is not a "green" solution. Methane leaks from LNG ships are 80x more damaging than CO2. The IMO must wake up to this reality before it's too late," Ocean Rebellion wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">2/5 Liquid Natural Gas (LNG) is not a "green" solution. Methane leaks from LNG ships are 80x more damaging than CO2. The IMO must wake up to this reality before it's too late. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SayNoToLNG?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SayNoToLNG</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ClimateCrisis?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ClimateCrisis</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/oceanrebellion?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@OceanRebellion</a> <a href="https://t.co/8tFqfqTvV4">pic.twitter.com/8tFqfqTvV4</a></p>
— Ocean Rebellion (@oceanrebellion) <a href="https://twitter.com/oceanrebellion/status/1842133327785914735?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/04/world-news/climate-change-activists-drown-themselves-with-oil-gas-and-flames-in-nightmarish-protest/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post</em></a>, the protest took place on Friday, the final day of meetings for the UN agency's Maritime Environment Protection Committee, which had convened to discuss reducing greenhouse gas emissions from ships. The protesters accused the agency of manipulating the fossil fuel industry and failing to protect the ocean.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The IMO is failing to protect our oceans. LNG is a dirty fuel disguised as clean. We demand transparency and accountability. Stop listening to fossil fuel lobbyists, start protecting our planet!" the group wrote on the microblogging site.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/antarctica-turning-green-at-an-alarming-rate-says-study-6715700">Antarctica Turning Green At An Alarming Rate, Says Study</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, climate change activists have been in the news with their high-profile direct-action protests, such as disrupting Premier League Football matches, and sporting events, to publicise their cause. They have thrown tomato soup on famous paintings and glued themselves to picture frames in galleries. They want the government to end all new oil and gas exploration and have promised not to let up in its protests until it does so.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago, three activists from Just Stop Oil threw soup at two of Vincent van Gogh's "Sunflowers" paintings at London's National Gallery. This incident occurred just hours after two other members of the protest group were sentenced to prison for a similar act in 2022.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/71sb3kh8_climate-change-activists-_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protest took place on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emirates-bans-pagers-walkie-talkies-onboard-flights-after-lebanon-blasts-6722986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Emirates Bans Pagers, Walkie-Talkies Onboard Flights After Lebanon Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emirates-bans-pagers-walkie-talkies-onboard-flights-after-lebanon-blasts-6722986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 17:51:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dubai's Emirates Airlines has banned passengers from carrying pagers and walkie-talkies on its flights, following last month's attacks on Lebanese group Hezbollah involving communication devices that exploded.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dubai's Emirates Airlines has banned passengers from carrying pagers and walkie-talkies on its flights, following last month's attacks on Lebanese group Hezbollah involving communication devices that exploded.</p>

<p>"All passengers traveling to, from, or via Dubai are prohibited from transporting pagers and walkie-talkies in checked or cabin baggage," the airline said in a statement on its website on Friday. It added that any prohibited items found will be confiscated by Dubai Police as part of heightened security measures.</p>

<p>In the deadly September attacks, thousands of booby-trapped Hezbollah pagers and hundreds of radios exploded - attacks that were widely blamed on Israel but which it has not claimed.</p>

<p>The Middle East's largest airline also announced that flights to Iraq and Iran will remain suspended until Tuesday, while services to Jordan will resume on Sunday.</p>

<p>Flights to Lebanon will remain suspended until Oct. 15 due to escalating Israeli attacks against Iran-backed Hezbollah, including strikes near Beirut's airport.</p>

<p>Several other airlines have also suspended flights to Beirut and other regional airports amid heightened tensions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/bnku9h1_emirates_625x300_10_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Middle East's largest airline also announced that flights to Iraq and Iran will remain suspended.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-takes-31-trips-to-disney-world-after-stealing-over-rs-4-crore-from-government-6722941]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Couple Takes Dozens Of Trips After Stealing Rs 4 Crore From Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-takes-31-trips-to-disney-world-after-stealing-over-rs-4-crore-from-government-6722941]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 17:43:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A couple in the United States defrauded the government of nearly $500,000 (approximately Rs 4.2 Crore) to take dozens of lavish vacations to Walt Disney World while claiming they were travelling for work.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A couple in the United States defrauded the government of nearly $500,000 (approximately Rs 4.2 Crore) to take dozens of lavish vacations to Walt Disney World while claiming they were travelling for work. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, 61-year-old Thomas Bouchard, who is an Army contractor, used his government connections to get his girlfriend, 53-year-old Cantelle Boyd, hired for a "no-show" job as his assistant so they could take numerous vacations, including 31 trips to Walt Disney World in Flordia. Their elaborate scheme cost the Department of Defence more than $490,000, prosecutors said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Citing the US Attorney's Office for the District of Massachusetts, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/04/us-news/couple-took-31-trips-to-disney-after-stealing-500k-from-government-feds/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post </em></a>reported that the couple claimed that they were travelling for work. Mr Bouchard, who was in charge of the US Army Natick Contracting Division in Massachusetts, reportedly used his "long-standing relationship with government contractor Evolution Enterprise Inc., to have Ms Boyd hired as an assistant to support him. She was paid a government salary of $487,658 and performed "little if any useful function" from 2014 to 2018, costing the government an extra $75,583 in travel expenses, prosecutors said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The couple reportedly booked vacations ranging from two to 15 days, and their travels - which were done during business hours - included staying a hotels, lounging by the pool and visiting Disney parks. In addition to this, the couple also travelled to Virginia and other Florida locations. Prosecutors said that the 61-year-old concealed the nature of their trips and sought reimbursement by falsifying and then approving expense records.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-tests-robot-dogs-armed-with-ai-enabled-guns-at-military-facility-in-middle-east-report-6716933">&nbsp;US Army Tests Robot Dogs Armed With AI-Enabled Guns At Military Facility In Middle East: Report</a></strong></p>

<p>Federal authorities arrested the couple in July 2020. They each pleaded guilty to one count of conspiracy and 10 counts of theft of government funds and false declarations. The 61-year-old was sentenced in August to one year and one day in prison and is required to pay $487,658 in restitution.</p>

<p>"Those of us who are privileged to work in public service owe a duty to the taxpayers to act with integrity at all times," said Acting US Attorney Joshua S. Levy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This defendant clearly failed in adhering to this solemn oath and abused his position of trust to line his own pockets, hire a friend into a phantom position and enjoy junkets all on the taxpayer's dime. He will now pay the price for his inexcusable conduct," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Ms Boyd was sentenced to six months of home confinement on October 2. Prosecutors said she is required to pay restitution "at a later date".&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g1qsjp7_disney-world-_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Federal authorities arrested the couple in July 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-capital-locked-down-as-imran-khans-supporters-try-to-seize-the-streets-6722928]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Capital Locked Down As Imran Khan's Supporters Try To Seize The Streets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-capital-locked-down-as-imran-khans-supporters-try-to-seize-the-streets-6722928]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 17:41:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's capital was locked down on Saturday, swarmed by security forces with mobile internet cut as supporters of jailed ex-prime minister Imran Khan attempted to seize the streets in protest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's capital was locked down on Saturday, swarmed by security forces with mobile internet cut as supporters of jailed ex-prime minister Imran Khan attempted to seize the streets in protest.</p>

<p>Khan was barred from standing in the February elections that were marred by allegations of rigging, and sidelined by dozens of legal cases.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But his Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) party has defied a crackdown to needle the government with regular demonstrations.</p>

<p>PTI activists began driving to Islamabad on Friday from his powerbase in northwestern Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province but were met with shipping container roadblocks and volleys of tear gas.</p>

<p>On Saturday, small and scattered convoys pressed in on Islamabad in defiance of the government which approved troops for deployment on the streets -- citing the need to guarantee security ahead of a Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) summit due to open on October 15.</p>

<p>"I am so proud of all our people," said a message from Khan posted on social media site X on Saturday afternoon. "You showed unfaltering resilience and courage as you came out yesterday and overcame unbelievable obstacles."</p>

<p>Protests were also due Saturday in Lahore, however the main motorway linking the eastern megacity to the capital was blocked.</p>

<p>Amnesty International said the communications cuts and road blockades "infringe on people's right to freedom of expression, access to information, peaceful assembly and movement".</p>

<p>"These restrictions are part of a worrying clampdown on the right to protest in Pakistan," the rights group said.</p>

<p>The social media site X -- formerly Twitter -- has also been blocked across Pakistan since after the election, when mobile internet was likewise cut on polling day and PTI allege widespread vote tampering took place.</p>

<p>The 72-year-old Khan served as prime minister from 2018 to 2022, when he was ousted in a parliamentary no-confidence vote after falling out with the powerful military establishment considered Pakistan's political kingmakers.</p>

<p>As opposition leader he led an unprecedented campaign of defiance before becoming tangled in slews of court cases he claims have been orchestrated to prevent his return to power.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c40qgd7g_islamabad-protest_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Saturday, small and scattered convoys pressed in on Islamabad.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-officials-struggle-to-quash-hurricane-helene-conspiracy-theories-6722644]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Officials Struggle To Quash Hurricane Helene Conspiracy Theories]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-officials-struggle-to-quash-hurricane-helene-conspiracy-theories-6722644]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 16:59:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the wake of the devastation of Hurricane Helene in the United States this week, a new storm emerged on social media - false rumours about how disaster funds have been used, and even claims that officials control the weather.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the wake of the devastation of Hurricane Helene in the United States this week, a new storm emerged on social media - false rumours about how disaster funds have been used, and even claims that officials control the weather.</p>

<p>Local and national government officials say they are trying to combat the rumours, including one spread by Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump.</p>

<p>One of the more far-fetched rumours is that Helene was an engineered storm to allow corporations to mine regional lithium deposits. Others accuse the administration of President Joe Biden of using federal disaster funds to help migrants in the country illegally or suggest officials are deliberately abandoning bodies in the cleanup.</p>

<p>Republican Congress member Marjorie Taylor Greene posted on X Thursday night: "Yes they can control the weather. It's ridiculous for anyone to lie and say it can't be done."</p>

<p>The conspiracy theories are pivotal for rescue and recovery efforts following the storm, one of the deadliest U.S. hurricanes this century. And the presidential election between Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris is just over a month away.</p>

<p>Republicans and Democrats alike say the rumours are causing problems.</p>

<p>"I just talked to one Senator that has had 15 calls TODAY about why we don't stop ........ 'fill in the blank,'" said Kevin Corbin, a Republican in the North Carolina Senate - a state that is one of the hardest hit by Helene. "98% chance it's not true and if it is a problem, somebody is aware and on it," he wrote on Facebook.</p>

<p>"I'm growing weary of intentional distractions," he added.</p>

<p>White House officials on Friday accused some Republican leaders and conservative media of intentionally peddling rumours to divide Americans in a way that could harm disaster relief efforts.</p>

<p>"Disinformation of this kind can discourage people from seeking critical assistance when needed most," a White House memo said. "It is paramount that every leader, whatever their political beliefs, stops spreading this poison."</p>

<p>The memo highlighted a claim by Trump during a rally this week that Biden and Harris had used federal emergency funds "on people that should not be in our country."</p>

<p>"This is FALSE," the memo said. "No disaster relief funding at all was used to support migrants housing and services. None. At. All."</p>

<p>In response to a request for comment for this article, the Trump campaign repeated accusations that FEMA funds had been spent on housing migrants in the country illegally.</p>

<p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency has the funds for immediate response and recovery efforts for Helene, the White House memo said, and has provided millions of dollars in relief to those recovering.</p>

<p>FEMA has been the target of so many falsehoods it has set up a rumour response page on its website to try to tamp them down.</p>

<p>Helene slammed into Florida a week ago, killed over 200 people and devastated a half dozen states in the U.S. Southeast.</p>

<p>Some officials are trying to combat the disinformation themselves on social media. Katie Keaotamai, who works at FEMA but said she was speaking on social media in a personal capacity, explained FEMA's disaster response processes in several TikTok posts with thousands of views.</p>

<p>Disaster events are often politicized, said Kate Starbird, co-founder of the Center for an Informed Public at the University of Washington, adding that social media rewards "sensationalism and outrage with attention."</p>

<p>"Manipulating the sensemaking process (e.g. spreading conspiracy theories and disinformation) and politicizing the event will both make it harder to respond and recover now - and to make informed decisions about how to prepare for and mitigate the next one," Starbird said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m84jp7so_hurricane-helene-afp-_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The conspiracy theories are pivotal for rescue and recovery efforts following the storm.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/young-female-soldiers-in-israel-raise-alarms-about-security-risks-on-border-6721669]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Young Female Soldiers In Israel Raise Alarms About Security Risks On Border]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/young-female-soldiers-in-israel-raise-alarms-about-security-risks-on-border-6721669]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 14:19:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite the ongoing military campaign against Hezbollah, the observers assert that they continue to be sidelined. Many believe this is partly due to an ingrained culture of misogyny within the IDF.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For over a year, a dedicated group of young women in Israel's military has been on high alert, observing movements along the border with Lebanon. This female-only unit, known as field observers, has played a critical role in identifying threats from Hezbollah, diligently tracking the group's activities from their posts. These soldiers, aged between 18 and 20, are responsible for monitoring drone activity, mortar rounds, and rockets that have plagued northern Israel since last October. Yet, even as tensions escalated, they feel their warnings and contributions have been largely ignored.</p>

<p>"We are unprotected, which is a problem for us, but it is also dangerous for our work, which is very important," an observer near the border with Lebanon told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/04/israel-female-field-observers-october-7-attacks-hamas-gaza/" rel="NoFollowNoIndex">The Washington Post</a>. "Our superiors only want to shut us up, to not come to them with complaints, so they're ignoring us even more," she added.</p>

<p>Despite the ongoing military campaign against Hezbollah, the observers assert that they continue to be sidelined. Many believe this is partly due to an ingrained culture of misogyny within the IDF.</p>

<p>"It is a male army, where the 'girls' are seen as hysterical, where the commanders regularly say, 'If you continue to send these alarms, you will be put in jail,'" said Gili Yuval, a former field observer who served during the early 2000s when Israel withdrew its forces and dismantled its settlements in Gaza.</p>

<p>Since October 7, she has led a loosely organized network of current and former observers, supplying essentials like food and clothing to victims of the attack.</p>

<p>The IDF has declined to comment on the circumstances surrounding these claims.</p>

<p>Gili Shrvit, 20, an observer stationed at another location along the Gaza border in Kissufim, recounted that on the morning of October 7, she was at her workstation, trembling and in tears as she reported the unfolding devastation: Hundreds of Hamas gunmen had breached their fence, shot out their cameras, and invaded their base.</p>

<p>"We were calling our superiors, telling them we are about to die," she recalled. "They said they have no one for us."</p>

<p>They took cover under their workstations, with no weapons to defend themselves, Shrvit recalled. Their commanders, located 20 miles away, informed them that combat soldiers were trapped in ambushes and could not assist.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3rq7uv1_a-broken-fence-near-the-nahal-oz-base-o_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A damaged fence close to the Nahal Oz base on September 17, 11 months following the attack.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jpmorgan-ceo-jamie-dimon-rejects-donald-trump-s-claim-of-presidential-endorsement-6721274]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Has JPMorgan CEO Jamie Dimon Endorsed Donald Trump? What He Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jpmorgan-ceo-jamie-dimon-rejects-donald-trump-s-claim-of-presidential-endorsement-6721274]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 13:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Friday promoted an endorsement from JPMorgan Chief Executive Jamie Dimon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jamie Dimon has firmly denied former US president Donald Trump's recent claim that the CEO of JPMorgan Chase has endorsed him for the US presidency. This clarification came shortly after Trump claimed he had Dimon's support. A spokesperson for Dimon, Joe Evangelisti, refuted the endorsement, telling <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/04/trump-jamie-dimon-endorsement-jpmorgan.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNBC</a>, “Jamie Dimon has not endorsed anyone. He has not endorsed a candidate.”<br />
<br />
According to the CNBC report, Trump on his social media platform, Truth Social, shared a screenshot falsely claiming that Dimon was backing his presidential bid. The post read, “New: Jamie Dimon, the CEO of JPMorgan Chase, has endorsed Trump for President.”<br />
<br />
The claim seems to have first surfaced on X (formerly Twitter) on October 4 and was quickly circulated by several pro-Trump accounts. It gained further traction when Trump himself shared it before JPMorgan Chase issued a denial.<br />
<br />
However, when NBC questioned Trump about the post on October 4, the former president claimed ignorance of its origin, distancing himself from responsibility. He told NBC, “Somebody put it up. I don't know.” Even hours after the remark, the post was still accessible on Trump's official social media account. CNBC's attempts to contact the Trump campaign for further comment went unanswered.<br />
<br />
Earlier in September, Dimon made his political stance clear during an interview at the JPMorgan Investor Summit in Mumbai. At the time, he emphasised his neutrality, stating, “I'm not endorsing anyone at this time.”<br />
<br />
Although Dimon has occasionally praised Trump, he also criticised the former president. Their relationship has seen its share of public disputes. During the Republican primaries, Dimon voiced support for former South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, urging business leaders to back her instead of Trump.<br />
<br />
Trump, in response, lashed out at Dimon for endorsing Haley, recalling their interactions during his presidency. He said, “I've never been a big Jamie Dimon fan, but had to live with this guy when he came begging to the White House,” adding fuel to their already tense rapport.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tabv3mlg_jamie-dimon-donald-trump_625x300_05_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-3-lakh-lavender-plants-adorn-starry-night-themed-bosnian-park-6720707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1.3 Lakh Lavender Plants Adorn "Starry Night" Themed Bosnian Park]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-3-lakh-lavender-plants-adorn-starry-night-themed-bosnian-park-6720707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 11:31:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Vincent Van Gogh aficionado in Bosnia has turned a plot of land into a giant, living reproduction of the painter's masterpiece, "Starry Night", composed of thousands of plants.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Vincent Van Gogh aficionado in Bosnia has turned a plot of land into a giant, living reproduction of the painter's masterpiece, "Starry Night", composed of thousands of plants.</p>

<p>"Vincent Van Gogh belongs to us too. It's our heritage and this is a way of paying tribute to him," Halim Zukic told AFP.</p>

<p>Behind him, tens of thousands of lavender bushes, grasses and other plants form swirls and spirals across a dozen hectares that -- seen from the air -- unmistakably resemble the celestial configuration painted by the Dutch post-Impressionist master in 1889.</p>

<p>"It wasn't possible to simply reproduce a flat image on a three-dimensional space," Zukic said.</p>

<p>"Inspired by the painting, we tried to stick to the shapes and proportions, so that it looks like the painting as much as possible.</p>

<p>"And I think we succeeded."</p>

<p>The 56-year-old entrepreneur first noticed the land 20 years ago when he was returning from a day out picking mushrooms nearby, in the woods surrounding the village of Luznica in central Bosnia.</p>

<p>He bought the first plot with the idea of building a hut and creating a small, rounded garden.</p>

<p>At the time, he wasn't even thinking about "Starry Night", one of the favourite landscapes in New York's Museum of Modern Art (MoMA).</p>

<p>But the idea just clicked in 2018 when Zukic noticed the tracks left on the lawn by a tractor.</p>

<p>"To my eyes, these tracks looked like spirals from "Starry Night" and it was an immediate decision."</p>

<p><strong>130,000 lavender plants</strong></p>

<p>The former insurance company owner, who now works in tourism, bought more land and started working it, helped daily by up to 20-30 gardeners.</p>

<p>He declined to say what it cost to complete his labour of love, which took six years to acquire its final shape.</p>

<p>"We planted around 130,000 lavender bushes, tens of thousands of aromatic and medicinal plants, several thousand trees," he said.</p>

<p>"There isn't a single straight line in the park -- just like in nature."</p>

<p>At the same time, Zukic became interested in Van Gogh, about whom he knew very little at the time.</p>

<p>Today, Zukic talks animatedly about the painter, his "love of nature" and the "passion with which he did his work".</p>

<p>In 2023, he travelled to France to visit the places where Van Gogh spent some of his most prolific years -- Arles and Saint-Remy-en-Provence.</p>

<p>The artist painted "Starry Night" in June 1889 while he was in a Saint Remy psychiatric hospital.</p>

<p>A year later, he committed suicide, aged 37.</p>

<p>For the time being, only a handful of visitors have had the chance to appreciate Zukic's park.</p>

<p>The plants and trees still need time to flourish so the public will need a few more months of patience, he said. "Having money is not enough. You need time for a park," he said. "I'd say we've created a good foundation. The park will be more beautiful every year."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ubl2sn7o_van-gogh-starry-night-bosnian-park_625x300_05_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vincent Van Gogh painted "Starry Night" in June 1889 while he was in a Saint Remy psychiatric hospital.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-israel-hit-irans-nuclear-facilities-what-top-us-official-said-6720390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Will Israel Hit Iran's Nuclear Facilities? What Top US Official Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-israel-hit-irans-nuclear-facilities-what-top-us-official-said-6720390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 10:32:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It is "really hard to tell" if Israel will use the anniversary of Hamas' October 7 attacks to retaliate, a top US State Department official told CNN on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel hasn't clarified its intention of targeting Iran's nuclear facilities in retaliation for the Iranian ballistic missile strikes earlier this week on Tuesday. It is as ambiguous as it could be. It is "really hard to tell" if Israel will use the anniversary of Hamas' October 7 attacks to retaliate, a top US State Department official told CNN on Friday.</p>

<p>"We hope and expect to see some wisdom as well as strength, but as you guys know, no guarantees," the official said when asked by CNN if Israel has assured the US that Iran's nuclear sites are off the table.</p>

<p>"I think in some ways they would want to avoid the seventh, so in my estimation, if there is anything it would likely be before or after," the senior State Department official said.</p>

<p>Iran launched a barrage of 181 ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday night, triggering nationwide air raid sirens and forcing nearly 10 million Israelis into bomb shelters. Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) claimed responsibility for the missile assault, targeting three Israeli military bases near Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>Although a majority of missiles were intercepted, there were scattered reports of damage and injuries. In Tel Aviv, two civilians were lightly injured by shrapnel, while in the West Bank city of Jericho, a Palestinian civilian was killed by debris from one of the missiles, news agency AFP reported. The Israeli military quickly announced that the immediate threat had passed, and civilians were allowed to leave bomb shelters after an hour.</p>

<p>US officials have voiced support for Israel and its response to Iran's missile attack earlier this week. "Israel has a right to defend itself, as any nation does. In terms of what Israel's response will be, of course, there must be consequences for Iran for this attack. We've made clear that there must be consequences," said Matthew Miller, Spokesperson, US Department of State, during a press briefing.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden opposed Israel's idea of targeting Iran's nuclear facilities.</p>

<p>"If I were in their shoes, I'd be thinking about other alternatives than striking oil fields," Biden said at a press briefing Friday.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fpmdben_israel-attack-on-beirut_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran launched a barrage of 181 ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday night.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-country-sells-citizenship-to-become-worlds-most-climate-resilient-island-6720215]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Country Sales Citizenship For Greater Resilience Against Hurricanes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-country-sells-citizenship-to-become-worlds-most-climate-resilient-island-6720215]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 09:54:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Caribbean nation aims to become the world's most climate-resilient island without accruing massive debt or waiting for promised aid from wealthier nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a bid to rebuild and thrive after the devastation of Hurricane Maria seven years ago, Dominica has turned to an unconventional funding source: selling passports, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2024/10/04/dominica-hurricane-passports/" rel="NoFollowNoIndex">The Washington Post</a> reported. The Caribbean nation aims to become the world's most climate-resilient island without accruing massive debt or waiting for promised aid from wealthier nations. By offering citizenship to affluent individuals, often from China and the Middle East, for hundreds of thousands of dollars, Dominica has found a way to fund its ambitious recovery efforts.</p>

<p>The nation's citizenship programme dates back to the 1990s but has rapidly expanded since the hurricane, becoming the primary source of national revenue. Funds raised have been directed toward critical infrastructure projects, including new medical clinics and residential complexes for those displaced by the storm. Former Foreign Minister Francine Baron calls the initiative a "saviour," while Finance Minister Irving McIntyre emphasized the need for a "self-dependent form of financing" to tackle climate change.</p>

<p>"This programme means a lot to us. We realised we had to get a self-dependent form of financing to deal with climate change," Mr McIntyre told The Post.</p>

<p>Despite its success, the programme has raised eyebrows over transparency and security concerns. Although the price for citizenship has recently increased to a minimum of $200,000 (Rs 1.68 crore), it remains one of the most affordable options globally. Some recipients reside in Dominica, a small island with a population of 71,000, known for its lush landscapes.</p>

<p>The aftermath of Hurricane Maria severely damaged the economy, with losses estimated at over double the country's gross domestic product (GDP). Prime Minister Roosevelt Skerrit vowed to rebuild better and more resilient, emphasizing the urgent need for funding to mitigate future climate risks.</p>

<p>Dominican officials claim that climate change, largely driven by emissions from wealthier nations, is resulting in hurricanes that are both more frequent and severe.</p>

<p>Dominica's proactive stance on climate resilience includes substantial investments in housing and infrastructure. The government claims to have funded around 2,000 homes in locations designed to withstand future disasters.</p>

<p>The nation aims to invest in resilient infrastructure to mitigate climate risks while seeking support from developed nations amid a funding shortfall highlighted by the UN in global climate discussions.</p>

<p>While passport sales have become a lifeline, the approach has sparked debates about the potential risks associated with granting citizenship to individuals with unclear backgrounds. Critics argue that such programs may not be adequately scrutinized. The European Union and other international bodies have raised alarms regarding security measures, especially following reports of Dominica issuing passports to individuals from dubious backgrounds.</p>

<p>Despite the scrutiny, the demand for Dominican passports remains robust. With limited flight options to the US, the island has become a hub for those seeking greater mobility and access through alternative citizenship. However, the rapid growth of the programme has prompted calls for greater oversight and accountability.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b6pitgg8_dominica_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Citizenship in this country costs $200,000 (approximately Rs 1.68 crore).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-hostage-recalls-hamas-captivity-in-gaza-suddenly-youd-hear-someone-6720160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Heard Screams Of...": Freed Hamas Hostage Recounts Nightmarish Captivity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-hostage-recalls-hamas-captivity-in-gaza-suddenly-youd-hear-someone-6720160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 09:43:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to reports, while 117 of the 251 hostages held in Gaza have so far been freed, 64 people are still in Hamas' captivity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the Gaza war nears its first anniversary, an Israeli man taken hostage by Hamas on Friday recalled his confinement, saying he heard beatings while in captivity.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-rescued-4-hostages-alive-in-gaza-5845858" target="_blank">Shlomi Ziv</a>, 41, was among the four Israeli hostages who were rescued alive from Hamas captivity in June.</p>

<p>They were kidnapped from the Nova music festival, a trance festival held in Israel's Negev Desert, on October 7 last year.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Noa Argamani (25), Almog Meir Jan (21), Andrey Kozlov (27), and Shlomi Ziv (40) were rescued in a special operation by the IDF, ISA and Israel Police from 2 separate locations in the heart of Nuseirat after being kidnapped by Hamas from the Nova music festival.<br />
<br />
They are in good… <a href="https://t.co/PnkjL4GRQz">pic.twitter.com/PnkjL4GRQz</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1799392501586952256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"There were quiet nights in captivity when you could hear every little sound, and then suddenly, you'd hear someone getting beaten," Ziv was quoted as saying by the Israeli newspaper The Jerusalem Post.</p>

<p>"It was chilling to hear the screams of that person being brutally beaten," he added.</p>

<p>"One thing that my captivity in Gaza reinforced more than anything else is the understanding and realization that they don't want any peace with us or to live next to us or with us," Ziv said.</p>

<p>He also said the Hamas members called them "cockroaches" and always said that the next time they do something like the October 7 attack, "they won't take hostages, but would kill them".</p>

<p>According to the Israel Defense Forces, Ziv was working as security director at the Nova music festival when he was taken hostage.</p>

<p>Hamas members staged their worst-ever attack on Israel on October 7, 2023, and took 251 hostages from the Nova music festival and Nir Oz kibbutz, triggering the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-a-brief-history-of-israel-and-palestine-understanding-a-decades-old-conflict-6700902" target="_blank">war in Gaza</a>.</p>

<h3><strong>64 Hostages Still Held By Hamas In Gaza</strong></h3>

<p>According to reports, while 117 of the 251 hostages have so far been freed, most of them women, children, and foreign workers, 64 people are still in Hamas' captivity.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is the moment the elite Yamam unit rescued former hostages Shlomi Ziv, Almog Meir Jan and Andrey Kozlov from captivity in Gaza.<br />
<br />
Real life superheroes. <a href="https://t.co/1fMGPu3xpz">pic.twitter.com/1fMGPu3xpz</a></p>
— Israel ישראל (@Israel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel/status/1800240482947088454?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Of the 64 thought to be alive, 57 are Israelis, six are Thai nationals and one is Nepalese, according to news agency AFP.</p>

<p>Fifty-two men, 10 women, two children, and eleven military personnel are said to be held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Most of the hostages were released during a week-long truce in late November in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>The Israeli army has confirmed 70 others are dead, 33 of whose bodies are still in Gaza.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/188j3grg_shlomi-ziv_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shlomi Ziv was among the four Israeli hostages who were rescued alive from Hamas captivity in June.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/celebrated-russian-spy-whale-hvaldimir-did-not-die-of-gunshot-wounds-6720033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian "Spy Whale" Death: New Claim By Cops On How Hvaldimir Died]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/celebrated-russian-spy-whale-hvaldimir-did-not-die-of-gunshot-wounds-6720033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 09:16:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A beluga whale "Hvaldimir", found dead in Norway in August, was not shot to death as claimed by animal rights groups but died of bacterial infection, said Norwegian Police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A beluga whale “Hvaldimir”, found dead in Norway in August, reportedly died of bacterial infection and not gunshot wounds, said Norwegian police on Friday. The probable cause of bacterial infection is the wound in the mouth, caused by a stuck stick.</p>

<p>The 14-foot-long and 2,700-pound whale was first spotted in 2019 with a harness reading “Equipment St. Petersburg” fueling speculations that the whale was a Russian spy. This prompted people to nickname him Hvaldimir, the spy whale. Hvaldimir is a blend of the Norwegian word for whale, "hval," and the first name of Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>The white whale was found dead outside Stavanger on August 31.</p>

<p>Animal rights organizations NOAH and One Whale claimed the whale had been shot dead and filed a police report. Following this, the Veterinary Institute in Sandnes, on behalf of the Directorate of Fisheries, conducted an autopsy and found a 35-centimeter (14-inch) stick lodged in his mouth.</p>

<p>“The report concluded that the probable cause of death was a bacterial infection, possibly a result of wounds in his mouth caused by a stick that got stuck,” Amund Preede Revheim, Norway police official said.</p>

<p>“Pinnen (Norwegian word for peg, a wooden stick) may also have led to Hvaldimir having challenges with its nutrition, thus increasing infections,” stated the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.politiet.no/aktuelt-tall-og-fakta/aktuelt/nyheter/2024/10/04/sor---vest-oppdatering-hvaldimir-endelig-obduksjonsrapport-er-klar/">press release</a> issued by Norway police.</p>

<p>“Assessment done by the Veterinary Institute and police criminal technicians found that there was no injury. X-ray of the chest and head can be conducted without the presence of a projector or other metal fragments,” it added.</p>

<p>The police didn't find any trace of bullets and therefore, no further investigation was done.</p>

<p>“There are no investigations that indicate that Hvaldimir is living illegally. The police therefore had no reason to launch an investigation into the whale's death, and responded to the incoming report”, said Preed Revheim.</p>

<p>For biosecurity reasons, remains are usually destroyed after autopsies at the Veterinary Institute. In this case, the Directorate of Fisheries has decided to donate the skeleton of the white whale Hvaldimir to the Nature Museum and Botanical Garden at UiA University in Agder.</p>

<p>Last year, Norway requested its citizens to avoid any contact with Hvaldimir who was seen in a fjord close to Oslo.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pvlb0bmo_spy-whale-_625x300_01_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hvaldimir became an internet sensation as he was suspected to be a Russian spy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/600-people-shot-dead-within-hours-by-al-qaeda-in-this-african-country-burkina-faso-barsalogho-6719743]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Collected Bodies For 3 Days": 600 Massacred Within Hours In This Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/600-people-shot-dead-within-hours-by-al-qaeda-in-this-african-country-burkina-faso-barsalogho-6719743]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:05:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[About 600 people were killed within a few hours by members affiliated with Al-Qaeda in an August attack on the town of Barsalogho in Burkina Faso, reports claimed on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About 600 people were killed within a few hours by members affiliated with Al-Qaeda in an August attack on the town of Barsalogho in Burkina Faso, a report claimed on Friday. The residents of Barsalogho were shot dead on August 24 as they dug protective trenches.</p>

<p>The attack, in which most of the victims were women and children, was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/170-people-executed-in-attacks-on-3-villages-in-burkina-faso-report-5167872" target="_blank">one of the worst in the West African country's history</a>, which has been grappling with a jihadist insurgency waged by rebels affiliated with Al-Qaeda and the Islamic State group that spilled over from neighbouring Mali in 2015.</p>

<p>The members of Jama'at Nusrat al-Islam wal-Muslimin (JNIM), an Al-Qaeda affiliate based in Mali and active in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/browns-not-greens-how-an-arid-africa-country-is-reimagining-golf-courses-3876165" target="_blank">Burkina Faso</a>, shot down villagers as they swept into the outskirts of Barsalogho on bikes.</p>

<p>While the United Nations estimated a death count of around 200, JNIM said it had killed nearly 300 "fighters". However, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/04/africa/burkina-faso-massacre-600-dead-french-intel-intl/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>, citing a French government security assessment, reported that up to 600 people were shot dead in the attack.</p>

<p>A man, who said he was one of dozens of men told to dig the trenches by the army, told CNN that he was 4 kilometers from the town at about 11 am, in a trench, when he heard the first gunshots.</p>

<p>“I started to crawl into the trench to escape.&nbsp;But it seemed that the attackers were following the trenches. So, I crawled out and came across the first bloodied victim. There was blood everywhere on my way. There was screaming everywhere. I got down on my stomach under a bush, until later in the afternoon, hiding,” he said.</p>

<p>Another survivor, who lost two members of her family in the attack, said JNIM killed people "all day long".</p>

<p>"For three days we were collecting bodies - scattered everywhere. Fear got into our hearts. At the burial time, there are so many bodies lying on the ground that burying was hard," she said.</p>

<p>The military reportedly ordered the locals to dig a vast trench network around the town to protect it from jihadists circulating nearby.</p>

<p>JNIM has warned civilians against endorsing the army in its fight against the insurgency.</p>

<p>According to the ACLED analysis group, which tracks global conflict, members affiliated with Al-Qaeda - which was founded by Osama bin Laden and carried out the 9/11 attacks in the US - and the Islamic State group have killed about 3,800 this year.</p>

<p>Since the start of the conflict in 2015, more than 20,000 people have been killed and over two million displaced in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/burkina-faso-army-announces-overthrow-of-military-government-amid-violence-3393970" target="_blank">Burkina Faso</a>, one of the world's poorest countries situated in the Sahel, a region wracked by instability.</p>

<p><em>(With agency inputs)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qmppb3g8_burkina-faso_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-israeli-strikes-pound-beirut-after-fresh-warning-from-iran-10-points-6719624]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[More Israeli Strikes Pound Beirut After Fresh Warning From Iran: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-israeli-strikes-pound-beirut-after-fresh-warning-from-iran-10-points-6719624]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 07:25:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli airstrikes continued to pound Beirut on Saturday after Iran's supreme leader declared the country's allies won't back down in the war in West Asia that threatens severe global ramifications.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli army issued fresh evacuation orders in Beirut's southern suburbs last evening, after which a series of loud blasts were heard in the area near the airport.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hezbollah is also engaged in ongoing clashes with Israeli troops in the Lebanon border area during ground raids. It said in a statement that Israeli soldiers tried to approach the village of Adaysseh when their operatives confronted them.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Three hospitals in Lebanon were forced to suspend work after damages due to Israeli strikes as the Lebanese Prime Minister urged the global community to pressure Israel to allow rescuers to reach bombed sites.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel is now fighting both Palestine and Lebanon, which are part of the Iran-backed 'Axis of Resistance' group, in a war that started with the October 7 attack by Hamas and has now widened to a regional conflict.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Palestinian Hamas group's October 7, 2023 attack, called the 'Al-Aqsa Flood', had targeted Israeli border towns, sparking a fierce West Asia showdown that continues till date. The Lebanese Hezbollah group - also backed by Iran-later entered the war in support of Hamas.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Khamenei yesterday said its allies won't back down and defended his country's missile strikes on Israel. In a rare public sermon, he asserted after leading the Friday prayers that Israel would "not last long".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli Defence Forces, which has been conducting ground raids inside Lebanon, claimed in their latest update they have eliminated over 2,000 military targets and 250 Hezbollah operatives, including over a dozen commanders.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli Air Force has also been pounding Beirut and its suburbs with airstrikes over the past few weeks. Former Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah was killed in one such strike a week, dealing a major blow to the Lebanese group.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran's missile salvo on Israel on Tuesday marked a massive escalation in the West Asia war as Israel vowed to hit back stronger. It is feared that Israel may target oil and nuclear infrastructure in the country. Fears of oil supply disruptions have already sparked a rise in oil prices.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">US President Joe Biden has advised Israel against striking oil facilities in Iran. But his predecessor Donald Trump, who is contesting November polls to return to the White House, has said that he believes Israel should strike Iran's nuclear facilities in response to the missile barrage.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j9v8f388_beirut-ruins-afp_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-not-renew-parole-program-for-migrants-from-cuba-haiti-nicaragua-and-venezuela-6719594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Will Not Renew Legal Status For "Hundreds Of Thousands" Of Migrants]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-not-renew-parole-program-for-migrants-from-cuba-haiti-nicaragua-and-venezuela-6719594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 07:14:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden administration will not renew a temporary humanitarian entry program for hundreds of thousands of migrants with US sponsors who arrived in recent years, the US Department of Homeland Security said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden administration will not renew a temporary humanitarian entry program for hundreds of thousands of migrants with US sponsors who arrived in recent years, the US Department of Homeland Security said on Friday (October 4).</p>

<p>Some 530,000 migrants from Cuba, Haiti, Nicaragua and Venezuela have entered the US by air since October 2022 and received two-year grants under the "parole" program that will begin to expire in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>However, many of those migrants could remain in the country under other programs.</p>

<p>The parole program allows migrants with existing US sponsors to enter the country for humanitarian reasons or if their entry is deemed a significant public benefit. It will continue to accept new applications from those abroad.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden's administration launched the parole program as a way to provide migrants avenues to enter legally and decrease illegal crossings at the US-Mexico border. Record numbers of migrants were caught crossing illegally during Biden's presidency but crossings have plummeted in recent months as Biden rolled out new border restrictions.</p>

<p>Immigration is a top voter issue in the Nov. 5 election that will pit Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris against Republican Donald Trump, who has criticized the parole program.</p>

<p>The decision not to renew the parole program for the four nationalities follows the plan outlined by DHS when the program was launched, spokesperson Naree Ketudat said in a statement.</p>

<p>Migrants without permission to remain in US "will need to depart the United States prior to the expiration of their authorized parole period or may be placed in removal proceedings," Ketudat said.</p>

<p>Other parole programs for Ukrainians and Afghans have been extended.</p>

<p>Most of the four nationalities allowed entry under the so-called CHNV parole program have avenues to stay in the US.</p>

<p>Many Cubans are eligible for permanent residence and eventual citizenship under the 1966 Cuban Adjustment Act.</p>

<p>Most Haitians and Venezuelans in the US are eligible for Temporary Protected Status, which grants them deportation relief and work permits.</p>

<p>All four nationalities could apply for asylum.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ekj236q_us-migrants-reuters_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Immigration is a top voter issue in the Nov. 5 election in the US.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>