<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 10:30:08 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-elon-musk-changes-x-display-picture-to-show-support-for-donald-trump-6726978]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Changes X Display Picture To Show Support For Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-elon-musk-changes-x-display-picture-to-show-support-for-donald-trump-6726978]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 10:05:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has changed his X display picture to show his public support for Republican US Presidential candidate Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has changed his X display picture to show his public support for Republican US Presidential candidate Donald Trump. The image, which features Musk wearing a “Make America Great Again” cap against the backdrop of the American flag, comes as the former US president prepares for the upcoming 2024 presidential election on November 5.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/3rp9bd61kX">pic.twitter.com/3rp9bd61kX</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1842730813885948001?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The internet was quick to react to this public show of support.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One user commented, “Who loves Elon and President Trump?”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Who loves Elon and President Trump? ????</p>
— ????????Kelli Kay???????? (@KelliKayK) <a href="https://twitter.com/KelliKayK/status/1842731041720524854?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“I gotta get one of those hats. Who else will be getting one?” asked another.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I gotta get one of those hats. Who else will be getting one?????‍♂️</p>
— ProudPatriotUS???????? (@PrPatriotUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/PrPatriotUS/status/1842731018534432976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Others dubbed him the “Dark MAGA” with comments like, “Dark MAGA rises.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="tl">Dark MAGA rises ???? <a href="https://t.co/NG9f1m3Fxd">pic.twitter.com/NG9f1m3Fxd</a></p>
— Julia ???????? (@Jules31415) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jules31415/status/1842737184920539249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Elon Musk's endorsement, while notable, is not entirely unexpected. He has been a vocal supporter of Trump in the past and <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-donald-trump-pennsylvania-butler-assassination-site-2024-us-presidential-elections-6726322 ">recently attended a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania</a> – the same venue where the former president was nearly assassinated in July. He was seen wearing the same cap that he posted on his X account. During the event, Donald Trump acknowledged Elon Musk's presence by inviting him on stage and referred to him as an “incredible guy.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>In his speech, Elon Musk took a dig at US President Joe Biden, saying, “We had one president who couldn't climb a flight of stairs and another who is fist pumping after getting shot.” He went on to emphasise Trump's importance in the upcoming election, declaring, “Trump must win to preserve democracy in America.”</p>

<p>Donald Trump, speaking behind bulletproof glass at the rally, recalled the assassination attempt from July 13, where a bullet grazed his ear. He called the would-be assassin a “vicious monster.” Elon Musk, referencing the incident, said the 2024 election was the “most important election of our lifetime,” urging the crowd to rally behind Trump.</p>

<p>Elon Musk also encouraged supporters to take action, saying, “Get everyone you know, and everyone you don't know, drag them to register to vote. If they don't, this will be the last election. That's my prediction.”</p>

<p>Following the rally, Elon Musk took to <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1842706955497766939">his X account</a>, warning of a potential shift in the political landscape if Trump doesn't win, writing, “The Democratic Party will legalize so many illegals that there will be no swing states. America will become a single-party socialist state, just like what happened to California, where they just made requiring voter ID illegal.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dhjbtamo_elon-musk-twitter_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has been a vocal supporter of Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-hot-for-beach-visit-dubais-floodlit-beaches-are-a-hit-at-night-6726948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Too Hot For Beach Visit? Dubai's Floodlit Beaches Are A Hit At Night]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-hot-for-beach-visit-dubais-floodlit-beaches-are-a-hit-at-night-6726948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 09:59:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Roasted by summer temperatures too hot for the beach, Dubai has turned to an innovative solution: opening them at night, complete with floodlights and lifeguards carrying night-vision binoculars.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Roasted by summer temperatures too hot for the beach, Dubai has turned to an innovative solution: opening them at night, complete with floodlights and lifeguards carrying night-vision binoculars.</p>

<p>The idea, in one of the world's hottest regions, with temperatures climbing ever higher through climate change, has proved popular -- more than one million people have visited the night beaches since last year, an official said.</p>

<p>Even with much of the region preoccupied with the widening conflict that pits Israel against Hamas, Hezbollah and Iran, the United Arab Emirates' giant neighbour, the night beaches remain busy on weekend evenings.</p>

<p>"The temperature drops down in the evening after the sun sets. So, yeah, it's amazing," said Mohammed, 32, from Pakistan, who brought his children to enjoy the sea without having to worry about the burning Gulf sun.</p>

<p>For residents of Dubai, a coast-hugging, desert metropolis of about 3.7 million people, the hot season from June to October is an annual trial.</p>

<p>With temperatures regularly topping 40 degrees Celsius (104 degrees Fahrenheit), often with high humidity, outdoor activities are severely limited.</p>

<p>The city now has more than 800 metres (yards) of designated night beaches fitted with shark nets and illuminated by giant, bright floodlights.</p>

<p>"While you're... bathing inside the water, you can see the sand even on your foot and your hands and everything," said Mohammed, who has lived in Dubai for a decade.</p>

<p>Lifeguards are posted 24 hours a day and, beyond the floodlights' glare, they use the night-vision binoculars to keep an eye on swimmers or kayakers further out in the water.</p>

<p>Officials are also testing an artificial intelligence camera system meant to detect when people are in distress.</p>

<p><strong>'Feels like a bath'</strong></p>

<p>At nearly midnight on a recent Friday, with temperatures still above 30C (86F), Umm Suqeim beach was packed with people -- mainly expatriates, who make up about 90 percent of the UAE's population.</p>

<p>Mary Bayarka, a 38-year-old fitness coach from Belarus, was enjoying being outside after a "long, hot day", even if the Gulf seawater was a little warm.</p>

<p>"It feels like (I'm) in a bath," she said.</p>

<p>Nearby, Filipina saleswoman Laya Manko was burying her body in the sand. The beach is an escape for the 36-year-old, one of the hundreds of thousands of migrant workers who keep Dubai's economy ticking.</p>

<p>"Every weekend we come here to have fun," she said. "Sometimes we sleep here with my friends.</p>

<p>"Because you work hard in Dubai, you feel you need to relax. Yes, this is my stress reliever," said Manko.</p>

<p>For the authorities, the night beaches are another way to tempt tourists, especially in summer when the stifling heat usually keeps them indoors.</p>

<p>"I believe we are one of the only cities in the world to have such infrastructure on public beaches at night," said Hamad Shaker, an official from the Dubai municipality.</p>

<p><strong>Extreme weather</strong></p>

<p>Dubai used to empty out in summer as expats fled the heat in droves, said Manuela Gutberlet, a tourism researcher at the University of Breda in the Netherlands.</p>

<p>But with attractions such as the world's tallest building, giant malls and indoor amusement parks, it has become "a year-round urban destination", attracting more than 17 million visitors last year, she said.</p>

<p>However, climate change could limit its ambitions, Gutberlet warned, citing the unprecedented rains that paralysed the city for several days in April.</p>

<p>Extreme weather events and a further rise in temperatures could discourage some visitors, she said, highlighting the need to "adapt quickly to new risks".</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Frenchman Laziz Ahmed, 77, found himself on the night beach during his first holiday in Dubai, where he was visiting relatives.</p>

<p>"During the day, I don't go out much," he said, adding that in the evening "I make up for it".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8n7hkfgo_dubai-beach-at-night_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-guts-bring-him-back-to-the-site-of-failed-assassination-6726828]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's "Guts" Bring Him Back To The Site Of Failed Assassination]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-guts-bring-him-back-to-the-site-of-failed-assassination-6726828]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 09:29:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Supporters knelt and others bowed their heads as Donald Trump led a moment of silence at 6:11 pm, the time when shots rang out at a rally in the same rural Pennsylvania showground exactly 12 weeks earlier.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Supporters knelt and others bowed their heads as Donald Trump led a moment of silence at 6:11 pm, the time when shots rang out at a rally in the same rural Pennsylvania showground exactly 12 weeks earlier.</p>

<p>An opera singer belted out "Ave Maria" as a Secret Service sniper scanned the horizon with binoculars and a surveillance drone hovered above the tens of thousands of rallygoers. Heavily armed officers patrolled behind the stage.</p>

<p>The crowd in Butler periodically erupted into chants of "fight, fight, fight" -- echoing Trump's rallying cry just after the July 13 shooting that grazed his ear and briefly upended the campaign for November's election.</p>

<p>"I love the fact that he came back... He said he'd come back to finish his speech, and to me (that takes) guts," said Robert Dupain, 53, a local construction worker who was at the July rally.</p>

<p>"That's what (these) 50,000 people stand for," said Dupain, who described having "nervous excitement all week" about attending.</p>

<p>Though there was no official count, Saturday's rally was significantly better attended than the previous one.</p>

<p>Trump's return to Butler, a deeply conservative community in the key swing state of Pennsylvania, was marked by noticeably tighter security.</p>

<p>"As I was saying," Trump said to laughter from behind bulletproof glass as he began his speech, riffing on the violent interruption to his July monologue.</p>

<p>The same chart towards which Trump turned his head at the moment the would-be assassin open fired three months ago was also flashed up on a big screen Saturday, to cheers.</p>

<p>In a typically meandering speech, Trump repeated lies about immigration, transgender athletes and his political opponents.</p>

<p>The would-be assassin had fired from a complex of buildings left outside the security perimeter, despite its proximity to Trump's podium. It was ringed by state police on Saturday.</p>

<p>Trucks were also parked around the venue, blocking potential sightlines.</p>

<p>'Unnerving'</p>

<p>"There's a lot going on that's unnerving," said Heather Hughes, 43, who had traveled from New Castle in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"Do I think he's safe? No, I think there's going to be another attempt. But I think he's going to make it through."</p>

<p>Trump on Saturday suggested his opponents had "maybe even tried to kill me."</p>

<p>The gunman in July was quickly shot dead by a countersniper, but not before he killed rallygoer Corey Comperatore, a firefighter, and wounded two others.</p>

<p>The sound of a bell ringing four times was played at the beginning of Trump's speech, once for each victim including the former president.</p>

<p>An artist created a memorial of Comperatore, complete with his firefighter's helmet, while a singer performed a song about the shooting.</p>

<p>The July attempt, and a September incident at Trump's golf course in Florida that the FBI said was another attempted assassination, raised fears the campaign and the November vote could be marred by more violence.</p>

<p>Retiree Glen Scheirer, who along with five relatives were wearing identical "By the grace of God" T-shirts, described the 20-year-old gunman as "mentally ill," but suggested he could have been influenced by rhetoric calling Trump a threat to democracy.</p>

<p>'Fight, fight, fight'</p>

<p>The crowd chanted Comperatore's name when the mayor of nearby Slippery Rock, Jondavid Longo, paid tribute to the victims of July 13.</p>

<p>"We're glad to welcome president Trump back to Butler," he said.</p>

<p>"His return is not just political -- it signifies our refusal to be defined by tragedy."</p>

<p>James Sweetland, a doctor who ran to Comperatore in the wake of the shooting, told the crowd that "an assassin's bullet should not decide our election."</p>

<p>He was called on once again Saturday when a rallygoer was taken ill in the grandstand alongside the stage.</p>

<p>Sally Sherry, a first responder at Butler Memorial Hospital who treated Trump, said he was not the hard character "like you see on TV."</p>

<p>"I wasn't supposed to make it," Trump reflected. "I'm a little bit embarrassed to say it, but fight, fight, fight!"</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/79qnvvao_donald-trumps-returns-to-butler-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-israeli-airstrikes-hit-beirut-hezbollah-heir-apparent-missing-10-points-6726826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Airstrikes Hit Beirut, Hezbollah Heir Apparent Missing: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-israeli-airstrikes-hit-beirut-hezbollah-heir-apparent-missing-10-points-6726826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 09:27:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli airstrikes hit southern Beirut late Saturday night, with Lebanese media reporting particularly violent strikes lasting into early Sunday morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Explosions were heard for over two hours across southern Beirut, with news agency AFP reporting balls of flame and plumes of smoke rising from the targeted sites. In one particularly severe strike, thick smoke filled the air, and flares lit up the night sky for almost an hour. Residents fled the scene in panic, some on foot, others on motorbikes, as explosions echoed in the background.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) confirmed the operation, claiming on their Telegram channel that they were targeting Hezbollah's infrastructure. The strikes came after an earlier call by the Israeli army for residents of southern Beirut to evacuate, warning civilians to move at least 500 meters away from designated buildings.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">This latest escalation comes amid ongoing hostilities between Hezbollah and Israel. The two sides have exchanged fire nearly daily over the past year, following the outbreak of the Gaza war.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Since September 23, Israel has launched a series of airstrikes in Lebanon, killing over 1,110 people and displacing over a million. Just last week, Israeli forces killed Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah in an airstrike on southern Beirut.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">A high-ranking Hezbollah source told news agency AFP that communication had been lost with Hashem Safieddine, a senior Hezbollah figure expected to succeed Nasrallah, following Israeli airstrikes earlier in the week.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">While Hezbollah has not officially confirmed the loss of contact, two sources close to the organisation said attempts to reach Safieddine were being impeded by continued Israeli bombardments. It was reported that Safieddine had been with Hezbollah's head of intelligence, Hajj Murtada, at the time of the attack.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The recent strikes are among the most significant in Israel's campaign against Hezbollah, with 11 consecutive airstrikes on Hezbollah strongholds in southern Beirut recorded early Friday. Israel's military claimed to have hit Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in Beirut during these attacks.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In addition to the escalating conflict in Lebanon, Israel is preparing for further tensions related to the anniversary of the Hamas attack on October 7. The Israeli military has increased forces and heightened alert, anticipating possible retaliatory strikes from Hezbollah or its Iranian backers. Iran has already launched missile attacks in response to Israeli operations.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Since Monday, Israeli forces have reportedly killed 440 Hezbollah fighters in ground and air operations in Lebanon. The strikes aim to neutralise Hezbollah's rocket fire, which has targeted northern Israel for nearly a year, displacing tens of thousands of Israeli civilians.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The United States has evacuated 600 citizens from Lebanon since the escalation began, with 145 passengers leaving on flights organised by the US State Department on Saturday alone.</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j1qtj708_israel-hezbollah-afp-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The recent strikes are among the most significant in Israel's campaign against Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-hit-south-beirut-sparking-flashes-of-red-and-white-seen-for-30-minutes-6726725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Massive Israeli Strikes Hit South Beirut, Sparking Flashes Seen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-hit-south-beirut-sparking-flashes-of-red-and-white-seen-for-30-minutes-6726725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 09:04:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Massive consecutive strikes hit Beirut's southern suburbs from late Saturday into Sunday, Reuters eyewitnesses said, sending booms across the city and sparking flashes of red and white for nearly 30 minutes visible from several kilometers away.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Massive consecutive strikes hit Beirut's southern suburbs from late Saturday into Sunday, Reuters eyewitnesses said, sending booms across the city and sparking flashes of red and white for nearly 30 minutes visible from several kilometers away.</p>

<p>The strikes came after days of bombing by Israel of Beirut suburbs considered strongholds for Iran-backed armed group Hezbollah, killing its leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, and possibly his potential successor.</p>

<p>A Lebanese security source said on Saturday that Hashem Safieddine, the potential successor, had been out of contact since Friday, after an Israeli airstrike near the city's international airport that was reported to have targeted him.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it eliminated Nasrallah in a strike on the group's central command headquarters in Beirut on Sept. 27. Hezbollah confirmed he had been killed.</p>

<p>Lebanese security sources said Israeli strikes since Friday on Dahiyeh, a residential area and Hezbollah stronghold south of central Beirut, have kept rescue workers from scouring the site of Thursday night's attack.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has made no comment so far on Safieddine.</p>

<p>His loss would be another blow to the group and its patron Iran. Israeli strikes across the region in the past year, sharply accelerated in the past few weeks, have decimated Hezbollah's leadership.</p>

<p>Israel has been expanding its actions in Lebanon. On Saturday, it made its first strike in the northern city of Tripoli, a Lebanese security official said, and Israeli troops launched raids in the south.</p>

<p>At least eight strikes rocked Beirut's southern suburbs late on Saturday including close to the airport, according to Reuters witnesses, after the Israeli military warned some residents to flee.</p>

<p>Before the recent upsurge, exchanges of fire between Israel and Hezbollah had been mostly limited to the Israel-Lebanon border area, in parallel to Israel's year-old war in Gaza against Palestinian group Hamas.</p>

<p>Israeli military spokesperson Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari said on Saturday that Israel had killed 440 Hezbollah fighters in its ground operations in southern Lebanon and destroyed 2,000 Hezbollah targets. Hezbollah has not released death tolls.</p>

<p>Israel says it stepped up its assault on Hezbollah to enable the safe return of tens of thousands of citizens to homes in northern Israel, bombarded by the group since last Oct. 8.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities said on Saturday that nine Israeli soldiers had been killed in southern Lebanon so far.</p>

<p><strong>Civilian Deaths, Displacement</strong></p>

<p>The Israeli assault has also killed hundreds of ordinary Lebanese, Lebanese officials say, and forced 1.2 million people - almost a quarter of the population - from their homes.</p>

<p>The Lebanese security official told Reuters that Saturday's strike on a Palestinian refugee camp in Tripoli killed a member of Hamas, his wife and two children. Media affiliated with the Palestinian group said the strike killed a leader of its armed wing, naming him as Saeed Atallah.</p>

<p>The Israeli said in a statement that it had killed two Hamas members operating in Lebanon, but did not say whether they had been in Tripoli, a Sunni Muslim-majority port city also targeted during a 2006 war with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Hamas.</p>

<p>In northern Israel, air raid sirens on Saturday sent people running for shelters amid rocket fire from Lebanon.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it had fired missiles at what it called "ATA company for military industries near Sakhnin base," close to Haifa. It was not immediately clear what Hezbollah was referring to.</p>

<p>The Israeli army said two projectiles had crossed from Lebanon, one of which was intercepted while the other landed but caused no damage.</p>

<p><strong>Anniversary Of October 7</strong></p>

<p>The violence came as the anniversary approached of Hamas' Oct. 7 attack on southern Israel, in which 1,200 people were killed and about 250 taken hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on Gaza has killed nearly 42,000 Palestinians, according to Gaza's health ministry, and displaced nearly all of the enclave's population of 2.3 million.</p>

<p>The impact on civilians has prompted widespread protests internationally. Thousands of demonstrators took to the streets in major cities around the world on Saturday as the anniversary approached.</p>

<p>Iran, which backs both Hezbollah and Hamas, and which has lost key commanders of its elite Revolutionary Guards Corps to Israeli airstrikes this year, launched ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday. The strikes did little damage.</p>

<p>Israel has been weighing options for its response.</p>

<p>Oil prices have risen on the possibility of an Israeli attack on Iranian oil facilities. U.S. President Joe Biden on Friday urged Israel to consider alternatives to striking Iranian oil infrastructure.</p>

<p>The top U.S. general for the region, Army General Michael "Eric" Kurilla, is traveling in the Middle East, a U.S. defense official said on Saturday, declining to specify which country or to confirm Israeli media reports that he had arrived in Israel for consultations with Israeli military officials.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/cguuhd4o_israel-strikes-beirut_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least eight strikes rocked Beiruts southern suburbs late on Saturday including close to the airport.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-robber-breaks-into-home-cooks-meal-for-victim-hangs-clothes-to-dry-6726718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Robber Breaks Into Home, Cooks Meal For Victim, Hangs Clothes To Dry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-robber-breaks-into-home-cooks-meal-for-victim-hangs-clothes-to-dry-6726718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 09:00:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A burglar broke into a womans home in the UK and decided to feel at home and finish several household chores including cooking, cleaning and hanging out washed clothes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A burglar broke into a woman's home in the UK and decided to feel at home and finish several household chores including cooking, cleaning and hanging out washed clothes. He left the house with a note, “Don't worry, be happy, eat up and scratch.”</p>

<p>Damian Wojnilowicz, 36, conducted an unusual burglary in Monmouthshire on July 16. Cardiff Crown Court sentenced him to 22 months of jail on Thursday, reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czeg6xk6rkko">BBC</a>.</p>

<p>This left the victim too scared to stay in her home. “Two weeks after the crime until he was caught, I was living in a state of heightened anxiety I had never experienced before,” said the woman in a personal statement. “I wondered if it was somebody who knew me, if it was going to turn into a stalking incident, if he knew I lived alone and if I had been targeted,” she added.</p>

<p>“I was too scared to stay in my own home and stayed with a friend.”</p>

<p><strong>Burglar's To-Do</strong></p>

<p>Damian Wojnilowicz unpacked a pair of shoes and discarded the packaging in the recycling bin. Similarly, he replaced toothbrush heads and kitchen utensils.</p>

<p>Wojnilowicz took grocery shopping out of bags and put them in the refrigerator. He went on to rearrange the fridge. He also refilled bird feeders, removed plant pots, moped the floor and kept an empty bottle of wine in a rack.</p>

<p>Before leaving, Wojnilowicz cooked a meal using ingredients from the woman's cupboard.</p>

<p>When the woman returned home, she saw a bottle of red wine had been left out, next to a glass and bottle opener, and a bowl of sweets was lying on the living room table.</p>

<p>She spoke to her neighbour who described seeing someone hanging out washing.</p>

<p><strong>Burglar Gets Caught</strong></p>

<p>Wojnilowicz carried out a second burglary at another home on July 29, following which he was arrested. He was caught when the homeowner received a CCTV alert on his phone which showed Wojnilowicz walking on his driveway.</p>

<p>This time he used the shower in a summerhouse to wash and clean his clothes. He consumed food and drink and left the hot tub dirty.</p>

<p>When the homeowner asked his son-in-law to attend to the property, Wojnilowicz was found holding a glass and appeared to be drunk. He left the house upon asking.</p>

<p>The homeowner said he felt "sick, horrified, and useless" when he became aware of the burglary, reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czeg6xk6rkko">BBC</a>.</p>

<p>Wojnilowicz was homeless and was undergoing several difficulties during that time, said Tabitha Walker, the defendant.</p>

<p>Sentencing, Recorder Christian Jowett said: "This was a significant intrusion in their homes."</p>

<p>The court heard he has four previous convictions for offences including common assault, public order offences, and failing to surrender.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k17gobg_uk-robber-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Damian Wojnilowicz, 36, left the house with a note, "Don't worry, be happy, eat up and scratch."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shame-on-them-netanyahu-as-macron-criticises-israel-calls-for-halt-on-arms-deliveries-6726378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Shame On Them": Netanyahu As Macron Calls For Halt On Arms Deliveries]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shame-on-them-netanyahu-as-macron-criticises-israel-calls-for-halt-on-arms-deliveries-6726378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 07:23:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["I think that today, the priority is that we return to a political solution, that we stop delivering weapons to fight in Gaza," Emmanuel Macron told French broadcaster France Inter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron called Saturday for a halt on arms deliveries to Israel for use in Gaza, provoking a sharp response from Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>Macron also criticised Netanyahu's decision to send troops into ground operations in Lebanon.</p>

<p>"I think that today, the priority is that we return to a political solution, that we stop delivering weapons to fight in Gaza," Macron told French broadcaster France Inter.</p>

<p>"France is not delivering any," he added during the interview, which was recorded Tuesday.</p>

<p>Macron reiterated his concern over the conflict in Gaza that is continuing despite repeated calls for a ceasefire.</p>

<p>"I think we are not being heard," he said. "I think it is a mistake, including for the security of Israel," he said, adding that the war was leading to "hatred".</p>

<p>His comments brought a swift response from Netanyahu.</p>

<p>"As Israel fights the forces of barbarism led by Iran, all civilised countries should be standing firmly by Israel's side," Netanyahu said in a statement issued by his office.</p>

<p>"Yet, President Macron and other Western leaders are now calling for arms embargoes against Israel. Shame on them."</p>

<p>Israel was fighting a war on several fronts against groups backed by arch-foe Iran, the statement added.</p>

<p>Macron' office responded with a statement of its own later Saturday.</p>

<p>France is a "steadfast friend of Israel", it said, describing Netanyahu's reaction as "excessive and detached from the friendship between France and Israel".</p>

<p>Qatar, a key mediator in Gaza ceasefire talks, said Macron's statement was "an important and appreciated step towards stopping the war".</p>

<p>Jordan welcomed the French leader's remarks and stressed "the importance of imposing a complete ban on the export of weapons to Israel" and "real consequences" for the country's actions.</p>

<p><strong>Ceasefire call</strong></p>

<p>In his interview, Macron also said avoiding an escalation in Lebanon was a "priority."</p>

<p>"Lebanon cannot become a new Gaza," he added.</p>

<p>And he returned to the subject Saturday in a speech to a conference of French-speaking nations in Paris.</p>

<p>While both Paris and Washington had called for a ceasefire, said Macron, "I regret that Prime Minister Netanyahu has made another choice, has taken this responsibility, in particular, for ground operations on Lebanese soil."</p>

<p>The 88 members of the International Organisation of La Francophonie (OIF), including France and Canada, have called for an "immediate and lasting" ceasefire in Lebanon, he added.</p>

<p>But Macron reaffirmed Israel's right to self-defence and said that on Monday he would be meeting relatives of Franco-Israelis held hostage in Gaza.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israel marks the first anniversary of the October 7 Hamas attack that sparked the Gaza war and has now engulfed neighbouring Lebanon, creating a perilous regional crisis.</p>

<p>The attack resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity. Israel's retaliatory offensive on Gaza has so far killed at least 41,825 people, a majority of them civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run Palestinian territory. The UN has said those figures are reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/macron-netanyahu-afp_650x400_81500258704.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French President criticised Netanyahu's decision to send troops into ground operations in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/end-shocking-violence-and-bloodshed-says-un-chief-on-hamas-attack-anniversary-6726351]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[End "Shocking Violence", Says UN Chief On Hamas Attack Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/end-shocking-violence-and-bloodshed-says-un-chief-on-hamas-attack-anniversary-6726351]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 07:12:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN secretary-general denounced Hamas and called for an immediate end to the "shocking violence and bloodshed" in Gaza and Lebanon in a statement Saturday ahead of the anniversary of the Palestinian group's October 7 attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN secretary-general denounced Hamas and called for an immediate end to the "shocking violence and bloodshed" in Gaza and Lebanon in a statement Saturday ahead of the anniversary of the Palestinian group's October 7 attack.</p>

<p>Monday marks one year since the devastating assault on Israel that sparked the ongoing war in Gaza, with Lebanon now also pulled into the fray and world leaders warning of a potential all-out regional crisis.</p>

<p>"This is a day for the global community to repeat in the loudest voice our utter condemnation of the abhorrent acts of Hamas, including the taking of hostages," UN chief Antonio Guterres said in an anniversary message released Saturday evening.</p>

<p>While demanding the hostages' "immediate and unconditional release," Guterres also implored Hamas to allow the hostages to be visited by Red Cross personnel.</p>

<p>Hamas militants abducted 251 people on October 7, 97 of whom are still captive in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military has said are dead.</p>

<p>Guterres additionally voiced concern over the conflict spreading to Lebanon, where Israel in recent days has pounded the Hamas-allied group Hezbollah, killing over a thousand people and forcing more than a million to flee their homes.</p>

<p>"The war that has followed the terrible attacks of one year ago continues to shatter lives and inflict profound human suffering for Palestinians in Gaza, and now the people of Lebanon," Guterres said.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive on Gaza has so far killed at least 41,825 people, a majority of them civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run Palestinian territory. The UN has said those figures are reliable.</p>

<p>"Since October 7th, a wave of shocking violence and bloodshed has erupted," said Guterres.</p>

<p>"It is time for the release of the hostages," he said. "Time to silence the guns. Time to stop the suffering that has engulfed the region. Time for peace, international law and justice."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/jrqqdt7c_un-chief-650_625x300_22_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UN Chief demands "immediate and unconditional release" of the hostages by Hamas]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-donald-trump-pennsylvania-butler-assassination-site-2024-us-presidential-elections-6726322]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If Donald Trump Doesn't Win....": Elon Musk Joins Ex US President On Stage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-donald-trump-pennsylvania-butler-assassination-site-2024-us-presidential-elections-6726322]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 07:05:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump was shot in the ear when he was addressing a rally in Pennsylvania's Butler on July 13.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Saturday returned to the venue of a campaign rally where he was nearly assassinated in July, calling his would-be assassin a "vicious monster". He also invited billionaire <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-pays-5-2-million-brazil-fines-but-to-wrong-account-6719495" target="_blank">Elon Musk</a> on stage in Pennsylvania's Butler, saying that he is an "incredible guy".</p>

<p>"As I was saying," Trump said as he started speaking behind bulletproof glass, pretending he was resuming the speech that was interrupted when he was grazed in the ear by a bullet on July 13.</p>

<p>"Exactly 12 weeks ago this evening, on this very ground, a cold-blooded assassin aimed to silence me," he told thousands of his supporters.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">PRESIDENT TRUMP RETURNS TO BUTLER:<br />
<br />
"As I was saying..." ? <a href="https://t.co/0w7MaJZvSt">pic.twitter.com/0w7MaJZvSt</a></p>
— Trump War Room (@TrumpWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpWarRoom/status/1842687307352060254?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The gunman, identified as 20-year-old <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-reveals-gunman-viewed-donald-trump-rally-as-target-of-opportunity-report-6441328" target="_blank">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a>, had climbed a nearby rooftop with a direct line of sight to where <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-claims-big-threats-on-his-life-by-iran-moves-were-already-made-6644974" target="_blank">Trump </a>was speaking. He was subsequently shot and killed by a Secret Service agent.</p>

<p>As blood dripped down his face, Trump raised a fist and shouted "fight, fight, fight" to his supporters, an image that had gone viral on social media.</p>

<p>During the Saturday rally, Musk praised Trump and took a dig at US President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>"We had one president who couldn't climb a flight of stairs and another who is fist pumping after getting shot," he said.</p>

<p>It was the first time Musk, the owner of social media platform X, attended a Trump poll rally since he endorsed him on July 13.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">.<a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elonmusk</a> delivers remarks in Butler, PA: <a href="https://t.co/adh9xac0Ua">pic.twitter.com/adh9xac0Ua</a></p>
— Trump War Room (@TrumpWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpWarRoom/status/1842701245129048248?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-admits-lack-of-diligence-ahead-of-trump-rally-shooting-6612861" target="_blank">Trump</a> "must win to preserve democracy in America," Musk said as he called the 2024 US presidential poll the "most important election of our lifetime".</p>

<p>"There is no truer test than courage under fire," he said.</p>

<p>“Get everyone you know, and everyone you don't know, drag them to register to vote,” he told the Republican supporters. “If they don't, this will be the last election. That's my prediction.”</p>

<p>"Fight, fight, fight, vote, vote, vote," he said as he wrapped up his nearly 7-minute speech.</p>

<p>He then took to his official X account after the rally and said if Trump doesn't win, the "Democratic Party will legalize so many illegals that there will be no swing states."</p>

<p>"America will become a single-party socialist state, just like what happened to California, where they just made requiring voter ID illegal," he said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">If <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a> doesn't win, the “Democratic” Party will legalize so many illegals that there will be no swing states!<br />
<br />
America will become a single-party socialist state, just like what happened to California, where they just made requiring voter ID illegal. <a href="https://t.co/I9FhicDbfP">https://t.co/I9FhicDbfP</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1842706955497766939?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>JD Vance, Trump's vice presidential running mate, also addressed the rally, which came exactly one month before the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump took a bullet for democracy. What have you done?" Vance said in an apparent attack on Democrat nominee Kamala Harris.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fimjltlo_donald-trump-elon-musk_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump and Elon Musk during a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-march-for-ceasefire-ahead-of-israel-hamas-war-anniversary-6726291]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands March For Ceasefire Ahead Of Israel-Hamas War Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-march-for-ceasefire-ahead-of-israel-hamas-war-anniversary-6726291]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 07:00:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of protesters marched in cities around the world on Saturday calling for a ceasefire in Gaza and Lebanon as the war in the Palestinian territory neared the one-year mark.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of protesters marched in cities around the world on Saturday calling for a ceasefire in Gaza and Lebanon as the war in the Palestinian territory neared the one-year mark.</p>

<p>Kicking off a planned wave of demonstrations worldwide, pro-Palestinian supporters gathered in cities in Europe, Africa and the Americas to demand an end to the conflict, which has killed nearly 42,000 people in Gaza.</p>

<p>Dozens of protests and commemorations are set to take place ahead of the anniversary Monday of Hamas's attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,825 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the territory's health ministry and described as reliable by the United Nations.</p>

<p>With Israel now mounting a ground operation in Lebanon and vowing to respond to a barrage of missiles fired by Iran this week, there are fears the conflict could spiral into a wider war.</p>

<p>Underlining international polarisation over events in the Middle East, demonstrations in support of both Israel and the Palestinians are planned worldwide -- sometimes with rival events scheduled in the same city.</p>

<p><strong>'Worse and worse'</strong></p>

<p>A pro-Palestinian protest in Rome that drew thousands of people turned violent, as dozens of young demonstrators threw bottles and firecrackers at police, who responded with tear gas and water cannon.</p>

<p>At least one policeman was wounded and two protestors detained, AFP journalists said.</p>

<p>"Israel is a criminal state!" the demonstrators shouted.</p>

<p>In Berlin, police said they had detained 26 people who shouted insults at a pro-Israeli commemoration attended by around 650 people.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a pro-Palestinian demonstration drew just over 1,000 protestors in the German capital, police said.</p>

<p>At the "National March for Palestine" in London, chants of "stop bombing civilians" were joined by shouts of "hands off Lebanon".</p>

<p>Zackerea Bakir, 28, said he has attended dozens of marches around the United Kingdom. Large numbers continue to turn up because "everyone wants a change", he told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's continuing to just get worse and worse, and yet nothing seems to be changing," said Bakir, joined at the rally by his mother and brother.</p>

<p>While the rally in London was largely peaceful, at least 15 people were arrested, including three on suspicion of assaulting an emergency worker and one on suspicion of supporting a proscribed organisation.</p>

<p>In Dublin, several hundred people took to the streets, waving Palestinian flags and chanting: "Ceasefire now!".</p>

<p>In France, thousands of people marched in Paris, Lyon, Toulouse, Bordeaux and Strasbourg to express solidarity with Palestinians, AFP journalists said.</p>

<p>Around 5,000 people joined a pro-Palestinian protest in Madrid, brandishing signs with messages such as "Boycott Israel".</p>

<p>A pro-Palestinian demonstration in the Swiss city of Basel drew several thousand people, the Keystone-ATS news agency reported.</p>

<p>Hundreds of pro-Palestinian demonstrators also marched on the Israeli embassy in Athens, which was heavily guarded by riot police.</p>

<p><strong>Soaring tension</strong></p>

<p>In Cape Town in South Africa, hundreds walked to parliament, chanting: "Israel is a racist state" and "We are all Palestinian."</p>

<p>Pro-Gaza marches were also planned Saturday in Johannesburg and Durban.</p>

<p>In Caracas, hundreds of pro-Palestinian demonstrators protested outside the United Nations's headquarters for Venezuela, carrying a giant Palestinian flag.</p>

<p>They delivered a petition to the UN calling for an end to the "genocide" of the Palestinians.</p>

<p>"Where are the UN peacekeepers? Why haven't they intervened?" university professor Jesus Reyes, 53, told AFP.</p>

<p>Other pro-Palestinian protests were planned over the weekend and on Monday in cities including New York, Sydney, Buenos Aires, Madrid, Manila, and Karachi.</p>

<p>Commemorations for victims of the October 7 attack are also scheduled internationally, including ceremonies in London, Washington, Paris and Geneva.</p>

<p>Pope Francis has called for a day of "prayer and fasting for peace" on the anniversary of the attack, amid soaring tension in the Middle East.</p>

<p>An official anniversary ceremony will be held in Jerusalem on Monday.</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog will lead a memorial service at Sderot, one of the cities hardest hit during the onslaught by Palestinian militants.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1l02v8k8_israel-hamas-war-anniversary_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pro-Palestinian supporters gathered in cities in Europe, Africa and the Americas to demand an end of war]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-government-linked-hackers-infiltrated-major-us-internet-providers-6726286]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Highly-Skilled Chinese Hackers Infiltrated Multiple US Telecom Firms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-government-linked-hackers-infiltrated-major-us-internet-providers-6726286]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 06:56:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of highly skilled Chinese hackers linked to the Chinese government successfully infiltrated multiple US telecommunications firms in the last few months, CNN reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of highly skilled Chinese hackers linked to the Chinese government successfully infiltrated multiple US telecommunications firms in the last few months, CNN <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/05/politics/chinese-hackers-us-telecoms/index.html?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=whatsappCNN&amp;utm_content=2024-10-05T23:51:39" title="n">reported</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to CNN, US investigators believe the hackers may have gained access to wiretap warrant requests, although the extent of the damage and what exact information was compromised remains under investigation. The hackers targeted major broadband and internet providers, including AT&amp;T, Verizon, and Lumen, all critical players in the US telecom industry.</p>

<p>This newly discovered cyber-espionage campaign has prompted grave concerns among US officials about the potential national security risks posed by the hackers' success. The breach represents yet another sophisticated attack attributed to Chinese cyber operatives, coinciding with heightened tensions between Washington and Beijing over cyber espionage and broader security issues.</p>

<p>The US telecommunications industry forms the backbone of the country's internet and phone communications, making it a prime target for any state-sponsored hackers. Telecom firms possess vast amounts of caller and user data, and law enforcement agencies often seek access to specific portions of this data as part of national security investigations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Both AT&amp;T and Lumen declined to comment on the ongoing investigation, while Verizon did not respond to CNN's multiple requests for a statement. US agencies involved in the investigation, such as the Department of Justice and the FBI, have also remained tight-lipped, refusing to provide any official comment.</p>

<p>The Chinese Embassy in Washington DC denied any involvement by Beijing-backed hackers in the breach. Liu Pengyu, a spokesperson for the embassy, labelled the accusations as a "distortion of the fact" and accused the US of politicising cybersecurity issues to "smear China."</p>

<p>The US Congress has been briefed on the severity of the situation, CNN reported, with both the House and Senate intelligence committees receiving updates on the hacking campaign. Major cybersecurity players, such as Microsoft and Mandiant, have also been brought in to assist in probing the attacks. Sources close to the investigation have highlighted the persistence and sophistication of the hacking group, known in cybersecurity circles as Salt Typhoon.</p>

<p>FBI Director Christopher Wray has even remarked that Chinese government-backed hackers vastly outnumber FBI cyber personnel by a staggering 50 to 1.</p>

<p>One such Chinese hacking group has allegedly been lurking in US transportation and communication networks, ready to disrupt any US response in the event of a Chinese military invasion of Taiwan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another notable Chinese hacking operation occurred last year when hackers breached the unclassified email accounts of senior US diplomats just before Secretary of State Antony Blinken's high-profile visit to China.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-11/k7p6skds_hacking-generic-reuters_625x300_16_November_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Chinese Embassy in Washington DC denied any involvement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-of-devastation-israel-on-alert-ahead-of-hamas-attack-anniversary-6726257]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Year Of Devastation: Israel On Alert Ahead Of Hamas Attack Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-of-devastation-israel-on-alert-ahead-of-hamas-attack-anniversary-6726257]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 06:46:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel placed its forces on alert Saturday ahead of the anniversary of Hamas's October 7 attack, after a military official said the country was preparing its retaliation for Iran's missile attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel placed its forces on alert Saturday ahead of the anniversary of Hamas's October 7 attack, after a military official said the country was preparing its retaliation for Iran's missile attack.</p>

<p>The alert came with Israel engaged in an intensifying war with the Lebanese Hezbollah group, which army chief Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi said would be hit "without concession or respite".</p>

<p>Ahead of Monday's grim anniversary, military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari said at a televised briefing: "We are prepared with increased forces in anticipation for this day", when there could be "attacks on the home front".</p>

<p>The unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel by the Palestinian group resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>One year later, although the war in Gaza continues at a lower tempo, Israel has turned its focus north to Lebanon, where it is now at war with Hezbollah, and is focused on the movement's backer Iran.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it had killed around 440 Hezbollah fighters "from the ground and from the air" since Monday when troops began "targeted" ground operations against Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel says it aims to allow tens of thousands of Israelis displaced by almost a year of Hezbollah rocket fire into northern Israel to return home.</p>

<p>Israel's President Isaac Herzog called Iran an "ongoing threat" after Tehran, which backs armed groups across the Middle East, on Tuesday launched around 200 missiles at Israel in revenge for Israeli killings of top militant leaders.</p>

<p><strong>'Duty' to respond</strong></p>

<p>The missile attack killed one person in the Israeli-occupied West Bank and damaged an Israeli air base, according to satellite images.</p>

<p>It the same day Israeli ground forces began their raids into Lebanon after days of intense strikes on Hezbollah strongholds across Lebanon.</p>

<p>One Israeli military official, speaking to AFP on condition of anonymity as he was not authorised to discuss the issue publicly, said the army "is preparing a response" to Iran's attack.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, in a statement, noted Iran had twice launched "hundreds of missiles" at Israeli territory since April.</p>

<p>"Israel has the duty and the right to defend itself and to respond to these attacks and that is what we will do," said Netanyahu. His critics accuse him of obstructing efforts to reach a Gaza ceasefire and deal to free hostages still held by Hamas.</p>

<p>A senior Hezbollah source said Saturday the group had lost contact with Hashem Safieddine, widely tipped to be the next Hezbollah leader, after air strikes this week in Beirut.</p>

<p>The movement is yet to name a new chief after Israel assassinated Hassan Nasrallah late last month in a massive strike in the Lebanese capital.</p>

<p>Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on Friday said that "the resistance in the region will not back down".</p>

<p><strong>Fresh strikes on Hamas</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah said its fighters were confronting Israeli troops in Lebanon's southern border region, and early Sunday claimed to have repelled an attempted Israeli incursion into a border village.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Saturday it had struck militants inside a mosque in Bint Jbeil. It also reported frequent rocket fire from Lebanon while Hezbollah claimed a rocket attack on northern Israel's Ramat David air base, and on a "military industries company" near Israel's coastal city of Acre.</p>

<p>Hamas said Israeli strikes had killed two of its operatives in north and east Lebanon Saturday, as Israel's military confirmed the killing of two Hamas figures.</p>

<p>Hamas said one of them was hit near Tripoli, the first such strike in the northern area.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said Israel had "destroyed a large part" of Hezbollah's arsenal and "changed the course of the war".</p>

<p>In a March report, the Center for Strategic and International Studies said estimates of Hezbollah's rockets and missiles varied from 120,000-200,000.</p>

<p><strong>'Never-ending'</strong></p>

<p>On central Beirut's busy Hamra Street, Salma Salman said she had been camping out with her seven-year-old twin daughters for nearly two weeks.</p>

<p>"We're living a terrifying, never-ending nightmare," she said.</p>

<p>Late Saturday Israel issued a new appeal for residents of southern Beirut, a Hezbollah stronghold, to evacuate.</p>

<p>A little later, official Lebanese media said five Israeli strikes hit south Beirut and its outskirts, four of them "very violent".</p>

<p>AFP correspondents in Beirut heard several explosions and saw smoke rising south of Beirut.</p>

<p>Across Lebanon, the wave of strikes on Hezbollah strongholds has killed more than 1,110 people since September 23, according to a tally based on official figures.</p>

<p>The head of the UN's refugee agency, Filippo Grandi, said in Lebanon that the country "faces a terrible crisis" and warned "hundreds of thousands of people are left destitute or displaced by Israeli air strikes".</p>

<p>Israeli bombardment has put at least four hospitals in Lebanon out of service, the facilities said.</p>

<p>British foreign minister David Lammy described reports of the strikes "deeply disturbing" in a post on X.</p>

<p>The UN peacekeeping force in Lebanon (UNIFIL) said it rejected a request by the Israeli military to "relocate some of our positions" in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>Ireland's President Michael Higgins, whose country has peacekeepers in the mission, said Israel was "demanding that the entire UNIFIL... walk away", which he called "an insult to the most important global institution".</p>

<p>Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi, visiting Damascus on Saturday after a stop in Beirut, renewed his call for ceasefires in both Gaza and Lebanon, while threatening Israel with an "even stronger" reaction to any attack on Iran.</p>

<p>French President Emmanuel Macron said it was time "that we stop delivering weapons to fight in Gaza," adding that France was not providing any.</p>

<p>He also criticised Israel's decision to send ground troops into Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>Unhealed wounds</strong></p>

<p>US, Qatari and Egyptian mediators tried unsuccessfully for months to reach a Gaza truce and secure the release of 97 hostages still held in the Hamas-ruled territory.</p>

<p>Medics and rescuers said Israeli fire early Saturday killed at least 12 people across Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,825 people in Gaza, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the territory's health ministry and described as reliable by the UN.</p>

<p>Ahead of the October 7 anniversary, thousands joined pro-Palestinian rallies in London, Paris, Cape Town and other cities.</p>

<p>Herzog, the Israeli president, said his country's October 7 "wounds still cannot fully heal".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dmff0tg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[October 7 attack on Israel by the Palestinian group resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/75-new-zealand-sailors-rescued-from-shipwreck-off-samoa-6726899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[75 New Zealand Sailors Rescued From Shipwreck Off Samoa]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/75-new-zealand-sailors-rescued-from-shipwreck-off-samoa-6726899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 06:44:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New Zealand said Sunday it had rescued all 75 sailors from a navy vessel that ran aground and sank off Samoa while conducting a reef survey.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand said Sunday it had rescued all 75 sailors from a navy vessel that ran aground and sank off Samoa while conducting a reef survey.</p>

<p>Emergency services worked through the night to rescue dozens of crew from the smouldering and sinking HMNZS Manawanui after it struck the reef off the south coast of Upolu.</p>

<p>Samoan emergency services said a fire rescue team worked "from last night until this morning" to collect and treat the 75 crew members.</p>

<p>"Fortunately, no one was heavily injured and no lives were lost," Samoa Fire and Emergency Services Authority said.</p>

<p>New Zealand Commodore Shane Arndell confirmed that "the 75 crew and passengers on board HMNZS Manawanui have made it to safety in Samoa".</p>

<p>The exact cause of the wreck is not yet known.</p>

<p>The HMNZS Manawanui was used for hydrographic surveys, diving operations and marine salvage and featured a 100-tonne sea crane.</p>

<p>It had been conducting a hydrographic survey one nautical mile from shore in difficult conditions.</p>

<p>Samoan authorities had issued a marine warning for the island's south coast over the weekend.</p>

<p>Winds of up to 40 kilometres (25 miles) per hour and ocean swells of up to four metres (13 feet) were forecast around the time of the incident.</p>

<p>The New Zealand military said rescuers had battled currents and winds that pushed the life rafts and sea boats toward the reefs and "swells made the rescue effort particularly challenging."</p>

<p>The military said it was trying to "understand the implications and minimise the environmental impacts" of the wreckage.</p>

<p>The 85-metre-long ship was built in 2003 and purchased from Norway in 2019.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0edrag98_new-zealand-navy-ship_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A fire rescue team worked "from last night until this morning" to collect and treat the 75 crew members.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-threatens-of-even-stronger-retaliation-to-any-israeli-attack-6725054]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Threatens Of "Even Stronger" Retaliation To Any Israeli Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-threatens-of-even-stronger-retaliation-to-any-israeli-attack-6725054]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 23:50:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tehran's top diplomat in Damascus on Saturday threatened an "even stronger" reaction to any aggression, as Israel readied its response to an Iranian missile attack earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tehran's top diplomat in Damascus on Saturday threatened an "even stronger" reaction to any aggression, as Israel readied its response to an Iranian missile attack earlier this week.</p>

<p>"Our reaction to any attack by the Zionist regime is completely clear," Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi told reporters in the Syrian capital, where he met top officials including Tehran's ally President Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<p>"For every action, there will be a proportional and similar reaction from Iran, and even stronger," he said.</p>

<p>He spoke after an Israeli military official told AFP on condition of anonymity, as he was not authorised to discuss the issue publicly, the army was "preparing a response to the unprecedented and unlawful Iranian attack".</p>

<p>In Damascus earlier, Araghchi renewed his call for ceasefires in the Gaza Strip and in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Araghchi's visit, his first since he took office in August, comes almost a year after Iran-backed Palestinian militant group Hamas attacked Israel, triggering the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The conflict has also drawn in Iran's Lebanese ally Hezbollah, and on September 23 Israel sharply intensified its campaign against the militant group.</p>

<p>"The most important issue today is the ceasefire, especially in Lebanon and in Gaza," Araghchi said.</p>

<p>"There are initiatives in this regard. There have been consultations that we hope will be successful."</p>

<p>His meetings in Damascus follow a visit to Beirut on Friday during which he voiced support for a truce in Lebanon acceptable to Hezbollah, "simultaneously with a ceasefire in Gaza".</p>

<p>He travelled to Syria's capital by air after Lebanon said an Israeli air strike on Friday severed the main international highway linking the two countries.</p>

<p>Israel said the strike aimed to prevent the flow of weapons to Hezbollah from neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>Iran has been a staunch ally of Assad throughout the civil war that erupted in 2011 following the suppression of anti-government protests.</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, Assad's office quoted him as saying Iran's missile attack on Israel was "a strong response and taught the Zionist entity a lesson".</p>

<p>The attack came just days after an Israeli air strike in southern Beirut killed Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1kv784ko_iranian-missile-on-israel-sky_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iranian attack came just days after an Israeli air strike in southern Beirut.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-city-has-been-voted-worlds-best-for-its-unique-indoor-outdoor-way-of-life-6724240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This City Has Been Voted World's Best, Per Readers' Choice Awards 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-city-has-been-voted-worlds-best-for-its-unique-indoor-outdoor-way-of-life-6724240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 21:17:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sydney has been named the world's best city in a survey conducted by Conde Nast Traveller. The top-10 global cities rankings are part of the publication's annual Readers' Choice Awards for 2024, which launched on October 1 in the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sydney has been named the world's best city in a survey conducted by <em>Conde Nast Traveller</em>. The top-10 global cities rankings are part of the publication's annual Readers' Choice Awards for 2024, which launched on October 1 in the UK. Sydney, which ranked no. 1 with a score of 92.26, was praised by the Conde Nast Traveller UK for its "unique, indoor-outdoor way of life". Sydney beat out tourism hotspots spanning five continents, including Valencia in Spain (92.78), Singapore (92.47), Hong Kong (91.72) and Stockholm, Sweden (91.11), which ranked second to fifth place respectively.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/05/world-news/sydney-ranked-as-best-city-in-the-world-second-behind-singapore-in-friendliest-in-new-list/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post</em></a>, Sydney was also named the world's second-most friendly city, with a score of 93.85, behind Singapore, with 94.84 points, while Sydney hotel The Fullerton was crowned the best hotel in Australasia.</p>

<p>Conde Nast Traveler US also unveiled its Readers' Choice Awards this week, with Sydney placing third in the US awards list of the best cities in the world, describing it as "an ideal getaway no matter the season". Australian hotel Ritz-Carlton Melbourne was named the best hotel in Australia and New Zealand for 2024.</p>

<p>The UK and US Readers' Choice Awards winners were chosen based on the votes of more than half a million survey respondents, the <em>Post </em>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If you've experienced a snippet of life Down Under, you've probably fallen hard for the unique, indoor-outdoor way of life the Aussies embrace so well," Traveller said about Sydney.</p>

<p>Moreover, the publication also had readers vote on their favourite airlines with Air New Zealand coming first, followed by Singapore Airlines, Qatar Airways, Emirates and British Airways.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-couple-takes-31-trips-to-disney-world-after-stealing-over-rs-4-crore-from-government-6722941">US Couple Takes 31 Trips To Disney World After Stealing Over Rs 4 Crore From Government</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, in September, Sydney was also named Oceania's Leading City Destination in the World Travel Awards 2024.</p>

<p>With results like that, you'd think Sydney was in the midst of an international tourism boom. However, according to the Post, the reality is somewhat different. According to the most recent International Visitor Survey data from Tourism Research Australia, Sydney welcomed only 3,446,000 foreign visitors in June, a figure still 16 per cent below the same period in 2019.</p>

<p>But John O'Sullivan, chief executive of Experience Co and former Tourism Australia managing director, told the Sydney Morning Herald, that the stellar awards results could go a long way to putting Sydney on the radar of high-value international travellers - that is, those likely to spend more, stay longer and travel further within Australia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dukptafo_sydney-generic_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sydney was also named the world's second-most friendly city.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-detained-in-brussels-for-blocking-road-during-protest-6724092]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greta Thunberg Detained In Brussels For Blocking Road During Protest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-detained-in-brussels-for-blocking-road-during-protest-6724092]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 20:53:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Climate activist Greta Thunberg was among dozens of protesters detained Saturday for blocking a road in the Belgian capital at a demonstration against fossil fuel subsidies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate activist Greta Thunberg was among dozens of protesters detained Saturday for blocking a road in the Belgian capital at a demonstration against fossil fuel subsidies.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist saw the iconic Swede -- who has previously been detained for civil disobedience at protests in various countries -- carried away by police after refusing to leave a sit-in.</p>

<p>Thunberg, 21, was part of a smaller group of demonstrators who broke away from a march organised by the United for Climate Justice movement that began outside the European Parliament.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The rally was calling for the European Union -- headquartered in Brussels -- to end subsidies for fossil fuels to achieve its ambitious goal of making the continent carbon neutral by 2050.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This will not happen without an immediate phase-out of fossil fuel subsidies," climate activists, scientists and economists wrote in an open letter to EU leaders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Until these necessary changes occur, people will continue to take to the streets to make our voices heard and hold you accountable."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/up9ir4u_greta-thunberg_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rally was calling for the European Union to end subsidies on Fossil Fuels.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasrallahs-potential-successor-out-of-contact-after-israeli-strikes-report-6723933]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Heir Apparent Out Of Contact After Israeli Air Strikes: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasrallahs-potential-successor-out-of-contact-after-israeli-strikes-report-6723933]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 20:27:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The potential successor to slain Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been out of contact since Friday, a Lebanese security source said on Saturday, after an Israeli airstrike that is reported to have targeted him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The potential successor to Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been out of contact since Friday, a Lebanese security source told Reuters on Saturday, after an Israeli airstrike that is reported to have targeted him.</p>

<p>In its campaign against the Iran-backed Lebanese group, Israel carried out a large strike on Beirut's southern suburbs late on Thursday that Axios cited three Israeli officials as saying targeted Hashem Safieddine in an underground bunker.</p>

<p>The Lebanese security source and two other Lebanese security sources said that ongoing Israeli strikes on Beirut's southern suburb - known as Dahiyeh - since Friday have kept rescue workers from scouring the site of the attack.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has made no comment so far on Safieddine since the attack.</p>

<p>Israeli Lieutenant Colonel Nadav Shoshani said on Friday the military was still assessing the Thursday night airstrikes, which he said targeted Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters.</p>

<p>The loss of Nasrallah's rumoured successor would be yet another blow to Hezbollah and its patron Iran. Israeli strikes across the region in the past year, sharply accelerated in the past few weeks, have decimated Hezbollah's leadership.</p>

<p>Israel expanded its conflict in Lebanon on Saturday with its first strike in the northern city of Tripoli, a Lebanese security official said, after more bombs hit Beirut suburbs and Israeli troops launched raids in the south.</p>

<p>Israel has begun an intense bombing campaign in Lebanon and sent troops across the border in recent weeks after nearly a year of exchanging fire with Hezbollah. Fighting had previously been mostly limited to the Israel-Lebanon border area, taking place in parallel to Israel's year-old war in Gaza against Palestinian group Hamas.</p>

<p>Israel says it aims to allow the safe return of tens of thousands of citizens to their homes in northern Israel, bombarded by Hezbollah since Oct.8 last year.</p>

<p>The Israeli attacks have eliminated much of Hezbollah's senior military leadership, including Secretary General Nasrallah in an air attack on Sept. 27.</p>

<p>The Israeli assault has also killed hundreds of ordinary Lebanese, including rescue workers, Lebanese officials say, and forced 1.2 million people - almost a quarter of the population - to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The Lebanese security official told Reuters that Saturday's strike on a Palestinian refugee camp in Tripoli killed a member of Hamas, his wife and two children. Media affiliated with the Palestinian group also said the strike killed a leader of its armed wing.</p>

<p>The Israeli military did not immediately comment on the strike on Tripoli, a Sunni Muslim-majority port city that its warplanes also targeted during a 2006 war with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israel has meanwhile staged nightly bombardment of Dahiyeh, once a bustling and densely populated area of Beirut and a stronghold for Hezbollah.</p>

<p>On Saturday, smoke billowed over Dahiyeh, large parts of which have been reduced to rubble sending residents fleeing to other parts of Beirut or of Lebanon.</p>

<p>In northern Israel, air raid sirens sent people running for their shelters amid rocket fire from Lebanon.</p>

<p>ISRAEL WEIGHS OPTIONS FOR IRAN</p>

<p>The violence comes as the anniversary approaches of Hamas' attack on southern Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, which killed 1,200 people and in which about 250 were taken as hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on Gaza has killed nearly 42,000 Palestinians, according to Gaza's health ministry, and displaced nearly all of the enclave's population of 2.3 million.</p>

<p>Iran, which backs both Hezbollah and Hamas, and which has lost key commanders of its elite Revolutionary Guards Corps to Israeli air strikes in Syria this year, launched a salvo of ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday. The strikes did little damage.</p>

<p>Israel has been weighing options in its response to Iran's attack.</p>

<p>Oil prices have risen on the possibility of an attack on Iran's oil facilities as Israel pursues its goals of pushing back Hezbollah militants in Lebanon and eliminating their Hamas allies in Gaza.</p>

<p>U.S. President Joe Biden on Friday urged Israel to consider alternatives to striking Iranian oil fields, adding that he thinks Israel has not yet concluded how to respond to Iran.</p>

<p>Israeli news website Ynet reported that the top U.S. general for the Middle East, Army General Michael Kurilla, is headed for Israel in the coming day. Israeli and U.S. officials were not immediately reachable for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rj463n3_hashem-safieddine_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The loss of Nasrallah's rumoured successor would be yet another blow to Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-on-pm-narendra-modis-vladimir-putin-volodymyr-zelensky-meetings-6723587]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Beginning Of Communication...": S Jaishankar On PM's Putin, Zelensky Meets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-on-pm-narendra-modis-vladimir-putin-volodymyr-zelensky-meetings-6723587]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 19:29:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi's meetings with the top leaders of Russia and Ukraine were "beginnings of a communication process" between two countries engaged in a serious conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi's meetings with the top leaders of Russia and Ukraine were "beginnings of a communication process" between two countries engaged in a serious conflict that has had enormous consequences, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said on Saturday.</p>

<p>In an interactive session at The Conclave 2024 organised by news channel Pratidin Time, Mr Jaishankar said Prime Minister Modi was one of the very few world leaders who has the "ability" to speak to both the leaders, who "trust" him.</p>

<p>"What are we trying to do? You don't necessarily have to mediate... sometimes you have to communicate. We are actually, simultaneously talking to two countries who are having a conflict," he said to a question on India's role in "mediation" in the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said Prime Minister Modi has had at least three meetings with Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky and one meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>He said National Security Adviser Ajit Doval also met Putin in September to brief him about PM Modi's discussions with Zelensky.</p>

<p>"Obviously that talk is centered around what the conflict is all about. It was necessary for NSA Doval to go to Russia so that the Russians know what the Prime Minister spoke to Zelensky," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>He said the Russia-Ukraine conflict has entered the third year and has had enormous human cost and huge economic consequences across the world.</p>

<p>"You can either watch this conflict and say none of us could do anything about it and say it will end when it ends. Or you can say I am one of the few countries or in our case one of the few prime ministers who has the ability to speak there and both parties trust him and see whether out of these conversations something moves," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>"I think these are the beginnings of a communication process. Where it will lead, I have not quite reached that point," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said the world leaders were supportive of what India was doing.</p>

<p>"People are very happy today. They say you have a person like PM Modi who has the ability to go to both capitals and have that kind of communication," he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ch4htg18_modi-zelensky_625x300_24_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar said the world leaders were supportive of what India was doing. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-activists-pretend-to-drown-themselves-in-oil-outside-un-agency-in-london-6723173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Protesters Pretend To Drown Themselves In Oil In London]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-activists-pretend-to-drown-themselves-in-oil-outside-un-agency-in-london-6723173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 18:22:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ocean Rebellion campaigners recently pretended to drown themselves in oil and gas in a protest outside a United Nations agency in London.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate protesters have become a daily sight on London's streets, undeterred by the honking horns of irate motorists, personal insults and even arrests. This time, Ocean Rebellion campaigners pretended to drown themselves in oil and gas in a protest outside a United Nations agency in London. The climate change activists staged the frightening demonstration on the steps of the International Maritime Organisation, the UN agency responsible for regulating maritime transport. "A drowning ocean goddess symbolizes the dire threat LNG poses to our oceans," the group wrote on X while sharing pictures of the stunt show.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The images show, one activist, dressed as an "ocean goddess", donning a fishbowl on her head filled with black liquid as though she was drowning. She could be seen screaming as the liquid engulfed her face before it quickly drained from the bowl. Other protesters around her were seen wearing gas masks and brandishing petrol pumps with flames spouting out of them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Liquid Natural Gas (LNG) is not a "green" solution. Methane leaks from LNG ships are 80x more damaging than CO2. The IMO must wake up to this reality before it's too late," Ocean Rebellion wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">2/5 Liquid Natural Gas (LNG) is not a "green" solution. Methane leaks from LNG ships are 80x more damaging than CO2. The IMO must wake up to this reality before it's too late. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SayNoToLNG?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SayNoToLNG</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ClimateCrisis?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ClimateCrisis</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/oceanrebellion?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@OceanRebellion</a> <a href="https://t.co/8tFqfqTvV4">pic.twitter.com/8tFqfqTvV4</a></p>
— Ocean Rebellion (@oceanrebellion) <a href="https://twitter.com/oceanrebellion/status/1842133327785914735?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/04/world-news/climate-change-activists-drown-themselves-with-oil-gas-and-flames-in-nightmarish-protest/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post</em></a>, the protest took place on Friday, the final day of meetings for the UN agency's Maritime Environment Protection Committee, which had convened to discuss reducing greenhouse gas emissions from ships. The protesters accused the agency of manipulating the fossil fuel industry and failing to protect the ocean.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The IMO is failing to protect our oceans. LNG is a dirty fuel disguised as clean. We demand transparency and accountability. Stop listening to fossil fuel lobbyists, start protecting our planet!" the group wrote on the microblogging site.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/antarctica-turning-green-at-an-alarming-rate-says-study-6715700">Antarctica Turning Green At An Alarming Rate, Says Study</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, climate change activists have been in the news with their high-profile direct-action protests, such as disrupting Premier League Football matches, and sporting events, to publicise their cause. They have thrown tomato soup on famous paintings and glued themselves to picture frames in galleries. They want the government to end all new oil and gas exploration and have promised not to let up in its protests until it does so.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago, three activists from Just Stop Oil threw soup at two of Vincent van Gogh's "Sunflowers" paintings at London's National Gallery. This incident occurred just hours after two other members of the protest group were sentenced to prison for a similar act in 2022.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/71sb3kh8_climate-change-activists-_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protest took place on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emirates-bans-pagers-walkie-talkies-onboard-flights-after-lebanon-blasts-6722986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Emirates Bans Pagers, Walkie-Talkies Onboard Flights After Lebanon Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emirates-bans-pagers-walkie-talkies-onboard-flights-after-lebanon-blasts-6722986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 05 Oct 2024 17:51:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dubai's Emirates Airlines has banned passengers from carrying pagers and walkie-talkies on its flights, following last month's attacks on Lebanese group Hezbollah involving communication devices that exploded.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dubai's Emirates Airlines has banned passengers from carrying pagers and walkie-talkies on its flights, following last month's attacks on Lebanese group Hezbollah involving communication devices that exploded.</p>

<p>"All passengers traveling to, from, or via Dubai are prohibited from transporting pagers and walkie-talkies in checked or cabin baggage," the airline said in a statement on its website on Friday. It added that any prohibited items found will be confiscated by Dubai Police as part of heightened security measures.</p>

<p>In the deadly September attacks, thousands of booby-trapped Hezbollah pagers and hundreds of radios exploded - attacks that were widely blamed on Israel but which it has not claimed.</p>

<p>The Middle East's largest airline also announced that flights to Iraq and Iran will remain suspended until Tuesday, while services to Jordan will resume on Sunday.</p>

<p>Flights to Lebanon will remain suspended until Oct. 15 due to escalating Israeli attacks against Iran-backed Hezbollah, including strikes near Beirut's airport.</p>

<p>Several other airlines have also suspended flights to Beirut and other regional airports amid heightened tensions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/bnku9h1_emirates_625x300_10_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Middle East's largest airline also announced that flights to Iraq and Iran will remain suspended.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>