<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 09:47:34 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shooting-an-assassination-attempt-fbi-after-donald-trump-injured-in-shooting-6101786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["An Assassination Attempt": FBI After Trump Injured In Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shooting-an-assassination-attempt-fbi-after-donald-trump-injured-in-shooting-6101786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 09:47:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The shooting that wounded Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Saturday was an assassination attempt, the FBI confirmed in a late night press conference.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The shooting that wounded Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Saturday was an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-long-history-of-shootings-in-us-presidential-politics-6101507">assassination attempt</a>, the FBI confirmed in a late night press conference.</p>

<p>"This evening we had what we are calling an assassination attempt against our former president Donald Trump," Special Agent Kevin Rojek told reporters in Butler, Pennsylvania, where Trump was holding a rally when shots rang out.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jv1gl7do_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-bloodied-defiant-image-after-shooting-pumps-up-his-voter-base-6101742]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Bloodied, Defiant Image After Shooting Pumps Up His Voter Base]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-bloodied-defiant-image-after-shooting-pumps-up-his-voter-base-6101742]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 09:35:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A moment of terrifying political violence at a Pennsylvania rally Saturday instantly turned into a piece of Donald Trump iconography that's likely to turbocharge his presidential bid.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A moment of terrifying political violence at a Pennsylvania rally Saturday instantly turned into a piece of Donald Trump iconography that's likely to turbocharge his presidential bid.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Images of a defiant Trump - with his fist raised over his head and his bloody right ear, as Secret Service agents surround him and the American flag waving in the background - are blazing across social media and television.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Extraordinary.<br />
<br />
God bless President Trump. <a href="https://t.co/GEipCSwl6G">pic.twitter.com/GEipCSwl6G</a></p>
— Ted Cruz (@tedcruz) <a href="https://twitter.com/tedcruz/status/1812257101089235195?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 13, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>His supporters, many of whom viewed him as a movement figure and martyr long before the violence on Saturday, seized on the photos as a metaphor for the former president's resiliency.</p>

<p>A bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear, Trump said. The shooter is dead, as is a bystander, according to the Butler County district attorney.</p>

<p>Several vice presidential hopefuls and senators voiced their support and shared images from the scene, while billionaire Elon Musk posted a message on X that said: "I fully endorse President Trump and hope for his rapid recovery."</p>

<p>David Urban, an informal Trump adviser and lobbyist who helped to run his operation in Pennsylvania in 2016, said he expects the shooting to unify Americans behind Trump.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is a fighter," Urban said. "That photo will be iconic."</p>

<p>Political Division<br />
The gunfire at the rally speaks to the divisiveness and contentiousness of this rematch of the 2020 presidential contest between Trump and President Joe Biden, as well as a looming sense of political violence that now permeates through the political discourse.</p>

<p>"I think we're all shocked," said 22-year-old Cooper Waldron, a registered Republican and Trump supporter from East Peoria, Illinois. "You never expect something like that to happen in an election in the US."</p>

<p>Half of swing state voters already said they feared violence around the election in a Bloomberg/Morning Consult poll taken in May.</p>

<p>David McCormick, a Republican candidate for Senate in Pennsylvania, was at the rally and near Trump when he was shot. Two people sitting behind him at the rally were also shot, according to a person familiar with the matter, bringing the specter of violence into not just a presidential campaign, but a down ballot campaign as well.</p>

<p>Several Republican lawmakers pinned blame Saturday for the shooting on the rhetoric of their political opponents, peppering social media with fiery statements and making unsubstantiated claims that Democrats incited the violence.</p>

<p>Prominent Democrats, including President Biden, rallied around Trump. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"I'm grateful to hear that he's safe and doing well," Biden said Saturday night. "There's no place for this kind of violence in America. We must unite as one nation to condemn it."</p>

<p>Many polls show Trump with a consistent lead over Biden in both national and swing state polling. Biden's disastrous debate performance last month was considered - by both sides - to have helped Trump's bid.</p>

<p>In the coming week, Trump is slated to both announce his pick for vice president and headline the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>A huge chunk of the Trump campaign, including top advisers, were in Milwaukee at the time of shooting. It was unclear how the shooting would affect the security in Milwaukee, where thousands of Republicans are gathering for their once-every-four-years political convention</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0clom45s_donald-trump-bloomberg_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-elon-musk-fully-endorses-donald-trump-after-rally-shooting-6101736]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk "Fully" Endorses Donald Trump After Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-elon-musk-fully-endorses-donald-trump-after-rally-shooting-6101736]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 09:34:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tech billionaire Elon Musk said today he "fully" endorses Donald Trump after the Republican presidential candidate was shot at a campaign rally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech billionaire Elon Musk said today he "fully" endorses Donald Trump after the Republican presidential candidate was shot at a campaign rally.</p>

<p>"I fully endorse President Trump and hope for his rapid recovery," he wrote on X - which he owns - as he shared a video of Trump pumping his fist while being escorted away by Secret Service officials.</p>

<p>"Last time America had a candidate this tough was Theodore Roosevelt," he said in another post.</p>

<p>Shots were fired during the rally speech by Donald Trump early this morning, in an incident that investigators are treating as a possible assassination attempt on the former president.</p>

<p>The shooting took place shortly after Trump took the stage at his final campaign rally. 78-year-old Trump grimaced and clutched a hand to his right ear, with blood soon visible across his face.</p>

<p>He turned back to the crowd and repeatedly raised his fist as the security officials surrounded him to escort him off the stage, in what is set to become an iconic image.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden led the condemnation after his election rival Donald Trump was wounded in an apparent assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday, in violence that also left a bystander dead.</p>

<p>"There's no place in America for this kind of violence. It's sick. It's sick. It's one of the reasons why we have to unite this country... We cannot be like this, we cannot condone this," President Joe Biden said.</p>

<p>Biden's former boss, Barack Obama, echoed his words in a statement, saying there was "absolutely no place for political violence in our democracy."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/fpd88p5s_elon-musk-donald-trump_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The shooting took place shortly after Donald Trump took the stage]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-possible-security-lapses-in-focus-after-trump-injured-in-rally-shooting-6101622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Possible Security Lapses In Focus After Trump Injured In Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-possible-security-lapses-in-focus-after-trump-injured-in-rally-shooting-6101622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 09:04:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While information about the incident is still sparse, at least one person interviewed by the BBC said he had tried to alert police and the US Secret Service, to no avail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The attack on Donald Trump raised questions about how the Republican presidential candidate is protected on the campaign trail and what caused the apparent security lapses at Saturday's rally.</p>

<p>While information about the incident is still sparse, at least one person interviewed by the BBC said he had tried to alert police and the US Secret Service, to no avail, to an apparent sniper climbing onto a nearby roof outside the security perimeter of the rally venue in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>As a former president and the Republican presidential candidate, Trump is protected primarily by the Secret Service.</p>

<p>During most of Trump's campaign stops, local police aid the Secret Service in securing the venue. Agents from other agencies within the Department of Homeland Security, such as the Transportation Security Administration, occasionally help.</p>

<p>It is no easy task. Many Trump rallies feature thousands of audience members, take place in the open air and last for hours.</p>

<p>Before the event, agents scan the venue for bombs or other threats, and Trump invariably arrives in a fortified motorcade.</p>

<p>Law enforcement officials typically put up barriers as a perimeter, and require all attendees to go through a metal detector to enter the venue. Armed protective agents search all attendees' bags and even wallets. Many rallygoers are patted down by hand.</p>

<p>Saturday's attack, however, appeared to have been committed by a gunman located outside the secured perimeter, according to initial media reports.</p>

<p>A local resident who was present at the Saturday event and asked to remain anonymous, said he saw what appeared to be two Secret Service agents perched on a nearby roof ahead of the event. He said the agents had been scanning the area with binoculars beforehand.</p>

<p>"They kept looking over to the left behind the event, before Trump came on stage. They seemed very focused on that area," said the attendee.</p>

<p>The Secret Service said shortly after the shooting that it has begun an investigation and briefed Democratic President Joe Biden, though the agency did not immediately respond to additional requests for comment regarding its protocols.</p>

<p>The Pennsylvania State Police referred questions to the Secret Service, which did not immediately respond.</p>

<p>In the moments after Trump was injured, the former president was quickly surrounded by Secret Service personnel who formed a human shield, while heavily armed agents in body armor and toting rifles also took to the stage and appeared to scan the area for threats.</p>

<p>Trump was whisked by the agents to a black SUV, and taken to a local hospital, according to the campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eraokem_donald-trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is protected primarily by the Secret Service]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-witness-recounts-how-man-next-to-him-was-shot-dead-6101578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Witness Recounts How Man Next To Him Was Shot Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-witness-recounts-how-man-next-to-him-was-shot-dead-6101578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 08:51:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A witness to Saturday's shooting at a Donald Trump rally told how a man next to him was shot dead during the apparent assassination attempt on the Republican presidential candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A witness to Saturday's shooting at a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-pierced-upper-part-of-my-right-ear-donald-trump-on-shooting-at-rally-6101088#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Donald Trump rally</a> told how a man next to him was shot dead during the apparent assassination attempt on the Republican presidential candidate.</p>

<p>"I heard several gunshots. The man beside me suffered a gunshot to the head, was instantly killed (and) fell to the bottom of the bleachers. Another woman looked like she got hit in the forearm or hand," the man, whose name was only given as Joseph, told NBC News.</p>

<p>He said it seemed the victim was "in the way of the shots between whoever was shooting the gun and the president."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photo-shows-bullet-inches-from-donald-trumps-face-at-us-rally-6101307#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Trump said he was hit in the ear</a> but was not seriously injured by the gunman, who was killed after the incident. Two other spectators were critically injured, the Secret Service said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/66dl2pf8_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-long-history-of-shootings-in-us-presidential-politics-6101507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Long History Of Shootings In US Presidential Politics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-long-history-of-shootings-in-us-presidential-politics-6101507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 08:34:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shots were fired during a rally speech by Donald Trump, in an incident that investigators are treating as a possible assassination attempt on the former president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shots were fired during a rally speech by Donald Trump, in an incident that investigators are treating as a possible assassination attempt on the former president.</p>

<p>Including Abraham Lincoln and JFK, here are some notable examples of shootings involving US presidents or presidential candidates:</p>

<p><strong>- Ronald Reagan (1981) -</strong></p>

<p>President Reagan was shot and seriously wounded as he left an event at the Hilton hotel in Washington. The attacker was John Hinckley Jr, who was granted unconditional release in 2022.</p>

<p>Reagan spent twelve days in the hospital. The incident boosted Reagan's popularity, as he displayed humor and resilience during his recovery.</p>

<p><strong>- Gerald Ford (1975) -</strong></p>

<p>President Ford was left unscathed in two separate assassination attempts by women in September 1975, both in California and within a span of just 17 days.</p>

<p><strong>- George Wallace (1972) -</strong></p>

<p>While campaigning for the Democratic presidential nomination, Wallace was shot four times and paralyzed for life at a shopping mall in Laurel, Maryland.</p>

<p>The assassination attempt on Wallace, who was known for his segregationist views and populist appeal, highlighted the ongoing political tensions in the US and potential for domestic violence in the Vietnam war era.</p>

<p><strong>- Robert F. Kennedy (1968) -</strong></p>

<p>President John F. Kennedy's brother Robert, who was running for the Democratic presidential nomination, was shot and killed at the Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles, California.</p>

<p>The assassination had a profound impact on the 1968 presidential race and occurred just two months after the killing of civil rights leader Martin Luther King Jr, adding to the political turmoil of the late 1960s.</p>

<p><strong>- John F. Kennedy (1963) -</strong></p>

<p>Riding in his motorcade with his wife Jackie, President Kennedy was assassinated in Dallas, Texas by Lee Harvey Oswald.</p>

<p>The Warren Commission investigating the assassination concluded in 1964 that Lee Harvey Oswald, a former marine who had lived in the Soviet Union, had acted alone.</p>

<p>Many Americans believe the death of JFK began a more violent period in US politics and society, with the Vietnam War build up and the civil rights struggle as a backdrop.</p>

<p><strong>- Franklin D. Roosevelt (1933) -</strong></p>

<p>As president-elect, FDR was the target of an assassination attempt in Miami, Florida. He was unharmed, but Chicago Mayor Anton Cermak was killed in the attack.</p>

<p><strong>- Theodore Roosevelt (1912) -</strong></p>

<p>Like Trump, Teddy Roosevelt was running for the White House as a former president when he was shot in Milwaukee, Wisconsin.</p>

<p>The bullet, which remained lodged in his chest for the rest of his life, was slowed by the folded 50-page speech and steel eyeglass case in his breast pocket.</p>

<p>Famously, Roosevelt decided to deliver his scheduled speech despite being shot.</p>

<p><strong>- William McKinley (1901) </strong>-</p>

<p>President McKinley was shot and killed by anarchist Leon Czolgosz in Buffalo, New York.</p>

<p><strong>- Abraham Lincoln (1865) -</strong></p>

<p>Lincoln was assassinated by John Wilkes Booth, a well-known actor and Confederate sympathizer, while watching a play called "Our American Cousin" at Ford's Theater in Washington.</p>

<p>Booth's attack, just days after the Confederate surrender in the Civil War, was part of a larger plot that included attempts to assassinate Vice President Andrew Johnson and Secretary of State William Seward.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e4j4trvg_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was shot at a campaign rally today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-condemns-attack-on-friend-trump-says-violence-has-no-place-in-politics-6101470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Violence Has No Place In Politics": PM Condemns Attack On "Friend" Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-condemns-attack-on-friend-trump-says-violence-has-no-place-in-politics-6101470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 08:24:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi Condemns Attack On "Friend' Trump, Says "Violence Has No Place In Politics"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Violence and no place in politics and democracies, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said this morning, expressing concern over the assassination attempt on former US President Donald Trump at a poll rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"Deeply concerned by the attack on my friend, former President Donald Trump. Strongly condemn the incident. Violence has no place in politics and democracies. Wish him speedy recovery," Prime Minister Modi posted on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Deeply concerned by the attack on my friend, former President Donald Trump. Strongly condemn the incident. Violence has no place in politics and democracies. Wish him speedy recovery.<br />
<br />
Our thoughts and prayers are with the family of the deceased, those injured and the American…</p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1812315611940176344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Our thoughts and prayers are with the family of the deceased, those injured and the American people," he added.</p>

<p>Rahul Gandhi, Congress MP and Leader of the Opposition in Lok Sabha, said he is "deeply concerned" by the assassination attempt.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am deeply concerned by the assassination attempt on former US President Donald Trump.<br />
<br />
Such acts must be condemned in the strongest possible terms.<br />
<br />
Wishing him a swift and complete recovery.</p>
— Rahul Gandhi (@RahulGandhi) <a href="https://twitter.com/RahulGandhi/status/1812328028640592177?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"I am deeply concerned by the assassination attempt on former US President Donald Trump. Such acts must be condemned in the strongest possible terms. Wishing him a swift and complete recovery," he said on X.</p>

<p>Trump was shot at while he was speaking at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania's Butler on Saturday. The 78-year-old has said the bullet pierced his right ear. Visuals from the rally showed security officials rushing him off the state, blood across his face. A bystander was killed and two others critically injured as the shooter fired multiple rounds. He was gunned down by the security personnel, but is yet to be identified.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, who faces Trump in the US election due in November, strongly condemned the incident and also spoke to his arch rival after the shooting.</p>

<p>"There's no place in America for this kind of violence. It's sick. It's sick. It's one of the reasons why we have to unite this country... We cannot be like this, we cannot condone this," Biden told reporters in an emergency briefing after the attack on Trump.</p>

<p>"The idea that there's political violence, or violence in America like this, is just unheard of. It's just not appropriate. Everybody, everybody must condemn it. Everybody," Biden said.</p>

<p>"I have been briefed on the shooting at Donald Trump's rally in Pennsylvania. I'm grateful to hear that he's safe and doing well. I'm praying for him and his family and for all those who were at the rally, as we await further information.</p>

<p>Jill and I are grateful to the Secret Service for getting him to safety. There's no place for this kind of violence in America. We must unite as one nation to condemn it," Biden said in a post on X.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-02/76a2lc1g_narendra-modi-donald-trump-twitter_625x300_26_February_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shooting-ivanka-trump-thank-you-note-for-secret-service-after-shooting-at-rally-6101442]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ivanka Trump's 'Thank You' Note For Secret Service After Shooting At Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shooting-ivanka-trump-thank-you-note-for-secret-service-after-shooting-at-rally-6101442]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 08:18:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, former US president, was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination attempt by a gunman at a rally in Pennsylvania today, a shocking incident that will fuel fears of instability ahead of the 2024 US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, former US president, was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination attempt by a gunman at a rally in Pennsylvania today, a shocking incident that will fuel fears of instability ahead of the 2024 US presidential election.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Republican candidate was addressing a fervent crowd when a gunman opened fire, striking Trump in the ear. Blood was visible on his face as US Secret Service swiftly intervened, whisking him offstage to safety.</p>

<p>Ivanka Trump, daughter of the former president, conveyed gratitude for the outpouring of support and concern following the violent incident. In a statement released shortly after the shooting, she expressed deep appreciation for the swift actions of the Secret Service and law enforcement, underscoring their role in averting further tragedy.</p>

<p>"Thank you for your love and prayers for my father and for the other victims of today's senseless violence in Butler, Pennsylvania," Ivanka Trump's statement read. "I am grateful to the Secret Service and all the other law enforcement officers for their quick and decisive actions today. I continue to pray for our country. I love you Dad, today and always."</p>

<p>Thousands of Trump supporters were attending the rally when the shooting, which was captured live on news channels, happened.&nbsp; As the bullet hit his ears, the former president was seen ducking with the secret service surrounding him. He could be heard making a few comments on an audio feed from the stage.&nbsp; Trump said, “Let me get my shoes,” as he was escorted to the safe place. He was seen pumping his fist to the public.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/04v3crnc_ivanka-trump-getty_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-secret-service-snipers-in-action-after-shots-fired-at-donald-trump-6101405]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Secret Service, Snipers In Action After Shots Fired At Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-secret-service-snipers-in-action-after-shots-fired-at-donald-trump-6101405]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 08:02:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination attempt by a gunman at a campaign rally today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination attempt by a gunman at a campaign rally today.</p>

<p>The Secret Service said that the apparent assassination attempt on Donald Trump involved "multiple shots (fired) toward the stage from an elevated position outside the rally venue.</p>

<p>A video has now emerged showing snipers and Secret Service officials in action as shots were fired at Donald Trump.</p>

<p>As the Secret Service officials hear the gunshots, they swarm onto the podium, surround the Republican candidate to escort him off the stage.</p>

<p>Two armed officials were also seen aiming at the gunman after the shots rang out at the rally.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Footage showing the Reaction of the U.S. Secret Service Counter-Sniper Team who Eliminated the Shooter, the Moment that Shots rang out at the Trump Campaign Rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. <a href="https://t.co/1ni7L1Makp">pic.twitter.com/1ni7L1Makp</a></p>
— OSINTdefender (@sentdefender) <a href="https://twitter.com/sentdefender/status/1812300234241757274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The shooter was later captured and neutralised by the Security Service officials.&nbsp;The shooter's identity and motive were not immediately clear.</p>

<p>The shooting took place shortly after Trump took the stage at his final campaign rally. 78-year-old Trump grimaced and clutched a hand to his right ear, with blood soon visible across his face.</p>

<p>He turned back to the crowd and repeatedly raised his fist as the security officials surrounded him, in what is set to become an iconic image.</p>

<p>"I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear," Donald Trump later posted on Truth Social.</p>

<p>"I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin," Trump said.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aur8tvk_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump Rally Shooting: The shooter was later captured and neutralised]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-injured-in-shooting-but-doing-well-says-his-campaign-6101371]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Injured In Shooting But "Doing Well", Says His Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-injured-in-shooting-but-doing-well-says-his-campaign-6101371]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 07:54:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump, who survived an assassination attempt that happened during his election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday, is "doing well", his campaign said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump, who survived an assassination attempt that happened during his election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday, is “doing well”, his campaign said.</p>

<p>Trump got injured during his election rally when at about 6.15 pm, a suspected shooter fired multiple shots toward the stage from an elevated position outside of the rally venue in Butler, the US Secret Service said.</p>

<p>Law enforcement officials said the US Secret Service shot dead the suspected shooter at the election venue.&nbsp; “As was communicated earlier this evening, President Trump is doing well and grateful to law enforcement and first responders for their fast action,” his campaign said.&nbsp;&nbsp; The former president was hit with a bullet that pierced the upper part of his right ear.</p>

<p>“President Trump looks forward to joining you all in Milwaukee as we proceed with our convention to nominate him to serve as the 47th President of the United States. As our party's nominee, President Trump will continue to share his vision to Make America Great Again,” his campaign said.</p>

<p>Thousands of Trump supporters were attending the rally when the shooting, which was captured live on news channels, happened.&nbsp; As the bullet hit his ears, the former president was seen ducking with the secret service surrounding him. He could be heard making a few comments on an audio feed from the stage.&nbsp; Trump said, “Let me get my shoes,” as he was escorted to the safe place. He was seen pumping his fist to the public.</p>

<p>The incident happened two days before the start of the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, where Trump will formally become the party's nominee.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, Vice President Kamala Harris and former presidents, Barack Obama, George W Bush and Bill Clinton have condemned the attack.</p>

<p>“US Secret Service personnel neutralised the shooter, who is now deceased. The US Secret Service quickly responded with protective measures and Former President Trump is safe,” Anthony Guglielmi, Secret Service spokesperson said in a statement.</p>

<p>“One spectator was killed, and two spectators were critically injured. This incident is currently under investigation. and the Secret Service has notified the FBI,” he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/t8vi6jio_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shooting-news-pics-show-chaos-at-donald-trump-rally-as-bullets-flew-by-6101340]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pics Show Chaos, Panic At Trump Rally As Bullets Flew By]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shooting-news-pics-show-chaos-at-donald-trump-rally-as-bullets-flew-by-6101340]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 07:48:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination attempt by a gunman at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania today.The gunman and a spectator have been killed and two others critically injured.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-pierced-upper-part-of-my-right-ear-donald-trump-on-shooting-at-rally-6101088" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> was hit in the ear in an apparent assassination bid by a gunman at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania today.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The unidentified gunman and a spectator have been killed and two others "critically" injured, officials said.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Republican presidential candidate, whose team said he was "safe", was attacked when he had just started his speech.</p>

<p>As the shots rang out, he was seen grabbing his right ear with his right hand, with blood smeared across his face.<br />
<br />
<img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/11s9prdo_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c8drk4j_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: REUTERS</span></p>
</div>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photo-shows-bullet-inches-from-donald-trumps-face-at-us-rally-6101307" target="_blank">Trump</a>&nbsp;then&nbsp;dropped to his knees behind the podium to take cover.</p>

<p>The agents of the Secret Service, a law enforcement agency that protects US political leaders, then rushed to the stage, yelling “get down” and forming a circle around him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They then escorted him roughly off the stage to a nearby vehicle.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opkp8i88_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Bloomberg</span></p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o9vstd5o_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>As <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-evacuated-from-pennsylvaniarally-stage-after-apparent-shots-heard-report-6100727" target="_blank">Trump was evacuated by the Secret Service agents</a>, he turned back to the crowd and repeatedly raised his fist.</p>

<p>He also mouthed words that weren't immediately discernable.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ovemrjig_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: REUTERS</span></p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jm5r3u6g_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: REUTERS</span></p>
</div>

<p>The rally descended into panic after shots were heard and screams and shouts rang out.</p>

<p>"Let me get my shoes," Trump was reportedly heard saying on microphone, as security agents helped him back to his feet.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/i4h4seeg_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g7g4eppo_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>After the chaotic and shocking incident that comes ahead of the 2024 US presidential election, Trump said, "I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear."</p>

<p>"I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin," Trump said.</p>

<p>"Much bleeding took place, so I realized then what was happening," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/oi81ft3_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was evacuated by Secret Service agents after he was hit in the ear in assassination bid]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photo-shows-bullet-inches-from-donald-trumps-face-at-us-rally-6101307]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Photo Shows Bullet Inches From Donald Trump's Face At US Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/photo-shows-bullet-inches-from-donald-trumps-face-at-us-rally-6101307]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 07:33:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump was shot at while he was addressing a campaign rally in Pennsylvania ahead of the US presidential elections. The 78-year-old leader hid behind the podium on stage as several shots rang out at the rally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-injured-in-assassination-attempt-at-rally-what-we-know-so-far-6101121">Donald Trump</a> was shot at while he was addressing a campaign rally in Pennsylvania ahead of the US presidential elections. The 78-year-old leader hid behind the podium on stage as several <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-pierced-upper-part-of-my-right-ear-donald-trump-on-shooting-at-rally-6101088">shots </a>rang out at the rally.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The leader, who was seen with blood on his right ear, was quickly swarmed by Secret Service agents who encircled the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-evacuated-from-pennsylvaniarally-stage-after-apparent-shots-heard-report-6100727">former president </a>and escorted him off stage. While being whisked off, he raised his fist to the crowd and mouthed "fight, fight".</p>

<p>In a photo, purportedly captured moments before he was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-moment-donald-trump-was-attacked-at-pennsylvania-rally-6100971">attacked</a>, a bullet can be seen whizzing past his face. The image clicked by New York Times photographer Doug Mills shows a bullet near Trump's cheek as faced the crowd while delivering his speech.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Photo by New York Times photographer Doug Mills shows bullet flying just behind Trump's head. <a href="https://t.co/0ncIBC0i1v">pic.twitter.com/0ncIBC0i1v</a></p>
— The Spectator Index (@spectatorindex) <a href="https://twitter.com/spectatorindex/status/1812293722832318726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>A witness has claimed that he saw the man who fired at Trump on the roof of a building near the event grounds. Talking to the BBC, he said that the shooter was armed with a rifle and had crawled on top of the building. "The guy crawled up the building 50 feet from us. He had a rifle," he said.</p>

<p>He said that he informed police, Secret Service about a suspicious man on a roof with a rifle. "I'm thinking to myself 'Why is Trump still speaking, why have they not pulled him off the stage'... the next thing you know, five shots ring out," he told the BBC.</p>

<p>Taking to Truth Social, a social media company owned by him, the former US president said he was "shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear." "I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin," he said.</p>

<p>The attack has united US political leaders on both sides the spectrum with Trump's rival and US President Joe Biden condemning the attack, saying there was "no place in America for this kind of violence".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/16gsphn_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-talks-on-halt-israel-not-serious-say-egyptian-sources-6101242]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Talks On Halt, Israel Not Serious, Say Egyptian Sources]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-talks-on-halt-israel-not-serious-say-egyptian-sources-6101242]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 07:11:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza ceasefire talks have been halted after three days of intense negotiations failed to produce a viable outcome, two Egyptian security sources said on Saturday, blaming Israel for lacking a genuine intent to reach agreement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza ceasefire talks have been halted after three days of intense negotiations failed to produce a viable outcome, two Egyptian security sources said on Saturday, blaming Israel for lacking a genuine intent to reach agreement.</p>

<p>The sources, who spoke to Reuters on condition of anonymity, said that the behaviour of the Israeli mediators revealed "internal discord".</p>

<p>According to the sources, the Israeli delegation would give approvals on several conditions under discussion, but then come back with amendments or introduce new conditions that risked sinking the negotiations.</p>

<p>The sources said the mediators viewed the "contradictions, delays in responses, and the introduction of new terms contrary to what was previously agreed" as signs the Israeli side viewed the talks as a formality aimed at influencing public opinion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/t86ju6k8_gaza-strike-reuters_625x300_13_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Hamas war has been going on since October 7, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/multiple-shots-came-from-elevated-position-outside-trump-rally-secret-service-6101214]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Multiple Shots Came From "Elevated Position": Secret Service As Trump Injured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/multiple-shots-came-from-elevated-position-outside-trump-rally-secret-service-6101214]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 07:08:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The apparent assassination attempt on Donald Trump involved "multiple shots (fired) toward the stage from an elevated position outside the rally venue," the US Secret Service said today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The apparent assassination attempt on Donald Trump involved "multiple shots (fired) toward the stage from an elevated position outside the rally venue," the US Secret Service said today.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"One spectator was killed, two spectators were critically injured," the agency said in a statement, adding the shooter has been killed, without giving further details.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pnpp4s08_donald-trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-us-secret-service-said-after-attack-on-trump-during-campaign-rally-6101209]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What US Secret Service Said After Attack On Trump During Campaign Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-us-secret-service-said-after-attack-on-trump-during-campaign-rally-6101209]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 07:01:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump was shot at an election rally in a possible assassination attempt just a day before the Republican Party is scheduled to begin its convention to formally declare him its nominee for the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump was shot at an election rally in a possible assassination attempt just a day before the Republican Party is scheduled to begin its convention to formally declare him its nominee for the White House.</p>

<p>Trump touched the right side of his face after what seemed like the first two shots and dropped to the ground. Secret Service agents threw themselves on him to protect him. When they rose, the agents had him inside a circle.</p>

<p>"During former President Trump's campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, on the evening of July 13 at around 6:15 p.m., a suspected shooter fired multiple shots toward the stage from an elevated position outside of the rally venue. US Secret Service personnel neutralised the shooter, who is now deceased. The US Secret Service quickly responded with protective measures and the former President is safe and being evaluated. One spectator was killed, and two spectators were critically injured. The incident is currently under investigation and the Secret Service has formally notified the Federal Bureau of Investigation,"&nbsp;the Secret Service said in a statement:</p>

<p>The former President appeared to be bleeding on the right side of the face. He raised a fist in the air as he was led away. He was taken to a local medical facility for treatment.</p>

<p>"I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear," former President Trump said in a post on Truth Social, the media platform he launched after he was banished from Twitter, which is now called X.</p>

<p>"I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, and shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin. Much bleeding took place, so I realised then what was happening."</p>

<p>The shooter, who remains unidentified, was shot dead.</p>

<p>Local authorities said he was in a low-rise building outside the rally venue.</p>

<p>A member of the audience is also dead. Another person was grievously wounded.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden said in remarks to the nation that he had tried to speak to Trump -- addressing him as "Donald" for probably the first time in public.</p>

<p>"I plan on talking to them shortly, he said, adding, "There's no place in America for this kind of violence. It's sick sick… The bottom line is (the) rally should have been conducted peacefully without any problem."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/t8vi6jio_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The former President appeared to be bleeding on the right side of the face.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-suspected-shooter-was-outside-venue-says-local-prosecutor-6101148]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Suspected Shooter Was Outside Venue, Says Local Prosecutor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-suspected-shooter-was-outside-venue-says-local-prosecutor-6101148]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 06:42:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The alleged shooter who injured US presidential candidate Donald Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania was outside the event grounds, a local prosecutor said Saturday, adding that the suspect was dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The alleged shooter who injured US presidential candidate Donald Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania was outside the event grounds, a local prosecutor said Saturday, adding that the suspect was dead.</p>

<p>"I don't know how he would have gotten to the location where he was, but he was outside the grounds. And I think that's something that we're going to have to figure out how he got there," said Butler County district attorney Richard Goldinger.</p>

<p>He added that one rally attendee had died in the incident, while another was in serious condition in hospital.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9sfululg_trump-rally-gunshots_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Have to figure out how the shooter got there," said Butler County district attorney]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-donald-trump-shooting-trump-rally-shooting-witness-claims-he-saw-shooter-positioned-on-roof-before-he-fired-at-trump-6101147]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Witness Claims He Saw Shooter Positioned On Roof Before He Fired At Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-donald-trump-shooting-trump-rally-shooting-witness-claims-he-saw-shooter-positioned-on-roof-before-he-fired-at-trump-6101147]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 06:42:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A witness has claimed that he saw the man - who fired at Donald Trump while he was addressing a campaign rally - positioned on the roof of a building near the venue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A witness has claimed that he saw the man - who fired at Donald Trump while he was addressing a campaign rally - positioned on the roof of a building near the event grounds.</p>

<p>Greg told the BBC that the shooter was armed with a rifle and had crawled on top of the building.</p>

<p>"The guy crawled up the building 50 feet from us. He had a rifle," he said.</p>

<p>He said that he informed police, Secret Service about a suspicious man on a roof with a rifle.</p>

<p>"I'm thinking to myself 'Why is Trump still speaking, why have they not pulled him off the stage'... the next thing you know, five shots ring out," he told the BBC.</p>

<p>The shooting took place shortly after Trump took the stage at his final campaign rally. 78-year-old Trump grimaced and clutched a hand to his right ear, with blood soon visible across his face.</p>

<p>Secret Service agents swarmed onto the podium, surrounded the Republican candidate and escorted him roughly off the stage, as Trump raised a fist to the crowd in defiance.</p>

<p>His campaign said he was "fine" and being checked at a medical facility.</p>

<p>"I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear," Donald Trump later posted on Truth Social.</p>

<p>"I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin," Trump said.</p>

<p>The apparent assassination attempt on Donald Trump involved "multiple shots (fired) toward the stage from an elevated position outside the rally venue," the US Secret Service said, adding the shooter has been killed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8bmeish8_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The shooting took place shortly after Donald Trump took the stage]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-injured-in-assassination-attempt-at-rally-what-we-know-so-far-6101121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Injured In Assassination Bid At Rally: What We Know So Far]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-injured-in-assassination-attempt-at-rally-what-we-know-so-far-6101121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 06:37:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shots were fired at a campaign rally where former US President and Republican candidate Donald Trump was addressing a gathering in Pennsylvania on Sunday. Trump, who was seen with blood on his ear, is "safe" after he was rushed off stage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>The 78-year-old leader was seen ducking on the podium as rapid shots rang out at the rally. He was quickly surrounded by Secret Service agents who escorted him off the stage. The Republican nominee was seen raising his fist and mouthing "fight, fight" as he was whisked off the stage.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The Secret Service, a law enforcement agency that protects US political leaders, said that multiple shots were fired from an "elevated position" outside the rally venue.</li>
	<li>"I think that's something that we're going to have to figure out how he got there," Butler County district attorney Richard Goldinger told news agency AFP.</li>
	<li>According to local media, the suspected shooter has died. "Butler County District Attorney Richard Goldinger said two people are dead, including an apparent shooter," The Washington Post said. One spectator died from injuries at a hospital while two others are in a critical condition.</li>
	<li>Taking to Truth Social, a social media company owned by Trump, the former US president said he was "shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear."</li>
	<li>"I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin," he said.</li>
	<li>The attack has united US political leaders on both sides the spectrum with Trump's rival and US President Joe Biden condemning the attack, saying there was "no place in America for this kind of violence".</li>
	<li>"It's sick. It's one of the reasons why we have to unite this country... We cannot be like this, we cannot condone this. The idea that there's political violence, or violence in America like this, is just unheard of. It's just not appropriate. Everybody, everybody must condemn it," he said, adding that he will speak to Trump shortly.</li>
	<li>Former presidents Barack Obama and George W Bush have also slammed the "cowardly" attack.</li>
	<li>"Although we don't yet know exactly what happened, we should all be relieved that former President Trump wasn't seriously hurt, and use this moment to recommit ourselves to civility and respect in our politics," Obama said.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0punnpd8_trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was seen raising his fist and mouthing "fight, fight" as he was whisked off the stage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-pierced-upper-part-of-my-right-ear-donald-trump-on-shooting-at-rally-6101088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Says Bullet Pierced Part Of Right Ear, Saved By Secret Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-pierced-upper-part-of-my-right-ear-donald-trump-on-shooting-at-rally-6101088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 06:22:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump said that a bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear during a a campaign rally on Saturday in Pennsylvania.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump, in his first account of being shot at during a rally in Pennysylvania today said, "I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear."</p>

<p>"I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin," Trump, who was not seriously injured, said on his Truth Social site.</p>

<p>The former President is "fine and is being checked out at a local medical facility," Trump Communications Director Steven Cheung said in a statement.</p>

<p>The incident took place about seven minutes into the rally in Butler, in western Pennsylvania, on Saturday. Thousands of Trump supporters were attending the rally when the shooting, which was captured live on news channels, happened.&nbsp; As the bangs ran out, the 78-year-old was seen ducking with the secret service surrounding him. He could be heard making a few comments on an audio feed from the stage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Secret Service agents swarmed onto the podium, surrounded the Republican candidate and escorted him roughly off the stage, as Trump raised a fist to the crowd in defiance.</p>

<p>Trump said, “Let me get my shoes,” as he was escorted to the safe place.</p>

<p>The shocking incident happened two days before the start of the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, where Trump will formally become the party's nominee.</p>

<p>"I want to thank The United States Secret Service, and all of Law Enforcement, for their rapid response on the shooting that just took place in Butler, Pennsylvania. Most importantly, I want to extend my condolences to the family of the person at the Rally who was killed, and also to the family of another person that was badly injured," Trump said in his post.</p>

<p>"It is incredible that such an act can take place in our Country. Nothing is known at this time about the shooter, who is now dead. I was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear. I knew immediately that something was wrong in that I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin. Much bleeding took place, so I realized then what was happening. GOD BLESS AMERICA," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pg7gshog_gunfire-at-trump-rally_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-pennsylvania-rally-shooting-live-news-updates-trump-rushed-off-stage-after-shooting-at-rally-suspected-shooter-dead-6100977]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live Updates: Trump Injured In Assassination Bid At Rally, Is "Fine" Now]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-pennsylvania-rally-shooting-live-news-updates-trump-rushed-off-stage-after-shooting-at-rally-suspected-shooter-dead-6100977]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 14 Jul 2024 05:49:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump has been hit in the ear in an apparent assassination bid by a gunman at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-pierced-upper-part-of-my-right-ear-donald-trump-on-shooting-at-rally-6101088" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> has been hit in the ear in an apparent assassination bid by a gunman at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania today. The unidentified gunman and a spectator have been killed and two others "critically" injured, officials said.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Republican presidential candidate, whose team said he was "fine", was attacked when he had just started his speech. Blood was clearly visible across his cheek and mouth.</p>

<p><strong>Video: <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-moment-donald-trump-was-attacked-at-pennsylvania-rally-6100971#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Moment Trump Was Attacked At Rally</a></strong></p>

<p>In his first reaction to a shooting at his rally, he said in a statement he "was shot with a bullet that pierced the upper part of my right ear".</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, who will face Trump in the upcoming US Presidential election, said the incident was "sick" and added that there was "no place in America for this kind of violence."</p>

<h2><strong>Here are live updates on shooting at Donald Trump's rally:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ne3ae8o8_donald-trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump raised a fist to the crowd after shooting at his rally in Butler, Pennsylvania]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>