<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 14:37:54 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-and-the-trust-deficit-between-developing-and-developed-nations-6846182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Change And The "Trust Deficit" Between Developing, Developed Nations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-and-the-trust-deficit-between-developing-and-developed-nations-6846182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 14:22:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Climate change is a global challenge and it must be seen as a common issue for the entire planet to work together on, but it is increasingly caught in the web of whose responsibility it is - the developed world or the developing world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate change is a global challenge and it must be seen as a common issue for the entire planet to work together on, but it is increasingly caught in the web of whose responsibility it is - the developed world or the developing world, including the Global South. The other challenge being faced is the sharing of technology and financing the shift from fossil fuels to environment-friendly methods.</p>

<p>Speaking at the NDTV World Summit, Harjeet Singh, Global Engagement Director, Fossil Fuel Non-Proliferation Treaty Initiative, highlighted the trust deficit towards the developed world and their responsibility, or lack of it, that needs to be addressed on priority.</p>

<p>"The trust deficit is because of a reason," he said, elucidating that "When we see as India and other developing nations face tremendous pressure to move away from fossil fuels, and we must, but the reality is that there are sill millions who do not have access to energy in the developing world and need support, but in comparison, the developed world continue to increase its fossil fuel consumption."</p>

<p>"When you look at the global fossil fuel expansion, you see Australia, Canada, Norway, the UK, and the US put together are responsible for more than 50 per cent of the planet's fossil fuel expansion between now and 2050 - that is where the trust deficit stems from," he further said, adding that on top of it all, "they are not willing to share technology or help with finance."</p>

<p>Though he welcomed the new UK government's decision to stop issuing any more new licences for fossil fuel plants, he highlighted that the licences already issued in the last few years will have a tremendously negative impact on the climate over the next many decades. "The trust deficit is a real issue that needs to be dealt with as the developed nations have not acted based on their historical responsibility and contribute their fair share to the climate challenge, but continue to pressure developing countries to do more, that too without assisting with technology or finance."</p>

<p>Adding to this, another panelist, Shishir Priyadarshi, who is President of the Chintan Research Foundation said, "From the way the trade agenda was set in 1995 at the WTO, there are lots of lessons to be taken while working on the climate agenda. Why the setting up of the WTO led to a huge trade deficit was because of 2 reasons - One, the developed world made huge promises to the developing world if they simply lowered tariffs and opened up markets, and Second was that the developed world said 'we know' and 'we will tell you how it's done and what you need to do', and that is something that led to a huge deficit of trust. That is something that we must avoid while setting the climate agenda"</p>

<h2><strong>DEVELOPING COUNTRY DOING FAR MORE FOR CLIMATE CHANGE</strong></h2>

<p>Mr Priyadarchi highlighted how "The developing nations have done, and are doing far more to address climate change."</p>

<p>Citing India's example he said, "India has committed $2.5 trillion in investment towards climate funding between 2015 and 2030 - that's huge," he said, adding that "We (developing nations like India) are prepared to drive down the highway towards zero emissions, and we are absolutely with you (the developed world), but we will do it at our speed. You cannot tell us the speed with which changes need to be made or tell us that these are the restricted number of pitstops on the way. We will surely reach there, but we need the flexibility and support." If this is done, then it will bring down the "trust deficit" cinsiderably.</p>

<p>Giving a perspective from the developed nations, British High Commissioner to India Lindy Cameron said "Our foreign secretary had said recently that he had heard that developing countries believed the system didn't work for them. I understand that it is important we recognize that, but what we must recognize is that we all live on the same planet, and one must recognize that we in the UK have set ambitious targets like net-zero emissions by 2050."</p>

<p>She also said that "After 6 months in India, I do believe that India is the place where this (climate action) is going to happen. This is the place as this is the country that matters most for the future of the planet and for climate change, because India's ambition for development should not in any way be constrained by the responsibilities of the planet."</p>

<p>She further said that "We are committed to reforms like making more affordable finance available for developing countries. And we are also working here in India on technology and research to ensure that we can support those incredibly ambitious goals India has set."</p>

<p>The fourth panelist, Erik Solheim, Former Minister of Climate and the Environment of Norway, lauded China and India for their tremendous achievement in terms of climate action targets. Speaking at the NDTV World Summit he said, "Nobody should blame India or the developing world, especially when nations like the US where per capita emissions are 25 times that of India. The state of Gujarat alone has set the target of 100 Gigawatt of clean energy by 2030. This is enormous. It is as big as 20 times the entire energy grid of Nigeria - the biggest nation in Africa."</p>

<p>He further said that "Forget all of India and what all the rest of the country is doing, but if you see just the state of Gujarat...if it were a nation, it would be the 8th largest in terms of green energy."</p>

<p>He also had big praise for China, saying "China accounts for 60% of all green energy today and the rest of the world is the other 40%. India is second only to China."</p>

<p>He also lauded Indonesia which he said has "brought deforestation down to zero, and made it the biggest rain forest nation in the world".</p>

<p>"If ten years ago someone asked me where one needs to go to see climate progress, I would have said please go to Brussels or Berlin or Geneva or Paris, but today I would say go see what a Beijing, Delhi or Jakarta are doing," he concluded.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vlv3l2ig_ndtv-world-summit-climate-action_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The discussion on The Climate Agenda: Setting the terms at the NDTV World Summit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russian-north-korean-flags-seen-on-ukraine-battlefield-report-6846130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian, North Korean Flags Seen On Ukraine Battlefield: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russian-north-korean-flags-seen-on-ukraine-battlefield-report-6846130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 14:17:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea's National Intelligence Service last week said that North Korea had decided to send approximately 12,000 special forces to support Russia in its prolonged war with Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A pro-Russia Telegram account has posted a photo showing the Russian and North Korean flags side by side on a Ukrainian battlefield, indicating that North Korea has likely sent troops to support Russia in its prolonged war with Ukraine.</p>

<p>The image, shared by a blogger named @rvvoenkor_bot on Monday, showed the two flags raised together over a mine in Pokrovsk, one of the strongholds on Ukraine's eastern front, Yonhap news agency reported.</p>

<p>The blogger said that the North Korean flag has recently been raised on a hill at the mine near the city, which is one of the suspected locations where North Korean soldiers are believed to be stationed.</p>

<p>On Friday, South Korea's National Intelligence Service announced that North Korea had decided to send approximately 12,000 special forces to support Russia in its prolonged war with Ukraine, with about 1,500 already deployed to Russia's Far East.</p>

<p>The deployment marks the first time North Korea has sent ground troops on such a large scale, though it has previously dispatched smaller groups of soldiers overseas to earn foreign currency.</p>

<p>So far, North Korea's state media has not made any official statements regarding its troop deployment to Russia.</p>

<p>A North Korean envoy to the United Nations on Monday dismissed the accusations from South Korea and Ukraine that it is sending soldiers to fight alongside Russia in the war in Ukraine as "groundless rumours," arguing its relations with Moscow are "legitimate and cooperative."</p>

<p>On Monday, Russian Ambassador to South Korea Georgy Zinoviev told First Vice Foreign Minister Kim Hong-kyun that the cooperation with North Korea is "not directed against South Korea's security interests" and claimed that the cooperation is "carried out within the framework of international law," the Russian Embassy in Seoul said in a Facebook post.</p>

<p>A South Korean unification ministry official said North Korea has never acknowledged the deployment of its soldiers, as it would be considered an illegal act.</p>

<p>"When the North engages in illegal activities, it does not explicitly acknowledge them," the official said on condition of anonymity, citing the 2010 sinking of the Cheonan warship that killed 46 South Korean sailors.</p>

<p>A team of multinational investigators concluded in 2010 that a North Korean torpedo was responsible for the sinking. However, the North still adamantly denies its involvement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0pklftmo_russianorth-korea-flags_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An image shared by a blogger showed the two flags raised together over a mine in Pokrovsk]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-patrolling-agreement-ladakh-galwan-valley-clashes-trying-to-restore-trust-army-chief-on-india-china-patrolling-deal-6845928]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trying To Restore Trust": Army Chief On India-China Patrolling Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-patrolling-agreement-ladakh-galwan-valley-clashes-trying-to-restore-trust-army-chief-on-india-china-patrolling-deal-6845928]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:44:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian military is "trying to restore trust" in its Chinese counterpart, Chief of Army Staff General Upendra Dwivedi said Tuesday afternoon, a day after India and China reached a patrolling agreement along the Line of Actual Control.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian military is "trying to restore trust" in its Chinese counterpart, Chief of Army Staff General <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/general-upendra-dwivedi" target="_blank">Upendra Dwivedi</a> said Tuesday afternoon, a day after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/india-china-border" target="_blank">India and China</a> reached a patrolling agreement along the Line of Actual Control - the de facto border between the two nations.</p>

<p>"This (rebuilding of trust) will happen once we are able to see each other, and convince and reassure each other, that we are not creeping into buffer zones that have been created," the General said.</p>

<p>The Army chief said the goal, at this time, is to return military ties with Beijing to pre-April 2020 levels - before violent clashes in Ladakh's Galwan and along the LAC - put both countries on edge.</p>

<p>"We want to go back to the status quo of April 2020... thereafter we will look at disengagement and de-escalation, and then normal management of the LAC. This has been our stand since April 2020."</p>

<p>"As of now, we are trying to restore that trust," he said.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-india-china-border-patrol-agreement-and-why-it-is-important-6844560" target="_blank">India-China Border Patrol Deal: What Is It, Why Is It Important</a></p>

<p>Earlier this month General Dwivedi had suggested a deal is imminent, saying certain less critical issues had been addressed and only the more difficult issues needed to be worked out.</p>

<p>On Monday Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri confirmed a patrolling agreement, and that both countries were still working on disengagement and resolution of tension that started in May 2020.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Delhi: COAS Gen Upendra Dwivedi says, &quot;We want to go back to the status quo of April 2020. Thereafter we will be looking at disengagement, de-escalation and normal management of LAC... This has been our stand since April 2020. As of now, we are trying to restore the… <a href="https://t.co/jASAklyN2N">pic.twitter.com/jASAklyN2N</a></p>&mdash; ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1848628720942387261?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 22, 2024</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The accord follows nearly two dozen rounds of talks between Indian and Chinese military commanders and diplomats, the most recent of which was held on August 29.</p>

<p>It was agreed that restoration of peace and tranquillity, and respect for the LAC are the essential basis for restoration of normalcy in bilateral relations.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-agree-on-patrolling-agreement-along-lac-leads-to-disengagement-6838489" target="_blank">India To Resume Patrolling In Ladakh After Breakthrough With China</a></p>

<p>The deal is for patrolling in Depsang and Demchok areas, news agency PTI said.</p>

<p>Depsang is seen as critical for India since it provides access to the airstrip at Daulat Beg Oldie and prevents Chinese troops from threatening vital logistics centres in the area. Demchok, meanwhile is divided in two by the LAC; India controls the western part, which is claimed by China.</p>

<p>The breakthrough came before Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia; Mr Modi is in Kazan to attend the BRICS (Brazil, Russia, India, China, and South Africa) summit that starts today.</p>

<p>READ | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-will-be-able-to-go-back-to-2020-patrolling-s-jaishankar-on-lac-border-row-6839082" target="_blank">"Back To 2020...": S Jaishankar To NDTV On India, China Pact</a></p>

<p>Hours after the announcement External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told NDTV the agreement was the result of "patient and persevering diplomacy". Speaking at NDTV's World Summit, he said, "I think it creates a basis for peace and tranquillity along the border, which was there before 2020..."</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/qcr6vjes_ladakh-generic_625x300_10_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-million-dollar-us-voter-lottery-raises-questions-is-it-legal-6845561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Announces Million-Dollar US Voter Lottery, But Is It Legal?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-million-dollar-us-voter-lottery-raises-questions-is-it-legal-6845561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:54:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's offer of a million dollars to one registered voter in a swing state every day until the US Election Day on November 5 has raised questions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Donald Trump surrogate Elon Musk's offer of a million dollars to one registered voter in a swing state every day until the US Election Day on November 5 has raised questions about the legality of such a move.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">While Democratic candidate Kamala Harris's campaign has not commented on the contest, Josh Shapiro, the Democratic Governor of Pennsylvania, said on NBC's Meet the Press: "I think it's something that law enforcement should take a look at."</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Musk, the world's richest man, announced the contest Saturday in Pennsylvania, one of the seven "swing states" that will likely determine who will become the next US president -- Harris, or Republican Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">The contest requires entrants sign a petition "to support free speech &amp; the right to bear arms," Tesla and SpaceX CEO Musk said on X, the social media platform he owns.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">The endeavor enters hot water with the requirement that people are registered to vote in swing states in order to participate.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Danielle Lang, a professor at Georgetown Law School who specializes in election law, told AFP the contest could be "subject to civil or criminal enforcement by the Department of Justice."</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"It is illegal to give out money on the condition that recipients register as voters," she said.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"As the terms of this 'contest' to win $1 million require the recipient to be a registered voter in one of seven swing states (or to register if they have not already), the offer violates federal law," she continued.</p>

<h3 data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody"><strong>Gray area</strong></h3>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Rick Hasen, a political science professor at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) School of Law, expressed a similar sentiment on his Election Law Blog.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">He cited the specific law that prohibits anyone who "pays or offers to pay or accepts payment... for registration to vote," adding that the penalty involves a fine of $10,000 or up to five years imprisonment.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Not everyone is of the same mindset, however.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Brad Smith, the former chairman of the Federal Election Commission, told the New York Times what Musk is doing is "something of a gray area."</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Since Musk is not paying people to register directly, but rather for signing a petition, "I think he comes out OK here," Smith said.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">For his part, Musk defends his move by saying it is a simple get out and vote effort.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"We want to make sure that everyone in swing states hears about this and I suspect this will ensure they do," he wrote on X.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Tesla and SpaceX CEO Musk has pulled out all the stops in recent weeks to support former president Trump, including donating $75 million to a pro-Trump political action committee and appearing at campaign rallies.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"Just go out there and talk to your friends and family and acquaintances and people you meet in the street and... convince them to vote," he told the crowd at the rally where he announced the petition contest.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Lang said that schemes such as these occur "each election cycle."</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"We tend to see some businesses that engage in some questionable activity along these lines (such as offering a free item for showing an 'I Voted' sticker) but this is notable for its far larger size," she said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jb57vagg_elon-musk_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has defended his move by saying it is a simple get out and vote effort.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/something-thats-catching-fire-this-country-ireland-introduces-influencer-course-6845523]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Something That's Catching Fire": This Country Introduces Influencer Course]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/something-thats-catching-fire-this-country-ireland-introduces-influencer-course-6845523]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It's a job that didn't exist until recently but becoming an influencer is an ever more popular career path among Gen-Z youth in the modern era of social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's a job that didn't exist until recently but becoming an influencer is an ever more popular career path among Gen-Z youth in the modern era of social media. Now a first-of-its-kind course at an Irish university is teaching wannabe influencers how to convert online presence and content on platforms such as Instagram, TikTok and YouTube into revenue streams.</p>

<p>"Influencing is something that's catching fire," course director Irene McCormick told AFP at South East Technological University (SETU) in Carlow, an hour's drive southwest from the capital Dublin.</p>

<p>The idea grew out of a summer crash course "Digital Hustle" launched by McCormick that was taught by TikTokers and attracted 350 applicants for 30 places.</p>

<p>"It got amazing traction, we could see the appetite for more, so we broadened it to degree level," said McCormick, a former television producer and director.</p>

<p>After two years of development the course -- a four-year-long bachelor's degree in "Content Creation and Social Media" -- received accreditation and welcomed its first intake of 15 students last month.</p>

<p>On the state-of-the-art campus, students chatted, took selfies and scrolled their social media feeds on smartphones during a break between classes.</p>

<p>"My friends tell me I talk a lot so I thought I might as well make money out of it and try this course," Harry Odife, 22, told AFP in the campus TV studio during a roleplay exercise.</p>

<p>Most of the students are already immersed in the digital space or working in it and want to expand their toolset and knowledge, McCormick said.</p>

<p>"You can try to learn yourself at home but being empowered with practice and theory about how to connect with target demographics online is going to make a big difference to your career," she added. &nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Person branding</strong></h3>

<p>The term "influencer" was officially added to the dictionary in 2019, and refers to a person well-known through use of social media who uses their celebrity to endorse, promote, or generate interest in products and brands, often for payment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now the most prominent such as YouTube challenge stunt creator Mr Beast and gaming vlogger KSI tap vast online audiences, earning huge sums per sponsored post or via brand sponsorships and advertisements.</p>

<p>Surveys consistently show that most Gen-Z youths -- those born between 1997 and 2012 -- would consider a job as a vlogger, YouTuber or professional streamer.</p>

<p>"Of course people want to make money from influencing, so we look particularly at person branding, how to monetise being influential over large online followings," said McCormick.</p>

<p>Students said they hoped the course would help them leverage their interests and hobbies which range from beauty and fashion to entertainment, social justice, and sport.</p>

<p>"I post a lot of the hairstyles I do on TikTok and Instagram, it would be nice to have the knowledge to grow that into an actual business," said Favour Ehuchie, an 18-year-old hairdresser.</p>

<p>Another student, keen equestrian Marta Hughes Bravo, said horse stud farms now seek staff who are social media-savvy.</p>

<p>"Companies are all over Instagram, Facebook, and TikTok. One girl who works for a farm has been pulling in brand deals. To know how to do that would be fantastic," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Serious business'</strong></h3>

<p>Degree modules include creative video and storytelling psychology, entrepreneurship, celebrity studies, storytelling psychology, data analytics, and podcasting.</p>

<p>"A lot of people think it's an easy life being an influencer, just posting 60-second videos on TikTok, but there is way more to it," said Hughes Bravo.</p>

<p>Creating content involves "editing, planning, organising, and so on, it takes up more time than you might think, people don't understand that quite yet."</p>

<p>Practical elements of the course include camera and microphone learning, and work placements.</p>

<p>"Having influencer knowledge like how to be comfortable in front of cameras will help us build our confidence, whatever we end up doing," said another student Naoise Kelly, adding that becoming the next big thing on social media is not her top priority.</p>

<p>McCormick said employment opportunities for influencer talent are multiplying exponentially, either in front of camera or behind the scenes.</p>

<p>"Yes, influencer posts on social media may sometimes be frivolous, but the actual business is not, it is a very serious business," she added.</p>

<p>"So many Gen Z young people buy a lot of bling, and that bling is being sold through influencers.</p>

<p>"Around 70 percent of marketers now believe in influencers as the future of marketing, governments are also using them to message people, that's how we access markets now."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ub6sh858_ireland-influencer-course_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The idea grew out of a summer crash course launched by Irene McCormick]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/us-to-curb-ai-investment-in-china-soon-6845498]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US To Curb AI Investment In China Soon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/us-to-curb-ai-investment-in-china-soon-6845498]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:45:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The final rules, which target outbound investment to China in AI, semiconductors and microelectronics and quantum computing, are likely to be released with the next week or so.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. rules that will ban certain U.S. investments in artificial intelligence in China are under final review, according to a government posting, suggesting the restrictions are coming soon.</p>

<p>The rules, which will also require U.S. investors to notify the Treasury Department about some investments in AI and other sensitive technologies, stem from an executive order signed by President Joe Biden in August 2023 that aims to keep American investors' know-how from aiding China's military.</p>

<p>The final rules, which target outbound investment to China in AI, semiconductors and microelectronics and quantum computing, are under review at the Office of Management and Budget, the posting showed, which in the past has meant they will likely be released within the next week or so.</p>

<p>"It looks to me like they're trying to publish this before the election," said former Treasury official Laura Black, a lawyer at Akin Gump in Washington, referring to the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election. Black added that the Treasury office overseeing the regulations generally provides at least a 30-day window before such regulations go into effect.</p>

<p>The Treasury Department published proposed rules with a raft of exceptions in June and gave the public a chance to comment. The draft rules placed the responsibility on U.S. individuals and companies to determine which transactions will be restricted.</p>

<p>A Treasury Department spokesperson declined to comment.</p>

<p>Black expects the final rules to further clarify the scope of coverage over artificial intelligence and the threshold for limited partners.</p>

<p>The proposed rules banned transactions in AI for certain uses, and involving systems trained in using a specified quantity of computing power. They required notification of transactions related to the development of AI systems or semiconductors not otherwise prohibited.</p>

<p>Publicly traded securities such as index funds or mutual funds, certain limited partnership investments, and certain syndicated debt financings were among proposed exceptions.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8jllhg3_ai_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-al-qard-al-hassan-hezbollahs-main-cash-source-targeted-by-israel-6845398]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Al-Qard Al-Hassan, Hezbollah's Main Cash Source Targeted By Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-al-qard-al-hassan-hezbollahs-main-cash-source-targeted-by-israel-6845398]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:33:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel recently targeted branches of Al-Qard Al-Hassan (AQAH), a financial institution linked to the Iran-backed Lebanese militant group Hezbollah, with precision airstrikes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel recently targeted branches of Al-Qard Al-Hassan (AQAH), a financial institution linked to the Iran-backed Lebanese militant group Hezbollah, with precision airstrikes. The strikes hit across Beirut's southern suburbs, southern Lebanon, and the northeastern Beqaa Valley, areas known as Hezbollah strongholds. These attacks, which spanned late Sunday night into Monday morning, are part of Israel's effort to cripple Hezbollah's financial infrastructure and weaken its ability to fund operations.</p>

<p>The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) confirmed that at least 11 branches of AQAH were struck, in a campaign aimed at dismantling Hezbollah's access to vital financial resources.</p>

<h3><strong>What Is Al-Qard Al-Hassan?</strong></h3>

<p>Founded in 1983, Al-Qard Al-Hassan, which translates to "the benevolent loan," calls itself a charitable organisation adhering to Islamic finance principles, which prohibit interest. Its mission is to provide interest-free loans to Lebanon's Shiite population, particularly those aligned with Hezbollah. AQAH offers loans against collateral such as gold or jewellery, offering much-needed credit to a Lebanese population battling a declining economy.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-hamas-israel-claims-it-found-500-million-in-secret-hezbollah-bunker-in-beirut-6843741">Israel Claims It Found $500 Million In "Secret" Hezbollah Bunker In Beirut</a></p>

<p>Al-Qard Al-Hassan allegedly operates 30 branches across Lebanon, with many located in Hezbollah-controlled areas of Beirut. Its influence surged after Lebanon's financial collapse in 2019, as traditional banks severely limited depositors' access to their savings. AQAH, on the other hand, continued to operate, allowing those who banked with it to withdraw cash - often in hard currency - when other financial institutions could not.</p>

<p>AQAH operates under a license granted by the Lebanese government. The US Department of the Treasury sanctioned AQAH in 2007, accusing it of serving as Hezbollah's financial arm. US officials contend that while AQAH may serve Lebanon's Shiite population, it is also used to move Hezbollah's funds through shell accounts, allowing the group to gain access to the international financial system, despite sanctions designed to cut off its resources.</p>

<h3><strong>Hezbollah's Use Of AQAH</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah, which emerged as a dominant force in Lebanon after Israel's 1982 invasion of the country, has long relied on hawala networks and financial mechanisms to build and maintain support, especially among Lebanon's Shiite population. Over the years, Al-Qard Al-Hassan has become a crucial element in Hezbollah's strategy.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, there are hawala systems that work as money-exchange houses and move large quantities of sums.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Many Lebanese citizens, particularly Hezbollah's constituency, depend on AQAH for hard currency loans, with collateral as simple as jewellery or gold. While the average loan does not exceed $5,000, these loans are essential lifelines for those trying to pay for weddings, education, or starting small businesses. In recent years, Hezbollah has extended the invitation for all Lebanese, regardless of their sect or political affiliation, to utilize AQAH's services. The group has promoted AQAH as an alternative to the traditional banking system, which collapsed amidst the 2019 economic crisis.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's leadership has been open about the group's dependence on AQAH for financial support. After the organisation was hacked in 2020 and the names of its clients were leaked, Hezbollah's former leader, Hassan Nasrallah, publicly defended AQAH.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-kills-hezbollah-finance-chief-in-syria-managed-main-source-of-income-6843838">"Managed Main Source Of Income": Israel Kills Hezbollah Finance Chief In Syria</a></p>

<p>The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) confirmed that one of the strikes targeted a vault underneath a hospital building in Beirut, which they claim held $550 million meant to fund Hezbollah's military activities. These financial resources, Israel argues, are essential for Hezbollah to continue purchasing weapons and paying fighters. Israeli defence officials have alleged that AQAH is responsible for safeguarding as much as $750 million a year in Iranian funding, in addition to revenues from Hezbollah's other criminal enterprises, including drug trafficking and money laundering.</p>

<p>Yoav Gallant, Israel's Defense Minister, signed an order on Monday designating AQAH as a terrorist organisation.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tah3fgk_alqard-alhassan_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Al-Qard Al-Hassan allegedly operates 30 branches across Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sundar-pichai-on-why-google-invests-so-heavily-on-free-meals-to-employees-6845072]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sundar Pichai On Why Google Invests So Heavily On Free Meals To Employees]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sundar-pichai-on-why-google-invests-so-heavily-on-free-meals-to-employees-6845072]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:19:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google CEO Sundar Pichai has revealed why the company invests so heavily in its famous free meal policy. Contrary to popular belief, Mr Pichai explained these meals were not just perks, adding they served a deeper purpose.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google CEO Sundar Pichai has revealed why the company invests so heavily in its famous free meal policy. Contrary to popular belief, Mr Pichai explained these meals were not just perks, adding they served a deeper purpose.</p>

<p>"I can recall several times, when I was working at Google early on, being in cafes, meeting someone else, talking and getting excited about something. So, it sparks creativity," Mr Pichai shared in an interview on Bloomberg's The David Rubenstein Show.</p>

<p>Sundar Pichai, who started working at Google as a Product Manager in 2004, said that some of the most brilliant ideas emerge during these communal meals.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/food/google-employee-gives-a-glimpse-into-her-daily-work-meal-in-viral-video-6255425">Google Employee Gives A Glimpse Into Her Daily Work Meal In Viral Video</a></p>

<p>The CEO added that this collaborative environment, where employees gather over food, helps foster innovation. "The benefit that comes out of it dwarfs the cost," Mr Pichai remarked, saying the free meals weren't a financial burden but a long-term investment in creativity and community building.</p>

<p>Beyond the free meals, Mr Pichai noted that Google's employee-friendly initiatives positively impacted workplace dynamics. With over 1,82,000 employees globally, the tech giant attracts top talent, with approximately 90 per cent of job candidates accepting offers.</p>

<p>Discussing what Google looks for in potential hires, Mr Pichai said that criteria vary depending on the role. For engineering positions, he said, it was important to find skilled programmers who can adapt to new challenges. "We are really looking for 'superstar software engineers," he added.</p>

<p>Apart from complimentary meals, Google offers extensive health insurance, flexible remote work options, paid time off and wellness programmes, making it one of the most attractive workplaces in the industry.</p>

<p>However, despite the benefits, Sundar Pichai acknowledged that not all of Google's perks have remained intact in recent years. In 2023, the company announced plans to streamline its offerings, including reducing the hours of some office cafes and consolidating micro kitchens. However, he noted that Google's benefits still rank among the most generous in Silicon Valley, influencing other companies to adopt similar initiatives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-04/2omc9mog_sundar-pichai_625x300_26_April_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sundar Pichai said Google's employee-friendly initiatives positively impact workplace dynamics. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unsc-seat-for-india-g7s-diminishing-power-what-ex-diplomat-kishore-mahbubani-said-6845278]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UNSC Seat For India, G7's Diminishing Power: What Ex Diplomat Kishore Mahbubani Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unsc-seat-for-india-g7s-diminishing-power-what-ex-diplomat-kishore-mahbubani-said-6845278]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:17:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Singapore diplomat Kishore Mahbubani said it is time for Britain's permanent seat at the United Nations Security Council to be given to India. He also stressed India's role in addressing the conflict in Russia, Ukraine, Israel, among others.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">In light of the India-China patrol agreement finalised on Monday, Mr Mahbubani said Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping had regular engagements before the 2020 Galwan clash and following skirmishes along the Line of Actual Control. The recent agreement, he said, signifies India and China adjusting to the new 3M world. The 3Ms include “multicivislisations – where the world is no longer dominated by the West. In fact, the West is losing its sheen. Multipolar- where other powers are also emerging; and multilateral”.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Mr Mahbubani said it is time for Britain to give up its permanent seat in the United Nations Security Council and make way for India. He went on to say that India is among the greatest powers, with the fifth largest economy in the world, and on its way to become the third largest economy by the end of the decade. “The UK will probably will drop from the top 10 economies soon. It elected Boris Johnson as prime minister, who is a joker. Liz Truss was a joke too. The UK has lost the capability of playing a role on world stage,” he explained.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The world would cheer if India gets a permanent UNSC seat because it would give a perspective that would be understood both by the West and the East, Mr Mahbubani said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Calling BRICS a “sunrise club, Mr Mahbubani said, “Everyone wants to join BRICS. The G7, by contrast, is diminishing in power and influence. India and China's rise is part of a broader Asian rise. In 2000, Japan's economy was eight times bigger than ASEAN. By 2030, ASEAN is going to be bigger than Japan.”</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Mr Mahbubani stressed on the need for stronger figures to head the United Nations. “As the world is shrinking, we become an interdependent global village. Covid, climate change, financial stress, are among the issues we face, which we will survive if there is a strong village council. The UN is weak is not by accident, but by design. Great powers have insisted that the UN remains spineless. Now when the need for the UN is growing, we must persuade these powers to choose strong Secretary Generals, like Kofi Annan. There is no alternative to the UN,” he said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The former Singapore diplomat said India is already at the diplomatic high table. “When Prime Minister Narendra Modi demonstrated he could visit both Russia and Ukraine, he showed India can play a valuable bridging role. India can talk to Russia, Ukraine, Iran, Israel, Arab countries and majorly contribute to solving a problem that is worrying the world a great deal,” he said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">If India wants to join the global manufacturing supply chains, integration to some extent with China is required, Mr Mahbubani said. “Many components still come from China. If you want to become a major Apple phone facility, the components come from China,” he said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">“The future economic growth is coming from CIA countries - China, India Asean. The total population of these countries is 3.5 billion. in 2000, only 150 million people here had middle class living standards. By 2020, the number rose to 1.5 billion. And by 2030, it will 2.5-3 billion. Never before in human history have you seen an explosion of middle class population of this size and scale. Many in India is still want to look West, but the West is lost - geopolitcally, economically, domestically. Acting east is the future of India,” Mr Mahbubani said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The opportunities for India would be “magnificent” if it integrates with Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP). “Economic studies show Indians would add billions to its economy if it integrates with East Asia. Most manufacturing today comes from East Asia with the biggest sources being Japan, South Korea, China and ASEAN. They are the biggest sources for FDI. South East Asia has received more FDI than India, China, Korea, Japan combined. How did South East Asia do that? Because it integrated in global supply chains and RCEP. Manufacturers would love to come to India if the conditions are right,” Mr Mahbubani said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">India stepping up trade with the QUAD would be a positive development, Mr Mahbubani said. “There is a perception, which may be right or wrong, that the QUAD was set up to counterbalance China. But Japan, Australia and the US are already integrated with East Asia. Total trade of these three countries with East Asia is much larger than what they do with India. If India steps up trade with QUAD, that will be a positive development,” he added.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oq1rqj88_kishore-mahbubani_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/do-academics-respond-more-to-mails-from-melissa-or-rahul-study-reveals-6845266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Do Academics Respond More To Mails From "Melissa" Or "Rahul"? Study Says...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/do-academics-respond-more-to-mails-from-melissa-or-rahul-study-reveals-6845266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:16:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new research shows Australian academics responded differently to potential PhD students, depending on whether they were called "Melissa" or "Rahul".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Universities are supposed to be places where all students can learn, free from discrimination. A key part of this ideal is academics welcoming all students to study and research, regardless of their racial background.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>But as our <a href="https://doi.org/10.22230/ijepl.2024v20n1a1401">new research</a> shows, Australian academics responded differently to potential PhD students, depending on whether they were called “Melissa” or “Rahul”.</p>

<h2><strong>Racism on campus</strong></h2>

<p>Many <a href="https://www.ubcpress.ca/the-equity-myth">overseas</a> and <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2014.969224">Australian studies</a> have shown racism is both a historical and ongoing problem for universities.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://findanexpert.unimelb.edu.au/news/13920-most-of-australia's-uni-leaders-are-white--male-and-grey.-this-lack-of-diversity-could-be-a-handicap">2020 Australian study</a> showed universities tend to be run by older, white men. A <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2021.1905361">2021 UK study</a> showed academics from different cultural backgrounds face racism at work.</p>

<p>But there has been less specific attention paid to those trying to become academics.</p>

<p>The main way people start an academic career is via a doctoral degree. In the Australian system, before a student is accepted they usually require an established academic to agree to supervise them. So a student's initial communication with a potential supervisor is very important.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A group of young people sit around a table looking at a laptop. Books and papers are on the table." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">To start a PhD, students usually need to have a supervisor lined up.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/multiracial-group-young-students-studying-together-522965350">Jacob Lund/Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2><strong>How we set up our research</strong></h2>

<p>To investigate whether racism is playing a role at the entrance point to PhD study, in 2017 we sent about 7,000 emails from fictitious students to academics based at the main campuses of Australia's Group of Eight universities (billed as Australia's top research universities).</p>

<p>These are the Australian National University, Monash University, University of Adelaide, University of New South Wales, University of Melbourne, University of Sydney, University of Western Australia and University of Queensland.</p>

<p>We emailed staff ranked senior lecturer or above, as these are the levels most likely to be supervising PhD students. Academics were identified by university websites, and we sent emails to everyone who fit our rank criteria across all disciplines.</p>

<p>In this process, we found 70% of relevant academics were male and 84% were white. This did not improve in the more senior ranks – more than 68% of professors were white men.</p>

<h2><strong>What did the email say?</strong></h2>

<p>The emails asked for an meeting to talk about potential PhD supervision.</p>

<p>They were identical apart from the senders' names. These names were tested to be associated with male and female and with white-European, Indigenous, South Asian, Chinese and Arab identities. Recipients were randomly allocated to different name groups.</p>

<p>The emails indicated the sender was an Australia-based student with fluent English. It conveyed an interest in the recipient's research and urgency in meeting because the sender was only on campus for several days. It also noted “I have recently finished my honours degree” (a common path into a PhD in Australia) and was sent from a University of Sydney email address.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A close up of hands typing on a laptop keyboard." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">We emailed about 7,000 senior academics as part of our study.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/close-image-woman-hands-typing-on-1936676008">Tipa Patt/Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2><strong>What did we find?</strong></h2>

<p>Responses agreeing to a meeting or requesting further information were categorised as “positive”. Those who declined a meeting were “non-positive”. Automated replies and those who did not reply were “non-responses”.</p>

<p>Of 6,928 emails sent, 2,986 (43.1%) received a reply within 24 hours and 2,469 (35.6%) received a positive reply. There were 3,942 (56.9%) non-responses and 517 (7.5%) non-positive responses (declining a meeting).</p>

<p>We initially planned to give academics a week to respond, but after IT at one university noticed several staff had received emails with identical text, we ended the experiment after 24 hours.</p>

<p>From here, the results were stark: emails from names associated with non-white racial groups received significantly fewer responses and positive replies than those from names typically associated with white individuals.</p>

<p>An email from “Melissa Smith” was far more likely to get a positive response than an identical email from “Grace Chen Jinyan” (six percentage points lower) or “Omar al-Haddad” (nine percentage points lower).</p>

<p>The most dramatic gap was in the positive response rates to Melissa Smith, compared with “Rahul Kumar”. The rate of positive responses to Melissa was 12 percentage points higher than for Rahul.</p>

<p>Overall, our statistical analysis showed the white-sounding names averaged a 7% higher reply rate and a 9% higher positive response rate than the non-white sounding names. Both these findings were highly <a href="https://hbr.org/2016/02/a-refresher-on-statistical-significance">statistically significant</a>, meaning we can be very confident the results were not due to chance.</p>

<p>Of course, some faculty members may simply have been unable to meet with the student, or may have missed the email. However, given the randomisation used, it is reasonable to assume bias explains the gap in responses to students with different names.</p>

<p>This is alarming because it suggests racial bias is quietly influencing who gets a foot in the door of academia even before formal admissions processes begin.</p>

<h2><strong>Silver linings</strong></h2>

<p>One seemingly positive finding was academics at the more junior end of our study group appeared to show less bias towards students of different backgrounds.</p>

<p>For academics at senior lecturer or associate professor levels, Melissa was 10.5% more likely to receive a positive response than Rahul, while the corresponding figure for full professors was 14.7%.</p>

<p>However, junior academics often have <a href="https://educ.sites.olt.ubc.ca/files/2022/09/Literature-Review-Equity-in-Faculty-Hiring-UBC-Faculty-of-Education-2022.pdf">little institutional power</a> or much of a say on hiring. More research is needed to explore whether generational change is achievable (albeit painfully slow).</p>

<p>We also found that, unlike <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/11/opinion/sunday/professors-are-prejudiced-too.html">similar US studies</a>, there was no significant bias against female students. In fact, there was some evidence of positive bias, or preference, for female students.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A group of people, including young women sit in rows listening to a speaker at the front." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Our study found academics did not discriminate against potential candidates based on gender.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/business-entrepreneurship-symposium-speaker-giving-talk-1908799612">Matej Kastelic/ Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2><strong>Backlash to our study</strong></h2>

<p>We based our study on a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/11/opinion/sunday/professors-are-prejudiced-too.html">peer-reviewed study carried out in the United States</a>, and followed a research ethics protocol approved by our university.</p>

<p>However, minutes after academics received our follow-up email telling them they had been part of a research study (part of our ethics protocol), the backlash began.</p>

<p>The University of Sydney, our home institution at the time, received more than 500 inquiries about the study. While some were curious or supportive, the majority were complaints. These were primarily about our use of deception (a <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0191308509000239">well-researched and supported method</a> of studying bias). Megan MacKenzie, the more junior author (at the time a senior lecturer), received calls threatening her with consequences for her career.</p>

<p>Although unpleasant, the reaction was revealing. It reinforces <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/ssqu.12985">other research</a> on how defensive racial majorities can be when they believe they are suspected of bias. It also complements work <a href="https://journals.sfu.ca/ijepl/index.php/ijepl/article/view/1303">showing internal resistance</a> to diversity efforts in higher education.</p>

<h2><strong>What can we do?</strong></h2>

<p>Universities pride themselves on <a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/is-meritocracy-hurting-higher-education/">being meritocracies</a>, where the best ideas and brightest minds rise to the top. But our study suggests racial bias is undermining this principle by influencing who is even considered for an academic career.</p>

<p>There is growing acknowledgement racism is a significant problem on Australian university campuses (as well as <a href="https://humanrights.gov.au/our-work/race-discrimination/publications/anti-racism-framework-perspectives-multicultural">in broader society</a>). In May, the <a href="https://humanrights.gov.au/our-work/race-discrimination/projects/study-racism-australian-universities">federal government asked</a> the Australian Human Rights Commission to study the prevalence and impact of racism at Australian universities.</p>

<p>But this study is not due to deliver its final report until June 2025, and any ensuing action will be further away still.</p>

<p>What can be done now to tackle this issue?</p>

<p>First, universities need to acknowledge academia remains overwhelmingly white and male, in spite of efforts to increase diversity.</p>

<p>Second, universities also need to acknowledge the existence of racial bias, the need for ongoing research into how it operates in higher education and the most effective strategies to tackle it.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/241352/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><span>(<strong>Author:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/megan-mackenzie-1466320">Megan MacKenzie</a>, Professor and Simons Chair in International Law and Human Security, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/simon-fraser-university-1282">Simon Fraser University</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/benjamin-e-goldsmith-1172998">Benjamin E. Goldsmith</a>, Professor of Political Science, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/australian-national-university-877">Australian National University</a>)</span></p>

<p><em>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/are-academics-more-likely-to-answer-emails-from-melissa-or-rahul-the-answer-may-not-surprise-you-241352">original article</a>.)</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rm11grs_university_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-sunil-bharti-mittal-heard-own-ai-voice-it-asked-for-large-fund-transfer-6845145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunil Bharti Mittal Heard Own AI Voice. It Asked For Large Fund Transfer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-sunil-bharti-mittal-heard-own-ai-voice-it-asked-for-large-fund-transfer-6845145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:57:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence (AI) will shape the future of the global economy and geopolitics, said Bharti Enterprises chairman, Sunil Mittal, at the NDTV World Summit, adding that AI has its risks, particularly the potential for misuse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) will shape the future of the global economy and geopolitics, said Bharti Enterprises chairman, Sunil Mittal, at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://special.ndtv.com/ndtv-world-summit-2024-167/#pfrom=home-ndtvworld_world%20site">NDTV World Summit</a>, adding that AI has its risks, particularly the potential for misuse. Mr Mittal, who heads India's second-largest telecom firm, Bharti Airtel, recounted a personal experience illustrating AI's potential dangers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He described an incident where a senior finance official in Dubai received a fraudulent call that mimicked his voice, directing a large fund transfer. But the vigilant official detected the fraud in time. Upon hearing the voice recording himself, Mr Mittal admitted he was "stunned" by the accuracy, warning that future misuse could extend to digital signatures and even visual impersonation on video calls.</p>

<p>"And anyone who would not have been vigilant may have done something about it," Mr Mittal said. "We'll have to protect our societies from the evils of AI, and yet we have to use the goodness of AI because those companies, and nations that will not adopt AI will be left behind. So this is a conundrum for every time you get a new technology into place, there are pluses and minuses. I remain very optimistic about the benefit of AI that the human race will achieve and be able to do jobs which are otherwise very difficult to perform."</p>

<p>Mr Mittal said that AI is already transforming operations within Bharti Airtel. Routine and repetitive tasks, such as those in call centres and workforce management, are being replaced by AI, leading to greater efficiency but also reducing traditional jobs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Just 10 years back, every time a customer had to be onboarded onto a mobile phone, there was a physical form to be filled out. There were runners on scooters and more bikes who would take those forms to a different centre. From there, they would fax it to another place...in 10 years' time, it seems like a joke today," Mr Mittal said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Barti Group chief said that rapid advancements in AI will impact everything from global economies to geopolitics.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"AI will be one of the most important drivers of economy, politics, and geopolitics. But there will be misuse as well, and we will need to be more vigilant," Mr Mittal said. "Nation states will have to come up with guardrails. One will have to be vigilant, society will have to be protected from the evils of AI. I remain very optimistic of the various use of AI."&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/sunil-mittal-ndtv_650x400_41506497896.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Mittal said that AI is already transforming operations within Bharti Airtel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wall-street-journal-new-york-post-sue-perplexity-ai-for-copyright-infringement-6845139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Wall Street Journal Sues Perplexity AI For Copyright Infringement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wall-street-journal-new-york-post-sue-perplexity-ai-for-copyright-infringement-6845139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:55:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Wall Street Journal and the New York Post filed a lawsuit in a US court on Monday against AI company Perplexity AI, alleging massive copyright infringement and trademark violations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Wall Street Journal and the New York Post filed a lawsuit in a US court on Monday against AI company Perplexity AI, alleging massive copyright infringement and trademark violations. Perplexity is one of Silicon Valley's hottest startups, whose AI powered search engine is often mentioned as a potential disruptor to Google.</p>

<p>The lawsuit in a federal court in New York accuses Perplexity of illegally copying and reproducing copyrighted content from The Wall Street Journal and the New York Post to power its AI-driven "answer engine."</p>

<p>Perplexity.ai is a question-answering platform known for its minimalist and conversational interface.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unlike ChatGPT or Anthropic's Claude, Perplexity's tool provides up-to-date answers that often include links to source materials, allowing users to verify information.</p>

<p>And unlike a classic search engine, Perplexity provides ready-made answers on its webpage making it unnecessary for users to click through to the source website.</p>

<p>According to the complaint, this constituted a "massive freeriding" on protected content that allowed the company to divert readers and revenue from the Wall Street Journal and New York Post.</p>

<p>"Unlike the business model of a traditional internet search engine, Perplexity's business model does not drive business toward content creators. To the contrary, it usurps content creators' monetization opportunities for itself," the lawsuit alleged.</p>

<p>Perplexity, which is backed by Amazon-billionaire Jeff Bezos and AI juggernaut Nvidia, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The complaint also accused Perplexity of damaging the publishers' brands by attributing false information to their publications.</p>

<p>The publishers seek injunctive relief and statutory damages up to $150,000 per infringement.</p>

<p>The plaintiffs are also requesting the destruction of any database containing their copyrighted works.</p>

<p>The move follows similar allegations by The New York Times, which has sent a cease and desist letter to Perplexity, which is a first step towards a lawsuit.</p>

<p>In a similar case, the Times filed a lawsuit last year against OpenAI, accusing the ChatGPT-maker of stealing content to train its powerful AI with copyrighted material.</p>

<p>News Corp, the owner of The Wall Street Journal and the Post, has signed a content agreement with OpenAI and the suit alleged that Perplexity ignored requests to enter into such partnerships.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bbvk8rio_perplexity-ai_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Perplexity is backed by Amazon-billionaire Jeff Bezos and AI juggernaut Nvidia (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chase-strangio-the-first-openly-transgender-lawyer-to-argue-at-us-supreme-court-6845085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chase Strangio: The First Openly Transgender Lawyer To Argue At US Top Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chase-strangio-the-first-openly-transgender-lawyer-to-argue-at-us-supreme-court-6845085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:49:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chase Strangio, 41, represents a group of transgender people who pursued a lawsuit challenging the measure that prohibits some medical treatments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An American Civil Liberties Union lawyer will make history in December as the first openly transgender attorney to argue before the US Supreme Court, opposing Tennessee's Republican-backed law banning gender-affirming medical care for transgender minors.</p>

<p>The ACLU's Chase Strangio, 41, represents a group of transgender people who pursued a lawsuit challenging the measure that prohibits medical treatments including hormones and surgeries for minors experiencing gender dysphoria.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In one of the most consequential cases of the court's current nine-month term, the nine justices will hear arguments on December 4 in an appeal by President Joe Biden's administration of a lower court's decision upholding Tennessee's ban.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Supreme Court on Monday ordered that the argument time for the ban's challengers be divided between the Justice Department and attorneys representing the original plaintiffs who sued the state. Strangio will present the arguments for these plaintiffs at the lectern in the ornate courtroom.&nbsp;</p>

<p>ACLU Legal Director Cecillia Wang called Strangio the leading US legal expert on transgender rights.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He brings to the lectern not only brilliant constitutional lawyering, but also the tenacity and heart of a civil rights champion," Wang said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Strangio, who joined the ACLU in 2013, is the co-director of its LGBTQ &amp; HIV Project, helping the organization oppose state laws targeting transgender people, including 12 legal challenges against the laws like the one at issue before the Supreme Court.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Strangio has represented people in high-profile cases including transgender student Gavin Grimm, who fought a Virginia school board to use the bathroom corresponding with his gender identity, and Chelsea Manning, a transgender former U.S. soldier who served time in prison for leaking classified documents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Justice Department, Tennessee is one of 22 states that have passed measures targeting medical interventions for adolescents with gender dysphoria. That is the clinical diagnosis for significant distress that can result from an incongruence between a person's gender identity and the sex they were assigned at birth.</p>

<p>Lawmakers supporting the restrictions have called the treatments experimental and potentially harmful. Medical associations, noting that gender dysphoria is associated with higher rates of suicide, have said gender-affirming care can be life-saving, and that long-term studies show its effectiveness.</p>

<p>Several plaintiffs - including two transgender boys, a transgender girl and their parents - sued in Tennessee to defend the treatments they have said improved their happiness and wellbeing. The Justice Department intervened in the lawsuit to also challenge the law.</p>

<p>The challengers contend that banning care for transgender youth violates the U.S. Constitution's 14th Amendment &nbsp;promise of equal protection by discriminating against these adolescents based on sex and transgender status.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a written filing, the Justice Department highlighted that one of the law's "declared purposes is to enforce gender conformity and discourage adolescents from identifying as transgender."</p>

<p>The state asked the Supreme Court to let the law stand.</p>

<p>"Tennessee lawfully exercised its power to regulate medicine by protecting minors from risky, unproven gender-transition interventions," Tennessee Attorney General Jonathan Skrmetti said in a filing.</p>

<p>A federal judge blocked the law in Tennessee in 2023, finding that it likely violates the 14th Amendment. In a 2-1 decision in 2023, the Cincinnati-based 6th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals reversed the judge's preliminary injunction.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court has confronted several cases in the past decade implicating LGBT rights. In 2015, it legalized same-sex marriage nationwide. In 2020, it ruled that a landmark federal law forbidding workplace discrimination protects gay and transgender employees. In 2023, it decided in a case from Washington state that the constitutional right to free speech allows certain businesses to refuse to provide services for same-sex weddings.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0ea6ft8g_chase-strangio-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chase Strangio has represented people in high-profile cases]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dont-risk-war-with-russia-georgias-richest-person-bidzina-ivanishvili-tells-voters-ahead-of-polls-6845022]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Don't Risk War With Russia: Georgia's Richest Person Tells Voters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dont-risk-war-with-russia-georgias-richest-person-bidzina-ivanishvili-tells-voters-ahead-of-polls-6845022]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:39:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bidzina Ivanishvili's presence looms large over this small European country caught been Russia and the West and an election that could shape its destiny.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Georgia's saviour. Russia's stooge. Philanthropist. Oligarch. Bidzina Ivanishvili has been called all these things, and more. The billionaire, Georgia's richest person and the founder of its ruling party, is seldom seen in public and, of late, almost exclusively behind bulletproof glass. Yet his presence looms large over this small European country caught been Russia and the West and an election that could shape its destiny.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili can gaze down on downtown Tbilisi from a massive steel-and-glass clifftop mansion that rears about 60 metres over the capital, complete with helipad. He indulges exotic passions like keeping sharks and zebras and collecting rare trees.</p>

<p>The 68-year-old is viewed by many friends and foes alike as Georgia's most powerful figure, or eminence grise, even though he hasn't held public office for over a decade. He has cast Saturday's election as an existential fight to prevent a "Global War Party" in the West pushing Georgia into a ruinous conflict with former overlord Russia, like he says it did with Ukraine.</p>

<p>"Georgia and Ukraine were not allowed to join NATO and were left outside," he said in a rare public appearance at a pro-government rally in Tbilisi on Apr. 29.</p>

<p>"All such decisions are made by the Global War Party, which has a decisive influence on NATO and the European Union and which only sees Georgia and Ukraine as cannon fodder."</p>

<p>While most of Georgia's 3.7 million people are keen to move closer to the West by joining the EU and NATO, and largely don't trust Russia, opinion polls show, Ivanishvili's message resounds with many who want to avoid Ukraine's fate at all costs.</p>

<p>Memories are fresh of a 2008 war with Russia over the Moscow-backed breakway regions of South Ossetia and Abkhazia, which lasted five days and ended in Georgia's defeat.</p>

<p>Oleg Machavariani's home is only six miles from South Ossetia. The 75-year-old retired civil servant fears a rerun of history should the staunchly pro-Western and anti-Russian opposition win power.</p>

<p>"I think the first thing that will happen is that we'll get sucked into war."</p>

<p>Ivanishvili's Georgian Dream is on course to become the country's most popular party in the election, opinion polls indicate, though it is set to lose ground nationally since 2020 when it won a narrow majority in parliament.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili, who was strongly pro-Western throughout his party's first decade in power, was not available to be interviewed for this article, while Georgian Dream says it remains committed to integration with the West, and to a pragmatic policy towards neighbouring Russia.</p>

<p>Reuters interviews with several former close associates of the billionaire, as well as voters on both sides of the spectrum and Georgia experts, offer a window into the influence wielded by this mysterious magnate in the South Caucasus nation.</p>

<h3><strong>'THE CONSOLIDATION OF POWER IS HUGE'</strong></h3>

<p>Allies in the highest halls of power speak of him in near-messianic terms.</p>

<p>"When the people had lost all hope forever, a man appeared who gave it back to them," two-time former Prime Minster Irakli Garibashvili said of Ivanishvili's initial election win in 2012, after which he served as premier for one year.</p>

<p>Garibashvili was among a string of officials who heaped praise on Ivanishvili, the party's honorary chair, in speeches at a rally in September when - unlike the tycoon - they weren't shielded by bulletproof glass. Current premier Irakli Kobakhidze said Ivanishvili had sacrificed everything, including his wellbeing, to deliver Georgia from political enemies.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili spent much of the 1990s in Russia, founding banking, metals and telecoms companies and growing wealthy in the chaotic aftermath of the collapse of the Soviet Union.</p>

<p>His political opponents paint a picture of a power-hungry oligarch who wields dangerous control over former Soviet state Georgia. Many dub his party "Russian Dream". Some brand him a Kremlin asset, without presenting evidence for this.</p>

<p>"He has turned Georgia into a private company, of which he is the 100% owner," said Gia Khukhashvili, Ivanishvili's former top political adviser, who helped him launch Georgian Dream before their relationship broke down in 2014 when Khukhashvili accused him of retaining power from behind the scenes.</p>

<p>Giorgi Gakharia, who served as a Georgian Dream prime minister from 2019-21 and resigned after accusing Ivanishvili of interfering in government matters, echoed the critique.</p>

<p>"The consolidation of power is huge," said Gakharia, who now leads the For Georgia party, one of four main blocs of Georgia's splintered opposition running in the Oct. 26 election.</p>

<p>"There is not even one independent institution anymore in this country," said Gakharia, who listed the heads of Georgia's central bank, electoral commission, state audit office and judiciary as all being ultimately answerable to the magnate.</p>

<p>"All these people are directly connected with Ivanishvili. They are loyal to him."</p>

<p>Georgia's justice ministry, audit office and central bank didn't respond to requests for comment. The electoral commission said suggestions it was influenced by the ruling party were "unfounded and detrimental to the integrity of the electoral process."</p>

<h3><strong>'180-DEGREE TURN' ON WEST RHETORIC</strong></h3>

<p>Since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, Ivanishvili has all but reversed Georgia's long-standing alignment with the West, one which he himself championed while prime minister in 2012-13.</p>

<p>This year, the Georgian Dream government has pushed through bills on "foreign agents", which requires organisations receiving more than 20% of funding from abroad to register as such, and cracked down on LGBT rights, decisions praised by Moscow and denounced by critics as anti-democratic and Russian-inspired.</p>

<p>The moves, along with increased anti-Western rhetoric from Tbilisi, have led to the U.S. and EU suspending some aid to Georgia and the bloc freezing the country's membership application.</p>

<p>Giorgi Margvelashvili, Georgia's president in 2013-18 and a close colleague of Ivanishvili in opposition and the early years in power, said the billionaire had appeared sincerely pro-Western while in frontline politics.</p>

<p>He described him as a calm, strategic thinker who sought to balance a pro-EU and NATO policy with an imperative to avoid provoking Georgia's vast northern neighbour.</p>

<p>Margvelashvili said there had nonetheless been a new hostility in Ivanishvili's anti-West rhetoric since the Ukraine war, a shift which seemed to him deeply out of character.</p>

<p>"We can only speculate what forced Bidzina Ivanishvili into this kind of political turmoil," Margvelashvili said. "Suddenly changing the rhetoric 180 degrees is not his style."</p>

<p>NATO agreed at a 2008 Budapest summit that Georgia would eventually become a member. That was a few months before the war with Russia, and little progress has been made since.</p>

<p>Many Georgians are wary of the ordeal of Ukraine, where the pro-Western Maidan protests of 2013-2014 ousted a pro-Russian government before Moscow annexed Crimea and began supplying arms to separatists in the country's east.</p>

<p>Russian officials have repeatedly said they don't interfere with sovereign states and have accused the West of meddling in Georgian politics. Russia's foreign spy chief Sergei Naryshkin said this month he was sure Georgians would make the "correct" choice and vote for "healthy, patriotic forces".</p>

<p>Ex-adviser Khukhashvili said Ivanishvili had told him that he left Russia after Putin's rise to power in 2000, believing the president would crack down on politically ambitious businessmen. Khukhashvili said Ivanishvili's shift in foreign policy since the Ukraine conflict was an attempt to spare himself and Georgia from Putin's wrath.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili himself took a big hit in the West in 2020, when a rogue banker at Credit Suisse embezzled about $1 billion of his cash. Though much of the money has been recovered, his allies have cited the case as proof that he is under "de facto" U.S. sanctions. The U.S. has repeatedly said that Ivanishvili hasn't been sanctioned.</p>

<h3><strong>LET 'ORDINARY PEOPLE' LEAD GEORGIA</strong></h3>

<p>Natalie Sabanadze, a former Georgian ambassador to the EU, told Reuters Georgian Dream also drew strength from the unpopularity of the opposition, which has struggled to shake off its association with the divisive figure of former Georgian leader Mikheil Saakashvili, who ruled until 2012 and is now serving a six-year jail term for abuse of power.</p>

<p>Despite deteriorating relations with the West, the ruling party can still rely on a "status-quo factor", especially among rural and public-sector workers, said Sabanadze, a senior research fellow at London think-tank Chatham House.</p>

<p>Indeed, in the poor, rural western part of Georgia where Ivanishvili grew up, he's revered by many locals as a philanthropist. Levan Ivanashvili, district mayor in the town of Sachkhere, pointed out projects financed by the favourite son: three schools, a football stadium, swimming pool, hospital and hotel, as well as a restoration of the historic castle.</p>

<p>Other voters have had enough.</p>

<p>"Mr Ivanishvili has done positive things for Georgia in the past, but he has declined, Georgia under him is declining," Nikoloz Shurgaia said at an opposition rally in Tbilisi. "Let a new generation of politicians, ordinary people, lead Georgia to a better future."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fk78p9so_bidzina-ivanishvili_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bidzina Ivanishvili is viewed by many friends and foes alike as Georgia's most powerful figure]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-vibrant-market-for-carbon-credits-soon-6845020]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NDTV World Summit: Vibrant Market For Carbon Credits Soon?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-vibrant-market-for-carbon-credits-soon-6845020]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:38:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India will open up the possibility of monetizing carbon credits, said e-mobility expert Mustafa Wajid, hinting at a vibrant trade of carbon credits between different sectors in the near future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India will open up the possibility of monetizing carbon credits, said e-mobility expert Mustafa Wajid, hinting at a vibrant trade of carbon credits between different sectors in the near future. Speaking on Day 2 of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world">NDTV World Summit</a>, the co-founder of e-mobility firm BILLIONe said the government's vision is to create a carbon market just like the stock market.</p>

<p>His remarks came at a panel discussion on 'Aligning Profit With Purpose', also attended by Gagandeep Sethi, Senior Vice-President, Integrated Operations and Sustainability and Responsibility, Pernod Ricard India, and Ajay Pillai, Partner - Sustainability and Climate Change, Deloitte.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569"><strong>NDTV World Summit: Live Coverage</strong></a></p>

<p>"Carbon credits will come. Good organisations that can adapt their processes will generate carbon credits. And there will always be a sector generating carbon debits, for example, the cement and steel industries. There will be a very vibrant market with people wanting to buy carbon credits," said Mr Wajid, citing the example of Tesla which sold carbon credits to its rivals.</p>

<p>Mr Wajid said policies are being drafted for the trade of carbon credits, but its implementation won't be without challenges. "The process to create a carbon market is on. Policies are being drafted and we are very optimistic to see it kicking off in 2026. What we did with stock markets, we can do with the carbon markets," he said.</p>

<p>"De-carbonisation and sustainability can be monetized in the future, and can add to a company's bottomlines," he added.</p>

<p><strong>Opinion | </strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/voluntary-carbon-credits-what-india-can-do-to-become-a-market-leader-5598834">Voluntary Carbon Credits: What India Can Do To Lead The Market</a></p>

<p>The three industry experts also brainstormed over how to overcome sustainability-related challenges.</p>

<p>Mr Pillai listed the challenges to the implementation of ESG, or Environmental, Social, and Governance factors in the production process across sectors. These include quality and availability of data, lack of awareness and expertise, and lack of intent. "We want to imbibe sustainability as part of our business model," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Sethi said he has found, in his personal experience, that the first few steps towards sustainability is profit neutral.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-teslas-sporty-and-trendy-robotaxi-design-is-puzzling-industry-experts-6773568">Why Tesla's Sporty And Trendy Robotaxi Design Is Puzzling Industry Experts</a></p>

<p>"Steps like a sustainable switch of fuels hardly come with a cost. It's only profit. But to have ESG at the design stage itself and re-engineering is where the largest investment will come in. We need policy support and regulatory support to make the correct decisions, but there is a lot to be done till that stage," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Pillai echoed similar views: making sustainability part of the overall business, like water conservation or handling waste. "Initially, there is a capital investment, but if you are looking at your business for a longer term, sustainability is needed. The faster you adapt it, the better you are ready for future," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g9b1q03g_ndtv-world-summit-panel-discussion_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bhutanese-pm-tshering-tobgay-on-how-india-moulded-him-i-will-tell-you-secret-6842132]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Will Tell You Secret...": Bhutanese PM On How India Moulded Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bhutanese-pm-tshering-tobgay-on-how-india-moulded-him-i-will-tell-you-secret-6842132]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:32:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay shared deep personal insights into his connection with India during his speech at the 'NDTV World Summit 2024: The India Century.']]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay shared deep personal insights into his connection with India during his speech at the 'NDTV World Summit 2024: The India Century.'</p>

<p>He revealed that not only was he born in India, but his formative years in the country played a significant role in shaping his dedication to serving Bhutan, its people, and its king.</p>

<p>"I'll tell you a secret, in fact, my Bhutanese colleagues here also don't know; I was born in India. 1965, I was born in Kalimpong. My father was serving in Kalimpong, my parents were serving - I was born there, right?" <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-south-looks-to-indias-leadership-bhutan-pm-at-ndtv-world-summit-6838260">Mr Tobgay said</a>.</p>

<p>"What moulded me to serve my king, my country, and my people would have been not necessarily Pittsburgh and Harvard, but Dr Graham's homes in Kalimpong in West Bengal. I studied 11 years in India, and you asked me how 4 years in America has moulded me!"</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/will-further-strengthen-our-ties-with-india-bhutan-pm-after-meeting-gautam-adani-6179082">Mr Tobgay</a> went on to emphasise the long-standing educational connections between Bhutan and India. He shared how many Bhutanese, himself included, were educated in Indian schools due to the lack of institutions in Bhutan at the time.</p>

<p>"From kindergarten school, from baby class till class 10, I studied in India, as indeed many other Bhutanese studied in India those days, because we did not have enough schools in Bhutan. But when we did establish schools, we did not have enough teachers, and those teachers came from India," he added.</p>

<p>"I do believe they have taught us well, because we have been able to go back home and serve our King and country and our people."</p>

<p>When asked about India's growing global influence, particularly in the 21st century, Mr Tobgay was quick to praise the country's economic strength and leadership on the world stage. "The world needs India, and I'm very happy that you identify this century as India's century.</p>

<p>You asked me about Prime Minister Modi and his historic third term - why do you call it India's century? For many reasons! India has the largest population in the world - 1.45 billion. It's growing. It's projected to reach 1.6 billion."</p>

<p>Mr Tobgay also pointed out India's economic prowess and consumer base, noting, "India has a booming economy - it's crossed 3 trillion US Dollars. It should have crossed 5 trillion US Dollars had it not been for COVID. India has the biggest consumer base. India has almost 35 million successful people in the diaspora throughout the world, particularly in the advanced countries."</p>

<p>"By every measure, yes, this is India's century. But by one measure you stand out, and that is leadership. India's leadership, and trust in that leadership," he concluded.</p>

<p>The summit marked another milestone in reflecting on India's role not only as a regional power but also as a global leader, poised for further growth in the decades to come.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/etsqd4q_bhutan-prime-minister-dasho-tshering-tobgay_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tshering Tobgay pointed out India's economic prowess and consumer base.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-south-korea-a-new-way-to-buy-groceries-flying-shopping-cart-6844957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In South Korea, A New Way To Buy Groceries: "Flying Shopping Cart"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-south-korea-a-new-way-to-buy-groceries-flying-shopping-cart-6844957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:27:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean researchers have developed a transport drone flying on multiple flexible rotors that self-correct to stay level in flight and can be used as a "flying shopping cart" to carry goods over uneven terrain such as stairs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean researchers have developed a transport drone flying on multiple flexible rotors that self-correct to stay level in flight and can be used as a "flying shopping cart" to carry goods over uneven terrain such as stairs.</p>

<p>The prototype developed by a Seoul National University of Science and Technology team has a cargo platform mounted on top of a multi-rotor drone and is handled by a person using gentle force to guide the hovering aircraft.</p>

<p>Members of the team demonstrated the hovering platform with a handle bar much like one on a push shopping cart moving objects up and down stairs and loading boxes on top as it hovered mid-air and maintained its balance by using a centre of mass estimation algorithm.</p>

<p>To move objects over uneven terrain or stairs when a wheeled cart cannot, the drone responds to human control with what the developers call a physical human-robot interaction technique that anticipates human intentions for smooth flight, said Lee Seung-jae, professor of mechanical system design engineering.</p>

<p>But the broader focus of Lee's team is not on developing a shopping cart to be used over steps, but instead on applications that would use a drone with reliable horizontal stability without pitching and rolling.</p>

<p>"The Palletrone can be more than a flying shopping cart," he said, referring to the name the team gave the prototype by joining the words pallet, which is the platform for cargo on top, and drone.</p>

<p>Lee's team has tested a platform to carry objects up to 3 kg (6.6 lbs), and concedes commercial applications for cargo transportation at such a small weight easily carried by humans is limited.</p>

<p>Still, the mechanism that allows the drone to change directions in flight without banking and to maintain level attitude has applications for delivering sensitive or fragile payloads, Lee said.</p>

<p>But Lee's team is looking further ahead for the technology's potential use for uncrewed "flying taxis" carrying humans and for drones to be "refuelled" mid-air, by changing batteries so the aircraft do not need to return to base for a fresh charge.</p>

<p>Multi-rotor drones are inherently limited in speed and range compared to fixed-wing drones but have better control and manoeuvrability, including the ability to hover in flight.</p>

<p>They have been used to deliver cargo, food and medical supplies, but commercial applications have been limited largely because it is impractical to increase the size of the battery enough to transport a heavier payload over a longer distance.</p>

<p>Seoul Tech's work was published in IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters this year, the publication of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers based in New York.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vp03ravg_south-korea-flying-shopping-cart-reuters-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Members of the team demonstrated the hovering platform with a handle bar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-men-accused-of-killing-air-india-bombing-suspect-plea-guilty-6844828]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Men, Accused Of Killing Air India Bombing Suspect, Plead Guilty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-men-accused-of-killing-air-india-bombing-suspect-plea-guilty-6844828]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:04:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two men accused of killing Ripudaman Singh Malik, a Sikh man acquitted in the tragic 1985 Air India Kanishka terrorist bombing case, have pleaded guilty to second-degree murder in a Canadian court, according to media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two men accused of killing Ripudaman Singh Malik, a Sikh man acquitted in the tragic 1985 Air India Kanishka terrorist bombing case, have pleaded guilty to second-degree murder in a Canadian court, according to media reports. Tanner Fox and Jose Lopez entered the pleas in the British Columbia (BC) Supreme Court on Monday on the eve of their trial for the killing of 75-year-old Malik, who was shot several times outside his family business on the morning of July 14, 2022.</p>

<p>Malik was shot dead in Surrey, British Columbia in 2022. He and co-accused Ajaib Singh Bagri were acquitted in 2005 of mass murder and conspiracy charges related to the two bombings in 1985 that killed 331 people.</p>

<p>In the court in New Westminster on Monday, both Fox and Lopez pleaded guilty to the lesser charge of second-degree murder, the Global News reported.</p>

<p>The court heard an agreed statement of facts that revealed the two men had been hired to kill Malik, the report added.</p>

<p>"What we know from the agreed statement of facts is that there was some type of financial incentive that was involved in the commission of this crime, but in terms of any other specifics, it is another one of those situations where unfortunately it is just something that we as people on the outside will probably never know," Lopez' lawyer Gloria Ng told Global News.</p>

<p>"One of the things we certainly have in the forefront of our minds is the youth of our client - Lopez is a very young man and we are certainly hopeful with prospects for rehabilitation." In a statement, Malik's family described him as a "father, brother, husband and grandfather as well as a tireless community leader," the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation reported on Monday.</p>

<p>"While we are grateful that the shooters are being brought to justice, we know that nothing will erase the pain that we have gone through losing a family member in this way," the family said.</p>

<p>"However, the work is not complete. Tanner Fox and Jose Lopez were hired to commit this murder. Until the parties responsible for hiring them and directing this assassination are brought to justice, the work remains incomplete." The family called on the killers to "co-operate with the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) in bringing those that hired you to justice." Crown and defence lawyers have agreed that Fox and Lopez should not be eligible for parole for 20 years. And they will next appear in court on October 31 for sentencing.</p>

<p>The 1985 Air India bombing is among the worst terrorist attacks in Canadian history and in the history of the airline.</p>

<p>On June 23, 1985, Air India flight 182, carrying 329 people, including 268 Canadian citizens and 24 Indian citizens, flew from Toronto and stopped in Montreal from where it was en route to London and then onwards to its final destination Bombay.</p>

<p>The plane was flying 31,000 feet above the Atlantic Ocean when a suitcase bomb exploded in the front cargo, killing all on board.</p>

<p>Another bomb was meant to be planted in an Air India flight scheduled to take off from Japan but it exploded at Tokyo's Narita airport killing two baggage handlers.</p>

<p>Inderjit Singh Reyat was convicted on various charges and spent 30 years in prison for helping to make the bombs, and for lying during trials, including Malik's. He was released in 2016 after serving two-thirds of his perjury sentence.</p>

<p>Reyat was the only person convicted for the Kanishka bombing.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/fel7na5g_ripudaman-singh_625x300_16_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ripudaman Singh Malik was shot dead in Surrey, British Columbia in 2022]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-oscar-kills-6-in-cuba-amid-major-power-outage-6844816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hurricane Oscar Kills 6 In Cuba Amid Major Power Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-oscar-kills-6-in-cuba-amid-major-power-outage-6844816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:01:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cuba was bathed in darkness on Sunday when Hurricane Oscar made landfall in the eastern part of the country, causing several deaths and damage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Hurricane Oscar left six people dead after hitting Cuba over the weekend during a major power blackout, authorities said Monday, as electricity was restored to most of the capital. The lights went out for the Communist-run country's 10 million people on Friday after the collapse of the nation's largest power plant crippled the whole grid.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">By Monday afternoon, nearly 90 percent of customers in Havana -- home to some two million people -- had power again, the capital's electricity company said in a report published by state-run news portal Cubadebate.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"Of course I'm happy!" Olga Gomez, a 59-year-old housewife in Havana, said after the lights came back on.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"I have an elderly senile mother of 85 and an autistic son. It's very difficult when there's no power," she told AFP.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Many residents outside Havana, however, remained without electricity, according to the authorities.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Cuba was still bathed in darkness on Sunday when Hurricane Oscar made landfall in the eastern part of the country as a Category 1 storm, causing several deaths and damage.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"Regrettably, according to preliminary information, six lives have been lost,"&nbsp;President Miguel Diaz-Canel&nbsp;said in a televised remarks.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">The storm caused severe damage in the eastern province of Guantanamo, he said.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Oscar weakened into a tropical storm as it moved inland but was still expected to bring "significant, life-threatening flash flooding along with mudslides," the US National Hurricane Center warned.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Roofs and the walls of houses were damaged, and electricity poles and trees felled, state television reported.</p>

<h3 data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody"><strong>'Feel like crying'</strong></h3>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">With concerns of instability rising in a country already battling sky-high inflation and shortages of food, medicine, fuel and water, Diaz-Canel warned Sunday that his government would&nbsp;not tolerate attempts to "disturb public order."</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">In July 2021, blackouts sparked an unprecedented outpouring of public anger, with thousands of Cubans taking to the street and chanting slogans including "Freedom!" and "We are hungry."</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Residents voiced frustration at the latest power outage, which crippled businesses and caused food in fridges to go bad.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"I feel like crying, like screaming. Honestly, I don't know what I'm going to do," said Kenia Sierra, a housewife.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Dozens of people took to the streets over the weekend in one neighborhood, banging pots and pans and shouting "Turn on the lights."</p>

<h3 data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody"><strong>Decrepit infrastructure</strong></h3>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">The power grid failed in a chain reaction Friday due to the unexpected shutdown of the biggest of the island's eight decrepit coal-fired power plants, according to the head of electricity supply at the energy ministry, Lazaro Guerra.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Power was briefly restored Sunday to a few hundred thousand inhabitants before the grid failed again, according to the national electric utility UNE.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Authorities have suspended classes and business activities until Wednesday, with only hospitals and essential services remaining operational.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Cuba generates only a third of the electricity it needs, so to bolster the grid it has leased seven floating power plants from Turkish companies and also added many small diesel-powered generators.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">The country's main power plant was due to be reconnected to the national grid on Monday.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Diaz-Canel blamed the situation on Cuba's difficulties in acquiring fuel for its power plants, which he attributed to the tightening, during Donald Trump's presidency, of a six-decade-long US trade embargo.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">But the island is in the throes of a broader economic malaise --- the worst economic crisis, according to experts, since the collapse of the Soviet Union, which heavily subsidized Cuba.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"Cubans are tired of so much... There's no life here, (people) can't take it anymore," said Serguei Castillo, a 68-year-old bricklayer.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f9tejir8_hurricane-oscar-in-cuba_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cuba's power grid failed in a chain reaction amid Hurricane Oscar landfall]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-lidia-thorpe-the-australian-senator-who-shouted-you-re-not-my-king-to-charles-iii-6844640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Lidia Thorpe, Australian Senator Who Heckled King Charles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-lidia-thorpe-the-australian-senator-who-shouted-you-re-not-my-king-to-charles-iii-6844640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 10:38:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lidia Thorpe has long been critical of the British monarchy, calling King Charles "not the legitimate sovereign of these lands".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lidia Thorpe, an Independent Australian senator, has accused King Charles of committing genocide of Indigenous people and shouted, "You're not my king." The 51-year-old interrupted King Charles's parliamentary reception on Monday, saying, "You committed genocide against our people. Give us our land back. Give us what you stole from us - our bones, our skulls, our babies, our people." A video of Ms Thorpe's remarks before she was whisked away by security personnel went viral on social media.</p>

<h3><strong>Who is Lidia Thorpe?</strong></h3>

<p>Born in 1973 in Carlton, in the state of Victoria, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-lidia-thorpe-give-our-land-back-says-lawmaker-to-king-charles-at-australian-parliament-6836254">Lidia Thorpe</a> belongs to the Gunnai, Gunditjmara, and Djab Wurrung peoples and has been a prominent figure in politics and advocacy for Aboriginal causes.</p>

<p>She has a Diploma in Community Development from Swinburne University of Technology and a graduate certificate in public sector management. Ms Thorpe is known for her strong opposition to monarchy and advocacy for Indigenous rights.</p>

<h3><strong>Lidia Thorpe's&nbsp;political career</strong></h3>

<p>Lidia Thorpe was first elected to the Victorian Legislative Assembly from the Northcote seat in a 2017 by-election. She received over 45 percent primary votes. In December 2018, she lost her seat to Labour candidate Kat Theophanous.</p>

<p>In 2020, Victorian Greens members preselected Lidia Thorpe for the federal Senate seat, which fell vacant after the resignation of Richard Di Natale. Her election to the Senate also made her the first Aboriginal woman to represent Victoria in the Senate. She is also the first Aboriginal federal parliamentarian from the Greens.</p>

<p>After her re-election in May 2022, the Greens party room elected Lidia Thorpe as the party's deputy leader in the Senate. She quit the Greens in February 2023 after the party threw its weight behind the Indigenous voice to parliament referendum, a reform Ms Thorpe and some of her supporters did not approve of, The Guardian reported.</p>

<h3><strong>Why did Lidia Thorpe confront King Charles?</strong></h3>

<p>After her outburst at King Charles, Lidia Thorpe was escorted out of the venue. While the parliamentary reception continued, she later told the BBC that her goal was to send "a clear message" to Charles, stressing that "to be sovereign you have to be of the land. He is not of this land."</p>

<p>What are Lidia Thorpe's views on the British monarchy?</p>

<p>Lidia Thorpe has long been critical of the British monarchy, calling King Charles "not the legitimate sovereign of these lands" and accusing the institution of committing genocide against Indigenous Australians.</p>

<p>"How can he stand up there and say he's the King of our country - he's stolen so much wealth from our people and from our land and he needs to give that back. And he needs to entertain a conversation for a peace treaty in this country," she told the BBC.</p>

<p>She advocates for a treaty between Aboriginal and non-Aboriginal Australians to address historical wrongs. Ms Thorpe believes that moving towards a republic through a treaty process can help resolve "unfinished business."</p>

<p>She has been involved in Indigenous activism for many years, even before entering politics. She has campaigned for justice system reform, environmental issues, and Indigenous land rights. Lidia Thorpe's activism is deeply rooted in her upbringing. "I had no choice in being influenced by black activists and the black struggle of my people...I was born into it and I don't know anything else," she said in 2022.</p>

<p>Lidia Thorpe has a history of high-profile protests. In 2020, during her swearing-in ceremony as a senator, she raised a black power salute while wearing a traditional possum-skin cloak and holding an Aboriginal message stick. The stick bore 441 marks to symbolise Aboriginal deaths in custody following a royal commission in 1991. In 2022, after being re-elected, she referred to the late Queen Elizabeth II as "the colonising Her Majesty" during her oath, for which she was required to repeat the correct wording.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ipu0ak0g_lidia-thorpe_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>