<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:24:39 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-days-extraordinary-us-presidential-election-enters-the-homestretch-6209484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[100 days: Extraordinary US Presidential Election Enters The Homestretch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-days-extraordinary-us-presidential-election-enters-the-homestretch-6209484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:03:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 100-day sprint to the US election began Sunday, the final act of a campaign transformed by an assassination attempt and the stunning exit of President Joe Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 100-day sprint to the US election began Sunday, the final act of a campaign transformed by an assassination attempt and the stunning exit of President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>After weeks of infighting and despondency over Biden's candidacy, Democrats have consolidated behind Vice President Kamala Harris, radically reshaping the race to November 5 that was fast becoming Republican nominee Donald Trump's to lose.</p>

<p>Harris's candidacy has clearly reinvigorated the Democratic campaign, which said Sunday it had raised $200 million -- mostly from first-time donors -- since Biden dropped out and endorsed his vice president a week ago.</p>

<p>A new Wall Street Journal poll showed Harris had closed Biden's six-point deficit with Trump to just two points -- well within the margin of error -- with boosted support from Black, Latino and young voters.</p>

<p>But Republican pollster David Lee, who conducted the Journal survey, cautioned Democrats not to get carried away by the race tightening.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is in a far better position in this election when compared to a similar time in the 2020 election," Lee said.</p>

<p>If the race is at a dead heat nationally, the advantage still lies with Trump given the mathematics of the Electoral College system for electing the president.</p>

<p>Trump's 2016 victory over Hillary Clinton came despite losing the country-wide popular vote by nearly three million ballots.</p>

<h3><strong>'We are the underdogs'</strong></h3>

<p>"We are the underdogs in this race," Harris acknowledged at a fundraising event on Saturday.</p>

<p>"But this is a people-powered campaign and we have momentum," she added.</p>

<p>The Democratic convention in mid-August will seek to keep that momentum going with a jubilant celebration of Harris's candidacy.</p>

<p>It all looked so different just a month ago.</p>

<p>Dogged by voters' concerns about his age and mental acuity, the 81-year-old Biden was an outside bet at best, trailing his predecessor in the first presidential rematch since Dwight Eisenhower trounced Adlai Stevenson in 1956.</p>

<p>Biden's dismal June 27 debate showing ignited alarm and panic within his party.</p>

<p>The flames were fanned by a flawless show of unity behind 78-year-old Trump at the Republican national convention -- an event galvanized by the failed bid, just days earlier, to assassinate the former president at a rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>After an initial show of defiance, Biden bowed to the inevitable and dropped out last weekend.</p>

<p>Harris, a generation younger at 59, threw her hat in the ring -- turning what had been a stale contest between two unpopular, aging, white male candidates into a dynamic and unpredictable showdown.</p>

<p>The final result on November 5 will likely be determined by around 100,000 independent, undecided voters in a handful of battleground states that both campaigns will target exhaustively over the coming three months.</p>

<h3><strong>The Harris honeymoon</strong></h3>

<p>The challenge for Harris is substantial. Once the Republicans have adapted to her candidacy and honed their attack lines, they are set to hammer her over key voter issues such as immigration and rising prices.</p>

<p>Democratic strategist James Carville told MSNBC that Democrats needed to cut the happy talk and prepare for the coming storm.</p>

<p>"They're coming at us and they're going to keep coming. And this kind of giddy elation is not going to be very helpful much longer because that's now what we're going to be faced with," he said.</p>

<p>Even former president Barack Obama has cautioned against hubris, underlining Harris's underdog status and the need for her to earn the trust of voters.</p>

<p>Trump, who has seen his favorability ratings tick upward since the July 13 attempt on his life and the successful Republican convention, made his attack priorities clear at a rally Saturday in the traditionally Democratic state of Minnesota.</p>

<p>Labelling Harris a "crazy liberal" and a "radical left lunatic," Trump lied to make her sound like an extremist on abortion and made fun of her laugh.</p>

<p>"We have a brand-new victim," he told his cheering supporters.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fm0l6m_kamala-harris_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The challenge for Kamala Harris is substantial]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golan-heights-the-disputed-territory-between-israel-and-syria-6209083]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Golan Heights, The Disputed Territory Between Israel And Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golan-heights-the-disputed-territory-between-israel-and-syria-6209083]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 20:53:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Golan Heights, a rocky plateau where 12 youths were killed Saturday amid clashes between Lebanon's Hezbollah and Israeli forces, is a strategic territory partially captured by Israel from Syria.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Golan Heights, a rocky plateau where 12 youths were killed Saturday amid clashes between Lebanon's Hezbollah and Israeli forces, is a strategic territory partially captured by Israel from Syria.</p>

<p>Following the conquest of about two-thirds of the plateau during the 1967 Arab-Israeli war, Israel 1981 annexed the area in a move not recognised by the international community, with the exception of the United States since 2019.</p>

<p>Rich in water, the Golan Heights overlooks northern Israel's Galilee region and the Sea of Galilee and dominates the route to Damascus on the Syrian-controlled side.</p>

<h3><strong>Annexation&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Golan, the region's biblical Hebrew name, or Jawlan in Arabic, has been coveted by empires and foreign rulers for millennia.</p>

<p>It was occupied by Herod, the Franks, the Ottomans and others, and eventually made part of Syria which gained its independence from the French in 1946.</p>

<p>Most of the territory was captured by Israel on June 9, 1967, after fierce battles with the Syrian army which had been shelling Israeli positions below.</p>

<p>An additional pocket of about 510 square kilometres (nearly 200 square miles) was seized by Israel during the 1973 war, but was returned to Syria the following year under an armistice agreement along with a small part of the area occupied in 1967.</p>

<p>The 1974 agreement created a demilitarised buffer zone, and since then a UN observer force has been monitoring the ceasefire line on the Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Approximately 1,200 square kilometres of the Golan Heights, which also borders Lebanon and Jordan, were annexed by Israel on December 14, 1981.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of Syrian as well as Palestinian residents fled or were expelled from the Golan Heights when Israel seized it, though some remained in the Israeli-controlled part.</p>

<p>Today, about 25,000 Israeli settlers live there alongside some 23,000 members of the Druze community, which follows an offshoot of Shiite Islam.</p>

<p>The Golan Druze largely identify as Syrian while having resident status, rather than citizenship, in Israel.</p>

<h3><strong>Water</strong></h3>

<p>The volcanic plateau is home to significant water sources such as the Banyas, which feeds the Jordan River.</p>

<p>The Hasbani Stream, which finds it origin in Lebanon, flows through the Golan Heights before emptying into the Jordan, as does the Dan Stream.</p>

<p>In the 1990s, Israeli-Syrian peace negotiations stalled over the issue of the Golan, with Damascus demanding the territory's complete return up to the shores of the Sea of Galilee.</p>

<p>Apple production is a key source of income for farmers on the Golan Heights, though its rocky areas limit agricultural cultivation.</p>

<p>In the years preceding the 1967 war, the issue of water resources on the Golan was a major point of contention between Israel and Syria.</p>

<h3><strong>Conflict&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Israel and Syria remain officially in a state of war, though the ceasefire line has remained relatively calm over the decades.</p>

<p>Tensions have built up as Lebanon's Hezbollah armed group and Iran, two regional foes of Israel, grew closer to the regime of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<p>Since the Syrian war broke out in 2011, Israel has struck its northern neighbour hundreds of times, mainly targeting army positions and Iran-backed fighters including from Hezbollah.</p>

<p>But tensions soared since Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel triggered the ongoing war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Hamas ally Hezbollah, which has traded regular cross-border fire with Israeli forces since October 8, has launched rockets at the Golan Heights several times.</p>

<p>The Lebanese group says its attacks on Israel are in support of Hamas.</p>

<p>While Israel has evacuated most towns and villages along its border with Lebanon in the wake of the near-daily clashes, residents of the Golan area have remained there.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities said 12 children and teenagers, aged between 10 and 16 years, were killed by a Hezbollah rocket that hit the Druze town of Majdal Shams on Saturday.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which claimed numerous attacks on Israeli positions that day in response to a deadly raid on southern Lebanon, has denied responsibility.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/minnem2_golan-heights-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tensions soared since Hamas' October 7 attack on Israel triggered the ongoing Gaza war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-antony-blinken-hold-wide-ranging-talks-on-regional-global-issues-6208926]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar, Antony Blinken Hold Talks On Regional, Global Issues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-antony-blinken-hold-wide-ranging-talks-on-regional-global-issues-6208926]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 20:23:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday held "wide-ranging" talks with his American counterpart Antony Blinken against the backdrop of an unease in India-US ties following Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia three weeks back.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday held "wide-ranging" talks with his American counterpart Antony Blinken against the backdrop of an unease in India-US ties following Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia three weeks back.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar and Blinken are in Tokyo to attend a meeting of foreign ministers of the four-nation grouping Quad or Quadrilateral coalition on Monday.</p>

<p>The talks between the external affairs minister and the US secretary of state also came amid Washington consistently seeking accountability from New Delhi in the case relating to the alleged foiled plot to kill Khalistani terrorist Gurupatwant Singh Pannun in New York.</p>

<p>It is not immediately clear whether Prime Minister Modi's visit to Russia and the murder-for-hire plot figured in the Jaishankar-Blinken talks.</p>

<p>In a post on 'X', Mr Jaishankar said he and Blinken had a wide-ranging discussion on regional and global issues.</p>

<p>"Great to catch up with@SecBlinken in Tokyo today," he said.</p>

<p>"Our bilateral agenda progresses steadily. Also had a wide-ranging discussion on regional and global issues," Mr Jaishankar added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Great to catch up with <a href="https://twitter.com/SecBlinken?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SecBlinken</a> in Tokyo today.<br />
<br />
Our bilateral agenda progresses steadily. Also had a wide ranging discussion on regional and global issues.<br />
<br />
Look forward to attending the Quad FMM tomorrow.<br />
<br />
?? ?? <a href="https://t.co/TMGwHKHciT">pic.twitter.com/TMGwHKHciT</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1817440239750676617?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In his post on X, Blinken wrote that he met Mr Jaishankar "to deepen U.S.-India collaboration and affirm our shared commitment to regional peace, security, and prosperity."&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Met with Indian External Affairs Minister <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DrSJaishankar</a> to deepen U.S.-India collaboration and affirm our shared commitment to regional peace, security, and prosperity. <a href="https://t.co/sHSSH3uTtq">pic.twitter.com/sHSSH3uTtq</a></p>
— Secretary Antony Blinken (@SecBlinken) <a href="https://twitter.com/SecBlinken/status/1817539001030512845?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It is learnt that the Russia-Ukraine conflict and the overall situation in Gaza figured in the talks.</p>

<p>The US and several of its allies were outraged over the timing of Modi's July 8 to 9 visit to Moscow as it coincided with the NATO summit in Washington. Some Western capitals were also learnt to be peeved over Modi choosing Russia for his first bilateral trip in his third term.</p>

<p>US Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia Donald Lu told a US Congressional hearing on Tuesday that the US was disappointed by the "symbolism" and "timing" of Modi's visit to Russia.</p>

<p>The Biden administration official especially highlighted that the Indian prime minister paid the visit to Moscow when Washington was hosting a summit of the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation (NATO).</p>

<p>New Delhi on Thursday rejected Lu's comments and asserted that all countries have the "freedom of choice" in a multipolar world and everyone should be mindful of such realities.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, India and Ukraine are planning a visit to Kyiv by the Indian prime minister next month.</p>

<p>The India-US ties also came under some unease following the alleged murder-for-hire plot.</p>

<p>In November last year, US federal prosecutors charged Indian national Nikhil Gupta with working with an Indian government employee in the foiled plot to kill Pannun in New York.</p>

<p>Pannun, wanted in India on terror charges, holds dual citizenship of the US and Canada.</p>

<p>Nikhil Gupta, who was arrested in the Czech Republic in June last year, was extradited to the US last month.</p>

<p>Following the allegations by the US, India appointed a high-level inquiry committee to look into the inputs provided by the US on the plot.</p>

<p>In April, The Washington Post named an Indian official for the alleged plot.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rs98hd6g_s-jaishankar-and-antony-blinken_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two had a wide-ranging discussion on regional and global issues.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-israel-hezbollah-are-fighting-and-what-is-the-impact-so-far-6208718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Israel, Hezbollah Are Fighting And What's The Impact So Far]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-israel-hezbollah-are-fighting-and-what-is-the-impact-so-far-6208718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 19:44:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A deadly rocket strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights has added to concerns that Israel and the Iran-backed Lebanese group Hezbollah could be sucked into a full-scale war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A deadly rocket strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights has added to concerns that Israel and the Iran-backed Lebanese group Hezbollah could be sucked into a full-scale war - something they have both previously indicated they want to avoid but for which they have also said they are ready.</p>

<p>Israel said on Sunday it would strike hard at Hezbollah after accusing the group of killing 12 children and teenagers in a rocket attack on a football field in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights. Hezbollah denied any responsibility for the attack on Majdal Shams, the deadliest in Israel or Israeli-annexed territory since Hamas' Oct. 7 assault sparked the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>This is the background to hostilities between Israel and Hezbollah:</p>

<h3><strong>Why Are They Fighting?</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah began trading fire with Israel on Oct. 8, a day after the Palestinian group Hamas attacked communities in southern Israel and sparked the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, a Hamas ally, says its attacks aim to support Palestinians who are under Israeli bombardment in Gaza.</p>

<p>The Gaza war has drawn in Iran-backed operatives across the region. Hezbollah is widely deemed the most powerful member of the Iran-backed network, known as the Axis of Resistance.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said repeatedly it will not halt its attacks on Israel unless a ceasefire in Gaza comes into force.</p>

<p>While linked to Gaza, the conflict has its own dynamics.</p>

<p>Israel and Hezbollah have fought numerous wars.</p>

<p>The last was in 2006.</p>

<p>Israel has long viewed Hezbollah as the biggest threat at its borders and has been deeply alarmed by its growing arsenal, and the foothold it has established in Syria.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's ideology is largely defined by conflict with Israel. It was founded by Iran's Revolutionary Guards in 1982 to fight Israeli forces that had invaded Lebanon that year, and waged years of guerrilla war that led Israel to withdraw from south Lebanon in 2000.</p>

<p>Hezbollah deems Israel an illegitimate state established on occupied Palestinian lands and wants to see it gone.</p>

<h3><strong>What's The Impact So Far?</strong></h3>

<p>The current conflict has already taken a toll on both sides.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of people have been forced to flee their homes on both sides of the border. Israeli airstrikes have pounded areas where Hezbollah operates in southern Lebanon and struck the Bekaa Valley near the Syrian border.</p>

<p>Israel has also occasionally hit elsewhere, notably killing a senior Hamas commander in Beirut on Jan. 2.</p>

<p>Israeli strikes have killed some 350 Hezbollah fighters in Lebanon and more than 100 civilians, including medics, children and journalists, according to security and medical sources and a Reuters tally of death notifications issued by Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said after Saturday's attack the death count among civilians killed in Hezbollah attacks had risen to 23 since October, along with at least 17 soldiers. Hezbollah denied it was responsible for Saturday's attack.</p>

<p>In Israel, the displacement of so many Israelis is a big political issue. Officials had hoped they would be able to go home for the school year beginning Sept. 1 but that has looked increasingly unlikely as the standoff has continued.</p>

<h3><strong>How Much Worse Could It Get?</strong></h3>

<p>A lot. Despite the ferocity of these hostilities, this is still seen as a relatively contained confrontation.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned in December that Beirut would be turned "into Gaza" if Hezbollah started an all-out war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has previously signalled it is not seeking to widen the conflict while also saying it is ready to fight any war imposed on it and warning that it has used only a small part of its capabilities so far.</p>

<p>Any move by Israel to expand the conflict would be met by "devastation, destruction and displacement" in Israel, Hezbollah deputy leader Sheikh Naim Qassem said in an interview with Al Jazeera in June.</p>

<p>Past wars have inflicted heavy damage.</p>

<p>In 2006, Israeli strikes levelled large areas of Beirut's Hezbollah-controlled southern suburbs, knocked out Beirut airport, and hit roads, bridges and other infrastructure. Nearly 1 million people in Lebanon fled their homes.</p>

<p>In Israel, the impact included 300,000 people fleeing their homes to escape Hezbollah rockets and some 2,000 homes destroyed.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has a far bigger arsenal than in 2006, including rockets it says can hit all parts of Israel.</p>

<p>It has demonstrated advances in its weaponry since October, shooting down Israeli drones, launching its own explosive drones into Israel, and firing more sophisticated guided missiles.</p>

<p>Israeli troops have invaded Lebanon several times in the past, reaching as far as Beirut in the 1982 invasion that aimed to crush Lebanon-based Palestinian guerrillas.</p>

<h3><strong>Is Escalation Avoidable?</strong></h3>

<p>Much will depend on what happens in Gaza, where efforts to agree a ceasefire and a return of Israeli hostages have faltered. A ceasefire there could help bring about a rapid de-escalation of tensions in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>The United States, which deems Hezbollah a terrorist group, has been at the heart of diplomatic efforts aimed at easing the conflict.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has signalled its eventual openness to an agreement that benefits Lebanon, but has said there can be no discussions until Israel halts the Gaza offensive.</p>

<p>Israel has also said it would prefer a diplomatic settlement that would restore security in the north, but says it is also prepared for a military offensive to achieve the same goal.</p>

<p>The U.S. official at the heart of diplomatic contacts, Amos Hochstein, brokered an unlikely diplomatic deal between Lebanon and Israel in 2022 over their disputed maritime boundary.</p>

<p>Hochstein said on May 30 he did not expect peace between Hezbollah and Israel but that a set of understandings could remove some of the impetus for conflict and establish a recognised border between Lebanon and Israel.</p>

<p>A French proposal submitted to Beirut in February included elite Hezbollah fighters withdrawing 10 km (6 miles) from the frontier and negotiations aimed at settling disputes over the land border.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5ljfarso_israel-hezbollah_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mobile-internet-connection-restored-in-violence-hit-bangladesh-6208654]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mobile Internet Connection Restored In Violence-Hit Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mobile-internet-connection-restored-in-violence-hit-bangladesh-6208654]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 19:32:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The mobile internet connection was restored in Bangladesh on Sunday, 10 days after it was restricted by the authorities across the country to stop the spread of fake news on social media amidst the deadly nationwide violence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mobile internet connection was restored in Bangladesh on Sunday, 10 days after it was restricted by the authorities across the country to stop the spread of fake news on social media amidst the deadly nationwide violence over reforms in the quota system in government jobs.</p>

<p>Addressing a press conference, Minister of State for Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Zunaid Ahmed Palak announced that 5GB internet will be given for free to all users for three days after the connection is restored, the Dhaka Tribune newspaper reported.</p>

<p>The mobile internet connectivity was restored at around 3:00 pm local time.</p>

<p>Users of Robi, Grameenphone, Banglalink and other operators in Dhaka said they could access the internet through their phones around 3 pm, the report said.</p>

<p>On July 18, the government shut down mobile internet following the escalation of violence across the country.</p>

<p>At the time, Palak said the decision was made "in light of the current crisis in the country and to stop the spread of fake news on social media", The Daily Star newspaper reported.</p>

<p>The next day, amid escalating violence, the Department of Disaster Management building was set on fire, adjacent to which was a data centre. While Internet Service Providers Association of Bangladesh (ISPAB) officials said that the fire might cut 30-40 per cent of the bandwidth supply, broadband internet connection for the entire country was disrupted within an hour.</p>

<p>Bangladesh stayed disconnected from both broadband and mobile internet between July 18 and July 23, when broadband internet was restored in stages.</p>

<p>However, mobile internet remained unavailable until Sunday.</p>

<p>Regarding access to social media platforms, Palak said the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has sent letters to authorities of social media platforms, including Facebook, Tiktok and YouTube.</p>

<p>"Their representatives have to come to Dhaka by July 31 to give explanations. Then, after discussing it with them, we will make a decision," he said.</p>

<p>The BTRC is responsible for regulating all matters related to telecommunications in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Bangladesh witnessed violent clashes between the police and mostly student protesters demanding an end to a controversial quota system that reserved 30 per cent of government jobs for relatives of veterans who fought in Bangladesh's War of Independence in 1971.</p>

<p>The internet and mobile services were snapped following the countrywide violence.</p>

<p>On Monday last, the supreme court slashed the veterans' quota to just 5 per cent. Thus, 93 per cent of civil service jobs will be merit-based while the remaining 2 per cent reserved for members of ethnic minorities, transgender and physically challenged people.</p>

<p>The violence has reportedly killed more than 100 people, according to local newspapers. However, there are no official figures available for deaths.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Tuesday defended her decision to enforce a curfew with a shoot-on-sight order following the clashes, asserting that tough measures were taken to ensure the security of the lives and properties of the people.</p>

<p>Bangladesh crawled back to normalcy on Wednesday with rush hour traffic returning to streets in the capital, and limited reopening of banks, garment factories and internet services.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7ioml3tg_bangladesh-clashes-afp-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mobile internet connectivity was restored at around 3:00 pm local time. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-rail-chief-shares-big-update-on-paralysed-train-networks-service-resumption-6207978]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Rail Chief Shares Big Update On Paralysed Train Networks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-rail-chief-shares-big-update-on-paralysed-train-networks-service-resumption-6207978]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:31:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France's national rail operator on Sunday said it had repaired damage caused by saboteurs that paralysed the train network hours before the Olympics opening ceremony, and normal services would resume on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France's national rail operator on Sunday said it had repaired damage caused by saboteurs that paralysed the train network hours before the Olympics opening ceremony, and normal services would resume on Monday.</p>

<p>Train traffic on the main line west out of Paris was already "practically normal" and "three out of four" high-speed TGV trains were running on the main line north from the capital, "without any increase in travel time from now on", operator SNCF said on Sunday.</p>

<p>It remains unclear who carried out the three attacks on strategic points of the rail infrastructure overnight on Thursday to Friday, or if they were deliberately timed to disrupt the Games' opening spectacle later on Friday.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of rail passengers struggled through two days of cancelled and delayed trains on Friday and Saturday, when 800,000 travellers were due to leave for their summer holidays.</p>

<p>"Thanks to the exceptional efforts of SNCF Network staff, who worked non-stop since Friday morning, repairs are now fully completed on all the high-speed rail services affected by the sabotage attacks," the operator said.</p>

<p>"Tests have been conclusive and the train lines are now able to function as normal.</p>

<p>"There will be no more disruption from Monday morning onwards," it said.</p>

<p>No group has claimed responsibility for the meticulously planned night-time attacks. Maintenance workers thwarted a fourth.</p>

<h3><strong>Search for perpetrators</strong></h3>

<p>A source close to the Paris judicial authority, which has launched an investigation, said the attacks had all been carried out by "the same entity".</p>

<p>A statement signed by "an unexpected delegation" was sent to several news media outlets expressing support for the sabotage and criticising the Olympic Games as being a "celebration of nationalism" and the oppression of peoples by nation states.</p>

<p>But sources close to the investigation said it was simply a message of support, rather than a claim of responsibility per se, gave no details of the attacks and contained "nothing particularly serious".</p>

<p>"We have uncovered a certain number of elements that allow us to think that we will soon know who is responsible for what clearly did not sabotage the Olympic Games but did sabotage part of the holidays of the French people," Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin told France 2 television on Saturday.</p>

<p>French authorities are on high alert for a potential terrorist attack during the Games, which run until August 11.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of police and soldiers have been placed on security duties during the Olympics.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qgjtbsko_france-railways-afp-_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-endorses-reformist-masoud-pezeshkian-as-new-president-6207969]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's Supreme Leader Endorses Reformist Masoud Pezeshkian As New President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-endorses-reformist-masoud-pezeshkian-as-new-president-6207969]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:30:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei gave Sunday his official endorsement of Masoud Pezeshkian as the Islamic Republic's ninth president, following snap elections won by the reformist camp's candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei gave Sunday his official endorsement of Masoud Pezeshkian as the Islamic Republic's ninth president, following snap elections won by the reformist camp's candidate.</p>

<p>In a message read by the director of Khamenei's office, he said: "I endorse the vote (for) the wise, honest, popular and scholarly Mr Pezeshkian, and I am appointing him as the president of the Islamic Republic of Iran".</p>

<p>The new reformist president is due to be sworn in before parliament on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The endorsement ceremony was held in the capital Tehran in the presence of senior Iranian officials and foreign diplomats, and broadcast on state TV.</p>

<p>It took place as banks and most government offices were ordered shut nationwide on Sunday to tackle an extreme heatwave.</p>

<p>Following the event, acting president Mohammad Mokhber handed over official responsibilities to 69-year-old Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>Later Sunday, Pezeshkian appointed reformist Mohammad Reza Aref, 72, as his first vice president, according to an announcement carried by state TV.</p>

<p>Aref has represented Tehran in parliament and served as first vice president and communications minister under Iran's last reformist president Mohammad Khatami, who held office from 1997 to 2005.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian, a heart surgeon and parliament member for the northwestern city of Tabriz since 2008, was Khatami's health minister.</p>

<p>On July 5 the reformist candidate won a runoff race against the ultraconservative Saeed Jalili to replace President Ebrahim Raisi who died in a helicopter crash in May.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian secured more than 16 million votes or about 54 per cent of the roughly 30 million ballots cast.</p>

<p>Turnout in the runoff election stood at 49.8 per cent, up from a record low of about 40 per cent in the first round, according to Iran's electoral authority.</p>

<p>Jalili attended Sunday's ceremony, as did former moderate president Hassan Rouhani who had backed Pezeshkian's presidential bid along with Iran's main reformist coalition.</p>

<h3><strong>'Bad attitude'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Pezeshkian was the only candidate representing Iran's reformist camp allowed to stand in the election, for which all contenders were approved by the conservative-dominated Guardian Council.</p>

<p>Iran's president is not head of state, and the ultimate authority rests with the supreme leader -- a post held by Khamenei for the last 35 years.</p>

<p>Following Khamenei's official endorsement, Pezeshkian thanked the leader and the Iranian people, vowing to carry the "heavy burden" of the presidency.</p>

<p>The election came against a backdrop of heightened regional tensions since the Gaza war began in early October, disputes with Western powers over Iran's nuclear programme and domestic discontent over the state of the sanctions-hit economy.</p>

<p>During the ceremony, Khamenei urged the upcoming administration to form an "active and effective" response to regional developments, adding that diplomacy must prioritise neighbouring nations.</p>

<p>"We have no intention to oppose some European countries. The reason I didn't mention European countries as a priority is that they have not treated us well for many years," he added.</p>

<p>"If they don't have this bad attitude, then (ties with Europe) would be one of our priorities."</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, Pezeshkian had pledged to try to revive a 2015 nuclear deal with the United States and other world powers, which imposed curbs on Iran's nuclear activity in return for sanctions relief.</p>

<p>The deal collapsed in 2018 after Washington withdrew from it.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian has in a recent article called for "constructive relations" with European countries, even though he accused them of reneging on commitments to mitigate the impact of US sanctions.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7202qqho_iran-president-elect_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iran election came against a backdrop of heightened regional tensions since the Gaza war began]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/paris-olympics-tarun-tahiliani-not-a-couture-show-tarun-tahiliani-to-ndtv-amid-olympics-costume-row-6207878]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Not A Couture Show": Tarun Tahiliani To NDTV Amid Olympics Costume Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/paris-olympics-tarun-tahiliani-not-a-couture-show-tarun-tahiliani-to-ndtv-amid-olympics-costume-row-6207878]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:12:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Responding to the criticism of the Indian contingent's costume at Paris Olympics, fashion designer Tarun Tahiliani has said he stands by the design and slammed "armchair critics" for implying that he charged a fee for designing the athletes' attire.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Responding to the criticism of the Indian contingent's costume at Paris Olympics, fashion designer Tarun Tahiliani has said he stands by the design and slammed "armchair critics" for implying that he charged a fee for designing the athletes' attire.</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV, Mr Tahiliani said his team followed guidelines of International Olympic Committee while designing the kits. "Many things changed in the last minute. I stand by our design. This is what we Indians wear, and this is not to be a couture show. I accept people can have their views. I am good with that, but I stand by what we did," he said.</p>

<p>"We wanted the team in the colours of the tricolour as most countries follow their flag and that was visible from afar," he said.</p>

<p>Many in social media have criticised the designer over the Indian athletes' outfits and described them as dull. "It would have been very easy for me to send them in zardozi vests. But it's not appropriate," the designer said in response to such criticism.</p>

<p>Some social media users have pointed out that the outfits have digital prints on them and India, with its rich heritage of handloom and embroidery, should have been represented on this world stage by better attire.</p>

<p>The designer said his team had just three weeks to ready the costumes. "I can't weave handloom for 300 uniforms in that time. The shoes were brocade, brocade from Benares" he said.</p>

<p>He also responded to the charge that the logo of Tasva, an Aditya Birla Group brand of which Mr Tahiliani is chief design officer, was used on the costumes. "A symbol was made into a border, that's all. When you see a photograph, you won't even notice it. We earlier put the Indian flag there, but were told one should not use it. We followed the guidelines," he said.</p>

<p>The designer strongly denied claims that Tasva charged for designing the costumes. "The cheek of these armchair critics. This was paid for by Tasva. It was not done for a fee, it was done to support our athletes. Asking what I was paid for it just shows their mentality," he said.</p>

<p>Tasva had earlier said in a statement that it was honoured to design the outfits for the Indian contingent in collaboration with Tarun Tahiliani. "This prestigious collaboration for Tasva, as the 'Official Ceremonial Dress Partner' for Team India at the Paris Olympics, marks a significant milestone in Tasva's journey as it represents the spirit, culture, and elegance of India on the global stage," it said.</p>

<p>It said the Indian athletes' ceremonial attire for the opening ceremony draws profound inspiration from the Indian flag. "The tricolor palette embodies national pride and unity. The contemporary silhouettes of the Bundi jacket and the pre-pleated saree when combined with the thoughtful choice of fabrics-cotton and viscose crepe-along with practical detail, not just ensures comfort and functionality for the athletes, but also represents a fine balance of tradition with modernity."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g0i162so_indian-olympic_625x300_28_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The costume of the Indian athletes has been criticised on social media]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/12-killed-in-landslide-triggered-by-flash-flooding-in-china-report-6207870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[12 Killed In Landslide Triggered By Flash Flooding In China: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/12-killed-in-landslide-triggered-by-flash-flooding-in-china-report-6207870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:10:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A landslide caused by flooding in central China's Hunan province destroyed a guesthouse and killed 12 people on Sunday, state media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A landslide caused by flooding in central China's Hunan province destroyed a guesthouse and killed 12 people on Sunday, state media reported.</p>

<p>Official broadcaster CCTV said it had "been initially confirmed that 18 people were buried".</p>

<p>Twelve bodies and six injured survivors had been recovered by Sunday evening, the official Xinhua news agency said.</p>

<p>One person had been missing before the 12th body was found.</p>

<p>The landslide was caused by flash flooding on a mountain, which destroyed the guesthouse, according to CCTV.</p>

<p>More than 240 emergency personnel had been sent to the scene.</p>

<p>A video published by the state-run Beijing Youth Daily showed a swath of mud and debris cutting through a green hillside and an uprooted tree lying in front of a three-storey building.</p>

<p>An aerial video on Xinhua showed what appeared to be the ruined bottom half of a building at the top of the debris trail, as well as damaged buildings at the foot of the hill.</p>

<p>China has suffered a summer of extreme weather, with flash floods in the north and southwest killing at least 20 people this month.</p>

<p>A highway in southern China collapsed in May after days of rain, killing 48 people.</p>

<p>Scientists say climate change is making extreme weather more frequent and intense, and China is the world's largest emitter of greenhouse gases.</p>

<p>Long dependent on polluting energy sources such as coal, Beijing has pledged to bring emissions of planet-heating carbon dioxide to a peak by 2030 and to net zero by 2060.</p>

<p>It is already the world's largest producer of renewable energy, with research this month showing China is building almost twice as much solar and wind power capacity as the rest of the world combined.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/st7jrac_landslide-generic-unsplash-_625x300_28_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 240 emergency personnel had been sent to the scene (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-us-carries-out-putin-warns-of-cold-war-style-missile-crisis-6207683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If US Carries Out...": Putin Warns Of Cold War-Style Missile Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-us-carries-out-putin-warns-of-cold-war-style-missile-crisis-6207683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:42:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Sunday threatened to relaunch production of intermediate-range nuclear weapons if the United States confirmed its intention to deploy missiles to Germany or elsewhere in Europe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Sunday threatened to relaunch production of intermediate-range nuclear weapons if the United States confirmed its intention to deploy missiles to Germany or elsewhere in Europe.</p>

<p>"If the United States carries out such plans, we will consider ourselves liberated from the unilateral moratorium previously adopted on the deployment of medium- and short-range strike capabilities," Putin said during a naval parade in Saint Petersburg.</p>

<p>Putin added that now in Russia "the development of a number of such systems is in the final stages".</p>

<p>"We will take mirror measures in deploying them, taking into account the actions of the US, its satellites in Europe and in other regions of the world," the Russian president warned.</p>

<p>Such missiles, which can travel between 500 and 5,500 kilometres (300-3,400 miles), were the subject of an arms control treaty signed by the US and the Soviet Union in 1987.</p>

<p>But both Washington and Moscow withdrew from the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty in 2019, each accusing the other of violations.</p>

<p>Russia subsequently said it would not restart production of such missiles as long as the United States did not deploy missiles abroad.</p>

<p>In early July, Washington and Berlin announced that the "episodic deployments" of long-range US missiles, including Tomahawk cruise missiles, to Germany would begin in 2026.</p>

<p>Putin said that "important Russian administrative and military sites" would fall within the range of such missiles that "could in the future be equipped with nuclear warheads, such that our territories would be within around 10 minutes" of a strike being launched.</p>

<p>The Russian president also mentioned that the US has deployed Typhon mid-range missile systems in Denmark and the Philippines in recent exercises.</p>

<h3><strong>'Cold War' reminder&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"This situation reminds us of the events of the Cold War linked to the deployment of American Pershing medium-range missiles in Europe," said Putin.</p>

<p>The US deployed US Pershing ballistic missiles in West Germany in the 1980s at the height of the Cold War.</p>

<p>US missiles continued to be stationed through the reunification of Germany and into the 1990s.</p>

<p>But following the end of the Cold War, the United States significantly reduced the number of missiles stationed in Europe as the threat from Moscow receded.</p>

<p>The Kremlin had already warned in mid-July that the proposed US deployment would mean that European capitals would become a target for Russian missiles.</p>

<p>"We are taking steady steps towards the Cold War. All the attributes of the Cold War with the direct confrontation are returning," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told a state TV reporter.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pqsvmrc_vladimir-putin-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin said that US has used Typhon mid-range missile systems in Denmark and Philippines recently]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-warship-takes-part-in-traditional-maritime-parade-on-russias-navy-day-6207662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Warship Takes Part In Maritime Parade On Russia's Navy Day]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-warship-takes-part-in-traditional-maritime-parade-on-russias-navy-day-6207662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:40:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over 200 naval vessels, including ships from the Indian, Chinese, and Algerian navies, took part in the traditional maritime parade in St Petersburg to mark Russia's Navy Day on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 200 naval vessels, including ships from the Indian, Chinese, and Algerian navies, took part in the traditional maritime parade in St Petersburg to mark Russia's Navy Day on Sunday.</p>

<p>President Vladimir Putin, Defense Minister Andrey Belousov, and Commander-in-Chief of the Navy Admiral Aleksandr Moiseyev oversaw the parade, which takes place on the last Sunday of July, RT reported.</p>

<p>In his address on the occasion, President Putin vowed that Russia would continue to strengthen its naval forces and modernise its fleets with high-tech assets, including hypersonic missiles.</p>

<p>Over 15,000 service members and vessels of various classes drawn from Russia's Northern, Pacific, and Baltic fleets, the Caspian flotilla, as well as members of the naval force expedition in Syria, participated in the event. However, ships from the Black Sea Fleet were absent as they were engaged in active operations in the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>The parade is traditionally led by the Poltava, a reconstructed 18th-century 54-gun sailing ship. The original ship, launched in 1712, was named after the site of the battle where Russia won a crushing victory over Sweden in 1709, turning the tide of the Great Northern War and paving the way for Russia to become a major world power.</p>

<p>Another highlight of the parade was patrol icebreaker, 'Ivan Papanin', specifically designed for Arctic conditions. Russia currently possesses the largest icebreaker fleet in the world, numbering more than 40 vessels.</p>

<p>Other ships in the parade included several small-sized missile ships and corvettes, usually armed with Kalibr cruise missiles, which have a range of more than 1,000km.</p>

<p>The submarine force was represented by the diesel-electric submarine 'Mozhaisk', which can be armed with torpedoes or Kalibr missiles.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Chinese Navy's destroyer 'Jiaozuo' and replenishment ship 'Honghu', the Algerian Navy training ship 'La Soummam', and the Indian Navy's Russia-made Talwar-class stealth frigate 'Tabar', also took part.</p>

<p>The naval parade was followed by a parade on land, which included cadets from several Russian naval institutions, as well as a detachment of marines.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/21t7tp1_russia-navy-day_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The parade is traditionally led by the Poltava, a reconstructed 18th-century 54-gun sailing ship.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paris-olympics-winners-to-take-home-piece-of-eiffel-tower-6207641]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Paris Olympics Winners To Take Home 'Piece Of Eiffel Tower']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paris-olympics-winners-to-take-home-piece-of-eiffel-tower-6207641]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:39:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 2024 Paris Olympics have officially begun, bringing together the world's finest athletes vying for the ultimate prize.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 2024 Paris Olympics have officially begun, bringing together the world's finest athletes vying for the ultimate prize. This year's Olympic medals hold a secret that will make them truly unforgettable - a piece of Paris itself. Embedded within each medal is a fragment of the iconic Eiffel Tower.</p>

<p>Winners across the 329 events, taking place until mid-August, will receive these unique medals, each containing 18 grams of ironwork from the Eiffel Tower, salvaged during its 20th-century renovations and maintenance. The medals' design, inspired by the iconic monument, features a lattice pattern on the blue ribbons, which echo the Eiffel Tower's ribbing.</p>

<p>Crafted by luxury jewellers Chaumet and produced by the Monnaie de Paris, the medals reflect Paris' famous nickname, 'The City of Lights'. The gold medals weigh 529 grams, silver medals 525 grams and bronze medals 455 grams. A similar design will be used for the Paralympic medals, featuring red ribbons.</p>

<p>Earlier in February, the official X handle of the Olympic Games revealed, "When the structure underwent renovation work in the 20th century, certain metallic elements were removed and carefully preserved. Now, the Societe d'Exploitation de la Tour Eiffel has given these rare pieces of history a second lease of life ahead of #Paris2024.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">????When the structure underwent renovation work in the 20th century, certain metallic elements were removed and carefully preserved. Now, the Société d'Exploitation de la Tour Eiffel has given these rare pieces of history a second lease of life ahead of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Paris2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Paris2024</a>.<br />
<br />
You can read…</p>
— The Olympic Games (@Olympics) <a href="https://twitter.com/Olympics/status/1755577765909111044?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Later, it revealed the exciting news, "The most unique, historic and unforgettable souvenir of Paris! Every #Paris2024 Olympic and Paralympic medal will be adorned with a piece of original iron from the Eiffel Tower."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The most unique, historic and unforgettable souvenir of Paris! ????????<br />
<br />
???????????? Every <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Paris2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Paris2024</a> Olympic and Paralympic medal will be adorned with a piece of original iron from the Eiffel Tower. <a href="https://t.co/jIytQXFtUD">pic.twitter.com/jIytQXFtUD</a></p>
— The Olympic Games (@Olympics) <a href="https://twitter.com/Olympics/status/1755577759827415492?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Paralympic medals display an underneath view of the Eiffel Tower and are inscribed with "Paris 2024" in Braille, paying tribute to the French inventor of the writing system.</p>

<p>"What's impactful for this year will be having a part of the original Eiffel Tower metal, the iron, in these various medals, and so this is what we wanted to do, to infuse all these 2024 athletes with that metal," Tony Estanguet, President of the Paris 2024 Organising Committee, said, as per Forbes.</p>

<p>Around 5,084 medals have been made for the Paris Olympics, with approximately 2,600 for the Olympics and 2,400 for the Paralympics.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s6b4koag_paris-oympics-winner_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bronze medallist Italy's Luigi Samele celebrates on the podium during the medal ceremony]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/really-sorry-paris-organisers-apologise-for-offence-caused-by-last-supper-sketch-6207640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Paris Organisers Apologise For Offence Caused By 'Last Supper' Sketch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/really-sorry-paris-organisers-apologise-for-offence-caused-by-last-supper-sketch-6207640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:38:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Paris 2024 organisers apologised on Sunday to Catholics and other Christian groups angered by a kitsch tableau in the Olympic Games opening ceremony that parodied Leonardo Da Vinci's famous 'The Last Supper' painting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paris 2024 organisers apologised on Sunday to Catholics and other Christian groups angered by a kitsch tableau in the Olympic Games opening ceremony that parodied Leonardo Da Vinci's famous 'The Last Supper' painting.</p>

<p>The segment, which resembled the biblical scene of Jesus Christ and his apostles sharing a last meal before crucifixion and featured drag queens, a transgender model and a naked singer made up as the Greek god of wine Dionysus, drew dismay from the Catholic Church and the religious right in America.</p>

<p>"Clearly there was never an intention to show disrespect to any religious group. (The opening ceremony) tried to celebrate community tolerance," Paris 2024 spokesperson Anne Descamps told a press conference.</p>

<p>"We believe this ambition was achieved. If people have taken any offence we are really sorry."</p>

<p>France, while proud of its rich Catholic heritage, also has a long tradition of secularism and anti-clericalism. Blasphemy is not only legal, but also considered by many as an essential pillar of freedom of speech.</p>

<p>Supporters of the tableau praised its message of inclusivity and tolerance.</p>

<p>The Catholic church in France said it deplored a ceremony that "included scenes of derision and mockery of Christianity."</p>

<p>In Germany, the Bishop of Passau, Stefan Oster, said: "An impressive opening to hopefully peaceful games. The queer Last Supper was a low point, however, and wholly superfluous in the context."</p>

<p>Some commentators said the controversy was another example of 21st century culture wars turbocharged by a 24-hour news cycle and social media.</p>

<p>Thomas Jolly, the artistic director and mastermind behind the flamboyant opening ceremony, said religious subversion had never been his intention.</p>

<p>"We wanted to talk about diversity. Diversity means being together. We wanted to include everyone, as simple as that," he told reporters on Saturday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h4u60548_drag-parody_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The segment drew dismay from the Catholic Church]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-every-indication-hezbollah-behind-strike-in-israel-annexed-golan-6207613]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Says "Every Indication" Hezbollah Behind Strike In Golan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-every-indication-hezbollah-behind-strike-in-israel-annexed-golan-6207613]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:31:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Sunday that there was "every indication" that Lebanese fighter group Hezbollah was behind a rocket strike in the Israel-annexed Golan Heights that killed 12 young people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Sunday that there was "every indication" that Lebanese fighter group Hezbollah was behind a rocket strike in the Israel-annexed Golan Heights that killed 12 young people.</p>

<p>"Every indication is that indeed the rocket was from Hezbollah. We stand by Israel's right to defend its citizens from terrorist attacks," Blinken told reporters in Japan.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the young people were struck on Saturday by an Iranian-made rocket carrying a 50-kilogram warhead that Iran-backed Hezbollah fired at a football field in the Druze Arab town of Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has denied responsibility for the strike.</p>

<p>"We are determined to bring the Gaza conflict to a close. It's gone on for far too long. It's cost far too many lives. We want to see Israelis, we want to see Palestinians, we want to see Lebanese live free from the threat of conflict and violence," Blinken said.</p>

<p>"We're in conversations with the government of Israel. And again, I emphasise its right to defend its citizens and our determination to make sure that they're able to do that," he said in Tokyo.</p>

<p>"But we also don't want to see the conflict escalating. We don't want to see a spread. That has been one of our goals from day one, from October 7 on, and we'll continue to do that.</p>

<p>"But again, the best way to do that in a sustained way is to get the ceasefire in Gaza that we're working so hard on virtually every minute of the day," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5c05atig_golan-strikes_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has denied responsibility for the strike]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priti-patel-uk-elections-indian-origin-leaders-bid-to-replace-rishi-sunak-as-conservatives-head-6207211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Leader's Bid To Replace Rishi Sunak As Conservatives Head]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priti-patel-uk-elections-indian-origin-leaders-bid-to-replace-rishi-sunak-as-conservatives-head-6207211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:27:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Home Secretary Priti Patel entered the contest to lead the Conservative Party on Saturday, becoming the fifth contender in a fight to determine the direction of the Tories following their worst-ever election defeat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Home Secretary Priti Patel entered the contest to lead the Conservative Party on Saturday, becoming the fifth contender in a fight to determine the direction of the Tories following their worst-ever election defeat.</p>

<p>Patel is focusing her bid on uniting the Conservatives after they were kicked out of government after 14 years in power and cycled through five prime ministers in that time.</p>

<p>"It is time to put unity before personal vendetta, country before party, and delivery before self-interest," Patel said in a statement.</p>

<p>She joins former Work and Pensions Secretary Mel Stride, former Foreign and Home Secretary James Cleverly, former Security Minister Tom Tugendhat and ex-Immigration Minister Robert Jenrick in a race that will run until Nov. 2.</p>

<p>Leadership nominations will close mid-afternoon on Monday. Conservative Members of Parliament will then narrow the candidates by the end of September - in time for the party's annual conference - before shortlisting two for a party member vote. The new leader is set to be announced on Nov. 2.</p>

<p>Patel is trailing in fifth place at UK bookmakers, with odds as long as 10/1. The bookmakers' favorite to win is former Business Secretary Kemi Badenoch, who has yet to declare.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b9k1uga_priti-patel_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Priti Patel is focusing on uniting the Conservatives after they were kicked out of government this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-students-vow-to-resume-protests-unless-this-demand-is-fulfilled-6206398]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Students Vow To Resume Protests Unless This Demand Is Fulfilled]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-students-vow-to-resume-protests-unless-this-demand-is-fulfilled-6206398]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:56:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Bangladeshi student group has vowed to resume protests that sparked a lethal police crackdown and nationwide unrest unless several of their leaders are released from custody on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Bangladeshi student group has vowed to resume protests that sparked a lethal police crackdown and nationwide unrest unless several of their leaders are released from custody on Sunday.</p>

<p>Last week's violence killed at least 205 people, according to an AFP count of police and hospital data, in one of the biggest upheavals of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's 15-year tenure.</p>

<p>Army patrols and a nationwide curfew remain in place more than a week after they were imposed, and a police dragnet has scooped up thousands of protesters including at least half a dozen student leaders.</p>

<p>Members of Students Against Discrimination, whose campaign against civil service job quotas precipitated the unrest, said they would end their weeklong protest moratorium.</p>

<p>The group's chief Nahid Islam and others "should be freed and the cases against them must be withdrawn", Abdul Hannan Masud told reporters in an online briefing late Saturday.</p>

<p>Mr Masud, who did not disclose his location because he was in hiding from authorities, also demanded "visible actions" be taken against government ministers and police officers responsible for the deaths of protesters.</p>

<p>"Otherwise, Students Against Discrimination will be forced to launch tough protests" from Monday, he said.</p>

<p>Mr Islam and two other senior members of the protest group were on Friday forcibly discharged from a hospital in the capital Dhaka and taken away by a group of plainclothes detectives.</p>

<p>Earlier in the week, Mr Islam told AFP he was being treated at the hospital for injuries police inflicted on him during an earlier round of detention and said he was in fear for his life.</p>

<p>Home minister Asaduzzaman Khan told reporters Friday that the trio were taken into custody for their own safety but did not confirm if they had been formally arrested.</p>

<p>Police told AFP on Sunday that detectives had taken two others into custody, while a Students Against Discrimination activist told AFP that a third had been taken on Sunday morning.</p>

<p>At least 9,000 people have been arrested nationwide since the unrest began according to Prothom Alo, Bangladesh's largest daily newspaper.</p>

<p>While a curfew imposed last weekend remains in force, it has been progressively eased through the week, in a sign of the Hasina government's confidence that order was gradually being restored.</p>

<p>Telecommunications minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak told reporters the country's mobile internet network would be restored later on Sunday, 11 days after a nationwide blackout imposed at the height of the unrest.</p>

<p>Fixed line broadband connections had already been restored on Tuesday but the vast majority of Bangladesh's 141 million internet users rely on their mobile devices to connect with the world, according to the national telecoms regulator.</p>

<h2><strong>Jobs crisis&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Protests began this month over the reintroduction of a quota scheme reserving more than half of all government jobs for certain groups. With around 18 million young Bangladeshis out of work, according to government figures, the move deeply upset graduates facing an acute employment crisis.</p>

<p>Critics say the quota is used to stack public jobs with loyalists to the ruling Awami League.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court cut the number of reserved jobs last week but fell short of protesters' demands to scrap the quotas entirely.</p>

<p>Hasina has ruled Bangladesh since 2009 and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p>Her government is accused by rights groups of misusing state institutions to entrench its hold on power and stamp out dissent, including the extrajudicial killing of opposition activists.</p>

<p>Protests had remained largely peaceful until attacks by police and pro-government student groups on demonstrators last week.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hmsa96t_bangladesh-protest-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 9,000 people have been arrested in Bangladesh since the unrest began.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-olivia-coffey-a-private-equity-staffer-eyeing-gold-at-olympics-6207001]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Olivia Coffey, A Private Equity Staffer Eyeing Gold At Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-olivia-coffey-a-private-equity-staffer-eyeing-gold-at-olympics-6207001]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:48:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Private equity staffers regularly frequent the basement gym at 510 Madison Avenue in Manhattan. Among them: an athlete preparing to don the red, white and blue in her second Summer Olympics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Private equity staffers regularly frequent the basement gym at 510 Madison Avenue in Manhattan. Among them: an athlete preparing to don the red, white and blue in her second Summer Olympics.</p>

<p>Meet Olivia Coffey, a senior associate at One Equity Partners, representing Team USA in the women's eight next week. Her personal best time on an ergometer, or indoor rowing machine, over 2 kilometres is 6 minutes and 36 seconds.</p>

<p>Speaking to Bloomberg News from Erba in Northern Italy, where US rowers trained before travelling to Paris earlier this month, 35-year-old Coffey explained how she forged a career in the alternative asset management industry while pursuing her dreams on the water.</p>

<p>After graduating from Harvard in 2011, Coffey was recruited by One Equity Partners in a back-office role. Her parents trained with the firm's founder Dick Cashin - he and her father Cal rowed for the US at the 1976 Montreal Olympics (the elder Coffey won silver in the pair's event.)</p>

<p>Early in her career, Coffey missed out on selection for the London 2012 Olympics and was a spare for the Rio 2016 Games. She worked on the firm's research and valuations team and rowed while obtaining her MBA from the University of Cambridge, graduating in 2018.</p>

<p>That year, after winning the world championships in Plovdiv, Bulgaria, Coffey resumed work at One Equity Partners and targeted a place on the Olympic team - an effort that was rewarded with a berth in the women's eight, which placed fourth at the Covid-postponed Tokyo Olympics.</p>

<h3><strong>'Rowed to Paris'</strong></h3>

<p>"It was a really awful feeling to walk away without getting to my ultimate goal," she said. "I was ready to be done with rowing, but found my life wasn't balanced, it felt like something was missing," Coffey said.</p>

<p>She resumed workouts in the office basement gym, attended CrossFit classes and began training with a group who communicated on an appropriately-named WhatsApp chat: 'Rowed to Paris.'</p>

<p>Coffey, who lives between Princeton, New Jersey, Manhattan's Upper West Side and Watkins Glen in upstate New York, and spent the most recent winter in Sarasota, Florida, logs 14 to 15 exercise sessions per week.</p>

<p>Awake at 5:30 a.m. each morning, she spends about two hours on the water rowing 20 kilometres to 30 kilometres, and during afternoons, she spends about 90 minutes on another cardio or cross-training activity, be it running or cycling - sometimes in Central Park - or on the rowing machine or lifting weights.</p>

<p>"I usually hit 250 kilometres a week, or 40 kilometres to 50 kilometres a day," said Coffey, who rarely drinks alcohol when training. "I eat a ton of carbs - things like cookies and sweet drinks, which are not great for me long-term," she says.</p>

<p>"When I'm not training, I'm recovering or working," adds Coffey, who aims to be asleep by 10 p.m.</p>

<p>As part of her work at One Equity Partners, Coffey sits on the board of Dragonfly Financial Technologies, a digital banking platform, and is a board observer for Montgomery Transport, a flatbed trucking operator, as well as staffing firm Prime Time Healthcare.</p>

<p>One Equity Partners' flexibility enabled Coffey to schedule work around her training. "I'm thankful, the firm couldn't have been more supportive," she said. "I feel really fortunate to have understanding deal teams, and colleagues who can accommodate my schedule."</p>

<p>Due to her rowing commitments, Coffey isn't subject to what she describes as a classic 80-hour work week. "I work as much as I can within the confines of training," explains Coffey, who generally logs on by 9.30 a.m. or 10 a.m. each morning. Through the fall, when she was training intensely ahead of team trials in March, she notched an average work week of 40 hours. In the lead-up to Paris, that number has halved to about 20 hours, as she focuses on portfolio management and opts out of originating new business.</p>

<h3><strong>Olympians Everywhere</strong></h3>

<p>The&nbsp;US Olympic Committee&nbsp;gives rowers a stipend of $1,000 to $2,000 a month in addition to health insurance, which a lot of athletes supplement with full-time work, said Coffey, who on a regular day, can jump from working on a financial model in Microsoft Excel to a board presentation.</p>

<p>In her role, she deals with everything from origination to due diligence to hashing out terms of a credit agreement, and she especially enjoys meeting founders.</p>

<p>"I know what it feels like to be super passionate and the amount of sacrifice and perseverance it takes to put everything you have into something," Coffey said. "They love what they do."</p>

<p>She'll be supported in Paris by her family including husband Michael Blomquist, a managing director at renewable energy project finance brokerage Open Energy Group, who has made blue tops emblazoned with "Go Liv!" for her cheer squad. Blomquist understands Coffey's drive all too well - he quit Morgan Stanley to focus on qualifying for a spot on the London 2012 US Olympic team.</p>

<p>Also, there will be Jamie Koven, a partner at One Equity Partners, a co-chair of the National Rowing Foundation and former Olympic rower himself, having competed at the Olympics in 1996 and 2000 in Atlanta and Sydney, respectively.</p>

<p>Koven and Cashin are not the only co-workers to have competed at the Olympics. Senior adviser Fritz Hobbs, partners Charlie Cole, Matthew Hughes, Ante Kusurin, and associate Jack Lopas, all rowed at prior Summer Olympics, and principal Mario Ancic is a former professional tennis player who won a bronze medal at the Athens 2004 Games.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qc9adf2g_olivia-coffey_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[After graduating from Harvard in 2011, Olivia Coffey was recruited by One Equity Partners.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-kamala-harris-crazy-liberal-she-calls-out-his-wild-lies-6206955]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Calls Kamala Harris "Crazy Liberal", She Calls Out His "Wild Lies"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-kamala-harris-crazy-liberal-she-calls-out-his-wild-lies-6206955]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:39:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump labeled Vice President Kamala Harris a "crazy liberal," while she vowed to prevail over his "wild lies" as both laid out presidential campaign attack lines Saturday with just 100 days left until election day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump labeled Vice President Kamala Harris a "crazy liberal," while she vowed to prevail over his "wild lies" as both laid out presidential campaign attack lines Saturday with just 100 days left until election day.</p>

<p>After earlier addressing a bitcoin conference in Tennessee, Trump rallied supporters Saturday evening in Minnesota, seeking to make the historically Democratic midwest state into a battleground.</p>

<p>"This November, the American people are going to reject Kamala Harris's crazy liberal extremism in a massive landslide," the Republican told the crowd assembled in a hockey arena.</p>

<p>He quickly took aim at several positions Harris took during her 2020 Democratic primary campaign, some of which she has since walked back, such as a desire to ban fracking or majorly overhaul the criminal justice system.</p>

<p>Calling Harris a "radical left lunatic," Trump also hammered her and President Joe Biden's record on illegal immigration, inflation and crime -- all of which saw significant spikes during their term but have returned to historical averages in recent months.</p>

<p>In his 90-minute speech, the populist billionaire also repeated pledges to "have the largest deportation effort" in US history and end taxation of tips, while repeating unfounded allegations that his 2020 election loss had been "rigged."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Harris on Saturday held a fundraising event in Massachusetts with celebrity guests including singer-songwriter James Taylor and cellist Yoyo Ma.</p>

<p>"We are the underdogs in this race, but this is a people-powered campaign," she told the crowd at the event, which her campaign said would net $1.4 million.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump has been resorting to some wild lies about my record. And some of what he and his running mate are saying, well, it's just plain weird," she said.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign has adopted "weird" as a new catch-all for describing Trump's aggressive rhetoric.</p>

<p>His attacks, repeated on Saturday, include allegations that Harris wants to legalize killing newborn babies -- a falsehood stemming from the vice president's fervent support of abortion rights.</p>

<p>Harris has made her advocacy on the issue central to her campaign against Trump, whose three conservative nominees to the Supreme Court helped overturn the national right to the procedure in 2022.</p>

<p>Trump on Saturday thanked all six conservative justices by name "for the wisdom and courage they showed on this long-term, very contentious issue."</p>

<p>Harris, a former California prosecutor, also challenged Trump to a debate, after his campaign said this week he would not agree to keeping a September 10 televised face-off previously scheduled with Biden.</p>

<p>"I hope he reconsiders because we have a lot to talk about," she said.</p>

<h2><strong>'Mined, minted, made'</strong></h2>

<p>Trump, 78, is now the oldest major-party nominee in history and is scrambling to reorient an election against someone two decades his junior, having expected to face an 81-year-old incumbent Biden beset by concerns over infirmity.</p>

<p>On Saturday, he made his pitch to the cryptocurrency industry, one he previously called a "scam."</p>

<p>Saying China or others could seize the reins on the fast-growing field, Trump's appeal has been welcomed by crypto enthusiasts who feel they have been treated harshly by the Biden administration.</p>

<p>"If crypto is going to define the future, I want (it) to be mined, minted and made in the USA," he said to cheers, calling for the United States to be "the crypto capital of the planet."</p>

<p>Trump on Saturday also vowed a return to outdoor rallies two weeks after being wounded in an attempted assassination at a campaign event in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>He has made the shooting a key part of his campaign pitch, telling supporters he "took a bullet for democracy."</p>

<p>Harris, seeking to become the first female president in US history, is tasked with rapidly assembling a campaign against an opponent who has been in near permanent re-election mode since he became president in 2016.</p>

<p>Her late-starting White House bid has enjoyed early momentum. Polls that had shown Biden steadily slipping against Trump now show Harris in a practical tie.</p>

<p>She's garnered support from Democratic heavyweights, including Biden himself and most recently Barack and Michelle Obama.</p>

<p>Torianna Parrish, 34, was among the crowd greeting Harris upon her arrival Saturday afternoon at the airport in Westfield, Massachusetts.</p>

<p>"I wanted to show there's power in numbers. I wanted to show my support," she said.</p>

<p>"We're rooting for her and we want to see her make this country what it needs to be."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has earlier called Kamala Harris "radical left lunatic". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/sunita-williams-paris-olympics-how-sunita-williams-stuck-in-space-wished-all-the-best-to-paris-olympians-6206874]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Sunita Williams, Stuck In Space, Wished Godspeed To Paris Olympians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/sunita-williams-paris-olympics-how-sunita-williams-stuck-in-space-wished-all-the-best-to-paris-olympians-6206874]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:24:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For 52 days and counting, Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is in limbo at the International Space Station, but in a new video, she is seen celebrating the Olympics spirit in the weightless atmosphere, 400 kilometres above Paris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For 52 days and counting, Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is in limbo at the International Space Station, but in a new video, she is seen celebrating the Olympics spirit in the weightless atmosphere, 400 kilometres above Paris.</p>

<p>She can be seen grabbing an electronic version of the Olympic torch, performing gymnastic steps and doing somersaults inside the space station. Other astronauts are seen throwing discus, shot put balls and trying weightlifting manoeuvres in space where gravity is near zero.</p>

<p>"Let the games begin! Athletes from across the world are gathering today to kick off the 2024 #Olympics - pushing boundaries and inspiring generations. If you were an Olympic athlete, which sport would you play?," NASA has tweeted, sharing a video of astronauts inside the space station.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Let the games begin!<br />
<br />
Athletes from across the world are gathering today to kick off the 2024 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Olympics?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Olympics</a> – pushing boundaries and inspiring generations. If you were an Olympic athlete, which sport would you play? <a href="https://t.co/mnFC3vpvly">pic.twitter.com/mnFC3vpvly</a></p>
— NASA (@NASA) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1816862466816496101?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 26, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The astronauts sent their 'Godspeed' wishes to the athletes who will perform in tough competitive sports under actual gravity conditions. The nine astronauts on-board the space station continue their scientific work and are safe, says NASA.</p>

<p>In a separate update, the American space agency officials today said they conducted a 'hot test' on the troubled spacecraft, the Boeing Starliner, where the malfunctioning thrusters or rockets were tested while still being docked to the space station. "The thrusters performed at peak thrust rating values and the helium system remained stable." The world hopes that the Starliner could well return safely and soon.</p>

<p>Astronaut Sunita Williams and her crewmate Butch Wilmore reached the International Space Station on June 6 on a 10-day mission, but have been stuck after the Starliner malfunctioned. They do not know when and how they will return to Earth, though the US space agency asserts she and the eight other astronauts on-board the International Space Station are safe and in "good spirits".</p>

<p>In the new video, Sunita Williams and her fellow astronauts are seen playing sports in the weightless atmosphere to send good wishes to the athletes participating in the Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old Navy test pilot looks fit and in great spirits. She has helped design the Boeing Starliner and flew as its pilot on the maiden crewed test mission.</p>

<p>NASA has suggested that they are close to understanding the root cause of what is wrong with the Boeing Starliner's malfunctioning systems, but has given no clarity on when Williams and her crew mate Butch Wilmore will return.</p>

<p>According to Boeing, the Starliner can remain docked with the space station for a maximum period of ninety days, after which the batteries on board this spacecraft may drain out. This means that the space technologists in the US have less than six weeks to determine if Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore will return on the handicapped Boeing Starliner spacecraft or on SpaceX's Crew Dragon or Russian Soyuz spacecraft. These standby vehicles are already docked to the space station, so Sunita Williams and the other eight astronauts are not really stranded in space.</p>

<p>Boeing has faced several hiccups in the Starliner development. Initially, it was to have completed this with a $4.2 billion contract but has now spent a total of about $5.7 billion and the going is still uphill as the mission remains incomplete.</p>

<p>NASA wanted an alternative to SpaceX's Crew Dragon, and hence Boeing Starliner was being pushed through. Boeing is also going through a bad patch in general, and its aviation and aircraft business has also been stumbling. Recently, Boeing CEO David Calhoun was grilled by US Senators regarding the aviation giant's safety culture and transparency. If the Boeing Starliner fails to bring the two astronauts back to Earth, it would leave the aviation and space tech giant red-faced.</p>

<p>After today's hot test, whose results are still being assessed by Boeing and NASA, there is hope that Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore could return to Earth before the latest crew of four astronauts heads to the space station. The new crew will be onboard SpaceX's Falcon-9 rocket and Crew Dragon and the lift-off is likely after August 18.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dimhhbao_international-space-station_625x300_28_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The astronauts sent their 'godspeed' wishes to athletes competing in Paris Olympics]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disgusting-jd-vance-slams-jennifer-anistons-remarks-on-his-daughter-6206824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Disgusting": JD Vance Slams Jennifer Aniston's Remarks On His Daughter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disgusting-jd-vance-slams-jennifer-anistons-remarks-on-his-daughter-6206824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:15:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance has hit back at Jennifer Aniston after the actress dragged his two-year-old daughter into their ongoing feud.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican vice-presidential candidate JD Vance has hit back at Jennifer Aniston after the actress dragged his two-year-old daughter into their ongoing feud.</p>

<p>The spat has its roots in JD Vance's 2021 comments about "childless cat ladies" running the country, singling out Kamala Harris and others. Jennifer Aniston, who has spoken publicly about her own infertility struggles, shared a screenshot of the clip on Instagram and <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jennifer-aniston-slams-donald-trumps-running-mate-jd-vance-over-childless-cat-ladies-remark-6191543 ">slammed Vance's remarks</a>. In her post, the <em>Friends</em> star mentioned Vance's daughter, saying she hopes the child will be able to have children of her own one day and won't need to rely on IVF.</p>

<p>JD Vance responded to Aniston's comments on the Megyn Kelly Show, calling them "disgusting" and stating that his daughter is just "2 years old". "And second of all, if she had fertility problems, as I said in that speech, I would try everything I could to try to help her because I believe families and babies are a good thing," the Ohio&nbsp;Senator said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yRMWhqX7b5o?si=OmYlCnuZjInuNqhD" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Vance explained on the Megyn Kelly show that his "childless cat lady" remark was sarcastic and he had "nothing against cats." "People are focusing so much on the sarcasm and not on the substance of what I actually said," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He also pushed back against the criticism, arguing that it was a diversion from the core of his argument. "It's not a criticism of people who don't have children," Vance explained. "I explicitly said in my remarks that this is not about criticising people who, for various reasons, don't have kids. This is about criticising the Democratic Party for becoming anti-family and anti-child."</p>

<p>In a 2021 interview with Tucker Carlson, JD Vance criticised Democratic Party leaders, suggesting that their childlessness influences their policies and attitudes toward the country. Vance had described figures like Kamala Harris, Pete Buttigieg and Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez as "miserable" and lacking a "direct stake" in the country's future due to their lack of children. He also said, "It's just a basic fact - you look at Kamala Harris, Pete Buttigieg, AOC - the entire future of the Democrats is controlled by people without children."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ghp3c7s8_jd-vance-kamala-harris-jennifer-aniston_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance responded to Jennifer Aniston's comments on the Megyn Kelly Show]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>