<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 20:27:05 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-asks-troops-to-prepare-for-war-as-battle-drills-intensify-around-taiwan-6826978]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping Asks Troops To Prepare For War As Drills Intensify Around Taiwan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-asks-troops-to-prepare-for-war-as-battle-drills-intensify-around-taiwan-6826978]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 20:27:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping called this week for troops to strengthen their preparedness for war, state media reported today, just days after Beijing staged large-scale military drills around Taiwan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping called this week for troops to strengthen their preparedness for war, state media reported today, just days after Beijing staged large-scale military drills around Taiwan.</p>

<p>Xi made his comments while visiting a brigade of the People's Liberation Army Rocket Force on Thursday, according to state-run broadcaster CCTV.</p>

<p>Xi said the military should "comprehensively strengthen training and preparation for war, (and) ensure troops have solid combat capabilities", state media CCTV reported.</p>

<p>Soldiers must "enhance their strategic deterrent and combat capability," Xi said.</p>

<p>China, which claims Taiwan as part of its territory, has stepped up its shows of force around the self-ruled island in recent years.</p>

<p>On Monday, Beijing had deployed fighter jets, drones, warships and coast guard vessels to encircle Taiwan -- its fourth round of large-scale war games around the democratic island in just over two years.</p>

<p>China's communist leaders have insisted they will not rule out using force to bring Taiwan under Beijing's control.</p>

<p>Xi on Thursday said the Chinese military must "strongly safeguard the country's strategic security and core interests", according to the CCTV report.</p>

<p>The dispute between China and Taiwan dates back to a civil war in which the nationalist forces of Chiang Kai-shek were defeated by Mao Zedong's communist fighters and fled to the island in 1949.</p>

<p>China and Taiwan have been ruled separately since then.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-08/tsq1ntbg_chinese-army-afp_625x300_15_August_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China's Xi Jinping called this week for troops to strengthen their preparedness for war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starting-point-of-free-trade-pact-india-on-critical-mineral-deal-with-us-6826791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Starting Point Of Free Trade Pact": India On Critical Mineral Deal With US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starting-point-of-free-trade-pact-india-on-critical-mineral-deal-with-us-6826791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 19:48:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trade minister Piyush Goyal today said that India has sought a critical mineral partnership agreement with the United States as he hopes for talks on a broader trade pact between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trade minister Piyush Goyal today said that India has sought a critical mineral partnership agreement with the United States as he hopes for talks on a broader trade pact between the two nations.</p>

<p>"I had suggested that critical mineral MoU (memorandum of understanding) to be converted to a critical mineral partnership and become a starting point to become an FTA (Free Trade Agreement)," Piyush Goyal told reporters at a press briefing in New Delhi.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, India and the US signed an initial pact to cooperate on strengthening supply chains in the two countries for lithium, cobalt and other critical minerals used in electric vehicles and clean energy applications.</p>

<p>The MoU fell far short of a full critical minerals trade deal that would allow India to benefit from the $7,500 US electric vehicle tax credit.</p>

<p>Minerals-focused trade deals are one way that the US President Joe Biden's administration hopes to open up access for trusted allies to a $7,500 per vehicle EV tax credit introduced in last year's climate-focused Inflation Reduction Act.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qgh9640s_ships-in-port-generic-unsplash_625x300_19_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has sought a critical mineral partnership agreement with the United States. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-benjamin-netanyahu-what-you-should-know-about-israel-s-pm-6826005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Commando To Israel PM: The Life And Times Of Benjamin Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-benjamin-netanyahu-what-you-should-know-about-israel-s-pm-6826005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 17:38:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A year ago, in October 2023, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was grappling with his country's most significant security failure, facing backlash both at home and abroad.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A year ago, in October 2023, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was grappling with his country's most significant security failure, facing backlash both at home and abroad. After decades of promoting a tough image, Netanyahu appeared politically exposed following Hamas's attack on Israel on October 7, 2023. A year later, on October 18, Netanyahu's hold on power seemed stronger than it had been after announcing the death of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar.</p>

<p>The killing of Sinwar, who orchestrated October 7 attacks, is seen as a vindication for Prime Minister Netanyahu, Israel's longest-serving prime minister.</p>

<p><strong>Background and political career</strong></p>

<p>Born on October 21, 1949, in Tel Aviv, Benjamin Netanyahu's mother, Tzila Segal, was an Israeli-born Jew, while his father, Benzion Netanyahu, was from Poland who changed his name from Benzion Mileikowsky upon settling in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>Benjamin Netanyahu was raised in Jerusalem and attended high school in the US. His father was a historian. In 1963, the family moved to Philadelphia, US, where he spent his formative years.</p>

<p>At 18, Benjamin Netanyahu returned to Israel and served five years in the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) as a captain in the elite Sayeret Matkal commando unit.</p>

<p>Following his military service, Netanyahu pursued higher education at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), earning an MBA in 1976. His studies were briefly interrupted by the Yom Kippur War in 1973, where he served as a soldier. The loss of his brother Jonathan during the Entebbe raid in 1976 spurred him to establish the Jonathan Institute, dedicated to addressing terrorism-related issues through international conferences.</p>

<p>Fluent in English with a notable American accent, he quickly became a prominent voice for Israel, frequently appearing on US television as a strong advocate for his country. In 1982, he became Israel's deputy chief of mission in Washington. Two years later, he was appointed Israel's permanent representative to the United Nations in New York.</p>

<p>Benjamin Netanyahu's political career truly began in 1988 when he was elected to the Knesset (Israel's parliament) as a member of the Likud party. He swiftly rose through the ranks, serving as deputy foreign minister from 1988 to 1991 and later as deputy minister. In 1993, he became the leader of the Likud party, gaining prominence for his staunch opposition to the Israel-PLO peace accords and the subsequent Israeli withdrawals from the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>

<p><strong>Netanyahu's first term as PM</strong></p>

<p>At 47, Benjamin Netanyahu became Israel's youngest prime minister after the 1996 elections. His tenure began amid unrest, with strained relations with Syria and backlash from his decision to open a tunnel near the Al-Aqsa Mosque, sparking violent clashes.</p>

<p>Despite his staunch opposition to the 1993 Oslo peace accords, Benjamin Netanyahu made notable concessions during his first term as PM. He signed an agreement transferring 80% of Hebron to Palestinian Authority control and approved further withdrawals from the occupied West Bank, moves that drew sharp criticism from his right-wing base.</p>

<p>In 1999, after calling early elections 17 months ahead of schedule, Netanyahu was defeated by Labour leader Ehud Barak.</p>

<p>After this loss, Netanyahu remained a prominent figure in Likud but lost the party leadership to Ariel Sharon. He later served as foreign minister and finance minister in Sharon's government.</p>

<p><strong>Return to power</strong></p>

<p>In the February 2009 elections, Benjamin Netanyahu's Likud party secured 27 seats in the Knesset, narrowly trailing Kadima's 28. Netanyahu formed a coalition government with Yisrael Beiteinu, Shas and smaller parties, officially assuming office on March 31, 2009.</p>

<p>During this term, Netanyahu offered conditional support for a Palestinian state, but insisted it be demilitarised and recognise Israel as a Jewish state - conditions rejected by Palestinian leaders. Peace talks stalled in 2010 after Israel ended a moratorium on West Bank settlements.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's foreign policy was defined by his hardline stance on Iran, consistently advocating for international action against its nuclear programme.</p>

<p>Domestically, rising economic discontent triggered mass protests in 2011, with citizens demanding better public services. His coalition also struggled with tensions over military draft exemptions for ultra-Orthodox Jews, leading to early elections in 2012.</p>

<p>After returning to power post the elections with a more centrist coalition, Benjamin Netanyahu led a military operation in Gaza in 2014 following rocket attacks. Despite international criticism over civilian casualties, he claimed the operation weakened militant capabilities.</p>

<p>By late 2014, internal strife within his coalition over budget and legislation led to the dismissal of key cabinet members and elections in 2015. Relations with then US President Barack Obama became increasingly strained, particularly over Iran, culminating in Netanyahu's controversial address to the US Congress in early 2015.</p>

<p>Despite predictions of a tight race in the March 2015 elections, Netanyahu's Likud party emerged victorious.</p>

<p><strong>Corruption allegations and coalition crises</strong></p>

<p>Benjamin Netanyahu faced charges of fraud, breach of trust and corruption stemming from long-running investigations. Indicted in 2019, he was accused of accepting lavish gifts from millionaire associates and seeking regulatory favours for media moguls in exchange for positive coverage. Netanyahu denied any wrongdoing and refused to resign following his indictment, branding the investigations a politically motivated witch-hunt orchestrated by law enforcement, the media and the courts.</p>

<p>The corruption allegations became a rallying point for opposition parties, uniting politicians from across Israel's political spectrum. This growing opposition ultimately led to his ouster after the March 2021 elections, ending Netanyahu's another term as prime minister.</p>

<p><strong>2022 electoral comeback and controversy</strong></p>

<p>In early 2022, Benjamin Netanyahu's corruption trial faced setbacks after reports surfaced that police had used Pegasus spyware to hack the phones of key witnesses. Netanyahu's defence further questioned the allegations, citing an incorrect meeting date in the indictment.</p>

<p>As opposition leader, Netanyahu aggressively targeted the ruling coalition. The November 2022 elections saw a record voter turnout, with Netanyahu returning to power through a controversial coalition that included far-right ministers.</p>

<p><strong>Israel-Hamas war</strong></p>

<p>On October 7, 2023, Hamas launched a massive attack on Israel by land, sea, and air. In response, Israel launched airstrikes on Gaza. A ground invasion soon followed, intensifying the Israel-Hamas War.</p>

<p>Benjamin Netanyahu faced heavy criticism for his handling of the crisis, blamed for both the unpreparedness leading up to October 7 and the management of hostages and displaced civilians. Polls showed declining support for Netanyahu.</p>

<p>Internationally, Benjamin Netanyahu saw a shift from initial sympathy to isolation due to deteriorating conditions in Gaza. By March 2024, he faced a rift with US President Joe Biden over a planned offensive in Rafah, an area with a large concentration of civilians.</p>

<p>Domestic unrest grew as protests intensified in Tel Aviv by late May. On May 20, 2024, the International Criminal Court announced plans to seek arrest warrants for Benjamin Netanyahu, Defence Minister Yoav Gallant and Hamas leaders for alleged war crimes.</p>

<p>This decision drew condemnation, though Netanyahu's public support rose slightly.</p>

<p>In July 2024, Netanyahu insisted that any ceasefire must allow Israel to retain control over the Philadelphi Corridor between Gaza and Egypt, viewing it as critical to cutting off Hamas's supplies. This became a sticking point in negotiations.</p>

<p>By the end of August, the discovery of the bodies of six hostages escalated public anger, triggering massive protests. The protesters demanded the Netanyahu government to prioritise the release of remaining hostages. Despite growing pressure, Netanyahu maintained his stance on controlling the Philadelphi Corridor.</p>

<p>Israel is also fighting a war with Hamas ally Hezbollah in Lebanon. The two sides had exchanged rocket fire since the October 7 attack. The Benjamin Netanyahu government decided to send ground troops to Lebanon in September.</p>

<p>The situation in the Middle East remains very tense with the world eagerly watching Benjamin Neyanyahu's next step.</p>

<p>The killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar, the mastermind of the October 7 attacks, has significantly boosted Benjamin Netanyahu's image within Israel but it may escalate tension in the Middle East.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9c8o8p0g_netanyahu-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/science-proves-what-we-suspected-cats-are-basically-liquid-6825277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Science Proves What We Suspected, Cats Are Basically 'Liquid']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/science-proves-what-we-suspected-cats-are-basically-liquid-6825277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 15:44:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New research published in iScience reveals that cats possess body-size awareness, particularly when navigating narrow openings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cats and dogs have long been cherished as some of the most popular pets worldwide, admired for their companionship, loyalty, and distinct personalities. These creatures continue to improve the lives of families all around the world, whether it's because of the independent appeal of cats or the devoted character of dogs.</p>

<p>Cat owners are aware that their animals move differently from other pets. Cats are often characterised as "liquid," as if their bodies just spilt into any place they happened to inhabit. Many pet owners have been amazed by this fluid-like action, and it appears that cats are aware of their amazing skill, as they frequently display a smug demeanour while doing so.</p>

<p>Cats are cherished pets for more reasons than just their fluid motions. Their personalities, which are frequently marked by humour and independence, make them enticing company. Whether it's the grace or loyalty of a dog, these pets never fail to win people over and deepen the relationship that exists between people and animals.</p>

<p>According to the new research that has been published in<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cell.com/iscience/fulltext/S2589-0042(24)02024-8?_returnURL=https%3A%2F%2Flinkinghub.elsevier.com%2Fretrieve%2Fpii%2FS2589004224020248%3Fshowall%3Dtrue"><em> iScience,</em></a> cats selectively rely on body size awareness when negotiating short openings.</p>

<p>According to the author of the research paper, various animal species can make a priori decisions about the passability of openings based on their own size knowledge. So far, no one has tested the ability for self-representation in cats. We hypothesised that cats may rely on their size awareness when they have to negotiate small openings.</p>

<p>Companion cats were tested with incrementally decreasing-sized openings, which were either the same height or the same width. Cats approached and entered even the narrowest openings, but they slowed down before reaching and while passing through the shortest ones.</p>

<p>Because of their specific anatomical features and cautious locomotory strategy, cats readily opt for the trial-and-error method to negotiate narrow apertures, but they seemingly rely on their body-size representing capacity in the case of uncomfortably short openings. Ecologically valid methodologies can provide answers in the future as to whether cats would rely on their body awareness in other challenging spatial tasks, the authors of the study wrote.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fsv0qd3_cats-_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These findings further highlight the unique fluidity and grace that make cats such beloved pets.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-study-suggests-life-may-exist-on-mars-below-ice-surface-6825224]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Study Suggests Life May Exist On Mars Below Ice Surface]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-study-suggests-life-may-exist-on-mars-below-ice-surface-6825224]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 15:39:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Is there life on Mars? Scientists have been seeking an answer to this question for a long time. Although no concrete evidence has been found till date, a latest study by NASA has sparked curiosity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is there life on Mars? Scientists have been seeking an answer to this question for a long time. Although no concrete evidence has been found till date, a latest study by NASA has sparked curiosity. The US space agency suggests that microbes might find a potential home beneath the frozen water on the red planet's surface.</p>

<p>Based on computer modelling, the authors of the study have discovered that the amount of sunlight that penetrates the water ice could be enough for photosynthesis to occur in the shallow pools of meltwater beneath the surface of that ice.</p>

<p>The process of photosynthesis is utilised by plants and other organisms for converting light energy into chemical energy in search of food.</p>

<p>On the Earth, similar pools of water that form within ice are found to teem with life, including algae, fungi, and microscopic cyanobacteria -- all of them derive energy from photosynthesis.</p>

<p><strong>What does the study suggest?</strong></p>

<p>The NASA research was led by Aditya Khuller, who is associated with the space agency's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) in Southern California. The paper was published in Nature Communications Earth &amp; Environment.</p>

<p>"If we're trying to find life anywhere in the universe today, Martian ice exposures are probably one of the most accessible places we should be looking," Khuller said.</p>

<p>Since Mars has two kinds of ice -- frozen water and frozen carbon dioxide -- the research team looked at the water ice as a potential host of life.</p>

<p>Tracing its origin, the researchers said that large amounts of it had formed from snow mixed with dust which had fallen on the surface during a series of Martian ice ages in the past million years. The ancient snow, which has now solidified into ice, is still peppered with specks of dust, it added.</p>

<p>Even though these dust particles may obscure light in the ice's deeper layers, they hold the key to explaining how subsurface pools of water could form within ice after getting exposed to the Sun.</p>

<p>"Dark dust absorbs more sunlight than the surrounding ice, potentially causing the ice to warm up and melt up to a few feet below the surface," NASA states.</p>

<p>The study's co-author, Phil Christensen of Arizona State University in Tempe, has been studying ice on Mars for the past few decades.</p>

<p>"Dense snow and ice can melt from the inside out, letting in sunlight that warms it like a greenhouse, rather than melting from the top down," he said.</p>

<p>Aditya Khuller and his team now hope to re-create some of Mars' dusty ice in a lab to study it closely.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jmtbn33g_mars_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The NASA research was led by Aditya Khuller, a postdoctoral researcher at JPL (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-troop-deployment-locks-in-russia-military-alliance-6824976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Troop Deployment Locks In Russia Military Alliance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-troop-deployment-locks-in-russia-military-alliance-6824976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:58:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea's decision to deploy thousands of soldiers to Ukraine's front lines cements Pyongyang's contentious military alliance with Moscow, experts told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea's decision to deploy thousands of soldiers to Ukraine's front lines cements Pyongyang's contentious military alliance with Moscow, experts told AFP, and pulls Russia deeper into Korean peninsula security.</p>

<p>About 1,500 North Korean special forces soldiers are already in Russia acclimatising, likely to head to the front lines soon, Seoul's spy agency said Friday, with thousands more troops set to depart imminently, Pyongyang's first such deployment overseas.</p>

<p>The move demonstrates that the military deal signed by the North's Kim Jong Un and Russian President Vladimir Putin in June, which included a mutual defence clause, was not just for show.</p>

<p>"This establishes a framework where Russia's intervention or military support will automatically occur if North Korea is attacked or faces a crisis," Hong Min, a senior analyst at the Korea Institute for National Unification, told AFP.</p>

<p>The fact that North Korean soldiers will fight alongside Russia in Ukraine proves how "solid" the Putin-Kim deal really is, Hong said.</p>

<p>And the boost of troops from Pyongyang could help Moscow to hold "occupied territories or aid in further territorial gains", he added.</p>

<p>North and South Korea remain technically at war as the 1950 to 1953 conflict ended with an armistice, not a peace deal. But while Kim has built up a nuclear arsenal, Seoul lacks nukes of its own.</p>

<p>The South is protected by the so-called US nuclear umbrella, and Seoul and Washington routinely conduct large-scale joint military drills, which infuriate Pyongyang.</p>

<p>By sending troops to Russia, Kim could be hoping to create a more integrated North Korean and Russian military deterrent, akin to the US-South Korea alliance, potentially "resulting in a significant shift" in the Koreas' security dynamics, Hong said.</p>

<p><strong>'Significant shift'</strong></p>

<p>Ukraine's state-run Centre for Strategic Communication on Friday released a video that purportedly shows North Korean soldiers in what looks like a Russian military camp preparing to join Moscow's war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>In the footage, one of the soldiers appeared to say "move over" to his colleagues with a North Korean accent.</p>

<p>Seoul's spy agency told AFP that it was "inappropriate" for them to comment on materials released by another country's government.</p>

<p>Experts said the deployment gives North Korea's elite soldiers a chance to experience modern warfare, and see how the country's home-grown weaponry -- which Seoul has long accused Kim of sending to Russia -- fares on the battlefield.</p>

<p>It could also be a bid by Kim to enhance his international stature and negotiating position ahead of the US elections next month, Lee Sang-min, a researcher at Korea Institute for Defense Analyses, told AFP.</p>

<p>"One way to attract global attention by doing something reprehensible is by sending troops to support the war in Ukraine, which could prolong the conflict or shift it in Russia's favour," he said.</p>

<p><strong>War economy</strong></p>

<p>For Russia, the benefit of the North Korean deployment is clear, said Vladimir Tikhonov, professor of Korea studies at the University of Oslo.</p>

<p>"Russia's main bottleneck is shortage of both military and labour manpower, and North Korea has a great unexplored potential to alleviate both," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Relations between the two Koreas are at one of their lowest points in years, with Kim on Thursday stressing the country had jettisoned the "unreasonable idea of reunification".</p>

<p>Experts said Pyongyang could also be using Ukraine as a means of re-aligning its foreign policy.</p>

<p>By sending soldiers, North Korea is positioning itself within the Russian war economy as a supplier of weapons, military support and labour -- potentially even bypassing its traditional ally, neighbour and main trading partner, China, according to analysts.</p>

<p>"It means that Pyongyang won't be motivated to seek improvements in relations with Japan, South Korea and the US," Tikhonov said.</p>

<p>"It means a constant state of tension on the Korean Peninsula."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/uqugq52o_north-korea_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea is positioning itself within the Russian war economy as a supplier of weapons and men]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwars-death-clouds-path-to-freeing-israeli-hostages-6824913]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar's Death Clouds Path To Freeing Israeli Hostages]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwars-death-clouds-path-to-freeing-israeli-hostages-6824913]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:49:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Slain Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar was seen as a key obstacle to any agreement on the Israeli hostages seized during the October 7 attack that he orchestrated.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Slain Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar was seen as a key obstacle to any agreement on the Israeli hostages seized during the October 7 attack that he orchestrated.</p>

<p>With his group plunged into a leadership vacuum by his death, the future of hostage negotiations appears to have become even more complicated.</p>

<p>Hamas now needs to appoint a replacement, and that person will play a key role in determining the fate of the Israelis kept hostage since its attack on October 7, 2023.</p>

<p>Of the 251 hostages taken to the Gaza Strip that day, 97 are still being held there, including 34 who the Israeli army has confirmed are dead.</p>

<p>Negotiations for their release are led by Israel's intelligence services, with the help of the United States, Egypt and Qatar.</p>

<p>But that task will be no easier with Sinwar gone, analysts said.</p>

<p>"The hostages' fate may now be sealed for the simple reason that there is no one left to negotiate their release," said Karim Mezran, a Middle East expert at the Atlantic Council think tank.</p>

<p>US intelligence believed "Sinwar's stance had hardened in recent weeks, leading American negotiators to believe that Hamas was no longer interested in reaching a ceasefire or hostage agreement," said the New York-based Soufan Center.</p>

<p>So "any forthcoming negotiations can also serve as a litmus test for Hamas's operational capacity in the post-Sinwar era," the think tank added.</p>

<p>While the families of the hostages welcomed Sinwar's killing, they also expressed "deep concern" about those still held captive.</p>

<p>"We call on the Israeli government, world leaders, and mediating countries to leverage the military achievement into a diplomatic one by pursuing an immediate agreement for the release," the Hostages and Missing Persons Families Forum said on Friday.</p>

<p><strong>Hamas 'decentralised'</strong></p>

<p>Part of the problem lies in how Hamas is no longer the ultra-hierarchical organisation it was when it carried out the October 7 attack which sparked the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Decimated and scattered by Israel's offensive, and with the Gaza Strip cleaved in two by the Israeli army, today the militant group "operates in very localised cells, in a much more decentralised way", researcher David Khalfa at the Fondation Jean-Jaures think tank told AFP.</p>

<p>Hamas "is now more of a militia with local warlords" that has links with "families which apparently are holding hostages", he said.</p>

<p>That "is going to be a real problem for the Israelis and the Americans. Rather than a blanket agreement on the hostages, they will probably aim for releases bit by bit," Khalfa said.</p>

<p>Until the middle of 2024, Hamas's structure was split in two: on the one hand, the political branch led by Ismail Haniyeh, based in the Qatari capital Doha, and the paramilitary branch led by Sinwar in Gaza on the other.</p>

<p>Sinwar rose to become the overall leader of Hamas after Haniyeh was assassinated in July.</p>

<p>The balance of power between the two is now tilted towards the political bureau, "where the sources of funding, logistical support and militia training are concentrated", Khalfa said.</p>

<p>If it chooses a leader in exile, the group runs the risk of seeing its new chief alienated from its forces on the ground in the Palestinian territories.</p>

<p>But if it appoints a fighter such as Sinwar's brother Mohammed, Hamas will be signalling it has less interest in a political resolution to the war.</p>

<p><strong>'Much murkier' picture</strong></p>

<p>Hostage negotiations are now in unchartered territory.</p>

<p>"Prior negotiating efforts were all based on the idea that Sinwar had a line of connection to most of those holding hostages, and he could shape their actions," Jon Alterman of the US think tank CSIS said.</p>

<p>"The picture is much murkier now, and we are likely to see a diverse array of outcomes," he said.</p>

<p>There are even fears the hostages could be executed, perhaps in revenge for Sinwar's killing or because the militants feel they can no longer sell the hostages for cash.</p>

<p>With no one in the group "willing to take the deadly risk of looking after them... the hostages may be left to their own devices and able to escape," Mezran said.</p>

<p>"The fear is also that mid-level Hamas operatives may be tempted to eliminate the hostages to protect their own identities from the eventual retaliation of Israeli forces."</p>

<p>The pressure on Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is enormous, but his government does not appear prepared to secure the hostages' release at any price.</p>

<p>It will not have forgotten the 2011 release of more than 1,000 Palestinian prisoners in exchange for Israeli soldier Gilad Shalit, held hostage by Hamas for five years.</p>

<p>Among the Palestinians freed was Sinwar himself.</p>

<p>"They want to get away from the Shalit precedent, which was a mistake they paid a high price for," Khalfa said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ktv3udd_yahya-sinwar_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Families of the hostages welcomed Sinwar's killing, but expressed concern about those still held captive]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-proxy-resignations-the-new-trend-in-japan-6824898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Are Proxy Resignations? The New Trend In Japan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-are-proxy-resignations-the-new-trend-in-japan-6824898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:43:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Young professionals in Japan are seeking help from specialised agencies to quit their jobs. The phenomenon, known as proxy resignation, is quite popular in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Young professionals in Japan are seeking help from specialised agencies to quit their jobs.&nbsp;Momuri, a Tokyo-based agency, has reported a major spike in demand ever since it began offering proxy resignation services more than two years ago.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Shinji Tanimoto, the head of Albatross, the firm that runs Momuri, told The Guardian that they submit resignations on people's behalf as they are unable to do so for whatever reasons.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In Japanese, Momuri means "enough already".</p>

<p dir="ltr">"Sometimes it's just natural reluctance, but some might have experienced harassment or even violence from their employers. They are at their wits' end when they come to us," the official said.</p>

<p dir="ltr">At present, Momuri is among the estimated 100 companies that offer similar services across Japan. It has received a total of 350,000 online consultations and went on to complete 20,000 resignations.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>How does it work?</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">For this service, people usually get in touch with these agencies via popular messaging apps. In the case of Momuri, clients have to first complete a questionnaire and then sign a contract, besides paying the fee of ¥22,000 (roughly ₹12,344) for full-time workers and ¥12,300 (around ₹6,900) for part-time employees as well as those working on fixed-term contracts.</p>

<p dir="ltr">On behalf of the client, one of Momuri's staff calls the employer. The entire process, starting with the initial consultation to resignation, usually takes 20-30 minutes.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Why are people leaving jobs?</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">Surprisingly, 60% of the Momuri users are those people, who are in their 20s. As per Japan's labour ministry, over 30% of the recent graduates in the country are leaving their jobs within three years.</p>

<p dir="ltr">If experts are to be believed then this growing trend is due to a generational shift in people's attitude towards work that has been accelerated by the disruption to jobs as well as the lifestyles caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Labour shortage in Japan -- a symptom of its low birthrate -- has further made employers more determined towards retaining the staff members, even when it requires intimidating them into staying back. Also, there have been instances when they have allegedly forced workers to hunt for their own replacements before accepting their resignations.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mynavi, an employment information provider in Japan, said that one in six workers in the country took help from resignation agencies to switch to another company in the 12 months period, till June this year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/ubndul7o_job-resignation-generic_625x300_16_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The trend of 'proxy' resignation is rising in Japan. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harris-trump-deploy-celebrity-power-in-must-win-states-6824828]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris, Trump Deploy Celebrity Power In Must-Win States]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harris-trump-deploy-celebrity-power-in-must-win-states-6824828]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:26:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and Donald Trump will roll out starkly contrasting celebrity back-up this weekend in Pennsylvania and Michigan - among the most prized of the battleground states set to decide the tightest of US presidential races.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris and Donald Trump will roll out starkly contrasting celebrity back-up this weekend in Pennsylvania and Michigan -– among the most prized of the battleground states set to decide the tightest of US presidential races.</p>

<p>Pop star Lizzo will throw multi-Grammy award winning glitter behind the vice president's campaign in Detroit, while the world's richest man Elon Musk is to stump for Trump in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Harris will also be joined by R&amp;B star Usher at a get-out-the-vote rally in Atlanta, Georgia, on Saturday.</p>

<p>Both candidates are fighting on every front to seal up voters' support in a race that polls suggest is effectively tied with fewer than three weeks to Election Day.</p>

<p>Musk, who endorsed Trump in July, is one of President Joe Biden administration's fiercest critics and has emerged as a loud voice in US politics since taking over Twitter, now known as X. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO has taken an increasingly visible role in Trump's campaign and has donated almost $75 million to his political organization America PAC.</p>

<p>Harris has deployed high-wattage surrogates, from ex-president Barack Obama to Megan Thee Stallion since replacing Biden as the Democratic nominee in July.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Early voting underway</strong></p>

<p>Seeking to shift the polls in a desperately tight White House race, Harris has ramped up attacks on the mental fitness of the 78-year-old, who is the oldest presidential candidate in US history.</p>

<p>She questioned his ability to be president after Trump faced speculation that he is "exhausted" after backing out of a spate of interviews.</p>

<p>Politico reported that a Trump aide had told producers at a website negotiating an interview that the ex-president was "exhausted" and refusing some appearances -- a claim described by his campaign as "detached from reality."</p>

<p>Beyond the accusations, both candidates are spending their final campaign days in pivotal battleground states where early voting is already underway.</p>

<p>With less than three weeks to go, Harris has seen encouraging signs in her push for supporters to vote as soon as possible, as a bulwark against the traditional Republican edge among Election Day voters.</p>

<p>Almost 12 million votes had been cast by Friday evening -- around a third of them in the seven swing states expected to decide the election -- according to data tracked by the University of Florida Election Lab.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Georgia has been smashing records, while North Carolina reported a first day of voting Thursday that beat 2020, when there was a pandemic-linked surge in early ballots.</p>

<p>Where party breakdowns were available, registered Democrats accounted for roughly half of the total, while Republicans -- who have spent much of the Trump era casting aspersions over drop boxes and mailed ballots -- were responsible for around a third.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ldflnci8_kamala-harris-donald-trump-harris-trump-reuters_625x300_12_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahus-home-targeted-in-drone-attack-from-lebanon-6824374]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Yahya Sinwar's Killing, Drone Targets Benjamin Netanyahu's Residence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahus-home-targeted-in-drone-attack-from-lebanon-6824374]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 13:04:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A drone was launched towardsIsraeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's residence in the Israeli town of Caesarea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A drone was launched towards&nbsp;Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's residence in the Israeli town of Caesarea on Saturday, hours after Hamas leader <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-israel-hamas-small-ugly-broken-israel-soldiers-time-alone-with-yahya-sinwars-body-6822794">Yahya Sinwar was killed</a>.</p>

<p>Mr Netanyahu's spokesperson said he was not in the vicinity and there were no casualties in the attack on his residence.&nbsp;"A UAV (unmanned aerial vehicle) was launched toward the prime minister's residence in Caesarea. The prime minister and his wife were not at the location, and there were no injuries in the incident," the prime minister's office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Earlier, the Israeli military had said that the drone was launched from Lebanon and it had hit a building.&nbsp;Two more drones that crossed into Israeli territory were intercepted, the military was quoted as saying by Reuters.</p>

<p>The drone attack was not immediately claimed by Hezbollah, which has been trading fire with Israel since last October, or any other militant group.</p>

<p>Israel is also fighting a war with Hamas ally Hezbollah in Lebanon. The two sides had exchanged rocket fire since the October 7 attack, with Israel sending ground troops across the Lebanese border last month.</p>

<p>The drone attack comes a day after&nbsp;the Israeli military said it had destroyed Hezbollah's regional command centre with an air strike.&nbsp;Since late September, the war has left at least 1,418 people dead in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures, though the real toll is likely higher.</p>

<p>Meanwhile,&nbsp;Lebanese authorities said two people were killed in an Israeli strike on Saturday in Jounieh, north of Beirut, in the first strike on the area since Hezbollah and Israel started trading fire last year.&nbsp;The health ministry said an "Israeli enemy raid" hit a car in Jounieh, with Lebanese state media saying the attack occurred on a key highway linking the capital to the country's north.</p>

<p>The tripartite conflict in Middle East is likely to see further intensification after Sinwar was killed in an Israeli operation in southern Gaza. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-studying-in-prison-to-heading-hamas-oct-7-attack-who-was-yahya-sinwar-6817331">Sinwar, the mastermind</a> of the October 7 attacks&nbsp;which killed over 1,200 Israelis and brought more than 250 hostages into Gaza, took over as <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-will-replace-yahya-sinwar-these-top-hamas-leaders-are-in-contention-6815803">head of Hamas</a> after the killing of its leader Ismail Haniyeh in the Iranian capital Tehran.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o46p4p8g_netanyahu_625x300_07_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/vikas-yadav-ex-indian-spy-vikash-yadav-wanted-by-fbi-for-alleged-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-plot-was-arrested-for-delhi-kidnapping-last-year-6824153]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Indian Spy, Wanted By FBI, Was Arrested For Delhi Kidnapping Last Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/vikas-yadav-ex-indian-spy-vikash-yadav-wanted-by-fbi-for-alleged-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-plot-was-arrested-for-delhi-kidnapping-last-year-6824153]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 12:25:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vikas Yadav, a former Indian government employee on the Federal Bureau of Investigation's wanted list, was arrested ten months ago by the Delhi Police on charges of attempted murder and kidnapping.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vikas Yadav, a former Indian government employee on the Federal Bureau of Investigation's wanted list, was arrested ten months ago by the Delhi Police on charges of attempted murder and kidnapping.</p>

<p>The former officer of the Research and Analysis Wing (R&amp;AW) has been charged by US prosecutors for his alleged role in directing a failed plot to kill Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun, who holds dual citizenship of the US and Canada. The Ministry of External Affairs on Thursday confirmed that the individual named in the US Justice Department's indictment was "no longer an employee of the government of India".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-for-hire-case-ex-spy-vikash-yadav-drug-smuggler-nikhil-gupta-plot-to-kill-khalistani-terrorist-6816220">Vikas Yadav</a>, also known as Vikash Yadav, was arrested by the special cell of Delhi Police in December last year after a complaint by a businessman from Rohini in north west Delhi and a chargesheet was filed in March this year. Yadav got bail a month later in April.</p>

<p>The businessman - who is said to have many contacts in west Asia - told police that his acquaintance had introduced him to Vikas Yadav in November 2023 and told him that he was a senior government officer. They soon shared mobile numbers to stay in touch.</p>

<p>According to the complaint, Yadav often asked him about his work and friends. The former government employee had also told him that he worked as an undercover agent. But, he never shared any information about his work and office, the businessman told the police.</p>

<p>On December 11, Yadav called him and said that he wanted to discuss some issue and asked him to come to Lodhi Road, as per the complaint. There was another man with Yadav when he reached the location. The businessman claimed that they forcibly kidnapped him and took him to a flat in Defence Colony, where Yadav told him that gangster Lawrence Bishnoi had given him a contract to kill him.</p>

<p>Yadav's associate then hit him on the head and took away his gold chain and rings, he alleged, adding they went to his cafe and took whatever cash was there. According to the complainant, they left him on the side of a road and threatened him with a dire outcome if he complained to anyone.</p>

<p>The businessman soon went to the police and a First Information Report or FIR was filed in the case under the sections of attempt to murder, criminal conspiracy and kidnapping. Yadav and his associate were arrested on December 18.</p>

<p>During interrogation, the associate told the police that he joined the conspiracy with Vikas Yadav as he had suffered losses in his business of old vehicles. He said that Yadav told him that his father was in the Border Security Force.</p>

<p>Vikas Yadav said that he planned the whole crime the day he met the businessman. Delhi Police filed a case in March, and Vikas got bail in April. Although Vikas got interim bail on March 22, but then he got regular bail in April.</p>

<p><strong>US' Charges Against Vikas Yadav</strong></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-indian-spy-charged-in-us-over-alleged-khalistani-terrorist-murder-plot-report-6815072">Vikas Yadav</a> faces three charges: conspiracy to hire a hitman, the actual "murder-for-hire" plot, and money laundering. The charges against him and his alleged co-conspirator Nikhil Gupta, were unsealed in the Federal Southern District of New York Court on Thursday.</p>

<p>According to the indictment, Yadav was the alleged mastermind who recruited Gupta to carry out the plot in exchange for helping him get criminal cases against him dismissed. Nikhil Gupta was arrested in the Czech Republic and was extradited to the US in June.</p>

<p>Many of the details in the document repeat the same narratives made in earlier documents filed against Gupta, but this time, Yadav is identified by name.</p>

<p>"Yadav recruited Gupta to orchestrate the assassination of the Victim in the United States and that under Yadav's directions, Gupta contacted a government "confidential source" who he thought was "a criminal associate," it said.</p>

<p>As per the document, the alleged plot began around May 6 last year with Yadav sending Gupta a message on an encrypted app, "This is Vikas ... save my name as Aman".</p>

<p>In June 2023, they hired a "hitman" and agreed on a payment of $100,000 to allegedly kill the "victim", the court document which did not name Pannun said. Yadav and Gupta arranged through an "associate of Yadav" to give $15,000 as advance.</p>

<p>The plot, however, unravelled as the "hitman" they hired was an undercover US law enforcement officer, according to the 18-page court document, which also included a photograph of Yadav dressed in military fatigues.</p>

<p>The charges were filed a day after an Indian Enquiry Committee set up to investigate the allegations visited Washington to discuss the case with US officials.</p>

<p>In November last year, US federal prosecutors charged Nikhil Gupta of working with an Indian government employee in the foiled plot to kill Pannun in New York.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-05/4tqmje88_fbi-reuters_625x300_30_May_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vikas Yadav is on FBI's wanted list. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-views-on-ai-regulation-takes-centre-stage-in-us-polls-6823963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris Vs. Trump: Views On AI Regulation Takes Centre Stage In US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-views-on-ai-regulation-takes-centre-stage-in-us-polls-6823963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 11:52:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Its not surprising that technology regulation is an important issue in the 2024 US presidential campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">It's not surprising that technology regulation is an important issue in the 2024 US presidential campaign.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>The past decade has seen advanced technologies, from social media algorithms to large language model artificial intelligence systems, profoundly affect society. These changes, which spanned the Trump and Biden-Harris administrations, spurred calls for the federal government to regulate the technologies and the powerful corporations that wield them.</p>

<p>As <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=JpFHYKcAAAAJ&amp;hl=en">a researcher of information systems and AI</a>, I examined both candidates' records on technology regulation. Here are the important differences.</p>

<h3><strong>Algorithmic harms</strong></h3>

<p>With artificial intelligence now widespread, governments worldwide are grappling with how to <a href="https://iapp.org/resources/article/global-ai-legislation-tracker/">regulate various aspects of the technology</a>. The candidates <a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/how-harris-and-trump-differ-on-artificial-intelligence-policy/7718185.html">offer different visions</a> for U.S. AI policy. One area where there is a stark difference is in recognizing and addressing algorithmic harms from the widespread use of AI technology.</p>

<p>AI affects your life in ways that <a href="https://theconversation.com/forget-dystopian-scenarios-ai-is-pervasive-today-and-the-risks-are-often-hidden-218222">might escape your notice</a>. Biases in algorithms <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/algorithmic-bias-detection-and-mitigation-best-practices-and-policies-to-reduce-consumer-harms/#footnote-23">used for lending</a> and hiring decisions could end up <a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250215789/automatinginequality">reinforcing a vicious cycle of discrimination</a>. For example, a student who can't get a loan for college would then be less likely to get the education needed to <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/241363/weapons-of-math-destruction-by-cathy-oneil/">pull herself out of poverty</a>. At the AI Safety Summit in the UK in November 2023, Harris spoke of the promise of AI but also the perils of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2023/11/01/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-future-of-artificial-intelligence-london-united-kingdom/">algorithmic bias, deepfakes and wrongful arrests</a>. Biden <a href="https://theconversation.com/biden-administration-executive-order-tackles-ai-risks-but-lack-of-privacy-laws-limits-reach-216694">signed an executive order on AI</a> on Oct. 30, 2023, that recognized AI systems can pose unacceptable risks of harm to civil and human rights and individual well-being. In parallel, federal agencies such as the Federal Trade Commission <a href="https://theconversation.com/ftc-probe-of-openai-consumer-protection-is-the-opening-salvo-of-us-ai-regulation-209821">have carried out enforcement actions</a> to guard against algorithmic harms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>By contrast, the Trump administration did not take a public stance on mitigation of algorithmic harms. Trump has said he <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ai-artificial-intelligence-kamala-harris-trump-vance-1c94ba2ee6a1410e61d980faa51b19e4">wants to repeal President Biden's AI executive order</a>. In recent interviews, however, Trump noted the dangers of technologies such as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1N_Gdo6tABo">deepfakes and challenges posed to security</a> from AI systems, suggesting a willingness to engage with the growing risks from AI.</p>

<h3><strong>Technological standards</strong></h3>

<p>The Trump administration signed the <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/ai/executive-order-ai/">American AI Initiative executive order</a> on Feb. 11, 2019. The order pledged to double AI research investment and established the first set of national AI research institutes. The order also included a <a href="https://www.nist.gov/system/files/documents/2019/08/10/ai_standards_fedengagement_plan_9aug2019.pdf">plan for AI technical standards</a> and established guidance for the federal government's use of AI. Trump also signed an executive order on Dec. 3, 2020, <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/presidential-actions/executive-order-promoting-use-trustworthy-artificial-intelligence-federal-government/">promoting the use of trustworthy AI in the federal government</a>.</p>

<p>The Biden-Harris administration has tried to go further. Harris convened the heads of Google, Microsoft and other tech companies at the White House on May 4, 2023, to undertake <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ai-artificial-intelligence-kamala-harris-trump-vance-1c94ba2ee6a1410e61d980faa51b19e4">a set of voluntary commitments</a> to safeguard individual rights. The Biden administration's <a href="https://theconversation.com/biden-administration-executive-order-tackles-ai-risks-but-lack-of-privacy-laws-limits-reach-216694">executive order contains an important initiative to probe the vulnerability</a> of very large-scale, general-purpose AI models trained on massive amounts of data. The goal is to determine the risks hackers pose to these models, including the ones that power OpenAI's popular ChatGPT and DALL-E.</p>

<h3><strong>Antitrust</strong></h3>

<p>Antitrust law enforcement – restricting or conditioning mergers and acquisitions – is another way the federal government regulates the technology industry.</p>

<p>The Trump administration's antitrust dossier <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2017/11/20/trump-lawsuit-att-time-warner-merger-250956">includes its attempt to block AT&amp;T's acquisition of Time Warner</a>. The merger was eventually <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2018/06/12/att-time-warner-merger-approved-642333">allowed by a federal judge</a> after the FTC under the Trump administration filed a suit to block the deal. The Trump administration <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/10/20/justice-department-antitrust-case-google-430281">also filed an antitrust case against Google</a> focused on its dominance in internet search.</p>

<p>Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/09/executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">signed an executive order</a> on July 9, 2021, to enforce antitrust laws arising from the anticompetitive effects of dominant internet platforms. The order also targeted the acquisition of nascent competitors, the aggregation of data, unfair competition in attention markets and the surveillance of users. The Biden-Harris administration has filed antitrust cases against <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/03/22/ai-apple-biden-antitrust-suit">Apple and Google</a>.</p>

<p>The Biden-Harris administration's <a href="https://www.investors.com/news/technology/big-tech-antitrust-crackdown-2024-presidential-election/">merger guidelines in 2023</a> outlined rules to determine when mergers can be considered anticompetitive. While both administrations filed antitrust cases, the Biden administration's antitrust push appears stronger in terms of its impact in potentially reorganizing or <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/09/biden-administration-google-antitrust-00177843">even orchestrating a breakup</a> of dominant companies such as Google.</p>

<h3><strong>Cryptocurrency</strong></h3>

<p>The candidates have different approaches to cryptocurrency regulation. Late in his administration, Trump tweeted <a href="https://corpgov.law.harvard.edu/2019/08/06/a-roadmap-for-president-trumps-crypto-crackdown/">in support of cryptocurrency regulation</a>. Also late in Trump's administration, the federal Financial Crimes Enforcement Network <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sm1216">proposed regulations</a> that would have required financial firms to collect the identity of <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/05/30/trump-crypto-bitcoin-nfts">any cryptocurrency wallet to which a user sent funds</a>. The regulations were not enacted.</p>

<p>Trump has since shifted his position on cryptocurrencies. He has criticized <a href="https://theconversation.com/make-bitcoin-great-again-what-donald-trumps-backing-of-crypto-could-mean-for-the-industry-235988">existing US laws</a> and <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/25/nx-s1-5056183/trump-has-a-pro-cryptocurrency-platform-while-harris-chases-the-crypto-vote">called for the United States to be a Bitcoin superpower</a>. The Trump campaign is the first presidential campaign to <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91156274/bitcoin-crypto-rise-after-trump-shooting">accept payments in cryptocurrencies</a>.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/crypto-community-divided-over-kamala-070903707.html">Biden-Harris administration</a>, by contrast, has laid out regulatory restrictions on cryptocurrencies with the Securities and Exchange Commission, which brought about <a href="https://www.cornerstone.com/insights/reports/sec-cryptocurrency-enforcement/">a series of enforcement actions</a>. The <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/house-representatives-vote-biden-veto-overturn-sec-rule">White House vetoed</a> the Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act that aimed to clarify accounting for cryptocurrencies, a bill <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/house-representatives-vote-biden-veto-overturn-sec-rule">favored by the cryptocurrency industry</a>.</p>

<h3><strong>Data privacy</strong></h3>

<p>Biden's AI <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2023/10/30/executive-order-on-the-safe-secure-and-trustworthy-development-and-use-of-artificial-intelligence/">executive order</a> calls on Congress to adopt privacy legislation, but it does not provide a legislative framework to do so. The Trump White House's American AI Initiative <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/ai/executive-order-ai/">executive order</a> mentions privacy only in broad terms, calling for AI technologies to uphold “<a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2019/02/14/2019-02544/maintaining-american-leadership-in-artificial-intelligence">civil liberties, privacy, and American values</a>.” The order did not mention how existing privacy protections would be enforced.</p>

<p>Across the US, several states have tried to pass legislation addressing aspects of data privacy. At present, there is a patchwork of statewide initiatives and a lack of <a href="https://www.dataguidance.com/jurisdiction/usa-federal">comprehensive data privacy legislation</a> at the federal level.</p>

<p>The paucity of federal data privacy protections is a stark reminder that while the candidates are addressing some of the challenges posed by developments in AI and technology more broadly, a lot still remains to be done to regulate technology in the public interest.</p>

<p>Overall, the Biden administration's efforts at antitrust and technology regulation seem broadly aligned with the goal of reining in technology companies and protecting consumers. It's also reimagining monopoly protections for the 21st century. This seems to be the chief difference between the two administrations.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/239676/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/anjana-susarla-334987">Anjana Susarla</a>, Professor of Information Systems, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/michigan-state-university-1349">Michigan State University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/ai-cryptocurrencies-and-data-privacy-comparing-the-trump-and-harris-records-on-technology-regulation-239676">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qnq9s648_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has since shifted his position on cryptocurrencies. (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unfit-for-worlds-toughest-job-harris-targets-trump-after-report-of-exhaustion-6823808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Unfit For World's Toughest Job': Harris Slams Trump's Age]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unfit-for-worlds-toughest-job-harris-targets-trump-after-report-of-exhaustion-6823808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 11:27:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris questioned Donald Trump's fitness for office as the oldest major-party White House candidate in history faced speculation that he is "exhausted" after backing out of a spate of interviews.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris questioned Donald Trump's fitness for office Friday as the oldest major-party White House candidate in history faced speculation that he is "exhausted" after backing out of a spate of interviews.</p>

<p>While he has been appearing on friendly TV networks, the 78-year-old Republican has cancelled sitdowns with media outlets including NBC, CNBC and CBS. He has also refused a second debate with Harris, after being soundly bested in the first.</p>

<p>Politico reported that a Trump aide had told producers at a website negotiating an interview that the ex-president was "exhausted" and refusing some appearances -- a claim described by his campaign as "detached from reality."</p>

<p>But Harris, who turns 60 this weekend, hammered Trump over his health and resilience.</p>

<p>"If you are exhausted on the campaign trail, it raises real questions about whether you are fit for the toughest job in the world," Harris told supporters during a day of multiple stops across the swing state of Michigan.</p>

<p>The former president has hardly been idle, pursuing a busy schedule of appearances with new and traditional media, but most have been on outlets where he is rarely challenged.</p>

<p>Trump reacted angrily to Harris's jab, telling reporters that he had canceled nothing and calling his Democratic opponent a "loser" who "doesn't have the energy of a rabbit."</p>

<p><strong>Dueling rallies</strong></p>

<p>He also claimed to be "killing" her in the polls and that she did not pass the bar exam.</p>

<p>Harris -- a former California attorney general who passed the bar exam in 1990 -- has a narrow lead in national polling averages, while numerous October surveys in Michigan show them neck and neck.</p>

<p>Trump has surprised analysts with a program that mixes swing state stops with appearances in regions he has no chance of winning, but where he is guaranteed big crowds.</p>

<p>He was in the liberal stronghold of New York for a Catholic charity dinner on Thursday, where he mocked Harris in an occasionally mean-spirited speech that earned gasps for its off-color remarks and profanity.</p>

<p>But he was back on home turf Friday morning for a soft Fox News interview, before heading to Michigan for counterprogramming against Harris.</p>

<p>Both candidates are spending their final campaign days in pivotal battleground states where early voting is already underway.</p>

<p>With less than three weeks to go, Harris has seen encouraging signs in her push for supporters to vote as soon as possible, as a bulwark against the traditional Republican edge among Election Day voters.</p>

<p>Almost 12 million votes had been cast by Friday evening -- around a third of them in the seven swing states expected to decide the election -- according to data tracked by the University of Florida Election Lab.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Early voting surge</strong></p>

<p>Georgia has been smashing records, while North Carolina reported a first day of voting Thursday that beat 2020, when there was a pandemic-linked surge of early ballots.</p>

<p>Where party breakdowns were available, registered Democrats accounted for roughly half of the total, while Republicans -- who have spent much of the Trump era casting aspersions over drop boxes and mailed ballots -- were responsible for around a third.</p>

<p>After her event in Grand Rapids, Harris targeted blue-collar voters with remarks at a union hall in Lansing, giving a more manufacturing-focused speech in which she argued that the future of the labor movement was "on the line" in November's election.</p>

<p>She was set to hold an evening rally in Oakland County before returning to Detroit on Saturday.</p>

<p>The Democrat has found herself on eggshells as she upholds President Joe Biden's support for key ally Israel, while Muslim and Arab American voters -- particularly in Michigan -- have voiced outrage over the death toll in Gaza.</p>

<p>The killing of Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar drew optimism from Harris for a Gaza ceasefire, but Israel quickly said his death is not the end of the campaign launched in response to the militant group's October 7, 2023 attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking to journalists ahead of a speech in Detroit, Trump said Sinwar's death had increased the likelihood of a peaceful solution to the war in Gaza -- while warning Biden not to try to restrain Israel.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b64vd7go_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris' comment came as Trumpcancelled sitdowns with several media outlets]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sydneys-mystery-toxic-beach-balls-are-cosmetic-cleaning-product-waste-6823739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sydney's 'Mystery' Toxic Beach Balls Are Cosmetic, Cleaning Product Waste]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sydneys-mystery-toxic-beach-balls-are-cosmetic-cleaning-product-waste-6823739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 11:11:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Beaches in Sydney re-opened for swimmers after authorities cleared thousands of black pollution balls washed ashore.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Beaches in Sydney re-opened on Saturday for swimmers after authorities cleared thousands of black pollution balls washed ashore, which testing found to be formed from chemicals similar to those in cosmetics and cleaning products.</p>

<p>Around 2,000 of the mystery black balls, some golf ball-sized, had washed onto beaches across Sydney since Tuesday, forcing the closure of eight beaches, including the iconic Bondi Beach, and a massive clean-up operation, amid fears they were highly toxic.</p>

<p>"Based on advice from the Environment Protection Authority, we can now confirm the balls are made up of fatty acids, chemicals consistent with those found in cleaning and cosmetic products, mixed with some fuel oil," said New South Wales Maritime Executive Director Mark Hutchings in a statement.</p>

<p>He added the balls, which continued to appear on Friday in fewer numbers, are not harmful to health when left on the sand, but should not be touched.</p>

<p>The New South Wales Environment Protection Authority said laboratory testing was continuing, to try to determine where the balls came from.</p>

<p>"It is still somewhat of a mystery and may take a few more days to determine origin," said EPA Executive Director Stephen Beaman.</p>

<p>Sydney's ocean beaches, famed for golden sand and clean water, draw tourists from around the globe.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rki4nmio_tar-ball-generic-x-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The balls are not harmful to health when left on the sand, but should not be touched.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/record-high-colombian-cocaine-production-in-2023-un-6823705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Record High Colombian Cocaine Production In 2023: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/record-high-colombian-cocaine-production-in-2023-un-6823705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 11:07:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Colombia, the world's biggest cocaine exporter, set a new record last year for production of the drug and cultivation of the coca leaf it is made from, a United Nations report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Colombia, the world's biggest cocaine exporter, set a new record last year for production of the drug and cultivation of the coca leaf it is made from, a United Nations report said Friday.</p>

<p>Coca leaf cultivation was 10 percent higher last year than in 2022, while cocaine production rose 53 percent from 1,738 tonnes to 2,600, according to the UN Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC).</p>

<p>These were the highest numbers since the UN started monitoring in 2001. Most Colombian cocaine is destined for the United States and Europe.</p>

<p>Coca leaf production now spreads over 253,000 hectares (625,100 acres) in the country.</p>

<p>The trend has been upward since 2014 despite a US-based war on drugs worth millions of dollars.</p>

<p>The areas of Colombia with the biggest increase in 2023 were the Cauca and Narino departments, both bastions of dissidents groups of the FARC guerrilla army that disbanded in 2017.</p>

<p>Some 20 percent of the total area under coca cultivation in Colombia is on land belonging to communities of African descent, 10 percent on Indigenous reserves and 18 percent in protected forest areas.</p>

<p>The Colombian city of Cali will host the COP16 global summit on biodiversity for two weeks starting Monday.</p>

<p>Colombia's first-ever leftist President Gustavo Petro has accused US anti-drug policies of causing a "genocide" of Latin Americans for focusing on "repression" rather than prevention and public health.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/fhmcad18_cocaine-large_625x300_02_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[20% of the area under coca cultivation in Colombia is on land belonging to communities of African descent]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-chinas-continued-persecution-of-religious-minorities-6823501]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: China's Continued Persecution Of Religious Minorities]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-chinas-continued-persecution-of-religious-minorities-6823501]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 10:29:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's government has been going ahead with its religious persecution without impunity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's government has been going ahead with its religious persecution without impunity. In its latest salvo, they have clamped down on all churches - Catholic and Protestant - in the country by ordering the pulling out of images of Jesus and his replacement with images of President Xi Jinping, according to a US government report on anti-religious activities in China.</p>

<p>In the continuing saga of 'Sinicization', China has pushed to align all religions or shape all religions to adapt to the doctrines of the CCP (Communist Party of China) and the customs of the majority Han Chinese population.</p>

<p>Since President Xi Jinping came to power in March 2013, authorities have insisted on adhering to Communist Party values like speaking only in Mandarin Chinese and rejecting all foreign influence that may endanger China's unity.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>What is Sinicization?</strong></p>

<p>Sinicization is the procedure in which non-Chinese groups or societies are integrated into Chinese culture. The process includes the adoption of Chinese language, culture, ethnic identity and societal norms.</p>

<p>Sinicization is also a part of the Chinese government's policy of subordinating religious groups to the Communist Party of China's (CCP) political agenda. The policy of Sinicization has been started under the leadership of Xi Jinping and has transformed China's religious landscape. Some of the government-introduced actions include:</p>

<p>1)Placing CCP supporters as religious leaders</p>

<p>2)Changing the designs of religious places like mosques, churches etc with CCP-approved architecture</p>

<p>3) Mixing CCP publicity into religious doctrines</p>

<p>4) Outlawing non-CCP-backed religious activities</p>

<p>China is officially an atheist country but it recognises five religions: Buddhism, Catholicism, Daoism, Islam, and Protestantism. The practice of any other faith is formally prohibited.</p>

<p>While the Chinese constitution (Article 36) mentions that citizens 'enjoy the freedom of religious belief' and bars discrimination based on religion, the law controls religion by preventing state organs, public organisations etc. It dissuades citizens from following any faith. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>The anti-religion campaign initiated by President Xi has the backing of all state-controlled religious organisations.</p>

<p>There is also a feeling that homegrown religions like Confucianism, Buddhism, and Daoism do not challenge the CCP's rule but others do.</p>

<p><strong>Why does China fear Buddhists and Christians?</strong></p>

<p>The Tibetan Buddhists staying in China's Tibetan region have faced high levels of religious persecution. Chinese authorities keep a firm eye on the daily operations of their major monasteries. Despite China's strict vigilance, reports of detainments and torture of monks and nuns for refusing to denounce the Dalai Lama often surface. Followers of the Dalai Lama too have been ordered to replace his photos with those of the Chinese leaders. China fears 'outside influence' from the exiled Dalai Lama.</p>

<p>As per the US government report made public recently, "The government has ordered the removal of crosses from churches, replaced images of Jesus Christ or the Virgin Mary with pictures of President Xi, required the display of CCP slogans at the entrances of churches, censored religious texts, imposed CCP-approved religious materials, and instructed clergy to preach CCP ideology."</p>

<p>The Vatican can't take up the issue of repression of Catholics estimated to be around 10 to 12 million, since it does not have diplomatic ties with China.</p>

<p>The Vatican's recognition of Taiwan and a dispute over the bishop appointment process in China have been the reasons for the dispute. Of late, both countries have come to a sort of agreement whereby the Pope has recognised several Chinese state-appointed bishops.</p>

<p>As of now, Christians have rejected the government-controlled churches completely and instead are worshipping independently.</p>

<p><strong>How China targeted Muslims? &nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Muslims form around 1 to 1.5% of China's population. Reports of China's genocide against the Uyghur population and other mostly-Muslim ethnic groups in the north-western region of Xinjiang have been circulated for years now.</p>

<p>According to China's 2020 census, there are more than 11 million Uyghurs in this region. The Uyghurs were brutalised because they spoke their language, similar to Turkish, and considered themselves culturally and ethnically close to Central Asian countries.</p>

<p>More than one million Uyghurs have been held captive over the past few years in a large network of what China calls its 're-education camps', and sentenced hundreds of thousands to prison terms. There has been mass sterilisation to control the Uyghur population and thousands have been enlisted to work as forced labourers in farms and factories put up by China. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>Authorities have banned their religious practices in the region and made mosques and tombs non-operational. Despite the hue and cry from human rights groups and the world at large, China's atrocities on Uyghurs didn't cease.</p>

<p>Till very late, Hui Muslims had been lucky to avoid the tight control of the Chinese government as the latter's focus remained on the Uyghur Muslims in the Xinjiang region.</p>

<p>In 2020-21, China targeted the Hui Muslim community by removing the domes and minarets from thousands of mosques across the country. The Chinese authorities then, like now, felt that the domes are signs of foreign Saudi and Arabic religious influence. They demolished domes as they were symbolic of Islamic architecture - and were not Chinese in origin. This was part of an ongoing push to Sinicize Muslims to make them traditionally Chinese. As part of the process, mosques were closed and the mosque properties were acquired by the government, and imams were arrested.</p>

<p><strong>Reactions from the world</strong></p>

<p>Of course, China has repeatedly denied all allegations and continues to rubbish charges that it is carrying out oppression of the Uyghur population and other minorities. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The US and Western nations have called out China several times. They presented a draft resolution to request a discussion in the UN Human Rights Council about the Xinjiang report in October 2022. The draft resolution failed by a slim margin of two votes. But many countries have been silent on the issue.</p>

<p>India and ten other nations abstained from voting in the UN against China over the human rights situation in the Xinjiang region.</p>

<p>However, officially India took a stand that the community's human rights should be "respected". Amidst border issues, India has been treading cautiously on geo-political issues with China on international forums.</p>

<p>The response of many countries on the Uyghur issue has been based on political calculations on how they have aligned with China.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qo5q2uh8_chinese-president-xi-jinping-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Xi's campaign has the backing of all state-controlled religious organisations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israeli-tank-fire-at-yahya-sinwars-gaza-hideout-before-ground-raid-6823407]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Israeli Tank Fires At Yahya Sinwar's Hideout Before Ground Raid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israeli-tank-fire-at-yahya-sinwars-gaza-hideout-before-ground-raid-6823407]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 10:05:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel killed Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar in an armour-infantry assault in southern Gaza's Rafah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel killed Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar in an armour-infantry assault in southern Gaza's Rafah. Israel's 828th Brigade conducted "intelligence-based targeted raids and operations," the Israel Defence Forces said, giving details of the damage assessment, where they found assault rifles and snipers in the hideout and Sinwar's body.</p>

<p>The IDF also shared a video of a tank firing at the Hamas leader's hideout in Rafah. The drone footage shows a building - circled in red - is the target. IDF claims that it is the building in which Yahya Sinwar barricaded himself.</p>

<p>The tank fires a round, destroying the structure, which was already in ruins. The troops then moved in for damage assessment and found AK assault rifles, an SVD Dragunov sniper rifle, magazines, and live ammunition.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j5hi9b3g_hamas-weapons_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: IDF</span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>In another video, the ground troops are seen operating in the area where Yahya Sinwar was eliminated. After the "success" of the operation MG Yaron Finkelman, Commanding Officer of the Southern Command, Israel Army, addressed the troops and said, "The perseverance, patience and terrain analysis...and the initiation of contact and you fired at them...is a matter that is very significant."</p>

<p>The Israeli troops found a body resembling Yahya Sinwar's, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-hamas-lebanon-sinwar-gaza-iran-10-18-24-intl-hnk#cm2f17my500053b6q9qqm93ef" rel="no follow, no index">CNN reported</a>. They cut his finger off for a DNA confirmation with a profile the troops had when Sinwar was in Israeli prison for two decades until his release in 2011 in a prisoner-swap deal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Videos of Israeli troops searching the hideout surfaced on social media. One of the videos, assessed by NDTV, shows two Israeli soldiers standing next to a body (claimed to be Yahya Sinwar's) with the index finger of the left hand being chopped off. Meanwhile, CNN in its report said they analysed videos which showed his left hand with all five fingers, and then later with one finger missing.</p>

<p>He told CNN that the Hamas leader suffered other injuries, including from a tank shell, but he was confident a bullet to the head was what had killed the Hamas leader.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-in-head-finger-cut-off-chilling-details-of-yahya-sinwars-autopsy-6822817">IDF claims that the tank</a> round fired at the building eliminated the Hamas leader. The video assessed by NDTV showed the body's skull being ruptured, with injuries to the face, corroborating claims made by the chief pathologist in the CNN report.</p>

<p>Yahya Sinwar was the mastermind of the October 7, 2023 attack on Israel in which over 1,200 people were killed, resulting in a year-long Israeli operation in Gaza, killing over 40,000 including children.</p>

<p>Israel vowed to uproot Hamas from Gaza and has so far eliminated most of its top leadership, including its previous chief Ismail Haniyeh, who was assassinated in July.</p>

<p>After Sinwar's death, Israel now hopes the hostages still stuck in Gaza would be returned. Sinwar's deputy Khalil Al-Hayya, who is viewed as a potential successor, struck a defiant note, saying hostages would not be returned until Israeli troops withdrew from Gaza and the war ended.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rm782pk_yahya-sinwar-attack_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar was the mastermind of the October 7, 2023 attack on Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-payne-used-hallucinogenic-drug-before-falling-to-his-death-report-6823367]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Liam Payne Used Hallucinogenic Drug Before Falling To His Death: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-payne-used-hallucinogenic-drug-before-falling-to-his-death-report-6823367]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 09:57:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Liam Payne's death has been deemed suspicious and under the possible influence of drug abuse by authorities investigating the circumstances leading to it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British popstar and former One Direction member Liam Payne used powerful hallucinogenic drugs before falling to his death from a hotel in Argentina on October 16, a report said. Payne, 31, was found dead after falling from a third-floor balcony at the CasaSur Palermo Hotel in Buenos Aires.</p>

<p>Police indicated that Mr Payne was using a dangerous substance known as "Cristal," which is notorious for causing extreme highs and lows in users, often leading to aggressive behaviour. Test results on the narcotics and medications recovered from his room, confirming the same, are being awaited.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/18/entertainment/liam-payne-was-using-powerful-hallucinogenic-drug-when-he-plunged-to-death-at-argentina-hotel-report/">reports</a>, he may have been under the influence of multiple substances at the time of his fall. Emergency services were called to the hotel after staff frantically described him as "an aggressive man overwhelmed with drugs and alcohol." The police statement to AP further said that he "had jumped" from the balcony of his hotel room.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Photos from Liam Payne's hotel room in Argentina, where he met his tragic end<br />
<br />
You can see drugs and damage throughout the hotel room <a href="https://t.co/hm6zWRSyBB">pic.twitter.com/hm6zWRSyBB</a></p>
— keep6ixsolid (@keep6ixsolid) <a href="https://twitter.com/keep6ixsolid/status/1846678136944988265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Upon entering Mr Payne's hotel suite, authorities discovered a chaotic scene, with broken items and various drugs scattered throughout. Among the substances found were packs of clonazepam, a central nervous system depressant, along with energy supplements and over-the-counter medications.</p>

<p>Forensic teams also recovered a whiskey bottle, lighter, and cell phone from the courtyard where his body was located. Investigators noted that the absence of defensive injuries suggested he may have been in a state of semi-consciousness or complete unconsciousness when he fell.</p>

<p>As reported by<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/18/entertainment/liam-payne-was-using-powerful-hallucinogenic-drug-when-he-plunged-to-death-at-argentina-hotel-report/" rel="No Link, No Follow"> </a>The New York Post, Mr Payne said during a 2021 appearance on the "The Diary of a CEO" podcast, "I was worried how far my rock bottom was going to be. Where's rock bottom for me? And you would never have seen it. I'm very good at hiding it. No one would ever have seen it."</p>

<p>Mr Payne had previously entered rehab multiple times and also had expressed suicidal thoughts during his career. Despite claims of sobriety earlier this year, sources indicate he was battling significant drug addiction leading up to his death. The investigation into the circumstances surrounding his passing is ongoing.</p>

<p>As the investigation continues, fans gathered outside the hotel to pay tribute to Payne, leaving flowers and candles in his memory. His former bandmates expressed their devastation over his passing, emphasizing their cherished memories of him and calling for privacy as they grieve.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ggnu5k6_liam-payne-and-hotel-where-he-died_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to reports, he may have been under the influence of multiple substances at the time of his fall]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/probe-into-israels-elite-ghost-sniper-unit-accused-of-war-crimes-in-gaza-6823326]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Probe Into Israel's Elite "Ghost" Sniper Unit Accused Of War Crimes In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/probe-into-israels-elite-ghost-sniper-unit-accused-of-war-crimes-in-gaza-6823326]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 09:44:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Belgian court has opened an investigation into allegations of war crimes by an Israel Defence Forces (IDF) soldier in the ongoing conflict in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Belgian court has opened an investigation into allegations of war crimes by an Israel Defence Forces (IDF) soldier in the ongoing conflict in Gaza. The Belgian Federal Prosecutor's Office launched a probe into a dual Belgian-Israeli national serving in the IDF, who is in his early twenties. The soldier was born and raised in a suburb of Brussels, and serves in the IDF's elite Multidimensional "Ghost" (Refaim) sniper unit, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-825183" rel="nofollow,noindex">report</a> said.</p>

<p>The investigation centres around accusations that the soldier targeted unarmed civilians in the Gaza Strip. The complaints suggest that uninvolved civilians were deliberately shot, violating international laws protecting non-combatants.</p>

<p>The Belgian-Palestinian Association (ABP) filed the complaint that triggered the investigation. Belgian law allows the prosecution of its citizens for crimes committed abroad.</p>

<p>The Belgian Federal Prosecutor's Office confirmed the investigation on Friday, stating that it aims to verify whether the alleged war crimes were committed by the sniper.</p>

<p>This case follows a report by Palestinian journalist <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/ytirawi/status/1842242729436201158" rel="nofollow,noindex">Younis Tirawi</a>, who accused the Refaim sniper unit of deliberately targeting unarmed civilians. According to Tirawi, his findings were corroborated by a senior American officer serving within the unit. The officer allegedly shared evidence and recounted instances where the unit fired on civilians, even when there was no threat to IDF forces.</p>

<p>The Refaim Unit, to which the accused soldier belongs, has reportedly been active in Gaza since October 2023. This elite Israeli military unit, consisting of 21 soldiers, includes members from various nationalities. In addition to the Belgian under investigation, the unit comprises three Americans, two French citizens, one German, and one Italian, among others.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The case against the Belgian sniper draws heavily on interviews conducted by Tirawi. According to the journalist, the senior American officer provided chilling testimony, likening Gaza to the biblical city of Sodom, which was destroyed due to its sins.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The officer allegedly referred to Gaza's residents as "Amalekites," a term from the Old Testament often used in historical contexts to describe enemies of the Israelites.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n1i3h0v8_ghost-unit-_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Refaim Unit has reportedly been active in Gaza since October 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-woman-risks-childrens-lives-on-23rd-floor-ac-unit-to-upset-husband-during-argument-6823202]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Woman Risks Children's Lives On 23rd-Floor AC Unit To Upset Husband]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-woman-risks-childrens-lives-on-23rd-floor-ac-unit-to-upset-husband-during-argument-6823202]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 09:17:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman in central China sparked outrage after placing her two young children on an air conditioning unit outside their 23rd-floor apartment during an argument with her husband.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a fight with her husband, a woman in central China allegedly disturbed him by placing her two small children on an air conditioner outside their 23rd-floor apartment, according to <em>the South China Morning Post.</em></p>

<p>On October 10, neighbours in Luoyang, Henan province, heard the children's cries and recorded the event for posterity in a viral video. The children were not wearing any safety gear; therefore, the mother prevented the father from getting to them. The daughter was crying, while her brother seemed more composed. It's unknown what caused the couple's fight. A nearby resident reported the incident to the police.</p>

<p>"The firefighting vehicle came and the children were rescued," an official at the local Women and Children's Federation said, adding that they were looking into the case.</p>

<p>According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3282333/china-mother-sits-children-23rd-floor-outdoor-air-con-unit-annoy-husband-during-row">SCMP</a>, </em>the police are also investigating the incident. It was not disclosed whether the mother would receive punishment. The video clip, viewed 55 million times on Weibo alone, received a huge response in China.</p>

<p>"A mother should protect her children. But she put her children in dire danger. She is not fit to be a mother," one online observer said.</p>

<p>"If an accident happens, she will regret it more than anyone else. Why adopt such an extreme measure? Calm down. If you cannot live with him any longer, just divorce him," another person wrote.</p>

<p>"This woman is insane and horrible! She should receive serious judicial punishment," said another.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jp3preb8_23rdfloor-apartment_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mother blocked the father from reaching them.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>